<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 21:34:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Use creative automation software to amp up your brand&#8217;s lower-funnel assets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/use-creative-automation-software-to-amp-up-your-brands-lower-funnel-assets/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/use-creative-automation-software-to-amp-up-your-brands-lower-funnel-assets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 21:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Ecommerce and D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2200484</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In addition to driving a clear lift in revenue, automating digital marketing assets means cost and time savings, too. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Miha Mikek</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/mihamikek1">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<p>
Miha Mikek is the CEO and co-founder of creative automation company <a href="https://celtra.com/">Celtra</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">With the holiday season around the corner, growth marketers are gearing up for their busiest time of the year. E-commerce brands are now leaning heavily on social sales and digital advertising, but should also expect an omnichannel shopper &#8212; <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/celtras-2021-holiday-marketing-survey-reveals-shopper-desire-for-omnichannel-ad-personalization-301365523.html">62% of shoppers</a> plan to purchase both online and in-store this holiday season, according to Celtra.</p>
<p>The marketplace is crowded. Digital marketing requires high volumes of on-brand creative assets, and it is tough to produce them fast enough without compromising on brand equity or storytelling. While marketing channels have exploded in volume, most creative production workflows are the same as they were 50 years ago.</p>
<p>But marketing is a monster that feeds on creative assets, requiring more and more each quarter.</p>
<p>The reality is, any paid impression is also a brand impression and a chance to differentiate in the market. In fact, paid impressions are often the only chance you get to influence some shoppers. That&#8217;s why creative &#8212; your brand, your design and your message &#8212; matters. In growth marketing, traffic, subscriptions, direct-to-consumer channels, testing and, ultimately, revenue all rely on creative to succeed.</p>
<p>Yet, lower-funnel assets are rarely brilliant in branding or even remotely interesting. Teams are limited in meeting global demands across more channels than ever, and the creative they produce is suffering. Brands don’t have the luxury of spending time on design craft and storytelling at scale. Conversely, most creative automation solutions that can assist with efficiency aren’t currently equipped to scale high-quality creative that prioritizes branding and design excellence.</p>
<p>Enterprises are suffering from a creative gap where their content and asset needs are growing fast while team resources and budgets are stagnant or even declining.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, there isn’t a magic AI bullet to solve the challenge. You can’t just buy creative technology in the hopes that it alone will bridge the gap. You need to rethink workflows and team collaboration. If you’re serious about elevating your growth marketing creative, you need to invest in tools that are built for scale and brand governance at once.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/use-creative-automation-software-to-amp-up-your-brands-lower-funnel-assets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2200484</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Intuit confirms $12B deal to buy Mailchimp</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/intuit-confirms-12b-deal-to-buy-mailchimp/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/intuit-confirms-12b-deal-to-buy-mailchimp/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 20:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mailchimp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201803</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This afternoon Intuit confirmed persistent rumors that it was in the process of buying Mailchimp, detailing a $12 billion transaction that will bring the well-known email infra company to its corporate remit. Intuit is not a well-known player in the email marketing space. The company is instead best known for its TurboTax software (and associated [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This afternoon Intuit <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210913005806/en/Intuit-to-Acquire-Mailchimp">confirmed</a> persistent rumors that it was in the process of buying Mailchimp, detailing a $12 billion transaction that will bring the well-known email infra company to its corporate remit.</p>
<p>Intuit is not a well-known player in the email marketing space. The company is instead best known for its TurboTax software (and associated lobbying of the U.S. government to ensure its rent-seeking can continue), its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/24/intuit-credit-karma/">recent purchase of Credit Karma</a> and its more <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2009/09/14/the-value-of-techcrunch50-mint-acquired-by-intuit-for-170m-two-years-after-winning-tc40/#:~:text=Today%2C%20exactly%20two%20years%20after%20launching%20at%20TechCrunch40%2C,as%20the%20maker%20of%20Quicken%2C%20QuickBooks%2C%20and%20TurboTax.">dated acquisition of Mint</a>.</p>
<p>The Mailchimp transaction will comprised both cash and stock.</p>
<p>The question rattling around your brain at the moment is the correct thing to ask: <em>Why is Intuit spending 10% of its market capitalization to buy an email marketing company?<strong> </strong></em></p>
<p>Per a release, Intuit thinks that the deal &#8220;advances&#8221; its &#8220;powering prosperity around the world, and its strategy to become an AI-driven expert platform.&#8221; Normally at this juncture I&#8217;d convert the company&#8217;s corporate-speak to something in English, but I&#8217;m struggling.</p>
<p>The company had more to say in that its Mailchimp buy would allow it to &#8220;accelerate two of [Intuit&#8217;s] previously shared strategic Big Bets: to become the center of small business growth; and to disrupt the small business midmarket.&#8221;</p>
<p>This is a bit more grokkable. Intuit&#8217;s QuickBooks service is a well-known product in the SMB space. Presumably Intuit reckons that it can sell more services to its existing small business customers. It still feels like a bit of a stretch, but we presume that the eggheads have come to the conclusion that ensuing corporate synergies will more than compensate for the sticker shock that the deal includes.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Shares of Intuit are up a slim 0.15% in after-hours trading, implying something of a shrug from Wall Street concerning the transaction; given how well leaked the deal was on its way to consummation, the combination may have already been priced into Intuit&#8217;s share price.</p>
<p>For Atlanta, where Mailchimp is headquartered, the deal is a win. Mailchimp is a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/13/mailchimps-ben-chestnut-on-bootstrapping-a-startup-to-700m-in-revenue/">famously bootstrapped company</a>, so if you were looking for confirmation that you can build decacorns outside of Silicon Valley and without venture capital help, here&#8217;s evidence.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/intuit-confirms-12b-deal-to-buy-mailchimp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201803</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitch sues two users for harassing streamers with hate raids</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/twitch-hate-raids-lawsuits/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/twitch-hate-raids-lawsuits/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 20:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content moderation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online harassment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitch filed a lawsuit late last week against two people on its own platform for running automated hate and harassment campaigns. The harassment, often targeted at Black and LGBTQ streamers, manifests in a unique Twitch phenomenon as a &#8220;hate raid.&#8221; On Twitch, creators regularly point viewers toward another friendly account after their stream concludes to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitch filed a lawsuit late last week against two people on its own platform for running automated hate and harassment campaigns.</p>
<p>The harassment, often targeted at Black and LGBTQ streamers, manifests in a unique Twitch phenomenon as a &#8220;hate raid.&#8221; On Twitch, creators regularly point viewers toward another friendly account after their stream concludes to boost their audiences, a practice known as a &#8220;raid.&#8221; Hate raids invert that formula, sending swarms of bots to harass streamers who have inadequate tools at their disposal to block the influx of abuse.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pbSHQiakmM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/streamers-are-boycotting-twitch-today-to-protest-the-platforms-lack-of-action-on-hate-raids/">Streamers are boycotting Twitch today to protest the platform&#8217;s lack of action on &#8216;hate raids&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Streamers are boycotting Twitch today to protest the platform&#8217;s lack of action on &#8216;hate raids&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/streamers-are-boycotting-twitch-today-to-protest-the-platforms-lack-of-action-on-hate-raids/embed/#?secret=pbSHQiakmM" data-secret="pbSHQiakmM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The hate raids leverage Twitch&#8217;s new tagging system, which many transgender users had requested to make it easier to build community and to discover content that resonates. In May, Twitch added more than 350 new tags to help viewers sort streams by &#8220;gender, sexual orientation, race, nationality, ability, mental health, and more.&#8221; Accounts spreading abuse now use those tags to target racist, sexist, transphobic and homophobic harassment toward streamers, another unfortunate misuse of a tool explicitly designed to give creators a boost.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">We’ve seen a lot of conversation about botting, hate raids, and other forms of harassment targeting marginalized creators. You’re asking us to do better, and we know we need to do more to address these issues. That includes an open and ongoing dialogue about creator safety.</p>
<p>&mdash; Twitch (@Twitch) <a href="https://twitter.com/Twitch/status/1425550620887375876?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 11, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>In the suit, Twitch described hate raiders as &#8220;highly motivated&#8221; malicious individuals who improvise new ways to circumvent the platform&#8217;s terms of service. Twitch named two users, &#8220;CruzzControl&#8221; and &#8220;CreatineOverdose,&#8221; in the suit but the company was unable to obtain their legal names. The users are based in the Netherlands and Austria, respectively, and their activity began in August of this year. Twitch alleges that CruzzControl alone has been linked to 3,000 bot accounts involved in hate raids.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While it&#8217;s possible that Twitch won&#8217;t be able to identify the real identities of individuals behind the recent harassment campaigns, the lawsuit could act as a deterrent for other accounts directing waves of abuse on the streaming platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;While we have identified and banned thousands of accounts over the past weeks, these actors continue to work hard on creative ways to circumvent our improvements, and show no intention of stopping,&#8221; the lawsuit reads. &#8220;We hope this Complaint will shed light on the identity of the individuals behind these attacks and the tools that they exploit, dissuade them from taking similar behaviors to other services, and help put an end to these vile attacks against members of our community.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;This Complaint is by no means the only action we’ve taken to address targeted attacks, nor will it be the last,&#8221; a Twitch spokesperson told TechCrunch. &#8220;Our teams have been working around the clock to update our proactive detection systems, address new behaviors as they emerge, and finalize new proactive, channel-level safety tools that we’ve been developing for months.&#8221;</p>
<p>Prior to Twitch&#8217;s legal action, some Twitch creators <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/streamers-are-boycotting-twitch-today-to-protest-the-platforms-lack-of-action-on-hate-raids/">organized #ADayOffTwitch</a> to protest the company&#8217;s failure to offer solutions for users targeted by hate raids. People participating in the protest demanded that Twitch take decisive actions toward protecting streamers from hate raids, including letting creators deny incoming raids and screen out chat participants with newly made accounts. They also drew attention to Twitch policies that allow unlimited accounts to be linked to a single email address, a loophole that makes it easy to create and deploy armies of bot accounts.</p>
<p><iframe class="scribd_iframe_embed" src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/525072029/content?start_page=1&view_mode&access_key=key-xpRLiCP4IDAiS4C4TwrW"  data-auto-height="true" scrolling="no" id="scribd_525072029" width="100%" height="500" frameborder="0"></iframe>
		<div style="font-size:10px;text-align:center;width:100%"><a href="https://www.scribd.com/doc/525072029" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">View this document on Scribd</a></div></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tBXfrJVyRm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/twitch-off-platform-harassment-policy/">Twitch expands its rules against hate and abuse to include behavior off the platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitch expands its rules against hate and abuse to include behavior off the platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/twitch-off-platform-harassment-policy/embed/#?secret=tBXfrJVyRm" data-secret="tBXfrJVyRm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="72YfJNW2DX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/twitch-updates-its-hateful-content-and-harassment-policy-after-company-called-out-for-its-ownabuses/">Twitch updates its hateful content and harassment policy after company called out for its own abuses</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitch updates its hateful content and harassment policy after company called out for its own abuses&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/twitch-updates-its-hateful-content-and-harassment-policy-after-company-called-out-for-its-ownabuses/embed/#?secret=72YfJNW2DX" data-secret="72YfJNW2DX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/twitch-hate-raids-lawsuits/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201731</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple patches an NSO zero-day flaw affecting all devices</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/apple-zero-day-nso-pegasus/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/apple-zero-day-nso-pegasus/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 19:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Citizen Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imessage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile phones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NSO Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pegasus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spyware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple has released security updates for a newly discovered zero-day vulnerability that affects every iPhone, iPad, Mac and Apple Watch. Citizen Lab, which discovered the vulnerability and was credited with the find, urges users to immediately update their devices. The technology giant said iOS 14.8 for iPhones and iPads, as well as new updates for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple has released security updates for a newly discovered zero-day vulnerability that affects every iPhone, iPad, Mac and Apple Watch. Citizen Lab, which discovered the vulnerability and was credited with the find, urges users to immediately update their devices.</p>
<p>The technology giant said iOS 14.8 for iPhones and iPads, as well as new updates for Apple Watch and macOS, will fix at least one vulnerability that it said &#8220;may have been actively exploited.&#8221;</p>
<p>Citizen Lab said it has now discovered new artifacts of the ForcedEntry vulnerability, details it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/nso-pegasus-bahrain-iphone-security/">first revealed</a> in August as part of an investigation into the use of a zero-day vulnerability that was used to silently hack into iPhones belonging to at least one Bahraini activist.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qSOvjORNW0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/nso-pegasus-bahrain-iphone-security/">A new NSO zero-click attack evades Apple&#8217;s iPhone security protections, says Citizen Lab</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A new NSO zero-click attack evades Apple&#8217;s iPhone security protections, says Citizen Lab&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/nso-pegasus-bahrain-iphone-security/embed/#?secret=qSOvjORNW0" data-secret="qSOvjORNW0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Last month, Citizen Lab said the zero-day flaw — named as such since it gives companies zero days to roll out a fix — took advantage of a flaw in Apple’s iMessage, which was exploited to push the Pegasus spyware, developed by Israeli firm NSO Group, to the activist’s phone.</p>
<p>Pegasus gives its government customers near-complete access to a target’s device, including their personal data, photos, messages and location.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--callout block--right" >
		<h4 class="block--callout__title">Read more on TechCrunch</h4>
		
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/nso-pegasus-bahrain-iphone-security/">A new NSO zero-click attack evades Apple’s iPhone security protections</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/20/citizen-lab-iphone-nso-group/">Dozens of journalists’ iPhones hacked with NSO ‘zero-click’ spyware</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/nso-fleming-data-location/">NSO used real people’s location data to pitch its contact-tracing tech</a></li>
</ul>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>The breach was significant because the flaws exploited the latest iPhone software at the time, both iOS 14.4 and later iOS 14.6, which Apple released in May. But also the vulnerabilities broke through new iPhone defenses that Apple had baked into iOS 14, dubbed BlastDoor, which were supposed to prevent silent attacks by filtering potentially malicious code. Citizen Lab calls this particular exploit ForcedEntry for its ability to skirt Apple&#8217;s BlastDoor protections.</p>
<p>In its <a href="https://citizenlab.ca/2021/09/forcedentry-nso-group-imessage-zero-click-exploit-captured-in-the-wild/">latest findings</a>, Citizen Lab said it found evidence of the ForcedEntry exploit on the iPhone of a Saudi activist, running at the time the latest version of iOS. The researchers said the exploit takes advantage of a weakness in how Apple devices render images on the display.</p>
<p>Citizen Lab now says that the same ForcedEntry exploit works on all Apple devices running, until today, the latest software.</p>
<p>Citizen Lab said it reported its findings to Apple on September 7. Apple pushed out the updates for the vulnerability, known officially as <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201222">CVE-2021-30860</a>. Citizen Lab said it attributes the ForcedEntry exploit to NSO Group with high confidence, citing evidence it has seen that it has not previously published.</p>
<p>John Scott-Railton, a researcher at Citizen Lab, told TechCrunch that messaging apps, like iMessage, are increasingly a target of nation states hacking operations and this latest find underlines the challenges in securing them.</p>
<p>When reached, Apple declined to comment. NSO Group declined to answer our specific questions.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NO6ayjQwng"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/toolkit-nso-pegasus-iphone-android/">This tool tells you if NSO&#8217;s Pegasus spyware targeted your phone</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;This tool tells you if NSO&#8217;s Pegasus spyware targeted your phone&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/toolkit-nso-pegasus-iphone-android/embed/#?secret=NO6ayjQwng" data-secret="NO6ayjQwng" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/apple-zero-day-nso-pegasus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201737</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Instagram is building a &#8216;Favorites&#8217; feature so you don&#8217;t miss important posts</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/instagram-is-building-a-favorites-feature-so-you-dont-miss-important-posts/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/instagram-is-building-a-favorites-feature-so-you-dont-miss-important-posts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 19:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[like button]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news feed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201703</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Instagram confirmed it&#8217;s developing a new feature called &#8220;Favorites,&#8221; which would allow users to select certain accounts whose posts they would like to see higher in their feed. A similar feature already exists on Facebook where it gives users a bit more control over the News Feed algorithm. On Facebook, users can select up to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Instagram confirmed it&#8217;s developing a new feature called &#8220;Favorites,&#8221; which would allow users to select certain accounts whose posts they would like to see higher in their feed. A similar feature already exists on Facebook where it gives users a bit more control over the News Feed algorithm. <a href="https://www.facebook.com/help/1634545223376778">On Facebook</a>, users can select up to 30 friends or Facebook Pages whose posts get shown higher in the News Feed. It&#8217;s unclear what limit an Instagram Favorites feature would have, however.</p>
<p>The Instagram Favorites feature was recently spotted in development by reverse engineer <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/">Alessandro Paluzzi</a>, who found a new pushpin icon for Favorites in the Instagram Settings menu, and other details about how the feature may work.</p>
<p>According to screenshots Paluzzi <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1435919581277609989">posted</a> on Twitter, users will be able to search across the Instagram accounts they are currently following to create a list of Favorites. This list can be edited at any time, and Instagram notes that users would not be notified when they&#8217;re added to someone&#8217;s Favorites.</p>
<p>This is a similar level of privacy as offered by Instagram&#8217;s several-years-old &#8220;Close Friends&#8221; feature, which instead focuses on allowing users to create a separate list of followers so they can share their more private and personal Instagram Stories with a select group of their own choosing.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Instagram?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Instagram</a> is working on &quot;Favorites&quot; <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f440.png" alt="👀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2139.png" alt="ℹ" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Posts from your favorites are shown higher in feed. <a href="https://t.co/NfBd8v4IHR">pic.twitter.com/NfBd8v4IHR</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Alessandro Paluzzi (@alex193a) <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1435919581277609989?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2021</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Paluzzi tells us he was able to add contacts to the Favorites list, but didn&#8217;t yet notice any changes to the Instagram feed after doing so. That implies the feature is still being built and a launch is not imminent.</p>
<p>&#8220;This feature is an internal prototype that’s still in development, and not testing externally,&#8221; an Instagram spokesperson told TechCrunch. They declined to share any other specifics about the feature.</p>
<p>A Favorites feature could play into Instagram&#8217;s larger plans to better establish itself as a home for creator content. In other leaks, Paluzzi had also found the company was building out &#8220;Fan Subscriptions,&#8221; which would allow users to pay for elevated access to creator content &#8212; like exclusive live videos or Stories, for example. Paid subscribers may also be given a special badge that would highlight their name when they commented, DM&#8217;ed or viewed the creator&#8217;s Stories.</p>
<p>Given that users who were paying for content would not want to miss a moment, it would make sense to give them tools to designate those creators as &#8220;Favorites&#8221; whose posts were also more highly ranked in their Feed.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Let&#39;s see another step of the Creators&#39; onboarding screen of the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Instagram?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Instagram</a>&#39;s Fan Subscriptions feature <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f440.png" alt="👀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/eBxIp6BtXw">pic.twitter.com/eBxIp6BtXw</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Alessandro Paluzzi (@alex193a) <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1437372672791531528?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 13, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>A Favorites feature could also be useful to those who had taken a break from Instagram and would rather see the important photos and videos they missed from favorite accounts upon their return, rather than just the most recent or interesting updates from across all of the accounts they follow.</p>
<p>And while not likely the main goal, the new feature could help to address users&#8217; complaints about the algorithmic feed in general.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ru1ft3h7uo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/15/understanding-instagrams-founding-story-and-more-from-sxsw/">Understanding Instagram&#8217;s founding story and more from SXSW</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Understanding Instagram&#8217;s founding story and more from SXSW&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/15/understanding-instagrams-founding-story-and-more-from-sxsw/embed/#?secret=ru1ft3h7uo" data-secret="ru1ft3h7uo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Today, there are still a number of people who want to be able to see Instagram posts in chronological order, preferring to not have posts re-ordered by an algorithm they can&#8217;t control. Favorites wouldn&#8217;t give in to this demand (though Instagram has <a href="https://thenextweb.com/news/instagram-is-testing-a-way-to-display-posts-in-chronological-order">tested</a> a chronological feed in the past). But it would at least give users the ability to ensure they weren&#8217;t missing the posts from those whose updates they wanted to see the most.</p>
<p>Though Instagram did say it&#8217;s working on the development of Favorites, it doesn&#8217;t necessarily mean such a feature will launch to the public. Companies of Instagram&#8217;s size often prototype new ideas, but only some of those tests make it to a general release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/instagram-is-building-a-favorites-feature-so-you-dont-miss-important-posts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201703</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ford hires new chief digital information officer as it seeks to expand into software and services</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/ford-hires-new-chief-digital-information-officer-as-it-seeks-to-expand-into-software-and-services/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/ford-hires-new-chief-digital-information-officer-as-it-seeks-to-expand-into-software-and-services/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 18:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford Motor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201686</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ford Motor has hired Mike Amend as its chief digital and information officer as the automaker seeks to expand into software, subscriptions and in-vehicle connectivity. Amend, who was president of Lowe’s Online for three years, will focus on Ford’s “use of data, software and technology” — all areas central to Ford’s new Ford+ strategy, the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Ford Motor has hired Mike Amend as its chief digital and information officer as the automaker seeks to expand into software, subscriptions and in-vehicle connectivity. Amend, who was president of Lowe’s Online for three years, will focus on Ford’s “use of data, software and technology” — all areas central to Ford’s new Ford+ strategy, the OEM said.</p>
<p>The hire is just the latest sign that Ford is serious about beefing up its digital offerings for customers, as the company seeks to pivot toward high-tech segments. The company calls this plan “Ford+,” which it unveiled earlier this year. Central to this plan is electric vehicles, which Ford wants to comprise around half of its global sales by 2030, as well as expanding into new sources of revenue via subscriptions and digital services.</p>
<p>To that end, Amend will oversee a number of teams, including Ford’s technology and software platform function and its global data insight and analytics section.</p>
<p>Amend isn’t Ford’s only recent hire of note. The automaker also recently poached Doug Field — the tech executive who was leading Apple’s special projects team, and who also led the development of the Model 3 at Tesla — as chief advanced technology and embedded systems officer. The two will work closely, along with chief of product Hau Thai-Tang, Ford said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yf2tdk3x5e"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/ford-hires-apple-executive-who-led-its-secret-car-project/">Ford hires Apple executive who led its secret car project</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ford hires Apple executive who led its secret car project&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/ford-hires-apple-executive-who-led-its-secret-car-project/embed/#?secret=yf2tdk3x5e" data-secret="yf2tdk3x5e" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Amend’s career includes growing the online businesses of major retailers, including Lowe’s, The Home Depot and JCPenney. Ford’s interim chief information officer, Sakis Kitsopanidis, will continue to serve as director of integrated enterprise resource planning.</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/ford-hires-new-chief-digital-information-officer-as-it-seeks-to-expand-into-software-and-services/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201686</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 keys to pricing early-stage SaaS products</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/3-keys-to-pricing-early-stage-saas-products/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/3-keys-to-pricing-early-stage-saas-products/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 18:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The pricing journey is long and, despite what some founders might think, jumping headfirst into customer acquisition isn’t the first stop. Step one is making sure you have a fully fledged product.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Yousuf Khan</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/yakhan">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/yousufakhan">Yousuf Khan</a> is a partner at <a href="https://ridge.vc/">Ridge Ventures</a>. Prior to joining Ridge, he was the first CIO of Automation Anywhere, CIO and vice president of Customer Success at cloud-based AI platform Moveworks, as well as CIO of Pure Storage, Qualys and Hult International Business School. 	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/21/develop-a-buyers-guide-to-educate-your-startups-sales-team-and-customers/">Develop a buyer’s guide to educate your startup&#8217;s sales team and customers</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/customer-advisory-boards-are-a-gold-mine-for-startup-brand-champions/">Customer advisory boards are a gold mine for startup brand champions</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">I’ve met hundreds of founders over the years, and most, particularly early-stage founders, share one common go-to-market gripe: Pricing.</p>
<p>For enterprise software, traditional pricing methods like per-seat models are often easier to figure out for products that are hyperspecific, especially those used by people in essentially the same way, such as Zoom or Slack. However, it&#8217;s a different ballgame for startups that offer services or products that are more complex.</p>
<p>Most startups struggle with a per-seat model because their products, unlike Zoom and Slack, are used in a litany of ways. Salesforce, for example, employs regular seat licenses and admin licenses — customers can opt for lower pricing for solutions that have low-usage parts — while other products are priced based on negotiation as part of annual renewals.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			You may have a strong champion in a CIO you’re selling to or a very friendly person handling procurement, but it won’t matter if the pricing can’t be easily explained and understood. Complicated or unclear pricing adds more friction.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Early pricing discussions should center around the buyer’s perspective and the value the product creates for them. It&#8217;s important for founders to think about the output and the outcome, and a number they can reasonably defend to customers moving forward. Of course, self-evaluation is hard, especially when you’re asking someone else to pay you for something you’ve created.</p>
<p>This process will take time, so here are three tips to smoothen the ride.</p>
<h2>Pricing is a journey</h2>
<p>Pricing is not a fixed exercise. The enterprise software business involves a lot of intangible aspects, and a software product’s perceived value, quality, and user experience can be highly variable.</p>
<p>The pricing journey is long and, despite what some founders might think, jumping headfirst into customer acquisition isn’t the first stop. Instead, step one is making sure you have a fully fledged product.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re a late-seed or Series A company, you’re focused on landing those first 10-20 customers and racking up some wins to showcase in your investor and board deck. But when you grow your organization to the point where the CEO isn’t the only person selling, you’ll want to have your go-to-market position figured out.</p>
<p>Many startups fall into the trap of thinking: &#8220;We need to figure out what pricing looks like, so let&#8217;s ask 50 hypothetical customers how much they would pay for a solution like ours.&#8221; I don&#8217;t agree with this approach, because the product hasn&#8217;t been finalized yet. You haven&#8217;t figured out product-market fit or product messaging and you want to spend a lot of time and energy on pricing? Sure, revenue is important, but you should focus on finding the path to accruing revenue versus finding a strict pricing model.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/3-keys-to-pricing-early-stage-saas-products/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201429</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Join Team TechCrunch at these speed networking sessions at Disrupt</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/join-team-techcrunch-for-a-series-of-speed-networking-meet-greets-the-day-before-tc-disrupt-2021-begins/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/join-team-techcrunch-for-a-series-of-speed-networking-meet-greets-the-day-before-tc-disrupt-2021-begins/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 17:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2198670</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Grab a red Sharpie, circle September 20 on your calendar (ooh, how old-school) and get ready to jumpstart your TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 networking experience. Sure, Disrupt’s “official” run is September 21-23, but why wait to meet other movers and shakers in your specific tech category? We’re hosting a series of speed networking sessions to get [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Grab a red Sharpie, circle September 20 on your calendar (ooh, how old-school) and get ready to jumpstart your <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> networking experience. Sure, Disrupt’s “official” run is September 21-23, but why wait to meet other movers and shakers in your specific tech category?</p>
<p>We’re hosting a series of speed networking sessions to get your Disrupt kicked off on Monday, September 20. These events will take place in CrunchMatch, our AI-powered platform that helps you find and connect with attendees on your must-meet list.</p>
<p><strong>Pro Tip 1:</strong> If you purchased a pass, you received an email with instructions on how to access CrunchMatch. Yeah, you did.</p>
<p><strong>Pro Tip 2:</strong> You still have time to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/tickets/">buy your Disrupt 2021 pass</a> for less than $100. Look through <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/#0affacde-e0ed-4a3c-abc4-988cb1c0eb3e">the Disrupt agenda</a> and see all the programming, events and opportunity waiting for you.</p>
<p>We love free swag, and we’re pretty sure you do, too. So, we’ll randomly select<strong> one participant from each networking session to receive a TC swag bag</strong>. W00t!</p>
<p>Here are the meet and greets happening at Disrupt &#8212; choose your category and kickstart your connections.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Peer-to-Peer: Investors</strong> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Connect with your community of startup investors to share connections, insights and expertise.</span></li>
<li><strong>Peer-to-Peer: Early-Stage Founders</strong> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Meet the founders also launching at Disrupt to share insights and grow your support network.</span></li>
<li><strong>The Full Stack:</strong> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Meet the data analysts, engineers, hackers, data scientists and software developers that power your tech.</span></li>
<li><strong>BIPOC &amp; Women of Disrupt</strong> <strong>(and their allies): <span style="font-weight: 400;">We invite all women and BIPOC (and all allies) attending Disrupt to join us for this roundup to inspire one another and grow your network.</span></strong></li>
<li><strong>B2B 2 Connect: <span style="font-weight: 400;">Are you working on products that make it easier for businesses to thrive? Meet and share ideas and others with the SaaS and Enterprise community.</span></strong></li>
<li><strong>DNA/Tech: <span style="font-weight: 400;">Meet the scientists who are using technology and engineering to produce advancements in health and biology. </span></strong></li>
<li><strong>Planet/Impact: </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">Passionate about making an impact on our planet? Join this networking session focused on sustainability, green tech and clean tech projects.   </span></li>
<li><strong>Money Matters:</strong> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Network with the power brokers changing the face of financial services, banking and crypto.</span></li>
<li><strong>Autonobot: <span style="font-weight: 400;">Discover the builders automating our lives with robotics and hardware alongside the scientists creating the artificial intelligence that powers it all.</span></strong></li>
<li><strong>The Station: <span style="font-weight: 400;">Share insights with people pushing the boundaries of mobility including drone technology, autonomous vehicles and transportation.</span></strong></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> takes place on September 21-23, and these meet-and-greet sessions can help you hit the networking ground running. Make the most out of your TC Disrupt experience!</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at Disrupt 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			width="99%"
			height="1300"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/join-team-techcrunch-for-a-series-of-speed-networking-meet-greets-the-day-before-tc-disrupt-2021-begins/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2198670</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Colossal sold investors on a quest to resurrect a woolly mammoth</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/how-colossal-sold-investors-on-a-quest-to-resurrect-a-woolly-mammoth/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/how-colossal-sold-investors-on-a-quest-to-resurrect-a-woolly-mammoth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Betuel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 17:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colossal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRISPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gene editing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mammoth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are a growing number of companies interested in CRISPR&#8217;s potential to upend medicine. It’s probably safe to say there’s only one company interested in using the gene-editing system to create a living, breathing woolly mammoth. Or, at least, something pretty close to it.  That’s the primary mission of a new company called Colossal. Co-founded [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are a growing number of companies interested in CRISPR&#8217;s potential to upend medicine. It’s probably safe to say there’s only one company interested in using the gene-editing system to create a living, breathing woolly mammoth. Or, at least, something pretty close to it. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That’s the primary mission of a new company called Colossal. Co-founded by maverick geneticist </span><a href="https://wyss.harvard.edu/team/core-faculty/george-church/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">George Church</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and entrepreneur Ben Lamm, the former CEO of Hypergiant, the company aims to bring one of those creatures back to life using CRISPR to edit the genomes of existing Asian elephants. In that sense the creature would be very similar to a woolly mammoth, but would be more like an elephant-mammoth hybrid. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s a project that Church’s lab has been invested in for years. But now, Church and Lamm have managed to sell investors on the idea that bringing back a mammoth is more than a science-fiction project. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today Colossal announced its launch and a $15 million seed round led by </span><a href="https://www.forbes.com/profile/thomas-tull/?sh=69eeff657645"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thomas Tull</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, former CEO of Legendary Entertainment (the company responsible for the likes of Dune, Jurassic World and The Dark Knight). The round includes investments from Breyer Capital, Draper Associates, Animal Capital, At One Ventures, Jazz Ventures, Jeff Wilke, Bold Capital, Global Space Ventures, Climate Capital, Winklevoss Capital, Liquid2 Ventures, Capital Factory, Tony Robbins and First Light Capital.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;These two are a powerhouse team who have the ability to completely shift our understanding of modern genetics while developing innovative technologies that not only help bring back lost species, but advance the entire industry,” Robbins tells TechCrunch. “I am proud to be an investor in their journey.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lamm comes to Colossal as the founder of Hypergiant, a Texas-based AI company. He has also built and sold three other companies:</span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/06/07/conversable-chatbot-will-offer-allergy-info-along-with-a-side-of-wingstop-wings/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Conversable</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (acquired by LivePerson), </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/07/22/chaotic-moon-sells-to-accenture/?_ga=2.258284355.817522353.1631490695-1476558031.1622655185"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chaotic Moon Studios</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (acquired by Accenture) and Team Chaos (acquired by Zynga). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And big, provocative, projects are part of what Church is already famous for. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Church created the first direct genomic sequencing method in the 1980s, and went on to help initiate the Human genome project. Now, he leads synthetic biological efforts at the Wyss Institute, where he </span><a href="https://wyss.harvard.edu/team/core-faculty/george-church/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">has focused</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on synthesizing entire genes and genomes. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> While CRISPR gene editing has only just entered human trials, and typically aims to edit a single disease-causing gene, Church’s projects often think far bigger &#8212; often along the lines of speeding along evolution. In 2015, Church and colleagues edited </span><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nature.2015.18525"><span style="font-weight: 400;">62 genes in pig embryos</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (a record at the time) in an effort to create organs for human transplants. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company spun out of that endeavor, eGenesis, is behind on Church’s initial timeline (he predicted pig organs would be viable transplants by 2019), but the company is performing </span><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2019/06/12/239014/crispr-pig-organs-are-being-implanted-in-monkeys-to-see-if-theyre-safe-for-humans/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">preclinical experiments</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on monkeys.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Resurrecting a woolly mammoth has long been in Church’s crosshairs. </span><a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2121503-can-we-grow-woolly-mammoths-in-the-lab-george-church-hopes-so/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2017</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, his lab at Harvard University reported that they had managed to add 45 genes to the genome of an Asian elephant in an attempt to recreate the mammoth. Through a sponsored research agreement, this company will fully support the mammoth work at Church’s lab.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company’s pitch for bringing back the Mammoth, per the press release, is to combat the effects of climate change through ecosystem restoration. Lamm expands on that point: </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our goal is not to just bring back the Mammoth, that’s a feat in itself,” he says. &#8220;It’s for the successful re-wilding of mammoths. If you take that toolkit, you have all the tools are your disposal to prevent extinction or to bring back critically endangered species.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">About 1 million plant and animal species are </span><a href="https://www.un.org/sustainabledevelopment/biodiversity/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">threatened with extinction</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Colossal’s mammoth project, should it succeed, would suggest they have developed the capacity to both repopulate recently dead creatures, and even perform what Lamm calls &#8220;genetic rescue&#8221; to stop them from disappearing in the first place. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Genetic rescue is the process of increasing genetic diversity in an endangered population &#8212; this could be achieved through gene-editing, or in some cases, cloning new individuals to create a wider gene pool (provided the clone and the existing animals have different enough genes). There is already some evidence that this is possible. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In February 2021, a black-footed ferret named </span><a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/elizabeth-ann-first-cloned-black-footed-ferret-180977065/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Elizabeth Ann</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> became the first cloned endangered species native to North America. She was cloned from the DNA housed in frozen tissue samples collected in 1988. </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2201592" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2201592" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2201592" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="640" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg 3300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg?resize=768,480 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg?resize=680,425 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg?resize=1536,960 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg?resize=2048,1280 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2201592" class="wp-caption-text">Mammoth in the middle of mountains. This is a 3D render illustration. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Orla / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bringing back extinct species might help combat a consequence of climate change, but it doesn’t solve the root problem. As long as the human-based drivers of climate change remain in-tact, there’s not much hope for a newly reborn creature that was killed by climate change the first time; in fact, fluctuating climates were </span><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-021-21201-8"><span style="font-weight: 400;">one reason megafauna </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">died off in the first place.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And, there could be serious </span><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S1617138120300844?via%3Dihub"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ecosystem ramifications</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from re-wilding long-dead species, like spreading novel disease, displacing existing species and altering the actual landscape (elephants are ecosystem engineers, after all). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If tackling biodiversity is part of Colossal’s core pitch, why go directly for the mammoth when there are species that might be saved right now? Lamm notes that the company may also try to edit the genomes of Asian elephants to make them more resilient; however, the mammoth project remains the company&#8217;s “north star.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The argument, from Lamm’s perspective, is that the mammoth project is a moonshot. Even if the company shoots for the moon and lands among the stars, they will have to develop proprietary technology for de-extinction that might then be licensed or sold to potential buyers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It’s very similar to the Apollo program &#8212; which was a literal moonshot. A bunch of technologies were created along the way. Things like GPS, the fundamentals of the internet and semiconductors. All those were highly monetizable,” he says.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In short, the mammoth project is more like an incubator for developing a host of intellectual property. That might include projects like artificial wombs or other applications of CRISPR, Lamm notes. These products will still face massive scientific hurdles &#8212; existing artificial womb projects </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">aren’t even near entering human trials</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8212; but those hurdles might be slightly more achievable than living, breathing beings. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Not that Colossal doesn’t have plenty of interim plans while that research is being done. The company is also out to create an especially memorable brand along the way. Lamm says you could think of the brand as “Harvard meets MTV.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though there’s no company that Lamm says is a direct comparison to Colossal, he mentioned several large space brands and agencies, like Blue Origin, SpaceX and notably NASA in our conversation — “I think that NASA is the best brand the United States ever made,” he notes. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“If you look at SpaceX and Blue Origin and Virgin, my 91-year-old grandmother knew these guys went to space. ULA and other people have been launching rockets and putting satellites up there for decades &#8212; nobody cared. These companies did a great job of bringing the public in,” he says. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s all a bit reminiscent of Elon Musk’s plan for </span><a href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/full/10.1089/space.2017.29009.emu"><span style="font-weight: 400;">sending humans to Mars</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, although Starship (the vehicle that’s supposed to get us there) hasn’t moved beyond </span><a href="https://www.space.com/spacex-starship-orbital-test-flight-readiness-musk"><span style="font-weight: 400;">prototype test</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> flights. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The big ideas, says Lamm, draw in the public. The intellectual property developed along the way can pacify investors in the meantime. The perspective is inescapably sci-fi, but perhaps it’s supposed to be that way. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And that’s not to say that the company isn’t absolutely dead-set on bringing a mammoth to life. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">This capital, says Lamm, should be sufficient to help develop a viable mammoth embryo. They’re aiming to have the first set of calves born in the next four to six years. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/how-colossal-sold-investors-on-a-quest-to-resurrect-a-woolly-mammoth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201508</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GM invests in radar software startup Oculii as demand for automated driving features rise</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/gm-invests-in-radar-software-startup-oculii-as-demand-for-automated-driving-features-rise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/gm-invests-in-radar-software-startup-oculii-as-demand-for-automated-driving-features-rise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 16:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lidar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oculii]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving cars]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201532</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oculii, a software startup that aims to improve the spatial resolution of radar sensors by up to 100-fold, has scored a new investment from General Motors. The new funding, which the two companies say is in the millions, comes just months after Oculii closed a $55 million Series B. Oculii and GM have already been [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Oculii, a software startup that aims to improve the spatial resolution of radar sensors by up to 100-fold, has scored a new investment from General Motors. The new funding, which the two companies say is in the millions, comes just months after Oculii closed a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/oculii-looks-to-supercharge-radar-for-autonomy-with-55m-round-b/">$55 million Series B</a>.</p>
<p>Oculii and GM have already been working together “for some time now,” CEO Steven Hong told TechCrunch in a recent interview. While he declined to specify exactly how GM plans to use Oculii’s software, it could be used to bolster the capabilities of the automaker&#8217;s hands-free advanced driver assistance system known as Super Cruise. Hong added that the company is also working with a few other OEMs, including one on the cap table.</p>
<p>“When a company like GM says, this is great technology and this is something that we potentially want to use down the line, it makes the entire supply chain take notice and effectively work more closely with you to adopt the solution, the technology, into what they&#8217;re selling to the OEMs,” he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uUdU5Dx5KK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/oculii-looks-to-supercharge-radar-for-autonomy-with-55m-round-b/">Oculii looks to supercharge radar for autonomy with $55M round B</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Oculii looks to supercharge radar for autonomy with $55M round B&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/oculii-looks-to-supercharge-radar-for-autonomy-with-55m-round-b/embed/#?secret=uUdU5Dx5KK" data-secret="uUdU5Dx5KK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The startup has no intention of building hardware for its auto clients (though it does work with robotics companies for whom the company does manufacture sensors, a company spokesperson said). Instead, Oculii wants to license software to radar companies. The startup claims it can take low-cost, commercially available radar sensors &#8212; sensors that weren’t designed for autonomous driving, but rather for limited scenarios like emergency breaking or parking assist &#8212; and use its AI software to enable more autonomous maneuvering, Hong said.</p>
<p>“We really believe that the way to deliver something that&#8217;s scalable is through software, because software fundamentally improves with data,” he said. “Software fundamentally improves with better hardware in each generation that&#8217;s released. Software fundamentally over time gets cheaper and cheaper and cheaper, much faster than hardware, for example.”</p>
<p>The news is certainly bullish for radar, a sensor that is generally used for assistive capabilities because of its imaging limitations. But if Oculii can actually improve the performance of radar, which tend to be much cheaper than lidar, it could mean massive cost savings for automakers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Tesla, the largest electric vehicle maker by sales volume in the world, recently nixed radar sensors from its advanced driver assistance system, in favor of a “pure vision” approach that uses cameras and a supercomputer-powered neural network. Hong said that the radar Tesla eliminated was very low resolution, and “wasn&#8217;t really adding anything to their existing pipeline.”</p>
<p>But he doesn’t think the company would always necessarily count out radar, should the technology improve. “Fundamentally, each of these sensors improves [the] safety case and gets you closer and closer to 99.99999% reliability. At the end of the day, that&#8217;s the most important thing, is getting as many nines of reliability as you can.”</p>
<p><em>The story was updated to include clarification on the company&#8217;s hardware manufacturing. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/gm-invests-in-radar-software-startup-oculii-as-demand-for-automated-driving-features-rise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201532</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The past, present and future of IoT in physical security</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/the-past-present-and-future-of-iot-in-physical-security/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/the-past-present-and-future-of-iot-in-physical-security/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 16:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facial recognition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet protocol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IP Camera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physical security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surveillance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2200058</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It is impossible to compare where the IP camera industry stands today to where it stood 25 years ago without being impressed.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Martin Gren</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/martingren">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Co-founder of Axis Communications, Martin Gren is an entrepreneur and inventor of the first network camera.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">When Axis Communications released the first internet protocol (IP) camera after the 1996 Olympic games in Atlanta, there was some initial confusion. Connected cameras weren’t something the market had been clamoring for, and many experts questioned whether they were even necessary.</p>
<p>Today, of course, traditional analog cameras have been almost completely phased out as organizations have recognized the tremendous advantage that IoT devices can offer, but that technology felt like a tremendous risk during those early days.</p>
<p>To say that things have changed since then would be a dramatic understatement. The growth of the Internet of Things (IoT) represents one of the ways physical security has evolved. Connected devices have become the norm, opening up exciting new possibilities that go far beyond recorded video. Further developments, such as the improvement and widespread acceptance of the IP camera, have helped power additional breakthroughs including improved analytics, increased processing power, and the growth of open-architecture technology. On the 25th anniversary of the initial launch of the IP camera, it is worth reflecting on how far the industry has come — and where it is likely to go from here.</p>
<h2>Tech improvements herald the rise of IP cameras</h2>
<p>Comparing today’s IP cameras to those available in 1996 is almost laughable. While they were certainly groundbreaking at the time, those early cameras could record just one frame every 17 seconds — quite a change from what cameras can do today.</p>
<p>But despite this drawback, those on the cutting edge of physical security understood what a monumental breakthrough the IP camera could represent. After all, creating a network of cameras would enable more effective remote monitoring, which — if the technology could scale — would enable them to deploy much larger systems, tying together disparate groups of cameras. Early applications might include watching oil fields, airport landing strips or remote cell phone towers. Better still, the technology had the potential to usher in an entirely new world of analytics capabilities.</p>
<p>Of course, better chipsets were needed to make that endless potential a reality. Groundbreaking or not, the limited frame rate of the early cameras was never going to be effective enough to drive widespread adoption of traditional surveillance applications. Solving this problem required a significant investment of resources, but before long these improved chipsets brought IP cameras from one frame every 17 seconds to 30 frames per second. Poor frame rate could no longer be listed as a justification for shunning IP cameras in favor of their analog cousins, and developers could begin to explore the devices’ analytics potential.</p>
<p>Perhaps the most important technological leap was the introduction of embedded Linux, which made IP cameras more practical from a developer point of view. During the 1990s, most devices used proprietary operating systems, which made them difficult to develop for.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Even within the companies themselves, proprietary systems meant that developers had to be trained on a specific technology, costing companies both time and money. There were a few attempts at standardization within the industry, such as the Wind River operating system, but these ultimately failed. They were too small, with limited resources behind them — and besides, a better solution already existed: Linux.</p>
<p>Linux offered a wide range of benefits, not the least of which was the ability to collaborate with other developers in the open source community. This was a road that ran two ways. Because most IP cameras lacked the hard disk necessary to run Linux, hardware known as JFFS was developed that would allow a device to use a Flash memory chip as a hard disk. That technology was contributed to the open source community, and while it is currently on its third iteration, it remains in widespread use today.</p>
<p>Compression technology represented a similar challenge, with the more prominent data compression models in the late ’90s and early 2000s poorly suited for video. At the time, video storage involved individual frames being stored one-by-one — a data storage nightmare. Fortunately, the H.264 compression format, which was designed with video in mind, became much more commonplace in 2009.</p>
<p>By the end of that year, more than 90% of IP cameras and most video management systems used the H.264 compression format. It is important to note that improvements in compression capabilities have also enabled manufacturers to improve their video resolution as well. Before the new compression format, video resolution had not changed since the ’60s with NTSC/PAL. Today, most cameras are capable of recording in high definition (HD).</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>1996</strong>: First IP camera is released.<br />
<strong>2001</strong>: Edge-based analytics with video motion detection arrive.<br />
<strong>2006</strong>: First downloadable, edge-based analytics become available.<br />
<strong>2009</strong>: Full HD becomes the standard video resolution; H.264 compression goes mainstream.<br />
<strong>2015</strong>: Smart compression revolutionizes video storage.</p></blockquote>
<h2>The growth of analytics</h2>
<p>Analytics is not exactly a “new” technology — customers requested various analytics capabilities even in the early days of the IP camera — but it is one that has seen dramatic improvement. Although it might seem quaint by today’s high standards, video motion detection was one of the earliest analytics loaded onto IP cameras.</p>
<p>Customers needed a way to detect movement within certain parameters to avoid having a tree swaying in the wind, or a squirrel running by, trigger a false alarm. Further refinement of this type of detection and recognition technology has helped automate many aspects of physical security, triggering alerts when potentially suspicious activity is detected and ensuring that it is brought to human attention. By taking human fallibility out of the equation, analytics has turned video surveillance from a reactive tool to a proactive one.</p>
<p>Reliable motion detection remains one of the most widely used analytics, and while false alarms can never be entirely eliminated, modern improvements have made it a reliable way to detect potential intruders. Object detection is also growing in popularity and is increasingly capable of classifying cars, people, animals and other objects.</p>
<p>License plate recognition is popular in many countries (though less so in the United States), not just for identifying vehicles involved in criminal activity, but for uses as simple as parking recognition. Details like car model, shirt color or license plate number are easy for the human eye to miss or fail to notice — but thanks to modern analytics, that data is cataloged and stored for easy reference. The advent of technology like deep learning, which features better pattern recognition and object classification through improved labeling and categorization, will drive further advancements in this area of analytics.</p>
<p>The rise of analytics also helps highlight why the security industry has embraced open-architecture technology. Simply put, it is impossible for a single manufacturer to keep up with every application that its customers might need. By using open-architecture technology, they can empower those customers to seek out the solutions that are right for them, without the need to specifically tailor the device for certain use cases. Hospitals might look to add audio analytics to detect signs of patient distress; retail stores might focus on people counting or theft detection; law enforcement might focus on gunshot detection — with all of these applications housed within the same device model.</p>
<p>It is also important to note that the COVID-19 pandemic drove interesting new uses for both physical security devices and analytics — though some applications, such as using thermal cameras for fever measurement, proved difficult to implement with a high degree of accuracy. Within the healthcare industry, camera usage increased significantly — something that is unlikely to change. Hospitals have seen the benefit of cameras within patient rooms, with video and intercom technology enabling healthcare professionals to monitor and communicate with patients while maintaining a secure environment.</p>
<p>Even simple analytics like cross-line detection can generate an alert if a patient who is a fall risk attempts to leave a designated area, potentially reducing accidents and overall liability. The fact that analytics like this bear only a passing mention today highlights how far physical security has come since the early days of the IP camera.</p>
<h2>Looking to the future of security</h2>
<p>That said, an examination of today’s trends can provide a glimpse into what the future might hold for the security industry. For instance, video resolution will certainly continue to improve.</p>
<p>Ten years ago, the standard resolution for video surveillance was 720p (1 megapixel), and 10 years before that it was the analog NTSC/PAL resolution of 572&#215;488, or 0.3 megapixels. Today, the standard resolution is 1080p (2 megapixels), and a healthy application of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moore%27s_law">Moore’s law</a> indicates that 10 years from now it will be 4K (8 megapixels).</p>
<p>As ever, the amount of storage that higher-resolution video generates is the limiting factor, and the development of smart storage technologies such as Zipstream has helped tremendously in recent years. We will likely see further improvements in smart storage and video compression that will help make higher-resolution video possible.</p>
<p>Cybersecurity will also be a growing concern for both manufacturers and end users.</p>
<p>Recently, one of Sweden’s largest retailers was <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-57707530">shut down for a week</a> because of a hack, and others will meet the same fate if they continue to use poorly secured devices. Any piece of software can contain a bug, but only developers and manufacturers committed to identifying and fixing these potential vulnerabilities can be considered reliable partners. Governments across the globe will likely pass new regulations mandating cybersecurity improvements, with California’s <a href="https://www.natlawreview.com/article/iot-manufacturers-what-you-need-to-know-about-california-s-iot-law">recent IoT protection law</a> serving as an early indicator of what the industry can expect.</p>
<p>Finally, ethical behavior will continue to become more important. A growing number of companies have begun foregrounding their ethics policies, issuing guidelines for how they expect technology like facial recognition to be used — not abused.</p>
<p>While new regulations are coming, it’s important to remember that regulation always lags behind, and companies that wish to have a positive reputation will need to adhere to their own ethical guidelines. More and more consumers now list ethical considerations among their major concerns—especially in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic—and today’s businesses will need to strongly consider how to broadcast and enforce responsible product use.</p>
<h2>Change is always around the corner</h2>
<p>Physical security has come a long way since the IP camera was introduced, but it is important to remember that these changes, while significant, took place over more than two decades. Changes take time — often more time than you might think. Still, it is impossible to compare where the industry stands today to where it stood 25 years ago without being impressed. The technology has evolved, end users’ needs have shifted, and even the major players in the industry have come and gone according to their ability to keep up with the times.</p>
<p>Change is inevitable, but careful observation of today’s trends and how they fit into today’s evolving security needs can help today’s developers and device manufacturers understand how to position themselves for the future. The pandemic highlighted the fact that today’s security devices can provide added value in ways that no one would have predicted just a few short years ago, further underscoring the importance of open communication, reliable customer support and ethical behavior.</p>
<p>As we move into the future, organizations that continue to prioritize these core values will be among the most successful.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/the-past-present-and-future-of-iot-in-physical-security/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2200058</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Epic Games appeals last week&#8217;s ruling in antitrust battle with Apple</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/epic-games-appeals-last-weeks-ruling-in-antitrust-battle-with-apple/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/epic-games-appeals-last-weeks-ruling-in-antitrust-battle-with-apple/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 16:14:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Epic Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iTunes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tim sweeney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201492</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fortnite maker Epic Games is appealing last week&#8217;s ruling in its court battle with Apple, where a federal judge said Apple would no longer be allowed to block developers from adding links to alternative payment mechanisms, but stopped short of dubbing Apple a monopolist. The latter would have allowed Epic Games to argue for alternative [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Fortnite maker Epic Games is appealing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/10/apple-prohibited-from-blocking-outside-payment-in-epic-ruling/">last week&#8217;s ruling in its court battle</a> with Apple, where a federal judge said Apple would no longer be allowed to block developers from adding links to alternative payment mechanisms, but stopped short of dubbing Apple a monopolist. The latter would have allowed Epic Games to argue for alternative means of serving its iOS user base, including perhaps, through third-party app stores or even sideloading capabilities built into Apple&#8217;s mobile operating system, similar to those on Google&#8217;s Android OS.</p>
<p>Apple immediately <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/10/apple-prohibited-from-blocking-outside-payment-in-epic-ruling/">declared</a> the court battle a victory, as the judge had agreed with its position that the company was &#8220;not in violation of antitrust law&#8221; and had also deemed Apple&#8217;s success in the app and gaming ecosystem as &#8220;not illegal.&#8221; Epic Games founder and CEO Tim Sweeney, meanwhile, said the ruling was not a win for either developers or consumers. On Twitter, he hinted that the company may appeal the decision <a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1436370884994928641">when he said</a>, &#8220;We will fight on.&#8221;</p>
<p>In a court filing published on Sunday (see below), Epic Games officially stated its attention to appeal U.S. District Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers&#8217; final judgment and &#8220;all orders leading to or producing that judgment.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pervoc5T8t"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/will-startup-valuations-change-given-rising-antitrust-concerns/">Will startup valuations change given rising antitrust concerns?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Will startup valuations change given rising antitrust concerns?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/will-startup-valuations-change-given-rising-antitrust-concerns/embed/#?secret=pervoc5T8t" data-secret="pervoc5T8t" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As part of the judge&#8217;s decision, Epic Games had been ordered to pay Apple the 30% of the $12 million it earned when it introduced its alternative payment system in Fortnite on iOS, which was then in breach of its legal contract with Apple.</p>
<p>The appellate court will revisit how Judge Gonzalez Rogers defined the market where Epic Games had argued Apple was acting as a monopolist. Contrary to both parties&#8217; wishes, Gonzalez Rogers defined it as the market for &#8220;digital mobile gaming transactions&#8221; specifically. Though an appeal may or may not see the court shifting its opinion in Epic Games&#8217; favor, a new ruling could potentially help to clarify the vague language used in the injunction to describe how Apple must now accommodate developers who want to point their customers to other payment mechanisms.</p>
<p>So far, the expectation floating around the developer community is that Apple will simply extend the &#8220;reader app&#8221; category exception to all non-reader apps (apps that provide access to purchased content). Apple recently settled <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/apple-announced-new-settlement-with-japan-allowing-developers-to-link-to-external-website/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">with a Japanese regulator</a> by agreeing to allow reader apps to point users to their own website where users could sign up and manage their accounts, which could include customers paying for subscriptions &#8212; like Netflix or Spotify subscriptions, for instance. Apple said this change would be global.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In briefings with reporters, Apple said the details of the injunction issued with the Epic Games ruling, however, would still need to be worked out. Given the recency of the decision, the company has not yet communicated with developers on how this change will impact them directly nor has it updated its App Store guidelines with new language.</p>
<p>Reached for comment, Epic Games said it does not have any further statements on its decision to appeal at this time.</p>
<p><iframe class="scribd_iframe_embed" src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/525024846/content?start_page=1&view_mode&access_key=key-49Sm8FVGJwM58jNKILQw"  data-auto-height="true" scrolling="no" id="scribd_525024846" width="100%" height="500" frameborder="0"></iframe>
		<div style="font-size:10px;text-align:center;width:100%"><a href="https://www.scribd.com/doc/525024846" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">View this document on Scribd</a></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/epic-games-appeals-last-weeks-ruling-in-antitrust-battle-with-apple/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201492</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BitSight raises $250M from Moody’s and acquires cyber risk startup VisibleRisk</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/bitsight-raises-250m-from-moodys-and-acquires-cyber-risk-startup-visiblerisk/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/bitsight-raises-250m-from-moodys-and-acquires-cyber-risk-startup-visiblerisk/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 16:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BitSight Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberattack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyberwarfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moody’s]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[risk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[risk analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[risk management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Team8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warburg pincus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201498</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BitSight, a startup that assesses the likelihood that an organization will be breached, has received a $250 million investment from credit rating giant Moody’s, and acquired Israeli cyber risk assessment startup VisibleRisk for an undisclosed sum. Boston-based BitSight says the investment from Moody’s, which has long warned that cyber risk can impact credit ratings, will [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">BitSight, a startup that assesses <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/28/bitsight-a-provider-of-security-ratings-raises-60m-at-a-valuation-of-around-600m/">the likelihood that an organization will be breached</a>, has received a $250 million investment from credit rating giant Moody’s, and acquired Israeli cyber risk assessment startup VisibleRisk for an undisclosed sum.</p>
<p>Boston-based BitSight says the investment from Moody’s, which has long warned that cyber risk can <a href="https://www.moodys.com/research/moodys-threat-of-cyber-risk-is-of-growing-importance-to--pr_339656">impact credit ratings</a>, will enable it to create a cybersecurity risk platform, while the credit ratings giant said it plans to make use of BitSight’s cyber risk data and research across its integrated risk assessment product offerings.</p>
<p>The investment values BitSight at $2.4 billion and makes Moody’s the largest shareholder in the company.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8CeIKGMUvy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/to-guard-against-data-loss-and-misuse-the-cybersecurity-conversation-must-evolve/">To guard against data loss and misuse, the cybersecurity conversation must evolve</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;To guard against data loss and misuse, the cybersecurity conversation must evolve&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/to-guard-against-data-loss-and-misuse-the-cybersecurity-conversation-must-evolve/embed/#?secret=8CeIKGMUvy" data-secret="8CeIKGMUvy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“Creating transparency and enabling trust is at the core of Moody’s mission,” Moody’s president and CEO Rob Fauber said in a statement. “BitSight is the leader in the cybersecurity ratings space, and together we will help market participants across disciplines better understand, measure, and manage their cyber risks and translate that to the risk of cyber loss.”</p>
<p>Meanwhile, BitSight&#8217;s purchase of VisibleRisk, a cyber risk ratings joint venture created by Moody’s and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/03/israels-team8-raises-104m-to-make-bigger-cybersecurity-bets/">Team8</a>, brings in-depth cyber risk assessment capabilities to BitSight&#8217;s platform, enabling the startup to better analyze and calculate an organization’s financial exposure to cyber risk. VisibleRisk, which has raised $25 million to date, says its so-called “cyber ratings” are based on cyber risk quantification, which allows companies to benchmark their cyber risk against those of their peers, and to better understand and manage the impact of cyber threats to their businesses.</p>
<p>Following the acquisition, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/bitsight">BitSight</a> will also create a risk solutions division focused on delivering a suite of critical solutions and analytics serving stakeholders, including chief risk officers, C-suite executives and boards of directors. This division will be led by VisibleRisk co-founder and CEO Derek Vadala, who previously headed up Moody&#8217;s cyber risk group.</p>
<p>Steve Harvey, president and CEO of BitSight, said the company&#8217;s partnership with Moody’s and its acquisition of VisibleRisk will expand its reach to &#8220;help customers manage cyber risk in an increasingly digital world.”</p>
<p>BitSight was founded in 2011 and has raised a total of $155 million in outside funding, most recently closing a $60 million Series D round led by Warburg Pincus. The startup has just shy of 500 employees and more than 2,300 global customers, including government agencies, insurers and asset managers.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WL4ZZRlzuX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/28/bitsight-a-provider-of-security-ratings-raises-60m-at-a-valuation-of-around-600m/">BitSight, a provider of security ratings, raises $60M at a valuation of around $600M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BitSight, a provider of security ratings, raises $60M at a valuation of around $600M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/28/bitsight-a-provider-of-security-ratings-raises-60m-at-a-valuation-of-around-600m/embed/#?secret=WL4ZZRlzuX" data-secret="WL4ZZRlzuX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/bitsight-raises-250m-from-moodys-and-acquires-cyber-risk-startup-visiblerisk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201498</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What to make of Freshworks&#8217; first IPO price range</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/what-to-make-of-freshworks-first-ipo-price-range/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/what-to-make-of-freshworks-first-ipo-price-range/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 15:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freshworks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renaissance capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It appears that Freshworks is pretty reasonably priced in its current range.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Two major private tech companies announced IPO price ranges this morning, with Toast targeting a market value of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/toast-looks-toward-18b-valuation-in-upcoming-ipo/">nearly $18 billion</a> at the top end of its range and Freshworks <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001544522/000162828021018417/freshworkss-1a1.htm">looking to price</a> its equity between $28 and $32 per share. TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/freshworks-aims-for-nearly-9-billion-valuation-in-us-ipo/">calculates</a> that the company would be worth around $8.9 billion at $32 per share, not employing a fully diluted share count.</p>
<p>Inclusive of shares represented by fully vested options and the like, Freshworks&#8217; valuation could reach $9.6 billion, <a href="https://www.renaissancecapital.com/IPO-Center/News/86012/Customer-support-software-company-Freshworks-sets-terms-for-$855-million-IP">Renaissance Capital reports</a>.</p>
<p>Unlike Toast, with a revenue mix including four distinct products, Freshworks is a more straightforward software company. That means we can do much more interesting work to understand its valuation. So, this morning, let&#8217;s unpack how Freshworks is considering valuing itself in its IPO at its present range, look at some market comps and come to a conclusion regarding whether we expect the unicorn to raise its valuation before it floats.</p>
<h2>Lies, damned lies and revenue multiples</h2>
<p>As a refresher, in the first half of 2021 (Q1 and Q2), Freshworks posted revenues of $168.9 million. That annualizes to $337.9 million, thanks to numerical rounding.</p>
<p>At a valuation of $9.6 billion &#8212; recall that simple IPO valuations for the company and lower share-price points from its IPO range generate <em>lower</em> valuations and therefore more <em>conservative</em> multiples than what we&#8217;ll be discussing here &#8212; Freshworks would be worth 28.4x its current revenue run rate, set during H1 2021.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/what-to-make-of-freshworks-first-ipo-price-range/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201454</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SpotOn raises $300M at a $3.15B valuation and acquires Appetize</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/spoton-raises-300m-at-a-3-15b-valuation-acquires-appetize/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/spoton-raises-300m-at-a-3-15b-valuation-acquires-appetize/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 15:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[appetize]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David George]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dragoneer investment group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DST Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Franklin Templeton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mubadala Investment Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payment processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[splunk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpotOn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201271</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last year at this time, SpotOn was on the brink of announcing a $60 million Series C funding round at a $625 million valuation. Fast-forward to almost exactly one year later and a lot has changed for the payments and software startup. Today, SpotOn said it has closed on $300 million in Series E financing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last year at this time, SpotOn was on the brink of announcing a $60 million Series C funding round at a $625 million valuation.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fast-forward to almost exactly one year later and a lot has changed for the payments and software startup.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, SpotOn said it has closed on $300 million in Series E financing that values the company at $3.15 billion &#8212; more than 5x of its valuation at the time of its Series C round, and significantly higher than its $1.875 billion valuation in May (yes, just three and a half months ago) when it </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/spoton-raises-125m-in-a16z-led-series-d-triples-valuation-to-1-75b/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">raised $125 million in a Series D funding event</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Andreessen Horowitz (a16z) led both the Series D and E rounds for the company, which says it has seen 100% growth year over year and a tripling in revenue over the past 18 months. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Existing investors DST Global, 01 Advisors, Dragoneer Investment Group, Franklin</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Templeton and Mubadala Investment Company too doubled down on their investments in SpotOn, joining new backers Wellington Management and Coatue</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Management. Advisors Douglas Merritt, CEO of Splunk, and Mike Scarpelli, CFO of Snowflake, also made individual</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">investments as angels. With the new capital, SpotOn has raised $628 million since its inception.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The latest investment is being used to finance the acquisition of another company in the space &#8212; Appetize, a digital and mobile commerce payments platform for enterprises such as sports and entertainment venues, theme parks and zoos. SpotOn is paying $415 million in cash and stock for the Los Angeles-based company.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PGP8FDOipg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/4-key-areas-saas-startups-must-address-to-scale-infrastructure-for-the-enterprise/">4 key areas SaaS startups must address to scale infrastructure for the enterprise</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;4 key areas SaaS startups must address to scale infrastructure for the enterprise&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/4-key-areas-saas-startups-must-address-to-scale-infrastructure-for-the-enterprise/embed/#?secret=PGP8FDOipg" data-secret="PGP8FDOipg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since its 2017 inception, SpotOn has been focused on providing software and payments technology to SMBs with an emphasis on restaurants and retail businesses. The acquisition of Appetize extends SpotOn’s reach to the enterprise space in a major way. Appetize will go to market as SpotOn and will work to grow its client base, which already includes an impressive list of companies and organizations, including Live Nation, LSU, Dodger Stadium and Urban Air. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In fact, Appetize currently covers </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">65% of all major league sports stadiums, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">specializing in contactless payments, mobile ordering and menu management. So for example, when you’re ordering food at a game or concert, Appetize’s technology makes it easier to pay in a variety of contactless ways through point of sale (POS) devices, self-service kiosks, handheld devices, online ordering, mobile web and API integrations.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2201274" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2201274" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2201274 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/SpotOn-Acquires-Appetize-Editorial-Only.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="511" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/SpotOn-Acquires-Appetize-Editorial-Only.jpg 3088w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/SpotOn-Acquires-Appetize-Editorial-Only.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/SpotOn-Acquires-Appetize-Editorial-Only.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/SpotOn-Acquires-Appetize-Editorial-Only.jpg?resize=768,577 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/SpotOn-Acquires-Appetize-Editorial-Only.jpg?resize=680,511 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/SpotOn-Acquires-Appetize-Editorial-Only.jpg?resize=1536,1154 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/SpotOn-Acquires-Appetize-Editorial-Only.jpg?resize=2048,1539 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/SpotOn-Acquires-Appetize-Editorial-Only.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2201274" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SpotOn</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SpotOn is taking on the likes of Square in the payments space. But the company says its offering extends beyond traditional payment processing and point-of-sale software. Its platform aims to give SMBs the ability to run their businesses “from building a brand to taking payments and everything in between.” SpotOn’s goal is to be a “one-stop shop” by incorporating tools that include things such as custom website development, scheduling software, marketing, appointment scheduling, review management, analytics and digital loyalty.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The combined company will have 1,600 employees &#8212; 1,300 from SpotOn and 300 from Appetize. SpotOn will now have over 500 employees on its product and technology team, according to co-founder and co-CEO Zach Hyman. It will also have clients in the tens of thousands, a number that SpotOn says is growing by “thousands more every month.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The acquisition is not the first for SpotOn, which also acquired </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">SeatNinja last year and Emagine in 2018.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But in Appetize it saw a company that was complementary both in its go-to-market and tech stacks, and a “natural fit.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;SMEs are going to benefit from the scalable tech that can grow with them, including things like kiosks and offline modes, and for the enterprise clients of Appetize, they&#8217;re going to be able to leverage products like sophisticated loyalty programs and extended marketing capabilities,” Hyman told TechCrunch. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SpotOn was not necessarily planning to raise another round so soon, Hyman added, but the opportunity came up to acquire Appetize.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We spent a lot of time together, and it was too compelling to pass up,” he told TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For its part, Appetize &#8212; which has raised over $77 million over its lifetime, according to </span><a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/appetize/company_financials"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Crunchbase</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8212; too saw the combination as a logical one.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It was important to us to retain a stake in the business. We were not looking to cash out,” said Appetize CEO </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Max Roper. “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are deeply invested in growing the business together. It&#8217;s a big win for our team and our clients over the long term. This is a rocketship that we are excited to be on.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No doubt that the COVID-19 pandemic only emphasized the need for more digital offerings from small businesses to enterprises alike.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There has been a high demand for our services and now as businesses are faced with a Covid resurgence, no one is closing down,” Hyman said. “So they see a responsibility to install the necessary technology to properly run their business.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rnsQThMOGo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/spoton-raises-125m-in-a16z-led-series-d-triples-valuation-to-1-75b/">SpotOn raises $125M in a16z-led Series D, triples valuation to $1.875B</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SpotOn raises $125M in a16z-led Series D, triples valuation to $1.875B&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/spoton-raises-125m-in-a16z-led-series-d-triples-valuation-to-1-75b/embed/#?secret=rnsQThMOGo" data-secret="rnsQThMOGo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the moves SpotOn has made, for example, is launching a vaccination alert system in its reservation management software platform to make it easier for consumers to confirm they are vaccinated for cities and states that have those requirements.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Clearly, a16z </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">General Partner David George too was bullish on the idea of a combined company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He told TechCrunch that the two companies fit together “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">extremely nicely.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It felt like a no-brainer for us to want to lead the round, and continue to support them,” George said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since first investing in SpotOn in May, the startup’s growth has “exceeded” a16z’s expectations, he added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“When companies are growing as fast as it is organically, they don’t need to rely on acquisitions to fuel growth,” he said. “But the strategic rationale here is so strong, that the acquisition will only turbocharge what is already high growth.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the Series E capital is primarily funding the acquisition, SpotOn continues to double down on its product and technology.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This is our time to shine and invest in the future with forward-thinking technology,” Hyman told TechCrunch. “We’re thinking about things like how are consumers going to be ordering their beer at a Dodgers game in three years? Are they going to be standing in line for 25 minutes or are they going to be interacting and buying merchandise in other unique ways? Those are the things we’re looking to solve for.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/spoton-raises-300m-at-a-3-15b-valuation-acquires-appetize/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201271</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spotify&#8217;s Clubhouse clone adds six new weekly shows, some that tie to Spotify playlists</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/spotifys-clubhouse-clone-adds-six-new-weekly-shows-some-that-tie-to-spotify-playlists/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/spotifys-clubhouse-clone-adds-six-new-weekly-shows-some-that-tie-to-spotify-playlists/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 15:06:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify Greenroom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201457</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This summer, Spotify launched its live audio app and Clubhouse rival, Spotify Greenroom, with the promises of more programming to come in the months ahead to augment its then primarily user-generated live content. Today, the company is making good on that earlier commitment, with the launch of six new shows on Spotify Greenroom focused on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This summer, Spotify <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/spotify-launches-its-live-audio-app-and-clubhouse-rival-spotify-greenroom/">launched</a> its live audio app and Clubhouse rival, Spotify Greenroom, with the promises of more programming to come in the months ahead to augment its then primarily user-generated live content. Today, the company is making good on that earlier commitment, with the launch of six new shows on Spotify Greenroom focused on pop culture and music, in addition to what Spotify calls &#8220;playlist-inspired shows&#8221; &#8212; meaning those that are inspired by Spotify&#8217;s own playlists.</p>
<p>This includes a new show based on the popular playlist Lorem, which launched in 2019, showcasing an eclectic mix of music that has included indie pop, R&amp;B, garage rock, hip-hop and more, <a href="https://www.oswegonian.com/2020/03/12/spotify-drops-new-playlist-lorem-tailor-made-for-generation-z/">focused on a younger, Gen Z audience</a>. That playlist today has over 884,000 &#8220;likes&#8221; on Spotify and has <a href="https://hypebeast.com/2020/11/spotify-lorem-playlist-interview">risen to become</a> one of the places new artists are able to break through on the platform. Now, Lorem listeners will be connected to &#8220;Lorem Life,&#8221; a Spotify Greenroom show that will feature a mix of culture and discussions about music, the environment, sustainability, fashion, and space, Spotify says. The show is hosted by Gen Z influencers and TikTok stars Dev Lemons and Max Motley, who will engage with other artists and influencers. It begins airing on Wednesday, September 15, at 9 PM ET.</p>
<p>Another new &#8220;playlist-inspired&#8221; show is &#8220;The Get Up LIVE.&#8221; If the name sounds familiar, it&#8217;s because &#8220;The Get Up&#8221; was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/22/spotify-takes-on-radio-with-its-own-daily-morning-show/">introduced last fall</a> as Spotify&#8217;s own take on a daily morning show by mixing music with talk radio-style content led by hosts who discuss the news, pop culture, entertainment and other topics. To date, that content has not been provided as a live program, however. Instead, the show has been pre-recorded then made available as a playlist that gives listeners the feel of a daily FM radio show. Now, &#8220;The Get Up&#8217;s&#8221; co-hosts Kat Lazo and Xavier “X” Jernigan will record their show live on Greenroom. The program was originally planning to launch Wednesday, Septtember 15 at 11 AM ET but has been delayed.*</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ji9dYvcWAU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/clubhouse-ux-teardown-a-closer-look-at-homepage-curation-follow-hooks-and-other-features/">Clubhouse UX teardown: A closer look at homepage curation, follow hooks and other features</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Clubhouse UX teardown: A closer look at homepage curation, follow hooks and other features&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/clubhouse-ux-teardown-a-closer-look-at-homepage-curation-follow-hooks-and-other-features/embed/#?secret=Ji9dYvcWAU" data-secret="Ji9dYvcWAU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This odd time seems to contradict Spotify&#8217;s original intention of providing a show for those who commute to the office. But with the rise of remote work in the face of the unending pandemic, addressing the commuter audience may be of less interest, with the new program. However, Spotify tells us &#8220;The Get up LIVE&#8221; will be complementary to the daily show, which will still run as normal &#8212; that&#8217;s why it has a later airing.</p>
<p>Other new Greenroom shows include &#8220;A Gay in the Life,&#8221; hosted by the married couple actor Garrett Clayton and writer and educator Blake Knight, who will discuss LGBTQIA+ news and issues (weekly, 8 PM ET, starting today); &#8220;Take a Seat,&#8221; hosted by Ben Mandelker and Ronnie Karam of the &#8220;Watch What Crappens&#8221; podcast, who will recap reality shows and dive into other pop culture fascinations (weekly, 10 PM ET, starting today); &#8220;The Movie Buff,&#8221; hosted by film buff and comedian Jon Gabrus, who will review and break down the latest hot movies (weekly, 11 PM ET, starting today); and &#8220;The Most Necessary: Live,&#8221; a complement to Spotify&#8217;s &#8220;Most Necessary&#8221; playlist, where host B.Dot will discuss up-and-comers in hip-hop (weekly, 9 PM ET, starting Tuesday).</p>
<p>In addition to the new programs, Deuxmoi’s show &#8220;Deux Me After Dark&#8221; will also air this evening (September 13) at 9 PM ET to recap the red carpet looks and gossip from this year&#8217;s Met Gala alongside guest Hillary Kerr, co-founder of Who What Wear.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2183360" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2183360" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2183360" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/greenroom.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="259" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/greenroom.png 1390w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/greenroom.png?resize=150,57 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/greenroom.png?resize=300,114 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/greenroom.png?resize=768,293 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/greenroom.png?resize=680,259 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/greenroom.png?resize=50,19 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2183360" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Spotify</p></div></p>
<p>Greenrom is now available to listeners in more than 135 global markets and has been quietly expanding with live audio from sports site and podcast network &#8220;The Ringer&#8221; as well as from artists like Pop Smoke, the company says. Other programs added include <a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/20VLkbny6CtlSZe5g0YjPy?si=ehecYV8gRfGNwED64tkGeQ&amp;dl_branch=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://open.spotify.com/episode/20VLkbny6CtlSZe5g0YjPy?si%3DehecYV8gRfGNwED64tkGeQ%26dl_branch%3D1&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1631632022228000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFjgmRT_WRpz2YA_Q-zjNd4LGrARg">Men In Blazers</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/53l2zgXZSsaCVlK5tKyqFC?si=9uceM4zDS1a29So04uVx6A&amp;dl_branch=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://open.spotify.com/episode/53l2zgXZSsaCVlK5tKyqFC?si%3D9uceM4zDS1a29So04uVx6A%26dl_branch%3D1&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1631632022228000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEytE_tZx7H9AACTB8O6K0ahVdwSg">Deaux Me After Dark</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/0ZXjkGQVTOXUS1z3HpVEiX?si=LYxS02ZsRHiMLkGwK_-1Ew&amp;dl_branch=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://open.spotify.com/episode/0ZXjkGQVTOXUS1z3HpVEiX?si%3DLYxS02ZsRHiMLkGwK_-1Ew%26dl_branch%3D1&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1631632022228000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHebpYQRKFNfY1oshNrRnn4zBknNg">True Crime Rewind</a> and <a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/5BGCn3r17pIMPB3y2v6JBi?si=Xp6wkpOaRqO-NGAQ1oI5Fg&amp;dl_branch=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://open.spotify.com/episode/5BGCn3r17pIMPB3y2v6JBi?si%3DXp6wkpOaRqO-NGAQ1oI5Fg%26dl_branch%3D1&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1631632022228000&amp;usg=AFQjCNF6exIRZjIYavDyytNGBFnF9A9RZg">Ask The Tarot</a>. Many of the shows are also being published on-demand after the live show ends.</p>
<p>The app had gotten off to a slower start this year, given its roots had been in sports talk live programming, which didn&#8217;t necessarily connect with Spotify&#8217;s music fans. Plus, it has faced growing competition from not only Clubhouse, which inspired its creation, but also other top social networks like Facebook, Twitter, Reddit, Discord and more. Without dedicated programs to garner user interest in yet another live audio app, the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/spotifys-clubhouse-rival-greenroom-tops-140k-installs-on-ios-100k-on-android/">had only seen 141,000 new downloads</a> for Greenroom on iOS a little over a month after its launch, and fewer on Google Play. But Spotify&#8217;s long-term vision for the service was to more closely tie Greenroom to the music, artists, programs and podcasts that were already available on its flagship music streaming app &#8212; and these new shows are an example of that plan in action.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>*Update, 9/13/21, 2:18 PM ET: Following its announcement, Spotify reached out to let TechCrunch know it has decided to delay the launch of &#8220;The Get Up LIVE.&#8221; According to a company representative: &#8220;due to a scheduling change, The Get Up LIVE’s launch has been postponed and a new premiere date will be announced soon.&#8221;  </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/spotifys-clubhouse-clone-adds-six-new-weekly-shows-some-that-tie-to-spotify-playlists/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201457</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Toast looks toward $18B valuation in upcoming IPO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/toast-looks-toward-18b-valuation-in-upcoming-ipo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/toast-looks-toward-18b-valuation-in-upcoming-ipo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 14:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201424</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you were considering buying into Toast's IPO in hopes of having a say in its future, don't. You won't.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As if <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/bostons-startup-market-is-more-than-setting-records-in-scorching-start-to-year/">the Boston startup market needed additional momentum</a>, it appears restaurant software startup Toast will dramatically bolster its valuation in its upcoming IPO.</p>
<p>For a city perhaps best known internationally for its hard tech and biotech efforts, to see Toast not only rebound from its early-pandemic layoffs to a public debut, but to target a valuation closer to $20 billion than $10 billion, is a coup.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>In a <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001650164/000119312521270772/d166297ds1a.htm">new S-1/A filing</a> this morning, Toast indicated an early IPO range of between $30 and $33 per share, leading to a maximum fundraise of $825 million in its IPO. The company was last valued at $4.9 billion in early 2020, when Toast raised $400 million. The company is set to dramatically supersede that valuation mark thanks to expanding revenues and an especially strong second quarter.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995211 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Let&#8217;s dig into the company&#8217;s new IPO price range, calculate simple and fully diluted results, and see what we can learn from where Toast may price. Recall that the company has a mix of recurring software (SaaS) incomes as well as fintech revenue (payments, mostly). Its revenue mix is interesting, and how Toast prices could help us better understand how to value vertical SaaS startups that are pursuing a payments-and-SaaS business approach.</p>
<p>Into the filing!</p>
<h2>Toast&#8217;s IPO valuation</h2>
<p>Toast is selling 21,739,131 Class A shares in its IPO. They get one vote. Class B shares get 10. If you were considering buying into Toast&#8217;s IPO in hopes of having a say in its future, don&#8217;t. You won&#8217;t. The company&#8217;s IPO is really a method by which public-market investors can endorse the company&#8217;s current management group &#8212; or decline to buy any ownership at all.</p>
<p>Regardless of how we feel about corporate governance structures designed to eliminate the influence of common shareholders, Toast will have 499,332,681 shares outstanding after its IPO, or 502,593,550 if its underwriters choose to purchase their allotted greenshoe option.</p>
<p>At the company&#8217;s expected IPO price range of $30 to $33 per share, Toast is worth $14.98 billion at the low end, and $16.48 billion at the top. Inclusive of shares from its underwriters&#8217; option, Toast&#8217;s simple IPO valuation range expands from $15.08 billion at the bottom to $16.59 billion at the top.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/toast-looks-toward-18b-valuation-in-upcoming-ipo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201424</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GrubMarket gobbles up $120M at a $1B+ pre-money valuation to take on the food supply chain</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/grubmarket-gobbles-up-120m-at-a-1b-pre-money-valuation-to-take-on-the-grocery-supply-chain/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/grubmarket-gobbles-up-120m-at-a-1b-pre-money-valuation-to-take-on-the-grocery-supply-chain/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 14:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arizona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[connecticut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital-Solutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farmigo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Georgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grocery store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grubhub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GrubMarket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instacart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan Post Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[massachusetts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michigan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Xu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Missouri]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new jersey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[olo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oregon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pegasus Tech Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pennsylvania]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reimagined Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber Eats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[washington]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whole foods]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When people talk about &#8220;online food delivery&#8221; services, chances are that they&#8217;ll think of the Uber Eats, Instacarts and Getirs of this world. But today a startup that&#8217;s tackling a different aspect of the market &#8212; addressing the supply chain that subsequently turns the wheels of the bigger food distribution machine &#8212; is announcing a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When people talk about &#8220;online food delivery&#8221; services, chances are that they&#8217;ll think of the Uber Eats, Instacarts and Getirs of this world. But today a startup that&#8217;s tackling a different aspect of the market &#8212; addressing the supply chain that subsequently turns the wheels of the bigger food distribution machine &#8212; is announcing a big round of funding as it continues to grow.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.grubmarket.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GrubMarket</a>, which provides software and services that help link up and manage relationships between food suppliers and their customers &#8212; which can include wholesalers and other distributors, markets and supermarkets, delivery startups, restaurants, and consumers &#8212; has picked up $120 million in a Series E round of funding.</p>
<p>The funding is coming from a wide mix of investors. Liberty Street Funds, Walleye Capital, Japan Post Capital, Joseph Stone Capital, Pegasus Tech Ventures, Tech Pioneers Fund are among the new backers, who are being joined by existing investors Celtic House Asia Partners, INP Capital, Reimagined Ventures, Moringa Capital Management, and others, along with other unnamed participants</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Mike-Xu-2021-Photo-3.jpg?w=680" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2201464" width="680" height="459" alt="" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Mike-Xu-2021-Photo-3.jpg 5103w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Mike-Xu-2021-Photo-3.jpg?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Mike-Xu-2021-Photo-3.jpg?resize=300,202 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Mike-Xu-2021-Photo-3.jpg?resize=768,518 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Mike-Xu-2021-Photo-3.jpg?resize=680,459 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Mike-Xu-2021-Photo-3.jpg?resize=1536,1036 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Mike-Xu-2021-Photo-3.jpg?resize=2048,1381 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Mike-Xu-2021-Photo-3.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" />Mike Xu, GrubMarket&#8217;s founder and CEO (pictured, above), tells me that the company is currently profitable in a big way. It&#8217;s now at a $1 billion annualized run-rate, having grown revenues 300% over last year, with some markets like New York growing even more (it went from less than $10 million ARR to $100 million+).</p>
<p>With operations currently in Arizona, California, Connecticut, Georgia, Michigan, New York, New Jersey, Missouri, Massachusetts, Oregon, Pennsylvania, Texas, and Washington, and some 40 warehouses nationwide. GrubMarket had a pre-money valuation of over $1 billion, and now it will be looking to grow even more, both in terms of territory and in terms of tech, moving ahead in a market that is largely absent from competitors.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are still the first mover in this space,&#8221; Xu said when I asked him in an interview about rivals. &#8220;No one else is doing consolidation on the supply chain side as we are. We are trying to consolidate the American food supply chain through software technologies, while also trying to find the best solutions in this space.&#8221;</p>
<p>(And for some context, the $1 billion+ valuation is more than double GrubMarket&#8217;s valuation in October 2020, when it raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/05/grubmarket-raises-60m-at-a-500m-valuation-as-food-delivery-stays-center-stage/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$60 million at a $500 million post-money valuation</a>.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Longer term, the plan will be to look at an IPO provisionally filing the paperwork by summer 2022, Xu added.</p>
<p>GrubMarket got its start several years ago as one of many companies looking to provide a more efficient farm-to-table service. Tapping into a growing consumer interest in higher quality, and more traceable food, it saw an opportunity to build a platform to link up producers to the consumers, restaurants and grocery stores that were buying their products. (Grocery stores, incidentally, might be independent operations, or something much bigger: one of GrubMarket&#8217;s biggest customers is Whole Foods, which uses GrubMarket for produce supply in certain regions of the U.S. It is currently is the company&#8217;s biggest customer.)</p>
<p>As we wrote <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/05/grubmarket-raises-60m-at-a-500m-valuation-as-food-delivery-stays-center-stage/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">last year</a>, GrubMarket &#8212; like many other grocery delivery services &#8212; found that the pandemic initially provided a big fillip, and a big rush of demand, from that consumer side of the business, as more people turned to internet-based ordering and delivery services to offset the fact that many stores were closed, or they simply wanted to curtail the amount of shopping they were doing in-person to slow the spread of Covid-19.</p>
<p>But fast forward to today, while the startup still serves consumers, this is currently not the primary part of its business. Instead, it&#8217;s B2B2C, serving companies that in turn serve consumers. Xu says that overall, demand from consumers has dropped off considerably compared to a year ago.</p>
<p>&#8220;We think that restaurant re-openings have meant more people are dining out again and spending less time at home,&#8221; Xu said, &#8221; and also they can go back to physical grocery stores, so they are not as interested as they were before in buying raw ingredients online. I don&#8217;t want to offend other food tech companies, but I think many of them will be seeing the same. I think B2C is really going to slow down going forward.&#8221;</p>
<p>The opening for GrubMarket has been not just positioning itself as a middleman between producers and buyers, but to do so by way of technology and consolidating what has been a very regionalized and fragmented market up to now.</p>
<p>GrubMarket has snapped up no less than 40 companies in the last three years. While some of these have been to help it expand geographically (it made 10 acquisitions in the Los Angeles area alone), many have also been made to double down on technology.</p>
<p>These have included the likes of <a href="https://www.farmigo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Farmigo</a>, once a <a href="https://beta.techcrunch.com/2012/12/11/farmigo-local-food-communities/?_ga=2.164545404.254421615.1631522567-209244718.1579131500" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Disrupt Battlefield contender</a> that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/13/farmigo-shuts-down-its-online-farmers-market/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pivoted</a> into becoming a software provider to CSAs (an area that GrubMarket sees a lot of opportunity), as well as software to help farms manage their business staffing, insurance and more: Pacific Farm Management is an example of the latter.</p>
<p>GrubMarket&#8217;s own in-house software, WholesaleWare, a cloud-based service for farmers and other food producers, saw its sales grow 3,500% over the last year, and it is now managing more than $4 billion in wholesale and retail activity across the U.S. and Canada.</p>
<p class="p1">There will be obvious ways to extend what GrubMarket does deeper into the needs of its customers on the purchasing end, but this is in many ways also a very crowded market. (And not just crowded, but crowded with big companies. Just today, Toast, the company that builds software for restaurants, <a href="https://www.techmeme.com/210913/p12#a210913p12" target="_blank" rel="noopener">filed for a $717 million IPO</a> at potentially a $16.5 billion valuation.) So instead, GrubMarket will continue to focus on what has been a more overlooked aspect, that of the suppliers.</p>
<p class="p1">&#8220;I am focused on the food supply chain,&#8221; Xu said. &#8220;Operators in the food supply chain business most of the time don’t have any access to software and e-commerce technology. But we are not just a lightweight online ordering system. We do a lot of heavyweight lifting around inventory management, pricing and customer relations, and even HR management for wholesales and distributors.&#8221; That will also mean, longer term, that GrubMarket will likely also start to explore connected hardware to help those customers, too: robotics for picking and moving items are on that agenda, Xu said.</p>
<p>“GrubMarket has built a profitable, high-growth business underpinned by its best-in-class technology platform that’s reinventing how businesses access healthy, fresh foods,” said Jack Litowitz, director of strategic investments at Reimagined Ventures, in a statement. “We’re proud to support GrubMarket as it continues to expand into new regions and grow its WholesaleWare 2.0 software platform. At Reimagined Ventures, we always seek to invest in businesses that are disrupting inefficient industries in innovative ways. Mike Xu and the GrubMarket team have built one of these businesses. We’re excited to back their vision and work in making the food supply chain more efficient.”</p>
<p>&#8220;GrubMarket is transforming the trillion-dollar food distribution industry with unprecedented speed by implementing advanced digital solutions and operational discipline. The company&#8217;s scale, growth, and profitability are extraordinarily impressive. Pegasus is delighted and honored to be part of GrubMarket&#8217;s exciting journey ahead,&#8221; added Bill Reichert, partner at Pegasus Tech Ventures.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/grubmarket-gobbles-up-120m-at-a-1b-pre-money-valuation-to-take-on-the-grocery-supply-chain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201428</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Disney+ &#8216;Hawkeye&#8217; trailer shows Clint Barton&#8217;s past catching up with him</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/disney-hawkeye-trailer-shows-clint-bartons-past-catching-up-with-him/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/disney-hawkeye-trailer-shows-clint-bartons-past-catching-up-with-him/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 14:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HawkEye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marvel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201450</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The next Marvel Cinematic Universe show will premiere on Disney+ in November and Hawkeye has a festive setting. Watch the trailer for the new show starring Jeremy Renner and Hailey Steinfeld now.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Kris Holt</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://www.twitter.com/krisholt">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Kris Holt is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com/">Engadget</a>. 	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/the-marvel-unlimited-comics-app-just-got-a-major-overhaul/">The Marvel Unlimited comics app just got a major overhaul</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/locast-suspends-local-tv-streaming-service-in-wake-of-court-ruling/">Locast suspends local TV streaming service in wake of court ruling</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The next <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/mcu" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1"><ins>Marvel Cinematic Universe</ins></a> show will premiere on Disney+ in November and, appropriately enough, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/hawkeye" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1"><em><ins>Hawkeye</ins></em></a><em> </em>has a festive setting. Clint Barton (aka Hawkeye) just wants to spend Christmas with his family, but his enemies have other plans.</p>
<p>The series marks the return of Jeremy Renner as Hawkeye. This time around, he has a new partner: <a href="https://www.engadget.com/marvels-avengers-kate-bishop-hawkeye-release-date-182816765.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="22" data-v9y="1">Kate Bishop</a> (Hailee Steinfeld), the self-professed &#8220;world&#8217;s greatest archer.&#8221; <em>Hawkeye</em> is said to center on the relationship between the two toxophilites, with Clint training Kate to take over as Hawkeye, as the character does in the comics. There are hints of that passing of the torch in the trailer. It shows the pair meeting for the first time and forming a bond as they work together to battle some goons.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5VYb3B1ETlk?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>There are a few nods to other parts of the MCU here, including the existence of a Broadway musical about Steve Rogers (aka Captain America) and a tip of the cap toward the &#8220;masked vigilante&#8221; Hawkeye battled in <em>Avengers: Endgame</em>. Something we <em>don&#8217;t </em>see in the trailer is an appearance by Florence Pugh, who made her MCU bow as assassin Yelena Belova in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/black%20widow" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="24" data-v9y="1"><em><ins>Black Widow</ins></em></a><em> </em>this summer. She was <a href="https://variety.com/2020/tv/news/hawkeye-disney-plus-florence-pugh-vera-farmiga-cast-1234845371/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="25" data-v9y="1"><ins>cast</ins></a> in <em>Hawkeye</em> last December.</p>
<p>In any case, you won&#8217;t have to wait too long to see what happens when Yelena, Clint and Kate encounter each other. The eight-episode first season of <em>Hawkeye</em>will debut on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/hawkeye-disney-plus-november-24-premiere-155812908.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="26" data-v9y="1"><ins>November 24th</ins></a> on Disney+.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/disney-plus-hawkeye-trailer-premiere-date-clint-barton-kate-bishop-hailee-steinfeld-140006373.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/disney-hawkeye-trailer-shows-clint-bartons-past-catching-up-with-him/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201450</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Only one week until TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 opens a world of opportunity</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/only-one-week-until-techcrunch-disrupt-2021-opens-a-world-of-opportunity/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/only-one-week-until-techcrunch-disrupt-2021-opens-a-world-of-opportunity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 14:07:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199370</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One. More. Week. Just seven days until more than 10,000 people around the world storm the internet to attend TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 on September 21-23. We’re talking three event- and programming-packed days focused on anything — and everything — related to early-stage tech startups. You’ll hear from iconic founders, unicorn makers, boundary-benders — all of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">One. More. Week. Just seven days until more than 10,000 people around the world storm the internet to attend <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> on September 21-23. We’re talking three event- and programming-packed days focused on anything — and everything — related to early-stage tech startups.</p>
<p>You’ll hear from iconic founders, unicorn makers, boundary-benders — all of it served up with a gigantic side of DIY tips, actionable advice, encouragement and inspiration. And, because Disrupt is highly interactive, you’ll have plenty of opportunity to engage, ask questions and receive answers.</p>
<p><strong>Admit one:</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/tickets/">Buy your TC Disrupt 2021 pass</a> — for less than $100 — and go find or create the opportunities that can help you move your business forward.</p>
<p>We’ll hit a few of the highlights, but be sure to check the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/#0affacde-e0ed-4a3c-abc4-988cb1c0eb3e">Disrupt 2021 agenda</a> for all the interviews, panel discussions, breakout sessions and events. Your pass includes video-on-demand, so you can catch any sessions you miss when your schedule allows.</p>
<p>Disrupt always brings <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/#eb919231-f3e4-4def-8dd0-afb0bc7c9c6e">world-class speakers</a> to the stage, and this year is no exception. We have more than 80 presentations (and counting) on tap. Talk about something for everyone. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/17/discover-all-things-biotech-with-mayfield-at-disrupt-2021/">Biotech</a>? Covered. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/were-focusing-on-fintech-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/">Fintech</a>? Also covered. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/fundraising-for-your-startup-weve-got-you-covered-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/">Fundraising</a>? Well, of course. Robots, health tech, space — heck, there’s so much more we can’t cover it here. Head to the agenda and plan your strategy.</p>
<p>Explore hundreds of innovative startups exhibiting in Startup Alley, our expo area. Visit their virtual booths, get a product demo and start a conversation. You can also catch Startup Alley founders pitching to TechCrunch staff. Look for the Startup Pitch Feedback Sessions scheduled over all three days.</p>
<p>Who’s ready for Startup Battlefield? Watch as 20 of the top early-stage founders compete for the coveted championship title and $100,000 in equity-free prize money. Some of today’s top tech companies launched at Startup Battlefield — think Dropbox, Vurb and Tripit. Don’t miss your chance to see the future of tech take the stage.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<blockquote><p>The Startup Battlefield translated easily to the virtual format. You could see the excitement, enthusiasm and possibility of the young founders, and I loved that. You could also ask questions through the chat feature, and you don&#8217;t always have time for questions at a live event. — Rachael Wilcox, creative producer, Volvo Cars.</p></blockquote>
<p>Remember we said you’ll find plenty of actionable advice? Don’t miss the expert VC guidance in these two sessions: <strong>Crafting a Pitch Deck that Can’t Be Ignored</strong> and <strong>Pitch Deck Teardown</strong>.</p>
<blockquote><p>Disrupt is a great sweet spot, and highly valuable, for anyone in the idea stage all the way through to having raised some angel money. Soak up the pitch deck teardowns and the VC presentations. They’re telling you what they&#8217;re looking for, what motivates them, what pushes them to contact you for a meeting. And that’s exactly what every startup raising capital needs to know. — Michael McCarthy, CEO, Repositax.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> kicks off in just one week. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/tickets/">Buy your pass</a>, plan your schedule and get ready to disrupt your business in the best possible way.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			width="99%"
			height="1300"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/only-one-week-until-techcrunch-disrupt-2021-opens-a-world-of-opportunity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199370</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
