<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 15:55:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Relativity Space unveils plans for a new, much larger and fully reusable rocket</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/relativity-space-unveils-plans-for-a-new-much-larger-and-fully-reusable-rocket/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/relativity-space-unveils-plans-for-a-new-much-larger-and-fully-reusable-rocket/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 15:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3d printing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[falcon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Falcon 9]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generative manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international space station]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relativity Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tim ellis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118122</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[3D-printed rocket company Relativity Space has just revealed what comes after Terran 1, the small launch vehicle it hopes to begin flying later this year. It&#8217;s next rocket will be Terran R, a much larger orbital rocket with around 20x the cargo capacity of Terran 1, that will also be distinguished from its smaller, disposable [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">3D-printed rocket company Relativity Space has just revealed what comes after Terran 1, the small launch vehicle it hopes to begin flying later this year. It&#8217;s next rocket will be Terran R, a much larger orbital rocket with around 20x the cargo capacity of Terran 1, that will also be distinguished from its smaller, disposable sibling by being fully reusable – across both first and second-stages, unlike SpaceX&#8217;s Falcon 9.</p>
<p>I spoke to Relativity Space CEO and founder Tim Ellis about Terran R, and how long it&#8217;s been in the works for the space startup. Ellis said that in fact, the vision every since Relativity&#8217;s time at Y Combinator has included larger lift rockets – and much more.</p>
<p>&#8220;When I founded Relativity five years ago, it always was inspired by seeing SpaceX launching and landing rockets, docking with the International Space Station, and this idea that going to Mars was critically important for humanity&#8217;s future, and really expanding the possibilities for human experience, on Earth and beyond,&#8221; Ellis told me. &#8220;But that all of the animations faded to black right when people walked out [of spaceship landing on Mars], and I believed that 3D printing had to be this inevitable technology that was going to build humanity&#8217;s industrial base on Mars, and that we needed to really inspire dozens, or even hundreds of companies to work on making this future happen.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Q0WmBtGY2I"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/07/relativity-spaces-focus-on-3d-printing-and-cloud-based-software-helps-it-weather-the-covid-19-storm/">Relativity Space&#8217;s focus on 3D printing and cloud-based software helps it weather the COVID-19 storm</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Relativity Space&#8217;s focus on 3D printing and cloud-based software helps it weather the COVID-19 storm&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/07/relativity-spaces-focus-on-3d-printing-and-cloud-based-software-helps-it-weather-the-covid-19-storm/embed/#?secret=Q0WmBtGY2I" data-secret="Q0WmBtGY2I" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The long-term goal for Relativity Space, Ellis said, has always been to become an &#8220;end-product 3D printing company,&#8221; with its original Terran 1 light payload rocket simply representing the first of those products it&#8217;s bringing to market.</p>
<p>&#8220;3D printing is our new tech stack for aerospace, and really is rewriting something that we don&#8217;t feel has fundamentally changed over the last 60 years,&#8221; he said. &#8220;It&#8217;s really bringing automation that replaces the factory fixed tooling, supply chains, hundreds of thousands of parts, manual labor and slow iteration speed, with something that I believe is needed for the future on Earth, too.&#8221;</p>
<p>Terran R, which will have a payload capacity of over 20,000 kg (more than 44,000 lbs) to low-Earth orbit, is simply &#8220;the next logical step&#8221; for Relativity in that long-term vision of producing a wide range of products, including aerospace equipment for use right here on Earth. Ellis says that a larger launch vehicle makes sense given current strong customer demand for Terran 1, which has a max payload capacity of 1,250 kg (around 2,755 lbs) to low-Earth orbit, combined with the average size of satellites being launched today. Despite the boon in so-called &#8216;small&#8217; satellites, many of the constellations being build today have individual satellites that weigh in excess of 500 kilograms (1,100 lbs), Ellis points out, which means that Terran R will be able to delivery many more at once for these growing on-orbit spacecraft networks.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2118343" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2118343" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2118343" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Engine-Test-2.24.2021.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Engine-Test-2.24.2021.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Engine-Test-2.24.2021.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Engine-Test-2.24.2021.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Engine-Test-2.24.2021.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Engine-Test-2.24.2021.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Engine-Test-2.24.2021.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Engine-Test-2.24.2021.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Engine-Test-2.24.2021.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2118343" class="wp-caption-text">A test fire of the new engine that Terran R will use for higher thrust capabilities.</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s really the same rocket architecture, it&#8217;s the same propellant, same factory, it&#8217;s the same printers, the same avionics and the same team that developed Terran 1,&#8221; Ellis said about the forthcoming rocket. That means that it&#8217;s actually relatively easy for the company to spin up its new production line, despite Terran R actually being quite functionally different than the current, smaller rocket – particularly when it comes to its full reusability.</p>
<p>As mentioned, Terran R will have both a reusable first and second stage. SpaceX&#8217;s Falcon 9&#8217;s first stage (a liquid fuel rocket booster) is reusable, and detaches from the second stage before quickly re-orienting itself and re-entering Earth&#8217;s atmosphere for a propulsive landing just after entering space. The Falcon 9 second stage is expendable, which is the space term for essentially just junk that&#8217;s discarded and eventually de-orbits and burns up on re-entry.</p>
<p>SpaceX had planned to try to make the Falcon 9 second stage reusable, but it would&#8217;ve required too much additional mass via heat shielding for it to make sense with the economics it was targeting. Ellis was light on details about Terran R&#8217;s specifics, but he did hint that some unique use of fairly unusual materials made possible though 3D printing, along with some sparing use of generative design, will be at work in helping the Relativity rocket&#8217;s second stage reusable in a sustainable way.</p>
<p>&#8220;Because it&#8217;s still entirely 3D-printed, we&#8217;re actually going to use more exotic materials, and design geometries that wouldn&#8217;t be possible at all, traditionally, to manufacture,&#8221; Ellis said. &#8220;It&#8217;s just too complicated looking; it would be way too difficult to manufacture traditionally in the ways that that Terran R is designed. And that will actually make it a much more reusable rocket, and really helped build the best reusable rocket possible.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aVwr0cxDgs"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/relativity-space-raises-500-million-as-its-sets-sights-on-the-industrialization-of-mars/">Relativity Space raises $500 million as it sets sights on the industrialization of Mars</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Relativity Space raises $500 million as it sets sights on the industrialization of Mars&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/relativity-space-raises-500-million-as-its-sets-sights-on-the-industrialization-of-mars/embed/#?secret=aVwr0cxDgs" data-secret="aVwr0cxDgs" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Terran R will also use a new upper stage engine that Relativity Space is designing, which is also unique compared to the existing engines used on Terran 1. It&#8217;s 3D printed as well, but uses a copper thrust chamber that will allow it to have higher overall power and thrust capabilities, according to Ellis. When I spoke to Ellis on Thursday evening, Relativity had just completed its first full success duration test of the new engine, a key step towards full production.</p>
<p>Ellis said that the company will share more about Terran R over the course of this year, but did note that the existing large 3D printers in its production facilities are already sized correctly to start building the new rocket – &#8220;the only change is software,&#8221; he said. He also added that some of the test sites Relativity has contracted to use at NASA&#8217;s Stennis Space Center are able to support testing of a rocket at Terran R&#8217;s scale, too, so it sounds like he&#8217;s planning for rapid progress on this new launch vehicle.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/relativity-space-unveils-plans-for-a-new-much-larger-and-fully-reusable-rocket/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118122</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Newness raises $3.5 million for its &#8216;Twitch for beauty streamers&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/newness-raises-3-5-million-for-its-twitch-for-beauty-streamers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/newness-raises-3-5-million-for-its-twitch-for-beauty-streamers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 15:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118027</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Newness, a startup co-founded by former Twitch employees, has raised $3.5 million in a Sequoia-led seed round for its live-streaming platform aimed at beauty creators and their fan communities. Though today&#8217;s creators are not without options when it comes to livestreaming &#8212; Twitch, YouTube, TikTok, Instagram and Facebook are all popular choices &#8212; Newness is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://newness.com/">Newness</a>, a startup co-founded by former Twitch employees, has raised $3.5 million in a Sequoia-led seed round for its live-streaming platform aimed at beauty creators and their fan communities. Though today&#8217;s creators are not without options when it comes to livestreaming &#8212; Twitch, YouTube, TikTok, Instagram and Facebook are all popular choices &#8212; Newness is focused on building differentiated tools and features that work well for the beauty streamer market in particular. This includes offering options for both public and private streams, engagement mechanisms that reward positive contributions, moderation features, and the ability for fans to earn access to free beauty products by community participation.</p>
<p>In the new round, Jess Lee invested on behalf of Sequoia Capital. Other investors in <a href="https://newness.com/">Newness</a> include Cowboy Ventures (<a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/aileen-lee">Aileen Lee)</a>, Upside Partnership (<a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/kent-goldman">Kent Goldman)</a>, Dream Machine (former TechCrunch editor <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/alexia-tsotsis">Alexia Bonatsos</a>), Index Ventures (<a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/nina-achadjian">Nina Achadjian</a>), Twitch co-founder <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kevinlin3/">Kevin Lin</a>, former Twitch execs <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jshipman/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.linkedin.com/in/jshipman/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1614378233472000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFm84exhRM_tMimQ5UzW5bWNhj-Dg">Jonathan Shipman</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-sutton-b986611/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-sutton-b986611/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1614378233472000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGAVm0w-lsAvnzZLdzxEnutTIugGg">John Sutton</a>, Eventbrite founders <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/hartz/">Kevin</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/juliahartz/">Julia Hartz</a>, Incredible Health co-founder and CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/imanabuzeid/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.linkedin.com/in/imanabuzeid/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1614378233472000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE-IkRj2ZLpeD3W5-QeVIqjFMXNxw">Iman Abuzeid</a>, and other angel investors from Twitch.</p>
<p>The idea for Newness comes from CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jennyqian">Jenny Qian</a>, an early Twitch employee who held a number of roles at the game-streaming site over the years, most recently as the Senior Director of Business Strategy for Twitch&#8217;s video platform. She&#8217;s joined by CTO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/youripark/">Youri Park</a>, who also previously worked at Twitch, as well as Blizzard and Facebook Gaming.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Though always an avid gamer herself, Qian says she began getting into skincare after she turned 30. She then soon realized the potential in the live-streaming beauty space.</p>
<p>&#8220;I was so used to the format from Twitch. And, in some ways, I feel like I was spoiled with live-streaming,&#8221; she explains. Being able to hang out with streamers, ask questions, and learn from them was something that made the live format so compelling, she believes.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2118284" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2118284" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2118284" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-26-at-9.26.10-AM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="343" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-26-at-9.26.10-AM.jpg 3286w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-26-at-9.26.10-AM.jpg?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-26-at-9.26.10-AM.jpg?resize=300,151 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-26-at-9.26.10-AM.jpg?resize=768,388 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-26-at-9.26.10-AM.jpg?resize=680,343 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-26-at-9.26.10-AM.jpg?resize=1536,775 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-26-at-9.26.10-AM.jpg?resize=2048,1033 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-26-at-9.26.10-AM.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2118284" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Newness</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;It made me scratch my head and think: why didn&#8217;t something like this exist for the beauty community? It&#8217;s a community that is just as passionate, if not more so&#8230;and it&#8217;s a content category that is so incredibly popular. How come there isn&#8217;t a live medium available?,&#8221; she wondered.</p>
<p>But at the same time, Qian admits she didn&#8217;t feel comfortable going live on Twitch.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s one thing to be made fun of for my gameplay. But I think it&#8217;s another if I take my makeup off, and people are making fun of me for how I look. It just cuts to a whole new level,&#8221; she says.</p>
<p>With Newness, the goal is to create a sort of anti-Twitch, in a way. It aspires to be a wholesome, positive community for beauty creators and fans, where moderation is a key focus and fans get rewarded for quality participation, not trolling.</p>
<p>When creators go live, Newness will pair them with an in-house moderator to help them feel more comfortable and to keep the content flowing. Once they&#8217;re a more established streamer, Newness will work with the creator to locate and elevate a moderator from their own fan community to help out with future streams.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, fans are awarded virtual items called crystals for positive participation and good behavior &#8212; for example, for watching your favorite stream and engaging in chat. In Newness, every chat message also has a little heart next to it. And the more hearts you earn over time for higher-quality comments, the more crystals you also earn.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2118291" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2118291" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2118291" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-26-at-9.33.14-AM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="587" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-26-at-9.33.14-AM.jpg 1712w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-26-at-9.33.14-AM.jpg?resize=150,129 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-26-at-9.33.14-AM.jpg?resize=300,259 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-26-at-9.33.14-AM.jpg?resize=768,663 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-26-at-9.33.14-AM.jpg?resize=680,587 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-26-at-9.33.14-AM.jpg?resize=1536,1326 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-26-at-9.33.14-AM.jpg?resize=50,43 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2118291" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Newness</p></div></p>
<p>These crystals can be redeemed for full-size beauty products, which Newness will source through brand deals. Because moderators spend more time on the platform, they&#8217;ll also earn more crystals &#8212; and that means more opportunities for products.</p>
<p>The positive reward system has so far proven successful during beta tests, as around 66% of Newness viewers, on average, end up chatting during live streams, Qian says.</p>
<p>Another differentiating feature for Newness is the ability for creators to host both public and private streams. The latter is not meant to be some sort of OnlyFans equivalent, but is instead focused on allowing creators to host more professional and exclusive live events. With private streams, creators can sell both general admission and even pricier VIP tickets that could come with some sort of reward &#8212; like a goodie bag of beauty supplies.</p>
<p>In addition to events, Newness supports an in-app tipping mechanism called &#8220;gifting&#8221; on everyday streams.</p>
<p>Eventually, the startup plans to take a share of the revenue these transactions generate, but it hasn&#8217;t yet rolled that out as it&#8217;s still beta testing.</p>
<p>At present, the Newness community its small. And it still chooses which creators are allowed to live stream.</p>
<p>&#8220;We handpick the creators that we let on to our platform and keep it invite-only because we want to make sure that our earliest creators are helping to set the tone and building the culture of the community,&#8221; she says. The startup wants to ensure there are enough community members to sustain itself, while also not allowing the community to become toxic as it scales.</p>
<p>&#8220;We really care about cultivating an incredibly wholesome community. So for us, safety, moderation &#8212; all that is really important to us,&#8221; Qian notes.</p>
<p>The creators produce a range of content, including more expert advice and product reviews to more casual &#8220;get ready with me&#8221; videos and vlogs.</p>
<p>Newness, of course, will face steep competition from larger, existing platforms for streamers, like YouTube and Instagram, as well as from newcomers more focused on beauty videos, like <a href="https://supergreat.com/">Supergreat</a>.</p>
<p>The startup has been in beta testing since last year, and is only available on the web for the time being. With the seed funding, Newness expects to build out its iOS consumer app in 2021, to complement its dedicated streaming app for creators. (Creators can also opt to stream from their DSLRs, if they prefer.)</p>
<p>It also aims to hire engineering talent and build out its 14-person team that&#8217;s now spread out across San Francisco, New York (thanks to some ex-Glossier hires), and L.A.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/newness-raises-3-5-million-for-its-twitch-for-beauty-streamers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118027</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>First Boulevard raises $5M for its digital bank aimed at Black America</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/first-boulevard-raises-5m-for-its-digital-bank-aimed-at-black-america/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/first-boulevard-raises-5m-for-its-digital-bank-aimed-at-black-america/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 15:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anthemis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barclays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[george floyd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greenwood]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118303</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The murder of George Floyd last May ignited many things in the United States last year &#8212; one of which that was perhaps unexpected: a rise in the number of digital banks targeting the Black community. Some members of the Black community took their belief that big banks are not meeting their needs and turned [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The murder of George Floyd last May ignited many things in the United States last year &#8212; one of which that was perhaps unexpected: a rise in the number of digital banks targeting the Black community.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some members of the Black community took their belief that big banks are not meeting their needs and turned them into startup concepts.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of those startups, First Boulevard (formerly called Tenth), has just raised $5 million in seed funding from Barclays, Anthemis and a group of angel investors such as actress Gabrielle Union, Union Square Ventures John Buttrick and AutoZone CFO Jamere Jackson.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For co-founder and CEO </span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/donald-j-hawkins/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Donald Hawkins</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the genesis for the Overland, Kansas-bank came after Floyd’s murder, when he and friend </span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/asyabradley/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Asya Bradley</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> were talking about what they felt Black America “really needed to get out of a vicious cycle” of dealing with the same issues with no real solutions in sight.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2118318" style="width: 210px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2118318" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2118318 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KEN8097.jpeg?w=200" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KEN8097.jpeg 5504w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KEN8097.jpeg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KEN8097.jpeg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KEN8097.jpeg?resize=768,1152 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KEN8097.jpeg?resize=453,680 453w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KEN8097.jpeg?resize=1024,1536 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KEN8097.jpeg?resize=1365,2048 1365w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KEN8097.jpeg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2118318" class="wp-caption-text">CEO Donald Hawkins</p></div></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2118319" style="width: 250px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2118319" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2118319 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Copy-of-Asya-Bradley-7409908.jpg?w=240" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Copy-of-Asya-Bradley-7409908.jpg 2848w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Copy-of-Asya-Bradley-7409908.jpg?resize=120,150 120w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Copy-of-Asya-Bradley-7409908.jpg?resize=240,300 240w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Copy-of-Asya-Bradley-7409908.jpg?resize=768,960 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Copy-of-Asya-Bradley-7409908.jpg?resize=544,680 544w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Copy-of-Asya-Bradley-7409908.jpg?resize=1229,1536 1229w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Copy-of-Asya-Bradley-7409908.jpg?resize=1638,2048 1638w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Copy-of-Asya-Bradley-7409908.jpg?resize=40,50 40w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2118319" class="wp-caption-text">COO Asya Bradley</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“After viewing yet another tragedy engulf the Black community, and the all-too-familiar protests against persisting issues,” Hawkins said. “it was beyond clear to me that the solutions Black America needs must be financially-focused and developed within our community.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pair both had fintech experience. Hawkins had founded Griffin Technologies, a company focused on providing real-time, contextual intelligence to community banks and credit unions. And Bradley most recently was a founding team member and head of revenue at Synapse, a platform that built banking-as-a-service APIs to help bank the unbanked of America by connecting fintech platforms to banking institutions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">They discovered that there were only about 19 Black banks in the U.S., collectively holding about $5 billion in assets.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“And their technology was really behind the times,” Hawkins said. “We also took a hard look at some of the existing digital banks to really see who was really going about it  in the same way that we felt like America needed, and it was pretty clear at that point, that no one was really attacking the issue of helping Black America build some level of financial stability through the form of wealth-building play.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pair formed First Boulevard last August under the premise that Black Americans are “massively underserved consumers” of financial products and services despite having a collective spending power of </span><a href="https://www.catalyst.org/research/buying-power/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$1.4 trillion annually</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The startup’s mission is to empower Black Americans “ to take control of their finances, build wealth and reinvest in the Black economy” via a digitally-native platform. First Boulevard has 100,000 people on its waitlist currently.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Part of its goal with the new capital involves building out a Black business marketplace, which will give its members Cash Back for Buying Black<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />. It also plans to use the money to expand its team, increase its customer base and grow its platform to offer fee-free debit cards, financial education and on developing technology to help members automate their saving and wealth building goals.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">History has proven that oppressed communities can succeed when their finances are centralized, and when it comes to financial services for the Black community, a centralizing force is long overdue,” Hawkins said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The bank’s </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cash Back for Buying Black<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> program helps members earn up to 15% cashback when they spend money at black-owned businesses. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I believe the most recent stat but that also was that 41% of black owned businesses have closed since COVID-19 started,” Hawkins said. “We want to support them as much as we can.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">First Boulevard also is focused on passively building wealth for its communities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Black America as a whole has been blocked from learning how money works. We want to connect our members to wealth-building assets such as micro investments like money market accounts, high yield savings and cryptocurrency &#8212; things that Black America has largely been blocked from,&#8221; Hawkins said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bradley, who serves as First Boulevard’s COO, believes the current financial industry was not built to serve the needs of melanated people. Its goal is to take their understanding of the unique needs of the Black community to provide things such as early access to wages, round up savings features, targeted financial education and budgeting tools.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pair aims to have a “fully inclusive” team that represents the community it’s trying to serve. Currently, its 20-person staff is 60% black, and 85% BIPOC. Two-thirds of its leadership team are women and 100% is BIPOC. The company plans to boost its headcount to 50 by year&#8217;s end.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We are very proud of that considering that in the fintech space, those are not normal numbers from a leadership perspective,” Bradley said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Katie Palencsar, an investor at the Female Innovators Lab by Barclays and Anthemis, said </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">that her firm has always recognized “that access to financial services has long remained a challenge despite the digital evolution.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This is especially true for Black Americans who often reside in financial deserts and struggle to find platforms that truly look to serve them,” she said. “First Boulevard deeply understands the challenge.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Palencsar believes that First Boulevard’s mission of helping Black Americans not just bank, but actually build wealth, is unique in the market.</span></p>
<p><b>“</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">First Boulevard sees the wealth gap that continues to grow within the U.S. and wants to build a digital banking platform that addresses the systemic and structural challenges that face this population while enabling Black Americans and allies to invest in the community,” she said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company also recently announced a partnership with Visa, under which First Boulevard will be first to pilot Visa’s new suite of crypto APIs. First Boulevard will also launch a First Boulevard Visa Debit card.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">First Boulevard is one of several digital banks geared toward Black Americans that have emerged in recent months. Paybby, a digital bank for the black and brown communities, recently acquired Wicket, a neobank that uses AI and biometric technology to create a personalized experience for users. Hassan Miah, the CEO and founder of Paybby, said the bank’s goal is to be “the leading smart, digital bank for the Black and Brown communities.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Paybby, which started by offering a bank account and a way to expedite PPP loans, will soon be adding a cryptocurrency savings account for the Black and Brown communities.   </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Black buying power is projected to grow to $1.8 trillion by 2024,” Miah said. “Brown buying power is over $2 trillion. Paybby wants to take a good portion of this multi-trillion dollar market and give it back to these communities.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last October,</span> Greenwood <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/greenwood-closes-3-million-seed-round-to-build-online-banking-solution-for-blacks-and-latinx-301147915.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">raised $3 million in seed funding</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from private investors to build what it describes as “the first digital banking platform for Black and Latinx people and business owners.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the time, co-founder Ryan Glover, founder of Bounce TV network, said it was “no secret that traditional banks have failed the Black and Latinx community.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/first-boulevard-raises-5m-for-its-digital-bank-aimed-at-black-america/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118303</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why are we still dating LinkedIn in 2021?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/why-are-we-still-dating-linkedin-in-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/why-are-we-still-dating-linkedin-in-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alexis Ohanian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hopin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[olo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reddit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shippo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup communities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118066</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. Natasha and Danny and Alex and Grace were all here to chat through the week’s biggest tech happenings. Before we get into this week&#8217;s show, make sure to check out all the news here about how Equity is expanding, and becoming even more of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/3ad3d039-a273-46b7-bad3-f2e0a2aeaed9?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/DannyCrichton">Danny</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/gracedenhall">Grace</a> were all here to chat through the week’s biggest tech happenings. Before we get into this week&#8217;s show, make sure to check out all the news <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/the-equity-podcast-is-getting-bigger-and-better/">here</a> about how Equity is expanding, and becoming even more of a thing in 2021! We are beyond hyped about it.</p>
<p>Coming on the back of such a wild news week, we had to cut and cut from the notes doc to get the show to size. So, here&#8217;s what made the cut:</p>
<ul>
<li>Coinbase filed to go public. Alex <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/five-takeaways-from-coinbases-s-1/">wrote about its S-1 filing here</a>, and Danny <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/usv-has-been-aggressively-selling-off-shares-in-coinbase-in-run-up-to-ipo/">riffed on a fascinating nuance regarding its cap table here</a>.</li>
<li>Hopin is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/vcs-are-chasing-hopin-upwards-of-5-6b-valuation/">raising more money, at an even larger valuation</a>. Every time we cover the latest version of this story, we think it must be the last time. And then it happens again. So, check back here in October for when Hopin raises again.</li>
<li>Reddit also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/reddit-series-e-more-capital/">picked up more money</a>. Again. Our take is that the capital must mean that Reddit is a better business than we anticipated.</li>
<li>Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian backed a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/20/chief-community-officer-is-the-new-cmo/?tpcc=ECTW2020">new community tool</a> proving the monetary value of the community. That led us into a conversation about a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/contra-series-a/">professional network for independent workers</a> that is competing with LinkedIn, and a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/the-landing-is-bringing-shoppable-social-and-collaboration-to-interior-design/">collaborative workspace for interior design fans. </a></li>
<li>Toast is said to be on the road to an IPO, and so we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/understanding-toasts-expected-ipo-through-the-lens-of-olos-2020-results/?tpcc=ECTW2020">riffed on what Olo&#8217;s IPO can tell us</a> about the Boston-based unicorn.</li>
<li>Shippo <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/shippo-raises-45m-more-at-495m-valuation-as-ecommerce-booms/">raised more money after a big 2020</a>; can the company double again in 2021?</li>
<li>Finix raised $3 million through an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/fintech-startup-finix-closes-on-3m-in-black-and-latinx-investor-led-spv/">SPV filled with over 80 Black and LatinX investors. </a></li>
</ul>
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 AM PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts!</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/why-are-we-still-dating-linkedin-in-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118066</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TechCrunch Early Stage is the startup bootcamp you&#8217;ve always needed</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 14:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117860</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Wondering how to nail that virtual pitch meeting and raise VC funding? Or how to build a high-octane sales team? What about recruiting early team members that will fuel future growth? Managing the finances of a new company while also wondering about your own personal finances as a founder? Legal? Marketing? PR? Being a great [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Wondering how to nail that virtual pitch meeting and raise VC funding? Or how to build a high-octane sales team? What about recruiting early team members that will fuel future growth? Managing the finances of a new company while also wondering about your own personal finances as a founder? Legal? Marketing? PR? Being a great leader?</p>
<p>The answer to every single one of these questions, and many more, will be at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/?promo=startupbootcamppost">TechCrunch&#8217;s Early Stage events</a>.</p>
<p>The event series takes place across two dates: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/?promo=startupbootcamppost">April 1 &#8211; 2</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/?promo=startupbootcamppost">July 8 &#8211; 9</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Unlike other TechCrunch events, there is no &#8216;main stage.&#8217; Each session is designed to tackle one of the many core competencies any startup needs to be successful. But this isn&#8217;t just about listening — every session includes plenty of time built in for audience Q&amp;A. Essentially, it&#8217;s all breakout sessions, all day.</p>
<p>Our incredible speakers, who range from Zoom CRO Ryan Azus (&#8216;How to build a sales team&#8217;) to Calendly founder Tope Awotona (&#8216;How to bootstrap&#8217;) to Kleiner Perkins&#8217; Bucky Moore (&#8216;How to prep for Series A fundraising&#8217;), are making themselves available to answer your burning questions, on just about any topic.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more — everyone who buys a ticket to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/?promo=startupbootcamppost">TC Early Stage</a> gets free access to Extra Crunch! Folks who buy a ticket to one of the two events get three months free, and folks who purchase a combination ticket (to both events) get six months free! An Extra Crunch membership includes:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/extracrunch/investor-surveys/">Weekly investor surveys</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/extracrunch/fundraising/">Fundraising, growth, monetization, and workforce advice from startup experts</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/extracrunch/market-analysis/">Market analysis </a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/12/patreon-ec-1/">Late-deep dives</a></li>
<li>Access to weekly <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">Extra Crunch Live events</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/extra-crunch-partner-perks/">EC Perks Program</a> (save big $$$ on services and products you already use)</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/the-techcrunch-list/">The TechCrunch List</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Of course, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/?promo=startupbootcamppost&amp;display=true">TC Early Stage</a> dual event ticket holders will get access to both events (April 1 &#8211; 2 and July 8 &#8211; 9) and have access to all the content that comes out of the event on demand.</p>
<p>Mercenary CEOs know all too well that this is about the most bang you can get for your buck. Period.</p>
<p>Still on the fence? Take a look at a preview of some of the sessions at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/?promo=startupbootcamppost">TC Early Stage 2021</a>:</p>
<h3>Fundraising</h3>
<ul>
<li>Bootstrapping Best Practices (Tope Awotona and Blake Bartlett, Calendly)</li>
<li>Four Things to Think About Before Raising a Series A (Bucky Moore, Kleiner Perkins)</li>
<li>How to Get An Investor’s Attention (Marlon Nichols, MacVenture Partners)</li>
<li>How to Nail Your Virtual Pitch Meeting (Melissa Bradley, Ureeka)</li>
<li>How Founders Can Think Like a VC (Lisa Wu, Norwest Venture Partners)</li>
<li>The All-22 View, or Never Losing Perspective (Eghosa Omoigui, EchoVC Partners)</li>
</ul>
<h3>Operations:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Finance for Founders (Alexa von Tobel, Inspired Capital)</li>
<li>Building and Leading a Sales Team (Ryan Azus, Zoom CRO)</li>
<li>10 Things NOT to Do When Starting a Company (Leah Solivan, Fuel Capital)</li>
<li>Leadership Culture and Good Governance (David Easton, Generation Investment Management)</li>
</ul>
<h3>Marketing:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Keys to Nailing Product Market Fit (Rahul Vohra, Superhuman)</li>
<li>How to Build Your Early Team for Future Growth (Sarah Smith, Bain Capital Ventures)</li>
<li>How to Get Into an Accelerator (Neal Sales-Griffin, TechStars)</li>
<li>Finding Your Product Market Fit (Sean Lane, OliveAI)</li>
<li>How To Use Coaches To Your Advantage (Ted Wang, Cowboy VC)</li>
</ul>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-dde292b93a5f3017145419dd51bb9fce'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117860</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Has a startup finally found one of food science&#8217;s holy grails with its healthy sugar substitute?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/has-a-startup-finally-found-one-of-food-sciences-holy-grails-with-its-healthy-sugar-substitute/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/has-a-startup-finally-found-one-of-food-sciences-holy-grails-with-its-healthy-sugar-substitute/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 14:50:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aydin Senkut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cambridge university]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chef]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chemicals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colorado]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer products]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[douxmatok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Felicis Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food and Drug Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food ingredient]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impossible foods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managing partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soma capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sugar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taiwan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital Financing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wisconsin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117843</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A little less than three years ago at the Computer Science Museum in Mountain View, Calif. the founders of a young company hailing from Cambridge, England addressed a crowd of celebrities, investors and entrepreneurs at Y Combinator&#8217;s August Demo Day promising a revolution in food science. Over the years, the event has become a relatively [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A little less than three years ago at the Computer Science Museum in Mountain View, Calif. the founders of a young company hailing from Cambridge, England addressed a crowd of celebrities, investors and entrepreneurs at Y Combinator&#8217;s August Demo Day promising a revolution in food science.</p>
<p>Over the years, the event has become a relatively low-tech, low-budget showcase for a group of tech investors and billionaire industry insiders to take a look at early stage businesses that could be their next billion-dollar opportunity.</p>
<p>Sharing the stage with other innovation-minded budding entrepreneurs the Cambridge scientists boasted of a technology could produce a sweetener that would mimic not just the taste of sugar, but the caramelization and stickiness that makes sugar the go-to additive for the bulk of roughly 74% of packaged foods that are made with some form of sweetener.<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/21/yc-summer-2018-demo-day-1-picks/"> Their company, Cambridge Glycoscience </a> could claim a huge slice of a market worth at least a $100 billion market, they said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Now, the company has a new name, Supplant, and $24 million in venture capital financing to start commercializing its low-cost sugar substitute made from the waste materials of other plants.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yGrgeuySga"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/21/yc-summer-2018-demo-day-1-picks/">10 startups that caught our eye from day 1 of YC Demo Day S18</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;10 startups that caught our eye from day 1 of YC Demo Day S18&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/21/yc-summer-2018-demo-day-1-picks/embed/#?secret=yGrgeuySga" data-secret="yGrgeuySga" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>The bitter history of the sweetest ingredient</strong></p>
<p>Sugar came into the human diet roughly 10,000 years ago as sugarcane, which is native to New Guinea and parts of Taiwan and China. Over the next 2,000 years the crop spread from those regions to Madagascar and eventually took root in India, where it was first refined in about 500 BC.</p>
<p>From there, the sweetener spread across the known world. By the first century AD Greek and Roman scholars were referencing its medicinal properties and, after the Crusades, sugar consumption traveled across Europe through the Middle Ages.</p>
<p>It was a welcome replacement from Europe&#8217;s mainstay, honey, and the early artificial sweeteners used by the Romans, <a href="https://io9.gizmodo.com/the-first-artificial-sweetener-poisoned-lots-of-romans-5877587">which contained near-lethal doses of lead</a>.</p>
<p>The cold climates of Northern Europe proved mostly inhospitable to sugarcane cultivation so the root took root in the more temperate South and the islands off of Europe&#8217;s southern coast.</p>
<p>Those regions also became home to the first European experiments with agricultural slavery &#8212; a byproduct of the sugar trade, and one that would plant the seeds for the international exploitation of indigenous American and African labor for centuries as the industrial growth of sugar production spread to the New World.</p>
<p>First, European indentured servants and enslaved indigenous people&#8217;s powered the production of sugar in the Americas. But as native populations died off due to the introduction of European diseases, genocidal attacks, and back-breaking labor, African slaves were brought to the new colonies to work the fields and mills to make refined sugar.</p>
<p><b>Sugar hangover</b></p>
<p>The horrors of slavery may be the most damning legacy of industrial sugar, but it&#8217;s far from the only problem caused by the human craving for sweeteners.</p>
<p>As climate change becomes more of a threat, fears of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-brazil-environment-agriculture/brazil-cancels-decree-barring-sugarcane-cultivation-in-the-amazon-idUSKBN1XG311">increasing deforestation to meet the world&#8217;s demand &#8212; or to provide cover for other industrialization of virgin forests &#8212; have arisen</a> thanks to new policies in Brazil.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Conventional cane sugar is heavily heavily water intensive,&#8221; said Supplant co-founder Tom Simmons in an interview. That&#8217;s another problem for the environment as water becomes the next resource to be stressed by the currents of climate change. And species extinction presents another huge problem too.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8220;The WWF number one source for biodiversity lost globally is cane sugar plantations,&#8221; Simmons said. &#8220;Sugar is a massive consumer of water and in contrast, there&#8217;s big sustainability pitch for what we do.. the raw materials are products of the current agricultural industry.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>And the quest for sugar substitutes in the U.S. has come with related health costs as high fructose corn syrup has made its way into tons of American products. Invented in 1957, corn syrup is one of the most common sweeteners used to replace sugar &#8212; and one that&#8217;s thought to have incredibly disastrous effects on the health of consumers worldwide.</p>
<p>The use of corn syrup has been linked to <a href="https://www.healthline.com/nutrition/why-high-fructose-corn-syrup-is-bad#The-bottom-line-">an increasing prevalence of diabetes, obesity, and fatty liver disease</a>, in the world&#8217;s population.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2118308" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2118308" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2118308" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-519742134.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-519742134.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-519742134.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-519742134.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-519742134.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-519742134.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-519742134.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-519742134.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-519742134.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2118308" class="wp-caption-text">MELBOURNE, AUSTRALIA &#8211; APRIL 08: In this photo illustration, products containing high sugar levels are on display at a supermarket on April 8, 2016 in Melbourne , Australia. The World Health Organisation&#8217;s first global report on diabetes found that 422 million adults live with diabetes, mainly in developing countries. Australian diabetes experts are urging the Federal Government to consider imposing a sugar tax to tackle the growing problem. (Photo by Luis Ascui/Getty Images)</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Looking For A Healthier Substitute</strong></p>
<p>As Supplant and its investors look to take the crown as the reigning replacement for sugar, they join a long line of would-be occupants to sugar&#8217;s throne.</p>
<p>The first viable, non-toxic chemically derived sugar substitute was discovered in the late 18th century by a German chemist. Called saccharine it was popularized initially during sugar shortages caused by the first World War and gained traction during the health crazes of the sixties and seventies.</p>
<p>Saccharin, still available in pink Sweet n&#8217; Low packets and a host of products, was succeeded by aspartame (known commercially as Equal and present as the sugar substitute in beverages like Diet Coke), which was supplanted by sucralose (known as Splenda).</p>
<p>These chemically derived sweeteners have been the standard on the market for decades now, but with a growing push for natural &#8212; rather than chemical &#8212; substitutes for sugar and their failures to act as a replacement for all of the things that sugar can do as a food ingredient, the demand for a better sugar has never been higher.</p>
<p><strong>Supplanting the competition </strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Not everything that we back is going to change the world. This, at scale, does that.&#8221; said Aydin Senkut, the founder and managing partner of Felicis Ventures, the venture firm that&#8217;s one of Supplant&#8217;s biggest backers. </span></p>
<p>Part of what convinced Senkut is the fact that Supplant&#8217;s sweetener has already received preliminary approvals in the European Union by the region&#8217;s regulatory equivalent of the Food and Drug Administration. That approval not only covers the sale of Supplant&#8217;s product as a sweetener, but also as a probiotic with tangible health benefits he said.</p>
<p>So not only is the Supplant product arguably a better and more direct sugar replacement, as the founders claim, it also has health benefits through providing increased fiber in consumers who use it regularly, Senkut said.</p>
<p>&#8220;The European FDA is even stricter than the U.S. FDA,&#8221; Senkut said. &#8220;[And] they got pre-approval for this.&#8221;</p>
<p>Senkut and Felicis invested in Cambridge Glycosciences almost immediately after seeing the company&#8217;s presentation at Y Combinator.</p>
<p>&#8220;We became the largest investors at seed,&#8221; Senkut said.</p>
<p>Its selling points were the products extremely low glycemic index and its ability to be manufactured from waste plant fibers, which means that it ultimately can be produced at a lower cost, according to Senkut.</p>
<p><strong>What&#8217;s the difference? </strong></p>
<p>Supplant differs from its competition in a number of other key ways, according to company co-founder Tom Simmons.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">While companies like the Israeli startup <a href="https://www.douxmatok.com/">DouxMatok</a> or Colorado&#8217;s MycoTechnology and Wisconsin&#8217;s Sensient work on developing additives from fungus or tree roots or bark that can enhance the sweetness of sugars, Supplant uses alternative sugars to create its sweetener, Simmons said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;The core difference is they’re working with cane sugar,&#8221; according to Simmons. &#8220;Our pitch is we make sugars from fiber so you don’t need to use cane sugar.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Simmons said that these other startups have been approaching the problem from the wrong direction. &#8220;The problem that their technology addresses isn&#8217;t the problem the industry has,&#8221; Simmons said. &#8220;It&#8217;s about texture, bulking, caramelization and crystallization&#8230; We have a technology that&#8217;s going to give you the same sweetness gram for gram.&#8221;</p>
<p>There are six different types of calorific sugar, Simmons explained. There&#8217;s lactose, which is the sugar in milk; sucrose, which comes from sugarcane and sugar beets; maltose, found in grains like wheat and barley; fructose, the sugar in fruits and honey; glucose, which is in nearly everything, but especially carbohydrate-laden vegetables, fruits, and grains; and galactose, a simple sugar that derives from the breakdown of lactose.</p>
<p>Simmons said that his company&#8217;s sugar substitute isn&#8217;t based on one compound, but is derived from a range of things that come from fiber. The use of fibers means that the body recognizes the compounds as fibrous and treats them the same way in the digestive tract, but the products taste and act like sugar in food, he said. &#8220;Fiber derived sugars are in the category of sugars, but are not the calorific sugars,&#8221; said Simmons.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2118311" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2118311" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2118311" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-51829869.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="625" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-51829869.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-51829869.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-51829869.jpg?resize=300,183 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-51829869.jpg?resize=768,469 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-51829869.jpg?resize=680,415 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-51829869.jpg?resize=1536,937 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-51829869.jpg?resize=2048,1250 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-51829869.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2118311" class="wp-caption-text">NEW YORK &#8211; DECEMBER 6: Packets of the popular sugar substitute Splenda are seen December 6, 2004 in New York City. The manufacturer of sucralose, the key ingredient in the no-calorie sweetener, says demand is so high for the product that it will not be able to take on new U.S. customers until it doubles production in 2006. Splenda has been boosted by the popularity of the low-sugar Atkins diet. (Photo Illustration by Mario Tama/Getty Images)</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Trust the process? </strong></p>
<p>Supplant&#8217;s technology uses enzymes to break down and fragment various fibers. &#8220;As you start breaking it down, it starts looking molecularly like sucrose &#8212; like cane sugar &#8212; so it starts behaving in a similar way,&#8221; said Simmons.</p>
<p>This is all the result of years of research that Simmons began at Cambridge University, he said. &#8220;I arrived at Cambridge intending to be a professor. I did not arrive in Cambridge intending to start a business. I was interested in doing science, making inventions and stuff that would reach the wider world. I always imagined the right way for me to do that was to be a professor.&#8221;</p>
<p>In time, after receiving his doctorate and beginning his post-doctoral work into the research that would eventually turn into Supplant, Simmons realized that he had to start a company. &#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">To try and do something impactful I was going to have leave the university,&#8221; he said. </span></p>
<p>In some ways, Supplant operates at the intersection of all of Simmons&#8217; interests in health, nutrition, and sustainability. And he said the company has plans to apply the processing technology across a range of consumer products eventually, but for now the company remains focused on the $100 billion sugar substitute market.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;There’s a handful of different core underlying scientific approaches in different spaces,&#8221; he said. The sort of things that go into personal care and homecare. Those chemicals. A big drive in the industry is for both less harsh and harsh chemicals in shampoos but also to do so in a way that’s sustainable. That&#8217;s made form a sustainable source but also biodegradable.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><strong>Next steps </strong></p>
<p>With the money that the company has now raised from investors including Bonfire Ventures, Khosla Ventures, Felicis, Soma Capital, and Y Combinator, Supplant is now going to prove its products in a few very targeted test runs.* The first is a big launch with a celebrity chef, which Simmons teased, but did not elaborate on.</p>
<p>Senkut said that the company&#8217;s roll out would be similar to the ways in which Impossible Foods went to market. Beginning with a few trial runs in higher end restaurants and foodstuffs before trying to make a run at a mass consumer market.</p>
<p>The feedstocks for Supplant&#8217;s sugar substitute come from sugar cane bagasse, wheat and rice husks, and the processing equipment comes from the brewing industry. That&#8217;s going to be a benefit as the company looks to build out an office in the U.S. as it establishes a foothold for a larger manufacturing presence down the line.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re t<span style="font-weight: 400;">aking known science and applying it in the food industry where we know that it has value,&#8221; Simmons said. &#8220;We&#8217;re not inventing any brand new enzymes and each part of the process &#8212; none of it on their own are new. The discovery that these sugars work well and can replace cane sugar. That’s someone that no one has done before. Most sugars don’t behave like cane sugar in food. They’re too dry, they’re too wet, they’re too hard, they’re too soft.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Ultimately the consumer products mission resonates highly for Simmons and his twenty person team. &#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">We’re going to use these hugely abundant renewable resources produced all around the world,&#8221; he said. </span></p>
<p>*This story was updated to include Bonfire Ventures and Khosla Ventures as investors in Supplant.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/has-a-startup-finally-found-one-of-food-sciences-holy-grails-with-its-healthy-sugar-substitute/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117843</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brandwatch is acquired by Cision for $450M, creating a PR, marketing and social listening giant</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/brandwatch-is-acquired-by-cision-for-450m-creating-a-pr-marketing-and-social-listening-giant/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/brandwatch-is-acquired-by-cision-for-450m-creating-a-pr-marketing-and-social-listening-giant/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 12:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brandwatch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buzzsumo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crimson Hexagon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[executive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Highland Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Highland Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media monitoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nauta Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partech ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118247</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Online consumer intelligence and social media listening platform Brandwatch has been acquired by Cision, best known for its media monitoring and media contact database services, for $450 million, in a combined cash and shares deal. TechCrunch understands Brandwatch’s key executive team will be staying on. The move combines two large players to offer a broad [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Online consumer intelligence and social media listening platform <a href="http://Brandwatch.com">Brandwatch</a> has been acquired by <a href="http://Cision.com">Cision</a>, best known for its media monitoring and media contact database services, for $450 million, in a combined cash and shares deal. TechCrunch understands Brandwatch’s key executive team will be staying on. The move combines two large players to offer a broad range of services from PR to marketing and online customer engagement. The deal is expected to close in the second quarter of 2021.</p>
<p>Cision has a media contact database of approximately 1 million journalists and media outlets and claims to have over 75,000 customers. Brandwatch applies AI and machine learning the practice known as ‘social listening’.</p>
<p>Along the way, Brandwatch raised a total of around $65 million. It was Series A-funded by <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"><a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/nauta-capital">Nauta Capital</a>, </span>followed by <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/highland-capital-partners-europe">Highland Europe</a> and then <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/partech">Partech</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>IN a statement, Giles Palmer, founder, and CEO of Brandwatch said: “We have always built Brandwatch with ambition… Now is the time to take the next step – joining a company of significant scale to create a business and a suite of products that can have an important global impact.&#8221;</p>
<p>Abel Clark, CEO of Cision said: “The continued digital shift and widespread adoption of social media is rapidly and fundamentally changing how brands and organizations engage with their customers. This is driving the imperative that PR, marketing, social, and customer care teams fully incorporate the unique insights now available into consumer-led strategies. Together, Cision and Brandwatch will help our clients to more deeply understand, connect and engage with their customers at scale across every channel.”</p>
<p>Brandwatch has been on an almost case-study of a journey from fundraising to acquisition to a merger, but less characteristically for a well-funded tech company, it did much of it from its home-town of Brighton, on the southern coast of England.</p>
<p>The financing journey began for Giles Palmer, with Angel funding in 2006. In 2010 Brandwatch raised $1.5m from Durrants, a marketing and PR firm, and a Series A round from <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/nauta-capital">Nauta Capital</a>. In 2014 it raised $22 million in funding in a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/05/22/brandwatch-raises-22m-to-boost-its-social-media-monitoring-platform/">Series B round</a> led by Highland Europe. That was followed by a $33M <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/10/29/social-intelligence-startup-brandwatch-raises-33m-series-c-to-grow-in-us/">Series C financing</a> led by Partech Ventures in 2015.</p>
<p>With the war chest, it went on to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/10/social-media-monitor-brandwatch-acquires-content-marketing-platform-buzzsumo/">acquire</a> BuzzSumo in 2017, a content marketing and influencer identification platform, for an undisclosed sum. And in 2019 Brandwatch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/04/social-intelligence-platforms-brandwatch-and-crimson-hexagon-merge/">merged </a>with a similar business, Crimson Hexagon, creating a business with around $100 million in ARR. It also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/28/brandwatch-turns-its-war-chest-on-acquiring-market-research-startup-qriously/">acquired</a> the London-based SaaS research platform Qriously.</p>
<p>Brandwatch was recently <a href="https://www.brandwatch.com/p/forrester-2020-social-listening-wave/">named</a> a leader in Forrester’s guide for buyers of social listening solutions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/brandwatch-is-acquired-by-cision-for-450m-creating-a-pr-marketing-and-social-listening-giant/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118247</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>MyHeritage now lets you animate old family photos using deepfakery</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/myheritage-now-lets-you-animate-old-family-photos-using-deepfakery/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/myheritage-now-lets-you-animate-old-family-photos-using-deepfakery/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 12:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[D-ID]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deep nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deepfakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[myheritage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[synthesized media]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118238</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[AI-enabled synthetic media is being used as a tool for manipulating real emotions and capturing user data by genealogy service, MyHeritage, which has just launched a new feature &#8212; called &#8216;deep nostalgia&#8216; &#8212; that lets users upload a photo of a person (or several people) to see individual faces animated by algorithm. The Black Mirror-style [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">AI-enabled synthetic media is being used as a tool for manipulating real emotions and capturing user data by genealogy service, MyHeritage, which has just launched a new feature &#8212; called &#8216;<a href="https://www.myheritage.com/deep-nostalgia">deep nostalgia</a>&#8216; &#8212; that lets users upload a photo of a person (or several people) to see individual faces animated by algorithm.</p>
<p>The <em>Black Mirror</em>-style pull of seeing long lost relatives &#8212; or famous people from another era &#8212; brought to a synthetic approximation of life, eyes swivelling, faces tilting as if they&#8217;re wondering why they&#8217;re stuck inside this useless digital photo frame, has led to an inexorable <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">stream of social shares since it was unveiled yesterday at a family history conference&#8230; </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Rosalind Franklin brought to life with <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DeepNostalgia?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DeepNostalgia</a> <a href="https://t.co/DNQ3kzuf6h">pic.twitter.com/DNQ3kzuf6h</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&mdash; Dr Adam Rutherford (@AdamRutherford) <a href="https://twitter.com/AdamRutherford/status/1365251938053455877?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 26, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">My great great grandmother, Louisa Roakes (1871-1942), animated using the Deep Nostalgia tool on <a href="https://twitter.com/MyHeritage?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MyHeritage</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Genealogy?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Genealogy</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MyHeritage?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MyHeritage</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DeepNostalgia?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DeepNostalgia</a> <a href="https://t.co/mb9b9uQdwi">pic.twitter.com/mb9b9uQdwi</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Nathan Dylan Goodwin (@NathanDGoodwin) <a href="https://twitter.com/NathanDGoodwin/status/1364971638584979467?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 25, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">This is my great-grandmother, Kathleen. I’ve always felt so close to her even though she died when I was 2 years old. This <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DeepNostalgia?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DeepNostalgia</a> video brought tears to my eyes to see her move, almost like seeing her as she was posing for this photo. Remarkable! <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/RootsTechConnect?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#RootsTechConnect</a> <a href="https://t.co/ZRc41JOo3e">pic.twitter.com/ZRc41JOo3e</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Mike Quackenbush (@mikequack) <a href="https://twitter.com/mikequack/status/1365132002735714313?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 26, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">MyHeritage&#8217;s AI-powered viral marketing playbook with this deepfakery isn&#8217;t a complicated one: They&#8217;re going straight for tugging on your heart strings to grab data which can be used to drive sign ups for their other (paid) services. (Selling DNA tests is their main business.)</span></p>
<p>It&#8217;s free to animate a photo using the &#8216;deep nostalgia&#8217; tech on MyHeritage&#8217;s site but you don&#8217;t get to see the result until you hand over at least an email (along with the photos you want animating, ofc) &#8212; and agree to its T&amp;Cs and privacy policy. Both of which have attracted a number of concerns, over the years.</p>
<p>Last year, for example, the <a href="https://www.forbrukerradet.no/side/the-norwegian-consumer-council-reports-myheritage-for-unlawful-terms-and-conditions/">Norwegian Consumer Council</a> reported MyHeritage to the national consumer protection and data authorities after a legal assessment of the T&amp;Cs found the contract it asks customers to sign to be &#8220;incomprehensible&#8221;.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/05/myheritage-breach-exposes-92m-emails-and-hashed-passwords/">2018</a> MyHeritage also suffered a major data breach &#8212; and data from that breach was later <a href="https://www.theregister.com/2019/02/11/620_million_hacked_accounts_dark_web/">found for sale</a> on the dark web, among a wider cache of hacked account info pertaining to several other services.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="od34v0fZ9U"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/05/myheritage-breach-exposes-92m-emails-and-hashed-passwords/">MyHeritage breach exposes 92M emails and hashed passwords</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;MyHeritage breach exposes 92M emails and hashed passwords&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/05/myheritage-breach-exposes-92m-emails-and-hashed-passwords/embed/#?secret=od34v0fZ9U" data-secret="od34v0fZ9U" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The company &#8212; which, as we reported <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/francisco-partners-is-acquiring-myheritage-sources-say-for-600m/">earlier this week</a>, is being acquired by a US private equity firm for ~$600M &#8212; is doubtless relying on the deep pull of nostalgia to smooth over any individual misgivings about handing over data and agreeing to its terms.</p>
<p>The face animation technology itself is impressive enough &#8212; if you set aside the ethics of encouraging people to drag their long lost relatives into the uncanny valley to help MyHeritage cross-sell DNA testing (with all the <a href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2020-12-08/man-in-the-window">massive privacy considerations</a> around putting that kind of data in the hands of a commercial entity).</p>
<p>Looking at the inquisitive face of my <a href="https://myhr.tg/1hZSY9gd">great grandmother</a> I do have to wonder what she would have made of all this?</p>
<p>The facial animation feature is powered by Israeli company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/26/d-id-the-israeli-company-that-digitally-de-identifies-faces-in-videos-and-still-images-raises-13-million/">D-ID</a>, a TechCrunch Disrupt battlefield alum &#8212; which started out building tech to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/22/d-id-nabs-4m-to-protect-images-from-being-read-by-facial-recognition-algorithms/">digitally de-identify faces</a> with an eye on protecting images and video from being identifiable by facial recognition algorithms.</p>
<p>It released a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NxJMzNR_i5w">demo video</a> of the newer, photo-animating technology last year. The tech uses a driver video to animate the photo &#8212; mapping facial features from the photo onto that base driver to create a &#8216;live portrait&#8217;, as D-ID calls it.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Live Portrait solution brings still photos to life. The photo is mapped and then animated by a driver video, causing the subject to move its head and facial features, mimicking the motions of the driver video,&#8221; D-ID said in a press release. &#8220;This technology can be implemented by historical organizations, museums, and educational programs to animate well-known figures.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s offering live portraits as part of a wider &#8216;AI Face&#8217; platform which will offer third parties access to other deep learning, computer vision and image processing technologies. D-ID bills the platform as a &#8216;one-stop shop&#8217; for syntheized video creation.</p>
<p>Other tools include a &#8216;face anonymization&#8217; feature which replaces one person&#8217;s face on video with another&#8217;s (such as for documentary film makers to protect a whistleblower&#8217;s identity); and a &#8216;talking heads&#8217; feature that can be used for lip syncing or to replace the need to pay actors to appear in content such as marketing videos as it can turn an audio track into a video of a person appearing to speak those words.</p>
<p>The age of synthesized media is going to be a weird one, that&#8217;s for sure.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ejiMuBZIkM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/17/deepfake-video-app-reface-is-just-getting-started-on-shapeshifting-selfie-culture/">Deepfake video app Reface is just getting started on shapeshifting selfie culture</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Deepfake video app Reface is just getting started on shapeshifting selfie culture&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/17/deepfake-video-app-reface-is-just-getting-started-on-shapeshifting-selfie-culture/embed/#?secret=ejiMuBZIkM" data-secret="ejiMuBZIkM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rmjsgpQCuv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/14/sentinel-loads-up-with-1-35m-in-the-deepfake-detection-arms-race/">Sentinel loads up with $1.35M in the deepfake detection arms race</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Sentinel loads up with $1.35M in the deepfake detection arms race&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/14/sentinel-loads-up-with-1-35m-in-the-deepfake-detection-arms-race/embed/#?secret=rmjsgpQCuv" data-secret="rmjsgpQCuv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/myheritage-now-lets-you-animate-old-family-photos-using-deepfakery/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118238</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to land startup funding from real estate giant Brookfield, which manages $600 billion in assets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/how-to-land-startup-funding-from-brookfield-asset-management-which-manages-600-billion-in-assets/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/how-to-land-startup-funding-from-brookfield-asset-management-which-manages-600-billion-in-assets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 08:54:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118207</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are big investment firms, and then there are big investment firms. Brookfield Asset Management, the Toronto-based,122-year-old outfit whose current market cap is $63 billion and that oversees $600 billion in assets, clearly falls into the latter camp. Think real estate, infrastructure, renewable power, private equity, and credit. If it falls into a defined asset [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There are big investment firms, and then there are big investment firms. <a href="https://www.brookfield.com/">Brookfield Asset Management</a>, the Toronto-based,122-year-old outfit whose current market cap is $63 billion and that oversees $600 billion in assets, clearly falls into the latter camp. Think real estate, infrastructure, renewable power, private equity, and credit. If it falls into a defined asset class, Brookfield probably has it in its portfolio.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s also true of venture capital, though venture is new enough to Brookfield that founders who might like its capital are still getting the memo. Indeed, it was a little less than four years ago that Brookfield Technology Partners began investing off the company&#8217;s balance sheet and soon after recruited Josh Raffaelli &#8212; a Stanford MBA who cut his teeth as a principal with Draper Fisher Jurvetson, then spent another five years with Silver Lake &#8212; to lead the practice.</p>
<p>Its existence came as a surprise to him, actually. &#8220;I&#8217;ve been a tech investor in Silicon Valley,&#8221; says Raffaelli. &#8220;My entire professional career has been in a 15-minute drive from the house I grew up in. And I had never heard about Brookfield before they started this practice because it&#8217;s in businesses. It&#8217;s in real estate. It has done things that are not generally tech-enabled.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Not until fairly recently, that is. Raffaelli and his 11-person team have not only made dozens of bets since then, but they’re currently investing out of a pool of capital that features third party capital in addition to that of Brookfield — which is a first. As for what they are looking for, the idea is help Brookfield reimagine how its many office towers, malls and other real estate might be used or developed or leased or insured. It’s to make Brookfield smarter, better prepared, and more profitable. In return, the startups get industry expertise &#8212; and a major customer in Brookfield.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qlP6vCjajt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/renewable-investment-wave-continues-as-solar-lending-company-loanpal-raises-800-million/">Renewable investment wave continues as solar lending company Loanpal raises $800 million</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Renewable investment wave continues as solar lending company Loanpal raises $800 million&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/renewable-investment-wave-continues-as-solar-lending-company-loanpal-raises-800-million/embed/#?secret=qlP6vCjajt" data-secret="qlP6vCjajt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>To date, its bets have varied widely, as with <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.crn.com/news/security/iot-security-startup-armis-doubles-valuation-to-2b-with-125m-round">Armis</a>, an IoT startup focused on unmanaged device security; <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/renewable-investment-wave-continues-as-solar-lending-company-loanpal-raises-800-million/">Loanpal</a>, a point-of-sale payment platform for solar and other home efficiency products; and <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/carbon-health-raises-100-million-with-plans-to-expand-pop-up-clinics-ahead-of-covid-19-vaccination-programs/">Carbon Health</a>, a primary care company that blends real-world and virtual visits. &#8220;&#8221;We&#8217;re getting our themes effectively from the Brookfield ecosystem,&#8221; Raffaelli says.</p>
<p>Pulling back the curtain a bit more, Raffaelli says his team writes checks from $25 million to $50 million dollars and that they look for companies with $10 million in revenue that are seeing top-line year-over-year growth of more than 100%. In terms of pacing, they jump into roughly one new deal per quarter.</p>
<p>The fund is also independent and has its own custom committee, but that the committee is made up of the senior managing partners from each line of Brookfield&#8217;s businesses. (&#8220;These are the people that actually help us translate our investment themes that we&#8217;re generating here,&#8221; Raffaelli notes.)</p>
<p>To highlight how the operation works, Raffaelli points to <a href="https://www.latch.com/">Latch</a>, a smart access software business that announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/smart-lock-maker-latch-teams-with-real-estate-firm-to-go-public-via-spac/">last month</a> that it&#8217;s using a blank-check company backed by the real estate giant Tishman Speyer to become publicly traded. Brookfield owns roughly 70,000 multifamily units in North America, &#8220;so we have a lot of doors that need a lot of locks,&#8221; Raffaelli says. Latch, of course, is not the only smart access lock out there, so Brookfield ran &#8220;what was almost like a mini [proposal process], reaching out to all different companies in the market to understand how they compete,&#8221; he says.</p>
<p>It was a &#8220;six-month exercise,&#8221; but ultimately, his group led Latch&#8217;s Series B round in 2018 and since then, Brookfield was bought about 7,000 blocks from the business. It&#8217;s a meaningful difference, considering that when Brookfield first invested, the company had less than $20 million in bookings and those 7,000 locks have since brought in an additional $10 million to $15 million in revenue, Raffaelli says. &#8220;When we buy a lot of things at that stage of a company,&#8221; he adds, &#8220;we&#8217;re meaningfully enhancing their trajectory.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="biH9QGBgLo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/smart-lock-maker-latch-teams-with-real-estate-firm-to-go-public-via-spac/">Smart lock maker Latch teams with real estate firm to go public via SPAC</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Smart lock maker Latch teams with real estate firm to go public via SPAC&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/smart-lock-maker-latch-teams-with-real-estate-firm-to-go-public-via-spac/embed/#?secret=biH9QGBgLo" data-secret="biH9QGBgLo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>It&#8217;s not a foolproof strategy, doubling down. If Latch&#8217;s locks turned out to be lemons (they haven&#8217;t), Brookfield would be out a big check along with that capital expenditure. It&#8217;s why Brookfield takes its time, says Raffaelli, adding that if he has done his job right, his team is involved with a company well before it is raising a round and shown already that it is a &#8220;strategic partner that has another lever.&#8221;</p>
<p>Either way, Raffaelli says that while the commercial real estate market has been hard hit by the pandemic, it has, counterintuitively, been a productive time for his group given the stronger incentive it has given the real estate world to adopt tech tools faster. Among the bets about which Raffaelli sounds most excited right now is <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.vts.com/">VTS</a>, for example, a leasing and asset management platform that can show properties remotely, and <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://deliverr.com/">Deliverr</a>, an e-commerce fulfillment startup that Raffaelli describes as &#8220;Amazon Prime for everybody else.&#8221;</p>
<p>In fact, Raffaelli convincingly argues that while the use case for a lot of real estate is changing,  the so-called built world remains Brookfield&#8217;s strongest competitive advantage given the size of its footprint.  The way he sees it, its options going forward are plentiful. &#8220;You&#8217;re looking at retail locations becoming ghost kitchens; you&#8217;re looking at retail locations turning into distribution and logistics facilities. We can turn physical locations into healthcare sites for [our portfolio company] Carbon Health, and our mall locations into locations for urgent care and primary care clinics for testing and vaccinations.&#8221;</p>
<p>It will never be a completely seamless transition. Brookfield has to be &#8220;thoughtful&#8221; given the pandemic and its devastating impacts, too. But Raffaelli comes across as excited in conversation nonetheless. The idea of turning physical real estate into a &#8220;mechanism for change within technology businesses,&#8221; adds Raffaelli, is a &#8220;very powerful place to be.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/how-to-land-startup-funding-from-brookfield-asset-management-which-manages-600-billion-in-assets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118207</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Singapore-based Raena gets $9M Series A for its pivot to skincare and beauty-focused social commerce</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/singapore-based-raena-gets-9m-series-a-for-its-pivot-to-skincare-and-beauty-focused-social-commerce/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/singapore-based-raena-gets-9m-series-a-for-its-pivot-to-skincare-and-beauty-focused-social-commerce/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 05:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malaysia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raena]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skincare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118217</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Raena was founded in 2019 to create personal care brands with top social media influencers. After several launches, however, the Singapore-based startup noticed an interesting trend: customers were ordering batches of products from Raena every week and reselling them on social media and e-commerce platforms like Shopee and Tokopedia. Last year, the company decided to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2118218" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/IMG_8363.jpeg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2118218" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2118218" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/IMG_8363.jpeg" alt="A photo of social commerce startup Raena’s team. From left to right: chief operating officer Guo Xing Lim, chief executive officer Sreejita Deb and chief commercial officer Widelia Liu" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/IMG_8363.jpeg 3088w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/IMG_8363.jpeg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/IMG_8363.jpeg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/IMG_8363.jpeg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/IMG_8363.jpeg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/IMG_8363.jpeg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/IMG_8363.jpeg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/IMG_8363.jpeg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2118218" class="wp-caption-text">Raena&#8217;s team, from left to right: chief operating officer Guo Xing Lim, chief executive officer Sreejita Deb and chief commercial officer Widelia Liu</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://raenabeauty.com/">Raena</a> was founded in 2019 to create personal care brands with top social media influencers. After several launches, however, the Singapore-based startup noticed an interesting trend: customers were ordering batches of products from Raena every week and reselling them on social media and e-commerce platforms like Shopee and Tokopedia. Last year, the company decided to focus on those sellers, and pivoted to social commerce.</p>
<p>Today Raena announced it has raised a Series A of $9 million, co-led by Alpha Wave Incubation and Alpha JWC Ventures, with participation from AC Ventures and returning investors Beenext, Beenos and Strive. Its last funding announcement was a $1.82 million seed round announced in July 2019.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oazPaFDkap"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/24/raena-raises-1-82-million-to-help-influencers-in-southeast-asia-launch-their-own-consumer-brands/">Raena raises $1.82 million to help influencers in Southeast Asia launch their own consumer brands</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Raena raises $1.82 million to help influencers in Southeast Asia launch their own consumer brands&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/24/raena-raises-1-82-million-to-help-influencers-in-southeast-asia-launch-their-own-consumer-brands/embed/#?secret=oazPaFDkap" data-secret="oazPaFDkap" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>After interviewing people who had set up online stores with products from Raena, the company&#8217;s team realized that sellers&#8217; earnings potential was capped because they were paying retail prices for their inventory.</p>
<p>They also saw that even though new C2C retail models, like social commerce, are gaining popularity, the beauty industry&#8217;s supply chain hasn&#8217;t kept up. Sellers usually need to order minimum quantities, which makes it harder for people to start their own businesses, Raena co-founder Sreejita Deb told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>&#8220;Basically, you have to block your capital upfront. It&#8217;s difficult for individual sellers or micro-enterpreneurs to work with the old supply chain and categories like beauty,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>Raena decided to pivot to serve those entrepreneurs. The company provides a catalog that includes mostly Japanese and Korean skincare and beauty brands. For those brands, Raena represents a way to enter new markets like Indonesia, which the startup estimates has $20 billion market opportunity.</p>
<p>Raena resellers, who are mostly women between 18 to 34-years-old in Indonesia and Malaysia, pick what items they want to feature on their social media accounts. Most use TikTok or Instagram for promotion, and set up online stores on Shopee or Tokopedia. But they don’t have to carry inventory. When somebody buys a product from a Raena reseller, the reseller orders it from Raena, which ships it directly to the customer.</p>
<p>This drop-shipping model means resellers make higher margins. Since they don&#8217;t have to buy their inventory, it also dramatically lowers the barrier to launching a small business. Even though Raena&#8217;s pivot to social commerce coincided with the COVID-19 pandemic, Deb said it grew its revenue 50 times between January and December 2020. The platform now has more than 1,500 resellers, and claims a 60% seller retention rate after six months on the platform.</p>
<p>She attributes Raena&#8217;s growth to several factors, including the increase in online shopping during lockdowns and people looking for ways to earn additional income during the pandemic. While forced to stay at home, people also <a href="https://theaseanpost.com/article/social-media-habits-during-pandemic">began spending more time online</a>, especially on the social media platforms that Raena resellers use.</p>
<p>Raena also benefited from its focus on skincare. Though many retail categories, including color cosmetics, took a hit, <a href="https://www.voguebusiness.com/beauty/the-beauty-trends-customers-are-buying-during-covid-19">skincare products proved resilient</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;We saw skincare had higher margins, and there are certain markets that are experts at formulating and producing skincare products, and demand for those products in other parts of the world,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’ve continued being a skincare company and because that is a category we had insight into, it was our first entry point into this social selling model as well. 90% of our sales are skincare,&#8221; Deb added. &#8220;Our top-selling products are serums, toners, essences, which makes a lot of sense because people are in their homes and have more time to dedicate to their skincare routines.&#8221;</p>
<p>Social commerce, which allows people to earn a side income (or even a full-time income), by leveraging their social media networks, has taken off in several Asian markets. In China, for example, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/pinduoduo-agritech/">Pinduoduo has become a formidable rival</a> to Alibaba through its group-selling model and focus on fresh produce. In India, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/11/meesho-india">Meesho resellers</a> sell products like clothing through social media platforms including WhatsApp, Facebook and Instagram.</p>
<p>Social commerce is also gaining traction in Southeast Asia, with gross merchandise value growing threefold during the first half of 2020, <a href="https://ikala.tv/news/social-commerce-surges-in-southeast-asia/">according to iKala</a>.</p>
<p>Deb said one of the ways Raena is different from other social commerce companies is that most of its resellers are selling to customers they don’t know, instead of family and friends. Many already had TikTok or Instagram profiles focused on beauty and skincare, and had developed reputations for being knowledgeable about products.</p>
<p>As Raena develops, it plans to hire a tech team to build tools that will simplify the process of managing orders and also strike deals directly with manufacturers to increase profit margins for resellers. The funding will be used to increase its team from 15 to over 100 over the next three months, and it plans to enter more Southeast Asian markets.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FhTJQtFdge"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/27/tiktok-invests-in-social-commerce-via-new-shopify-partnership/">TikTok partners with Shopify on social commerce</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok partners with Shopify on social commerce&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/27/tiktok-invests-in-social-commerce-via-new-shopify-partnership/embed/#?secret=FhTJQtFdge" data-secret="FhTJQtFdge" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/singapore-based-raena-gets-9m-series-a-for-its-pivot-to-skincare-and-beauty-focused-social-commerce/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118217</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tim Hortons marks two years in China with Tencent investment</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/tim-hortons-china-fundraising-tencent/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/tim-hortons-china-fundraising-tencent/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 02:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118208</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tim Hortons, the Canadian coffee and doughnut giant, has raised a new round of funding for its Chinese venture. The investment is led by Sequoia China with participation from Tencent, its digital partner in China, and Eastern Bell Capital. The round comes two years after Tim Hortons made its foray into China&#8217;s booming coffee industry. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tim Hortons, the Canadian coffee and doughnut giant, has raised a new round of funding for its Chinese venture. The investment is led by Sequoia China with participation from Tencent, its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/12/tim-hortons-eyes-china-coffee-drinkers-with-tencent-investment/">digital partner in China</a>, and Eastern Bell Capital. The round comes two years after Tim Hortons made its foray into China&#8217;s booming coffee industry.</p>
<p>Tim Hortons didn&#8217;t disclose the amount of its latest fundraise but noted in a <a href="https://weibo.com/6969784101/K3G7jvUI7?from=page_1006066969784101_profile&amp;wvr=6&amp;mod=weibotime">social media post</a> that the proceeds will be used for opening more stores, building its digital infrastructure, brand presence, and more.</p>
<p>Tencent, the Chinese social media and entertainment behemoth, first backed the 57-year-old Canadian coffee chain <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/12/tim-hortons-eyes-china-coffee-drinkers-with-tencent-investment/">last May</a>. At the time the tie-up was seen as Tencent&#8217;s move to counter archrival Alibaba&#8217;s alliance with Starbucks to deliver coffee and help the American coffee titan go digital in China.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Tim Horton&#8217;s collaboration with the WeChat parent is in a similar vein. It has so far accumulated three million members through its WeChat mini program, a type of lightweight app that runs within the instant messenger. To appeal to young Chinese consumers, Tim Hortons opened <a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s?__biz=MzU2MTM3NjE5Mg==&amp;mid=2247485088&amp;idx=1&amp;sn=21ce8625300c131ca23a8797a60a3f8d&amp;chksm=fc78f80fcb0f7119766b4e140910a421b2fcc18ea945190febfbdde5b0a2540ed23735eabf9c&amp;scene=21#wechat_redirect">an esports-themed cafe</a> with Tencent, China&#8217;s biggest gaming company.</p>
<p>Two years into operating in China, Tim Hortons says it has reached storefront-level profitability with a footprint of 150 locations across 10 major cities. It plans to add more than 200 locations in 2021 and reach 1,500 stores nationwide in the next few years.</p>
<p>The dramatic <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/17/chinas-luckin-coffee-raises-up-to-651m-in-upsized-us-ipo/">rise</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/following-multiple-scandals-including-luckin-coffee-nasdaq-ready-to-tighten-rules-on-ipo-listings/">fall</a> of coffee delivery startup Luckin brought the prospects of China&#8217;s coffee market to the forefront. Despite the investment frenzy around Luckin and other coffee businesses, coffee drinking still has a relatively low penetration in China compared to countries like the United States and Germany. On the other hand, coffee consumption is growing at a much faster rate of 15% in China, well above the global average of 2%, and is projected to reach 1 trillion yuan ($150 million) in 2025, according to a 2020 <a href="https://pdf.dfcfw.com/pdf/H3_AP202004021377475527_1.pdf?1585842837000.pdf">report</a> by Dongxing Securities.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Hp1AS71IwJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/12/tim-hortons-eyes-china-coffee-drinkers-with-tencent-investment/">Tim Hortons eyes China coffee drinkers with Tencent investment</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tim Hortons eyes China coffee drinkers with Tencent investment&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/12/tim-hortons-eyes-china-coffee-drinkers-with-tencent-investment/embed/#?secret=Hp1AS71IwJ" data-secret="Hp1AS71IwJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/tim-hortons-china-fundraising-tencent/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118208</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bessemer Venture Partners closes on $3.3 billion across two funds</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/bessemer-venture-partners-closes-on-3-3-billion-across-two-funds/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/bessemer-venture-partners-closes-on-3-3-billion-across-two-funds/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bessemer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bessemer Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BVP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary D'Onofrio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Droesch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pagerduty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Redwood City]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tess hatch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118171</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Another VC firm has closed on some significant funding for investments &#8212; underscoring both the long-term confidence investors continue to have for backing startups in the tech sector, and the amount of money swimming around in venture at the moment. Bessemer Venture Partners announced Thursday the close of two new funds totaling $3.3 billion, money [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Another VC firm has closed on some significant funding for investments &#8212; underscoring both the long-term confidence investors continue to have for backing startups in the tech sector, and the amount of money swimming around in venture at the moment.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bvp.com">Bessemer Venture Partners</a> announced Thursday the close of two new funds totaling $3.3 billion, money that it will be using to back early-stage startups as well as growth rounds for more mature companies.</p>
<p>The Redwood City-based firm closed BVP XI with $2.475 billion and BVP Century II with $825 million in total commitments.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>With BVP XI, Bessemer plans to focus on early-stage companies spanning enterprise, consumer, healthcare and frontier technologies. Its Century II fund, meanwhile, will be aimed at backing growth-stage companies that Bessemer said it believes “will define the next century,” and will include both follow-on rounds for existing portfolio companies and investments in new ones.</p>
<p>Despite being founded more than 100 years ago, Bessemer didn’t actually enter the venture business until 1965. It’s known for its investments in LinkedIn, Blue Apron and many others, with a current portfolio that includes PagerDuty, Shippo, Electric and DocuSign. Exits include Twitch and Shopify, among many others.</p>
<p>And like many VCs in the last year, it has continued to keep active in both backing existing companies in its portfolio as well as new ones, with a focus being startups that have found that not just the pandemic, but the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/02/diverse-startups-and-investors-matter/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">changing tides</a> of consumer and enterprise demands, have brought them surges of new business. Recent investments include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/folx-health-raises-25-million-for-virtual-clinical-offerings-and-care-for-the-lgbtqia-community/">Folx</a> (which focuses on health services for the LGBTQIA+ community); <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/getaccept-raises-20m-series-b-led-by-bessemer-to-expand-its-sales-platform-for-smbs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GetAccept</a> (sales for SMBs); <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/stackpulse-announces-28m-investment-to-help-developers-manage-outages/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackPulse</a> (for developers to manage outages); a big round for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/drivenets-nabs-208m-at-a-1b-valuation-for-its-cloud-based-alternative-to-network-routers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DriveNets</a> (cloud-based network router technology); <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/07/mambu-raises-135m-at-a-2b-valuation-for-an-saas-platform-that-powers-banking-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mambu</a> (one of the leaders in the world of SaaS that powers fintech services at the back end); just earlier this week <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/electric-raises-40m-series-c-to-put-small-business-it-in-the-cloud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Electric</a> (cloud-based IT services for SMBs); a big round for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/sila-nanotechnologies-raises-590m-to-fund-battery-materials-factory/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sila Nano</a> (cutting edge battery materials technology) and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/stuffthatworks-nabs-9m-for-crowdsourced-insights-on-health-conditions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StuffThatWorks</a>.</p>
<p>Interestingly, last year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/25/the-highest-valued-company-in-bessemers-annual-cloud-report-has-defied-convention-by-staying-private/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BVP highlighted Stripe</a> as the top company in its annual cloud report. It doesn&#8217;t invest currently in it, but could that be a signal of something in the works? (Stripe <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jeffkauflin/2021/02/17/investors-are-now-valuing-stripe-at-115-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reportedly</a> is currently raising $100 million.)</p>
<p>With more money than ever before available for backing startups, the challenge now for VCs is to see how and if they can find (and invest in) whatever will define the next generation of tech, in competition with an ever-wider field of investors with deep pockets. Some of those firms are bringing more than just money to the table &#8212; they&#8217;re bringing ideals and ideas &#8212; and some of them are being spawned as talent leaks from the bigger firms.</p>
<p>Bessemer is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/2114967/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">not a stranger</a> to those trends and so is carving out a place for itself and what it can bring &#8212; not just money, but its eye for success, its reputation and the networking that this brings, and its time and commitment.</p>
<p>&#8220;As venture capitalists, we pay too much attention to pattern recognition and matching when in reality, the biggest opportunities exist where those patterns break,” the firm wrote in a<a href="https://www.bvp.com/news/backing-entrepreneurs-with-3-3b-in-new-funds"> blog post </a>today.</p>
<p>“Our job is to make perceptive bets on the future, especially those that others will dismiss and ridicule. We are fundamental optimists and strong believers in the power of innovation; our life’s work is putting our reputation, time, and money to help entrepreneurs realize a different future. They’re the ones pioneering something entirely new and obscure &#8212; a technology, a business model, a category.&#8221;</p>
<p>In addition to announcing the new funds, Bessemer also revealed today that it’s brought on five new partners, including<a href="https://www.bvp.com/team/jeff-blackburn/"> Jeff Blackburn</a>, who joins after a 22-year career at Amazon, alongside the promotion of existing investors <a href="https://www.bvp.com/team/mary-donofrio/">Mary D&#8217;Onofrio</a>, <a href="https://www.bvp.com/team/mike-droesch">Mike Droesch</a>, <a href="https://www.bvp.com/team/tess-hatch">Tess Hatch</a> and <a href="https://www.bvp.com/team/andrew-hedin">Andrew Hedin</a>.</p>
<p>Most recently at Amazon, Blackburn served as senior vice president of worldwide business development, where he oversaw dozens of Amazon’s minority investments and more than 100 acquisitions across all business lines &#8212; including retail, Kindle, Echo, Alexa, FireTV, advertising, music, streaming audio &amp; video and Amazon Web Services.</p>
<p>“Having been part of Amazon for more than two decades, I’m excited to begin a new chapter helping customer-focused founders build breakthrough companies,” said Blackburn in a written statement. &#8220;I’ve known the Bessemer team for many years and have long admired their strategic vision and success backing early-stage ventures.&#8221;</p>
<p>With the latest changes, Bessemer now has 21 partners and more than 45 investors, advisors and platform “team members” located in Silicon Valley, San Francisco, Seattle, New York, Boston, London, Tel Aviv, Bangalore and Beijing.</p>
<p>“At Bessemer, there’s no corner office or consensus; every partner has the choice, independently, to pen a check. This kind of accountability and autonomy means a founder is teaming up with a partner and board director who thoroughly understands your business and can respond quickly and decisively,” the firm’s blog post states.</p>
<p>Bessemer&#8217;s task is all the more difficult because there is more competition than ever before to get into the best deals.</p>
<p>TCV closed on a record $4 billion fund to invest in e-commerce, fintech, edtech, travel and more <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/tcv-closes-record-4b-fund-to-invest-in-e-commerce-fintech-edtech-travel-and-more/">in late January</a>.</p>
<p>Last November, Andreessen Horowitz (a16z) <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/a16z-is-now-managing-16-5-billion-after-announcing-two-new-funds/">closed a pair of funds</a> totaling $4.5 billion. The firm raised $1.3 billion for an early-stage fund focused on consumer, enterprise and fintech, and closed a $3.2 billion growth-stage fund for later-stage investments.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CtpWqBFMCb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/a16z-is-now-managing-16-5-billion-after-announcing-two-new-funds/">A16z is now managing $16.5 billion, after announcing two new funds</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A16z is now managing $16.5 billion, after announcing two new funds&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/a16z-is-now-managing-16-5-billion-after-announcing-two-new-funds/embed/#?secret=CtpWqBFMCb" data-secret="CtpWqBFMCb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>And, last April, <a href="http://insightpartners.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Insight</a>, the firm that has backed the likes of Twitter and Shopify and invests across a range of consumer and enterprise startups, announced it had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/03/insight-closes-9-5b-fund-to-help-support-portfolio-companies-through-the-pandemic-crunch/">closed a fund of $9.5 billion</a>, money it said it would be using to support startups and “scale-ups” (larger and older startups that are still private) in the coming months.</p>
<p>BVP XI marks Bessemer’s largest fund in its 110-year history. Its last fund was closed in October 2018, when the firm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/25/bessemer-venture-partners-has-a-brand-new-1-85b-fund/">brought in $1.85 billion</a> for its tenth flagship VC fund. This latest fund is Bessemer&#8217;s fifth consecutive to exceed $1 billion, based on <a href="https://pitchbook.com/profiles/investor/10134-73">PitchBook</a> data.</p>
<p>Although BVP is one of the older firms in the valley, there has been a new wave of investors, some like SoftBank with very deep pockets, and others will less money but a lot of credibility, so it will be interesting to see how these next two funds play out for the firm.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/bessemer-venture-partners-closes-on-3-3-billion-across-two-funds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118171</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Newsela, the replacement for textbooks, raises $100M and becomes a unicorn</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/newsela-the-replacement-for-textbooks-raises-100m-and-becomes-a-unicorn/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/newsela-the-replacement-for-textbooks-raises-100m-and-becomes-a-unicorn/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 23:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Franklin Templeton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Newsela]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[textbook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118157</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Newsela, a SaaS platform for K-12 instructional material backed by the likes of TCV, Kleiner Perkins, Reach Capital and Owl Ventures, announced today that it has raised $100 million in a Series D round. The financing was led by new investor Franklin Templeton, and brings Newsela’s valuation to $1 billion. The new round is larger [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Newsela, a SaaS platform for K-12 instructional material backed <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/newsela/company_financials">by the likes</a> of TCV, Kleiner Perkins, Reach Capital and Owl Ventures, announced today that it has raised $100 million in a Series D round. The financing was led by new investor Franklin Templeton, and brings Newsela’s valuation to $1 billion. The new round is larger than the aggregate of Newsela’s prior capital raised to date.</p>
<p>“Hitting $1 billion [in valuation] doesn’t change a thing,” Newsela CEO Matthew Gross told TechCrunch. But the startup is joining Quizlet, ApplyBoard and CourseHero as companies within the sector that have hit the unicorn mark as remote education <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/21/edtech-startups-flirt-with-unicorn-style-growth/">continues to gain traction. </a></p>
<p>Newsela has created a platform that strings together a number of different third-party content, such as primary source documents or the latest National Geographic articles. Gross defines it as “material that isn’t purpose-built for education, [but] purpose-built for being interesting and informative.” If Newsela is doing its job right, the content can replace textbooks within a classroom altogether, while helping teachers give fresh, personalized material.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Textbooks are dead in classrooms, but are well-and-live in district purchasing,” Gross said. The startup is on a mission to distribute its product better, and the money will be used to get it into more classrooms. Part of this, Gross explains, is telling teachers what else it can provide along with textbooks. Analytics has become a big part of Newsela’s business, as remote learning hurts student engagement.</p>
<p>The startup’s paid product is between $6 to $14 per student, which contrasts with textbooks that can cost a school $20 to $40 per student “even on an annualized basis.”</p>
<p>Like other edtech companies, Newsela offered its product for free in the beginning of the pandemic, which gave it a healthy bump of new users.</p>
<p>Newsela estimates that gross bookings have grown 115% over the pandemic, and that revenue grew 81%. It declined to share revenue numbers or if it has hit profitability. There will be more than 11 million students using Newsela licensing by the end of 2021, Gross said.</p>
<p>Newsela estimates that two-thirds of public schools in the United States are using their platform, likely aided by school district <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/edtech-startups-find-demand-from-an-unlikely-customer-public-schools/">flexibility that has grown amid the pandemic.</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lICixWNy0g"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/12-investors-say-lifelong-learning-is-taking-edtech-mainstream/">13 investors say lifelong learning is taking edtech mainstream</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;13 investors say lifelong learning is taking edtech mainstream&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/12-investors-say-lifelong-learning-is-taking-edtech-mainstream/embed/#?secret=lICixWNy0g" data-secret="lICixWNy0g" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/newsela-the-replacement-for-textbooks-raises-100m-and-becomes-a-unicorn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118157</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Twitter announces &#8216;Super Follow&#8217; subscriptions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/daily-crunch-twitter-announces-super-follow-subscriptions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/daily-crunch-twitter-announces-super-follow-subscriptions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 23:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118148</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter reveals its move into paid subscriptions, Australia passes its media bargaining law and Coinbase files its S-1. This is your Daily Crunch for February 25, 2021. The big story: Twitter announces &#8216;Super Follow&#8217; subscriptions Twitter announced its first paid product at an investor event today, showing off screenshots of a feature that will allow [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter reveals its move into paid subscriptions, Australia passes its media bargaining law and Coinbase files its S-1. This is your Daily Crunch for February 25, 2021.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: Twitter announces &#8216;Super Follow&#8217; subscriptions</strong></p>
<p>Twitter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/twitters-super-follow-creator-subscription-takes-shots-at-substack-and-patreon/">announced its first paid product</a> at an investor event today, showing off screenshots of a feature that will allow users to subscribe to their favorite creators in exchange for things like exclusive content, subscriber-only newsletters and a supporter badge.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company also announced a feature called Communities, which could compete with Facebook Groups and enable Super Follow networks to interact, plus a Safety Mode for auto-blocking and muting abusive accounts. On top of all that, Twitter said it plans to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/twitter-plans-to-double-revenue-by-2023-reach-315m-daily-users/">double revenue by 2023</a>.</p>
<p>Not announced: launch dates for any of these features.</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/after-facebooks-news-flex-australia-passes-bargaining-code-for-platforms-and-publishers/">After Facebook’s news flex, Australia passes bargaining code for platforms and publishers</a> — This requires platform giants like Facebook and Google to negotiate to remunerate local news publishers for their content.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/facebook-good-ideas-campaign/">New Facebook ad campaign extols the benefits of personalized ads</a> — The sentiments are similar to a campaign that Facebook launched last year in opposition to Apple’s upcoming App Tracking Transparency feature.</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/sergey-brins-airship-will-use-worlds-biggest-mobile-hydrogen-fuel-cell/">Sergey Brin’s airship aims to use world’s biggest mobile hydrogen fuel cell</a> — The Google co-founder&#8217;s secretive airship company LTA Research and Exploration is planning to power a huge disaster relief airship with an equally record-breaking hydrogen fuel cell.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/coinbase-files-to-go-public-in-a-key-listing-for-the-cryptocurrency-category/">Coinbase files to go public in a key listing for the cryptocurrency category</a> — Coinbase’s financials show a company that grew rapidly from 2019 to 2020 while also crossing the threshold into unadjusted profitability.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/boosted-by-the-pandemic-meeting-transcription-service-otter-ai-raises-50m/">Boosted by the pandemic, meeting transcription service Otter.ai raises $50M</a> — With convenient timing, Otter.ai added Zoom integration back in April 2020.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/digitaloceans-ipo-filing-shows-a-two-class-cloud-market/">DigitalOcean’s IPO filing shows a two-class cloud market</a> — The company intends to list on the New York Stock Exchange under the ticker symbol “DOCN.”</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/pilot-ceo-waseem-daher-tears-down-his-companys-60m-series-c-pitch-deck/">Pilot CEO Waseem Daher tears down his company’s $60M Series C pitch deck</a> — For founders aiming to entice investors, the pitch deck remains the best way to communicate their startup’s progress and potential.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/five-takeaways-from-coinbases-s-1/">Five takeaways from Coinbase’s S-1</a> — We dig into Coinbase’s user numbers, its asset mix, its growing subscription incomes, its competitive landscape and who owns what in the company.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/paramount-will-cost-4-99-per-month-with-ads/">Paramount+ will cost $4.99 per month with ads</a> — The new streaming service launches on March 4.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/register-for-tc-sessions-justice-for-a-conversation-on-diversity-equity-and-inclusion-in-the-startup-world/">Register for TC Sessions: Justice for a conversation on diversity, equity and inclusion in the startup world</a> — This is just one week away!</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/daily-crunch-twitter-announces-super-follow-subscriptions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118148</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AT&#038;T is turning DirecTV into a standalone company</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/att-is-turning-directv-into-a-standalone-company/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/att-is-turning-directv-into-a-standalone-company/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 23:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AT&T]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DirecTV]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118136</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[AT&#38;T just announced an agreement with private equity firm TPG that will turn DirecTV into a standalone company, albeit one that&#8217;s still majority owned by the telecom giant. Specifically, AT&#38;T says it will own 70% of the new company, while TPG owns 30%. This transaction values DirecTV at $16.25 billion — a dramatic decline from [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">AT&amp;T just <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210225006201/en/ATT-TPG-to-Form-New-Entity-to-Operate-ATT’s-U.S.-Video-Unit">announced an agreement</a> with private equity firm TPG that will turn DirecTV into a standalone company, albeit one that&#8217;s still majority owned by the telecom giant.</p>
<p>Specifically, AT&amp;T says it will own 70% of the new company, while TPG owns 30%. This transaction values DirecTV at $16.25 billion — a dramatic decline from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/07/24/forty-eight-point-five-billion/">the $48.5 billion that AT&amp;T paid</a> to acquire the pay TV provider in 2015, part of a wave of telecom-media acquisitions. (Verizon owns TechCrunch thanks to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/06/23/verizon-completes-its-acquisition-of-aol-for-4-4b/">its acquisition of AOL</a>.)</p>
<p>Even with new offerings <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/13/directv-nows-rebranding-to-att-tv-now-is-officially-rolling-out/">like AT&amp;T TV</a> (which will be part of the standalone company, along with the DirecTV and U-Verse services), pay TV subscriptions have been declining, with AT&amp;T reporting a net loss of 617,000 premium video subscribers <a href="https://about.att.com/story/2021/q4_earnings_2020.html">in its most recent quarter</a>. AT&amp;T is trying to point out the positive trends in the numbers by noting that &#8220;it hit its peak level of subscriber losses in 2019&#8221; and that &#8220;premium video net losses had improved sequentially for five straight quarters.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Meanwhile, AT&amp;T made an even bigger acquisition <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/15/att-completes-its-acquisition-of-time-warner/">with Time Warner</a> (now known as WarnerMedia), and its TV ambitions seem to be focused on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/warner-bros-hbo-max-simultaneous-release/">the streaming service HBO Max</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;As the pay-TV industry continues to evolve, forming a new entity with TPG to operate the U.S. video business separately provides the flexibility and dedicated management focus needed to continue meeting the needs of a high-quality customer base and managing the business for profitability,&#8221; said AT&amp;T CEO John Stankey in a statement. &#8220;TPG is the right partner for this transaction and creating a new entity is the right way to structure and manage the video business for optimum value creation.”</p>
<p>The company said the transaction should close in the second half of 2021. The combined entity is expected to pay AT&amp;T $7.8 billion, which the telecom company will use to reduce debt. AT&amp;T also said that when the transaction closes, DirecTV&#8217;s CEO will be Bill Morrow, currently CEO of AT&amp;T’s U.S. video unit.</p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/at-t-again-exploring-a-deal-for-directv-11598645254">reported last year</a> that AT&amp;T was exploring a deal for DirecTV.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wrKCQYRi98"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/07/24/forty-eight-point-five-billion/">FCC Approves $48.5 Billion AT&amp;T-DirecTV Merger</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;FCC Approves $48.5 Billion AT&amp;T-DirecTV Merger&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2015/07/24/forty-eight-point-five-billion/embed/#?secret=wrKCQYRi98" data-secret="wrKCQYRi98" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/att-is-turning-directv-into-a-standalone-company/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118136</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Orca wants to give boating navigation its &#8216;iPhone moment&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/orca-wants-to-give-boating-navigation-its-iphone-moment/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/orca-wants-to-give-boating-navigation-its-iphone-moment/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 20:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116721</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Boating is a hobby steeped in history and tradition — and so is the industry and those that support it. With worldwide connectivity, electric boats, and other technological changes dragging the sector out of old habits, Orca aims to replace the outdated interfaces by which people navigate with a hardware-software combo as slick as any [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Boating is a hobby steeped in history and tradition — and so is the industry and those that support it. With worldwide connectivity, electric boats, and other technological changes dragging the sector out of old habits, <a href="https://getorca.com/">Orca</a> aims to replace the outdated interfaces by which people navigate with a hardware-software combo as slick as any other modern consumer tech.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re a boater, and I know at least some of you are, you&#8217;re probably familiar with two different ways of chart-plotting, or tracking your location and route: the one attached to your boat and the one in your pocket.</p>
<p>The one on your boat is clunky and old-fashioned, like the GPS interface on a years-old budget sedan. The one in your pocket is better and faster — but the phone isn&#8217;t exactly seaworthy and the app drains your battery with a quickness.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Orca is a Norwegian startup from veterans of the boating and chart-plotters that leapfrogs existing products with a built-from-scratch modern interface.</p>
<p>&#8220;The industry hasn&#8217;t changed in the last 20 years — you have three players who own 80 percent of the business,&#8221; said co-founder and CEO Jorge Sevillano. &#8220;For them, it&#8217;s very hard to think of how software creates value. All these devices are built on a user interface that&#8217;s 10-15 years old; think about a Tomtom, lots of menus, lots of clicks. This business hasn&#8217;t had its iPhone moment, where it had to rethink its entire design. So we thought: let&#8217;s start with a blank slate and build a new experience.&#8221;</p>
<p>CTO and co-founder Kristian Fallro started working on something like this years ago, and his company was acquired by Navico, one of the big players Sevillano refers to. But they didn&#8217;t seem to want to move forward with the ideas, and so he and the others formed Orca to pursue them. Their first complete product <a href="https://getorca.com/store">opened up for pre-orders</a> this week.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/xek34Bv8Vro?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>&#8220;The challenge up until now has been that you need a combination of hardware and software, so the barrier to entry was very, very high,&#8221; Fallro explained. &#8220;It&#8217;s a very protected industry — and it&#8217;s too small for Apple and Google and the big boys.&#8221;</p>
<p>But now with a combination of the right hardware and a totally rebuilt software stack, they think they can steal a march on the dominant companies and be ready for the inevitable new generation of boaters who can&#8217;t stand to use the old tech any more. Shuttling an SD card to and from the in-boat system and your computer to update charts? Inputting destinations via directional pad? Using a separate mobile app to check weather and tides that might bear on your route? Not exactly cutting edge.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/aRl56XRsX48?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>The Orca system comprises a ruggedized industrial tablet sourced from Samsung, an off the shelf marine quality mounting arm, a custom-designed interface for quick attachment and charging, and a computing base unit that connects to the boat&#8217;s own sensors like sonar and GPS over the NMEA 2000 protocol. It&#8217;s all made to be as good or better than anything you&#8217;d find on a boat today.</p>
<p>So far, so similar to many solutions out there. But Orca has rebuilt everything from the ground up as a modern mobile app with all the conveniences and connections you&#8217;d expect. Routing is instantaneous and accurate, on maps that are clear and readable as those on Google and Apple Maps but clearly still of the nautical variety. Weather and tide reports are integrated, as is marine traffic. It all runs on Android or iOS, so you can also use your phone, send routes or places of interest to the main unit, and vice versa.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2118039" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/orca-devices.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2118039" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2118039" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/orca-devices.jpg" alt="Several devices showing the Orca chart-plotting interface." width="1024" height="543" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/orca-devices.jpg 1871w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/orca-devices.jpg?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/orca-devices.jpg?resize=300,159 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/orca-devices.jpg?resize=768,407 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/orca-devices.jpg?resize=680,361 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/orca-devices.jpg?resize=1536,814 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/orca-devices.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2118039" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Orca</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;We can build new services that chart plotters can&#8217;t even dream of including,&#8221; said Sevillano. &#8220;With the latest tide report and wind, or if there&#8217;s a commercial ship going in your way, we can update your range and route. We do updates every week with new features and bug fixes. We can iterate and adapt to user feedback faster than anyone else.&#8221;</p>
<p>These improvements to the most central system of the boat mean the company has ambitions for coming years beyond simply replacing the ageing gadgets at the helm.</p>
<p>Information collected from the boat itself is also used to update the maps in near real time — depending on what your craft is monitoring, it could be used for alerting others or authorities, for example if you encounter major waves or dangerous levels of chemicals, or detect an obstacle where none is recorded. &#8220;The Waze of the seas,&#8221; they suggested. &#8220;Our goal is to become the marine data company. The opportunities for boaters, industries related to the sea, and society are immense.&#8221;</p>
<p>Being flexible about the placement and features means they hope to integrate directly with boats, becoming the built-in OS for new models. That&#8217;s especially important for the up-and-coming category of electric boats, which sort of by definition buck the old traditions and tend to attract tech-savvy early adopters.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Sh1OxFh7CF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/zin-boats-reinvents-the-electric-speedboat-in-a-bid-to-become-the-tesla-of-the-sea/">Zin Boats reinvents the electric speedboat in a bid to become the Tesla of the sea</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Zin Boats reinvents the electric speedboat in a bid to become the Tesla of the sea&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/zin-boats-reinvents-the-electric-speedboat-in-a-bid-to-become-the-tesla-of-the-sea/embed/#?secret=Sh1OxFh7CF" data-secret="Sh1OxFh7CF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re seeing people take what works on land taking it to sea. They all have the same challenge though, the biggest problem is range anxiety — and it&#8217;s even worse on the water,&#8221; said Fallro. &#8220;We&#8217;ve been talking to a lot of these manufacturers and we&#8217;re finding that building a boat is hard but building that navigation experience is even harder.&#8221;</p>
<p>Whether that&#8217;s entirely true probably depends on your boat-building expertise, but it&#8217;s certainly the case that figuring out an electric boat&#8217;s effective range is a devilishly difficult problem. Even after building a new boat from starting principles and advanced physical simulations to be efficient and predictable, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/zin-boats-reinvents-the-electric-speedboat-in-a-bid-to-become-the-tesla-of-the-sea/">such as Zin Boats did</a>, the laws of physics and how watercraft work mean even the best estimate has to be completely revised every few seconds.</p>
<p>&#8220;Figuring out range at sea is very hard, and we think we&#8217;re one of the best out there. So we want to provide boat manufacturers a software stack with integrated navigation that helps them solve the range anxiety problem their users have,&#8221; said Fallro.</p>
<p>Indeed, it seems likely that prospective purchasers of such a craft would be more tempted to close the deal if they knew there was a modern and responsive OS that not only accurately tracked range but provided easy, real-time access to potential charge points and other resources. Sure, you could use your phone — and many do these days because the old chart plotters attached to their boats are so limited. But the point is that with Orca you won&#8217;t be tempted to.</p>
<p>The full device combo of computing core, mount, and tablet costs €1,449, with the core alone selling for €449, with a considerable discount for early bird pre-orders. (For people buying new boats, these numbers may as well be rounding errors.)</p>
<p>Fallro said Orca is operating with funding (of an unspecified amount) from Atomico and Nordic VC firm Skyfall Ventures, as well as angel investors including Kahoot co-founder Johan Brand. The company has its work cut out for it simply in fulfilling the orders it has collected (they are doing a brisk trade, Fallro intimated) before moving on to adding features and updating regularly as promised.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ITfVoPsM2R"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/09/brunswick-and-sea-ray-debut-a-boat-loaded-with-futuristic-features-at-ces/">Brunswick and Sea Ray debut a boat loaded with futuristic features at CES</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Brunswick and Sea Ray debut a boat loaded with futuristic features at CES&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/09/brunswick-and-sea-ray-debut-a-boat-loaded-with-futuristic-features-at-ces/embed/#?secret=ITfVoPsM2R" data-secret="ITfVoPsM2R" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/orca-wants-to-give-boating-navigation-its-iphone-moment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116721</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DigitalOcean&#8217;s IPO filing shows a two-class cloud market</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/digitaloceans-ipo-filing-shows-a-two-class-cloud-market/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/digitaloceans-ipo-filing-shows-a-two-class-cloud-market/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 19:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure market share]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital ocean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digitalocean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117862</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning DigitalOcean, a provider of cloud computing services to SMBs, filed to go public. The company intends to list on the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) under the ticker symbol &#8220;DOCN.&#8221; DigitalOcean&#8217;s offering comes amidst a hot streak for tech IPOs, and valuations that are stretched by historical norms. The cloud hosting company was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/">DigitalOcean</a>, a provider of cloud computing services to SMBs, filed to go public. The company intends to list on the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) under the ticker symbol &#8220;DOCN.&#8221;</p>
<p>DigitalOcean&#8217;s offering comes amidst a hot streak for tech IPOs, and valuations that are stretched by historical norms. The cloud hosting company was joined by Coinbase in filing its numbers publicly today.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			DigitalOcean&#8217;s offering comes amidst a hot streak for tech IPOs.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>However, unlike the cryptocurrency exchange, DigitalOcean intends to raise capital through its offering. Its S-1 filing lists a $100 million placeholder number, a figure that will update when the company announces an IPO price range target.</p>
<p>This morning let&#8217;s explore the company&#8217;s financials briefly, and then ask ourselves what its results can tell us about the cloud market as a whole.</p>
<h2>DigitalOcean&#8217;s financial results</h2>
<p>TechCrunch has covered DigitalOcean with some frequency in recent years, including its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/17/digitalocean-layoffs/">early-2020 layoffs</a>, its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/20/digitalocean-raises-100m-in-debt-as-it-scales-towards-revenue-of-300m-profitability/">early-2020 $100 million debt raise </a>and its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/14/digitalocean-raises-50m-more-from-access-industries-and-a16z/">$50 million investment from May of the same year</a> that prior investors Access Industries and Andreessen Horowitz participated in.</p>
<p>From those pieces we knew that the company had reportedly reached $200 million in revenue during 2018, $250 million in 2019 and that DigitalOcean had expected to reach an annualized run rate of $300 million in 2020.</p>
<p>Those numbers held up well. Per <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1582961/000119312521055798/d898181ds1.htm">its S-1 filing</a>, DigitalOcean generated $203.1 million in 2018 revenue, $254.8 million in 2019 and $318.4 million in 2020. The company closed 2020 out with a self-calculated $357 million in annual run rate.</p>
<p>During its recent years of growth, DigitalOcean has managed to lose modestly increasing amounts of money, calculated using generally accepted accounting principles (GAAP), and non-GAAP profit (adjusted EBITDA) in rising quantities. Observe the rising disconnect:<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/digitaloceans-ipo-filing-shows-a-two-class-cloud-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117862</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto company Anchorage raises $80 million after getting federal banking charter</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/crypto-company-anchorage-raises-80-million-after-getting-federal-banking-charter/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/crypto-company-anchorage-raises-80-million-after-getting-federal-banking-charter/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 19:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anchorage]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118033</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Anchorage has raised an $80 million Series C funding round led by GIC, also known as Singapore’s sovereign wealth fund. Andreessen Horowitz, Blockchain Capital, Lux and Indico are also participating in today’s funding round. The thinking behind this funding round is quite simple. Some companies, such as Tesla or Square, have recently chosen to invest [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://anchorage.com">Anchorage</a> has raised an $80 million Series C funding round led by GIC, also known as Singapore’s sovereign wealth fund. Andreessen Horowitz, Blockchain Capital, Lux and Indico are also participating in today’s funding round.</p>
<p>The thinking behind this funding round is quite simple. Some companies, such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/tesla-buys-1-5b-in-bitcoin-may-accept-the-cryptocurrency-as-payment-in-the-future/">Tesla</a> or Square, have recently chosen to invest in cryptocurrencies. They’re converting a small portion of their cash balance into cryptocurrencies. Some investors choose to invest in companies that help you add cryptocurrencies to your cash balance — Anchorage is one of them.</p>
<p>The startup originally offered a custody solution. It lets you keep your cryptocurrencies safe for you so that you don’t have to take care of the wallets and their public and private keys. But more recently, Anchorage received a federal banking charter, turning it into a digital asset bank.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Getting a thumbs-up sign from regulators should definitely help when it comes to confidence. Institutional investors are looking for trusty crypto partners to dip their toes into the crypto waters.</p>
<p>In addition to custody, Anchorage now offers several financial products, such as staking, crypto lending, etc. In other words, it wants to become a one-stop shop for institutional investors.</p>
<p>Interestingly, Anchorage also wants to become a crypto-banking-as-a-service startup. The startup thinks it could become the preferred crypto partner for both challenger banks and traditional banks.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DHh9uF2bQp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/anchorage-trading-from-custody/">The crypto rich find security in Anchorage</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The crypto rich find security in Anchorage&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/anchorage-trading-from-custody/embed/#?secret=DHh9uF2bQp" data-secret="DHh9uF2bQp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yvNoHuh57E"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/tesla-buys-1-5b-in-bitcoin-may-accept-the-cryptocurrency-as-payment-in-the-future/">Tesla buys $1.5B in bitcoin, may accept the cryptocurrency as payment in the future</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tesla buys $1.5B in bitcoin, may accept the cryptocurrency as payment in the future&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/tesla-buys-1-5b-in-bitcoin-may-accept-the-cryptocurrency-as-payment-in-the-future/embed/#?secret=yvNoHuh57E" data-secret="yvNoHuh57E" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/crypto-company-anchorage-raises-80-million-after-getting-federal-banking-charter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118033</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter&#8217;s &#8216;Super Follow&#8217; creator subscription takes shots at Substack and Patreon</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/twitters-super-follow-creator-subscription-takes-shots-at-substack-and-patreon/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/twitters-super-follow-creator-subscription-takes-shots-at-substack-and-patreon/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 19:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jack dorsey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Patreon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paywall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real time Web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[text messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been an all-around more ambitious year for Twitter. Following activist shareholder action last year that aimed to oust CEO Jack Dorsey, the company has been making long overdue product moves, buying up companies and aiming to push the envelope on how it can tap its network and drive new revenue streams. Things seem to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s been an all-around more ambitious year for Twitter. Following activist shareholder action last year that aimed to oust CEO Jack Dorsey, the company has been making long overdue product moves, buying up companies and aiming to push the envelope on how it can tap its network and drive new revenue streams. Things seem to be paying off for the company, as their share price sits at an all-time high — double that of its 2020 high.</p>
<p>Today, the company shared early details on its first ever paid product, a feature called &#8220;Super Follow&#8221; which aims to combine the community trends of Discord, the newsletter insights of Substack, the audio chat rooms of Clubhouse and the creator support of Patreon into a creator subscription. The company announced the service during its Analyst Day event Thursday morning.</p>
<p>Plenty of details are still up in the air for the feature, which notably does not have a launch timeline.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2118009" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2118009" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2118009 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-25-at-10.53.24-AM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="448" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-25-at-10.53.24-AM.jpg 2734w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-25-at-10.53.24-AM.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-25-at-10.53.24-AM.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-25-at-10.53.24-AM.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-25-at-10.53.24-AM.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-25-at-10.53.24-AM.jpg?resize=1536,1012 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-25-at-10.53.24-AM.jpg?resize=2048,1350 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-25-at-10.53.24-AM.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2118009" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twitter</p></div></p>
<p>Screenshots shared by Twitter showcase a feature that allows Twitter users to subscribe to their favorite creators for a monthly price (one screenshot details a $4.99 per month cost) and earn certain subscriber-only perks, including things like &#8220;exclusive content,&#8221; &#8220;subscriber-only newsletters,&#8221; &#8220;community access,&#8221; &#8220;deals &amp; discounts,&#8221; and a &#8220;supporter badge&#8221; for subscribers. Creators in the program will also be able to paywall certain media they share, including tweets, fleets and chats they organize in Twitter&#8217;s Clubhouse competitor Spaces.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s other big announcement of the event was &#8220;Communities,&#8221; a product that seems designed to compete with Facebook Groups but also will likely provide &#8220;Super Follow&#8221; networks a place to interact with creators in close cahoots. They also shared early details on a &#8220;safety mode&#8221; that will allow users to auto-block and mute abusive accounts.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Twitter announces Communities, like Facebook Groups but on Twitter</p>
<p>(they’ve started working on it in the web app since at least few weeks ago) <a href="https://t.co/5YBmEfgsUn">https://t.co/5YBmEfgsUn</a> <a href="https://t.co/JlkrZNjLBo">pic.twitter.com/JlkrZNjLBo</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Jane Manchun Wong (@wongmjane) <a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1364992322975330304?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 25, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Introducing paywalls into the Twitter feed could dramatically shift the mechanics of the service. Twitter has been pretty conservative over the years in building features that are intended for singular classes of users. Creator-focused features built for a network that is already home to so many creators could be a major threat to services like Patreon, which have largely popped up due to the lackluster monetization tools available from the big social platforms.</p>
<p>New revenue streams will undoubtedly be key to Twitter&#8217;s ambitious plan to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/twitter-plans-to-double-revenue-by-2023-reach-315m-daily-users/">double its revenues by 2023</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cFQpwGXJ0F"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/will-this-time-be-any-different-for-twitter/">Will this time be any different for Twitter?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Will this time be any different for Twitter?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/will-this-time-be-any-different-for-twitter/embed/#?secret=cFQpwGXJ0F" data-secret="cFQpwGXJ0F" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/twitters-super-follow-creator-subscription-takes-shots-at-substack-and-patreon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117983</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stoke Space aims to take reusable rockets to new heights with $9M seed</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/stoke-space-wants-to-take-reusable-rockets-to-new-heights-with-9m-seed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/stoke-space-wants-to-take-reusable-rockets-to-new-heights-with-9m-seed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 18:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[launch vehicle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[launch vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rocketry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rockets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stoke space]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2117944</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many launch providers think reusability is the best way to lower the cost and delay involved in getting to space. SpaceX and Rocket Lab have shown reusable first stages, which take a payload to the edge of space — and now Stoke Space Technologies says it is making a reusable second stage, which will take [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Many launch providers think reusability is the best way to lower the cost and delay involved in getting to space. SpaceX and Rocket Lab have shown reusable first stages, which take a payload to the edge of space — and now <a href="https://www.stoke-space.com/">Stoke Space Technologies</a> says it is making a reusable <em>second</em> stage, which will take that payload to orbit and beyond, and has raised a $9.1 million seed round to realize it.</p>
<p>Designing a first stage that can return to Earth safely is no small task, but the fact that it only reaches a certain height and speed, and doesn&#8217;t actually climb into orbit at an even higher velocity, means that it is simpler to try. The second stage takes over when the first is spent, accelerating and guiding the payload to its destination orbit, which generally means it will have traveled a lot farther and will be going a lot faster when it tries to come back down.</p>
<p>Stoke thinks that it&#8217;s not just possible to create a second stage that&#8217;s reusable, but crucial to building the low-cost space economy that will enable decades of growth in the industry. The team previously worked on the New Glenn and New Shepard vehicles and engines at Blue Origin, the Merlin 1C for the Falcon 9 at SpaceX and others.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Our design philosophy is to design hardware that not only can be reused, but is operationally reusable. That means fast turnaround times with low refurbishment effort. Reusability of that type has to be designed in from the beginning,&#8221; said Andy Lapsa, co-founder and CEO of Stoke.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2117977" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/stoke-hotfire.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2117977" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2117977" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/stoke-hotfire.jpg" alt="A rocket does a test fire in an industrial environment." width="1024" height="718" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/stoke-hotfire.jpg 2177w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/stoke-hotfire.jpg?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/stoke-hotfire.jpg?resize=300,210 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/stoke-hotfire.jpg?resize=768,538 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/stoke-hotfire.jpg?resize=680,477 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/stoke-hotfire.jpg?resize=1536,1077 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/stoke-hotfire.jpg?resize=2048,1436 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/stoke-hotfire.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2117977" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Stoke Space Technologies</p></div></p>
<p>Beyond the fact that the vehicle will employ a ballistic reentry and powered landing, Stoke did not comment on the engineering or method by which it would accomplish the Herculean feat of bringing down a few tons of precision equipment safely from 400 kilometers up and traveling some 28,000 km/h. (Though Lapsa did mention to <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2021/stoke-space-raises-9-1-million-create-new-breed-reusable-upper-stage-rockets/">GeekWire</a> that a &#8220;good, high-performing stable injector&#8221; is the core of their engine and therefore of the system around it.)</p>
<p>At speeds like that reentry can be deadly, so one hopes they save a little fuel not just for landing but for deceleration. That would increase the mass and complexity of the vehicle before payload, lowering its carrying capacity.</p>
<p>&#8220;It’s true that any reusable system will be inherently more complex than its expendable counterpart,&#8221; Lapsa said. &#8220;However, when one optimizes on mission cost and availability, that complexity is well worth it.&#8221;</p>
<p>As other launch companies have pointed out, you burn up a lot of money on reentry, but so far the safest move has been to keep the first stage alive. The second stage is by no means cheap, and any company would prefer to recycle it as well — and indeed it could lower the cost of launch enormously if they did so successfully.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gxt41frYMe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/complete-success-rocket-labs-booster-recovery-is-a-big-step-towards-reusability/">&#8216;Complete Success&#8217;: Rocket Lab&#8217;s booster recovery is a big step toward reusability</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;&#8216;Complete Success&#8217;: Rocket Lab&#8217;s booster recovery is a big step toward reusability&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/complete-success-rocket-labs-booster-recovery-is-a-big-step-towards-reusability/embed/#?secret=gxt41frYMe" data-secret="gxt41frYMe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The promise Stoke makes is not just to bring the upper stage home, but to bring it home and have it ready for reuse just a day later. &#8220;All launch hardware is reused time after time with aircraft-like regularity — zero refurbishment with 24-hour turnaround,&#8221; claims Lapsa.</p>
<p>Considering the amount of wear and tear a rocket goes through in ascent and landing, &#8220;zero refurbishment&#8221; may sound to many like an impossible dream. SpaceX&#8217;s reusable first stages can be turned around pretty quickly, but they can&#8217;t just fuel them up where they landed and press the button again.</p>
<p>Not only that, but Stoke aims to provide reusable-rocket service beyond low-Earth orbit, where the majority of small, lower-cost satellites go. Geosynchronous orbit and translunar or interplanetary trajectories are also planned.</p>
<p>&#8220;Missions to GTO, GEO direct, TLI and earth escape will initially be done with partially reusable or expendable vehicles, depending on mission requirements, however those vehicles will be the same ones that may have been used on previous fully reusable missions to LEO. The design is extensible to full reuse for these missions (and/or extraplanetary landers) in future variants,&#8221; said Lapsa.</p>
<p>These are ambitious claims — even, given the state of rocketry right now, ones people may with good reason call unrealistic. But the industry has advanced more quickly than many would have predicted a decade ago and seemingly unrealistic ambition drove those changes as well.</p>
<p>The $9.1 million seed round raised by Stoke will enable it to meet the next few milestones, but anyone who follows the industry will know that far more cash will be needed to cover the cost of development and testing in time.</p>
<p>The round was led by NFX and MaC Ventures, along with YC, Seven Seven Six (Alexis Ohanian), Liquid2 (Joe Montana), Trevor Blackwell, Kyle Vogt and Charlie Songhurst, among others.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Trm6JkW3Zc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/spacexs-new-850-million-raise-confirmed-in-sec-filing/">SpaceX&#8217;s new $850 million raise confirmed in SEC filing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SpaceX&#8217;s new $850 million raise confirmed in SEC filing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/spacexs-new-850-million-raise-confirmed-in-sec-filing/embed/#?secret=Trm6JkW3Zc" data-secret="Trm6JkW3Zc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/stoke-space-wants-to-take-reusable-rockets-to-new-heights-with-9m-seed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2117944</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
