<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 15:42:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Just 72 hours left to save $100 on passes to TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/just-72-hours-left-to-save-100-on-passes-to-tc-sessions-mobility-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/just-72-hours-left-to-save-100-on-passes-to-tc-sessions-mobility-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 15:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alex Wang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ben schippers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric aircraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emerging-Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitbit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joby Aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reid Hoffman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions: Mobility 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TezLab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video on demand]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146158</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So much can happen in 72 hours, and it’s easy to get distracted — especially when you’re building a startup in the fast lane that is mobility tech. But listen up: you have just 72 hours left to save $100 on your pass to TC Sessions: Mobility 2021 on June 9. Don’t let “busy” distract [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">So much can happen in 72 hours, and it’s easy to get distracted — especially when you’re building a startup in the fast lane that is mobility tech. But listen up: you have just 72 hours left to save $100 on your pass to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=3daysebcountdown&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=eb3days&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</a> on June 9.</p>
<p>Don’t let “busy” distract you. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=3daysebcountdown&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=eb3days&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Buy your pass to Mobility 2021</a> before the price increase goes into effect on <strong>Thursday, May 6 at 11:59 pm (PT).</strong></p>
<p>Why should you attend TC Sessions: Mobility 2021? It’s where you can tap into the latest trends, regulatory concerns, technical and ethical challenges surrounding the technologies that will forever change how we move people and material goods across towns, cities, states, countries — and space.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Or, as Jens Lehmann, technical lead and product manager at SAP, told us:</p>
<p>“TC Sessions Mobility is definitely worth your time, especially if you’re an early-stage founder. You get to connect to people in your field and learn from founders who are literally a year into your same journey. Plus, you can meet and talk to the movers and shakers — the people who are making it happen.”</p>
<p>Take a gander at just some of the fascinating people and topics waiting for you and see the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=3daysebcountdown&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=eb3days&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">event agenda here</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Supercharging Self-Driving Super Vision:</strong> Few startups were as prescient as Scale AI when it came to anticipating the need for massive sets of tagged data for use in AI. Co-founder and CEO Alex Wang also made a great bet on addressing the needs of lidar sensing companies early on, which has made the company instrumental in deploying AV networks. We’ll hear about what it takes to make sense of sensor data in driverless cars and look at where the industry is headed.</li>
<li><strong>EV Founders in Focus:</strong> We sit down with the founders poised to take advantage of the rise in electric vehicle sales. We’ll chat with Ben Schippers, co-founder and CEO of TezLab, an app that operates like a Fitbit for Tesla vehicles (and soon other EVs) and allows drivers to go deep into their driving data. The app also breaks down the exact types and percentages of fossil fuels and renewable energy coming from charging locations.</li>
<li><strong>The Future of Flight:</strong> Joby Aviation founder JoeBen Bevirt spent more than a decade quietly developing an all-electric, vertical take-off and landing passenger aircraft. Now he is preparing for a new phase of growth as Joby Aviation merges with the special purpose acquisition company formed by famed investor and Linked co-founder Reid Hoffman. Bevirt and Hoffman will come to our virtual stage to talk about how to build a startup (and keep it secret while raising funds), the future of flight and, of course, SPACs.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Pro tip:</strong> Between the live stream and video on demand, you can keep your work schedule on track without missing out.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=3daysebcountdown&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=eb3days&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</a> takes place on June 9, but you have only 72 short hours left to save $100 on all the info and opportunity that TC Sessions: Mobility 2021 offers. Kick distractions to the curb. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=3daysebcountdown&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=eb3days&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Buy your pass</a> before the early bird price disappears on <strong>Thursday, May 6 at 11:59 pm (PT).</strong></p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at TC Sessions: Mobility 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html?_ga=2.147735806.874617471.1572269011-985484541.1566312242">filling out this form</a><em>.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-71a70eba569f6ab0fb6c9a63fc276b30"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/71a70eba569f6ab0fb6c9a63fc276b30"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-71a70eba569f6ab0fb6c9a63fc276b30')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-71a70eba569f6ab0fb6c9a63fc276b30'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/just-72-hours-left-to-save-100-on-passes-to-tc-sessions-mobility-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146158</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>London&#8217;s Stride VC raised second $138.6M seed fund, hunts for third partner</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/londons-stride-vc-raised-second-138-6m-seed-fund-hunts-for-third-partner/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/londons-stride-vc-raised-second-138-6m-seed-fund-hunts-for-third-partner/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 15:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2147308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Stride VC, a London-based seed investment fund, has raised its second fund, which will be £100M ($138.6M) &#8211; identical to its first fund. The fund will invest primarily in London startups but also look at select European opportunities. The breakup of the LPs in the fund is 10% fund of funds, 60% other institutional, 28% [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://Stride.VC">Stride VC</a>, a London-based seed investment fund, has raised its second fund, which will be £100M ($138.6M) &#8211; identical to its first fund. The fund will invest primarily in London startups but also look at select European opportunities.</p>
<p>The breakup of the LPs in the fund is 10% fund of funds, 60% other institutional, 28% family offices, and 10% individuals. Stride said some 80% of this new fund came from returning LPs, and 20% from two new unnamed institutional investors. Stride does not have any public or government investment.</p>
<p>Investors include the founders of Cazoo, King, Pillpack, Dott, and institutional investors such as Delin Ventures, Draper Esprit, Mubadala, and CNP (Groupe Frere).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Stride founder Founder Fred Destin told me that while the fundraising was planned for June, the two new unnamed institutional investors &#8220;reached out in January, and confirmed their intention to invest around mid-Feb after a quick diligence process. We weren&#8217;t planning to raise until June. We secured all allocations March 12 and closed 31 March. Breakneck speed for a fund,” he said.</p>
<p>Stride has also gone through some personnel additions. The successful podcaster about VC, Harry Stebbings, who co-founded Stride with Destin, <a href="https://twitter.com/fdestin/status/1358507176843743233?s=20">departed amicably</a> in early February to set up his own fund. <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/cleo-sham-9294313/">Cleo Sham</a> is the new partner joining full-time in June, as announced <a href="https://twitter.com/fdestin/status/1368482488738316292?s=20">on Twitter</a>. In August last year it lost its Paris-based partner, Pia d&#8217;Iribarne, who has set up <a href="http://Newwave.vc">Newwave.vc</a>.</p>
<p>Destin also told me he will be looking for a new third partner for the fund, and two more team members: “I’m mainly looking for exceptional talent. If they don&#8217;t fit some kind of mold, or don’t have an MBA and speak like MBA people, even better. What I mean is I don&#8217;t want people who just look for your references.&#8221; But, he added, &#8220;don&#8217;t @ me on Twitter about it!&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/shane-burgess-550891/">Shane Burgess</a> has joined to head up talent; <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/pietro-invernizzi/">Pietro Invernizzi</a>, formerly of The Family, runs the &#8216;First Check Programme&#8217;.</p>
<p>Destin says Stride remains &#8220;firmly committed to Seed”, usually leading or co-leading a funding round. But that it will also expand from pre-seed funding with £250K checks to sometimes larger investments in companies like Huboo where it invested £4.5M. Its core investment program ranges from £750K to £4M (usually £2M) and lower rounds from £250K.</p>
<p>Destin describes the fund as &#8220;artisan venture capital” where it invests in  &#8220;small batches”. He said: &#8220;We understand startups are chaotic and we embrace the chaos. We value trust over everything else. We are not about control; we&#8217;re about impact. We&#8217;d rather do the work than talk about it, hence the minimal website.”</p>
<p>Over a call, he added: “We don&#8217;t take board seats, we prefer to provide something to the founders that&#8217;s meaningful to them. So we&#8217;ll do ad hoc things, such as a strategy session, help them recruit someone, pointed interventions. The founders seem to really like it.”</p>
<p>Stride’s Fund I has backed 29 companies so far. Perhaps the best know is Cazoo. Although much of its portfolio is undisclosed and defies ‘themes’ it’s known to have invested in:</p>
<ul>
<li>API Infrastructure: STRAPI, Impala, WeGift</li>
<li>Ecommerce: Cazoo, Front of the Pack</li>
<li>SaaS: SEDNA, Cord, Unibuddy, WeGift</li>
</ul>
<p>Destin told me: “We don&#8217;t necessarily think it&#8217;s helpful for companies to be announcing what they do and what they&#8217;ve raised. And for ourselves, we don&#8217;t need it to flatter our ego. A lot of our companies are happily operating below the radar.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/londons-stride-vc-raised-second-138-6m-seed-fund-hunts-for-third-partner/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2147308</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>As Q2&#8217;s lull fades, unicorn IPOs are revving up</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/as-q2s-lull-fades-unicorn-ipos-are-revving-up/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/as-q2s-lull-fades-unicorn-ipos-are-revving-up/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 15:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Darktrace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Real Estate and Proptech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expensify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SmartRent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[squarespace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2147250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Let’s discuss IPOs this morning to fully understand where we stand today in the realm of unicorn liquidity.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The public markets give, and the public markets take away. Earlier this morning, enterprise cloud storage and productivity company Box got into <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/starboard-value-puts-box-on-notice-that-its-looking-to-take-over-board/">a more public spat</a> with some of its shareholders upset with its performance and management decisions. But while Box endures the more difficult chapters of being a public company, other companies are racing to join the ranks of the listed concerns of the world.</p>
<p>If it feels like IPO news slowed for a few weeks at the start of the second quarter, your gut is correct. Investors previously told The Exchange that the first, third and fourth quarters of 2021 would be hot periods for public debuts, but that Q2 would be slower. Their argument revolved around reporting cadences and how long it takes for certain periods of accounting work to be completed.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>So we weren’t surprised when the second quarter’s IPO cycle began to feel a bit soft compared to the rapid-fire first quarter. And, as we’ve all heard in recent days, the great SPAC rush is slowing.</p>
<p>But that hasn’t stopped a number of firms from defying expectations and going public all the same. Online hosting and website builder Squarespace <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/squarespace-files-for-a-direct-listing-on-the-nyse/">has not only filed</a> but filled in its public filing with notes on its anticipated direct listing. We have to talk about its choice to list directly in light of new financial information we have concerning its recent performance.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995210 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>But there’s more: Expensify <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210503005265/en">filed to go public</a> yesterday, albeit privately. And the SmartRent SPAC combination, though now slightly dated, is also worth a moment of our time.</p>
<p>The final element in the current IPO landscape is the recent Darktrace IPO in the United Kingdom, which, after that market <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/what-to-make-of-deliveroos-rough-ipo-debut/">had a rough start to its tech IPO calendar</a>, is now <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/30/darktrace-ipo-dark-stock-skyrockets-43percent-in-london-debut.html">seeing better results</a>. So, let’s discuss IPOs to fully understand where we stand today in the realm of unicorn liquidity.</p>
<h2>Squarespace’s direct listing</h2>
<p>When The Exchange first dug into Squarespace’s IPO filing, we did our best to parse its full-year results because we lacked its quarterly details. This leaves us with two things to chew on: Why is Squarespace pursuing a direct listing over another listing technique, and what can its current and more granular operating results tell us about the choice?</p>
<p>On the first count, if Squarespace is direct listing, we can presume that it doesn’t need more cash to operate. So, how much cash does the company have on hand? A good chunk of change: $183.3 million.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/as-q2s-lull-fades-unicorn-ipos-are-revving-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2147250</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Evening Fund debuts with $2M micro fund focused on investments between $50K  and $100K</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/evening-fund-debuts-with-2m-micro-fund-focused-on-investments-between-50k-and-100k/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/evening-fund-debuts-with-2m-micro-fund-focused-on-investments-between-50k-and-100k/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 15:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evening Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kat Orekhova]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[micro-investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rapha Danilo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seed Investing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2147267</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We tend to think of venture capital in tens or hundreds of millions, even billions of dollars, so it&#8217;s refreshing to find Evening Fund, a new $2 million micro fund that focuses on small investments between $50,000 and $100,000 as it seeks to help young startups that may be struggling to find funding elsewhere. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We tend to think of venture capital in tens or hundreds of millions, even billions of dollars, so it&#8217;s refreshing to find <a href="https://www.evening.fund/">Evening Fund</a>, a new $2 million micro fund that focuses on small investments between $50,000 and $100,000 as it seeks to help young startups that may be struggling to find funding elsewhere.</p>
<p>The new fund was launched by Kat Orekhova and Rapha Danilo. Orekhova, who started her career as a math professor, is a former Facebook data scientist who has been dabbling in angel investing and working with young startups for awhile now. They call it Evening Fund because they work as founders by day and investors by night.</p>
<p>She says that she wanted to create something more formal to help early-stage startups get off the ground and has help from limited partners that include Sarah Smith at Bain Capital, Lee Linden, general partner at Quiet Capital and a long list of tech industry luminaries.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Orekhova says she and her partner invest small sums of money in B2B SaaS companies, which are pre-seed, seed and occasionally A rounds. They will invest in consumer here and there as well. She says one of their key value propositions is that they can help with more than just the money. &#8220;One way in which I think Rapha and I can really help our founders is that we give very specific, practical advice, not just kind of super high level,&#8221; she told me.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="D3FFRaNoYb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/us-seed-stage-investing-flourished-during-pandemic/">US seed-stage investing flourished during pandemic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;US seed-stage investing flourished during pandemic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/us-seed-stage-investing-flourished-during-pandemic/embed/#?secret=D3FFRaNoYb" data-secret="D3FFRaNoYb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That could be something like how to hire your first designer where the founders may not even know what a designer does. &#8220;You&#8217;re figuring out &#8216;how do I hire my first designer?&#8217; and &#8216;what does the designer even do?&#8217; because most founders have never hired a designer before. So we give them extremely practical hands-on stuff like &#8216;here are the competencies&#8217; or &#8216;what&#8217;s the difference between a graphic designer, a visual designer, a UX designer and a researcher,&#8217; &#8221; she said. They go so far as to give them a list of candidates to help them get going.</p>
<p>She says that she realized while she was at Facebook that she wanted to eventually start a company, so she began volunteering her time to work with companies going through Y Combinator. &#8220;I think a lot of people don&#8217;t know where to start, but in my case I looked at the YC list, found a company that I thought I could be helpful to. I reached out cold and said &#8216;Hey, I don&#8217;t want money. I don&#8217;t want equity. I just want to try to be helpful to you and see where that goes,&#8217; &#8221; she said.</p>
<p>That lead to scouting for startups for some larger venture capital firms and eventually dabbling in financing some of these startups that she was helping. Today&#8217;s announcement is the culmination of these years of work and the groundwork she laid to make herself familiar with how the startup ecosystem works.</p>
<p>The new firm already has its first investment under its belt, <a href="https://www.dala.ai/">Dala</a>, an AI-powered internal search tool that helps connect users to workplace knowledge that&#8217;s often locked in applications like Google Suite, Slack and Notion.</p>
<p>As though Evening isn&#8217;t enough to keep her and Danilo busy, they are also working on a startup, which she says is very much related to the fund. But she wasn&#8217;t ready to share much on that just yet as the company remains in stealth.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cUH1x0OaVI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/10/operator-collective-brings-diversity-and-inclusion-to-enterprise-investing/">Operator Collective brings diversity and inclusion to enterprise investing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Operator Collective brings diversity and inclusion to enterprise investing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/10/operator-collective-brings-diversity-and-inclusion-to-enterprise-investing/embed/#?secret=cUH1x0OaVI" data-secret="cUH1x0OaVI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/evening-fund-debuts-with-2m-micro-fund-focused-on-investments-between-50k-and-100k/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2147267</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Live video platform Bright lets you Zoom with your favorite creators</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/live-video-platform-bright-lets-you-zoom-with-your-favorite-creators/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/live-video-platform-bright-lets-you-zoom-with-your-favorite-creators/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 15:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ashton kutcher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bright]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creator economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guy oseary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Powers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sound ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146920</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What if you could Zoom with your favorite creator and ask them questions? That&#8217;s the promise of Bright, the new live video platform launching today from co-founders Guy Oseary and early YouTube product manager Michael Powers. The service, built on top of Zoom, allows fans to engage in live, face-to-face video sessions with creators, ask [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">What if you could Zoom with your favorite creator and ask them questions? That&#8217;s the promise of <a href="https://brightlive.com/">Bright</a>, the new live video platform launching today from co-founders Guy Oseary and early YouTube product manager Michael Powers. The service, built on top of Zoom, allows fans to engage in live, face-to-face video sessions with creators, ask questions and even join creators on a virtual stage for a more personal and direct learning experience.</p>
<p>Though the startup has some similarities to voice chat apps like Clubhouse, as it also democratizes access to big-name talent at times, the co-founders explain that Bright&#8217;s focus will be very different. Besides being a video-on experience, Bright is solely focused on educational content &#8212; that is, learning from people who are sharing their expertise with the community. In addition, the sessions hosted on Bright are ticketed events, where the creator decides how many tickets they want to sell and how much they&#8217;re charging.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2146975" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2146975" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2146975" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Bright-Homepage-ft.-Ugo-Mozie.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="420" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Bright-Homepage-ft.-Ugo-Mozie.jpg 2900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Bright-Homepage-ft.-Ugo-Mozie.jpg?resize=150,93 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Bright-Homepage-ft.-Ugo-Mozie.jpg?resize=300,185 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Bright-Homepage-ft.-Ugo-Mozie.jpg?resize=768,475 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Bright-Homepage-ft.-Ugo-Mozie.jpg?resize=680,420 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Bright-Homepage-ft.-Ugo-Mozie.jpg?resize=1536,950 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Bright-Homepage-ft.-Ugo-Mozie.jpg?resize=2048,1266 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Bright-Homepage-ft.-Ugo-Mozie.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2146975" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bright</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Twenty percent of the content on YouTube was learning. It was the second-biggest area next to music. And that was true the first year of YouTube and it&#8217;s true now at scale,&#8221; explains Bright CEO Michael Powers, as to why Bright has chosen to focus on learning. Powers knows the creator industry firsthand, having launched the YouTube Channels feature while at YouTube, and later managed YouTube&#8217;s first revenue-generating opportunities for creators. More recently, he served as SVP and GM at CBS Interactive.</p>
<p>Powers says he saw how powerful educational and learning content could be, but also how difficult it was for creators earning a rev share off an ad network, like YouTube&#8217;s, to become self-sustainable.</p>
<p>&#8220;I watched that over the past five years, especially, as the different platforms have scaled up,&#8221; Powers says, and became inspired to launch a better way for creators to monetize their expertise. &#8220;We&#8217;ve got to empower [creators] so they can go beyond just being a personal brand or social brand, and be an actual business,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p>Oseary, meanwhile, was tooling around with a similar concept, having also had direct experience with creators in the music industry and through his investments. The founder of Maverick music management company, Oseary <a href="https://variety.com/2020/music/news/guy-oseary-madonna-u2-manager-maverick-1234618275/">continues to manage</a> Madonna and U2, but these days has his hands in numerous startups as the co-founder of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/ashton-kutchers-sound-ventures-targets-150m-for-third-fund/">Sound Ventures</a> and <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/a-grade-investments">A-Grade Investments</a> with actor Ashton Kutcher.</p>
<p>Though Oseary and Powers have yet to meet in person, they connected over the web &#8212; much like Bright&#8217;s creators will now do &#8212; to get the new startup off the ground during a pandemic.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dkVSyx1FEy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/ashton-kutchers-sound-ventures-targets-150m-for-third-fund/">Ashton Kutcher&#8217;s Sound Ventures targets $150M for third fund</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ashton Kutcher&#8217;s Sound Ventures targets $150M for third fund&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/ashton-kutchers-sound-ventures-targets-150m-for-third-fund/embed/#?secret=dkVSyx1FEy" data-secret="dkVSyx1FEy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>With today&#8217;s launch, <a href="https://brightlive.com/">Bright</a> is promising a lineup of more than 200 prominent creators, many from the arts, including Madonna, Ashton Kutcher, Naomi Campbell, Shawn Mendes, Amy Schumer, D-Nice, the D’Amelio Sisters, Laura Dern, Judd Apatow, Deepak Chopra, Diplo, Kenny Smith, Kane Brown, Drew and Jonathan Scott (Property Brothers), Lindsey Vonn, Rachel Zoe, Diego Boneta, Tal Fishman, Ryan Prunty, Demi Skipper, Charlotte McKinney, Jason Bolden, Yris Palmer, Cat &amp; Nat, Ronnie2K, Chef Ludo Lefebvre and Jonathan Mannion, among others.</p>
<p>And it has another 1,500 creators on a waitlist, ready to begin hosting their own sessions when Bright opens up further.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2146982" style="width: 391px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2146982" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2146982" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Session-Card-Laura-Dern.jpg?w=381" alt="" width="381" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Session-Card-Laura-Dern.jpg 909w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Session-Card-Laura-Dern.jpg?resize=84,150 84w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Session-Card-Laura-Dern.jpg?resize=168,300 168w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Session-Card-Laura-Dern.jpg?resize=768,1371 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Session-Card-Laura-Dern.jpg?resize=381,680 381w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Session-Card-Laura-Dern.jpg?resize=860,1536 860w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Session-Card-Laura-Dern.jpg?resize=28,50 28w" sizes="(max-width: 381px) 100vw, 381px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2146982" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bright session example</p></div></p>
<p>Although Bright&#8217;s lineup implies it&#8217;s aiming at a high-profile creator crowd, Oseary insists Bright will be for anyone with an audience of their own &#8212; not just famous names.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is not elitist&#8230;If you&#8217;ve got an audience and you have something to offer your audience, we would like you on the platform,&#8221; he says.</p>
<p>Today, creators can go to other social networks, like Facebook Live or Instagram Live, if they want to just chat with fans more casually. But people will come to Bright to be educated, Oseary notes. And short of getting a creator to FaceTime you directly, he believes this will be the next best way to reach them &#8212; and one people are familiar with using, thanks to the Zoom adoption that grew out of the pandemic&#8217;s impact to business culture and remote work.</p>
<p>&#8220;The best way to connect is to use a platform that we&#8217;ve all learned how to use this last year,&#8221; Oseary says, referring to Bright&#8217;s Zoom connection. &#8220;We all already have the app. We already know how to navigate through it. We&#8217;ve added a bunch of features to make it more interesting,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2146985" style="width: 391px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2146985" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2146985" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Session-Card-Kenny-Smith-2.jpg?w=381" alt="" width="381" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Session-Card-Kenny-Smith-2.jpg 1818w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Session-Card-Kenny-Smith-2.jpg?resize=84,150 84w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Session-Card-Kenny-Smith-2.jpg?resize=168,300 168w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Session-Card-Kenny-Smith-2.jpg?resize=768,1371 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Session-Card-Kenny-Smith-2.jpg?resize=381,680 381w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Session-Card-Kenny-Smith-2.jpg?resize=860,1536 860w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Session-Card-Kenny-Smith-2.jpg?resize=1147,2048 1147w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Session-Card-Kenny-Smith-2.jpg?resize=28,50 28w" sizes="(max-width: 381px) 100vw, 381px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2146985" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bright</p></div></p>
<p>At launch, fans will be able to <a href="http://www.brightlive.com/">visit Bright&#8217;s website</a>, view the array of upcoming events and purchase tickets. Some of the first sessions include Laura Dern leading a &#8220;Tell Your Story&#8221; session about personal growth; Kenny Smith will interview favorite athletes and discuss their mindsets at turning points in their careers; Property Brothers Jonathan &amp; Drew Scott will host &#8220;Room by Room,&#8221; focused on home improvement; recording artist Kane Brown will host &#8220;Record This: Nashville Edition&#8221; about the country music industry; and Ronnie2K will host a series about building a career in gaming.</p>
<p>Bright&#8217;s model will see it taking a 20% commission on creator revenue, which is lower than the traditional marketplace split of 30/70 (platform/creator), but higher than the commission-free payments on Clubhouse (at least for the time being!). Further down the road, Bright envisions building out more tools to help creators with other aspects of their business &#8212; like the sale of physical or digital goods, for example.</p>
<p>Though there are numerous creator platforms to choose from these days, Bright aims to give creators direct access to their own analytics about their biggest fans, their content and fans&#8217; contact information, like names and emails. This allows them to continue their relationship with their community beyond Bright into other areas of their business &#8212; whether that&#8217;s email newsletters or Shopify stores.</p>
<p>To make all this work, LA-based <a href="https://brightlive.com/">Bright</a> has recruited a team with deep expertise in both the creator economy and tech.</p>
<p>This includes Bright&#8217;s VP of Talent &amp; Partnership, Kaitlyn Powell, former head of Talent at Caffeine; Bright&#8217;s lead Creator &amp; Product Strategy, Sadia Harper, formerly a UX Strategist at Instagram; Bright&#8217;s director of Creative Programming, Jeben Berg, previously of YouTube &amp; Maker Studios; Design lead Heather Grates, previously of Pinterest; and Bright&#8217;s finance lead Jarad Backlund, previously in roles at Apple and Facebook.</p>
<p>The startup has raised an undisclosed amount funding from Oseary&#8217;s own Sound Ventures, as well as RIT Capital, Norwest, Globo and other investors.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="t8eS1vFQvr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/06/4-creator-economy-vcs-see-startup-opportunities-in-monetization-discovery-and-much-more/">5 creator economy VCs see startup opportunities in monetization, discovery and much more</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 creator economy VCs see startup opportunities in monetization, discovery and much more&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/06/4-creator-economy-vcs-see-startup-opportunities-in-monetization-discovery-and-much-more/embed/#?secret=t8eS1vFQvr" data-secret="t8eS1vFQvr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/live-video-platform-bright-lets-you-zoom-with-your-favorite-creators/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146920</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Instagram adds a captions option for Stories and soon, Reels</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/instagram-adds-a-captions-option-for-stories-and-soon-reels/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/instagram-adds-a-captions-option-for-stories-and-soon-reels/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 15:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accessibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[captions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deaf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[videos]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2147236</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Instagram is making its video Stories and Reels more accessible with the launch of a new &#8220;captions sticker&#8221; that will allow users to watch without having the sound on. The addition will not only make it easier for users who are hard of hearing or deaf to engage with video content, it also offers a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Instagram is making its video Stories and Reels more accessible with the launch of a new &#8220;captions sticker&#8221; that will allow users to watch without having the sound on. The addition will not only make it easier for users who are hard of hearing or deaf to engage with video content, it also offers a way for users to watch videos when they&#8217;re somewhere they don&#8217;t want to have their sound on &#8212; and either don&#8217;t want to wear or don&#8217;t have access headphones or earbuds.</p>
<p>To use the feature, creators will first record a new video using the Stories or Reels Camera in the Instagram app, or select a video to upload from their phone&#8217;s gallery. Then, you&#8217;ll open the sticker tray and look for the new &#8220;Captions&#8221; sticker, which will convert your speech to text. You can also edit the style, position of the caption, and the text and color so it matches your content. When you post, the captions will appear alongside your video for everyone to see.</p>
<p>At launch, the feature is only available in English and in English-speaking countries, but Instagram plans to roll it out to other countries and languages soon, it says. It&#8217;s also rolling out the captions sticker first to Stories and will then begin testing it in Reels, with a broader launch to follow.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The captions sticker had been <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1303070629386690562">spotted</a> last year while in development, alongside other potential new additions, like <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1322287223232991234">a Collab sticker</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1384220655239897097">Link sticker,</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1380624546135478275">Reshare sticker,</a> and others. Instagram parent Facebook also appears to have<a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1380307322262667266"> a captions sticker of its own</a> in development. The sticker then <a href="https://twitter.com/MattNavarra/status/1369351891445030918">began testing earlier this spring</a> with some number of Instagram users.</p>
<p>The addition comes only weeks after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/tiktok-adds-auto-captions-to-make-videos-accessible-to-hard-of-hearing-and-deaf/">TikTok announced its own captions feature</a>, which it calls auto captions. The two products are somewhat different, however. Auto captions automatically translate the speech from a TikTok video in either American English and Japanese, to start, but the text itself isn&#8217;t customizable and can be turned on or off by the viewer from the app&#8217;s share panel. It also hasn&#8217;t yet been broadly adopted and many TikTok creators tend to still use captions they create themselves or via third-party apps.</p>
<p>Instagram notes it had previously launched support for captions across Threads and IGTV, but its expansion to Stories and Reels will make more of an impact, given that instagram Stories alone is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/30/instagram-stories-500-million/">used by over 500 million people</a> every day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/instagram-adds-a-captions-option-for-stories-and-soon-reels/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2147236</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chromebook shipments grew 275% in Q1</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/chromebook-shipments-grew-275-in-q1/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/chromebook-shipments-grew-275-in-q1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 14:49:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chrome os]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chromebooks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tablets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2147276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New numbers from research firm Canalys point to continued growth for PCs in 2020/21, as the pandemic has forced many to rethink how – and where – they work. PC shipments have grown for four straight quarters. All told, the numbers (within which the firm lumps tablets, incidentally) grew 53% year over year. Chromebooks were [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">New numbers from research firm Canalys point to continued growth for PCs in 2020/21, as the pandemic has forced many to rethink how – and where – they work. PC shipments have grown for four straight quarters. All told, the numbers (within which the firm lumps tablets, incidentally) grew 53% year over year.</p>
<p>Chromebooks were the major force in growth, according to the figures. The category jumped 275% y-o-y for Q1 to 12 million units. HP saw a pretty massive chunk of that, with 36.4% of the total market, up from 18.6% percent. Lenovo, Acer, Samsung and Dell rounded out the top five.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2147277" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2147277" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2147277" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/unnamed-12.png" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/unnamed-12.png 4000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/unnamed-12.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/unnamed-12.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/unnamed-12.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/unnamed-12.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/unnamed-12.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/unnamed-12.png?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/unnamed-12.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2147277" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Canalys</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The category’s growth continues to be driven primarily by the education sector. That’s long been the foothold for devices that have traditionally failed to crack through to mainstream usage. As many classrooms have been forced to go virtual, that category has continued to see impressive growth. And that may now be extending beyond education.</p>
<p>“Chromebooks are well and truly a mainstream computing product now,” Canalys’ Brian Lynch said in a release tied to the news. “While the education sector still accounts for the majority of shipments, their popularity with consumers and traditional commercial customers has reached new heights over the course of the last year.”</p>
<p>Tablets, too, had a solid quarter, after a period of middling sales. Education is a big driver there, as well, along with broader usage. Apple led the category with 38.2% of the market, with Samsung and Lenovo rounding out the top three. On the PC (plus tablets again) side, Lenovo leads the way, followed by Apple and HP.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xe5hCGsAf5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/chromebooks-had-a-banner-2020/">Chromebooks had a banner 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chromebooks had a banner 2020&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/chromebooks-had-a-banner-2020/embed/#?secret=xe5hCGsAf5" data-secret="xe5hCGsAf5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/chromebook-shipments-grew-275-in-q1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2147276</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Headway raises $70M at a $750M valuation to help connect therapists with people and insurance schemes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/headway-raises-70m-at-a-750m-valuation-to-help-connect-therapists-with-people-and-insurance-schemes/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/headway-raises-70m-at-a-750m-valuation-to-help-connect-therapists-with-people-and-insurance-schemes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 14:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[headway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[therapy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thrive]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2147211</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mental health, and how it is getting addressed, has been one of the major leitmotifs of the past year of pandemic living. Covid-19 not only has led to a lot of people getting ill or worse; it has increased isolation, economic uncertainty, and led to a lot of other kinds of disappointments, and that all [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Mental health, and how it is getting addressed, has been one of the major leitmotifs of the past year of pandemic living. Covid-19 not only has led to a lot of people getting ill or worse; it has increased isolation, economic uncertainty, and led to a lot of other kinds of disappointments, and that all has had a knock-on effect on our collective and individual state of mind.</p>
<p>Today a startup called <a href="https://headway.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Headway</a>, which has been working on building a better way for people to attend to themselves &#8212; by way of a three-sided marketplace of sorts, by helping a person to find and afford a therapist via a free-to-use portal, by making it possible for those therapists to accept a wider range of insurance plans, and by helping those insurance plans facilitate more therapy appointments for their patient networks &#8212; is announcing a major round of funding on the heels of strong growth.</p>
<p>The startup has raised $70 million, money that it will be using to continue expanding its platform with more partnerships, more hiring for its team (it wants to have 300 people this year) and opening up in new regions, aiming to be nationwide this year in the U.S.. This round, a Series B, has a number of big names attached to it: it is being led by Andreessen Horowitz, with Thrive, GV and Accel also participating. (The latter three are repeat investors: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/headway-raises-26m-to-help-people-find-therapists-and-therapists-to-accept-insurance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Thrive and GV led its Series A</a>, while Accel led its seed.) This Series B is coming in at a $750 million valuation.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The rapid pace of funding, the backers, and that valuation all underscore the timeliness of the concept, and also the traction that Headway is getting for its approach.</p>
<p>When we last covered Headway &#8212; it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/headway-raises-26m-to-help-people-find-therapists-and-therapists-to-accept-insurance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised $26 million just last November</a>, six months ago &#8212; it said it had registered some 1,800 therapists on its platform in the New York metro area, where it is based. Now that number is up to over 3,000 with its network now covering not just NYC, but also New Jersey, Florida, North Carolina, Texas, Georgia, Michigan, Virginia, Washington, Illinois and Colorado. It has over 2,000 patients joining the platform each month and has so far helped facilitate 300,000 appointments, with a current average of 30,000 appointments each month. Revenues have in the last year, menawhile, grown nine-fold.</p>
<p>The approach that Headway is taking &#8212; creating not just a vertical search portal for therapists, but building a back-end system to help those therapists grow their business by making it easier for them to accept insurance coverage &#8212; comes directly out of the experiences faced by one of the startup&#8217;s co-founders.</p>
<p>Andrew Adams, the CEO of Headway, told me last year he came up with the idea after he moved to New York from California several years ago to take a job. In seeking a therapist, he found most unwilling to accept his insurance plan as payment, making getting therapy unaffordable.</p>
<p>This is a very typical problem, he said. Some 70% of therapists do not accept insurance today because it&#8217;s too complicated for them to integrate, since about 85% of all therapists happen to be solo practitioners. So something that should be accessible to everyone becomes something typically only used by those who can afford it, or have entered into social care programs that might provide it. But that leaves a massive gap in the middle.</p>
<p>“This is the defining problem in the space,” he said at the time. “Health insurance is built around a medical world dominated by billers and admins, but therapists are small practitioners and don’t have the bandwidth to handle that, so they don’t. So we thought if we could make it easier for them to, they would, and they have.”</p>
<p>And indeed, if you are needing to see a therapist, the very last thing you need or want to be doing is spending your time trying to work out the economics of doing so: you need to be focused on finding someone who you feel you can talk to; someone who can help you.</p>
<p>The problem is a huge one. In the U.S. alone it&#8217;s estimated that there are some 82 million people who have treatable health conditions. Headway was founded on the premise that most of them currently do not seek that treatment because of cost or accessibility.</p>
<p>A lot of therapy has traditionally been about seeing people in person &#8212; and arguably the fact that we&#8217;ve had so much reduced contact with people has contributed to mental health issues this past year &#8212; but in the event, Headway has definitely adapted to the current climate.</p>
<p>The company says that some 89% of its appointments at the moment are being carried out remotely. This is down from 97% at the peak of the pandemic in the U.S., and has been slowly starting to taper off, the company said. Some of the increased volume, meanwhile, is a direct result of therapists working remotely: they can fit more people in to a daily schedule as a result.</p>
<p>In terms of insurers, the company currently works with Aetna, Cigna, United Healthcare, Oscar and Oxford and says the list will be growing. On interesting detail is that Headway has not only built out a bigger funnel for these insurers in terms of the practitioners that they work with and individuals who can subsequently use insurance to pay for therapy, but conversely has served to be a conduit for those insurance groups in bringing more patients through to those therapists, who are now a part of their networks, by way of Headway&#8217;s platform.</p>
<p>Headway says that using its system can help a patient get an appointment within 5 days, versus the the 30-day average you typically face when using an insurance directory.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">It&#8217;s the kind of scale and &#8220;software eating the world&#8221; efficiency that has attracted Andreessen Horowitz to backing companies before, with the added detail of this being particular relevant to the time we are living in. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">“By getting the mental health provider community on the same page with insurance companies for the first time, Headway unlocks affordable mental healthcare for millions of Americans,” said Scott Kupor, managing partner at Andreessen Horowitz. “We’re incredibly excited to work alongside the Headway team.” Kupor is also joining Headway’s board with this round.</span></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Cherry Miao, a former Partner at Accel and Headway’s lead seed investor, is also joining as Head of Finance &amp; Data.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“I’ve been fortunate to work with some of the world’s most influential startups, and know that being part of Headway’s meaningful mission, robust business model, and incredibly talented team is a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity,&#8221; she said. &#8220;I’m thrilled to be helping rebuild America’s mental healthcare system for access and affordability.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/headway-raises-70m-at-a-750m-valuation-to-help-connect-therapists-with-people-and-insurance-schemes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2147211</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Personalized nutrition startup Zoe closes out Series B at $53M total raise</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/personalized-nutrition-startup-zoe-closes-out-series-b-at-53m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/personalized-nutrition-startup-zoe-closes-out-series-b-at-53m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 14:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ahren Innovation Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eli manning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[George Hadjigeorgiou]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microbiome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personalized nutrition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[series B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tim Spector]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zoe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Personalized nutrition startup Zoe &#8212; named not for a person but after the Greek word for &#8216;life&#8217; &#8212; has topped up its Series B round with $20M, bringing the total raised to $53M. The latest close of the B round was led by Ahren Innovation Capital, which the startup notes counts two Nobel laureates as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Personalized nutrition startup <a href="https://joinzoe.com">Zoe</a> &#8212; named not for a person but after the Greek word for &#8216;life&#8217; &#8212; has topped up its Series B round with $20M, bringing the total raised to $53M.</p>
<p>The latest close of the B round was led by Ahren Innovation Capital, which the startup notes counts two Nobel laureates as science partners. Also participating are two former American football players, Eli Manning and Ositadimma &#8220;Osi&#8221; Umenyiora; Boston, US-based seed fund Accomplice; healthcare-focused VC firm THVC and early stage European VC, Daphni.</p>
<p>The U.K.- and U.S.-based startup was founded back in 2017 but operated in stealth mode for three years, while it was conducting research into the microbiome &#8212; working with scientists from Massachusetts General Hospital, Stanford Medicine, Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health, and King’s College London.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>One of the founders, professor Tim Spector of King’s College &#8212; who is also the <a href="https://www.tim-spector.co.uk/the-diet-myth/#:~:text=THE%20DIET%20MYTH%20is%20a,into%20microbes%2C%20genetics%20and%20diet.">author</a> of a number of popular science books focused on food &#8212; became interested in the role of food (generally) and the microbiome (in particular) on overall health after spending decades researching twins to try to understand the role of genetics (nature) vs nurture (environmental and lifestyle factors) on human health.</p>
<p>Zoe used data from <a href="https://joinzoe.com/whitepapers/the-predict-program">two large-scale microbiome studies</a> to build its first algorithm which it began commercializing last September &#8212; launching its first product into the U.S. market: A home testing kit that enables program participants to learn how their body responds to different foods and get personalized nutrition advice.</p>
<p>The program costs around $360 (which Zoe takes in six instalments) and requires participants to (self) administer a number of tests so that it can analyze their biology, gleaning information about their metabolic and gut health by looking at changes in blood lipids, blood sugar levels and the types of bacteria in their gut.</p>
<p>Zoe uses big data and machine learning to come up with predictive insights on how people will respond to different foods so that it can offer individuals guided advice on what and how to eat, with the goal of improving gut health and reducing inflammatory responses caused by diet.</p>
<p>The combination of biological responses it analyzes sets it apart from other personalized nutrition startups with products focused on measuring one element (such as blood sugar) &#8212; is the claim.</p>
<p>But, to be clear, Zoe&#8217;s first product is not a regulated medical device &#8212; and its <a href="https://joinzoe.com/faqs">FAQ</a> clearly states that it does not offer medical diagnosis or treatment for specific conditions. Instead it says only that it&#8217;s &#8220;a tool that is meant for general wellness purposes only&#8221;. So &#8212; for now &#8212; users have to take it on trust that the nutrition advice it dishes up is actually helpful for them.</p>
<p>The field of scientific research into the microbiome is undoubtedly early &#8212; Zoe&#8217;s co-founder states that very clearly when we talk &#8212; so there&#8217;s a strong component here, as is often the case when startups seek to use data and AI to generate valuable personalized predictions, whereby early adopters are helping to further Zoe&#8217;s research by contributing their data. Potentially ahead of the sought for individual efficacy, given so much is still unknown around how what we eat affects our health.</p>
<p>For those willing to take a punt (and pay up), they get an individual report detailing their biological responses to specific foods that compares them to thousands of others. The startup also provides them with individualized &#8216;Zoe&#8217; scores for specific foods in order to support meal planning that&#8217;s touted as healthier for them.</p>
<p>&#8220;Reduce your dietary inflammation and improve gut health with a 4 week plan tailored to your unique biology and life,&#8221; runs the blurb on Zoe&#8217;s <a href="https://joinzoe.com/how-it-works">website</a>. &#8220;Built around your food scores, our app will teach you how to make smart swaps, week by week.&#8221;</p>
<p>The marketing also claims no food is &#8220;off limits&#8221; &#8212; implying there&#8217;s a difference between Zoe&#8217;s custom food scores and (weight-loss focused) diets that perhaps require people to cut out a food group (or groups) entirely.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our aim is to empower you with the information and tools you need to make the best decisions for your body,&#8221; is Zoe&#8217;s smooth claim.</p>
<p>The underlying premise is that each person&#8217;s biology responds differently to different foods. Or, to put it another way, while we all most likely know at least one person who stays rake-thin and (seemingly) healthy regardless of what (or even how much) they eat, if we ate the same diet we&#8217;d probably expect much less pleasing results.</p>
<p>&#8220;What we&#8217;re able to start scientifically putting some evidence behind is something that people have talked about for a long time,&#8221; says co-founder George Hadjigeorgiou. &#8220;It&#8217;s early [for scientific research into the microbiome] but we have shown now to the world that even twins have different gut microbiomes, we can change our gut microbiomes through diet, lifestyle and how we live &#8212; and also that there are associations around particular [gut] bacteria and foods and a way to improve them which people can actually do through our product.&#8221;</p>
<p>Users of Zoe&#8217;s first product need to be willing (and able) to get pretty involved with their own biology &#8212; collecting stool samples, performing finger prick tests and wearing a blood glucose monitor to feed in data so it can analyze how their body responds to different foods and offer up personalized nutrition advice.</p>
<p>Another component of its study of biological responses to food has involved thousands of people eating &#8220;special scientific muffins&#8221;, which it makes to standardized recipes, so it can benchmark and compare nutritional responses to a particular blend of calories, carbohydrate, fat, and protein.</p>
<p>While eating muffins for science sounds pretty fine, the level of intervention required to make use of Zoe&#8217;s first at-home test kit product is unlikely to appeal to those with only a casual interest in improving their nutrition.</p>
<p>Hadjigeorgiou readily agrees the program, as it is now, is for those with a particular problem to solve that can be linked to diet/nutrition (whether obesity, high cholesterol or a disease like type 2 diabetes, and so on). But he says Zoe&#8217;s goal is to be able to open up access to personalized nutrition advice much more widely as it keeps gathering more data and insights.</p>
<p>&#8220;The idea is, as always, we start with a focused set of people with problems to solve who we believe will have a life-changing experience,&#8221; he tells TechCrunch. &#8220;At this point we are not trying to create a product for everyone &#8212; and we understand that that has limitations in terms of how much we scale in the beginning. Although even still within this focused group of people I can assure you there&#8217;s tonnes of people!</p>
<p>&#8220;But absolutely the whole idea is that after we get a first [set of users]&#8230; then with more data and with more experience we can simplify and start making this simpler and more accessible &#8212; both in terms of its simplicity and also it&#8217;s price. So more and more people. Because at the end of the day everyone has this right to be able to optimize and understand and be in control &#8212; and we want to make that available to everyone.</p>
<p>&#8220;Regardless of background and regardless of socio-economic status. And, in fact, many of the people who have the biggest problems around health etc are the ones who have maybe less means and ability to do that.&#8221;</p>
<p>Zoe isn&#8217;t disclosing how many early users it&#8217;s onboarded so far but Hadjigeorgiou says demand is high (it&#8217;s currently operating a wait-list for new sign ups).</p>
<p>He also touts promising early results from interim trial with its first users &#8212; saying participants experienced more energy (90%), felt less hunger (80%) and lost an average of 11 pounds after three months of following their AI-aided, personalized nutrition plan. Albeit, without data on how many people are involved in the trials it&#8217;s not possible to quantify the value of those metrics.</p>
<p>The extra Series B funding will be used to accelerate the rollout of availability of the program, with a U.K. launch planned for this year &#8212; and other geographies on the cards for 2022. Spending will also go on continued recruitment in engineering and science, it says.</p>
<p>Zoe already grabbed some eyeballs last year, as the coronavirus pandemic hit the West, when it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/25/self-reporting-app-for-covid-19-symptoms-for-uk-research-sees-650k-downloads-in-24-hours/">launched a COVID-19 symptom self-reporting app</a>. It has used that data to help scientists and policy makers understand how the virus affects people.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TVmQO5ODul"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/25/self-reporting-app-for-covid-19-symptoms-for-uk-research-sees-650k-downloads-in-24-hours/">Self-reporting app tracking COVID-19 symptoms in UK sees 750K downloads in 24 hours</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Self-reporting app tracking COVID-19 symptoms in UK sees 750K downloads in 24 hours&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/25/self-reporting-app-for-covid-19-symptoms-for-uk-research-sees-650k-downloads-in-24-hours/embed/#?secret=TVmQO5ODul" data-secret="TVmQO5ODul" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The Zoe COVID-19 app has had some 5M users over the last year, per Hadjigeorgiou &#8212; who points to that (not-for-profit) effort as an example of the kind of transformative intervention the company hopes to drive in the nutrition space down the line.</p>
<p>&#8220;Overnight we got millions and millions of people contributing to help uncover new insights around science around COVID-19,&#8221; he says, highlighting that it&#8217;s been able to publish a number of research papers based on data contributed by app users. &#8220;For example the lack of smell and taste&#8230; was something that we first [were able to prove] scientifically, and then it became &#8212; because of that &#8212; an official symptom in the list of the government in the U.K.</p>
<p>&#8220;So that was a great example how through the participation of people &#8212; in a very, very fast way, which we couldn&#8217;t predict when we launched it &#8212; we managed to have a big impact.&#8221;</p>
<p>Returning to diet, aren&#8217;t there some pretty simple &#8216;rules of thumb&#8217; that anyone can apply to eat more healthily &#8212; i.e. without the need to shell out for a bespoke nutrition plan? Basic stuff like eat your greens, avoid processed foods and cut down (or out) sugar?</p>
<p>&#8220;There are definitely rules of thumb,&#8221; Hadjigeorgiou agrees. &#8220;We&#8217;ll be crazy to say they&#8217;re not. I think it all comes back to the point that although there are rules of thumb and over time &#8212; and also through our research, for example &#8212; they can become better, the fact of the matter is that most people are becoming less and less healthy. And the fact of the matter is that life is messy and people do not eat even according to these rules of thumb so I think part of the challenge is&#8230; [to] educate and empower people for their messy lives and their lifestyle to actually make better choices and apply them in a way that&#8217;s sustainable and motivating so they can be healthier.</p>
<p>&#8220;And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re finding with our customers. We are helping them to make these choices in an empowering way &#8212; they don&#8217;t need to count calories, they don&#8217;t need to restrict themselves through a Keto [diet] regime or something like that. We basically empower them to understand this is the impact food has on your body &#8212; real time, how your blood sugar levels change, how your bacteria change, how your blood fat levels changes. And through that empowerment through insight then we say hey, now we&#8217;ll give you this course, it&#8217;s very simple, it&#8217;s like a game &#8212; and we&#8217;ll given you all these tools to combine different foods, make foods work for you. No food is off limits &#8212; but try to eat most days a 75 score [based on the food points Zoe&#8217;s app assigns].</p>
<p>&#8220;In that very empowering way we see people get very excited, they see a fun game that is also impacting their gut and metabolism and they start feeling these amazing effects &#8212; in terms of less hunger, more energy, losing weight and over time as well evolving their health. That&#8217;s why they say it&#8217;s life changing as well.&#8221;</p>
<p>Gamifying research for the goal of a greater good? To the average person that surely sounds more appetitizing than &#8216;eat your greens&#8217;.</p>
<p>Though, as Hadjigeorgiou concedes, research in the field of microbiome &#8212; where Zoe&#8217;s commercial interests and research USP lie &#8212; is &#8220;early&#8221;. Which means that gathering more data to do more research will remain a key component of the business for the foreseeable future. And with so much still to be understood about the complex interactions between food, exercise and other lifestyle factors and human health, the mission is indeed massive.</p>
<p>In the meanwhile, Zoe will be taking it one suggestive nudge at a time.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;Sugar is bad, kale&#8217;s great but the whole kind of magic happens in the middle,&#8221; Hadjigeorgiou goes on. &#8220;Is oatmeal good for you? Is rice good for you? Is wholewheat pasta good for you? How do you combine wholewheat pasta and butter? How much do you have? This is where basically most of our life happens.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;Because people don&#8217;t eat ice-cream the whole day and people don&#8217;t eat kale the whole day. They eat all these other foods in the middle and that&#8217;s where the magic is &#8212; knowing how much to have, how to combine them to make it better, how to combine it with exercise to make it better? How to eat a food that doesn&#8217;t dip your sugar levels three hours after you eat it which causes hunger for you. Theses are all the things we&#8217;re able to predict and present in a simple and compelling way through a score system to people &#8212; and in turn help them [understand their] metabolic response to food.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kIeiNwBwSL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/22/eat-this-not-that-exercise-now-new-personalized-software-predicts-and-helps-prevents-blood-sugar-spikes/">Eat this, exercise now; new personalized software predicts and helps prevent blood sugar spikes</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Eat this, exercise now; new personalized software predicts and helps prevent blood sugar spikes&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/22/eat-this-not-that-exercise-now-new-personalized-software-predicts-and-helps-prevents-blood-sugar-spikes/embed/#?secret=kIeiNwBwSL" data-secret="kIeiNwBwSL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ApnR4ueNb4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/gainful-series-a/">Gainful raises $7.5M for personalized sports nutrition</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gainful raises $7.5M for personalized sports nutrition&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/gainful-series-a/embed/#?secret=ApnR4ueNb4" data-secret="ApnR4ueNb4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hvP7DGRiWS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/has-a-startup-finally-found-one-of-food-sciences-holy-grails-with-its-healthy-sugar-substitute/">Has a startup finally found one of food science&#8217;s holy grails with its healthy sugar substitute?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Has a startup finally found one of food science&#8217;s holy grails with its healthy sugar substitute?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/has-a-startup-finally-found-one-of-food-sciences-holy-grails-with-its-healthy-sugar-substitute/embed/#?secret=hvP7DGRiWS" data-secret="hvP7DGRiWS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/personalized-nutrition-startup-zoe-closes-out-series-b-at-53m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146133</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Radical Ethereum entrepreneurs are redefining what &#8216;rape kit&#8217; means</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/radical-ethereum-entrepreneurs-are-redefining-what-rape-kit-means/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/radical-ethereum-entrepreneurs-are-redefining-what-rape-kit-means/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Riggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 14:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leda Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexual assault]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146443</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Their investors call them disruptive innovators and detractors. Some call them “dirty scammers.” But the Leda Health co-founders think of themselves as advocates for sexual assault survivors.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Their investors call them disruptive innovators. Detractors like North Carolina Attorney General Josh Stein call them “</span><a href="https://www.wcnc.com/article/news/investigations/investigators/founders-of-metoo-at-home-rape-kit-defend-product-against-nc-ag-allegations/275-45487fea-ed35-4aee-bd9e-f13ada80db41"><span style="font-weight: 400;">dirty scammers</span></a>.<span style="font-weight: 400;">” But Leda Health co-founders Madison Campbell and Liesel Vaidya think of themselves as advocates for sexual assault survivors. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Among the </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/pussy-riot-shows-the-cypherpunk-power-of-feminist-nfts/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">feminists leveraging Ethereum</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for subversive use cases, Leda Health’s do-it-yourself evidence-collecting kit for sexual assault survivors is among the most ambitious projects. So far, 16 members of Congress </span><a href="https://sylviagarcia.house.gov/media/in-the-news/diy-rape-kits-metoo-and-preservekit-face-scrutiny"><span style="font-weight: 400;">condemned</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Leda Health’s </span><a href="https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2020/04/diy-remote-rape-kit-coronavirus/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">upcoming kits</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which Michigan Attorney General Dana Nessel described as “shamelessly trying to take financial advantage of the #MeToo movement.&#8221; Leda Health’s DIY kit was nearly banned in </span><a href="https://www.billtrack50.com/BillDetail/1151968"><span style="font-weight: 400;">New Hampshire</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://www.sltrib.com/news/2021/02/27/bill-ban-sale-diy-rape/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Utah</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> before it even launched. But that hasn’t deterred Campbell and Vaidya. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Campbell is a survivor herself, so she knows the reasons people don’t immediately go to police after an assault. In her case, by the time she’d grappled with the trauma and was ready to come forward, it would have just been her word against his.  </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There are also </span><a href="https://www.endthebacklog.org/backlog/what-rape-kit-backlog"><span style="font-weight: 400;">rape kits</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in every state that have been </span><a href="https://time.com/5731230/rape-kits-minneapolis/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">lost</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">,” Campbell said. “The sheer amount of sexual assault survivors that reach out to me and tell me this product could change their lives, that’s what keeps me going.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As such, Campbell said her startup plans to launch these kits in fall 2021, partnering with several universities for a beta rollout. Support services, to complement the take-home kits, include </span><a href="https://www.leda.co/healingcircles"><span style="font-weight: 400;">therapy and transformative justice</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> groups run by licensed facilitators.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We plan on being a business-to-business company, for universities and corporations and the military, partners like that,” Campbell said. “Our goal is for institutions to eventually pay for products and services to help these students. We know it will be difficult, that we’ll need a lot of case studies showing whether this helps&#8230; including healing work with people who committed harm about accountability and boundaries, to end that cycle of harm.” </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JXS381ga1Z"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/pussy-riot-shows-the-cypherpunk-power-of-feminist-nfts/">Pussy Riot shows the cypherpunk power of feminist NFTs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pussy Riot shows the cypherpunk power of feminist NFTs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/pussy-riot-shows-the-cypherpunk-power-of-feminist-nfts/embed/#?secret=JXS381ga1Z" data-secret="JXS381ga1Z" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Starting by offering institutions free therapy services and resources should seem like a no-brainer. Yet critics argue these kits give survivors false hope, because they are less effective in court than rape kits managed by law enforcement and related clinics. On the other hand, every year </span><a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/2015/07/16/untested-rape-kits-evidence-across-usa/29902199/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">tens of thousands</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of </span><a href="https://www.sacbee.com/news/politics-government/capitol-alert/article242840071.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">rape kits</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> aren’t tested by police. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vaidya said Leda Health’s Ethereum-powered mobile app gives survivors the choice to document their own accounts, using blockchain technology for time-stamping evidence collected in the kit, which puts power back in survivors’ hands. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re not in the business of proving consent. We’re just in the business of providing resources,” Vaidya said.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Chief Deputy District Attorney John Henry, in California’s Riverside County, this commercial product will be the first of its kind. He said it’s too soon to tell whether this could help survivors who are, for whatever reason, reluctant to immediately turn to law enforcement. Timing is also a factor. If the survivor is unable to get to a clinic promptly after the assault, there won’t be any biological evidence left to collect. </span></p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Love them or hate them, there’s no denying these blockchain-savvy entrepreneurs are challenging the status quo in a space where women are horrifically underserved.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nurses and police have some degree of experience and training on what to ask, where to follow up, what information is important. That is information the general public doesn’t have. As a prosecutor, I’d rather have those statements, and the additional investigation that goes on, done by law enforcement and medical personnel,” Henry said. “If a kit is collected in a way that is inconsistent with regulations and best practices, it’s not inadmissible. But that is something the jury would need to take into account… I can see the benefit of some type of evidence, as opposed to none. I can’t give a definitive opinion yet about whether it [Leda Health] is a good idea or a bad idea.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A rape kit alone, of any variety, cannot result in a conviction or expulsion. It is merely a tool used as part of a broader investigation. Even so, the idea of survivors managing their own data has sparked vehement backlash. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Back in 2019, our office was broken into,” Vaidya said. “We’ve also documented potential investors engaging with social media posts calling for us to be jailed.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Campbell added they are now both subjected to routine online harassment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We also take Ubers home from meetings or offices ever since 2019, because our lawyers told us not to take the subway. We might be followed,” Campbell said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The way this controversial kit works is a nondescript box comes with plastic bags, swabs and instructions all labeled with QR codes. Users download Leda Health’s app and are prompted to type in information while they save evidence of the assault, such as ripped panties, in separate Ziploc bags. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The blockchain creates a sense of accountability, because these records can’t be changed,” Vaidya said. “There’s only myself and perhaps one more person in the company that has access to the data and it’s encrypted&#8230;there are access locks regarding when and how and we might access that data if compelled to by a legal authority.” </span></p>
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter">
<div data-qa="message_content"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Leda Health outsources most of the tricky Ethereum software support to the blockchain startup </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://deqode.com/">Deqode</a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Deqode engineer Shivam Bohare said Leda Health’s system relies on Ethereum infrastructure services from </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.theblockcrypto.com/linked/84173/ethereum-data-startuo-funding-blocknative">Blocknative</a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a company that attracted investment from Coinbase Ventures, and </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://infura.io/">Infura</a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a startup </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.coindesk.com/consensys-investors-ethereum-2019-joe-lubin">partially owned</a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by Ethereum co-founder Joe Lubin. The encrypted data and profile are attached to a specific user account, not any self-custodied token, so the blockchain aspects of this app all occur under the hood. Users don’t need to know anything about Ethereum. </span></div>
</div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Access to the user data is guarded using strict authorization,” Bohare said. “Even the users don&#8217;t have access to their own data (without proper authorization from Leda Health administration) once it&#8217;s been uploaded to the cloud.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unlike a kit administered by police, survivors can physically hold the kit until they turn it over to lawyers or authorities, rather than hoping their case isn’t one of the thousands that gets lost in the system. Plus, the DIY kit, combined with the records stored through the app, can be used for mediation outside of court, like group therapy sessions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“People tend to forget that self-collected evidence is extremely common in the U.S. court system and analyzed for admissibility and other issues on a regular basis,” said attorney Jiadai Lin, who provides outside counsel to Leda Health. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Indeed, rape kits donated by another private manufacturer were </span><a href="https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2020/04/diy-remote-rape-kit-coronavirus/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">reportedly</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> used in April 2020 in Monterey County, California, under a temporary process developed for the pandemic.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I believe survivors should have the right to gather information about their own bodies on their own terms, and entrepreneurs should have the right to try their hand at innovation,” Lin said. “In my view, legislative efforts to ban the product have been excessively restrictive. And that makes me feel even more strongly about standing behind Leda Health.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Critics cast the startup’s entrepreneurial approach as greedy opportunism. Leda Health investors like Romeen Sheth, a Harvard law school alum and former co-president of the Harvard Association for Law and Business, poured $2 million into the startup so far because they believe the for-profit strategy can complement nonprofit organizations already working in this space. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Disruptive innovation in any industry is never comfortable; it never starts out as something that the incumbents are pleased with,” Sheth said. “I&#8217;m bullish on products and services that keep users as the top priority&#8230; I&#8217;m interested in investing in forward progress, not in maintaining the status quo. Leda Health defines that ethos and I&#8217;m hopeful their efforts make sexual trauma and sexual harassment less embarrassing, painful and traumatic.&#8221; </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, as </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Campbell and Vaidya finish work on the prototype, Leda Health already started offering support groups for sexual assault survivors, led by licensed therapists. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We have two groups going right now and another five starting in May,” Vaidya said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Love them or hate them, there’s no denying these blockchain-savvy entrepreneurs are challenging the status quo in a space where </span><a href="https://www.rainn.org/statistics/campus-sexual-violence"><span style="font-weight: 400;">women</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, in particular, are horrifically underserved by current resources. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“For sexual assault victims, the cost of the status quo, which includes under-reporting, a massive kit processing backlog and general lack of support services, is very high. Leda is demonstrating there are innovative low-risk solutions available,” said investor Duriya Farooqui. “Second, among the reasons an assault victim may not immediately report is because the procedure for collecting evidence via a rape kit can feel invasive and in itself can add to trauma. Leda wants to provide options.” </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/radical-ethereum-entrepreneurs-are-redefining-what-rape-kit-means/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146443</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>HoneyBook raises $155M at $1B+ valuation to help SMBs, freelancers manage their businesses</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/honeybook-raises-155m-at-1b-valuation-to-help-smbs-freelancers-manage-their-businesses/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/honeybook-raises-155m-at-1b-valuation-to-help-smbs-freelancers-manage-their-businesses/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 14:09:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advisors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business models]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chelsea Stoner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[citi ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[executive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[honeybook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[norwest venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[productivity tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[small business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tel Aviv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiger Global Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zeev Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2147233</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[HoneyBook, which has built out a client experience and financial management platform for service-based small businesses and freelancers, announced today that it has raised $155 million in a Series D round led by Durable Capital Partners LP. Tiger Global Management, Battery Ventures, Zeev Ventures, 01 Advisors as well as existing backers Norwest Venture Partners and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">HoneyBook, which has built out a client experience and financial management platform for service-based small businesses and freelancers, announced today that it has raised $155 million in a Series D round led by Durable Capital Partners LP.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tiger Global Management, Battery Ventures, Zeev Ventures, 01 Advisors as well as existing backers Norwest Venture Partners and Citi Ventures also participated in the financing, which brings the San Francisco-based company’s valuation to over $1 billion. With the latest round, HoneyBook has now raised $248 million since its 2013 inception. The Series D is a big jump from the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/21/honeybook-a-client-management-platform-for-creative-businesses-raises-28m-series-c-led-by-citi-ventures/">$28 million</a> that HoneyBook raised in March 2019. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When the COVID-19 pandemic hit last year, HoneyBook’s leadership team was concerned about the potential impact on their business and braced themselves for a drop in revenue.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rather than lay off people, they instead asked everyone to take a pay cut, and that included the executive team, who cut theirs “by double” the rest of the staff.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I remember it was terrifying. We knew that our customers’ businesses were going to be impacted dramatically, and would impact ours at the same time dramatically,” recalls </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">CEO Oz Alon</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. “We had to make some hard decisions.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But the resilience of HoneyBook’s customer base surprised even the company, who ended up reinstating those salaries just a few months later. And, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">as corporate layoffs driven by the COVID-19 pandemic led to more people deciding to start their own businesses, HoneyBook saw a big surge in demand.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our members who saw a hit in demand went out and found demand in another thing,” Oz said. As a result, HoneyBook ended up doubling its number of members on its SaaS platform and tripling its annual recurring revenue (ARR) over the past 12 months. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Members booked more than $1 billion in business on the platform in the past nine months alone. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">HoneyBook combines tools like billing, contracts, and client communication on its platform with the goal of helping business owners stay organized. Since its inception, service providers across the U.S. and Canada such as </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">graphic designers, event planners, digital marketers and photographers </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">have booked more than $3 billion in business on its platform. And as the pandemic had more people shift to doing more things online, HoneyBook prepared to help its members adapt by being armed with digital tools.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2147245" style="width: 585px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2147245" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2147245" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/HoneyBook_Features.png?w=300" alt="" width="575" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/HoneyBook_Features.png 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/HoneyBook_Features.png?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/HoneyBook_Features.png?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/HoneyBook_Features.png?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/HoneyBook_Features.png?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/HoneyBook_Features.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 575px) 100vw, 575px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2147245" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> HoneyBook</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Clients now expect streamlined communication, seamless payments, and the same level of exceptional service online, that they were used to receiving from business owners in person,” Alon said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oz co-founded HoneyBook with longtime friend Dror Shimoni and wife Naama. Oz and Naama were both small business owners themselves at one time, so they had firsthand insight on the pain points of running a service-based business. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">HoneyBook’s software not only helps SMBs do more business, but helps them “convert potentials to actual clients,” Oz said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We help them communicate with potential clients so they can win their business, and then help them manage the relationship so they can keep them,” Naama said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company plans to use its new capital toward continued </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">product development and to “dramatically” boost its 103-person headcount across its New York and Tel Aviv offices.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re seeing so much demand for additional services and products, so we definitely want to invest and create better ways for our members to present themselves online,” Alon told TechCrunch. “We’re also seeing demand for financial products and the ability to access capital faster. So that’s just a few of the things we plan to invest in.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company also wants to make its platform “more customizable” for different categories and verticals.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chelsea Stoner, general partner at Battery Ventures, said her firm recognized that the expansive market of productivity tools to serve small businesses and entrepreneurs was “a market of discrete and separate productivity tools.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">HoneyBook, she said, is a true platform for SMBs, “providing a huge array of functionality in one cohesive UX.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It unites and connects every task for the solopreneurs, from creating and distributing marketing collateral, to organizing and executing proposals, to sending invoices and collecting payments,” Stoner said. “The company is constantly innovating and iterating in response to its members; we also see a lot of opportunity with payments going forward&#8230;And, due to Covid-19 and other factors, the company is sitting on pent-up demand that will accelerate growth even more.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/honeybook-raises-155m-at-1b-valuation-to-help-smbs-freelancers-manage-their-businesses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2147233</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SAP CEO Christian Klein looks back on his first year</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/sap-ceo-christian-klein-looks-back-on-his-first-year/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/sap-ceo-christian-klein-looks-back-on-his-first-year/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 13:58:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christian Klein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Cloud and Enterprise Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ERP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sap]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146370</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As he looked back on the one-year mark, Klein sat down to discuss the unique set of challenges he faced.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">SAP CEO Christian Klein <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/10/saps-bill-mcdermott-on-stepping-down-as-ceo/">was appointed co-CEO</a> with Jennifer Morgan last April just as the pandemic was hitting full force across the world. Within six months, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/21/and-then-there-was-one-co-ceo-jennifer-morgan-to-depart-sap/">Morgan was gone and he was sole CEO</a>, put in charge of a storied company at 38 years old. By October, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/26/sap-shares-fall-sharply-after-covid-19-cuts-revenue-profit-forecast-at-software-giant/">its stock price was down</a> and revenue projections for the coming years were flat.</p>
<p>That is definitely not the way any CEO wants to start their tenure, but the pandemic forced Klein to make some decisions to move his customers to the cloud faster. That, in turn, had an impact on revenue until the transition was completed. While it makes sense to make this move now, investors weren&#8217;t happy with the news.</p>
<p>There was also the decision to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/26/sap-will-spin-out-its-8b-spin-in-qualtrics-acquisition/">spin out Qualtrics</a>, the company his predecessor <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/11/sap-agrees-to-buy-qualtrics-for-8b-in-cash-just-before-the-survey-software-companys-ipo/">acquired for $8 billion in 2018</a>. As he looked back on the one-year mark, Klein sat down with me to discuss all that has happened and the unique set of challenges he faced.</p>
<h2>Just a pandemic, no biggie</h2>
<p>Starting in the same month that a worldwide pandemic blows up presents unique challenges for a new leader. For starters, Klein couldn&#8217;t visit anyone in person and get to know the team. Instead, he went straight to Zoom and needed to make sure everything was still running.</p>
<p>The CEO says that the company kept chugging along in spite of the disruption. &#8220;When I took over this new role, I of course had some concerns about how to support 400,000 customers. After one year, I&#8217;ve been astonished. Our support centers are running without disruption and we are proud of that and continue to deliver value,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Taking over when he couldn&#8217;t meet in person with employees or customers has worked out better than he thought. &#8220;It was much better than I expected, and of course personally for me, it&#8217;s different. I&#8217;m the CEO, but I wasn&#8217;t able to travel and so I didn&#8217;t have the opportunity to go to the U.S., and this is something that I&#8217;m looking forward to now, meeting people and talking to them live,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s something he simply wasn&#8217;t able to do for his first year because of travel restrictions, so he says communication has been key, something a lot of executives have discussed during COVID. &#8220;I&#8217;m in regular contact with the employees, and we do it virtually. Still, it&#8217;s not the same as when you do it live, but it helps a lot these days. I would say you cannot over-communicate in such times,&#8221; he said.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/sap-ceo-christian-klein-looks-back-on-his-first-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146370</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Firefly Aerospace raises $75M Series A at a $1B+ valuation, plus $100M in secondary sale</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/firefly-aerospace-raises-75m-series-a-at-a-1b-valuation-plus-100m-in-secondary-sale/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/firefly-aerospace-raises-75m-series-a-at-a-1b-valuation-plus-100m-in-secondary-sale/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 13:37:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Firefly Aerospace]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2147194</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Firefly Aerospace has raised a total of $175 million, across a $75 million Series A round that valued the company north of $1 billion, and a $100 million secondary transaction which consisted of the sale of holdings held by primary Firefly investor Noosphere Ventures. The launch startup also announced that it intends to raise another [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Firefly Aerospace has raised a total of $175 million, across a $75 million Series A round that valued the company north of $1 billion, and a $100 million secondary transaction which consisted of the sale of holdings held by primary Firefly investor Noosphere Ventures. The launch startup also announced that it intends to raise another $300 million later in 2021, after its forthcoming inaugural Alpha rocket launch, which is currently targeting a June take-off.</p>
<p>Firefly is one of a crop of new commercial launch providers aiming to follow in the footsteps of SpaceX and Rocket Lab, with a goal of serving the growing small satellite launch market. The company has been developing its Alpha rocket for the past few years, and has also been awarded commercial and civil government launch contracts from NASA, General Atomics and others. The Texas-based startup has had its share of setbacks, including the bankruptcy of its original iteration, Firefly Space Systems, which was subsequently re-born as Firefly Aerospace as a wholly owned venture bankrolled by Noosphere Ventures.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s second life also includes a redesigned Alpha vehicle that has more launch capacity, with the ability to carry 1000kg to low Earth orbit, or 600kg to sun-synchronous orbit. It&#8217;s also developing a lunar lander called &#8216;Blue Ghost,&#8217; in order to provide lunar payload delivery services for NASA as part of its Commercial Lunar Payload Services (CLPS) program.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Firefly does appear closer than ever to actually flying its launch vehicle, with preparations already significantly advanced at its launch facility in Vandenberg Space Force Base in California. The June window for its debut flight is rapidly approaching, and the company is clearly hoping to use the momentum from that demonstration to boost interest for its next big raise, since it&#8217;s declaring its intentions ahead of head (while also claiming this Series A round was &#8220;oversubscribed.&#8221;)</p>
<p>The Series A ws led by DADA Holdings, and includes participation by Astera Institute, Canon Ball LLC and others. The secondary generated from the sale of Noosphere holdings also included Series A participants, as well as &#8220;other investors&#8221; according to Firefly.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/firefly-aerospace-raises-75m-series-a-at-a-1b-valuation-plus-100m-in-secondary-sale/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2147194</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tesla taps tiny startup&#8217;s tech to build cheaper, cleaner batteries</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/tesla-taps-tiny-startups-tech-to-build-cheaper-cleaner-batteries/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/tesla-taps-tiny-startups-tech-to-build-cheaper-cleaner-batteries/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 13:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CATL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG Chem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lithium ion batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Panasonic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2147076</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When Elon Musk stood on stage at Tesla’s Battery Day in September and promised to cut lithium-ion battery prices in half, he claimed some of the savings would come from reinventing the dirty and complex process of making their nickel metal cathodes. “It’s insanely complicated, like digging a ditch, filling it in and digging the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When Elon Musk stood on stage at Tesla’s Battery Day in September and promised to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/22/tesla-says-its-battery-innovations-will-deliver-its-goal-of-a-25000-mass-market-electric-car/">cut lithium-ion battery prices in half</a>, he claimed some of the savings would come from reinventing the dirty and complex process of making their nickel metal cathodes.</p>
<p>“It’s insanely complicated, like digging a ditch, filling it in and digging the ditch again,” <span style="font-weight: 400;">he said <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l6T9xIeZTds">at the event</a>. So we looked at the entire value chain and said how can we make this as simple as possible?”</span></p>
<p>The simplest route to appears to involve a small Canadian battery startup — or at least its patent applications.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Two weeks before Battery Day, Tesla purchased a number of patent applications from Springpower International, a small company based just outside Toronto, for a grand total of $3, <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/20692829-2021-1-26-spi-to-tesla-6-properties">according to public records</a>.</p>
<p>One of those applications details an innovative process similar to one that Drew Baglino, Tesla’s senior vice-president of engineering, described on stage at Tesla’s factory in Fremont, California, on Battery Day. Buying the patent application means that when the patent itself was finally granted in January, it was issued to Tesla, with no mention of Springpower.</p>
<p>Manufacturing cathodes for electric vehicle batteries traditionally generates large quantities of contaminated water &#8211;  up to 4,000 gallons containing ammonia, metal particles and toxic chemicals for every ton of cathode material produced. Springpower’s process cleverly <a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/US20210013507A1/en?q=%22METHOD+TO+PRODUCE+CATHODE+MATERIALS+FOR+LI-ION+BATTERIES%22&amp;oq=%22METHOD+TO+PRODUCE+CATHODE+MATERIALS+FOR+LI-ION+BATTERIES%22">recirculates the chemical solution</a>, removing the need for expensive water treatment.</p>
<p>Baglino’s presentation also depicted a method that also reuses water and produces no effluent. In addition to cutting operational costs by more than 75%, he said: “We can also use that same process to directly consume the metal powder coming out of recycled electric vehicle and grid storage batteries.”</p>
<p>It now seems likely that Tesla may have bought more than just Springpower’s intellectual property. A week before Battery Day, Springpower International’s website was replaced by a <a href="https://www.springpowerintl.com/">single holding page</a>. And in the months since then, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/yang-liu-8b50a9a2/">several</a> Springpower <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/amrit-bhogan-b395a1140/">researchers have altered their LinkedIn profiles to indicate that they are now working at Tesla. </a></p>
<p>Springpower International CEO Michael Wang, whose own <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-w-511278b/detail/recent-activity/">LinkedIn page</a>now features dozens of updates from Tesla staffers (including Baglino), did not respond to a request for comment, and calls to the company’s switchboard went unanswered.</p>
<p>A senior Springpower International executive reached by phone would neither confirm nor deny Tesla’s purchase, and referred TechCrunch to Tesla’s public affairs team. (Tesla no longer has a press office, and emails to the company did not receive a reply).</p>
<p>Springpower International was founded in March 2010, in part by Chinese battery firm Highpower International, as a research arm for its Springpower subsidiary in Shenzen. But Highpower walked away from Springpower International within six months, writing off a $100,000 investment after deciding its technologies were too far from commercialization.</p>
<p>James Sbrolla, an “entrepreneur in residence” at a Canadian government-funded program, stepped in to mentor the young company. He helped it secure some small grants, and ultimately a $3.4 million (Canadian) sustainable technology award in <a href="https://www.canada.ca/en/innovation-science-economic-development/news/2018/04/government-of-canada-invests-in-cutting-edge-clean-technology.html">2018</a>. However, he told TechCrunch that he has not talked to anyone at Springpower International since late 2020.</p>
<p>Sbrolla was not surprised to hear that the company might have been purchased.</p>
<p>“It&#8217;s a group of smart people, no question about it,” Sbrolla said. “Technology like Springpower&#8217;s gives tremendous upside with a reduced environmental footprint, and being attached to a larger organization makes scaling much quicker and easier.”</p>
<p>If, as seems likely, Springpower International has been acquired by Tesla, it would join only a dozen or so others, including another Canadian battery company, Hibar,<a href="https://electricautonomy.ca/2019/10/04/tesla-acquires-canadian-battery-specialist-hibar-systems/"> bought in similar stealth </a>in 2019.</p>
<p>Elon Musk has long looked north of the border for lithium-ion battery expertise. In 2015, Tesla signed a five-year exclusive partnership with Jeff Dahn, a leading battery researcher and professor at Dalhousie University in Nova Scotia. Dahn is named on a <a href="https://patents.google.com/?q=dahn+tesla&amp;assignee=Tesla+Motors+Canada+ULC">number of recent Tesla battery patents</a>, and in January Tesla renewed Dahn’s contract for another five years.<br />
Musk is on a years-long push to bring battery production in-house and scale back Tesla’s reliance on its current suppliers, Panasonic, LG Chem, and CATL. “Now that we have this process, we&#8217;re going to start building our own cathode facility in North America,” said Baglino on Battery Day.</p>
<p>Musk added that the combined benefits of Tesla’s new battery technologies could enable a $25,000 vehicle, but cautioned not to expect too much, too soon: “It will take us probably a year to 18 months to start realizing these advantages, and three years or thereabouts to fully realize them.”</p>
<p>Perhaps by that time, Springpower International’s role will be a little clearer.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0PRr9Kn5tu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/can-solid-state-batteries-power-up-for-the-next-generation-of-evs/">Can solid state batteries power up for the next generation of EVs?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Can solid state batteries power up for the next generation of EVs?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/can-solid-state-batteries-power-up-for-the-next-generation-of-evs/embed/#?secret=0PRr9Kn5tu" data-secret="0PRr9Kn5tu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/tesla-taps-tiny-startups-tech-to-build-cheaper-cleaner-batteries/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2147076</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter acquires distraction-free reading service Scroll to beef up its subscription product</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/twitter-acquires-distraction-free-reading-service-scroll-to-beef-up-its-subscription-product/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/twitter-acquires-distraction-free-reading-service-scroll-to-beef-up-its-subscription-product/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 13:23:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nuzzel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paywall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[publishers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scroll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscriptions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2147183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter this morning announced it&#8217;s acquiring Scroll, a subscription service that offers readers a better way to read through long-form content on the web, by removing ads and other website clutter that can slow down the experience. The service will become a part of Twitter&#8217;s larger plans to invest in subscriptions, the company says, and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter this morning announced it&#8217;s acquiring <a href="https://scroll.com/">Scroll</a>, a subscription service that offers readers a better way to read through long-form content on the web, by removing ads and other website clutter that can slow down the experience. The service will become a part of Twitter&#8217;s larger plans to invest in subscriptions, the company says, and will later be offered as one of the premium features Twitter will provide to subscribers.</p>
<p>Premium subscribers will be able to use Scroll to easily read their articles from news outlets and from Twitter&#8217;s own newsletters product, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitter-acquires-revue/">Revue</a>, another recent <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitter-acquires-revue/">acquisition</a> that&#8217;s already been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/twitter-quietly-rolls-out-revue-newsletters-integration-on-web/">integrated</a> into Twitter&#8217;s service. When subscribers use Scroll through Twitter, a portion of their subscription revenue would go to support the publishers and the writers creating the content, explains Twitter in an <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2021/a-better-way-to-publish-and-read-on-twitter.html">announcement</a>.</p>
<p>Scroll&#8217;s service today works across hundreds of sites, including The Atlantic, The Verge, USA Today, The Sacramento Bee, The Philadelphia Inquirer and The Daily Beast, among others. For readers, the experience of using Scroll is similar to that of a &#8220;reader view&#8221; &#8212; ads, trackers, and other website junk is stripped so readers can focus on the content.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2147196" style="width: 650px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2147196" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2147196" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/scroll-before-afterr.gif?w=640" alt="" width="640" height="640" /><p id="caption-attachment-2147196" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twitter</p></div></p>
<p>Scroll&#8217;s pitch to publishers has been that it can end up delivering cleaner content that can make them more money than advertising alone.</p>
<p>Deal terms were not disclosed, but Twitter will be bringing on the entire Scroll team, totalling 13 people.</p>
<p>For the time being, Scroll will pause new customer sign-ups so it can focus on integrating its product into Twitter&#8217;s subscriptions work and prepare for the expected growth. It will, however, continue to <a href="https://partner.scroll.com/">onboard</a> new publishers who want to participate in Scroll&#8217;s network, following the deal&#8217;s closure.</p>
<p>And Scroll itself will be headed back into private beta as the team works to integrate the product into Twitter.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2147206" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2147206" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2147206" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/scroll-blog-image.png.img_.fullhd.medium.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="478" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/scroll-blog-image.png.img_.fullhd.medium.png 1120w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/scroll-blog-image.png.img_.fullhd.medium.png?resize=150,106 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/scroll-blog-image.png.img_.fullhd.medium.png?resize=300,211 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/scroll-blog-image.png.img_.fullhd.medium.png?resize=768,540 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/scroll-blog-image.png.img_.fullhd.medium.png?resize=680,478 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/scroll-blog-image.png.img_.fullhd.medium.png?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2147206" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twitter</p></div></p>
<p>Twitter says it will also be winding down Scroll&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/07/scroll-acquires-nuzzel/">news aggregator Nuzzel product</a>, but will work to bring some of Nuzzel&#8217;s core elements to Twitter over time. Nuzzel&#8217;s <a href="https://blog.nuzzel.com/nuzzel-is-going-away-for-now/">blog post</a> has more details, explaining that the product will need to be rebuilt in order to scale with Twitter.</p>
<p>&#8220;Twitter exists to serve the public conversation. Journalism is the mitochondria of that conversation. It initiates, energizes and informs. It converts and confounds perspectives. At its best it helps us stand in one another’s shoes and understand each other’s common humanity,&#8221; said Tony Haile, Scroll CEO, in the <a href="https://scroll.blog/2021/05/04/scroll-is-joining-twitter/">company&#8217;s post about Scroll&#8217;s acquisition</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;The mission we’ve been given by Jack and the Twitter team is simple: take the model and platform that Scroll has built and scale it so that everyone who uses Twitter has the opportunity to experience an internet without friction and frustration, a great gathering of people who love the news and pay to sustainably support it,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Twitter earlier this year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/twitters-super-follow-creator-subscription-takes-shots-at-substack-and-patreon/">detailed its plans to head into subscriptions</a>, as a way to diversify beyond ad revenue for its own business. The company unveiled what it&#8217;s calling &#8220;Super Follow,&#8221; a creator-focused subscription that would give paid subscribers access to an expanded array of perks, like exclusive content, subscriber-only newsletters, deals, badges, paywalled media, and more. The company is aiming to use this new product to help it achieve its goal of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/twitter-plans-to-double-revenue-by-2023-reach-315m-daily-users/">doubling company revenue</a> from $3.7 billion in 2020 to $7.5 billion or more in 2023, it said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/twitter-acquires-distraction-free-reading-service-scroll-to-beef-up-its-subscription-product/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2147183</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indian online teaching platform Teachmint raises $16.5 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/indian-online-teaching-platform-teachmint-raises-16-5-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/indian-online-teaching-platform-teachmint-raises-16-5-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 13:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Better Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learn capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed india partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2147172</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An Indian startup that began its life after the global pandemic broke last year said on Tuesday it has concluded its third financing round as it enables hundreds of thousands of teachers in the world&#8217;s second largest internet market run classes online and serve their students. Bangalore-based Teachmint said today it has raised $16.5 million [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">An Indian startup that began its life after the global pandemic broke last year said on Tuesday it has concluded its third financing round as it enables hundreds of thousands of teachers in the world&#8217;s second largest internet market run classes online and serve their students.</p>
<p>Bangalore-based <a href="https://www.teachmint.com">Teachmint</a> said today it has raised $16.5 million in its Series A financing round. The round was led by Learn Capital, the San Francisco Bay Area-headquartered venture capital firm that focuses on edtech firms and has backed some of the world&#8217;s most promising online learning startups including Coursera, Udemy, Nerdy, Minerva, and Brainly.</p>
<p>Existing investors Better Capital, which first invested in Teachmint before the startup had even registered itself, and Lightspeed India Partners also participated in the new round, which brings the Indian startup&#8217;s to-date raise to $20 million.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Teachmint helps teachers conduct classes online through an app on their Android smartphone or iPhone or through web. The startup has built an all-in-one product that allows teachers to kickstart a live class, do doubt-clearing sessions, take attendance, conduct webinars, collect fees, find new students, offer support via phone calls, and take tests among other tasks.</p>
<p>&#8220;When the pandemic broke, teachers were struggling with several tools including Google Meet, Zoom and even Youtube/Facebook Live to teach online. They were using additional tools like Google Forms for tests and WhatsApp for communication. It was a difficult and disconnected experience for most teachers as none of these tools were productised for teaching. That’s when we decided to build a mobile-first video-first solution specifically for teaching,” said Mihir Gupta, co-founder and chief executive of Teachmint, in an interview with TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The product, available in 10 local languages, is highly localised for India-specific needs, said Gupta.</p>
<p>More than 700,000 teachers from over 1,500 cities and towns have signed up on the platform in less than 10 months since the launch of Teachmint&#8217;s product, said Gupta.</p>
<p>“From the Learn Capital team’s first meeting with Teachmint’s co-founders several months ago, it was clear that their collective team had meticulously architected an end-to-end, multi-modal, and best-in-class solution enabling teachers in India to instantly and seamlessly digitize their classrooms,&#8221; said Vinit Sukhija, Partner at Learn Capital, in a statement.</p>
<p>&#8220;Now with over 700,000 teachers, Teachmint has become India’s leading online teaching platform,&#8221; he said, adding that Learn Capital believes that Teachmint can eventually expand its offering outside of India.</p>
<p>Gupta said Teachmint is currently not monetizing its product, and doesn&#8217;t intend to do so in the immediate future as it is currently priortizing reaching more teachers in India and also expand its offerings.</p>
<p>He said most teachers have learnt about Teachmint through friends and network  with limited investment in marketing. Teachmint is open to exploring any strategic acquisition opportunities with smaller startups, he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/indian-online-teaching-platform-teachmint-raises-16-5-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2147172</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Persona lands $50M for identity verification after seeing 10x YoY revenue growth</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/persona-lands-50m-for-identity-verification-after-seeing-10x-yoy-revenue-growth/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/persona-lands-50m-for-identity-verification-after-seeing-10x-yoy-revenue-growth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Angellist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coatue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[driver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[identity verification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Index Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mark goldberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[verification]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2147049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The identity verification space has been heating up for a while and the COVID-19 pandemic has only accelerated demand with more people transacting online. Persona, a startup focused on creating a personalized identity verification experience “for any use case,” aims to differentiate itself in an increasingly crowded space. And investors are banking on the San [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The identity verification space has been heating up for a while and the COVID-19 pandemic has only accelerated demand with more people transacting online.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://withpersona.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Persona</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a startup focused on creating a personalized identity verification experience “for any use case,” aims to differentiate itself in an increasingly crowded space. And investors are banking on the San Francisco-based company’s ability to help businesses customize the identity verification process &#8212; and beyond &#8212; via its no-code platform in the form of a $50 million Series B funding round. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Index Ventures led the financing, which also included participation from existing backer Coatue Management. In late January 2020, Persona raised $17.5 million in a Series A round. The company declined to reveal at which valuation this latest round was raised.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Businesses and organizations can access Persona’s platform by way of an API, which lets them use a variety of documents, from government-issued IDs through to biometrics, to verify that customers are who they say they are. The company wants</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to make it easier for organizations to implement more watertight methods based on third-party documentation, real-time evaluation such as live selfie checks and AI to verify users.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Persona&#8217;s platform also collects passive signals such as a user’s device, location, and behavioral signals to provide a more holistic view of a user’s risk profile. It offers a low code and no code option depending on the needs of the customer.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company’s momentum is reflected in its growth numbers. The startup&#8217;s revenue has surged by “more than 10 times” while its customer base has climbed by five times over the past year, according to co-founder and CEO Rick Song, who did not provide hard revenue numbers. Meanwhile, Persona&#8217;s headcount has more than tripled to just over 50 people.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="760ZIRUAzF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/3-steps-to-ease-the-transition-to-a-no-code-company/">3 steps to ease the transition to a no-code company</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 steps to ease the transition to a no-code company&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/3-steps-to-ease-the-transition-to-a-no-code-company/embed/#?secret=760ZIRUAzF" data-secret="760ZIRUAzF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">When we look back at the space five to 10 years ago, AI was the next differentiation and every identity verification company is doing AI and machine learning,” Song told TechCrunch. “We believe the next big differentiator is more about tailoring and personalizing the experience for individuals.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As such, Song believes that growth can be directly tied to Persona’s ability to help companies with “unique” use cases with a SaaS platform that requires little to no code and not as much heavy lifting from their engineering teams. Its end goal, ultimately, is to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">help businesses deter fraud, stay compliant and build trust and safety while making it easier for them to customize the verification process to their needs. Customers span a variety of industries, and include Square, Robinhood, Sonder, Brex, Udemy, Gusto, BlockFi and AngelList, among others.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The strategy your business needs for identity verification and management is going to be completely different if you’re a travel company verifying guests versus a delivery service onboarding new couriers versus a crypto company granting access to user funds,” Song added. “Even businesses within the same industry should tailor the identity verification experience to each customer if they want to stand out.”</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2147253" style="width: 631px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2147253" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2147253" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/persona-dashboard-transparent@2x-2.png?w=300" alt="" width="621" height="449" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/persona-dashboard-transparent@2x-2.png 1680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/persona-dashboard-transparent@2x-2.png?resize=150,109 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/persona-dashboard-transparent@2x-2.png?resize=300,217 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/persona-dashboard-transparent@2x-2.png?resize=768,556 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/persona-dashboard-transparent@2x-2.png?resize=680,492 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/persona-dashboard-transparent@2x-2.png?resize=1536,1112 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/persona-dashboard-transparent@2x-2.png?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 621px) 100vw, 621px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2147253" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Persona</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Song, another thing that helps Persona stand out is its ability to help customers beyond the sign-on and verification process. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’ve built an identity infrastructure because we don&#8217;t just help businesses at a single point in time, but rather throughout the entire lifecycle of a relationship,” he told TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In fact, much of the company’s growth last year came in the form of existing customers finding new use cases within the platform in addition to new customers signing on, Song said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’ve been watching existing customers discover more ways to use Persona. For example, we were working with some of our customer base on a single use case and now we might be working with them on 10 different problems &#8212; anywhere from account opening to a bad actor investigation to account recovery and anything in between,” he added. “So that has probably been the biggest driver of our growth.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Index Ventures Partner Mark Goldberg, who is taking a seat on Persona’s board as part of the financing, said he was impressed by the number of companies in Index’s own portfolio that raved about Persona.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’ve had our antennas up for a long time in this space,” he told TechCrunch. “We started to see really rapid adoption of Persona within the Index portfolio and there was the sense of a very powerful and very user friendly tool, which hadn&#8217;t really existed in the category before.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Its personalization capabilities and building block-based approach too, Goldberg said, makes it appealing to a broader pool of users.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The reality is there&#8217;s so many ways to verify a user is who they say they are or not on the internet, and if you give people the flexibility to design the right path to get to a yes or no, you can just get to a much better outcome,” he said. “That was one of the things we heard &#8212; that the use cases were not like off the rack, and I think that has really resonated in a time where people want and expect the ability to customize.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Persona plans to use its new capital<span style="font-weight: 400;"> to grow its team another twofold by year&#8217;s end to support its growth and continue scaling the business.</span></p>
<p>In recent months, other companies in the space that have raised big rounds include Socure and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/fraud-prevention-platform-sift-raises-50m-at-over-1b-valuation-eyes-acquisitions/">Sift</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IuCzctggUd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/socure-raises-100m-at-1-3b-valuation-proving-identity-verification-is-hotter-than-ever/">Socure raises $100M at $1.3B valuation, proving identity verification is hotter than ever</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Socure raises $100M at $1.3B valuation, proving identity verification is hotter than ever&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/socure-raises-100m-at-1-3b-valuation-proving-identity-verification-is-hotter-than-ever/embed/#?secret=IuCzctggUd" data-secret="IuCzctggUd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/persona-lands-50m-for-identity-verification-after-seeing-10x-yoy-revenue-growth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2147049</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Starboard Value puts Box on notice that it&#8217;s looking to take over board</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/starboard-value-puts-box-on-notice-that-its-looking-to-take-over-board/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/starboard-value-puts-box-on-notice-that-its-looking-to-take-over-board/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 12:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[activist investors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Box]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud content management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starboard Value]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2147144</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Activist investor Starboard Value is clearly fed up with Box and it let the cloud content management know it in no uncertain terms in a letter published yesterday. The firm, which bought a 7.7% stake in Box two years ago claims the company is underperforming, executing poorly and making bad business decisions &#8212; and it [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Activist investor <a href="https://www.starboardvalue.com/">Starboard Value</a> is clearly fed up with Box and it let the cloud content management know it in no uncertain terms in a <a href="https://www.starboardvalue.com/wp-content/uploads/Starboard_Value_LP_Letter_to_Box_Stockholders_05.03.2021.pdf">letter published yesterday</a>. The firm, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/03/starboard-value-takes-7-5-stake-in-box/">bought a 7.7% stake in Box</a> two years ago claims the company is underperforming, executing poorly and making bad business decisions &#8212; and it wants to inject the board of directors with new blood.</p>
<p>While they couched the letter in mostly polite language, it&#8217;s quite clear Starboard is exasperated with Box. &#8220;While we appreciate the dialogue we have had with Box&#8217;s management team and Board of Directors (the &#8220;Board&#8221;) over the past two years, we have grown increasingly frustrated with continued poor results, questionable capital allocation decisions, and subpar shareholder returns,&#8221; Starboard wrote in its letter.</p>
<p>Box as you can imagine did not take kindly to the shot across its bow and <a href="https://www.boxinvestorrelations.com/news-and-media/news/press-release-details/2021/Box-Responds-to-Starboard-Value-and-Reiterates-the-Boards-Unified-Commitment-to-Stockholder-Value-Creation/default.aspx">responded in a press release</a> that it has bent over backwards to accommodate Starboard including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/23/activist-investor-starboard-value-taking-three-box-board-seats-as-involvement-deepens/">refreshing the board last year</a> when they added several numbers, whom they point out were approved by Starboard.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Box has a diverse and independent Board with directors who bring extensive technology experience across enterprise and consumer markets, enterprise IT, and global go-to-market strategy, as well as deep financial acumen and proven track records of helping public companies drive disciplined growth, profitability, and stockholder value. Furthermore, seven of the ten directors on the Box Board will have joined the Board within the last three years,&#8221; the company wrote in a statement. In other words, Box is saying it already has injected the new blood that Starboard claims it wants.</p>
<p>Box recently got <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/08/kkr-hands-box-a-500m-lifeline/">a $500 million cash injection from KKR</a> widely believed to be an attempt to bulk up cash reserves with the goal generating growth via acquisition. Starboard was particularly taken aback by this move, however. &#8220;The only viable explanation for this financing is a shameless and utterly transparent attempt to &#8220;buy the vote&#8221; and shows complete disregard for proper corporate governance and fiscal discipline,&#8221; Starboard wrote.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xB8uJCCrzS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/08/kkr-hands-box-a-500m-lifeline/">KKR hands Box a $500M lifeline</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;KKR hands Box a $500M lifeline&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/08/kkr-hands-box-a-500m-lifeline/embed/#?secret=xB8uJCCrzS" data-secret="xB8uJCCrzS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Alan Pelz-Sharpe, founder and principal analyst at Deep Analysis, a firm that closely tracks the content management market, says the two sides clearly aren&#8217;t aligned and that&#8217;s not likely to change. &#8220;Starboard targeted and gained a seat on the board at Box at a difficult time for the firm, thats the modus operandi for activist investors. Since that time there has clearly been a lot of improvements in terms of Box’s financial goals. However, there is and will remain a misalignment between Starboard&#8217;s goals, and Box led by Levie as a whole. Though both would like to see the share price rise, Starboard&#8217;s end goal is most likely to see Box acquired, sooner rather than later, and that is not Box&#8217;s goal,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Starboard believes the only way to resolve this situation is to inject the board with still more new blood, taking a swipe at the Box leadership team while it was at it. &#8220;There is no good reason that Box should be unable to deliver improved growth and profitability, at least in-line with better performing software companies, which, in turn, would create significant shareholder value,&#8221; Starboard wrote.</p>
<p>As such the firm indicated it would be putting up its own slate of board candidates at the company&#8217;s next board meeting. In the tit for tat that has been this exchange, Box indicated it would be doing the same.</p>
<p>Meanwhile Box vigorously defended its results. &#8220;In the past year, under the oversight of the Operating Committee, the company has made substantial progress across all facets of the business &#8212; strategic, operational and financial &#8212; as demonstrated by the strong results reported for the full year of fiscal 2021,&#8221; the company wrote, pointing to its revenue growth last fiscal year as proof of the progress with revenue of $771 million up 11% year over year.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s unclear how this standoff will play out, but clearly Starboard wants to take over the Board and have its way with Box, believing that it can perform better if it were in charge. That could result ultimately, as Pelz-Sharpe suggested, in Box being acquired.</p>
<p>We would appear to heading for a showdown, and when it&#8217;s over, Box could be a very different company, or the current leadership could assert control once and for all and we could proceed with Box&#8217;s current growth strategy still in place. Time will tell which is the case.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HEX7HVPmMy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/as-activist-investors-loom-whats-next-for-box/">As activist investors loom, what’s next for Box?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As activist investors loom, what’s next for Box?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/as-activist-investors-loom-whats-next-for-box/embed/#?secret=HEX7HVPmMy" data-secret="HEX7HVPmMy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/starboard-value-puts-box-on-notice-that-its-looking-to-take-over-board/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2147144</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Acronis raises $250M at a $2.5B+ valuation to double down on cyber protection services</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/acronis-raises-250m-at-a-2-5b-valuation-to-double-down-on-cyber-protection-services/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/acronis-raises-250m-at-a-2-5b-valuation-to-double-down-on-cyber-protection-services/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 12:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2147139</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As cybersecurity continues to grow in profile amid an increasingly complex and dangerous landscape of malicious activity, a cyber security vendor that specializes in &#8220;all-in-one&#8221; services covering the many aspects of security IT has closed a big round of funding to grow. Acronis has raised $250 million in equity, and co-founder and CEO Serguei Beloussov [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As cybersecurity continues to grow in profile amid an increasingly complex and dangerous landscape of malicious activity, a cyber security vendor that specializes in &#8220;all-in-one&#8221; services covering the many aspects of security IT has closed a big round of funding to grow.</p>
<p>Acronis has raised $250 million in equity, and co-founder and CEO Serguei Beloussov said in an interview the company plans to use the financing both to grow organically, as well as for acquisitions to bring more &#8220;proactive&#8221; technology into its portfolio. The funding is being led by CVC and values Acronis at over $2.5 billion.</p>
<p>Originally a spinoff from the parent company of virtualization giant Parallels, Acronis initially made its name in data recovery and backup but has over time, and to better differentiate itself from competitors like Commvault, Veeam and Barracuda (among others), it has expanded to provide an all-in-one package of services to include continuous data protection, patch management, anti-malware protection and more.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Integrating with a range of popular enterprise <a href="https://solutions.acronis.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">software packages and platforms</a> and service providers, its business is now profitable, with some 10,000 managed service providers and 500,000 businesses (SMBs and bigger) among its customers.</p>
<p>&#8220;We didn’t need the money, but now we will invest it to grow faster and capitalise on our leadership,&#8221; Beloussov said in an interview.</p>
<p>New-wave revenues, based on its newer (not legacy) products such as Acronis Cyber Protect, grew 100% during the pandemic, he added. &#8220;We are s<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">pending they money on engineers and M&amp;A to complement our cyber protection,&#8221; he said. &#8220;</span>We have a single mission, which is to protect all data applications, providing privacy and security in one package. We protect about 10 million workloads today and we are aiming to grow that to 100x. There is a lot to do in terms of making that protection easier and deeper for our customers.&#8221;</p>
<p>He said that while the company is continuing to remain private, it&#8217;s also starting to think about its next steps, which could involve a public listing or a sale, in the next 12-24 months.</p>
<p>&#8220;With private equity investors like Goldman Sachs [which led its previous round in 2019] and CVC, they definitely expect liquidity at some point,&#8221; Beloussov said.</p>
<p>The funding and Acronis&#8217;s strategy to double down on growing its business comes at a key moment in the world of cybersecurity. The bigger landscape in the world of business has seen a huge shift in the last year to more people working remotely and across a wider set of geographies and devices. Although that shift was pushed along by the Covid-19 pandemic, many believe that the longer-term effect will be a very different working environment, with a greater acceptance that less people in will be spending all of their time in their offices, and that it won&#8217;t necessarily impact productivity.</p>
<p>What it has impacted is how IT provisions and manages networks and the device that run on them, and specifically has exposed some of the loopholes in company&#8217;s cybersecurity policies. Malicious hackers, who were hard at work well before the pandemic, have jumped on this and exploited it.</p>
<p>Acronis has been one of the companies that has seen a growing demand for its services as a result of all that, with   Acronis&#8217;s software sold via managed service providers seeing a particular lift.</p>
<p class="p1">&#8220;Last year definitely pushed customers to understand that IT is mission critical and that is for every business,&#8221; Beloussov said, with security coming along with that by association. With security, though, organizations have realized that &#8220;managing by in-house resources is not always ideal so outsourcing to special service providers can guarantee service levels. With internal IT people, you can only shout at them, and that is okay because they are used to it.&#8221; Third parties, by contrast, operate with service-level agreements that are easier to enforce if something goes wrong.</p>
<p class="p1">“Acronis’ talented management and R&amp;D teams have invested significant resources developing an innovative cloud-native ‘MSP in a box’ solution, with integrated backup, disaster recovery, cybersecurity, remote management, and workflow tools,” said Leif Lindbäck, Senior Managing Director of CVC Capital Partners. “Acronis provides mission-critical solutions to more than 10,000 MSPs and half a million small and medium businesses. CVC has a strong track record in cybersecurity and partnering up with successful entrepreneurs, and we are looking forward to teaming up with Serguei Beloussov and the Acronis team to accelerate the company’s growth.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/acronis-raises-250m-at-a-2-5b-valuation-to-double-down-on-cyber-protection-services/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2147139</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India grants approval for 5G trials, avoids Chinese firms</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/india-grants-approval-for-5g-trials-avoids-chinese-firms/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/india-grants-approval-for-5g-trials-avoids-chinese-firms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 12:07:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airtel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Huawei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jio Platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vodafone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vodafone Idea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zte]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2147143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Indian telecom ministry on Tuesday said it has granted several telecom service providers permission to conduct a six-month trial for the use and application of 5G technology in the country. New Delhi has granted approval to over a dozen firm spanning multiple nationalities &#8212; excluding China. Among the telecom operators that have received the grant include [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Indian telecom ministry on Tuesday said it has granted several telecom service providers permission to conduct a six-month trial for the use and application of 5G technology in the country. New Delhi has granted approval to over a dozen firm spanning multiple nationalities &#8212; excluding China.</p>
<p>Among the telecom operators that have received the grant include Jio Platforms, Airtel, Vodafone Idea, and MTNL. These firms, the ministry said, will work with original equipment manufacturers and tech providers Ericsson, Nokia, Samsung, and C-Dot. Jio Platforms, additionally, has been granted permission to conduct trials using its own homegrown technology.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://www.pib.gov.in/PressReleseDetailm.aspx?PRID=1715927">press note</a>, the Department of Telecommunications didn&#8217;t specify anything about China, but a person familiar with the matter confirmed that Chinese giants Huawei and ZTE aren&#8217;t among those who have received the approval.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Last year, Airtel (India&#8217;s second largest telecom operator) had said that it was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/reliance-jio-platforms-says-it-will-roll-out-5g-in-india-in-second-half-of-2021/">open to the idea of collaborating with global firms for components</a>. “Huawei, over the last 10 or 12 years, has become extremely good with their products to a point where I can safely today say their products at least in 3G, 4G that we have experienced is significantly superior to Ericsson and Nokia without a doubt. And I use all three of them,” Sunil Mittal, the founder of Airtel, said at a conference last year.</p>
<p>In the same panel, then U.S. commerce secretary Wilbur Ross had urged India and other allies of the U.S. to avoid Huawei. The geo-political tension between India and China escalated last year with skirmishes at the shared border. India, which early last year amended a rule to make it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/18/to-avoid-hostile-takeovers-amid-covid-19-india-mandates-approvals-on-chinese-investments/">difficult for Chinese firms to invest in Indian companies</a>, has since banned <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/29/india-bans-tiktok-dozens-of-other-chinese-apps/">over 200 apps including TikTok, UC Browser, and PUBG Mobile</a> that have affiliation with China over cybersecurity concerns.</p>
<p>India&#8217;s move on Tuesday follows similar decisions taken by the U.S., UK, and Australia, all of which have expressed concerns about Huawei and ZTE and their ties with the Chinese government.</p>
<p>The Indian government branch said it gave permission to telecom service providers, who chose their own priorities and technology partners.</p>
<p>The experimental spectrum is being given in various bands which include the mid-band (3.2 GHz to 3.67 GHz), millimeter wave band (24.25 GHz to 28.5 GHz) and in Sub-Gigahertz band (700 GHz). Technology service providers will also be permitted to use their existing spectrum owned by them (800 MHz, 900 MHz, 1800 MHz and 2500 MHz) to conduct of 5G trials.</p>
<p>&#8220;The permission letters specify that each TSP will have to conduct trials in rural and semi-urban settings also in addition to urban settings so that the benefit of 5G Technology proliferates across the country and is not confined only tourban areas. The TSPs are encouraged to conduct trials using 5Gi technology in addition to the already known 5G Technology,&#8221; the ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>&#8220;The objectives of conducting 5G trials include testing 5G spectrum propagation characteristics especially in the Indian context; model tuning and evaluation of chosen equipment andvendors; testing of indigenous technology; testing of applications (such as tele-medicine, tele-education, augmented/ virtual reality, drone-based agricultural monitoring, etc.); and to test 5G phones and devices.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/india-grants-approval-for-5g-trials-avoids-chinese-firms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2147143</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
