<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 15:46:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Short seller says Lemonade website bug exposed insurance customers&#8217; account data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/lemonade-insurance-bug-exposed-account-data/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/lemonade-insurance-bug-exposed-account-data/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 15:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[albums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beyonce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daniel schreiber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Formation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[four loko]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lemonade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PDF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151695</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An activist short seller has written a letter to the chief executive of insurance giant Lemonade with details of an &#8220;accidentally discovered&#8221; security flaw that exposes customers&#8217; account data. Carson Block, founder of investment research firm Muddy Waters Research, sent the letter to Lemonade co-founder and chief executive Daniel Schreiber on Thursday, describing the bug [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">An activist short seller has written a letter to the chief executive of insurance giant Lemonade with details of an &#8220;accidentally discovered&#8221; security flaw that exposes customers&#8217; account data.</p>
<p>Carson Block, founder of investment research firm Muddy Waters Research, sent the letter to Lemonade co-founder and chief executive Daniel Schreiber on Thursday, describing the bug that allowed anyone to inadvertently access personally identifiable data from customers’ accounts as “unforgivably negligent.”</p>
<p>Block&#8217;s <a href="https://www.muddywatersresearch.com/research/lmnd/open-letter/">letter</a> said: &#8220;By clicking on search results from public search engines, we shockingly found ourselves logged in to and able to edit Lemonade customers&#8217; accounts without having to provide any user credentials whatsoever.&#8221;</p>
<p>Lemonade launched in 2015 and offers renters&#8217;, homeowners&#8217; and pet insurance policies across the U.S. and Europe. The company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/08/softbank-backed-lemonade-files-to-go-public/">went public last year</a> and saw its shares rocket by more than 130% on the day of its initial public offering. Lemonade <a href="https://www.barrons.com/articles/lemonade-stock-is-falling-after-earnings-februarys-freeze-in-texas-didnt-help-51620827012">this week</a> reported a $49 million quarterly loss, deeper than what Wall Street was expecting.</p>
<p>The bug was co-discovered by Muddy Waters Research and Wolfpack Research, Block said. In <a href="https://twitter.com/Reed_Wolfpack/status/1392829803246587908">a tweet</a>, Wolfpack lead analyst Reed Sherman said one of Muddy Waters&#8217; security experts &#8220;was able to send me a PDF of my renter&#8217;s insurance policy less than 15 minutes after this was first discovered.&#8221;</p>
<p>Block told TechCrunch that his firm is shorting the company&#8217;s stock, per his letter, &#8220;because it is clear Lemonade does not give a fuck about securing its customers&#8217; sensitive personal information.&#8221; Block said in his letter that Lemonade should &#8220;shut down its website, APIs, and mobile application&#8221; until the issue is fixed, which he says may date back to July 2020.</p>
<p>Block published his letter to Lemonade with redactions as to not give away specific details of the bug. In a call, Block provided more details about the bug to TechCrunch in order to verify the vulnerability. One indexed search result let us log into a person&#8217;s Lemonade account and view their name, address, and quote details without ever asking for the user&#8217;s password.</p>
<p>A short time later, some of the indexed results stopped working. TechCrunch asked Lemonade for comment but did not hear back prior to publication. We&#8217;ll update when we do.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SUdP5ymZVw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/geico-driver-license-numbers-scraped/">Geico admits fraudsters stole customers&#8217; driver&#8217;s license numbers for months</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Geico admits fraudsters stole customers&#8217; driver&#8217;s license numbers for months&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/geico-driver-license-numbers-scraped/embed/#?secret=SUdP5ymZVw" data-secret="SUdP5ymZVw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/lemonade-insurance-bug-exposed-account-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151695</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sylvera grabs seed backing from Index to help close the accountability gap around carbon offsetting</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/sylvera-grabs-seed-backing-from-index-to-help-close-the-accountability-gap-around-carbon-offsetting/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/sylvera-grabs-seed-backing-from-index-to-help-close-the-accountability-gap-around-carbon-offsetting/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 15:24:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon offset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carlos Gonzalez-Cadenas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[citibank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Index Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sylvera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ucla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151682</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[UK-based startup Sylvera is using satellite, radar and lidar data-fuelled machine learning to bolster transparency around carbon offsetting projects in a bid to boost accountability and credibility &#8212; applying independent ratings to carbon offsetting projects. The ratings are based on proprietary data sets it&#8217;s developed in conjunction with scientists from research organisations including UCLA, the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">UK-based startup <a href="https://www.sylvera.com">Sylvera</a> is using satellite, radar and lidar data-fuelled machine learning to bolster transparency around carbon offsetting projects in a bid to boost accountability and credibility &#8212; applying independent ratings to carbon offsetting projects.</p>
<p>The ratings are based on proprietary data sets it&#8217;s developed in conjunction with scientists from research organisations including UCLA, the NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory, and University College London.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s just grabbed $5.8M in seed funding led by VC firm Index Ventures. All its existing institutional investors also participated &#8212; namely: Seedcamp, Speedinvest and Revent. It also has backing from leading angels, including the existing and former CEOs of NYSE, Thomson Reuters, Citibank and IHS Markit. (It confirms it has committed not to receive any investment from traditional carbon-intensive companies when as ask.) And it&#8217;s just snagged a $2M research contract from Innovate UK.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The problem it&#8217;s targeting is that the carbon offsetting market suffers from a lack of transparency.</p>
<p>This fuels concerns that many offsetting projects aren&#8217;t living up to their claims of a net reduction in carbon emissions &#8212; and that &#8216;creative&#8217; carbon accountancy is rather being used to generate a lot of hot air: In the form of positive sounding PR which sums to meaningless greenwashing and more pollution as polluters get to keep on pumping out climate changing emissions.</p>
<p>Nonetheless the carbon offset markets are poised for huge growth &#8212; of at least 15x by 2030 &#8212; as large corporates accelerate their net zero commitments. And Sylvera&#8217;s bet is that that will drive demand for reliable, independent data &#8212; to stand up the claimed impact.</p>
<p>How exactly is Sylvera benchmarking carbon offsets? Co-founder Sam Gill says its technology platform draws on multiple layers of satellite data to capture project performance data at scale and at a high frequency.</p>
<p>It applies machine learning to analyze and visualize the data, while also conducting what it bills as &#8220;deep analytical work to assess the underlying project quality&#8221;. Via that process it creates a standardised rating for a project, so that market participants are able to transact according to their preferences.</p>
<p>It makes its ratings and analysis data available to its customers via a web application and an API (for which it charges a subscription).</p>
<p>&#8220;We assess two critical areas of a project &#8212; its carbon performance, and its &#8216;quality&#8217;,&#8221; Gill tells TechCrunch. &#8220;We score a project against these criteria, and give them ratings &#8212; much like a Moody’s rating on a bond.&#8221;</p>
<p>Carbon performance is assessed by gathering &#8220;multi-layered data&#8221; from multiple sources to understand what is going on on the ground of these projects &#8212; such as via multiple satellite sources such as multispectral image, Radar, and Lidar data.</p>
<p>&#8220;We collate this data over time, ingest it into our proprietary machine learning algorithms, and analyse how the project has performed against its stated aims,&#8221; Gill explains.</p>
<p>Quality is assessed by considering the technical aspects of the project. This includes what Gill calls &#8220;additionality&#8221;; aka &#8220;does the project have a strong claim to delivering a better outcome than would have occurred but for the existence of the offset revenue?&#8221;.</p>
<p>There is a known problem with some carbon offsets claimed against forests where the landowner had no intention of logging, for example. So if there wasn&#8217;t going to be any deforestation the carbon credit is essentially bogus.</p>
<p>He also says it looks at factors like permanence (&#8220;how long will the project’s impacts last?&#8221;); co-benefits (&#8220;how well has the project incorporated the UN’s Sustainability Development Goals?); and risks (&#8220;how well is the project mitigating risks, in particular those from humans and those from natural causes?&#8221;).</p>
<p>Clearly it&#8217;s not an exact science &#8212; and Gill acknowledges risks, for example, are often interlinked.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is critical to assess these performance and quality in tandem,&#8221; he tells TechCrunch. &#8220;It’s not enough to simply say a project is achieving the carbon goals set out in its plan.</p>
<p>&#8220;If the additionality of a project is low (e.g. it was actually unlikely the project would have been deforested without the project) then the achievement of the carbon goals set out in the project does not generate the anticipated carbon goals, and the underlying offsets are therefore weaker than appreciated.&#8221;</p>
<p>Commenting on the seed funding in a statement, Carlos Gonzalez-Cadenas, partner at Index Ventures, said: “This is a phenomenally strong team with the vision to build the first carbon offset rating benchmark, providing comprehensive insights around the quality of offsets, enabling purchase decisions as well as post-purchase monitoring and reporting. Sylvera is  putting in place the building blocks that will be required to address climate change.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/sylvera-grabs-seed-backing-from-index-to-help-close-the-accountability-gap-around-carbon-offsetting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151682</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sequoia&#8217;s Shaun Maguire and Vise&#8217;s Samir Vasavada will talk success in fintech on Extra Crunch Live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/sequoias-shaun-maguire-and-vises-samir-vasavada-will-talk-success-in-fintech-on-extra-crunch-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/sequoias-shaun-maguire-and-vises-samir-vasavada-will-talk-success-in-fintech-on-extra-crunch-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 15:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ECL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch live announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samir Vasavada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shaun Maguire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vise]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144992</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the past few weeks, we&#8217;ve heard Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand discuss the biggest opportunities in prop tech, heard why Scale AI&#8217;s Alex Wang and Accel&#8217;s Dan Levine think that unconventional VC deals can be the best option and taken a stroll through the Poshmark Series A deck with CEO Manish [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In the past few weeks, we&#8217;ve heard <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/fifth-walls-brendan-wallace-and-hippos-assaf-wand-discuss-proptechs-biggest-opportunities/">Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand discuss the biggest opportunities in prop tech</a>, heard why <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/09/scale-ceo-alex-wang-and-accels-dan-levine-explain-why-sometimes-unconventional-vc-deals-are-best/">Scale AI&#8217;s Alex Wang and Accel&#8217;s Dan Levine think that unconventional VC deals can be the best option</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/27/ceo-manish-chandra-and-investor-navin-chaddha-explain-why-poshmarks-series-a-deck-sings/">taken a stroll through the Poshmark Series A deck with CEO Manish Chandra and Mayfield&#8217;s Navin Chaddha</a>.</p>
<p>This is the particular flavor of content, rich in key insights and tactical advice for founders, that goes down on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">Extra Crunch Live</a>.</p>
<p>In an upcoming episode on Wednesday, May 19, we&#8217;ll sit down with Sequoia&#8217;s Shaun Maguire and Vise CEO and co-founder Samir Vasavada.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Maguire focuses on enterprise, fintech and frontier technology for Sequoia. His portfolio companies include AMP Robotics, Knowde, Physna and Vise. He joined Sequoia in 2019, before which he was a partner at GV, where he led investments in Stripe, Opendoor, IonQ, SpinLaunch, Lambda School, Dandelion Energy, Clutter and Mode and sourced the firm&#8217;s investment in Segment.</p>
<p>Maguire has also been an entrepreneur in his own right, co-founding Expanse (a cybersecurity company), which was ultimately acquired by Palo Alto Networks for more than $800 million.</p>
<p>If that weren&#8217;t enough, Maguire also spent two years working at DARPA, and was deployed to Afghanistan, participating on a team that earned a Joint Meritorious Unit Award from the U.S. Secretary of Defense.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XAgbkrhJ6p"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/28/justworks-series-b-pitch-deck-may-be-the-most-wonderfully-simple-deck-ive-ever-seen/">Justworks&#8217; Series B pitch deck may be the most wonderfully simple deck I&#8217;ve ever seen</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Justworks&#8217; Series B pitch deck may be the most wonderfully simple deck I&#8217;ve ever seen&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/28/justworks-series-b-pitch-deck-may-be-the-most-wonderfully-simple-deck-ive-ever-seen/embed/#?secret=XAgbkrhJ6p" data-secret="XAgbkrhJ6p" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Samir Vasavada co-founded Vise in 2016. Vise is an AI-powered investment management platform that aims to give independent financial advisors access to technology and tools to build and manage personalized portfolios for their clients, ultimately giving those advisors more time and energy to spend on the relationships.</p>
<p>Vise has raised upwards of $60 million.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll talk to Maguire and Vasavada about what brought them together, key tips for fundraising and how to be successful in the fintech space, and ask about the next great opportunity in fintech.</p>
<p>On the second half of the episode, Maguire and Vasavada will put on their feedback hats and listen to live elevator pitches from the audience as part of the ECL Pitch-off. Folks attending the event will be able to raise their hand and pitch their startup to the VC/founder duo, and then answer their questions and get their feedback.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="g2KGo0WwM4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/join-ecl-on-wednesday-to-pitch-your-startup-to-fifth-walls-brendan-wallace-and-hippos-assaf-wand/">Join ECL on Wednesday to pitch your startup to Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Join ECL on Wednesday to pitch your startup to Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/join-ecl-on-wednesday-to-pitch-your-startup-to-fifth-walls-brendan-wallace-and-hippos-assaf-wand/embed/#?secret=g2KGo0WwM4" data-secret="g2KGo0WwM4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But the only way you can pitch is to show up. This episode of Extra Crunch Live goes down on Wednesday, May 19 at 3pm ET/12pm PT. Anyone can attend as long as they register here, but on-demand access to the content is reserved strictly for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe">Extra Crunch members</a>, who also have access to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">complete library of Extra Crunch Live content, among many, many other awesome articles and perks. </a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/sequoias-shaun-maguire-and-vises-samir-vasavada-will-talk-success-in-fintech-on-extra-crunch-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144992</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The fulfilling world of warehouse robotics</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/robotics-roundup-11/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/robotics-roundup-11/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 15:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[berkshire grey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Youibot]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the pandemic finish line in sight &#8212; at least for some &#8212; now is a good time to start assessing which segments have been most impacted by the events of the past year and a half. In terms of robotics, investments have been all over the place &#8212; and for good reasons. COVID-19 seems [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With the pandemic finish line in sight &#8212; at least for some &#8212; now is a good time to start assessing which segments have been most impacted by the events of the past year and a half. In terms of robotics, investments have been all over the place &#8212; and for good reasons. COVID-19 seems destined to have a profound and lasting impact on work, and more than ever, robots and automation are going to play a part in that.</p>
<p>Food has been a big target. Manufacturing and health, as well &#8212; all for pretty clear reasons. When we come out of this, however, we may end up seeing that the most immediate and profound impact was on warehouse and fulfillment. Not that it needed much help, but online retail had a huge moment &#8212; led, naturally, by Amazon.</p>
<p>As the company butted heads with workers and union organizers at one fulfillment center in Alabama, the company has been readying additional fulfillment centers. <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/gov-edwards-announces-new-amazon-robotics-facility-in-shreveport-301286880.html">Shreveport, Louisiana is the latest</a>, with Governor John Bel Edwards referring to the new warehouse as a “robotics fulfillment center.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As with all of these, that means a combination of humans and robots. There are, of course, questions with regard to what the balance will be, going forward. And, of course, it’s no surprise that pro-union Amazon workers frequently cited being treated like a robot among their biggest workplace concerns.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="h9lIRb7Ryx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/03/robotics-startup-lets-machines-get-closer-as-humans-keep-their-distance/">Robotics startup lets machines get closer as humans keep their distance</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Robotics startup lets machines get closer as humans keep their distance&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/03/robotics-startup-lets-machines-get-closer-as-humans-keep-their-distance/embed/#?secret=h9lIRb7Ryx" data-secret="h9lIRb7Ryx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Attempting to stay afloat in the world of Amazon is a big part of why so many warehouses are particularly interested in robotics at the moment. After all, the tech has not only given the retailer a competitive advantage, it’s helped keep them running amid a global pandemic.</p>
<p>Berkshire-Grey has been one of the bigger players in the category, thanks in no small part to some massive raises. To date, the Boston-area company has raised $263 million, before announcing a SPAC last year. <a href="https://www.berkshiregrey.com/resources/press-release/berkshire-grey-accelerates-company-momentum-in-2021/">Today, it announced</a> that it’s using some of that money to further expand into markets including Canada and Japan.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2151610" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2151610" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2151610" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/berkshire-grey.png" alt="" width="1024" height="538" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/berkshire-grey.png 1317w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/berkshire-grey.png?resize=150,79 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/berkshire-grey.png?resize=300,158 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/berkshire-grey.png?resize=768,404 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/berkshire-grey.png?resize=680,357 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/berkshire-grey.png?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2151610" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Berkshire Grey</p></div></p>
<p>“2020 was a pivotal time for eCommerce companies, retailers, grocers and package handling logistics providers – and it continues into this year. The need to automate to meet consumer needs was already pronounced and the pandemic accelerated the changes and increased the need,” founder and CEO Tom Wagner said in a release. “Many of these changes in consumer behaviors are here to stay and that means, businesses need to adapt and improve operations with robotic automation to fulfill those needs. We’re honored to work with companies who have enlisted our AI-enabled robotic solutions to help meet business goals and consumer expectations.”</p>
<p>The already-hot China market continues to gain momentum, as well. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/youibot-funding/">Youibot this week</a> announced a $15 million raise, led by Softbank Ventures. The Shenzhen company is a HAX grad that produces manufacturing robots.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2151613" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2151613" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2151613" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-07-at-8.50.25-AM-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="573" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-07-at-8.50.25-AM-1.png 1390w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-07-at-8.50.25-AM-1.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-07-at-8.50.25-AM-1.png?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-07-at-8.50.25-AM-1.png?resize=768,430 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-07-at-8.50.25-AM-1.png?resize=680,381 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-07-at-8.50.25-AM-1.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2151613" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong></p></div></p>
<p>Here’s Rita on the company:</p>
<blockquote><p>Founded by a group of PhDs from China’s prestigious Xi’an Jiaotong University, Youibot develops solutions for factory automation and logistics management, as well as inspection and maintenance for various industries. For example, its robots can navigate around a yard of buses, inspect every tire of the vehicles and provide a detailed report for maintenance, a feature that helped it rack up Michelin’s contract.</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zk4RPg6kl8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/youibot-funding/">SoftBank leads $15M round for China&#8217;s industrial robot maker Youibot</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SoftBank leads $15M round for China&#8217;s industrial robot maker Youibot&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/youibot-funding/embed/#?secret=zk4RPg6kl8" data-secret="zk4RPg6kl8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/robotics-roundup-11/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151417</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Framework’s repairable laptop is up for preorder, starting at $999</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/frameworks-repairable-laptop-is-up-for-pre-order-starting-at-999/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/frameworks-repairable-laptop-is-up-for-pre-order-starting-at-999/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 15:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[framework]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laptop]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151242</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Repairability has been a big sticking point for consumer electronics over the past several years. As devices have gotten thinner &#8212; and companies have pushed to maintain control over proprietary systems &#8212; many devices have become near impossible for an every-day person to repair. It’s an issue for a number of reasons &#8212; not the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Repairability has been a big sticking point for consumer electronics over the past several years. As devices have gotten thinner &#8212; and companies have pushed to maintain control over proprietary systems &#8212; many devices have become near impossible for an every-day person to repair.</p>
<p>It’s an issue for a number of reasons &#8212; not the least of which is an inability to upgrade a system instead of scrapping it altogether. In a world where human impact on the environment is increasingly top of mind, forced obsolescence is an understandably important issue for many.</p>
<p>Framework is one of an increasing number of companies working to address these issues. It’s a list that also includes products like Fairphone on the mobile side. It’s a niche versus the overall market, to be sure, but it’s one that could well be growing. Announced in January, the Framework Laptop <a href="https://frame.work/">is up for preorder today</a>. The 13.5-inch notebook starts at $999 and will start shipping at the end of July.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/7hMV1Jq8Vt4?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>The SF-based company had initially targeted spring shipping, but ongoing chip supply problems have delayed the product. The system actually doesn’t look half-bad for a product and company that are clearly repair/upgrade-first.</p>
<p>There are three basic configurations &#8212; Base, Performance and Professional, ranging from $999 to $1,999, upgrading from an Intel Core i5, 8GB of Ram and 256GB of storage to a Core i7 and 32GB/1TB. Windows also gets upgraded from Home to Pro at the top level. At $749, the company offers a barebones shell, where users can plug in their own internals.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2151275" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2151275" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2151275 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Press-Assets-img02.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Press-Assets-img02.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Press-Assets-img02.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Press-Assets-img02.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Press-Assets-img02.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Press-Assets-img02.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Press-Assets-img02.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Press-Assets-img02.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2151275" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Framework</p></div></p>
<p>Other upgrades include:</p>
<blockquote><p>On top of that, the Framework Laptop is deeply customizable in unique ways. Our Expansion Card system lets you choose the ports you want and which side you want them on, selecting from four at a time of USB-C, USB-A, HDMI, DisplayPort, MicroSD, ultra-fast 250GB and 1TB storage, and more. Magnetic-attach bezels are color-customizable to match your style, and the keyboard language can be swapped too.</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pxUJLsfptJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/08/fairphone-3-is-a-normal-smartphone-with-ethical-shine/">Fairphone 3 is a normal smartphone with ethical shine</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fairphone 3 is a normal smartphone with ethical shine&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/08/fairphone-3-is-a-normal-smartphone-with-ethical-shine/embed/#?secret=pxUJLsfptJ" data-secret="pxUJLsfptJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fsWLGVg8KU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/from-surviving-to-thriving-as-a-hardware-startup/">From surviving to thriving as a hardware startup</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;From surviving to thriving as a hardware startup&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/from-surviving-to-thriving-as-a-hardware-startup/embed/#?secret=fsWLGVg8KU" data-secret="fsWLGVg8KU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/frameworks-repairable-laptop-is-up-for-pre-order-starting-at-999/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151242</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SpecTrust raises millions to fight cybercrime with its no-code platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/spectrust-raises-millions-to-fight-cybercrime-with-no-code-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/spectrust-raises-millions-to-fight-cybercrime-with-no-code-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 15:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit card fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreamit ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eBay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fraud prevention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[identity theft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rally Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[risk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signalfire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[threatmetrix]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151447</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Risk defense startup SpecTrust is emerging from stealth today with a $4.3 million seed raise and a public launch. Cyber Mentor Fund led the round, which also included participation from Rally Ventures, SignalFire, Dreamit Ventures and Legion Capital. SpecTrust aims to “fix the economics of fighting fraud” with a no-code platform that it says cuts [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Risk defense startup <a href="https://www.spec-trust.com/">SpecTrust</a> is emerging from stealth today with a $4.3 million seed raise and a public launch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cyber Mentor Fund led the round, which also included participation from Rally Ventures, SignalFire, Dreamit Ventures and Legion Capital.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SpecTrust aims to “fix the economics of fighting fraud” with a no-code platform that it says cuts 90% of a business’ risk infrastructure spend that responds to threats in “minutes instead of months.” </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“In </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">January of 2020, I got a bug in my ear to, instead of an API, build a cloud-based service that handles all this complex orchestration and unifies all this data,” said CEO </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nate Kharrl, who co-founded the company with Bryce Verdier and </span>Patrick Chen<span style="font-weight: 400;">. “And, it worked. And it worked fast enough that you can’t even tell it’s there doing its work.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example, he says, SpecTrust even in its early days was able to pull identity behavior information in seconds.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Today, it’s more like five and seven milliseconds,” he said. “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">And, engineers don’t have to lift anything or adjust data models.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since the San Jose, California-based startup’s offering is deployed on the internet, between a website or app and its users, an organization gets fraud protection without draining the resources of its engineers, the company says. Founded by a team that ran risk management divisions at eBay and ThreatMetrix, SpecTrust is banking on the fact that companies &#8212; especially financial institutions &#8212; will be drawn to the flexibility afforded by a no-code offering.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1iqWWNUCCM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/dont-hate-on-low-code-and-no-code/">Don&#8217;t hate on low-code and no-code</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Don&#8217;t hate on low-code and no-code&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/dont-hate-on-low-code-and-no-code/embed/#?secret=1iqWWNUCCM" data-secret="1iqWWNUCCM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Much of the industry is split up between compliance and onboarding, authenticating risk and payments, and user trust and safety, Kharrl said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We put all the tools together to address all things combined, to make sure the person an institution is talking to is who they say they are, and not acting with malicious intent,” he told TechCrunch. “We sit in between them and their traffic to make sure the risk and fraud teams have what they need to spot bad guys.”</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2151466" style="width: 1337px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2151466" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2151466 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/SpecTrust.jpg" alt="" width="1327" height="716" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/SpecTrust.jpg 1327w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/SpecTrust.jpg?resize=150,81 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/SpecTrust.jpg?resize=300,162 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/SpecTrust.jpg?resize=768,414 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/SpecTrust.jpg?resize=680,367 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/SpecTrust.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1327px) 100vw, 1327px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2151466" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credit: SpecTrust</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Online businesses spend billions on risk defense yet still lose a lot of money to fraudsters, scammers and identity thieves, Kharrl said. And, the COVID-19 pandemic led to a global shift in the digital economy </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">as more people came to rely on the internet to meet day-to-day needs. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“With these new trends in commerce and banking came more opportunities for fraudsters, scammers and identity thieves to target people and businesses,” </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">he added. For example, an alarming number of cybercriminals employed no-code attack tools and click-to-deploy infrastructure to launch sophisticated attacks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fintech and crypto companies are feeling the biggest impacts, as legacy software designed for big banks, for example, can be slow and expensive, said Kharrl. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We built SpecTrust to instantly put complete assessment, automation and enforcement capabilities in the hands of teams charged with fighting modern cybercrime threats,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Using its platform, the company says an organization’s risk team can review and investigate everything a customer does “from its first page view to its last click with unified behavior, identity, history and risk data.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even non-technical staffers can do things like identify attack behavior,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> verify customer identity information, validate payment details and work to mitigate threats before they become losses, according to Kharrl.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="E7wj5ogSgM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/fraud-prevention-platform-sift-raises-50m-at-over-1b-valuation-eyes-acquisitions/">Fraud prevention platform Sift raises $50M at over $1B valuation, eyes acquisitions</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fraud prevention platform Sift raises $50M at over $1B valuation, eyes acquisitions&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/fraud-prevention-platform-sift-raises-50m-at-over-1b-valuation-eyes-acquisitions/embed/#?secret=E7wj5ogSgM" data-secret="E7wj5ogSgM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jon Lim of SignalFire says that</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> SpecTrust has built an end-to-end risk protection platform that enables customers of all sizes and risk profiles “to access the latest innovative risk protection solutions, quickly respond to the evolving threat landscape and share the best practices and learnings across the entire customer base.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And of course, it was drawn to the startup’s no-code platform and ability to provide visibility over every user interaction versus treating each interaction as an independent event.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This not only delivers stronger protection to customers but also a smoother experience to the end user,” Lim said.</span></p>
<p>The fraud prevention space is hot these days. Sift, which also aims to predict and prevent fraud, in April <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/fraud-prevention-platform-sift-raises-50m-at-over-1b-valuation-eyes-acquisitions/">raised $50 million in a funding round</a> that valued the company at over $1 billion.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/spectrust-raises-millions-to-fight-cybercrime-with-no-code-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151447</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Discord announces Stage Discovery, a portal that connects events with communities</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/discord-stage-discovery/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/discord-stage-discovery/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 15:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discord]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151469</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you’re new to Discord, you might be thrown off by the lack of an endless feed peppered with ads. On Discord, all of the action happens in interest-specific servers, and the company wants to make it easier for anyone to stumble across and plunge into those communities. The company launched Stage Channels, its own [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If you’re new to Discord, you might be thrown off by the lack of an endless feed peppered with ads. On Discord, all of the action happens in interest-specific servers, and the company wants to make it easier for anyone to stumble across and plunge into those communities.</p>
<p>The company launched<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/discord-stage-channels-voice-events/"> Stage Channels</a>, its own Clubhouse-like voice event rooms, in late March. With those building blocks in place, in June Discord will start surfacing events (think open mic nights, book clubs, etc.) through a new portal called Stage Discovery, adding a way for anybody to connect with the cool communities in the process.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2151701" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/discord-stage-discovery.jpeg?w=680" alt="discord-stage-discovery" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/discord-stage-discovery.jpeg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/discord-stage-discovery.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/discord-stage-discovery.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/discord-stage-discovery.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/discord-stage-discovery.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/discord-stage-discovery.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Discord Product Manager Rick Ling says Stage Channels are a hit so far, and the company realized that events can be a gateway to introduce new users to the communities at the heart of the platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;For us, just dropping in and out of these audio conversations is not the end goal,&#8221; Ling said during a press event. Soon, servers will be able to list public events, inviting anybody to come check things out. Discord also says that its new discovery feature will launch with some noteworthy partners, hinting that “one rhymes with…… rhymes.” (It’s Grimes.)</p>
<p>Discord has a few other new features around the corner too. Threaded conversations are on the way this summer and the company is about to begin a pilot program to test paid, ticketed audio events. The latter could be a huge boon for creators, who haven&#8217;t been able to make money through the platform previously, and an important extra revenue stream for a platform that has no plans to get into the targeted advertising game.</p>
<h2>Discord&#8217;s next evolution</h2>
<p>Stage Discovery is a bit of a departure for Discord. Previously, to check out a live event, you needed to pop into a server first. Because the platform is so community-based, people interested in a topic, say a particular Twitch streamer, often hop directly into those servers from elsewhere.</p>
<p>Discord does have some discovery and search functionality — users can thumb through popular and featured public servers in its Discover tab — but historically it’s been relatively basic. But by expanding the “discovery surface,” Discord is likely to attract a lot of people who either haven’t heard of the app or think it’s just a voice chat utility for gamers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bhD2YNPSc6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/discords-10b-exit-compass-and-intermedia-cloud-communications-set-ipo-price-ranges/">Discord&#8217;s reported $10B exit; Compass and Intermedia Cloud Communications set IPO price ranges</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Discord&#8217;s reported $10B exit; Compass and Intermedia Cloud Communications set IPO price ranges&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/discords-10b-exit-compass-and-intermedia-cloud-communications-set-ipo-price-ranges/embed/#?secret=bhD2YNPSc6" data-secret="bhD2YNPSc6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The new feature will show up in the home tab, offering a directory of live voice events. While that much is Clubhouse-esque, the feature’s real promise is that those events can bring new users into the fold, connecting them to thriving communities that have a lot more going on beyond events. Users will be able to see voice events at which their friends are hanging, events that servers they belong to are hosting and other live events that they aren’t connected to.</p>
<p>“At the end of the day, this is still really a window into communities and how to join communities,” Discord Product Marketing spokesperson Jesse Wofford told TechCrunch. Wofford emphasized that Discord isn’t trying to lure anybody into an endless scrolling loop — instead the goal is connecting users with the vibrant communities for which the platform is known.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2151687" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Desktop.jpeg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Desktop.jpeg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Desktop.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Desktop.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Desktop.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Desktop.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Desktop.jpeg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Desktop.jpeg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Desktop.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<h2>Discord grows up</h2>
<p>Discord is also celebrating its sixth birthday by sprucing up its brand a little, brightening its color scheme and making a few tweaks to its apparently beloved anthropomorphized little purple controller dude, Clyde. (Discord insists that Clyde is “blurple.”) The company says it wants to keep things playful while making its visual identity “more inclusive and welcoming” to the kind of people who haven’t been using the app for years.</p>
<p>While a big boost to discovery is on the near horizon, Discord’s product philosophy hasn’t changed. “There are no feeds, no likes, no way for anything to go viral,&#8221; Discord founder and CEO Jason Citron said, adding that Discord was designed with community building in mind from day one.</p>
<p>Discord wasn’t always such a welcoming place. The app has always served gamers, but it was also a<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/08/15/technology/discord-chat-app-alt-right.html"> haven for white supremacists</a>, including the ones who organized the Charlottesville rally that left Heather Heyer dead. In a not-so-distant past life, dangerous far-right extremism thrived on Discord, even as the company largely avoided the bad headlines that slammed more mainstream social platforms for facilitating hate.</p>
<p>Discord <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/2/28/17062554/discord-alt-right-neo-nazi-white-supremacy-atomwaffen">rooted out neo-Nazis</a> and other dangerous communities starting in 2017, and by 2021 the company was well-positioned to tell a different story. Now, 15% of the company works on its Trust and Safety team, a group dedicated to protecting users and shaping content moderation policies. Discord says it has 150 million monthly active users and most of them are Gen Z (18 to 24-year-olds). The product was built for gamers from the get-go, but Discord has been broadening its horizons recently and started having conversations with users about how it’s helped them fight isolation during the pandemic.</p>
<p>Unlike Instagram’s ad-choked social feed or Twitter’s often brain-melting endless feed, Discord is often a joy to use. And all of that user-friendliness doesn’t appear to be a bait and switch either. Revenue from its Nitro premium product and other paid perks are growing fast and the company has no plans for targeted ads.</p>
<p>Discord&#8217;s savvy pandemic-era campaign to broaden Discord’s appeal to nongaming communities — musicians, study groups, <a href="https://discord.com/invite/3uFgJhu">surrealist fantasy baseball leagues</a> — appears to be paying off. Discord’s user numbers are explosive and the company is adding sensible new features at a healthy clip. The outlook is good for the company and its users alike — and what a rare convergence that is.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dKRC8eYVfy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/discord-ipo-microsoft-deal/">Discord walked away from Microsoft talks, may pursue an IPO</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Discord walked away from Microsoft talks, may pursue an IPO&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/discord-ipo-microsoft-deal/embed/#?secret=dKRC8eYVfy" data-secret="dKRC8eYVfy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/discord-stage-discovery/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151469</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The hamburger model is a winning go-to-market strategy</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/the-hamburger-model-is-a-winning-go-to-market-strategy/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/the-hamburger-model-is-a-winning-go-to-market-strategy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer relationship management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer success]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go-to-market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pricing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2150399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Assembling the perfect burger, or perfect sales model, is more complicated than it sounds, though. Here are some of the biggest do's and don'ts:]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Caryn Marooney</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/carynm650">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Caryn Marooney is general partner at <a href="https://www.coatue.com/">Coatue Management</a> and sits on the boards of Zendesk and Elastic. In prior roles she oversaw communications for Facebook, Instagram, WhatsApp and Oculus and co-founded The OutCast Agency, which served clients like Salesforce.com and Amazon.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/ribs-the-messaging-framework-for-every-company-and-product/">RIBS: The messaging framework for every company and product</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/bottom-up-saas-a-framework-for-mapping-pricing-to-customer-value/">Bottom-up SaaS: A framework for mapping pricing to customer value</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">David Cahn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/david-cahn-60150793/">David Cahn</a> is an investor at Coatue, where he focuses on software investments. David is passionate about open-source and infrastructure software and previously worked in the Technology Investment Banking Group at Morgan Stanley.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/bottom-up-saas-a-framework-for-mapping-pricing-to-customer-value/">Bottom-up SaaS: A framework for mapping pricing to customer value</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/28/should-your-saas-startup-embrace-a-bottom-up-gtm-strategy/">Should your SaaS startup embrace a bottom-up GTM strategy?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">In the old software world — think Oracle and SAP — sales were the competitive advantage. Today, we live in a world of product-led growth, where engineers (and the software they have built) are the biggest differentiator. If your customers love what you’re building, you’re headed in the right direction. If they don’t, you’re not.</p>
<p>However, even the most successful product-led growth companies will reach a tipping point, because no matter how good their product is, they’ll need to figure out how to expand their customer base and grow from a startup into a $1 billion+ revenue enterprise.</p>
<p>The answer is the hamburger model. Why call it that? Because the best go-to-market (GTM) strategies for startups are like hamburgers:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>The bottom bun:</strong> Bottom-up GTM.</li>
<li><strong>The burger</strong>: Your product.</li>
<li><strong>The top bun:</strong> Enterprise sales.</li>
</ul>
<p>In the hamburger GTM model, your product is the meat. We’ll go through each layer before talking about some of the best ways to implement the model successfully at your company.</p>
<h2>The hamburger model</h2>
<p><strong>The meat — product at the center</strong>: The hamburger model starts with a great product. As a founder, this means you don’t need to think about revenue on Day One. You do, however, need to obsess over your customers, what they want and how to build it. Nothing is more important.</p>
<p><strong>The bottom bun —</strong> <strong>users not leads:</strong> In a top-down sales model, marketing creates leads that are then converted into sales by enterprise reps. In a bottom-up model, marketing creates users, not leads, and those users are never touched by sales. For companies that have been customer-obsessed from the very beginning because they built something people love, this bottom-up model can feel far more natural and fuel a successful business.</p>
<p><strong>The top bun —</strong> <strong>building enterprise sales:</strong> Even the best bottom-up sales models aren’t enough on their own, and every company eventually needs top-down sales. It may sound counterintuitive, but even the companies most famous for their bottom-up approaches now have enterprise sales teams. That’s because there are certain types of customers — for example, healthcare, insurance and government — that require salespeople to engage with due to compliance and security reasons.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2150401" style="width: 380px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2150401" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2150401 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/image1-1.png" alt="The Hamburger go-to-market strategy" width="370" height="408" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/image1-1.png 370w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/image1-1.png?resize=136,150 136w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/image1-1.png?resize=272,300 272w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/image1-1.png?resize=45,50 45w" sizes="(max-width: 370px) 100vw, 370px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2150401" class="wp-caption-text">The hamburger go-to-market strategy. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Coatue</p></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>These are the basic elements of the hamburger GTM model: A killer product that sets you apart, a bottom-up sales strategy to convert users into paying customers, and a sales team to go after bigger customers that require more attention.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/the-hamburger-model-is-a-winning-go-to-market-strategy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2150399</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Walmart acquires virtual clothing try-on startup Zeekit</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/walmart-acquires-virtual-clothing-try-on-startup-zeekit/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/walmart-acquires-virtual-clothing-try-on-startup-zeekit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[a.i.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apparel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[image-processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online brands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[simulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tel Aviv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151641</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Retail giant Walmart announced this morning it&#8217;s acquiring the Tel Aviv-based startup Zeekit, which allows consumers to virtually &#8220;try on&#8221; clothing when shopping online. The company leverages a combination of real-time image processing, computer vision, deep learning and other A.I. technology to show shoppers how they would look in an item by way of a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Retail giant Walmart <a href="https://corporate.walmart.com/newsroom/2021/05/13/walmart-announces-plans-to-acquire-zeekit-a-leading-virtual-fitting-room-platform-to-enable-enhanced-and-social-shopping-experience-for-customer">announced</a> this morning it&#8217;s acquiring the Tel Aviv-based startup <a href="https://zeekit.me/">Zeekit</a>, which allows consumers to virtually &#8220;try on&#8221; clothing when shopping online. The company leverages a combination of real-time image processing, computer vision, deep learning and other A.I. technology to show shoppers how they would look in an item by way of a simulation that takes into account body dimensions, fit, size, and even the fabric of the garment itself.</p>
<p>Deal terms were not disclosed. According to data from Pitchbook, Zeekit had raised over $24 million in outside capital, but we&#8217;ve confirmed that&#8217;s inaccurate. Zeekit <a href="https://jewishbusinessnews.com/2016/09/15/israeli-startup-zeekit-the-most-advanced-virtual-fitting-room-app-raises-9-million/">raised a $9 million Series A</a> in 2016, and has raised a total of $16 million since 2014.</p>
<p>The company had already been working with a range of retailers and brands ahead of the acquisition, including Walmart, as well Macy&#8217;s, Asos, Tommy Hilfiger, Adidas, and others. It had once <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/09/rebecca-minkoffs-fashion-week-show-uses-augmented-reality-to-help-real-women-shop-the-look-live/">worked with Rebecca Minkoff during Fashion Week</a> to help women shop the show&#8217;s looks.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Zeekit had been founded in 2013 by CEO Yael Vizel, VP of Research and Development Nir Appleboim and CTO Alon Kristal, with the premise that if online shoppers could see how clothing would look on their own bodies, the technology could reduce the rate of returns due to non-fitting, non-flattering items.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2151668" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2151668" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2151668" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/download.gif?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" /><p id="caption-attachment-2151668" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong></p></div></p>
<p>Walmart says customers will be able to use the Zeekit technology to virtually try on items brands including Free People, Champion, Levi’s Strauss, ELOQUII Elements, Free Assembly, Scoop, Sofia Jeans by Sofia Vergara, plus its own private label brands, like Time and Tru, Terra &amp; Sky, Wonder Nation and George.</p>
<p>When the technology goes live on Walmart.com, customers can choose to upload an image of their own or choose from a series of models that best represent their height, shape and skin tone in order to see themselves virtually in any item of clothing. The goal is to provide a similar experience to trying on clothing when shopping online as you would otherwise have had when in a retail store.</p>
<p>Shoppers will also be able to share their virtual outfits with friends for a second opinion, via the new integration, adding the social element back into online shopping.</p>
<p>In addition to the virtual try-on, Walmart says Zeekit&#8217;s technology may be used to build other fashion experiences over time, including a virtual closet experience where you could mix and match styles.</p>
<p>With the deal&#8217;s closure, Zeekit&#8217;s three co-founders will be joining Walmart.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’re confident that with the team’s expertise in bringing real-time image technologies, computer vision and artificial intelligence to the world of fashion, we’ll identify even more ways to innovate for our customers in our continued effort to be the first-choice destination for fashion,&#8221; said Denise Incandela, Walmart U.S. EVP of Apparel and Private Brands, in an <a href="https://corporate.walmart.com/newsroom/2021/05/13/walmart-announces-plans-to-acquire-zeekit-a-leading-virtual-fitting-room-platform-to-enable-enhanced-and-social-shopping-experience-for-customer">announcement</a>.</p>
<p>Walmart in years past had heavily invested in apparel, including by acquiring online brands like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/16/walmart-to-buy-bonobos-for-310m-in-its-bigger-push-into-fashion-retail/">Bonobos</a>, ModCloth, Eloquii, and others, and even tried offering some brands, like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/05/bonobos-and-nike-get-their-own-branded-shops-on-walmarts-jet-com/">Nike</a>, their own shop on Walmart. com. Not all of these efforts paid off. <a href="https://www.retaildive.com/news/walmart-sells-modcloth-to-financial-firm/564464/">Walmart sold ModCloth</a> only a couple of years after buying it, for example, after ModCloth customers balked at being owned by a retail giant, and the brand remained unprofitable. More recently, Walmart <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/09/rebecca-minkoffs-fashion-week-show-uses-augmented-reality-to-help-real-women-shop-the-look-live/">partnered</a> with online consignment shop ThredUP to list a large number of secondhand items on Walmart&#8217;s website.</p>
<p>In addition to the struggles around profitability, apparel more broadly been a harder area for online retail to get right, often because of the difficulties involved with picking out items that have to fit unique bodies and the non-standard sizing fashion designers use &#8212; meaning clothing can run smaller or larger, depending on given brand, even when shopping &#8220;your size.&#8221;</p>
<p>Another factor that may have impacted the acquisition was the pandemic, which pushed e-commerce years ahead, as retailers closed their doors and consumers stayed home to shop online due the circumstances of the health crisis. During this time, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/17/amazon-unseats-walmart-to-become-the-no-1-apparel-retailer-in-the-us.html?">Amazon passed Walmart</a> as the top apparel retailer in the U.S., according to Wells Fargo, which estimated its apparel and footwear sales grew 15% in 2020 to over $41 billion, or 20-25% higher than Walmart.</p>
<p>Walmart didn&#8217;t say when Zeekit would go live on Walmart&#8217;s website, only that it would show up &#8220;soon.&#8221;</p>
<p>We understand that, post-acquisition, Walmart will not continue to operate Zeekit’s existing business. Zeekit will work with their current customers on a transition plan.</p>
<p><em>Updated 5/13/21, 11:05 AM ET with more accurate funding totals. Previously we noted Pitchbook data. We&#8217;ve since confirmed the figures directly. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/walmart-acquires-virtual-clothing-try-on-startup-zeekit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151641</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BluBracket nabs $12M Series A to expand source code security platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/blubracket-nabs-12m-series-a-to-expand-source-code-security-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/blubracket-nabs-12m-series-a-to-expand-source-code-security-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ajay Arora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BluBracket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[code security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evolution equity partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151632</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BluBracket, an early stage startup that focuses on keeping source code repositories secure, even in distributed environments, announced a $12 million Series A today. Evolution Equity Partners led the round with help from existing investors Unusual Ventures, Point72 Ventures, SignalFire and Firebolt Ventures. When combined with the $6.5 million seed round we reported on last [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.blubracket.com/">BluBracket</a>, an early stage startup that focuses on keeping source code repositories secure, even in distributed environments, announced a $12 million Series A today.</p>
<p>Evolution Equity Partners led the round with help from existing investors Unusual Ventures, Point72 Ventures, SignalFire and Firebolt Ventures. When combined with the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/blubracket-scores-6-5m-seed-to-help-secure-code-in-distributed-environments/">$6.5 million seed round</a> we reported on last year, the company has raised $19.5 million so far.</p>
<p>As you might imagine, being able to secure code in distributed environments came in quite handy when much of the technology world moved to work from home last year. BluBracket co-founder and COO Ajay Arora says that the pandemic forced many organizations to look carefully at how they secured their code base.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;So the anxiety organizations had about making sure their source code was secure and that it wasn&#8217;t leaking, from that standpoint that was a big tailwind for us. [With companies moving to a] completely remote development workforce, and with code being so important to their business as intellectual property, they needed to get that visibility into what vulnerabilities were there,&#8221; Arora explained.</p>
<p>Even prior to the pandemic, the company was finding they were gaining traction with developers and security pros by using a bottom up approach offering a free community version of the software. Having that free version as a top of the funnel for their sales motion was also helpful once COVID hit full force.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zRMcejaEB6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/2020-was-a-disaster-but-the-pandemic-put-security-in-the-spotlight/">2020 was a disaster, but the pandemic put security in the spotlight</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;2020 was a disaster, but the pandemic put security in the spotlight&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/2020-was-a-disaster-but-the-pandemic-put-security-in-the-spotlight/embed/#?secret=zRMcejaEB6" data-secret="zRMcejaEB6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Today, Arora says the company has multiple thousands of developers, DevOps and SecOps users across dozens of organizations using the company&#8217;s suite of products. The big reference company right now is Priceline, but he says there are other big names that would prefer not to be public about it.</p>
<p>The company currently has 30 employees with plans to double that by the end of the year, and he says that building diversity and inclusion into the hiring process is part of the company&#8217;s core values, and part of how the executive team gets measured.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re big believers in putting our money where our mouth is and one of the OKRs for me and my co-founder [CEO Prakash Linga], or one of the things that we&#8217;re actually compensated for is how well we are doing in building diversity and inclusion on the team,&#8221; he said. He adds that the recruiters that they are using are also being held to the same standard when it comes to providing a diverse set of candidates for open positions.</p>
<p>The company launched in 2018 and the founding team came from Vera, a startup that helped secure documents in motion. That company <a href="https://www.helpsystems.com/about/news/helpsystems-acquires-vera-broaden-data-security-portfolio">was sold to HelpSystems in December 2020</a> after Arora and Linga had left to start BluBracket.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GTy024ZfoU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/blubracket-scores-6-5m-seed-to-help-secure-code-in-distributed-environments/">BluBracket scores $6.5M seed to help secure code in distributed environments</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BluBracket scores $6.5M seed to help secure code in distributed environments&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/blubracket-scores-6-5m-seed-to-help-secure-code-in-distributed-environments/embed/#?secret=GTy024ZfoU" data-secret="GTy024ZfoU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/blubracket-nabs-12m-series-a-to-expand-source-code-security-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151632</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Don&#8217;t wait for legislation banning NDAs: Write ethical policies now</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/dont-wait-for-legislation-banning-ndas-write-ethical-policies-now/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/dont-wait-for-legislation-banning-ndas-write-ethical-policies-now/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labor rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ndas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pinterest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexual harassment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2150441</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Don't wait for laws preventing the use of NDAs. Companies should shape these policies on their own, rather than waiting for legislation to drag an ethical NDA policy out of them.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Julie Goldsmith Reiser</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/CohenMilstein">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.cohenmilstein.com/professional/julie-g-reiser">Julie Goldsmith Reiser</a> is the co-chair of the Securities Litigation &amp; Investor Protection group at national plaintiffs’ law firm Cohen Milstein Sellers &amp; Toll. 	</div>
	
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Louise Renne</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/rennepubliclaw">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://rennepubliclawgroup.com/team_member/louise-renne/">Louise Renne</a> is a founding partner of Renne Public Law Group and leads the firm’s public interest litigation.     	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Companies across the United States should be closely following the California State Legislature hearings on the “Silenced No More Act,” which would prevent the use of nondisclosure agreements (NDAs) to silence employees from speaking up about all forms of discrimination and harassment.</p>
<p>The legislation was introduced in response to the stunning claims brought forward by former Pinterest employees alleging a pattern of racial and gender discrimination, harassment and retaliation. They courageously called attention to the hypocrisy of Pinterest’s aspirational comments on social issues even though the company had required them to sign NDAs.</p>
<p>As attorneys who work with shareholders to hold companies accountable for this misconduct, these allegations have deeply impacted our work. They formed the basis of an ongoing shareholder derivative lawsuit that a state pension fund we represent brought against Pinterest’s board of directors and top executives for participating in and otherwise protecting powerful executives who are alleged to have discriminated against Pinterest employees.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Failure to recognize this necessity will lead to future corporate scandals as multiple accounts of the same type of misconduct in the workplace come to light.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>The Silenced No More Act would extend existing laws that limit the use of NDAs. Such laws are important because NDAs are intended to protect executives by keeping their harassment, discrimination and retaliation under wraps. That NDAs chill the voices of employees who have already been victimized makes them even more toxic. NDAs cause women to fear reprisal from the company, sometimes even incorporating financial penalty clauses, long after their individual claims have been resolved.</p>
<p>The Silenced No More Act should pass swiftly and be a model for other states, but this is what all companies throughout the country should be doing on their own, rather than waiting for legislation to drag an ethical NDA policy out of them.</p>
<p>Failure to recognize this necessity will lead to future corporate scandals as multiple accounts of the same type of misconduct in the workplace come to light. It will continue to uphold an unsustainable corporate system where executives in positions of power assume they will be protected no matter how unlawful their behavior toward others in the workplace.</p>
<p>We have seen from our investigations the compounding impacts of NDAs and how they allow problems to fester over years.</p>
<p>The two of us, working with others and on behalf of Alphabet shareholders, were part of the team that led a groundbreaking <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/09/25/alphabet-settles-shareholder-lawsuit-.html">$310 million settlement</a> with the tech company that led to historic diversity, equity and inclusion (DEI) reforms at the company. That settlement was the result of a shareholder derivative lawsuit where stockholders alleged that executives and board members violated their fiduciary duties by enabling a double standard that allowed executives to sexually harass and discriminate against women without consequence.</p>
<p>In that case, we believe Alphabet’s “culture of concealment” was driven in large part by the silencing effects of NDAs.</p>
<p>The duration of misconduct, enabled by NDAs, goes far beyond Alphabet and Pinterest. There is no shortage of #MeToo scandals at powerful companies, many with presences in California, that were exacerbated by muzzling NDAs. Weinstein Company, Wynn Resorts, NBC and 21st Century Fox are prominent examples of companies that first tried to keep allegations quiet through the use of NDAs and later faced a firestorm of allegations from former employees.</p>
<p>Fortunately, the landscape surrounding discrimination and harassment in the workplace is changing. Shareholders, workers, customers and other key business stakeholders are becoming more active in demanding that companies stop protecting harassers.</p>
<p>All of this should send a message to boards and C-suite executives that they must set the tone from the top and they are far better off being proactive than reactive. That means actively creating a company culture where DEI is a foundational component &#8212; not an afterthought. It also means intentionally prioritizing transparency and proactively doing away with policies that are antithetical to that goal, like NDAs that are intentionally designed to suppress the voices of employees.</p>
<p>The public and shareholders want to be associated with companies that do right by their employees. Business should recognize this change from a culture of compliance to one of equity and inclusion and embrace this new reality by stopping the practice of requiring complainants to enter into NDAs and fostering a culture of inclusion and accountability.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="a06eytQJHo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/pinterest-settles-gender-discrimination-lawsuit-with-former-coo-for-22-5-million/">Pinterest settles gender discrimination lawsuit with former COO for $22.5 million</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pinterest settles gender discrimination lawsuit with former COO for $22.5 million&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/pinterest-settles-gender-discrimination-lawsuit-with-former-coo-for-22-5-million/embed/#?secret=a06eytQJHo" data-secret="a06eytQJHo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/dont-wait-for-legislation-banning-ndas-write-ethical-policies-now/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2150441</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Worksome pulls $13M into its high skill freelancer talent platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/worksome-pulls-13m-into-its-high-skill-freelancer-talent-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/worksome-pulls-13m-into-its-high-skill-freelancer-talent-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:11:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adecco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Copenhagen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiverr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flexible work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freelance marketplace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freelancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kalo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telecommuting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upwork]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worksome]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151562</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[More money for the now very buzzy business of reshaping how people work: Worksome is announcing it recently closed a $13 million Series A funding round for its &#8220;freelance talent platform&#8221; &#8212; after racking up 10x growth in revenue since January 2020, just before the COVID-19 pandemic sparked a remote working boom. The 2017 founded [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">More money for the now very buzzy business of reshaping how people work: <a href="https://worksome.eu">Worksome</a> is announcing it recently closed a $13 million Series A funding round for its &#8220;freelance talent platform&#8221; &#8212; after racking up 10x growth in revenue since January 2020, just before the COVID-19 pandemic sparked a remote working boom.</p>
<p>The 2017 founded startup, which has a couple of ex-Googlers in its leadership team, has built a platform to connect freelancers looking for professional roles with employers needing tools to find and manage freelancer talent.</p>
<p>It says it&#8217;s seeing traction with large enterprise customers that have traditionally used Managed Service Providers (MSPs) to manage and pay external workforces &#8212; and views employment agency giants like Randstad, Adecco and Manpower as ripe targets for disruption.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Most multinational enterprises manage flexible workers using legacy MSPs,&#8221; says CEO and co-founder Morten Petersen (one of the Xooglers). &#8220;These largely analogue businesses manage complex compliance and processes around hiring and managing freelance workforces with handheld processes and outdated technology that is not built for managing fluid workforces. Worksome tackles this industry head on with a better, faster and simpler solution to manage large freelancer and contractor workforces.&#8221;</p>
<p>Worksome focuses on helping medium/large companies &#8212; who are working with at least 20+ freelancers at a time &#8212; fill vacancies within teams rather than helping companies outsource projects, per Petersen, who suggests the latter is the focus for the majority of freelancer platforms.</p>
<p>&#8220;Worksome helps [companies] onboard people who will provide necessary skills and will be integral to longer-term business operations. It makes matches between companies and skilled freelancers, which the businesses go on to trust, form relationships with and come back to time and time again,&#8221; he goes on.</p>
<p>&#8220;When companies hire dozens or hundreds of freelancers at one time, processes can get very complicated,&#8221; he adds, arguing that on compliance and payments Worksome &#8220;takes on a much greater responsibility than other freelancing platforms to make big hires easier&#8221;.</p>
<p>The startup also says it&#8217;s concerned with looking out for (and looking after) its freelancer talent pool &#8212; saying it wants to create &#8220;a world of meaningful work&#8221; on its platform, and ensure freelancers are paid fairly and competitively. (And also that they are paid faster than they otherwise might be, given it takes care of their payroll so they don&#8217;t have to chase payments from employers.)</p>
<p>The business started life in Copenhagen &#8212; and its Series A has a distinctly Nordic flavor, with investment coming from the Danish business angel and investor on the local version of the <em>Dragons&#8217; Den</em> TV program Løvens Hule; the former Minister for Higher Education and Science, Tommy Ahlers; and family home manufacturer Lind &amp; Risør.</p>
<p>It had raised just under $6M prior to thus round, per <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/worksome/company_financials">Crunchbase</a>, and also counts some (unnamed) Google executives among its earlier investors.</p>
<p>Freelancer platforms (and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/06/upwork-ipo/">marketplaces</a>) aren&#8217;t new, of course. There are also an increasing number of players in this space &#8212; buoyed by a <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">new flush of VC dollars chasing the &#8216;future of work&#8217;, whatever hybrid home-office flexible shape that might take. </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">So Worksome is by no means alone in offering tech tools to streamline the interface between freelancers and businesses.</span></p>
<p>A few others that spring to mind include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/23/lystable-takes-10m-top-up-to-tackle-freelancer-payments/">Lystable</a> (now Kalo), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/14/malt-raises-28-6-million-for-its-freelancer-platform/">Malt</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/15/fiverr-business/">Fiverr</a> &#8212; or, for techie job matching specifically, the likes of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/13/hackerrank-raises-30m-to-match-developers-with-jobs/">HackerRank</a> &#8212; plus, on the blue collar work side, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/jobandtalent-tops-up-with-108m-for-its-workforce-as-a-service-platform/">Jobandtalent</a>. There&#8217;s also a growing number of startups focusing on helping freelancer teams specifically (e.g. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/collective-launches-a-saas-marketplace-for-freelancer-teams/">Collective</a>), so there&#8217;s a trend towards increasing specialism.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wlGOHLe2bv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/collective-launches-a-saas-marketplace-for-freelancer-teams/">Collective launches a SaaS marketplace for freelancer teams</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Collective launches a SaaS marketplace for freelancer teams&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/collective-launches-a-saas-marketplace-for-freelancer-teams/embed/#?secret=wlGOHLe2bv" data-secret="wlGOHLe2bv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Worksome says it differentiates vs other players (legacy and startups) by combining services like tax compliance, background and ID checks and handling payroll and other admin with an AI powered platform that matches talent to projects.</p>
<p>Although it&#8217;s not the only startup offering to do the back-office admin/payroll piece, either, nor the only one using AI to match skilled professionals to projects. But it claims it&#8217;s going further than rival &#8216;freelancer-as-a-service&#8217; platforms &#8212; saying it wants to &#8220;address the entire value chain&#8221; (aka: &#8220;everything from the hiring of freelance talent to onboarding and payment&#8221;).</p>
<p>Worksome has 550 active clients (i.e. employers in the market for freelancer talent) at this stage; and has accepted 30,000 freelancers into its marketplace so far.</p>
<p>Its current talent pool can take on work across 12 categories, and collectively offers more than 39,000 unique skills, per Petersen.</p>
<p>The biggest categories of freelancer talent on the platform are in Software and IT; Design and Creative Work; Finance and Management Consulting; plus &#8220;a long tail of niche skills&#8221; within engineering and pharmaceuticals.</p>
<p>While its largest customers are found in the creative industries, tech and IT, pharma and consumer goods. And its biggest markets are the U.K. and U.S.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are currently trailing at +20,000 yearly placements,&#8221; says Petersen, adding: &#8220;The average yearly spend per client is $300,000.&#8221;</p>
<p>Worksome says the Series A funding will go on stoking growth by investing in marketing. It also plans to spend on product dev and on building out its team globally (it also has offices in London and New York).</p>
<p>Over the past 12 months the startup doubled the size of its team to 50 &#8212; and wants to do so again within 12 months so it can ramp up its enterprise client base in the U.S., U.K. and euro-zone.</p>
<p>&#8220;Yes, there are a lot of freelancer platforms out there but a lot of these don’t appreciate that hiring is only the tip of the iceberg when it comes to reducing the friction in working with freelancers,&#8221; argues Petersen. &#8220;Of the time that goes into hiring, managing and paying freelancers, 75% is currently spent on admin such as timesheet approvals, invoicing and compliance checks, leaving only a tiny fraction of time to actually finding talent.&#8221;</p>
<p>Worksome woos employers with a &#8220;one-click-hire&#8221; offer &#8212; touting its ability to find and hire freelancers &#8220;within seconds&#8221;.</p>
<p>If hiring a stranger in seconds sounds ill-advised, Worksome greases this external employment transaction by taking care of vetting the freelancers itself (including carrying out background checks; and using proprietary technology to asses freelancers&#8217; skills and suitability for its marketplace).</p>
<p>&#8220;We have a two-step vetting process to ensure that we only allow the best freelance talent onto the Worksome platform,&#8221; Petersen tells TechCrunch. &#8220;For step one, an inhouse-built robot assesses our freelancer applicants. It analyses their skillset, social media profiles, profile completeness and hourly or daily rate, as well as their CV and work history, to decide whether each person is a good fit for Worksome.</p>
<p>&#8220;For step two, our team of talent specialists manually review and decline or approve the freelancers that pass through step one with a score of 85% or more. We have just approved our 30,000th freelancer and will be able to both scale and improve our vetting procedure as we grow.&#8221;</p>
<p>A majority of freelancer applicants fail Worksome&#8217;s proprietary vetting processes. This is clear because it says it has received 80,000 applicants so far &#8212; but only approved 30,000.</p>
<p>That raises interesting questions about how it&#8217;s making decisions on who is (and isn&#8217;t) an &#8216;appropriate fit&#8217; for its talent marketplace.</p>
<p>It says its candidate assessing &#8220;robot&#8221; looks at &#8220;whether freelancers can demonstrate the skillset, matching work history, industry experience and profile depth&#8221; deemed necessary to meet its quality criteria &#8212; giving the example that it would not accept a freelancer who says they can lead complex IT infrastructure projects if they do not have evidence of relevant work, education and skills.</p>
<p>On the AI freelancer-to-project matching side, Worksome says its technology aims to match<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> freelancers &#8220;who have the highest likelihood of completing a job with high satisfaction, based on their work-history, and performance and skills used on previous jobs&#8221;. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;This creates a feedback loop that&#8230; ensure that both clients and freelancers are matched with great people and great work,&#8221; is its circular suggestion when we ask about this. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">But it also emphasizes that its AI is not making hiring decisions on its own &#8212; and is only ever supporting humans in making a choice. (An interesting caveat since existing EU data protection rules, under Article 22 of the GDPR, provide for a right for individuals to object to automated decision making if significant decisions are being taken without meaningful human interaction.) </span></p>
<p>Using automation technologies (like AI) to make assessments that determine whether a person gains access to employment opportunities or doesn&#8217;t can certainly risk scaled discrimination. So the devil really is in the detail of how these algorithmic assessments are done.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s why such uses of technology are set to face close regulatory scrutiny in the European Union &#8212; under incoming rules on &#8216;high risk&#8217; users of artificial intelligence &#8212; including the use of AI to match candidates to jobs.</p>
<p>The EU&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/europe-lays-out-plan-for-risk-based-ai-rules-to-boost-trust-and-uptake/">current legislative proposals</a> in this area specifically categorize &#8220;employment, workers management and access to self-employment&#8221; as a high risk use of AI, meaning applications like Worksome are likely to face some of the highest levels of regulatory supervision in the future.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FvJZwiQSXl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/europe-lays-out-plan-for-risk-based-ai-rules-to-boost-trust-and-uptake/">Europe lays out plan for risk-based AI rules to boost trust and uptake</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe lays out plan for risk-based AI rules to boost trust and uptake&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/europe-lays-out-plan-for-risk-based-ai-rules-to-boost-trust-and-uptake/embed/#?secret=FvJZwiQSXl" data-secret="FvJZwiQSXl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Nonetheless, Worksome is bullish when we ask about the risks associated with using AI as an intermediary for employment opportunities.</p>
<p>&#8220;We utilise fairly advanced matching algorithms to very effectively shortlist candidates for a role based solely on objective criteria, rinsed from human bias,&#8221; claims Petersen. &#8220;Our algorithms don&#8217;t take into account gender, ethnicity, name of educational institutions or other aspects that are usually connected to human bias.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;AI has immense potential in solving major industry challenges such as recruitment bias, low worker mobility and low access to digital skills among small to medium sized businesses. We are firm believers that technology should be utilized to remove human bias’ from any hiring process,&#8221; he goes on, adding: &#8220;Our tech was built to this very purpose from the beginning, and the new proposed legislation has the potential to serve as a validator for the hard work we’ve put into this.</p>
<p>&#8220;The obvious potential downside would be if new legislation would limit innovation by making it harder for startups to experiment with new technologies. As always, legislation like this will impact the Davids more than the Goliaths, even though the intentions may have been the opposite.&#8221;</p>
<p>Zooming back out to consider the pandemic-fuelled remote working boom, Worksome confirms that most of the projects for which it supplied freelancers last year were conducted remotely.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;We are currently seeing a slow shift back towards a combination of remote and onsite work and expect this combination to stick amongst most of our clients,&#8221; Petersen goes on. </span>&#8220;Whenever we are in uncertain economic times, we see a rise in the number of freelancers that companies are using. However, this trend is dwarfed by a much larger overall trend towards flexible work, which drives the real shift in the market. This shift has been accelerated by COVID-19 but has been underway for many years.</p>
<p>&#8220;While remote work has unlocked an enormous potential for accessing talent everywhere, 70% of the executives expect to use more temporary workers and contractors onsite than they did before COVID-19, according to a recent McKinsey study. This shows that businesses really value the flexibility in using an on-demand workforce of highly skilled specialists that can interact directly with their own teams.&#8221;</p>
<p>Asked whether it&#8217;s expecting growth in freelancing to sustain even after we (hopefully) move beyond the pandemic &#8212; including if there&#8217;s a return to physical offices &#8212; <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Petersen</span> suggests the underlying trend is for businesses to need increased flexibility, regardless of the exact blend of full-time and freelancer staff. So platforms like Worksome are confidently poised to keep growing.</p>
<p>&#8220;When you ask business leaders, 90% believe that shifting their talent model to a blend of full-time and freelancers can give a future competitive advantage (Source: BCG),&#8221; he says. &#8220;We see two major trends driving this sentiment; access to talent, and building an agile and flexible organization. This has become all the more true during the pandemic &#8212; a high degree of flexibility is allowing organisations to better navigate both the initial phase of the pandemic as well the current pick up of business activity.</p>
<p>&#8220;With the amount of change that we’re currently seeing in the world, and with businesses are constantly re-inventing themselves, the access to highly skilled and flexible talent is absolutely essential &#8212; now, in the next 5 years, and beyond.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="85XB9hv01T"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/31/6-vcs-discuss-how-the-future-of-work-is-one-of-the-most-exciting-opportunities-right-now/">6 VCs share their bets on the future of work</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;6 VCs share their bets on the future of work&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/31/6-vcs-discuss-how-the-future-of-work-is-one-of-the-most-exciting-opportunities-right-now/embed/#?secret=85XB9hv01T" data-secret="85XB9hv01T" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CC7lqToqMw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/14/malt-raises-28-6-million-for-its-freelancer-platform/">Malt raises $28.6 million for its freelancer platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Malt raises $28.6 million for its freelancer platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/14/malt-raises-28-6-million-for-its-freelancer-platform/embed/#?secret=CC7lqToqMw" data-secret="CC7lqToqMw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aaNKaV5pe3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/15/fiverr-business/">Fiverr Business helps teams manage freelance projects</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fiverr Business helps teams manage freelance projects&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/15/fiverr-business/embed/#?secret=aaNKaV5pe3" data-secret="aaNKaV5pe3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/worksome-pulls-13m-into-its-high-skill-freelancer-talent-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151562</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Cloud teams up with SpaceX&#8217;s Starlink for enterprise connectivity at network&#8217;s edge</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/google-cloud-teams-up-with-spacexs-starlink-for-enterprise-connectivity-at-networks-edge/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/google-cloud-teams-up-with-spacexs-starlink-for-enterprise-connectivity-at-networks-edge/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:24:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broadband]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet access]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spacecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starlink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telecommunications]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151612</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SpaceX&#8217;s bourgeoning Starlink satellite-based broadband internet service just got a big boost from a significant new partner: Google Cloud. Thanks to a new partnership between the two, SpaceX will now be locating Starlink ground stations right within Google&#8217;s existing data centers, providing the Starlink network with direct access to ground-based network infrastructure to help facilitate [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">SpaceX&#8217;s bourgeoning Starlink satellite-based broadband internet service just got a big boost from a significant new partner: Google Cloud. Thanks to a new partnership between the two, SpaceX will now be locating Starlink ground stations right within Google&#8217;s existing data centers, providing the Starlink network with direct access to ground-based network infrastructure to help facilitate network connections for customers who are on the edges of the footprint of existing network access.</p>
<p>Starlink&#8217;s entire aim is to provide reliable, broadband-quality connections to areas that have typically be hard or impossible to reach with legacy ground-based network infrastructure, including cellular networks. The tie-up with Google means that not only will business and public sector customers taking advantage of that new network reach have access to internet connections, but also to cloud-based infrastructure and applications, including AI and machine learning capabilities, analytics and more.</p>
<p>This should not only bolster Starlink&#8217;s reliability in terms of its consumer clients, but also provide key capabilities for serving enterprise customers — another key target demographic for the growing Starlink business, though much of the public focus thus far for Starlink&#8217;s roll-out has been on residential access across its expanding beta.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Google and Starlink expect to begin to become available to enterprise customers soon — sometime pin the &#8220;second half of 2021&#8221; according to a<a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/google-cloud-and-spacexs-starlink-to-deliver-secure-global-connectivity-301290801.html"> press release</a> issued by the companies.</p>
<p>SpaceX has been very aggressive in building out the Starlink network in the past few months, launching 480 in just around there months. All that in-space infrastructure build out could well have been pre-amble to this collaboration and enterprise-focused service launch, in addition to helping SpaceX expand Starlink consumer service quality and availability.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uwU6I3c283"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/spacex-launches-60-more-starlink-satellites-claims-over-500000-service-pre-orders-so-far/">SpaceX launches 60 more Starlink satellites, claims over 500,000 service pre-orders so far</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SpaceX launches 60 more Starlink satellites, claims over 500,000 service pre-orders so far&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/spacex-launches-60-more-starlink-satellites-claims-over-500000-service-pre-orders-so-far/embed/#?secret=uwU6I3c283" data-secret="uwU6I3c283" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/google-cloud-teams-up-with-spacexs-starlink-for-enterprise-connectivity-at-networks-edge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151612</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>With its newest round, Liquid Death will exclusively &#8216;murder your thirst&#8217; at Live Nation events</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/with-its-newest-round-liquid-death-will-exclusively-murder-your-thirst-at-live-nation-events/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/with-its-newest-round-liquid-death-will-exclusively-murder-your-thirst-at-live-nation-events/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Liquid Death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[live-nation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Water]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151496</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Liquid Death, a  four-year-old, L.A.-based canned mountain water startup that has steadily garnered market share and press coverage by promising, amusingly, to &#8220;murder your thirst,&#8221; just raised $15 million in Series C funding. The round brings the company&#8217;s total backing to date to $50 million. The new financing &#8212; it follows a $23 million Series [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://liquiddeath.com/">Liquid Death</a>, a  four-year-old, L.A.-based canned mountain water startup that has steadily garnered market share and press coverage by promising, amusingly, to &#8220;murder your thirst,&#8221; just raised $15 million in Series C funding. The round brings the company&#8217;s total backing to date to $50 million.</p>
<p>The new financing &#8212; it follows a $23 million Series B round last fall &#8212; was seemingly about getting more strategic partners involved with the brand. Most meaningfully, Live Nation, the giant concert promoter, just became an equity investor and, as part of the deal, will only sell Liquid Death across its venues and festivals across the United States for a period of time.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s a big deal. Though Liquid Death has done pretty well on its own in terms of its distribution &#8212; it says its water is now carried in 16,000 locations throughout the U.S. including bars, tattoo parlors, cafes, local liquor stores and &#8220;big box&#8221; stores like Whole Foods, Walmart and 7-Eleven &#8212; Live Nation connects the brand with a massive and captive audience. Specifically, Live Nation says that in a typical (not COVID) year, it brings in 100 million fans to events across more than 120 Live Nation-owned-and-operated venues and festivals across the U.S. (Because Liquid Death comes in recyclable aluminum cans versus far-less recyclable plastic bottles, the tie-up is a good look for Live Nation, too.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Liquid Death cofounder and CEO Mike Cessario, a former creative director and copywriter, declined yesterday to say how much Live Nation plans to charge for his products. But he did confirm that because the now 60-person company has &#8220;seen a ton of growth in retail and online in the past year,&#8221; it &#8220;didn’t need to raise a ton of cash right now.&#8221; In fact, he noted that as a &#8220;maturing&#8221; startup, Liquid Death now has &#8220;more access to favorable debt terms for working capital&#8221; should it go that route at some point.</p>
<p>Other investors in the new round include Tony Hawk, Wiz Khalifa, Steve Aoki, Hulu president Kelly Campbell and Dollar Shave Club founder Michael Dubin.</p>
<p>Cessario says the new funding won&#8217;t be used to expand internationally &#8212; not yet. Though Liquid Death is available in Canada and receives &#8220;tons of requests on social for international expansion,&#8221; the company is &#8220;focused on conquering the U.S. and Canada for the time being,&#8221; he tells us. As for branching out into new products, he says the team is &#8220;exploring some ideas like limited-release flavors for later this year.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/with-its-newest-round-liquid-death-will-exclusively-murder-your-thirst-at-live-nation-events/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151496</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Morressier wants academic conferences to feel cutting edge</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/morressier-wants-academic-conferences-to-feel-cutting-edge/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/morressier-wants-academic-conferences-to-feel-cutting-edge/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Morressier]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151585</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While a unicorn named Hopin tends to dominate the virtual conferencing space, a new startup just raised millions of dollars by focusing on what it believes is an untapped niche in the same universe: academic conferences. Morressier, a virtual conference and publishing platform specifically for the scientific community, announced today that it has raised $18 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/07/hopin-might-be-the-fastest-growth-story-of-this-era/">While a unicorn named Hopin</a> tends to dominate the virtual conferencing space, a new startup just raised millions of dollars by focusing on what it believes is an untapped niche in the same universe: academic conferences.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.morressier.com/">Morressier</a>, a virtual conference and publishing platform specifically for the scientific community, announced today that it has raised $18 million in a Series A round led by Owl Ventures. Existing investors Cherry Ventures and Redalpine Venture Partners also participated in the round.</p>
<p>Founder <a href="https://twitter.com/samibln?lang=en">Sami Benchekroun</a> spent a lot of time at medical and scientific conferences while growing up thanks to his parents, who were both pursuing careers in medicine. Eventually, he began recognizing a pattern between all of the conferences.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“People from around the world would come together and literally bring physical content like printed out posters [or] a presentation on USB keys, to these conferences, but after the three days, all that content is lost,” he said. “All the people [who] are working on cancer research and HIV research are coming to these conferences completely offline, sharing the ideas, and then everything is lost.”</p>
<p>The irony of it was distracting so, in 2014, he began trying to digitize the early exchange of knowledge at a conference.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pilSWYTrHi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/edtech-zoom-university/">Tired of &#8216;Zoom University&#8217;? So is edtech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tired of &#8216;Zoom University&#8217;? So is edtech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/edtech-zoom-university/embed/#?secret=pilSWYTrHi" data-secret="pilSWYTrHi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“Democratizing sounds cheesy but it&#8217;s really that,” he said. “People from Africa or Asia have no chance to really get access to these really high profile conferences that are mainly happening in the States or Europe, so by actually making everything digital, we can give back.”</p>
<p>The company began with a focus on content ephemerality, and nearly 7 years later, Morressier has built an end-to-end software layer that it hopes makes the academic conference experience as cutting edge as the research within it.</p>
<p>First, Morressier works with a society to create a landing page for an upcoming conference. Researchers can apply there to present their research at said conference. Morressier then aggregates all the research submissions and begins conducting a peer review process, with academics from the society validating the research and deciding if its relevant. The peer review process can often happen offline on excel sheets and word documents, so Morressier helps move the entire operations online. Once the peer review is done, the startup creates a content library to go along with a virtual or in-person conference where it can live indefinitely.</p>
<p>Finally, it gets to hosting the dissemination of that content to giving post-event analytics to event hosts to understand how research is being consumed.</p>
<p>“In order to make a compelling, end to end solution for every society out there, we added that live stream video component only in the beginning of 2020,” he said.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-2151587" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Morressier-Screenshot-1.png" alt="" width="904" height="634" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Morressier-Screenshot-1.png 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Morressier-Screenshot-1.png?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Morressier-Screenshot-1.png?resize=300,210 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Morressier-Screenshot-1.png?resize=768,539 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Morressier-Screenshot-1.png?resize=680,477 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Morressier-Screenshot-1.png?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 904px) 100vw, 904px" /></p>
<p>Morressier has over 700,000 accounts on its service, and has held conferences with the American Chemical Society and the Society of Photo-optical Instrumentation Engineers among others. The company makes money by working directly with the societies and charging them a flat fee for using the platform conference organization and managing their peer review process. It also has a per document-based fee structure so as more research is uploaded to its database, Morressier makes more money.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2151586" style="width: 849px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2151586" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2151586" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Morressier-Screenshot-2.png" alt="" width="839" height="588" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Morressier-Screenshot-2.png 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Morressier-Screenshot-2.png?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Morressier-Screenshot-2.png?resize=300,210 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Morressier-Screenshot-2.png?resize=768,539 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Morressier-Screenshot-2.png?resize=680,477 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Morressier-Screenshot-2.png?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 839px) 100vw, 839px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2151586" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Morressier</p></div></p>
<p>While growth is the obvious next step for the freshly-funded company, Morressier hasn’t been exactly sluggish in the meantime. The company had 6x growth in number of authors and 13x growth in number of documents on its platform, bringing on $4.5 million in sales in 2020. The early-stage startup began 2020 with a 28-person staff, and plans to grow to 100 people by the end of 2021.</p>
<p>The founder, of course, accounts part of this growth to the pandemic, which took down some of the natural red tape that exists in education.</p>
<p>“I always try to play this down but quite frankly, in research and education, unfortunately things take longer [because of] government structures,” he said, of adoption speed. Indeed, the company took four years to raise its first check due to development. Now, three years after that, Morressier has closed another tranche of capital, thanks to a global understanding that virtual events are the future. Now, it&#8217;s just time for Morressier to prove its pandemic bump has paved a way for it to become a high-growth business.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BJ7ws0JE2z"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/virtual-hqs-race-to-win-over-a-remote-work-fatigued-market/">Virtual HQs race to win over a remote-work-fatigued market</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Virtual HQs race to win over a remote-work-fatigued market&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/virtual-hqs-race-to-win-over-a-remote-work-fatigued-market/embed/#?secret=BJ7ws0JE2z" data-secret="BJ7ws0JE2z" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/morressier-wants-academic-conferences-to-feel-cutting-edge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151585</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roku will launch original programming fueled by Quibi&#8217;s content on May 20</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/roku-launches-an-original-programming-lineup-fueled-by-quibis-content/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/roku-launches-an-original-programming-lineup-fueled-by-quibis-content/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ad-supported streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[avod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chrissy Teigen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[original programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[originals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quibi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roku]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151058</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roku today announced the launch of its own original programming, which will initially become available to viewers in the U.S., U.K., and Canada through the media platform&#8217;s free streaming hub, The Roku Channel, starting on May 20th. The debut lineup will include 30 titles, including both the scripted and reality programming Roku had acquired from [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Roku today announced the launch of its own original programming, which will initially become available to viewers in the U.S., U.K., and Canada through the media platform&#8217;s free streaming hub, The Roku Channel, starting on May 20th. The debut lineup will include 30 titles, including both the scripted and reality programming <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/roku-acquires-quibis-content/">Roku had acquired</a> from the short-form streaming service Quibi earlier this year, following its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/21/quibi-is-dead/">shutdown</a>.</p>
<p>Quibi, of course, had launched at an inopportune time for a service that was designed for on-the-go viewing, when it arrived <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/05/quibi-launches-its-mobile-streaming-service-in-the-middle-of-the-quarantine-era/">in the middle of a pandemic</a>. But some <a href="https://www.cnet.com/reviews/quibi-review/">have argued</a> that much of Quibi&#8217;s content <a href="https://www.vulture.com/2020/04/the-bites-are-quick-and-bad.html">wasn&#8217;t compelling</a> enough to pull in the number of subscribers to make the service a success. It will be interesting to see how well that same content now fares on Roku where it will no longer be &#8220;mobile-first,&#8221; but will more likely be streamed on a big-screen TV.</p>
<p>Among the better-known Quibi shows that will now be joining Roku are Chrissy Teigen&#8217;s &#8220;Chrissy&#8217;s Court,&#8221; Comedy Central&#8217;s &#8220;Reno 911!,&#8221; Kevin Hart&#8217;s &#8220;Die Hart&#8221; action series, <a href="https://variety.com/2020/tv/news/quibi-first-emmys-wins-1234774206/">Emmy-winning</a> &#8220;FreeRayshawn,&#8221; documentaries “Blackballed” and “Big Rad Wolf,” and reality show reboot &#8220;Punk&#8217;d.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>These and others will become Roku&#8217;s first original programs, joining the over 40,000 other free movies and TV shows on <a href="https://therokuchannel.roku.com/">The Roku Channel.</a> This free streaming hub has been growing rapidly, in part due to the pandemic which forced people to stay at home, but also because of broader demand for free streaming content.</p>
<p>In the fourth quarter of 2020, The Roku Channel reached 63 million people in U.S. households, up more than 100% year-over-year. Streaming hours also doubled year-over-year &#8212; growth that&#8217;s twice as fast as the overall Roku platform itself, the company notes. In the first quarter of 2021, The Roku Channel grew to reach an estimated 70 million people.</p>
<p>The full list of Roku Originals includes available for the May 20th launch include: #FreeRayshawn,&#8221; &#8220;About Face,&#8221; &#8220;Bad Ideas with Adam Devine,&#8221; &#8220;Barkitechture,&#8221; &#8220;Big Rad Wolf,&#8221; &#8220;Blackballed,&#8221; &#8220;Centerpiece,&#8221; &#8220;Chrissy’s Court,&#8221; &#8220;Cup of Joe,&#8221; &#8220;Die Hart,&#8221; &#8220;Dishmantled,&#8221;Dummy,&#8221; &#8220;Fight Like a Girl,&#8221; &#8220;Flipped, &#8220;The Fugitive,&#8221; &#8220;Gayme Show, &#8220;Iron Sharpens Iron,&#8221; &#8220;Last Looks, &#8220;Let’s Roll with Tony Greenhand,&#8221; &#8220;Most Dangerous Game,&#8221; Murder House Flip,&#8221; &#8220;Murder Unboxed,&#8221; &#8220;Nightgowns,&#8221; &#8220;Prodigy,&#8221; &#8220;Punk’d,&#8221; &#8220;Reno 911!,&#8221; &#8220;Royalties,&#8221; &#8220;Shape of Pasta,&#8221; &#8220;Thanks a Million,&#8221; and &#8220;You Ain’t Got These.&#8221;</p>
<p>Roku will market the shows to viewers inside The Roku Channel, through an ad unit below the left-side navigation on the Roku home screen, and even through a coveted slot in the navigation menu itself.</p>
<p>In addition to the 30 new programs launching in May, more Roku Originals will roll out over the course of 2021. In total, Roku acquired more than 75 titles from Quibi, in a deal that reportedly valued the content at <a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/roku-acquires-quibi-shows-free-streaming-1234881238/">&#8220;significantly less&#8221; than $100 million.</a> That means Roku users will eventually gain access to the Quibi shows that had been in the pipeline, but never got a chance to debut.</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QuMIPIGN7Ug" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Quibi&#8217;s content made sense for Roku because it was designed for ad-supported viewing and not because of Quibi&#8217;s mobile gimmicks &#8212; <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-08-quibi-mobile-video-turnstyle.html">like &#8220;turnstyle&#8221;</a> which made both portrait and landscape orientations look great, or horror shows that <a href="https://variety.com/2019/tv/news/steven-spielberg-quibi-jeffrey-katzenberg-horror-1203237395/">only stream after dark</a>, for instance.</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s always unique &#8216;stunt-y&#8217; ways to bring shows to life, and we will explore those for shows that make sense,&#8221; noted Roku VP Sweta Patel, who leads the company&#8217;s Engagement and Growth Marketing. &#8220;But it&#8217;s going to have to make sense for how our viewers view &#8212; which is primarily on a [Roku] device,&#8221; she says.</p>
<p>In other words, Roku viewers won&#8217;t care about all the Quibi tricks, just the content itself. However, the shows will stream through The Roku Channel mobile app, for the subset of viewers who do watch on the go.</p>
<p>Roku will also leverage the existing ad breaks Quibi had built into its content, it says. That means after every 8 to 10-minute long &#8220;episode,&#8221; a one-minute ad will play. That&#8217;s still a lighter ad load than traditional TV, Patel notes. The same ad-selling structure that The Roku Channel uses today will also apply to Originals, including the potential for brand sponsorships.</p>
<p>While Roku believes the Originals can help to bring in a younger, 18-34 year-old demographic, it&#8217;s not necessarily signaling a plan to increase investments in exclusive, original programming like this. Instead, Roku will watch to see how the new content performs and then use those insights to add more content to The Roku Channel&#8217;s library over time.</p>
<p>&#8220;This really It was a unique opportunity for us to get some incredible content for our growing base. We are always sourcing content and &#8212; whether that&#8217;s producing it or acquiring it &#8212; it has to make sense for our AVOD business model,&#8221; says Patel. However, now that Roku has its own programming to offer, it will make sense for the company to roll out The Roku Channel to its global markets outside the U.S., U.K., and Canada.</p>
<p>The company wouldn&#8217;t comment on those plans.</p>
<p>Alongside the launch of Roku Originals, Roku also announced a partnership with Laugh Out Loud, the comedy brand founded by Kevin Hart. It will now bring the linear channel LOL! Network to The Roku Channel, joining the now over 190 live, linear channels featured on the service.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/roku-launches-an-original-programming-lineup-fueled-by-quibis-content/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151058</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BRD&#8217;s Blockset unveils its white-label cryptocurrency wallet for banks and other enterprise clients</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/brds-blockset-unveils-its-white-label-cryptocurrency-wallet-for-banks-and-other-enterprise-clients/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/brds-blockset-unveils-its-white-label-cryptocurrency-wallet-for-banks-and-other-enterprise-clients/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wallet-as-a-service]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151531</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Blockset, the blockchain infrastructure platform for enterprises by BRD, announced early access to its Wallet-as-a-Service today. The white-label solution gives clients, like financial institutions, the ability to launch wallets that have the same features as BRD’s own mobile cryptocurrency wallet, which now has about 7 million users with over $20 billion assets under protection. Blockset’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://blockset.com/">Blockset</a>, the blockchain infrastructure platform for enterprises by <a href="https://brd.com/">BRD</a>, announced early access to its Wallet-as-a-Service today. The white-label solution gives clients, like financial institutions, the ability to launch wallets that have the same features as BRD’s own mobile cryptocurrency wallet, which now has about 7 million users with over $20 billion assets under protection.</p>
<p>Blockset’s clients include some of the largest ATM networks and Japanese investment bank (and BRD investor) SBI Holdings, CoinFlip, Welthee, CoinSwitch, Coinsquare and Wyre. BRD’s other investors include Ripple and it has raised $56 million in funding so far.</p>
<p>One of Blockset’s selling points is access to real-time data about several kinds of cryptocurrencies. This not only allows users to see how their assets are performing, but also enables institutions to perform compliance tasks, fraud detection, anti-money laundering and other important services. Blockset also claims that its multi-chain API has up to 99.999% uptime.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The platform currently supports Bitcoin, Ethereum, Ripple, Tezos, Hedera, Bitcoin Cash and Bitcoin SV, and will add more chains based on customer demand.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kaLQ30imAL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/cryptocurrency-wallet-brd-reaches-6-million-users-driven-by-growth-in-latin-america-and-india/">Cryptocurrency wallet BRD reaches 6 million users, driven by growth in Latin America and India</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cryptocurrency wallet BRD reaches 6 million users, driven by growth in Latin America and India&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/cryptocurrency-wallet-brd-reaches-6-million-users-driven-by-growth-in-latin-america-and-india/embed/#?secret=kaLQ30imAL" data-secret="kaLQ30imAL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Blockset already offered a white-label solution called WalletKit, before launching its current Wallet-as-a-Service with more features. BRD co-founder and CEO Adam Traidman compares its Wallet-as-a-Service to Google Maps, because both aggregate large amounts of constantly-changing data and can connect to other apps, while remaining user-friendly.</p>
<p>“The concept is really a result of learnings from working with our customers, tier one financial institutions, who need a couple things,” Traidman told TechCrunch. “Generally they want to custody crypto on behalf of their customers. For example, if you’re running an ETF, like a Bitcoin ETF, or if you’re offering customers buying and selling, you need a way to store the crypto, and you need a way to access the blockchain.”</p>
<p>“The Wallet-as-a-Service is the nomenclature we use to talk about the challenge that customers are facing, whereby blockchain is really complex,” he added. “There are three V’s that I talk about: variety, a lot of velocity because there’s a lot of transactions per second, and volume because there’s a lot of total aggregate data.”</p>
<p>Blockset also enables clients to add features like trading crypto or fiat or lending Bitcoin or Stablecoins to take advantage of high interest rates. Enterprises can develop and integrate their own solutions or work with Blockset’s partners.</p>
<p>Other companies that offer enterprise blockchain infrastructure include Bison Trails, which was recently acquired by Coinbase, and Galaxy Digital.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XYOHGypDhU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/a-conversation-with-bison-trails-the-aws-like-service-inside-of-coinbase/">A conversation with Bison Trails, the AWS-like service inside of Coinbase</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A conversation with Bison Trails, the AWS-like service inside of Coinbase&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/a-conversation-with-bison-trails-the-aws-like-service-inside-of-coinbase/embed/#?secret=XYOHGypDhU" data-secret="XYOHGypDhU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Blockset differentiates by focusing on real-time data. It looks at a smaller number of mainstream blockchains in order to ensure depth of information and speed.</p>
<p>“If you’re a financial institution, you can’t accept anything other than instant, accurate and highly-scalable kinds of data. Right down to the millisecond of latency is really important because it can give traders an advantage,” said Traidman.</p>
<p>In a press statement, Wyre chief executive officer Ioannis Giannaros said “Blockset is the clear industry leader in offering enterprise-grade SLAs [service-level agreements] that we require to guarantee high scalability, uptime and data integrity across multiple blockchains.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="udjcM89unO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/25/a-look-inside-crypto-firm-digital-galaxy-founded-by-sidelined-wall-street-legend-mike-novogratz/">A look inside crypto firm Galaxy Digital, founded by &#8216;sidelined&#8217; Wall Street legend Mike Novogratz</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A look inside crypto firm Galaxy Digital, founded by &#8216;sidelined&#8217; Wall Street legend Mike Novogratz&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/25/a-look-inside-crypto-firm-digital-galaxy-founded-by-sidelined-wall-street-legend-mike-novogratz/embed/#?secret=udjcM89unO" data-secret="udjcM89unO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CcNal2L9Me"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/coinbases-direct-listing-alters-the-landscape-for-fintech-and-crypto-startups/">Coinbase’s direct listing alters the landscape for fintech and crypto startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Coinbase’s direct listing alters the landscape for fintech and crypto startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/coinbases-direct-listing-alters-the-landscape-for-fintech-and-crypto-startups/embed/#?secret=CcNal2L9Me" data-secret="CcNal2L9Me" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/brds-blockset-unveils-its-white-label-cryptocurrency-wallet-for-banks-and-other-enterprise-clients/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151531</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon’s new Echo Buds are a nice upgrade</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/amazons-new-echo-buds-are-a-nice-upgrade/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/amazons-new-echo-buds-are-a-nice-upgrade/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earbuds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[echo buds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wireless earbuds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2150637</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s hard to recall a consumer electronics category that matured quite as quickly as the fully wireless earbuds. Things went from a handful of plucky startups to virtually every hardware manufacturer over the course of a year or two. When Amazon entered the category, it did so in an already arguably overcrowded field. The first [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It’s hard to recall a consumer electronics category that matured quite as quickly as the fully wireless earbuds. Things went from a handful of plucky startups to virtually every hardware manufacturer over the course of a year or two. When Amazon entered the category, it did so in an already arguably overcrowded field.</p>
<p>The first question you have to answer when you’re late to the party is what you’re bringing to the table. Ultimately, the original Echo Buds didn’t have a particularly compelling answer to the question in a world where you can pick up a pair of Ankers for $40. There were a smattering of other issues, as well, that ultimately ended in a pretty lukewarm write-up from me.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EfreBqeYdx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amazons-alexa-earbuds-return-with-a-smaller-design-and-wireless-charging/">Amazon’s Alexa earbuds return with a smaller design and wireless charging</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon’s Alexa earbuds return with a smaller design and wireless charging&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amazons-alexa-earbuds-return-with-a-smaller-design-and-wireless-charging/embed/#?secret=EfreBqeYdx" data-secret="EfreBqeYdx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>A little over a year later, the Buds are back. And to its credit, Amazon has both addressed some of the concerns with the original and offered a pretty solid upgrade over the original models. What’s more, the company added some features that other companies have saved for Pro models, while keeping the price at a reasonable $129.</p>
<p>I’ve been using the Echo Buds as my go-to headphones for several days now and can say, overall, I’ve enjoyed the experience. The product inhabits a kind of middle ground &#8212; I would still recommend a number of other products in the “Price Is No Object” category, and the Buds are not cheap enough to qualify for the low end.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2149819" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2149819" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2149819" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9136.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9136.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9136.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9136.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9136.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9136.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9136.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9136.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9136.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2149819" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>The new Echo Buds occupy a similar price point as Samsung Galaxy Buds Plus &#8212; and in a number of ways compare favorably. Most notable is the inclusion of active noise canceling, which has thus far mostly been the domain of more premium models. Amazon’s latest don’t offer the best ANC &#8212; nor really the best of anything &#8212; but they do form a well-rounded offering for the price point.</p>
<p>As Amazon has experienced with Alexa, the company’s at a disadvantage when competing directly with the likes of Apple, Google and Samsung, which can build devices that tie directly into their handsets. Amazon’s attempts at creating its own handsets have thus far failed, so the company has been forced to find another way to differentiate itself.</p>
<p>That has largely meant Alexa &#8212; and frankly, at the end of the day, the Echo Buds are really another way for the company to serve up its smart assistant. Built-in Alexa is mostly a selling point if you’re already invested in that ecosystem. I tend to prefer Assistant &#8212; especially given all of the other Google software offerings it integrates with, but for many intents and purposes, the personal assistants are often interchangeable.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2149814" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2149814" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2149814" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9127.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9127.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9127.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9127.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9127.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9127.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9127.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9127.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9127.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2149814" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>The new Buds are a fair bit smaller than their predecessors &#8212; but they’re not small exactly. They’re still a bit on the bulky side, and while they stayed put when using them indoors, I found they came loose a few times on a five-mile walk I did over the weekend. In that case, you’ll probably want to opt for the silicone cover, which sports small wings to better keep them in place. Probably the best option as well, if you’re planning to exercise with them in.</p>
<p>A weird design oversight here, however: I found the charging case doesn’t close all the way when the covers are on. The case doesn’t fully snap shut, and I learned the hard way last night that charging can be a bit tricky (in fact, I just got a “battery below 10%” warning in the right ear, while the left if currently in the high 90s. If you do end up using the wings, it’s best to pull them off after your workout &#8212; they’re also a bit on the snug side for too much extended use.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SXOY5bSBpo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amazons-latest-echo-buds-are-a-shameless-apple-knock-off/">Amazon&#8217;s latest Echo Buds are a shameless Apple knockoff</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon&#8217;s latest Echo Buds are a shameless Apple knockoff&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amazons-latest-echo-buds-are-a-shameless-apple-knock-off/embed/#?secret=SXOY5bSBpo" data-secret="SXOY5bSBpo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As Matt recently noted, the case is strongly…inspired by Apple. The differences are more pronounced when the two are next to one another, but the similarity is pretty undeniable:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2149818" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2149818" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2149818" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9135.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9135.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9135.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9135.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9135.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9135.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9135.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9135.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9135.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2149818" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>The case is longer and a little cheaper to the touch. Though the different shape does have the added bonus of being able to sit upright. For this reason, the charging port (USB-C) is on the rear of the case, rather than the bottom. There’s also a wireless charging case option, though that’s going to run you an added $20 &#8212; but probably worth it if you’ve got a Qi charger handy. There&#8217;s an Amazon arrow logo on the case (the company can’t help itself with the branding), but it’s subtle and located on the bottom. You’ll also find a light arrow on one of the earbuds.</p>
<p>The pair Amazon sent are “glacier white,” which is really more of a light gray. Again, it’s that much more pronounced when compared to the AirPods. Perhaps it’s a subtle way to further distinguish the design from Apple’s? Who knows.</p>
<p>Pairing is fairly easy. It’s not quite like using AirPods on an iPhone or Galaxy Buds on a Samsung, but it’s a couple of quick taps in the Alexa app. The company made the app the focal point of the Echo Buds for good reason. It serves as ground zero for everything you do on all of your Alexa-enabled devices. At a certain point, however, it may be time to consider breaking the app up a bit. It’s a bit of a double-edged sword &#8212; nobody needs more apps, but the thing is extremely noisy at this point.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2149816" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2149816" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2149816" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9129.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9129.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9129.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9129.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9129.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9129.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9129.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9129.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9129.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2149816" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>The upshot is that when the Buds are opened and paired, it surfaces the devices to the front. Tapping in lets you toggle between ANC and Pass Through modes (to my annoyance, I found that it would often default to the mode I wasn’t using when I put the Buds on for the first time in a while), turn the mic on and off and start Workout mode, which is opt-in. For people looking for more consistent workout tracking, an always-on wearable like a band or watch is a better choice.</p>
<p>The sound is a nice upgrade over the previous models. As with noise canceling, you can get better audio on more expensive systems, but for where this sits on the price spectrum, you’re getting solid sound for music, podcasting or calls. By default, it leans too heavily on bass for my preferences, but a few taps will take you to some equalizer sliders, where you can futz around with that.</p>
<p>The Bluetooth connection is pretty solid. I found I was able to walk around my apartment while leaving the iPhone in one place &#8212; a test failed by a number of the earbuds I’ve tested. I did, however, encounter some sync issues from time to time between the left and right bud when I was walking outside for long distances, creating an echoing effect. They can also send a sharp bit of feedback when held next to one another, owing to the fact that they don’t always instantly switch off when pulled out of the ear.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2149815" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2149815" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2149815" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9128.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9128.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9128.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9128.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9128.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9128.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9128.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9128.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9128.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2149815" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>The stated battery is up to five hours on the Buds (6.5 with ANC off), and 15 total hours with the case. Compare that to the listed 4.5 and five hours on the AirPods and AirPods Pro and 24 hours with case. I certainly found I was able to get through a full day of use by dipping into the case once or twice.</p>
<p>The new Echo Buds present on upgrade over their predecessors on just about every level, making for a solid pair of mid-price earbuds. They don’t really address the &#8220;why&#8221; that their predecessor failed to. For Amazon, it’s about getting Alexa on more products. For consumers, the answer isn’t quite so easy.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lQYv45bHCx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/29/amazon-echo-buds-review/">Amazon Echo Buds review</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon Echo Buds review&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/29/amazon-echo-buds-review/embed/#?secret=lQYv45bHCx" data-secret="lQYv45bHCx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WScg4bzGr1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/5-consumer-hardware-vcs-share-their-2021-investment-strategies/">5 consumer hardware VCs share their 2021 investment strategies</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 consumer hardware VCs share their 2021 investment strategies&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/5-consumer-hardware-vcs-share-their-2021-investment-strategies/embed/#?secret=WScg4bzGr1" data-secret="WScg4bzGr1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/amazons-new-echo-buds-are-a-nice-upgrade/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2150637</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Upsie’s direct-to-consumer swing at the warranty space nets $18.2M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/upsies-direct-to-consumer-swing-at-the-warranty-space-nets-18-2m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/upsies-direct-to-consumer-swing-at-the-warranty-space-nets-18-2m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Allstate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlanta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backstage capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Distance learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Georgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kapor Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[large]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matchstick Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Minnesota]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[puneet agarwal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silicon valley bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[squaretrade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[st. paul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Target]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[True Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upsie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warranty]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151348</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Upsie, a consumer warranty startup, has raised $18.2 million in a Series A round led by True Ventures.  The financing brings the total raised for the St. Paul, Minnesota-based startup to $25 million since its 2015 inception. A large group of investors participated in the round, including Concrete Rose VC, Avanta Ventures, Kapor Capital, Samsung [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://upsie.com">Upsie</a>, a consumer warranty startup, has raised $18.2 million in a Series A round led by True Ventures. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The financing brings the total raised for the St. Paul, Minnesota-based startup to $25 million since its 2015 inception.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A large group of investors participated in the round, including Concrete Rose VC, Avanta Ventures, Kapor Capital, Samsung Next, Massive, Backstage Capital, Awesome People Ventures, Draft Ventures, Matchstick Ventures, M25, Silicon Valley Bank and Uncommon VC, among others. A number of angels also put money in the round. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Clarence Bethea (pictured below) founded Upsie after realizing the significant markup that retailers were placing on warranties.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">His goal was to focus not on the retailer, but rather the end user and making the process more transparent, more affordable and simpler. For example, Upsie claims that it saves its customers anywhere from 50% to 90% compared to competitor warranty plans. Most other companies in the space, such as SquareTrade, offer warranties at the point of sale via retailers.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2151362" style="width: 293px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2151362" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2151362" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/PD5_1834-e1620852150189.jpg?w=200" alt="" width="283" height="424" /><p id="caption-attachment-2151362" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Upsie</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;ve walked into a Best Buy or a Target, and when you&#8217;re checking out somebody at the register is offering you a warranty. But what most customers don&#8217;t know is that you&#8217;re paying as much as 900% more for that warranty than you should,” Bethea said. “There&#8217;s no transparency at the register and you never get to ask what&#8217;s covered and what&#8217;s not covered, or what should you do if you need to make a claim.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just like many other companies, Upsie saw a bump in business last year thanks to the COVID-pandemic and resulting increase in consumer electronics sales (17%, according to the NPD Group Retail Tracking Service). In particular, there was a </span><a href="https://www.gizmochina.com/2020/12/25/shortages-laptops-pc-high-demand-last-till-2022/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">spike in demand</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for laptops, desktops and tablets for distance learning and remote work. As a result, Upsie’s revenue surged by 2.5x over the past 12 months, although Bethea declined to reveal hard revenue figures.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“With people working from home, devices were no longer a luxury but a necessity,” he told TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rather than at the point of sale, Upsie gives consumers an opportunity to purchase a warranty for a product via its website or mobile app after the transaction has taken place. The company offers protection for thousands of devices &#8212; from smartphones to appliances to gaming consoles to lawn and garden tools &#8212; or about 60% of the warranty market, according to Bethea.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Consumers have up to 120 days to purchase smartphone protection, 11 months to purchase appliance, TV and fitness equipment protection and up to 60 days for other consumer electronics. All warranty information, including a copy of the product receipt, is stored and accessible on demand. Upsie says it also aims to offer same-day repairs on many devices. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The process, according to Bethea, is straightforward. Consumers need only upload an image of their receipt and provide purchase price and serial/IMEA numbers. When they need to file a claim, it’s a matter of pressing a button. And to make the process even easier, it will </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">give consumers the ability to say, take their items directly to the Apple store for repair, and then get reimbursed afterwards by Upsie.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We want more people to be able to protect what they buy with their hard-earned money,” Bethea said. “Removing the worry around paying out of pocket to repair, say, your kid’s laptop is huge for families who have had to go with remote learning when the system doesn’t make this easy for everyone.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Upsie plans to use its new capital to increase customer awareness and continue building out its warranty product offerings and verticals, as well as to double its current headcount of 15.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We want to continue to grow our presence online through digital channels such as Facebook and Google, for one thing,” Bethea told TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Puneet Agarwal, partner at True Ventures, says his firm doubled down on its investment in Upsie after witnessing its solid growth over the years. (True Ventures led the startup’s $5 million seed round in April of 2019.)</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KHN4mem1Xu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/28/upsie-nabs-5m-to-build-a-direct-to-consumer-warranty-service/">Upsie nabs $5M to build a direct-to-consumer warranty service</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Upsie nabs $5M to build a direct-to-consumer warranty service&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/28/upsie-nabs-5m-to-build-a-direct-to-consumer-warranty-service/embed/#?secret=KHN4mem1Xu" data-secret="KHN4mem1Xu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">True Ventures was initially attracted to the sheer size of the warranty industry (estimated at $100 billion globally) and “how broken it was from the consumer experience perspective.” The firm also viewed Bethea as a “very special entrepreneur” who “exudes authenticity,” which must be refreshing to VCs who get inundated with pitches.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We love to invest in old, staid industries where companies can disrupt from a business model and product perspective,” Agarwal said. “Upsie has done that in a big way.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He went on to describe Bethea’s move to go direct to consumer in the warranty space as “bold.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Upsie is the only one doing that, and it’s the biggest swing to take in this type of industry,” Agarwal said. “We believe he’s cracked the code and that’s why we doubled down.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bethea’s background is not the same as a “typical” startup founder, which also was viewed as an advantage by True Ventures.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“He came from the streets of Atlanta, Georgia, and had to overcome so much in his life,” Agarwal told TechCrunch. “Clarence is the type of person that when we started True, we wanted to fund. We admire his perseverance and grit to come to this point.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YrfpGCx5T1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/fintech-startups-set-vc-records-as-the-2021-fundraising-market-continues-to-impress/">Fintech startups set VC records as the 2021 fundraising market continues to impress</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fintech startups set VC records as the 2021 fundraising market continues to impress&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/fintech-startups-set-vc-records-as-the-2021-fundraising-market-continues-to-impress/embed/#?secret=YrfpGCx5T1" data-secret="YrfpGCx5T1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/upsies-direct-to-consumer-swing-at-the-warranty-space-nets-18-2m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151348</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ford is bringing significant wireless software updates to its vehicles</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/ford-is-bringing-significant-wireless-software-updates-to-its-vehicles/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/ford-is-bringing-significant-wireless-software-updates-to-its-vehicles/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 12:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alexa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazon alexa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford Motor Company]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151336</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Internet of Things just got bigger. Four years after Ford Motor Company introduced an integration with Amazon’s suite of smart home devices, the automaker is beefing up its in-vehicle software offerings with built-in Alexa voice assistant and a wireless software update ecosystem. Ford&#8217;s over-the-air software updates, which it has branded Power-Up, will have the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Internet of Things just got bigger. Four years after Ford Motor Company introduced an integration with Amazon’s suite of smart home devices, the automaker is beefing up its in-vehicle software offerings with built-in Alexa voice assistant and a wireless software update ecosystem.</p>
<p>Ford&#8217;s over-the-air software updates, which it has branded Power-Up, will have the capability of updating &#8220;virtually all&#8221; of the computer modules in new Ford vehicles, not just the ones that focus on infotainment, the company said in a statement Thursday. Ford estimates that Power-Up will be able to update more than 110 computer modules on higher-end models. The automaker aims to manufacture 33 million vehicles equipped with this service and Alexa by 2028.</p>
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter">
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter__right" data-qa="message_content">
<div class="c-message_kit__blocks c-message_kit__blocks--rich_text">
<div class="c-message__message_blocks c-message__message_blocks--rich_text">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer" data-qa="block-kit-renderer">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper--first">
<div class="p-rich_text_block" dir="auto">
<div class="p-rich_text_section">Ford is clearly hoping shareholders and customers see the integration as a sign that the company can be a tech-forward automaker. One company executive in a media briefing Tuesday even referred to Ford as a “technology company.&#8221;</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>“We believe that data is the new oil, since it&#8217;s essential to our electric future and enables us to have an always-on relationship with our customer,” Alex Purdy, head of Ford’s business operations for enterprise connectivity, said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That &#8216;data is the new oil&#8217; line is nothing new. Former Intel CEO Brian Krzanich made that very <a href="https://newsroom.intel.com/editorials/krzanich-the-future-of-automated-driving/#gs.0oa5q8">declaration back in 2016</a>. New or not, data is seen as an increasingly valuable resource to automakers.</p>
<p>Purdy said the new software may reduce the need for repair trips and free up dealers to focus on more profitable services, like hardware repairs and maintenance. Many of the software updates will require little to no action from the driver, and they can schedule those updates that require a system reboot.</p>
<p>Using the built-in Alexa assistant, drivers will be able to use voice control to start or stop their engine, lock or unlock doors, defrost their windows, make a call or play music. Customers who have Alexa smart home devices will be able to connect the two systems so that they can, for example, turn on the lights in their home from their driveways. Ford aims to build Alexa software into 700,000 vehicles across the U.S. and Canada this year, though the company did not discuss rollouts in other countries.</p>
<p>Gone are the days of the customer survey – the new software ecosystem will give Ford data on how vehicle owners use their cars. “We can double down on the features people love, get rid of the ones people don’t,” Purdy said. Ford is giving all drivers complimentary access to Alexa for three years, suggesting that the automaker will likely receive mountains of very valuable information on the behavior of its customers from its use.</p>
<p>Ford and Amazon will work together on new features and commercial services for the next six years. It will be delivered via a Power-Up software update this fall beginning with F-150, Mach-E, Bronco, Edge, and Super Duty customers. The company will “work its way through” the remaining models until it’s available in Ford’s entire fleet of new vehicles, though Purdy acknowledged it will take many years to reach that goal.</p>
<p>The Power-Up system will also deliver BlueCruise, Ford’s Level 2 hands-free highway driving technology, though customers must purchase this upgrade. Drivers will be able to activate the technology on prequalified sections of divided highway. In the future Ford said it hopes to add more highway sections, lane change assist, and predictive speed assist that will adjust speed for road curves and other driving situations, similar to Tesla&#8217;s Autopilot.</p>
<p>Ford in February also announced a separate <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/ford-vehicles-will-be-powered-by-googles-android-operating-system/">six year partnership with Google</a> to bring Android apps and services to drivers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/ford-is-bringing-significant-wireless-software-updates-to-its-vehicles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151336</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
