<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 18:04:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Postscript raises $35M to give Shopify stores SMS superpowers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/postscript-raises-35m-to-give-shopify-stores-sms-superpowers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/postscript-raises-35m-to-give-shopify-stores-sms-superpowers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 18:04:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postscript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2120446</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Postscript helps Shopify stores stay in touch with customers via SMS, with a focus on keeping everything opt-in, legally compliant, and spam free. The company raised $4.5M back at the end of 2019; this morning it&#8217;s announcing it has raised a $35M Series B. The company has grown pretty rapidly over the last year. When [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.postscript.io">Postscript</a> helps Shopify stores stay in touch with customers via SMS, with a focus on keeping everything opt-in, legally compliant, and spam free. The company raised $4.5M back at the end of 2019; this morning it&#8217;s announcing it has raised a $35M Series B.</p>
<p>The company has grown pretty rapidly over the last year. When we last checked in with them<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/03/postscript-raises-4-5m-to-help-shopify-shops-stay-connected-with-customers-over-sms/"> in December of 2019</a>, they had 14 employees and around 530 customers; today, they&#8217;re at 61 employees with over 3,500 customers.</p>
<p>Their vision for the product has grown a bit over the last year as well. Initially envisioned as more of a one-way broadcasting for Shopify stores to market to existing customers (&#8220;Look! We&#8217;ve got new shoes in stock!&#8221;), they&#8217;re now working on expanding into more two-way interactions, enabling customers to do things like re-orders, subscription management, and reviews through SMS.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As before, Postscript is focused exclusively on compatibility with Shopify stores. Behind the scenes they&#8217;ve been building out an API to allow deeper integrations into other Shopify plugins — but still, they&#8217;re all about Shopify merchants for now.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re still focused exclusively there,&#8221; Postscript co-founder Alex Beller tells me. &#8220;We think it&#8217;s kind of our secret sauce, honestly, because we go so deep with the data and the ecosystem. There&#8217;s just a lot of tiny accumulating advantages there. It&#8217;s also the platform that&#8217;s growing the fastest in e-commerce, so it&#8217;s been a good place to be.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LkNSANYM26"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/03/postscript-raises-4-5m-to-help-shopify-shops-stay-connected-with-customers-over-sms/">Postscript raises $4.5M to help Shopify shops stay connected with customers over SMS</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Postscript raises $4.5M to help Shopify shops stay connected with customers over SMS&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/03/postscript-raises-4-5m-to-help-shopify-shops-stay-connected-with-customers-over-sms/embed/#?secret=LkNSANYM26" data-secret="LkNSANYM26" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>While the company&#8217;s December 2019 funding was a seed round, co-founder Adam Turner tells me that between the size of the round and the revenue the company is seeing, they&#8217;ve skipped the A round and have structured this one as a Series B.</p>
<p>The round was led by Greylock, and backed by YC, 1984vc, Ali Capital, Elephant VC, and Larry Fitzgerald. As part of the deal, Greylock partners Sarah Guo and Mike Duboe will be joining Postscript&#8217;s board.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/postscript-raises-35m-to-give-shopify-stores-sms-superpowers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2120446</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GSV Ventures doubles assets managed with new fund focused on global edtech</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/gsv-ventures-doubles-assets-managed-with-new-fund-focused-on-global-edtech/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/gsv-ventures-doubles-assets-managed-with-new-fund-focused-on-global-edtech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 17:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GSV Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Include]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2120422</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[GSV Ventures, co-founded by Deborah Quazzo and Michael Cohn, has raised $180 million in its second fund, exclusively focused on backing edtech startups across the globe. The startup now manages $277 million in cumulative assets, inclusive of its debut fund that was closed in 2016. The new fund will let GSV invest in 13 core [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><!-- Output copied to clipboard! --></p>
<p>GSV Ventures, co-founded by Deborah Quazzo and Michael Cohn, has raised $180 million in its second fund, exclusively focused on backing edtech startups across the globe. The startup now manages $277 million in cumulative assets, inclusive of its debut fund that was closed in 2016.</p>
<p>The new fund will let GSV invest in 13 core holdings, with an average check size of $15 million. The firm reserves up to $20 million per position for follow-on capital. It will invest in seed, Series A and late growth-stage opportunities.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While edtech was certainly spotlighted by the pandemic’s impact on the adoption of remote education, GSV Ventures is a case study in what happens when you invest in a category before it has generalist eyes on it. The first fund had three of its largest positions in Coursera, which <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/coursera-considers-going-public-2021-161155214.html">is planning to go public</a> this year; Course Hero, which was valued at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/26/course-hero-a-profitable-edtech-unicorn-raises-rare-cash/">$1.1 billion last year</a>; and ClassDojo, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/classdojos-second-act-comes-with-first-profits/">which finally hit profitability</a> after spending eight years focusing on customer growth instead of monetization.</p>
<p>The firm was also an early believer in Nearpod, which exited for $650 million in an all-cash deal <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/miami-edtech-startup-nearpod-acquired-by-renaissance/">in February 2021. </a>Quazzo, who contributed her angel portfolio into the fund, says that this gives the firm 10 exits under its belt to date.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vkDQFmWqZf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/edtech-valuations-arent-skyrocketing-but-investors-see-more-exit-opportunities/">Edtech valuations aren&#8217;t skyrocketing, but investors see more exit opportunities</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Edtech valuations aren&#8217;t skyrocketing, but investors see more exit opportunities&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/edtech-valuations-arent-skyrocketing-but-investors-see-more-exit-opportunities/embed/#?secret=vkDQFmWqZf" data-secret="vkDQFmWqZf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>GSV Ventures began around the same time as other exclusively-edtech funds launched, such as Reach Capital, Learn Capital and Owl Ventures. These funds have all closed new capital in the wake of the coronavirus, with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/reach-capital-fund-3/">$165 million</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/31/union-square-ventures-and-learn-capital-file-paperwork-indicating-new-funds/">$132 million</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/01/owl-ventures-new-pair-of-funds-gives-edtech-a-585-million-boost/">$585 million</a>, respectively.</p>
<p>The biggest change between GSV Ventures’ debut fund and Fund II is the opportunity that Quazzo seeds internationally. Fund 1 only had one investment outside the United States, and Fund II already has holdings in Capetown, Croatia, Jordan, as well as, Quazzo confirms, six incoming investments split between Indonesia and India.</p>
<p>“There are very important businesses being built in these markets with missions to democratize and improve the delivery of learning at scale to all people,” Quazzo tells TechCrunch. To date, GSV Ventures’ portfolio has 37% female founders and 43% people of color.</p>
<p>While there was a four-year gap between Fund I and Fund II, GSV’s ability to back edtech startups with an ambitious trajectory hasn’t gone unnoticed. Its third fund, already mid-raise, will have its first close in the next few months.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="n0TnMka1KO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/12-investors-say-lifelong-learning-is-taking-edtech-mainstream/">13 investors say lifelong learning is taking edtech mainstream</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;13 investors say lifelong learning is taking edtech mainstream&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/12-investors-say-lifelong-learning-is-taking-edtech-mainstream/embed/#?secret=n0TnMka1KO" data-secret="n0TnMka1KO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/gsv-ventures-doubles-assets-managed-with-new-fund-focused-on-global-edtech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2120422</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>From the ashes of nearly a billion dollars, Ample resurrects Better Place&#8217;s battery swapping business model</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/from-the-ashes-of-nearly-a-billion-dollars-ample-resurrects-better-places-battery-swapping-business-model/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/from-the-ashes-of-nearly-a-billion-dollars-ample-resurrects-better-places-battery-swapping-business-model/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 17:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ample]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[better place]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charging station]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inductive charging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lithium-ion battery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nissan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nissan leaf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[One Laptop Per Child]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[range anxiety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renault]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repsol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shai Agassi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shell Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2120330</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A little over thirteen years ago, Shai Agassi, a promising software executive who was in line to succeed the chief executive at SAP, then one of the world&#8217;s mightiest software companies, left the company he&#8217;d devoted the bulk of his professional career to and started a business called Better Place. That startup promised to revolutionize [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A little over thirteen years ago, Shai Agassi, a promising software executive who was in line to succeed the chief executive at SAP, then one of the world&#8217;s mightiest software companies, left the company he&#8217;d devoted the bulk of his professional career to and started a business called Better Place.</p>
<p>That startup promised to revolutionize the nascent electric vehicle market and make range anxiety a thing of the past. The company&#8217;s pitch? A network of automated battery swapping stations that would replace spent batteries with freshly charged ones.</p>
<p>Agassi&#8217;s company would go on to raise nearly $1 billion (back when that was considered a large sum of money) from some of the world&#8217;s top venture capital and growth equity firms. By 2013 it would be bankrupt and one of the many casualties of the first wave of cleantech investing.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Now serial entrepreneurs John de Souza and Khaled Hassounah are reviving the battery swapping business model with a startup called<a href="https://ample.com/"> Ample</a> and an approach that they say solves some of the problems that Better Place could never address at a time when the adoption of electric vehicles is creating a far larger addressable market.</p>
<p>In 2013, there were 220,000 vehicles on roads, <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/270603/worldwide-number-of-hybrid-and-electric-vehicles-since-2009/">according to data from Statista</a>, a number which has grown to 4.8 million by 2019.</p>
<p>Ample has actually raised approximately $70 million from investors including Shell Ventures, the Spanish energy company Repsol, and the venture capital arm of the $10 billion money manager, Moore Capital Management. That includes a $34 million investment <a href="https://www.greentechmedia.com/articles/read/ample-a-better-better-place">first reported back in 2018</a>, and a later round from investors including Japan&#8217;s energy and metals company, Eneos Holdings that closed recently.</p>
<p>&#8220;We had a lot of people that either said, I somehow was involved in that and was suffering from PTSD,&#8221; said de Souza, of the similarities between his business and Better Place. &#8220;The people who weren&#8217;t involved read up about it and then ran away.&#8221;</p>
<p>For Ample, the difference is in the modularization of the battery pack and how that changes the relationship with the automakers that would use the technology.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;The approach we’ve taken… is to modularize the battery and then we have an adapter plate that is the structural element of the battery that has the same shape of the battery, same bolt pattern and same software interface. Even though we provide the same battery system.. .it’s same as replacing the tire,&#8221; said Hassounah, Ample&#8217;s co-founder and chief executive. &#8220;Effectively we’re giving them the plate. We don’t modify the car whatsoever. You either put a fixed battery system or an Ample battery plate. We’re able to work with the OEMS where you can make the battery swappable for the use cases where this makes a lot of sense. Without really changing the same vehicle.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/5hcCbg1Nf-c?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Ample&#8217;s currently working with five different OEMs and has validated its approach to battery swapping with nine different car models. One of those OEMs also brings back memories of Better Place.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s clear that the company has a deal with Nissan for the Leaf thanks to the other partnership that Ample has announced with Uber. Ample&#8217;s founders declined to comment on any OEM relationships.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s clear that Ample is working with Nissan because Nissan is the company that<a href="https://www.uber.com/en-GB/newsroom/nissan-and-uber-advance-zero-emission-mobility/"> inked a deal with Uber earlier this year</a> on zero-emission mobility. And Uber is the first company to use Ample&#8217;s robotic charging stations at a few locations in the Bay Area, the company said. This work with Nissan echoes Better Place&#8217;s one partnership with Renault, another arm of the automaker, which proved to be the biggest deal for the older, doomed, battery swapping startup.</p>
<p>Ample says it only takes weeks to set up one of its charging pods at a facility and that the company&#8217;s charging drivers on energy delivered per mile. &#8220;We achieve economics that are 10% to 20% cheaper than gas. We are profitable on day one,&#8221; said Hassounah.</p>
<p>Uber is the first step. Ample is focused on fleets first and is in talks with multiple, undisclosed municipalities to get their cars added to the system. So far, Ample has done thousands of swaps, according to Hassounah with just Uber drivers alone.</p>
<p>The cars can also be charged at traditional charging facilities, Hassounah said, and the company&#8217;s billing system knows the split between the amount of energy it delivers versus another charging outlet, Hassounah said.</p>
<p>&#8220;So far, in the use cases that we have, for ride sharing it&#8217;s individual drivers who pay,&#8221; said de Souza. With the five fleets that Ample expects to deploy with later this year the company expects to have the fleet managers and owners pay for. charging.</p>
<p>Some of the inspiration for Ample came from Hassounah&#8217;s earlier experience working at One laptop per child, where he was forced to rethink assumptions about how the laptops would be used, the founder said.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Initially i worked on the keyboard display and then quickly realized the challenge was in the field and developed a framework for creating infrastructure,&#8221; Hassounah said.</span></p>
<p>The problem was the initial design of the system did not take into account lack of access to power for laptops at children&#8217;s homes. So the initiative developed a charging unit for swapping batteries. Children would use their laptops over the course of the day and take them home, and when they needed a fresh charge, they would swap out the batteries.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are fleets that need this exact solution,&#8221; said de Souza. But there are advantages for individual car owners as well, he said. &#8220;T<span style="font-weight: 400;">he experience for the owner of a vehicle is after time the battery degrades. With ours as we put new batteries in the car can go further and further over time.&#8221; </span></p>
<p>Right now, OEMs are sending cars without batteries and Ample is just installing their charging system, said Hassounah, but as the number of vehicles using the system rises above 1,000, the company expects to send their plates to manufacturers, who can then have Ample install their own packs.</p>
<p>Currently, Ample only supports level one and level two charging, but won&#8217;t offer fast charging options for the car makers it works with &#8212; likely because that option would cannibalize the company&#8217;s business and potentially obviate the need for its swapping technology.</p>
<p>At issue is the time it takes to charge a car. Fast chargers still take between 20 and 30 minutes to charge up, but advances in technologies should drive that figure down. Even if fast charging ultimately becomes a better option, Ample&#8217;s founders say they view their business as an additive step to faster electric vehicle adoption.</p>
<p>&#8220;When you&#8217;re moving 1 billion cars, you need everything&#8230; We have so many cars we need to put on the road,&#8221; Hassounah said. &#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">We think we need all solutions to solve the problem. As you think of fleet applications you need a solution that can match gas in charge and not speed. Fast charging is not available in mass. The challenge will not be can the battery be charged in 5 minutes. The cost of building  charges that can deliver that amount of power is prohibitive.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Looking beyond charging, Ample sees opportunities in the grid power market as well, the two founders said.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Time shift is built into our economics… that’s another way we can help,&#8221; said de Souza. &#8220;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We use that as grid storage… we can do demand charge and now that the federal mandate is there to feed into the grid we can help stabilize the grid by feeding back energy.. We don’t have a lot of stations to make a significant impact. As we scale up this year we will.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p>Currently the company is operating at a storage capacity of tens of megawatts per hour, according to Hassounah.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;We can use the side storage to accelerate the development of swapping stations,&#8221; de Souza said. &#8220;You don’t have to invest an insane amount of money to put them in. We can finance the batteries in multiple ways as well as utilize other sources of financing.&#8221; </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2120427" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2120427" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2120427" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Ample-152-1-2-1.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Ample-152-1-2-1.jpg 5554w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Ample-152-1-2-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Ample-152-1-2-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Ample-152-1-2-1.jpg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Ample-152-1-2-1.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Ample-152-1-2-1.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Ample-152-1-2-1.jpg?resize=2048,1367 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Ample-152-1-2-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2120427" class="wp-caption-text">Ample co-founders John de Souza and Khaled Hassounah. Image Credit: Ample</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/from-the-ashes-of-nearly-a-billion-dollars-ample-resurrects-better-places-battery-swapping-business-model/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2120330</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cables could help soft robots transform into harder structures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/cables-could-help-soft-robots-transform-into-harder-structures/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/cables-could-help-soft-robots-transform-into-harder-structures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 17:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSAIL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIT CSAIL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soft Robotics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2120325</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The sub-category of soft robotics has transformed the way many think about the field. Oft-influenced by natural phenomenon, the technology offers a dramatically different approach than the sort of rigid structures we traditionally think of when we discuss robots. Soft designs offer a number of benefits, including compliance, which has already seen a number of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The sub-category of soft robotics has transformed the way many think about the field. Oft-influenced by natural phenomenon, the technology offers a dramatically different approach than the sort of rigid structures we traditionally think of when we discuss robots.</p>
<p>Soft designs offer a number of benefits, including compliance, which has already seen a number of real-world applications in manufacturing and fulfillment. But like their more rigid cousins, soft robots have their limitations. As such, designers generally choose between one or the other for a given job &#8212; or, best-case scenario, design swappable parts.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ceo7hbP91p"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/21/mit-researchers-develop-a-much-better-way-to-optimize-the-control-of-soft-robots/">MIT researchers develop a much better way to optimize the control of soft robots</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;MIT researchers develop a much better way to optimize the control of soft robots&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/21/mit-researchers-develop-a-much-better-way-to-optimize-the-control-of-soft-robots/embed/#?secret=ceo7hbP91p" data-secret="ceo7hbP91p" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>A team at MIT’s CSAIL lab <a href="https://news.mit.edu/2021/helping-soft-robots-turn-rigid-demand">is exploring a technology</a> that could make choosing less of a trade-off. The project has been in the works since 2017, though it’s still in the somewhat early stages &#8212; still largely the realm of computer simulation, though the details have been outlined in a new paper.</p>
<p>“This is the first step in trying to see if we can get the best of both worlds,” CSAIL post-doc James Bern said in a release.</p>
<p>In the project (or the simulated version, at least), the robot is controlled by a series of cables. Pulling on them in the right combination turns the soft structure into a hard one. The team uses the analogy of a series of muscles controlling the human arm &#8212; if the right ones are flexed, you can effectively lock a position in place.</p>
<p>The team will present their findings at a conference next month. For the time being, they’re currently working on a prototype to showcase how it operates in a real-world setting. Combining the two fields could go a ways toward building safer collaborative robots for interacting with human workers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AYbtGfw6LT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/13/mit-showcases-soft-robotic-sensors-made-from-flexible-off-the-shelf-materials/">MIT showcases soft robotic sensors made from flexible, off-the-shelf materials</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;MIT showcases soft robotic sensors made from flexible, off-the-shelf materials&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/13/mit-showcases-soft-robotic-sensors-made-from-flexible-off-the-shelf-materials/embed/#?secret=AYbtGfw6LT" data-secret="AYbtGfw6LT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/cables-could-help-soft-robots-transform-into-harder-structures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2120325</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>EV rivals Tesla, Rivian unite to target direct sales legislation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/ev-rivals-tesla-rivian-unite-to-target-direct-sales-legislation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/ev-rivals-tesla-rivian-unite-to-target-direct-sales-legislation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 16:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lordstown Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucid Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rivian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2120367</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tesla, Rivian, Lordstown Motors and Lucid Motors &#8212; potential rivals in the burgeoning EV market &#8212; are working together to pass laws that would allow direct sales in at least eight states with another batch of proposed legislation likely being introduced this year. Passage of such legislation would clear the way for EV giants like [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tesla, Rivian, Lordstown Motors and Lucid Motors &#8212; potential rivals in the burgeoning EV market &#8212; are working together to pass laws that would allow direct sales in at least eight states with another batch of proposed legislation likely being introduced this year.</p>
<p>Passage of such legislation would clear the way for EV giants like Tesla, along with newcomers Lucid and Rivian, which have yet to bring a vehicle to market, to sell directly to consumers. However, Tesla&#8217;s cooperation could also cost the company its monopoly on direct sales in some states.</p>
<p>Tesla and a growing number of new EV companies have a different business model than legacy automakers like GM, Ford and Stellantis. Tesla sells vehicles through their own branded stores &#8212; similar to how Apple sells its products &#8212; and do not have franchised dealerships. The direct sales model has attracted the ire of auto dealers, who benefit from long-established rules in all 50 states that prevent manufacturers<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> with existing franchisees from opening their own dealerships to compete with them. Tesla and other allies argue that because they don&#8217;t have franchise dealers, they should be allowed to sell directly to consumers.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We support our other EV-only manufacturers and their desires to sell direct-to-consumers, to invest, to create jobs and to do that unfettered as we are allowed,&#8221; Thad Kurowski, senior policy manager at Tesla, said while testifying in the state of Washington during the House&#8217;s Consumer Protection and Business Committee. Washington is one of many states where such legislation is being considered. Tesla has six retail locations in the state.</p>
<p>Similar legislation is being considered in Connecticut, Nebraska, Georgia, New York, Wisconsin, Pennsylvania and Nevada. Some of these states ban all EV manufacturers from directly selling to customers; some only permit Tesla, at the exclusion of other companies, but cap the number of retail stores it can open.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a rare moment of cooperation for EV manufacturers, companies that must contend not only with each other but with legacy automakers for market share. Relations between the companies have not always been so copacetic: Tesla last July <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/tesla-takes-aim-at-rivian-in-lawsuit-alleging-trade-secret-theft-poaching-talent/">filed a lawsuit against Rivian</a> alleging theft of trade secrets and talent poaching. Rivian responded that two of the three claims in the case were nothing more than an attempt to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/rivian-fires-back-at-tesla-in-lawsuit/">smear its reputation</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cXUiIOP3Iy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/tesla-takes-aim-at-rivian-in-lawsuit-alleging-trade-secret-theft-poaching-talent/">Tesla takes aim at Rivian in lawsuit alleging trade secret theft, poaching talent</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tesla takes aim at Rivian in lawsuit alleging trade secret theft, poaching talent&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/tesla-takes-aim-at-rivian-in-lawsuit-alleging-trade-secret-theft-poaching-talent/embed/#?secret=cXUiIOP3Iy" data-secret="cXUiIOP3Iy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Tesla is a veteran of battles with state legislatures over direct sales. At least a dozen states, including Arizona, Colorado and Utah have reversed bans that prevented Tesla from selling directly to consumers either through new legislation or via the courts.</p>
<p>Michigan, home to major automakers GM and Ford, has been a longtime battleground.</p>
<p>Former Gov. Rick Snyder signed a bill in 2014 that was initiated and backed by the Michigan Automobile Dealers Association, banning Tesla from selling directly to consumers in the state. Two years later, Tesla sued the state of Michigan when it denied Tesla a dealership license. The Michigan Legislature last December considered a bill that would have banned all direct sales except for Tesla, an arrangement that allowed the automaker to deliver cars to customers, so long as the vehicle sale and title transfer didn&#8217;t occur in the state. That special exception for Tesla was removed from the proposed legislation, a move that would have threatened what little progress it had in the state. At the end, though, the legislation died, leaving Tesla&#8217;s arrangement intact.</p>
<p>Lucid is leading the charge in some states where direct sales legislation is being considered, according to Daniel Witt, who worked at Tesla before joining the new EV entrant as a public policy lead. Witt emphasized the bills are the result of efforts from the coalition of EV companies, grassroots lobbying from EV owners and EV enthusiasts and consumer groups. The legislation has also found support from environmental and clean energy groups, which argue that consumer choice and ease of access are key to helping people transition away from internal combustion engine cars.</p>
<p>&#8220;Any situation where the door got closed behind Tesla was not a matter of trying to gain a market advantage so much as it was just a product of the negotiations in a given legislature,&#8221; Witt said. &#8220;By and large, whether it&#8217;s New York, or Washington or Connecticut, we&#8217;re all rowing in the same direction.&#8221;</p>
<p>In a statement to TechCrunch, the Washington State Auto Dealers Association said franchised dealers support the transition toward zero-emission vehicles and want to sell them at their locations. But it said the direct sale bill is a &#8220;battle of Main Street vs. Wall Street.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hsXYV1bGU0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/rivian-fires-back-at-tesla-in-lawsuit/">Rivian fires back at Tesla in lawsuit, accuses automaker of attempting to &#8216;malign its reputation&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Rivian fires back at Tesla in lawsuit, accuses automaker of attempting to &#8216;malign its reputation&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/rivian-fires-back-at-tesla-in-lawsuit/embed/#?secret=hsXYV1bGU0" data-secret="hsXYV1bGU0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;Electric vehicle manufacturers perpetuate [the] myth of the middleman when the reality is that they would bear the same costs if they built their own stores, but would ship their revenue to their billionaire investors out of state after the sale is made instead of reinvesting in the community,&#8221; the group said.</p>
<p>The organization pointed out that Rivian has garnered $500 million in funding from Ford.</p>
<p>&#8220;What would stop Ford from abandoning its dealer network, and shifting the profits dealers generate for the company out of Ford and into greater ownership of Rivian? Or GM from spinning off an EV subsidiary?&#8221; the group said in its statement.</p>
<p>EV manufacturers have a long legislative road ahead of them. Bills generally must clear legislative committees and receive majority votes from both the House and Senate before being sent to the governor&#8217;s desk to be signed into law.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/ev-rivals-tesla-rivian-unite-to-target-direct-sales-legislation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2120367</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Netflix launches &#8216;Fast Laughs,&#8217; a TikTok-like feed of funny videos</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/netflix-launches-fast-laughs-a-tiktok-like-feed-of-funny-videos/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/netflix-launches-fast-laughs-a-tiktok-like-feed-of-funny-videos/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 16:59:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2120370</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Late last year, Netflix began experimenting with a new TikTok-like feed of funny videos inside its mobile app, which it called &#8220;Fast Laughs.&#8221; Today, the company announced the new feature is now rolling out on iOS, allowing users to watch, react, or share the short clips as well as add the show or movie to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Late last year, Netflix began <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/netflixs-latest-experiment-is-a-tiktok-like-feed-of-funny-videos/">experimenting</a> with a new TikTok-like feed of funny videos inside its mobile app, which it called &#8220;Fast Laughs.&#8221; Today, the company <a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/fast-laughs-is-here">announced</a> the new feature is now rolling out on iOS, allowing users to watch, react, or share the short clips as well as add the show or movie to a Netflix watchlist. You can also push the &#8220;Play&#8221; button to start watching the program immediately.</p>
<p>At launch, the feature will include short clips from Netflix&#8217;s comedy catalog, including films like &#8220;Murder Mystery,&#8221; series like &#8220;Big Mouth,&#8221; sitcoms like &#8220;The Crew,&#8221; as well as snippets from stand-up comedians like Kevin Hart and Ali Wong.</p>
<p>Netflix confirmed to TechCrunch the feature will tap into its full catalog, not just its own original programs. However, the company couldn&#8217;t says how many total shows or movies would be featured in the new experience at any given time.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2120394" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2120394" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2120394" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills_SMALLER_N-0-00-27-13.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills_SMALLER_N-0-00-27-13.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills_SMALLER_N-0-00-27-13.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills_SMALLER_N-0-00-27-13.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills_SMALLER_N-0-00-27-13.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills_SMALLER_N-0-00-27-13.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills_SMALLER_N-0-00-27-13.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills_SMALLER_N-0-00-27-13.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills_SMALLER_N-0-00-27-13.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills_SMALLER_N-0-00-27-13.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills_SMALLER_N-0-00-27-13.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills_SMALLER_N-0-00-27-13.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2120394" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Netflix</p></div></p>
<p>The feature, notably, has been given prominent placement in the Netflix app, where it&#8217;s accessible from the bottom navigation menu on its own tab, next to &#8220;Coming Soon.&#8221; This is no small experiment, then &#8212; but rather an indication of how successful the early tests of the &#8220;Fast Laughs&#8221; feature must have been in terms of engaging users and connecting them to Netflix content.</p>
<p>&#8220;Fast Laughs&#8221; is not the first time Netflix has borrowed concepts from social media to help users discover new shows or movies to watch in its app. A few years ago, Netflix <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/19/17255966/netflix-30-second-video-previews-mobile">introduced</a> its own short-form video &#8220;Stories&#8221; feature, called Previews, for example. But times have changed. Now users are drawn to short-form vertical video feeds, like those popularized by TikTok.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2120438" style="width: 393px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2120438" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2120438" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills-Kevin-hart-pink.jpg?w=383" alt="" width="383" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills-Kevin-hart-pink.jpg 1080w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills-Kevin-hart-pink.jpg?resize=84,150 84w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills-Kevin-hart-pink.jpg?resize=169,300 169w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills-Kevin-hart-pink.jpg?resize=768,1365 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills-Kevin-hart-pink.jpg?resize=383,680 383w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills-Kevin-hart-pink.jpg?resize=864,1536 864w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills-Kevin-hart-pink.jpg?resize=28,50 28w" sizes="(max-width: 383px) 100vw, 383px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2120438" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Netflix</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Fast Laughs&#8221; heavily borrows from the TikTok format, as its feed also features full-screen videos that you can swipe through vertically, and places the engagement buttons on the right side of the screen. These buttons let you react to the clip with an &#8220;LOL&#8221; (crying/laughing) emoji or share it via iMessage or other social media apps, like WhatsApp, Instagram, Snapchat or Twitter. You can also start watching the show immediately or save it for later viewing by adding it to &#8220;My List.&#8221;</p>
<p>During tests, &#8220;Fast Laughs&#8221; clips ranged in length anywhere from 15 to 45 seconds. Today, Netflix says there&#8217;s no exact clip length for these video snippets.</p>
<p>Because the clips&#8217; content may not be appropriate for children, the &#8220;Fast Laughs&#8221; tab won&#8217;t appear on Netflix kids&#8217; profiles. In addition, members will be able to filter the content based on their own settings for maturity rating levels.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2120393" style="width: 393px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2120393" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2120393" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills-Share-pink.jpg?w=383" alt="" width="383" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills-Share-pink.jpg 1080w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills-Share-pink.jpg?resize=84,150 84w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills-Share-pink.jpg?resize=169,300 169w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills-Share-pink.jpg?resize=768,1365 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills-Share-pink.jpg?resize=383,680 383w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills-Share-pink.jpg?resize=864,1536 864w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/FAST_LAUGHS_ANIMATIONS_v11_for-stills-Share-pink.jpg?resize=28,50 28w" sizes="(max-width: 383px) 100vw, 383px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2120393" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Netflix</p></div></p>
<p>The company is positioning the feature as a discovery tool.</p>
<p>&#8220;We wanted to give members a fun, fast, and intuitive way to discover our catalog by letting these comedic moments across genres speak for themselves in a mobile-native, full screen experience,&#8221; said Netflix Product Designer <a href="https://www.kimho.design/fastlaughs">Kim Ho</a>, who previously worked on product design at Facebook, Instacart, and Coin. &#8220;We worked hard to cut to just what was necessary in an intentional and minimalist UI design, from the transparent tab bar to ways to react in the moment (&#8216;LOL&#8217;) and plan their next laugh by adding to their list,&#8221; she added.</p>
<p>But though &#8220;Fast Laughs&#8221; is focused on finding new things to watch, the feature could, in fact, help Netflix compete with TikTok in terms of time spent on mobile devices, as it caters to the growing demand for shorter, more &#8220;snackable&#8221; video content.</p>
<p>Netflix says the feature is rolling out now to iOS and will begin testing on Android in the months to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/netflix-launches-fast-laughs-a-tiktok-like-feed-of-funny-videos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2120370</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>After 200% ARR growth in 2020, CourseKey raises $9M to digitize trade schools</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/after-200-arr-growth-in-2020-coursekey-raises-9m-to-digitize-trade-schools/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/after-200-arr-growth-in-2020-coursekey-raises-9m-to-digitize-trade-schools/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 16:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dennis yang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Distance learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san diego]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signalfire]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2120345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When the COVID-19 pandemic hit and forced educational institutions to go virtual, many were scrambling to develop online or blended curriculums. That struggle was particularly challenging for trade schools, many of which were not designed to teach online and were mostly paper-driven.  CourseKey, a San Diego-based trade school management SaaS startup, was in a unique [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When the COVID-19 pandemic hit and forced educational institutions to go virtual, many were scrambling to develop online or blended curriculums.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That struggle was particularly challenging for trade schools, many of which were not designed to teach online and were mostly paper-driven. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://coursekey.com">CourseKey</a>, a San Diego-based trade school management SaaS startup, was in a unique position. Demand surged and its ARR grew by 200% in 2020. And now, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">the company has raised $9 million in a Series B led by SignalFire and with participation from existing backer Builders VC to help it continue its momentum. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Founded in 2015 by</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Luke Sophinos and Fadee Kannah, CourseKey’s B2B platform is designed to work with organizations that teach some of our most essential workers &#8212; from automotive mechanics to electricians to plumbers to nurses, phlebotomists and dental assistants.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2120371" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2120371" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2120371" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/luke-sophinos-faddee-kannah.jpg" alt="CourseKey founders Luke Sophinos (left) and Faddee Kannah (right)" width="1024" height="512" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/luke-sophinos-faddee-kannah.jpg 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/luke-sophinos-faddee-kannah.jpg?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/luke-sophinos-faddee-kannah.jpg?resize=300,150 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/luke-sophinos-faddee-kannah.jpg?resize=768,384 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/luke-sophinos-faddee-kannah.jpg?resize=680,340 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/luke-sophinos-faddee-kannah.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2120371" class="wp-caption-text">CourseKey founders Luke Sophinos (left) and Fadee Kannah (right)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The goal is to help those organizations boost revenue by improving</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> student retention and graduation rates, helping them maintain regulatory compliance and generally streamline processes. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Things really took off last year when the coronavirus hit,” Sophinos said. “So many schools had to adopt a digital arsenal. We saw a massive acceleration trend that was already going to happen. Every industry had been eaten. We just found a space that wasn&#8217;t yet.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CourseKey currently works with over 200 career colleges, including the Paul Mitchell School and the Institute for Business &amp; Technology, among others. Over 100,000 students use its software.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Sophinos and Kannah, founding CourseKey was more than just a business opportunity. Kannah, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">who had fled Iraq as a refugee, saw family members going through trade schools that were lacking technology infrastructure and modern software tools. He architected the CourseKey platform. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sophinos, frustrated by his own college experience, applied for </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Thiel Fellowship &#8211; a program that supports students in company building instead of university attending. However, he recognized that not everyone who doesn’t want to go to traditional college has that option.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“While looking at alternatives, our early team began recognizing a market that we felt no one was paying attention to. It was occupied by our friends and by our family members,” Sophinos said. “It was a space that, for some odd reason, was largely being left out of the education conversation.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2017, CourseKey partnered with a large vocational education provider to build and launch what Sophinos describes as “the world’s first trade school management system.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We focused on automating daily classroom procedures like attendance and grading, enhancing the student experience through communication tools, helping to identify at-risk students, and simplifying compliance,” he said. “We also visualized data for retention purposes.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CourseKey also does things like track skill attainment, run evaluations and exams and integrate third-party tools.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2120365" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Product-Highlight-PR.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2120365" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2120365" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Product-Highlight-PR.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="512" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Product-Highlight-PR.jpg 4001w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Product-Highlight-PR.jpg?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Product-Highlight-PR.jpg?resize=300,150 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Product-Highlight-PR.jpg?resize=768,384 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Product-Highlight-PR.jpg?resize=680,340 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Product-Highlight-PR.jpg?resize=1536,768 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Product-Highlight-PR.jpg?resize=2048,1024 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Product-Highlight-PR.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2120365" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> CourseKey</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup’s goal with its new capital is to scale the platform to serve “every trade school in the country” with the mission of changing the narrative that four-year college is the &#8220;only option.&#8221; It also plans to add new features and capabilities, largely based on customer requests. CourseKey also plans to nearly double its current headcount of just over 50 employees to nearly 100 over the next two years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This is a massive market and massive business opportunity,” Sophinos said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CourseKey has an impressive list of supporters beyond SignalFire and Builders. Steve Altman, former vice chairman and president of Qualcomm, led its $3.5 million seed round which also included participation from Larry Rosenberger, former FICO CEO. Dennis Yang, former CEO of edtech giant Udemy, and Altman now serve on its board.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SignalFire Managing Director Wayne Hu, who also took a seat on the startup’s board with the new round, said his firm recognized that </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">vocational schools and their administrators, instructors, and students “suffer from a lack of purpose-built software.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Student Information Systems and Learning Management Systems are optimized for traditional K-12 schools and university workflow, but vocational schools are stuck relying on pen and paper or trying to shoe-horn in solutions that aren&#8217;t built for them,” Hu wrote in a blog post.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CourseKey, in SignalFire’s view, is reimagining a new education operating system built specifically for experiential, hands-on learning models, which continues to evolve with hybrid/distance learning.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hu also pointed out that since many of the jobs that vocational schools are preparing people for “have life or death consequences,&#8221; they are highly regulated.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Not only does CourseKey improve trade school business KPIs, it serves as insurance against this existential risk,” he added.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/after-200-arr-growth-in-2020-coursekey-raises-9m-to-digitize-trade-schools/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2120345</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>First impressions of AppLovin&#8217;s IPO filing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/first-impressions-of-applovins-ipo-filing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/first-impressions-of-applovins-ipo-filing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 16:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[applovin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[S-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2120294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Could a bet on AppLovin then be viewed as a wager not on its business income growth, but on the strength of consumer app demand?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">AppLovin released <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1751008/000119312521065782/d73804ds1.htm">its S-1 filing</a> yesterday, bringing the Palo Alto-based mobile-app-focused software company a step closer to joining the public markets.</p>
<p>The business results detailed in the document are generally impressive. While some companies going public in recent months have detailed <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/doordash-ipo-pricing/">pandemic-fueled growth to lean against </a>or membership in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/digitaloceans-ipo-filing-shows-a-two-class-cloud-market/">a sector hotter than individual results</a>, AppLovin&#8217;s filing tells the story of a rapidly growing company that has managed to scale adjusted profit as it has grown.</p>
<p>And now, with annual revenue north of $1 billion, AppLovin is also a very large company, meaning that its IPO will be widely watched.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a>, or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>So this morning we&#8217;re rifling through its IPO filing and yanking out what matters as we add one more name to our IPO lists.</p>
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995214 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>The Exchange has a lengthy list of non-IPO topics that we&#8217;d like to get to. If everyone could stop going public for a few days, we&#8217;d love to write about something else!</em> OK, let&#8217;s get into it!</p>
<h2>Most of the news is good</h2>
<p>As a short introduction, the company&#8217;s products are designed to help developers find users and monetize their apps. AppLovin has its own in-house suite of mobile apps, what its S-1 calls a &#8220;globally diversified portfolio of over 200 free-to-play mobile games run by 12 studios.&#8221; Those apps have 32 million global daily actives, the document added.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a pretty neat company to dig into if you&#8217;re into mobile apps at all. Regardless, what we care about today are its numbers. So let&#8217;s talk <strong>growth</strong>, <strong>revenue quality</strong>, <strong>profits</strong>, <strong>cash consumption</strong> and <strong>capital structure</strong>. Most of the news is good, even if there are some downsides to AppLovin&#8217;s capital structure.</p>
<p>Recall that KKR <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-applovin-m-a-kkr/kkr-agrees-to-buy-stake-in-applovin-at-2-billion-valuation-idUSKBN1K62W5">bought a chunk of AppLovin</a> back in mid-2018 at a valuation of around $2 billion. That number appears comically low, given that the company posted $483.4 million in revenue that year, a figure that it roughly doubled in 2019 to $994.1 million. Growth slowed in percentage terms in 2020, when AppLovin saw total revenues of $1.45 billion, though the company managed similar growth in gross-dollar terms.</p>
<p>In percentage terms, AppLovin grew 106% from 2018 to 2019, and 46% from 2019 to 2020. How KKR got to buy into the company at 4x revenues when it was growing at 100% is not clear.</p>
<p>The company is growing well, but is AppLovin accreting revenue of high quality? Yes, but we need to scrape some grime off the numbers to understand them. Turning to the company&#8217;s yearly results, AppLovin&#8217;s cost of revenue rose steadily as a percentage of revenue from 2018 to 2020. Indeed, the numbers went from 11% in 2018 to 24% in 2019 and 38% in 2020. That&#8217;s an awful progression, and if we lacked more information we&#8217;d posit that the company&#8217;s overall revenue quality was sharply declining.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not that bad. There&#8217;s about $1 million in share-based compensation inside the 2020 cost of revenue figure and $228.3 million of &#8220;amortization expense related to acquired intangibles.&#8221; If we yank out those from the cost-of-revenue line item, AppLovin&#8217;s gross margin for 2020 grows from 62% to 77.5%. That&#8217;s much better.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/first-impressions-of-applovins-ipo-filing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2120294</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft launches &#8216;Group Transcribe,&#8217; a transcription and translation app for in-person meetings</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/microsoft-launches-group-transcribe-a-transcription-and-translation-app-for-in-person-meetings/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/microsoft-launches-group-transcribe-a-transcription-and-translation-app-for-in-person-meetings/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 16:04:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meetings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft garage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Speech Recognition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transcription]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Translation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2120321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new project from Microsoft&#8217;s in-house incubator, Microsoft Garage, introduces a different take on meeting transcriptions. While today there are a number of real-time transcription apps to use on your phone &#8212; like Otter.ai or Google&#8217;s Recorder app for Pixel devices, for example &#8212; Microsoft&#8217;s new Group Transcribe app reimagines meeting transcriptions as a more [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A new project from Microsoft&#8217;s in-house incubator, Microsoft Garage, introduces a different take on meeting transcriptions. While today there are a number of real-time transcription apps to use on your phone &#8212; like <a href="https://otter.ai/">Otter.ai</a> or Google&#8217;s <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.recorder&amp;hl=en_US&amp;gl=US">Recorder</a> app for Pixel devices, for example &#8212; Microsoft&#8217;s <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/group-transcribe/id1527145885">new Group Transcribe app</a> reimagines meeting transcriptions as a more collaborative process, where everyone simultaneously records the meeting on their own device for higher accuracy. It also offers real-time translation for languages spoken in over 80 distinct locales.</p>
<p>To use the app, one person would first initiate the meeting in their own device. They can then invite the other meeting attendees to join the session via Bluetooth, a scannable QR code or by sharing a link. After the other participants join the session and the meeting begins, each person will see the transcript appear in real-time on their own device.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2120346" style="width: 411px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2120346" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2120346" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot4-1.png?w=401" alt="" width="401" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot4-1.png 425w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot4-1.png?resize=89,150 89w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot4-1.png?resize=177,300 177w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot4-1.png?resize=401,680 401w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot4-1.png?resize=30,50 30w" sizes="(max-width: 401px) 100vw, 401px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2120346" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Microsoft</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The app, which is powered by A.I. speech and language technology, is able to transcribe with higher accuracy and speaker attribution based on the volume of the speaker captured by the microphone of each phone being used in the meeting.</p>
<p>By comparing the level of a person&#8217;s voice volume, the cloud service attempts to determine which device is closest to the speaker and the language preferences of that speaker. This means speakers are also accurately labeled in the app, which can be a challenge for other transcription apps where only one person is recording.</p>
<p>In addition, if meeting participants want to speak in their own language, the app can provide the translation to others&#8217; devices in their own language.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2120347" style="width: 411px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2120347" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2120347" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot3-1.png?w=401" alt="" width="401" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot3-1.png 425w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot3-1.png?resize=89,150 89w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot3-1.png?resize=177,300 177w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot3-1.png?resize=401,680 401w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot3-1.png?resize=30,50 30w" sizes="(max-width: 401px) 100vw, 401px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2120347" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Microsoft</p></div></p>
<p>Microsoft says the app is designed with accessibility in mind, as it makes it easier for people who are deaf, hard of hearing, and non-native speakers to more fully participate in meetings by following along through the live transcriptions and translations.</p>
<p>The project itself was built by Microsoft employees who collectively speak over a dozen different languages and dialects.</p>
<p>&#8220;This can be a fantastic tool for communication. What I would love to see is for this to break down barriers for people speaking across multiple languages,” said Franklin Munoz, Principal Development Lead, when <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/garage/blog/2021/03/new-garage-project-group-transcribe-helps-you-transcribe-and-translate-while-advancing-inclusive-speech-ai/">introducing</a> the project.</p>
<p>Like most cloud-based transcription services, the app should not be used for highly confidential meetings. However, Microsoft has built granular data and privacy controls that allow users to decide if or when they want to share their conversation data.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2120349" style="width: 411px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2120349" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2120349" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot1-1.png?w=401" alt="" width="401" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot1-1.png 425w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot1-1.png?resize=89,150 89w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot1-1.png?resize=177,300 177w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot1-1.png?resize=401,680 401w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GroupTranscribe_ScreensShot1-1.png?resize=30,50 30w" sizes="(max-width: 401px) 100vw, 401px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2120349" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Microsoft</p></div></p>
<p>To work, the audio and text input data collected is sent to Microsoft&#8217;s online speech recognitions and translation technologies &#8212; though with a randomly generated identifier, not your real name.</p>
<p>While Microsoft doesn&#8217;t save the meeting transcripts and recordings itself after the fact &#8212; they&#8217;re saved on your device &#8212; the app does encourage participants to &#8220;contribute&#8221; their meetings recordings to Microsoft so it can improve the service.</p>
<p>This allows Microsoft to retain the audio and speech recognition-generated text transcriptions when all meeting participants agree to opt in for that session. By reviewing the data, Microsoft aims to improve its speech recognition and speaker attribution capabilities over time, it says. The user data will then be accessed under NDA by both Microsoft employees and contractors from other companies who work for Microsoft, but won&#8217;t include any of the speakers&#8217; account credentials.</p>
<p>Reviewers will also only have access to randomized snippets of audio, not full recordings. And Microsoft says it &#8220;de-identifies&#8221; meeting recordings by removing long strings of numbers that could represent things like credit card numbers or phone numbers, for example. Users can delete their previously shared recordings at any time, but otherwise they&#8217;re retained for up to 2 years on encrypted servers, the company says.</p>
<p>Because there&#8217;s not a way for a business, at an admin level, to configure or block the &#8220;contribution&#8221; setting for all users, people should carefully weigh the advantages and risks of such a service. It&#8217;s also a Microsoft Garage project, meaning it&#8217;s meant to be more experimental and could be shuttered at any time.</p>
<p>Currently, the Group Transcribe app is <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/group-transcribe/id1527145885">available on iOS only</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/microsoft-launches-group-transcribe-a-transcription-and-translation-app-for-in-person-meetings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2120321</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clari revenue forecasting platform snags $150M investment and triples valuation to $1.6B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/clari-revenue-forecasting-platform-snags-150m-investment-and-triples-valuation-to-1-6b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/clari-revenue-forecasting-platform-snags-150m-investment-and-triples-valuation-to-1-6b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 16:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silver lake]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2120333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Clari, the revenue operations platform that helps companies predict revenue outcomes, announced $150 million Series E today on a $1.6 billion valuation, a number that more than triples its 2019 Series D valuation of $500 million. Silver Lake led the latest investment with participation from B Capital Group and existing investors Sequoia Capital, Bain Capital [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://clari.com">Clari</a>, the revenue operations platform that helps companies predict revenue outcomes, announced $150 million Series E today on a $1.6 billion valuation, a number that more than triples its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/10/clari-snags-60m-series-d-on-valuation-of-around-500m/">2019 Series D valuation</a> of $500 million.</p>
<p>Silver Lake led the latest investment with participation from B Capital Group and existing investors Sequoia Capital, Bain Capital Ventures, Sapphire Ventures, Madrona Ventures, Thomvest and Tenaya Capital. The company reports it has now raised a total of $285 million.</p>
<p>While COVID made 2020 trying for everyone, a company with a product that allows executive teams to understand and predict revenue at a granular level was obviously going to be in demand, and Clari saw a lot of interest over the last year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;It was a surreal year for us, given the momentum we had and all of the tough news we saw going on around us. For us, the usage metrics were just off the charts, as people need visibility and predictability and control over their revenue forecasts,&#8221; company co-founder and CEO Andy Byrne told me.</p>
<p>While Byrne didn&#8217;t want to discuss revenue specifics, he did point out that he beat the revenue plan he submitted to his board by 110%. He said the performance has led to a lot of inbound investor interest in the company.</p>
<p>&#8220;That&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve had such great investor interest is that [VCs] were hearing in the investment community about how transformative Clari has been [&#8230;] just giving companies what we call revenue confidence, being able to go and understand where you&#8217;re going to be and to accurately predict the impact the pandemic is going to have on your trajectory, good or bad,&#8221; Byrne explained.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ibf93PshvR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/12/gong-raises-another-200m-on-2-2-billion-valuation/">Gong raises another $200M on $2.2B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gong raises another $200M on $2.2B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/12/gong-raises-another-200m-on-2-2-billion-valuation/embed/#?secret=Ibf93PshvR" data-secret="Ibf93PshvR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>To this point, the company has been working with sales and marketing teams, but Byrne says that the company is expanding the scope of the product to bring that same predictability to other parts of an organization.</p>
<p>Clari has mostly focused on technology companies with customers like HPE, Workday and Adobe, but it has plans to expand beyond that vertical. In fact, one of the ways Byrne plans to put today&#8217;s investment to work is to push into other verticals, which could also benefit from this kind of revenue visibility.</p>
<p>The company is up 300 employees with plans to double that number by the end of 2021. Byrne says he is building a positive work culture and points to recently being recognized as one of the best places to work by Inc., Bay Area News Group, #GirlsClub and Built In. He says they have made progress when it comes to diversity hirings across a number dimensions, but admits there is still work to be done.</p>
<p>&#8220;We actually specifically [established] a commission around diversity and inclusion that has board level [backing] that we&#8217;re running to continue to do better work there. Having said that, we still recognize that we&#8217;re not too dissimilar to a lot of companies where we feel like there&#8217;s so much more that we need to do,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>At this point in the company&#8217;s evolution with plenty of money in the bank and a healthy valuation, Byrne did not shy away from the IPO question, although as you would imagine, he wasn&#8217;t ready to discuss specifics.</p>
<p>&#8220;I would say the answer is unequivocally yes, and we&#8217;re building toward this. [&#8230;] We don&#8217;t have a timeframe upon which we know where we&#8217;re going to go public, but the next goal is to get to the IPO starting line,&#8221; he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="It8EgOSHhU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/10/clari-snags-60m-series-d-on-valuation-of-around-500m/">Clari snags $60M Series D on valuation of around $500M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Clari snags $60M Series D on valuation of around $500M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/10/clari-snags-60m-series-d-on-valuation-of-around-500m/embed/#?secret=It8EgOSHhU" data-secret="It8EgOSHhU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/clari-revenue-forecasting-platform-snags-150m-investment-and-triples-valuation-to-1-6b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2120333</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TC Sessions: Justice 2021 kicks off today — join the conversation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/tc-sessions-justice-2021-kicks-off-today-join-the-conversation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/tc-sessions-justice-2021-kicks-off-today-join-the-conversation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 15:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions: Justice 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118407</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today’s the day we roll up our collective sleeves, engage in vital conversations about diversity, inclusion and equity in tech — and continue the important work of building a better industry for everyone. TC Sessions: Justice 2021 features an impressive agenda packed with interactive presentations, breakout sessions and panel discussions with some of the tech world’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today’s the day we roll up our collective sleeves, engage in vital conversations about diversity, inclusion and equity in tech — and continue the important work of building a better industry for everyone.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/">TC Sessions: Justice 2021</a> features <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/#1fa16903-b3ec-435b-ba68-d43e00bd8d70">an impressive agenda</a> packed with interactive presentations, breakout sessions and panel discussions with some of the tech world’s brightest innovators, leaders and worker-activists. These folks are in the trenches, changing the world and creating exciting business opportunities. That’s a win-win.</p>
<p>Last-minute decision maker? No problem. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/#tickets">Join the conversation here</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>You’ll also have time to network and connect with attendees around the world, enjoy startup presentations and even meet some of the early-stage companies in our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/include/">TC Include</a> founder cohort.</p>
<p>We’re got an incredibly deep bench of talented experts and visionaries ready to take the virtual stage. Here are just a few of the panels and people you simply don’t want to miss.</p>
<p><strong>Finding the Next Unicorn:</strong> Arlan Hamilton, the founder and managing partner of Backstage Capital, has raised more than $12 million to back 150 companies led by underrepresented founders. In this session, Hamilton will discuss how she vets the biggest opportunities in investment, and how to disrupt in a positive way.</p>
<p><strong>Identifying and Dismantling Tech&#8217;s Deep Systems of Bias:</strong> Nearly every popular technology or service has within it systems of bias or exclusion, ignored by the privileged but obvious to the groups affected. How should these systems be exposed and documented, and how can we set about eliminating them and preventing more from appearing in the future? AI for the People’s Mutale Nkonde, disability rights lawyer Haben Girma, and author of Algorithms of Oppression Safiya Umoja Noble discuss a more inclusive future.</p>
<p><strong>Founders in Focus:</strong> We sit down with the founders poised to be the next big disruptors in this industry. Here we chat with Tracy Chou of Block Party, which works to protect people from abuse and harassment online.</p>
<p><strong>Why Social Media is Broken and What To Do About It: </strong>Toxic culture, deadly conspiracies and organized hate have exploded online in recent years. We’ll discuss how much responsibility social networks have in the rise of these phenomena and how to build healthy online communities that make society better, not worse. Naj Austin (Somewhere Good &amp; Ethel&#8217;s Club), Jesse Lehrich (Accountable Tech) and Rashad Robinson (Color of Change)</p>
<p><strong>Meeting of the Minds:</strong> Diversity and inclusion as an idea has been on the agenda of tech companies for years now. But the industry still lacks true inclusion, despite best efforts put forth by heads of diversity, equity and inclusion at these companies. We’ll seek to better understand what’s standing in the way of progress and what it’s going to take to achieve real change. Sandra Altine (Facebook), Wade Davis (Netflix) and Bo Young Lee (Uber)</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/">TC Sessions: Justice 2021</a> kicks off today. Join your colleagues, learn, connect, and discover new ways and opportunities to build stronger startups and a more just tech industry for all people.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954"
			width="99%"
			height="500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/tc-sessions-justice-2021-kicks-off-today-join-the-conversation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118407</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>International VC firm Presight Capital raises $350M second fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/presight-fund-two/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/presight-fund-two/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 15:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christian Angermayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presight Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2120324</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Presight Capital has closed its $350 million second fund only a year and a half after it announced an $80 million first fund. In fact, General Partner Christian Angermayer told me that the fund was raised in just a few weeks, and that it shot past the initial goal of $250 million. Presight is the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.presight.vc">Presight Capital</a> has closed its $350 million second fund only a year and a half after it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/26/presight-capital/">announced an $80 million first fund</a>. In fact, General Partner Christian Angermayer told me that the fund was raised in just a few weeks, and that it shot past the initial goal of $250 million.</p>
<p>Presight is the international venture arm of Angermayer&#8217;s family office <a href="https://www.apeiron-investments.com">Apeiron Investment Group</a>, which has more than $2.5 billion under management. When I spoke to him about Presight&#8217;s first fund, he emphasized the firm&#8217;s ability to help U.S. startups expand into Europe, particularly with navigating the regulatory landscape.</p>
<p>Angermayer told me the strategy remains the same for the second fund, and he pointed to a couple other key elements to the Presight approach. For one thing, there&#8217;s the firm&#8217;s co-investing approach: &#8220;Sometimes we&#8217;re co-leading [the round], but there&#8217;s always a partner we work with.&#8221; And although Presight has a relatively small investment team — besides Angermayer, there&#8217;s General Partner Fabian Hansen and Principal Philipp Schreiber — portfolio companies also have access to the larger Apeiron team (20 full-time employees) and network.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Hansen said Presight remains sector agnostic in its investments, with a particular interest in biotech and deeptech. It&#8217;s already had some big successes in these fields, with <a href="https://www.abcellera.com/news/2020-05-27-abcellera-closes-series-b-financing">an early investment</a> in AI-powered drug discovery platform AbCellera <a href="https://www.archyde.com/ai-biotech-provider-abcellera-goes-public-with-enormous-success/">leading to an IPO</a> and Compass Pathways (a company that has patented a synthetic version of psilocybin to treat depression) <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-09-18/-magic-mushroom-company-moves-toward-mainstream-in-nasdaq-ipo">also going public</a>.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2120336" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2120336" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2120336" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/HSL6637.jpg?w=680" alt="Fabian Hansen" width="680" height="454" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/HSL6637.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/HSL6637.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/HSL6637.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/HSL6637.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/HSL6637.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/HSL6637.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2120336" class="wp-caption-text">Fabian Hansen</p></div></p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/you-cant-put-price-tag-life-except-we-can-christian-angermayer/">a LinkedIn post</a> published last fall, Angermayer argued that biotech will be the biggest sector over the next 10 to 20 years, and that the key metric in this field is quality-adjusted life years — the idea being that a year of life at perfect health is worth 1 QALY, death is zero, while life without perfect health is somewhere in between (or could even have a value below zero).</p>
<p>&#8220;And here’s the real conclusion: The big winners – besides everyone benefitting from these advances – will be the companies who are PRODUCING QALYs: biotech companies,&#8221; Angermayer wrote. And he is open about the fact that he has a personal motive in this: &#8220;Put simply, I want to live forever! And in perfect health! And it is my sincere belief that we will achieve the means to do this within the next 20-30 years.&#8221;</p>
<p>Hansen added that there&#8217;s a &#8220;whole generation&#8221; of executives at biotech firms who are launching new startups as they realize, &#8220;I can start my own company, it&#8217;s not that expensive to try out new things, I can raise a venture round.&#8221;</p>
<p>According to a source with knowledge of the firm, limited partners in Presight Fund Two include AbCellera founder and CEO Carl Hansen, former Goldman Sachs CFO Martin Chavez, Uma Thurman, Founders Forum co-founder Brent Hoberman, Point72 and the family offices of XING founder Lars Inrich, Nicole Junkermann, Louis Bacon, Alan Howard and Mike Novogratz. Plus, Angermayer himself invested $60 million.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ENefWMu6SV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/26/presight-capital/">Presight Capital raises $80M fund to connect US startups with Europe</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Presight Capital raises $80M fund to connect US startups with Europe&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/26/presight-capital/embed/#?secret=ENefWMu6SV" data-secret="ENefWMu6SV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/presight-fund-two/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2120324</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Have a startup in Miami? Apply to pitch at TechCrunch&#8217;s Miami virtual meetup</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/have-a-startup-in-miami-apply-to-pitch-at-techcrunchs-miami-virtual-meetup/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/have-a-startup-in-miami-apply-to-pitch-at-techcrunchs-miami-virtual-meetup/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 15:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[city spotlight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miami]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2120309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TechCrunch is coming to Miami &#8212; virtually, at least. On March 11, TechCrunch is hosting a small online event with local venture capitalists, founders, and those curious about the growing ecosystem. There will also be a small pitch-off event where Florida-based startups have three minutes to pitch their companies to Florida-based VCs. Everyone is welcome [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TechCrunch is coming to Miami &#8212; virtually, at least. On March 11, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/attend-techcrunchs-free-virtual-miami-meetup-on-march-11/">TechCrunch is hosting a small online event</a> with local venture capitalists, founders, and those curious about the growing ecosystem. There will also be a small pitch-off event where Florida-based startups have three minutes to pitch their companies to Florida-based VCs.</p>
<p>Everyone is welcome to attend the event, but we&#8217;re looking for startups based in the Miami region to pitch at this event. TechCrunch has a long history of hosting small pitch-offs and we&#8217;re excited to revive this tradition despite the need to do it virtually.</p>
<p>Not in Miami? No worries. We&#8217;re spinning up similar events in other regions too. Spoiler: Detroit/Ann Arbor and Pittsburgh are next.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>Qualifications</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Early stage startup (Series A or earlier)</li>
<li>Startups based in the Miami region will be given priority</li>
<li>Pitch decks are highly recommended</li>
<li><a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/kZ4l728t">Apply for the pitch-off here</a></li>
</ul>
<p>The event is online and free, but space is limited. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/attend-techcrunchs-free-virtual-miami-meetup-on-march-11/">Register early.</a> We hope you can make it.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ud8QIxsomU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/attend-techcrunchs-free-virtual-miami-meetup-on-march-11/">Attend TechCrunch&#8217;s free virtual Miami meetup on March 11</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Attend TechCrunch&#8217;s free virtual Miami meetup on March 11&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/attend-techcrunchs-free-virtual-miami-meetup-on-march-11/embed/#?secret=ud8QIxsomU" data-secret="ud8QIxsomU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/miami/"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2107272" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="141" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=150,21 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=300,41 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=768,106 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=680,94 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=1536,211 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=2048,282 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=50,7 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/have-a-startup-in-miami-apply-to-pitch-at-techcrunchs-miami-virtual-meetup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2120309</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>$100 million for mealworms</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/100-million-for-mealworms/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/100-million-for-mealworms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 15:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AgTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future acres]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jon shieber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SESO Labor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119917</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/d13b6f32-a8b3-42a0-aacb-9322f033835f?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>This is our Wednesday show, where we niche down and focus on a single topic, or theme. This week we&#8217;re talking agtech, a surprisingly cool bit of the technology startup world. But <a href="https://twitter.com/cgates123">Chris</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/dannycrichton">Danny</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> were not alone in their quest to take a look into agtech, we brought alone TechCrunch climate editor <a href="https://twitter.com/jshieber">Jon Shieber</a> for the ride.</p>
<p>With his help we got through a number of pretty damn interesting things, including:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/seso-labor-is-providing-a-way-for-migrant-farmworkers-to-get-legally-protected-work-status-in-the-u-s/">SESO Labor raising $4.5 million</a> to help farms secure the labor they need, and navigate the American immigration system.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/future-acres-launches-with-the-arrival-of-crop-transporting-robot-carry/">Future Acres looking to raise $3 million</a> for its farming robots. And Farmwise, which last raised $14.5 million and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/farmwise-plans-to-add-autonomous-crop-dusting-to-its-suite-of-robotic-services/">has an idea regarding how to rent robot labor to farms</a>.</li>
<li>We also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/anuvia-raises-103-million-to-commercialize-its-novel-fertilizer/">chatted about Anuvia&#8217;s epic $103 million raise</a> that could help boost farm yields while cutting carbon emissions.</li>
<li>And Better Origin, which wants to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/better-origin-which-turns-flies-into-food-for-chickens-raises-3m-from-fly-ventures/">help farmers raise flies to feed to chickens</a>. Which we had a few ideas about.</li>
</ul>
<p>And that&#8217;s that! We&#8217;re back on Friday with our long-form, newsy episode. Thanks to everyone checking out our newest show. Oh, and don&#8217;t forget about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/">TechCrunch Early Stage</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/">TechCrunch Justice</a>. They are going to <em>rock</em>.</p>
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday morning at 7:00 a.m. PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts.</i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/100-million-for-mealworms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119917</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google says it won&#8217;t adopt new tracking tech after phasing out cookies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/google-renounces-ad-tracking/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/google-renounces-ad-tracking/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 14:59:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cookies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2120307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While we&#8217;ve written about attempts to build alternatives to cookies that track users across websites, Google says it won&#8217;t be going down that route. The search giant had already announced that it will be phasing out support for third-party cookies in its Chrome browser. Today it went further, with David Temkin (Google&#8217;s director of product management [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">While we&#8217;ve written about attempts to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/04/iab-cookie/">build alternatives to cookies that track users across websites</a>, Google says it won&#8217;t be going down that route.</p>
<p>The search giant had already announced that it will be <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/14/google-wants-to-phase-out-support-for-third-party-cookies-in-chrome-within-two-years/">phasing out support for third-party cookies in its Chrome browser.</a> Today it went further, with David Temkin (Google&#8217;s director of product management for ads privacy and trust) writing in <a href="https://blog.google/products/ads-commerce/a-more-privacy-first-web/">a blog post</a> that &#8220;once third-party cookies are phased out, we will not build alternate identifiers to track individuals as they browse across the web, nor will we use them in our products.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We realize this means other providers may offer a level of user identity for ad tracking across the web that we will not — like [personally identifiable information] graphs based on people’s email addresses,&#8221; Temkin continued. &#8220;We don’t believe these solutions will meet rising consumer expectations for privacy, nor will they stand up to rapidly evolving regulatory restrictions, and therefore aren’t a sustainable long term investment.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This doesn&#8217;t mean ads won&#8217;t be targeted at all. Instead, he argued that thanks to &#8220;advances in aggregation, anonymization, on-device processing and other privacy-preserving technologies,&#8221; it&#8217;s no longer necessary to &#8220;track individual consumers across the web to get the performance benefits of digital advertising.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fUZ9knBNUe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/14/google-wants-to-phase-out-support-for-third-party-cookies-in-chrome-within-two-years/">Google wants to phase out support for third-party cookies in Chrome within two years</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google wants to phase out support for third-party cookies in Chrome within two years&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/14/google-wants-to-phase-out-support-for-third-party-cookies-in-chrome-within-two-years/embed/#?secret=fUZ9knBNUe" data-secret="fUZ9knBNUe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As an example, Temkin pointed to a new approach being tested by Google called Federated Learning of Cohorts (FLoC), which allows ads to be targeted at large groups of users based on common interests. He said Google will begin testing FLoCs with advertisers in the second quarter of this year.</p>
<p>Temkin also said that these changes are focused on third-party data and don&#8217;t affect the ability of publishers to track and target their own visitors: &#8220;We will continue to support first-party relationships on our ad platforms for partners, in which they have direct connections with their own customers.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting, however, that the Electronic Frontier Foundation has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/google-claims-almost-no-change-in-ad-revenue-from-targeting-proposals-in-its-privacy-sandbox-but-privacy-upside-less-clear/">described FLoCs</a> as &#8220;the opposite of privacy-preserving technology” and compared them to a &#8220;behavioral credit score.&#8221;</p>
<p>And while cookies have been phased out across the industry, the U.K.’s Competition and Markets Authority is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/googles-plan-to-replace-tracking-cookies-goes-under-uk-antitrust-probe/">currently investigating Google&#8217;s cookie plan</a> over antitrust concerns, with critics suggesting that Google is using privacy as an excuse to increase its market power. (A similar criticism has been <a href="https://stratechery.com/2021/an-interview-with-eric-seufert-about-apple-facebook-and-mobile-advertising/">leveled against Apple</a> over <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/apple-app-tracking-transparency/">upcoming privacy changes in iOS</a>.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OAXo08lJE0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/googles-plan-to-replace-tracking-cookies-goes-under-uk-antitrust-probe/">Google&#8217;s plan to replace tracking cookies goes under UK antitrust probe</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google&#8217;s plan to replace tracking cookies goes under UK antitrust probe&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/googles-plan-to-replace-tracking-cookies-goes-under-uk-antitrust-probe/embed/#?secret=OAXo08lJE0" data-secret="OAXo08lJE0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/google-renounces-ad-tracking/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2120307</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yugabyte announces $48M investment as cloud native database makes enterprise push</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/yugabyte-announces-48m-series-c-as-cloud-native-database-makes-enterprise-push/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/yugabyte-announces-48m-series-c-as-cloud-native-database-makes-enterprise-push/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 14:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[databases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yugabyte]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2120295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As demand for cloud native applications is growing, Yugabyte, makers of the cloud native, open source YugabyteDB database are seeing a corresponding rise in demand for their products, especially with large enterprise customers. Today, the company announced a $48 million financing round to help build on that momentum. The round is an extension of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As demand for cloud native applications is growing, <a href="https://www.yugabyte.com/">Yugabyte</a>, makers of the cloud native, open source YugabyteDB database are seeing a corresponding rise in demand for their products, especially with large enterprise customers. Today, the company announced a $48 million financing round to help build on that momentum. The round is an extension of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/09/yugabyte-lands-30m-series-b-as-open-source-database-continues-to-flourish/">the startup&#8217;s $30 million Series B</a> last June.</p>
<p>Lightspeed Venture Partners led the round with participation from Greenspring Associates, Dell Technologies Capital, Wipro Ventures and 8VC. It has raised a total raised to $103 million, according to the company.</p>
<p>Kannan Muthukkaruppan, Yugabyte co-founder and president, says the startup saw a marked increase in interest in both the open source and commercial offerings in 2020 as the pandemic <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/the-cloud-infrastructure-market-hit-129b-in-2020/">pushed many companies to the cloud</a> faster than they might have gone otherwise, something many startup founders have pointed out to me.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;The distributed SQL space is definitely heating up, and if anything over the last six months almost in every vector in terms of enterprise customers &#8212; from Fortune 500 companies across financial, retail, ISP or telcos &#8212; are putting Yugabyte in production to be the system of record database to meet some of their business critical services needs,&#8221; Muthukkaruppan told me.</p>
<p>In addition, he&#8217;s seeing a similar rise in the level of interest from the open source version of the product.&#8221;Similarly, the groundswell on the community and the open source adoption has been phenomenal. Our Slack [open source] user community quadrupled in 2020,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>That kind of momentum led to the increased investor interest, says co-founder and CTO Karthik Ranganathan. &#8220;Some of the primary reasons to go and even ask for funding was that we realized we could accelerate some of this stuff, and we couldn&#8217;t do that with the original $30 million we had raised,&#8221; he said. The original thinking was to do a secondary raise in the $15-20 million, but multiple investors expressed interest in participating, and it ended up being $48 million when all was said and done.</p>
<p>Former Pivotal president Bill Cook came on board as CEO at the same time they were announcing their last funding round in June and brought some enterprise chops to the table. It was his job to figure out how to expand the market opportunity with larger high-value enterprise clients. &#8220;And so the last six or seven months has been about that, dealing with enterprise clients on one hand and then this emerging developer led cloud offering as well,&#8221; Cook said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DpMmkp66LS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/grafana-labs-launches-observability-stack-aimed-at-enterprise-users/">Grafana Labs launches observability stack for enterprise customers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Grafana Labs launches observability stack for enterprise customers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/grafana-labs-launches-observability-stack-aimed-at-enterprise-users/embed/#?secret=DpMmkp66LS" data-secret="DpMmkp66LS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The company has a three tier offering that includes the open source YugabyteDB. Then there is a fully managed cloud version called Yugabyte Cloud, and finally there is a self-managed cloud version of the database called Yugabyte Platform. The latter is especially attractive to large enterprise customers, who want to be in the cloud, but still want to maintain control of their data and infrastructure, and so choose to manage the cloud installation themselves.</p>
<p>Yugabyte started last year with 50 employees, doubled that to this point, and now expects to reach 200 by the end of this year. As they add employees, the leadership team is cognizant of the importance of building a diverse and inclusive workforce, while recognizing the challenges in doing so.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s work in progress as always. We&#8217;ve added diversity candidates right along the whole spectrum as we&#8217;ve grown but from my perspective it&#8217;s never sufficient, and we just need to keep pushing on it hard, and I think as a leadership team we recognize that,&#8221; Cook said.</p>
<p>The three leaders of the company have been working together remotely now since the announcement in June, and had only met briefly in person prior to the pandemic shutting down offices, but they say that it has gone smoothly. And while they would obviously like to meet in person again when the time is right, the momentum the company is experiencing shows that things are moving in the right direction, regardless of where they are getting their work done.</p>
<p><em>Note: The article originally stated this was a Series C round, but the company later clarified that was a B-1 round and we updated the article to reflect that.</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xFr1VvGvkj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/09/yugabyte-lands-30m-series-b-as-open-source-database-continues-to-flourish/">Yugabyte lands $30M Series B as open source database continues to flourish</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Yugabyte lands $30M Series B as open source database continues to flourish&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/09/yugabyte-lands-30m-series-b-as-open-source-database-continues-to-flourish/embed/#?secret=xFr1VvGvkj" data-secret="xFr1VvGvkj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/yugabyte-announces-48m-series-c-as-cloud-native-database-makes-enterprise-push/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2120295</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>$1.3M in grants go towards making the web&#8217;s open source infrastructure more equitable</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/1-3m-in-grants-go-towards-making-the-webs-open-source-infrastructure-more-equitable/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/1-3m-in-grants-go-towards-making-the-webs-open-source-infrastructure-more-equitable/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 14:02:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Philanthropy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cornell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intellectual property law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[northeastern university]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NYU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Omidyar Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uc-berkeley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[university of texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[university of washington]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119222</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Open source software is at the core of&#8230; well, practically everything online. But while much of it is diligently maintained in some ways, in others it doesn&#8217;t receive the kind of scrutiny that something so foundational ought to. $1.3 million worth of grants were announced today, split among 13 projects looking to ensure open source [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Open source software is at the core of&#8230; well, practically everything online. But while much of it is diligently maintained in some ways, in others it doesn&#8217;t receive the kind of scrutiny that something so foundational ought to. $1.3 million worth of grants were announced today, split among 13 projects looking to ensure open source software and development is being done equitably, sustainably, and responsibly.</p>
<p>The research projects will look into a number of questions about the way open source digital infrastructure is being used, maintained, and otherwise affected. For instance, many municipalities rely on and create this sort of infrastructure constantly as the need for government software solutions grows, but what are the processes by which this is done? Which approaches or frameworks succeed, and why?</p>
<p>And what about the private companies that contribute to major open-source projects, often without consulting one another — how do they communicate and share priorities and dependencies? How could that be improved, and with what costs and benefits?</p>
<p>These and other questions aren&#8217;t the type that any single organization or local government is likely to take on spontaneously, and of course the costs of such studies aren&#8217;t trivial. But they were deemed interesting enough (and possibly likely to generate new approaches and products) by a team of experts who sorted through about 250 applications over the last year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ERDTEotcxQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/equal-access-to-capital-and-entrepreneurship-is-the-final-civil-rights-movement/">Equal access to capital and entrepreneurship is the final civil rights movement</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Equal access to capital and entrepreneurship is the final civil rights movement&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/equal-access-to-capital-and-entrepreneurship-is-the-final-civil-rights-movement/embed/#?secret=ERDTEotcxQ" data-secret="ERDTEotcxQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The grantmaking operation is funded and organized by the Ford Foundation, Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, Open Society Foundations, Omidyar Network, and the Mozilla Open Source Support Program in collaboration with the Open Collective Foundation.</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s a dearth of funding for looking at the needs and potential applications of free and open source infrastructure. The public interest issues behind open source have been the missing piece,&#8221; said Michael Brennan, who&#8217;s leading<a href="https://www.fordfoundation.org/the-latest/news/major-philanthropies-tackle-inequality-by-strengthening-how-open-source-code-is-developed-and-maintained/"> the grant program at the Ford Foundation</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;The president of the foundation [Darren Walker] once said, &#8216;a just society relies on a just Internet,&#8217; &#8221; he quoted. &#8220;So our question is how do we create that just Internet? How do we create and sustain an equitable Internet that serves everyone equally? We actually have a lot more questions than answers, and few people are funding research into those questions.&#8221;</p>
<p>Even finding the right questions is part of the question, of course, but in basic research that&#8217;s expected. Early work in a field can seem frustratingly general or inconclusive because it&#8217;s as much about establishing the scope and general direction of the work as it is about suggesting actual courses of action.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="j22Ngusd7c"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/biased-ai-perpetuates-racial-injustice/">Biased AI perpetuates racial injustice</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Biased AI perpetuates racial injustice&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/biased-ai-perpetuates-racial-injustice/embed/#?secret=j22Ngusd7c" data-secret="j22Ngusd7c" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;The final portfolio wasn&#8217;t just about the &#8216;objectively best&#8217; ones, but how do we find a diversity of approaches and ideas, and tackle different aspects of this work, and also be representative of the diverse and global nature of the project?&#8221; Brennan said. &#8220;This year we also accepted proposals for both research and implementation. We want to see that the research is informing the building of that equitable and sustainable infrastructure.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://opencollective.com/di-grants">You can read the full research abstracts here</a>, but these are the short versions, with the proposer&#8217;s name:</p>
<ul>
<li>How are COVID data infrastructures created and transformed by builders and maintainers from the open source community? &#8211; <em>Megan Finn (University of Washington, University of Texas, Northeastern University)</em></li>
<li>How is digital infrastructure a critical response to fight climate change? &#8211; <em>Narrira Lemos de Souza</em></li>
<li>How do perceptions of unfairness when contributing to an open source project affect the sustainability of critical open source digital infrastructure projects? &#8211; <em>Atul Pokharel (NYU)</em></li>
<li>Supporting projects to implement research-informed best practices at the time of need on governance, sustainability, and inclusion. &#8211; <em>Danielle Robinson (Code for Science &amp; Society)</em></li>
<li>Assessing Partnerships for Municipal Digital Infrastructure &#8211; <em>Anthony Townsend (Cornell Tech)</em></li>
<li>Implement recommendations for funders of open source infrastructure with guides, programming, and models &#8211; <em>Eileen Wagner, Molly Wilson, Julia Kloiber, Elisa Lindinger, and Georgia Bullen (Simply Secure &amp; Superrr)</em></li>
<li>How we can build a “Creative Commons” for API terms of Service, as a contract to automatically read, control and enforce APIs Terms of service between infrastructure and applications? &#8211; <em>Mehdi Medjaoui (APIdays, LesMainteneurs, Inno3)</em></li>
<li>Indian case study of governance, implementation, and private sector role of open source infrastructure projects &#8211; <em>​Digital Asia Hub</em></li>
<li>Will cross-company visibility into shared free and open source dependencies lead to cross-company collaboration and efforts to sustain shared dependencies? &#8211; <em>​Duane O&#8217;Brien</em></li>
<li>How do open source tools contribute towards creating a multilingual internet? &#8211; <em>Anushah Hossain (UC Berkeley)</em></li>
<li>How digital infrastructure projects could embrace cooperatives as a sustainable model for working &#8211; ​<em>Jorge Benet (Cooperativa Tierra Común)</em></li>
<li>How do technical decision-makers assess the security ramifications of open source software components before adopting them in their projects and where can systemic interventions to the FOSS ecosystem be targeted to collectively improve its security? &#8211; <em>Divyank Katira (Centre for Internet &amp; Society in Bangalore)</em></li>
<li>How can African participation in the development, maintenance, and application of the global open source digital infrastructure be enhanced? &#8211; <em>Alex Comninos (Research ICT Africa (RIA) and the University of Cape Town)</em></li>
</ul>
<p>The projects will receive their grants soon, and later in the year (or whenever they&#8217;re ready) the organizers will coordinate some kind of event at which they can present their results. Brennan made it clear that the funders take no stake in the projects and aren&#8217;t retaining or publishing the research themselves; they&#8217;re just coordinating and offering support where it makes sense.</p>
<p>$1.3 million is an interesting number. For some, it&#8217;s peanuts. A startup might burn through that cash in a month or two. But in an academic context, a hundred grand can be the difference between work getting done or being abandoned. The hope is that small injections at the base layer produce a better environment for the type of support the Ford Foundation and others provide as part of their other philanthropic and grantmaking efforts.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OXVtAZJ4uS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/17/microsoft-accessibility-grants-go-out-to-companies-aiming-to-improve-tech-for-the-disabled/">Microsoft accessibility grants go out to companies aiming to improve tech for people with disabilities</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Microsoft accessibility grants go out to companies aiming to improve tech for people with disabilities&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/17/microsoft-accessibility-grants-go-out-to-companies-aiming-to-improve-tech-for-the-disabled/embed/#?secret=OXVtAZJ4uS" data-secret="OXVtAZJ4uS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/1-3m-in-grants-go-towards-making-the-webs-open-source-infrastructure-more-equitable/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119222</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deliverr scores $170M to bring fast delivery to every e-commerce vendor</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/deliverr-scores-170m-to-bring-fast-delivery-to-every-e-commerce-vendor/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/deliverr-scores-170m-to-bring-fast-delivery-to-every-e-commerce-vendor/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 14:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coatue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deliverr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shipping and logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warehouses]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119985</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At a time when e-commerce is exploding due in large part to the pandemic, a business that helps any online merchant ship goods to a consumer in one or two days is going to be in demand. Deliverr is a startup that fits that bill, and today the company announced a $170 million financing round. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At a time when e-commerce is exploding due in large part to the pandemic, a business that helps any online merchant ship goods to a consumer in one or two days is going to be in demand. <a href="https://deliverr.com/">Deliverr</a> is a startup that fits that bill, and today the company announced a $170 million financing round.</p>
<p>The round breaks down to $135 million Series D financing led by Coatue. The remaining $35 million comes in the form of a convertible note led by Brookfield Technology Partners. Existing investors Activant Capital, 8VC and GLP participated in both parts of the investment. In less than four years, the company has raced from from rounds A to D, raising $240 million along the way.</p>
<p>Deliverr co-founder and CEO Michael Krakaris says it has been a rapid rise, but that his business requires a lot of capital. &#8220;It has been this really kind of crazy journey, and we&#8217;ve been growing very fast, but also this space is very capital intensive, and it&#8217;s a winner-take-all market where you gain efficiency at scale. You know scale is what makes your model highly defensible in this space,&#8221; Krakaris told me.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The way Deliverr works is it uses software to determine how to get goods to warehouses in parts of the country where they are needed. It then uses these warehouses&#8217; fulfillment departments to help pick and pack the order. The software then finds the fastest and cheapest delivery method and it gets shipped to customers with a two-day delivery guarantee. They are also ramping a next-day delivery product to expand the business.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZDUQw8xPO2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/02/coupa-software-snags-llamasoft-for-1-5b-to-bring-together-spending-and-supply-chain-data/">Coupa Software snags Llamasoft for $1.5B to bring together spending and supply chain data</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Coupa Software snags Llamasoft for $1.5B to bring together spending and supply chain data&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/02/coupa-software-snags-llamasoft-for-1-5b-to-bring-together-spending-and-supply-chain-data/embed/#?secret=ZDUQw8xPO2" data-secret="ZDUQw8xPO2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Deliverr doesn&#8217;t actually own any warehouses. It rents out space, and part of the challenge of building this business is establishing relationships with those warehouses and working out a business arrangement, one that is still evolving as the company grows. &#8220;A year ago, I would have said we typically wanted to be 5-10% of a warehouse&#8217;s business. There are cases now where we are 100% of these warehouses&#8217; businesses. We&#8217;ve grown to that level,&#8221; he explained.</p>
<p>Krakaris says that the pandemic raised major challenges for the company. Just setting up a relationship with new warehouses could require driving long distances because getting on a plane would mean quarantining when they landed. In some instances there were shortages of items. In others, COVID would shut down all of the warehouses in a given region, forcing the executive team to make a set of business adjustments on the fly, but this constant crisis mentality also helped them learn how to shift resources quickly, a lesson that is highly useful in this business.</p>
<p>The company started 2020 with 50 people and have added 100 employees since. They plan to double that this year, although that is variable depending on how the year goes. He say that another challenge is that he has done this hiring during COVID, and has never met a majority of his workers.</p>
<p>&#8220;You know, I&#8217;ve never met more than half the company in person, but I&#8217;m try to be as open as I can and learn about everyone, and we hold events to try and get to know everybody, but obviously it&#8217;s not like being together in person,&#8221; he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eS3wrsA18W"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/deliverr-lands-40m-series-c-to-bring-two-day-shipping-to-any-merchant/">Deliverr lands $40M Series C to bring two-day shipping to any merchant</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Deliverr lands $40M Series C to bring two-day shipping to any merchant&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/deliverr-lands-40m-series-c-to-bring-two-day-shipping-to-any-merchant/embed/#?secret=eS3wrsA18W" data-secret="eS3wrsA18W" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/deliverr-scores-170m-to-bring-fast-delivery-to-every-e-commerce-vendor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119985</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brave is launching its own search engine with the help of ex-Cliqz devs and tech</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/brave-is-launching-its-own-search-engine-with-the-help-of-ex-cliqz-devs-and-tech/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/brave-is-launching-its-own-search-engine-with-the-help-of-ex-cliqz-devs-and-tech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 14:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brave Search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cliqz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Brave, the privacy-focused browser co-founded by ex-Mozilla CEO Brendan Eich, is getting ready to launch an own-brand search engine for desktop and mobile. Today it&#8217;s announced the acquisition of an open source search engine developed by the team behind the (now defunct) Cliqz anti-tracking search-browser combo. The tech will underpin the forthcoming Brave Search engine [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/brave/">Brave</a>, the privacy-focused browser co-founded by ex-Mozilla CEO Brendan Eich, is getting ready to launch an own-brand search engine for desktop and mobile.</p>
<p>Today it&#8217;s announced the acquisition of an open source search engine developed by the team behind the (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/01/cliqz-pulls-the-plug-on-a-european-anti-tracking-alternative-to-google-search/">now defunct</a>) Cliqz anti-tracking search-browser combo. The tech will underpin the forthcoming Brave Search engine &#8212; meaning it will soon be pitching its millions of users on an entirely &#8216;big tech&#8217;-free search and browsing experience.</p>
<p>&#8220;Under the hood, nearly all of today’s search engines are either built by, or rely on, results from Big Tech companies. In contrast, the Tailcat search engine is built on top of a completely independent index, capable of delivering the quality people expect but without compromising their privacy,&#8221; Brave writes in a press release announcing the acquisition.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Tailcat does not collect IP addresses or use personally identifiable information to improve search results.&#8221;</p>
<p>Cliqz, which was a privacy-focused European fork of Mozilla&#8217;s Firefox browser, got shuttered last May after its majority investor, <a href="https://www.burda.com/de/news/cliqz-schliesst-bereiche/">Hubert Burda Media</a>, called time on the multi-year effort to build momentum for an alternative to Google &#8212; blaming tougher trading conditions during the pandemic for forcing it to pull the plug sooner than it would have liked.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZmhXeylP5h"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/01/cliqz-pulls-the-plug-on-a-european-anti-tracking-alternative-to-google-search/">Cliqz pulls the plug on a European anti-tracking alternative to Google search</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cliqz pulls the plug on a European anti-tracking alternative to Google search&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/01/cliqz-pulls-the-plug-on-a-european-anti-tracking-alternative-to-google-search/embed/#?secret=ZmhXeylP5h" data-secret="ZmhXeylP5h" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The former Cliqz dev team, who had subsequently been working on Tailcat, are moving to Brave as part of the acquisition. The engineering team is led by Dr Josep M Pujol &#8212; who is quoted in Brave&#8217;s PR saying it&#8217;s &#8220;excited to be working on the only real private search/browser alternative to Big Tech&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;Tailcat is a fully independent search engine with its own search index built from scratch,&#8221; Eich told TechCrunch. &#8220;Tailcat as Brave Search will offer the same privacy guarantees that Brave has in its browser.</p>
<p>&#8220;Brave will provide the first private browser+search alternative to the Big Tech platforms, and will make it seamless for users to browse and search with guaranteed privacy. Also, owing to its transparent nature, Brave Search will address algorithmic biases and prevent outright censorship.&#8221;</p>
<p>Brave getting into the search business is a reflection of its confidence that privacy is becoming mainstream, per Eich. He points to &#8220;unprecedented&#8221; growth in usage of its browser over the past year &#8212; up from 11M monthly active users to 26M+ &#8212; which he says has mirrored the surge in usage <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/signal-brian-acton-talks-about-exploding-growth-monetization-and-whatsapp-data-sharing-outrage/">earlier this year</a> seen by the (not-for-profit) e2e encrypted messaging app Signal (after Facebook-owned WhatsApp announced a change to its privacy policies to allow for increased data-sharing with Facebook through WhatsApp business accounts).</p>
<p>&#8220;We expect to see even greater demand for Brave in 2021 as more and more users demand real privacy solutions to escape Big Tech’s invasive practices,” he added in a statement. “Brave’s mission is to put the user first, and integrating privacy-preserving search into our platform is a necessary step to ensure that user privacy is not plundered to fuel the surveillance economy.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="G9kfiLhe8y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/brave-web-browser-adds-native-support-for-peer-to-peer-ipfs-protocol/">Brave web browser adds native support for peer-to-peer IPFS protocol</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Brave web browser adds native support for peer-to-peer IPFS protocol&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/brave-web-browser-adds-native-support-for-peer-to-peer-ipfs-protocol/embed/#?secret=G9kfiLhe8y" data-secret="G9kfiLhe8y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Brave Search will be offered as a choice to users alongside a roster of more established third parties (Google, Bing, Qwant, Ecosia etc) which they can select as their browser default.</p>
<p>It will also potentially become the default (i.e. if users don&#8217;t pick their own) in future, per Eich.</p>
<p>&#8220;We will continue to support &#8216;open search&#8217; with multiple alternative engines,&#8221; he confirmed. &#8220;User choice is a permanent principle at Brave. Brave will continue to offer multiple alternative choices for the user’s default search engine, and we think our users will seek unmatched privacy with Brave Search. When ready, we hope to make Brave Search the default engine in Brave.&#8221;</p>
<p>Asked how the quality of Tailcat-powered results vs Google Eich described it as &#8220;quite good&#8221;, adding that it &#8220;will only get better with adoption&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;Google’s &#8216;long tail&#8217; is hard for any engine to beat but we have a plan to compete on that front too, once integrated into the Brave browser,&#8221; he told us in an email interview, arguing that Google&#8217;s massive size does offer some competitive opportunities for a search rival. &#8220;There are aspects where Google is falling behind. It is difficult for them to innovate in search when that’s the main source of their revenue.</p>
<p>&#8220;They are risk-averse against experimenting with new techniques and transparency, while under pressure from shareholders to tie their own businesses into scarce search engine results page (SERP) area, and pressure from search engine optimization (SEO).&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;On questions such as censorship, community feedback, and algorithmic transparency, we think we can do better from the get-go. Unlike other search engines, we believe that the only way to make big improvements is to build afresh, with the know-how that comes from building,&#8221; he added. &#8220;The option of using Bing (as other search offerings do) instead of building the index exists but it will get you only as far as Bing in terms of quality (and as with such offerings, you’ll be wholly dependent on Bing).&#8221;</p>
<p>Brave is aiming for general availability of Brave Search by the summer &#8212; if not late spring, per Eich. Users interested in testing an early iteration can sign up for a <a href="http://brave.com/search">waitlist here</a>. (A test version is slated as coming in &#8220;the next few weeks&#8221;.)</p>
<p>The name Tailcat is unlikely to be widely familiar as it was an internal project that Cliqz had not implemented into its browser before it was shut down.</p>
<p>Eich says development had been continuing at Burda &#8212; &#8220;in order to develop a full-fledged search engine&#8221;. (When the holding company a<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">nnounced the shuttering of Cliqz, </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.burda.com/en/news/cliqz-closes-areas-browser-and-search-technologies/">last April</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, it stated that Cliqz&#8217;s browser and search technologies would be shut down but also said it would draw out a team of experts &#8212; to work on technical issues in areas like AI and search.)</span></p>
<p>&#8220;Cliqz offered the SERP-based search engine but had not implemented Tailcat in its browser yet,&#8221; said Eich. &#8220;After Cliqz shut down last April, a development team at Burda continued to work on the search technology under the new project name Tailcat in order to develop a full-fledged search engine. The team hoped to find a long-term home for their work to continue their mission, and are thrilled to be part of Brave.&#8221;</p>
<p>The financial terms of the acquisition are not being disclosed &#8212; but we&#8217;ve confirmed that Burda is becoming a Brave shareholder as part of the deal.</p>
<p>“We are very happy that our technology is being used at Brave and that, as a result, a <u></u><u></u>genuine, privacy-friendly alternative to Google is being created in the core web <u></u><u></u>functions of browsing and searching,” said Paul-Bernhard Kallen, CEO of Hubert Burda Media, in a supporting statement. “As a Brave stakeholder we will continue to be involved in this exciting project.”</p>
<p>While Brave started out focused on building an alternative browser &#8212; with the idea of rethinking the predominate ad-funded Internet business model by baking in a cryptocurrency rewards system to generate payments for content creators (and pay users for their attention) &#8212; it now talks about itself as a pro-privacy &#8220;super app&#8221;.</p>
<p>Currently, the Brave Browser bundles a privacy-preserving ad platform (<a href="https://brave.com/brave-ads/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://brave.com/brave-ads/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1614762976261000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFDcbQpFf8g4R6rFI_PNQzxTSX6Xw">Brave Ads</a>); news reader (<a href="https://brave.com/announcing-brave-today/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://brave.com/announcing-brave-today/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1614762976261000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEP8PfxyjoONyl1WWCwP2Kobv6hIA">Brave Today</a>); and offers a <a href="https://brave.com/brave-and-guardian/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://brave.com/brave-and-guardian/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1614762976261000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFXFbjYtVmgW1GlCTqqRiX7lVFRZg">Firewall+VPN service</a> &#8212; which it will be further adding to with the forthcoming search engine (<a href="http://brave.com/search">Brave Search</a>), and a privacy-preserving video-conferencing service (<a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/brave-together">Brave Together</a>) that&#8217;s also in the pipeline.</p>
<p>The unifying brand proposition for its &#8216;super app&#8217; is a pledge to provide users with genuine control over their online experience &#8212; in contrast to mainstream alternatives.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UtDcKOiMqL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/signal-brian-acton-talks-about-exploding-growth-monetization-and-whatsapp-data-sharing-outrage/">Signal’s Brian Acton talks about exploding growth, monetization and WhatsApp data-sharing outrage</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Signal’s Brian Acton talks about exploding growth, monetization and WhatsApp data-sharing outrage&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/signal-brian-acton-talks-about-exploding-growth-monetization-and-whatsapp-data-sharing-outrage/embed/#?secret=UtDcKOiMqL" data-secret="UtDcKOiMqL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MBan5ynRc4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/13/brave-launches-version-1-0-of-its-privacy-focused-browser/">Brave launches version 1.0 of its privacy-focused browser</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Brave launches version 1.0 of its privacy-focused browser&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/13/brave-launches-version-1-0-of-its-privacy-focused-browser/embed/#?secret=MBan5ynRc4" data-secret="MBan5ynRc4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/brave-is-launching-its-own-search-engine-with-the-help-of-ex-cliqz-devs-and-tech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119503</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scarf helps open-source developers track how their projects are being used</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/scarf-helps-open-source-developers-track-how-their-projects-are-being-used/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/scarf-helps-open-source-developers-track-how-their-projects-are-being-used/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 14:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Docker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitHub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[npm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming languages]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scarf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wave Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2120100</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Almost by default, open-source developers get very little insight into who uses their projects. In part, that&#8217;s the beauty of open source, but for developers who want to monetize their projects, it&#8217;s also a bit of a curse because they get very little data back from these projects. While you usually know who bought your [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Almost by default, open-source developers get very little insight into who uses their projects. In part, that&#8217;s the beauty of open source, but for developers who want to monetize their projects, it&#8217;s also a bit of a curse because they get very little data back from these projects. While you usually know who bought your proprietary software &#8212; and those tools often send back some telemetry, too &#8212; that&#8217;s not something that holds true for open-source code. <a href="https://about.scarf.sh/">Scarf</a> is trying to change that.</p>
<p>In its earliest incarnation, Scarf founder Avi Press tried to go the telemetry route for getting this kind of data. He had written a few successful developer tools and as they got more popular, he realized that he was spending an increasingly large amount of time supporting his users.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2120117" style="width: 361px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PXL_20210217_204403624.MP_2-1.jpeg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2120117" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2120117" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PXL_20210217_204403624.MP_2-1.jpeg" alt="Scarf founder Avi Press" width="351" height="423" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PXL_20210217_204403624.MP_2-1.jpeg 480w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PXL_20210217_204403624.MP_2-1.jpeg?resize=124,150 124w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PXL_20210217_204403624.MP_2-1.jpeg?resize=249,300 249w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PXL_20210217_204403624.MP_2-1.jpeg?resize=41,50 41w" sizes="(max-width: 351px) 100vw, 351px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2120117" class="wp-caption-text">Scarf co-founder and CEO Avi Press (<strong>Image Credits:</strong> Scarf)</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;This project was now really sapping my time and energy, but also clearly providing value to big companies,&#8221; he said. &#8220;And that&#8217;s really what got me thinking that there&#8217;s probably an opportunity to maybe provide support or build features just for these companies, or do something to try to make some money from that, or really just better support those commercial users.&#8221; But he also quickly realized that he had virtually no data about how the project was being used beyond what people told him directly and download stats from GitHub and other places. So as he tried to monetize the project, he had very little data to inform his decisions and he had no way of knowing which companies to target directly that were already quietly using his code.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you were working at any old company &#8212; pushing code out to an app or a website &#8212; if you pushed out code without any observability, that would be reckless. You would you get fired over something like that. Or maybe not, but it&#8217;s a really poor decision to make. And this is the norm for every domain of software &#8212; except open source.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2120118" style="width: 490px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-02-25-at-4.01.10-PM-1.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2120118" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2120118 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-02-25-at-4.01.10-PM-1.png" alt="" width="480" height="504" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-02-25-at-4.01.10-PM-1.png 480w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-02-25-at-4.01.10-PM-1.png?resize=143,150 143w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-02-25-at-4.01.10-PM-1.png?resize=286,300 286w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screen-Shot-2021-02-25-at-4.01.10-PM-1.png?resize=48,50 48w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 100vw, 480px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2120118" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Scarf</p></div></p>
<p>That led to the first version of Scarf: a package manager that would provide usage analytics and make it easy to sell different versions of a project. But that wasn&#8217;t quite something <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20768365">the community</a> was ready to accept &#8212; and a lot of people questioned the open-source nature of the project.</p>
<p>&#8220;What really came out of those conversations, even chatting with people who were really, really against this kind of approach &#8212; everyone agrees that the package registries already have all of this data. So NPM and Docker and all these companies that have this data &#8212; there are many, many requests of developers for this data,&#8221; Press said, and noted that there is obviously a lot of value in this data.</p>
<p>So the new Scarf now takes a more sophisticated approach. While it still offers an NPM library that does phone home and pixel tracking for documentation, its focus is now on registries. What the company is essentially launching this week is a kind of middle layer between the code and the registry that allows developers to, for example, point users of their containers to the Scarf registry first and then Scarf sits in front of the Docker Hub or the GitHub Container Registry.</p>
<p>&#8220;You tell us, where are your containers located? And then your users pull the image through Scarf and Scarf just redirects the traffic to wherever it needs to go. But then all the traffic that flows through Scarf, we can expose that to the maintainers. What company did that pull come from? Was it on a laptop or on CI? What cloud provider was it on? What container runtime was it using? What version of the software did they pull down? And all of these things that are actually pretty trivial to answer from this traffic &#8212; and the registries could have been doing this whole time but unfortunately have not done so.&#8221;</p>
<p>To fund its efforts, Scarf recently raised a $2 million seed funding round led by <a href="http://wave.capital/">Wave Capital</a>, with participation from 468 Capital and a number of angel investors.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/KyX1_cBvmCA?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/scarf-helps-open-source-developers-track-how-their-projects-are-being-used/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2120100</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
