<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 16:50:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Following its acquisition by BuzzFeed, HuffPost shuts down its Brazil and India editions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/huffpost-india-brasil-shutdown/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/huffpost-india-brasil-shutdown/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 16:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buzzfeed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HuffPost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verizon Media]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[HuffPost is becoming part of BuzzFeed, but HuffPost India and HuffPost Brasil will not be making the transition — both sites are shutting down today. &#8220;Today is @huffpostIndia’s last day,&#8221; tweeted the team&#8217;s editor in chief Aman Sethi. &#8220;Pound for pound, story for story, reporter for reporter, this is the greatest newsroom I have worked [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/huffingtonpost" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="huffingtonpost">HuffPost <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is becoming part of <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/buzzfeed" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="buzzfeed">BuzzFeed, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> but <a href="https://www.huffingtonpost.in">HuffPost India</a> and <a href="https://www.huffpostbrasil.com">HuffPost Brasil</a> will not be making the transition — both sites are shutting down today.</p>
<p>&#8220;Today is @huffpostIndia’s last day,&#8221; <a href="https://twitter.com/Amannama/status/1331220841019830276">tweeted</a> the team&#8217;s editor in chief Aman Sethi. &#8220;Pound for pound, story for story, reporter for reporter, this is the greatest newsroom I have worked for; (and I still can’t quite believe I had the privilege to lead)[.] Thank you everyone for reading our stories and supporting our journalism.&#8221;</p>
<p>Last week, BuzzFeed announced that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/buzzfeed-acquires-huffpost/">it was acquiring HuffPost</a> as part of a broader deal with Verizon Media (which also owns TechCrunch). As part of the deal, the companies will be collaborating on content syndication and advertising.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Wc6X0n6Sda"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/buzzfeed-acquires-huffpost/">BuzzFeed acquires HuffPost</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BuzzFeed acquires HuffPost&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/buzzfeed-acquires-huffpost/embed/#?secret=Wc6X0n6Sda" data-secret="Wc6X0n6Sda" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;We confirm that HuffPost has closed its editions in India and Brazil with immediate effect,&#8221; <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/verizon-media" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="verizon-media">Verizon Media <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> said in a statement. &#8220;We would like to thank the HuffPost India and HuffPost Brazil teams for their hard work and contribution to the organization.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Daily Beast&#8217;s Maxwell Tani <a href="https://twitter.com/maxwelltani/status/1331271820809482242">tweeted</a> what appeared to be an internal comment from BuzzFeed CEO Jonah Peretti, who said that the company wasn&#8217;t &#8220;legally allowed to take on the Brazil and India editions&#8221; — he claimed that &#8220;foreign companies aren&#8217;t allowed to own news organizations&#8221; in India, while BuzzFeed cannot operate in Brazil as one of the conditions of selling BuzzFeed Brasil.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">As part of the HuffPost acquisition, the site&#39;s Brazil and India editions have shuttered. Responding to a message in Slack, <a href="https://twitter.com/peretti?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@peretti</a> addressed the closures. <a href="https://t.co/UYKF9UVuKz">https://t.co/UYKF9UVuKz</a> <a href="https://t.co/giv9o60LFo">pic.twitter.com/giv9o60LFo</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Max Tani (@maxwelltani) <a href="https://twitter.com/maxwelltani/status/1331271820809482242?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 24, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/huffpost-india-brasil-shutdown/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078183</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fortnite adds a $12 monthly subscription bundle</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/fortnite-adds-a-12-monthly-subscription-bundle/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/fortnite-adds-a-12-monthly-subscription-bundle/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 16:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Epic Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fortnite]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078179</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fortnite’s free to play model has no doubt been a big driver in the battle royale title’s stratospheric success. Epic clearly hasn’t had much issue monetizing the game. While revenue slipped last year, it still managed to pull in a massive windfall of $1.8 billion (down from an even more staggering $2.4 billion). The company [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Fortnite’s free to play model has no doubt been a big driver in the battle royale title’s stratospheric success. Epic clearly hasn’t had much issue monetizing the game. While revenue slipped last year, it still managed to pull in a massive windfall of $1.8 billion (down from an even more staggering $2.4 billion).</p>
<p>The company has had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/26/epic-games-the-creator-of-fortnite-raises-1-25-billion/">no shortage of investments</a>, though it could always use some extra cash for&#8230;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/epic-games-founder-tim-sweeney-likens-fight-against-apple-to-fight-for-civil-rights/">reasons</a>.</p>
<p>Today, the publisher announced a new model designed to deliver reoccurring payments, in addition to its standard micro transactions — offering up a discount on some of its virtual wares in the process.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The $11.99 monthly Fortnite Crew fee entitles players to a full season battle pass, 1,000 monthly bucks and a Crew Pack featuring an exclusive outfit bundle. The monthly fee adds up — as monthly fees do. It’s certainly significantly pricier than just going in for the standard battle pass, which runs a couple of bucks less and generally lasts a few months or so. Ditto for a 1,000 V-Bucks, which run around $8.</p>
<p>The plan will launch December 2, along Chapter 2, Season 5 of the game. The first pack includes a Galaxia outfit. It’s a space-themed suit that also includes a unicorn-head pickaxe. Content from popular properties like the Star Wars series &#8220;The Mandalorian&#8221; may also be on the horizon, as well. Certainly exclusive access to well-known IP would go a ways toward sweetening the appeal of yet another monthly subscription.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="p44FdMzaT7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/epic-games-founder-tim-sweeney-likens-fight-against-apple-to-fight-for-civil-rights/">Epic Games founder Tim Sweeney likens fight against Apple to fight for civil rights</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Epic Games founder Tim Sweeney likens fight against Apple to fight for civil rights&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/epic-games-founder-tim-sweeney-likens-fight-against-apple-to-fight-for-civil-rights/embed/#?secret=p44FdMzaT7" data-secret="p44FdMzaT7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/fortnite-adds-a-12-monthly-subscription-bundle/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078179</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tesla is now worth half a trillion dollars</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/tesla-is-now-worth-half-a-trillion-dollars/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/tesla-is-now-worth-half-a-trillion-dollars/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 16:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078158</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Surging Tesla shares have pushed the company&#8217;s market capitalization to more than $515 billion, a fivefold increase since the start of the year. The traditionally volatile stock has continued to experience price swings. But since reaching a low for the year in March, Tesla&#8217;s share price has been on an upwards trajectory that accelerated in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Surging <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/tesla-motors" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="tesla-motors">Tesla <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> shares have pushed the company&#8217;s market capitalization to more than $515 billion, a fivefold increase since the start of the year.</p>
<p>The traditionally volatile stock has continued to experience price swings. But since reaching a low for the year in March, Tesla&#8217;s share price has been on an upwards trajectory that accelerated in August. Tesla&#8217;s share price, which rose 4.6% in morning trading to $545.62, has helped blast its CEO Elon Musk into the upper stratosphere of <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/billionaires/?sref=AwwRcx4b">Bloomberg&#8217;s Billionaire Index</a>. As of Tuesday, Musk&#8217;s net worth had risen $7.24 billion to more than $128 billion. Only Amazon&#8217;s Jeff Bezos stands in his way to becoming the world&#8217;s wealthiest person.</p>
<p>Tesla shares have been fueled over the past week by news that it will be added to the S&amp;P 500 index in December. Since Friday, the company has added more than $52 billion to its market cap — the equivalent of adding nearly one and a half Ford Motor Co., to its valuation.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The S&amp;P Dow Jones Indices announced November 16 that Tesla will officially join the benchmark index prior to trading December 21, putting the electric automaker in the same company as heavyweights like Apple, Berkshire Hathaway and Microsoft.</p>
<p>When Tesla joins the S&amp;P 500, it will be among the most valuable companies on the benchmark. Its weighting will be so influential that the S&amp;P DJI is mulling whether to add the stock at the full float-adjusted market capitalization weight all at once or in two tranches.</p>
<p>Tesla&#8217;s addition to the S&amp;P 500 isn&#8217;t just a symbolic nod. Joining the S&amp;P 500 has real financial benefits, as investors that have index-tracked funds will be forced to buy shares. With share prices already popping, that will mean investors will have to sell other stocks to make room for Tesla.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/tesla-is-now-worth-half-a-trillion-dollars/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078158</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>HMBradley raises $18.25 million planting a flag as LA&#8217;s entrant into the challenger bank business</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/hmbradley-raises-18-25-million-planting-a-flag-as-las-entrant-into-the-challenger-bank-business/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/hmbradley-raises-18-25-million-planting-a-flag-as-las-entrant-into-the-challenger-bank-business/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 15:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HMBradley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ing group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078123</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With $90 million in deposits and $18.25 million in new financing, HMBradley is making moves as the Los Angeles-based entrant into the challenger bank competition. LA is home to a growing community of financial services startups and HMBradley is quickly taking its place among the leaders with a novel twist on the banking business. Unlike [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With $90 million in deposits and $18.25 million in new financing, <a href="https://www.hmbradley.com/">HMBradley</a> is making moves as the Los Angeles-based entrant into the challenger bank competition.</p>
<p>LA is home to a growing community of financial services startups and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/hmbradley" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="hmbradley">HMBradley <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is quickly taking its place among the leaders with a novel twist on the banking business.</p>
<p>Unlike most banking startups that woo customers with easy credit and savvy online user interfaces, HMBradley is pitching a better savings account.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company offers up to 3% interest on its savings accounts, much higher than most banks these days, and it&#8217;s that pitch that has won over consumers and investors alike, according to the company&#8217;s co-founder and chief executive, <span style="font-weight: 400;">Zach Bruhnke. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With climbing numbers on the back of limited marketing, Bruhnke said raising the company&#8217;s latest round of financing was a breeze. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;They knew after the first call that they wanted to do it,&#8221; Brunke said of the negotiations with the venture capital firm Acrew, a venture firm whose previous exposure to fintech companies included backing the challenger bank phenomenon which is <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/chime-2" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="chime-2">Chime <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>. &#8220;It was a very different kind of fundraise for us. Our seed round was a terrible, treacherous 16-month fundraise,&#8221; Brunke said.</p>
<p>For Acrew&#8217;s part, the company actually had to call <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/chime-2" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="chime-2">Chime&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> founder to ensure that the company was okay with the venture firm backing another entrant into the banking business. Once the approval was granted, Brunke said the deal was smooth sailing.</p>
<p>Acrew, Chime, and HMBradley&#8217;s founders see enough daylight between the two business models that investing in one wouldn&#8217;t be a conflict of interest with the other. And there&#8217;s plenty of space for new entrants in the banking business, Bruhnke said. &#8220;It&#8217;s a very, very large industry as a whole,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>As the company grows its deposits, Bruhnke said there will be several ways it can leverage its capital. That includes commercial lending on the back end of HMBradley&#8217;s deposits and other financial services offerings to grow its base.</p>
<p>For now, it&#8217;s been wooing consumers with one click credit applications and the high interest rates it offers to its various tiers of savers.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;When customers hit that 3% tier they get really excited,&#8221; Bruhnke said. &#8220;If you’re saving money and you’re not saving to HMBradley then you’re losing money.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The money that HMBradley raised will be used to continue rolling out its new credit product and hiring staff. It already poached the former director of engineering at Capital One, Ben Coffman, and fintech thought leader Saira Rahman, the company said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In October, the company said, deposits doubled month-over-month and transaction volume has grown to over $110 million since it launched in April. </span></p>
<p>Since launching the company&#8217;s cash back credit card in July, HMBradley has been able to pitch customers on 3% cash back for its highest tier of savers &#8212; giving them the option to earn 3.5% on their deposits.</p>
<p>The deposit and lending capabilities the company offers are possible because of its partnership with the California-based <a href="http://hmb.to/hatch">Hatch Bank</a>, the company said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/hmbradley-raises-18-25-million-planting-a-flag-as-las-entrant-into-the-challenger-bank-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078123</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Australia&#8217;s spy agencies caught collecting COVID-19 app data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/australia-spy-agencies-covid-19-app-data/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/australia-spy-agencies-covid-19-app-data/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 15:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bluetooth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contact tracing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exposure notification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiber Optic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mass surveillance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pakistan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078137</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Australia&#8217;s intelligence agencies have been caught &#8220;incidentally&#8221; collecting data from the country&#8217;s COVIDSafe contact tracing app during the first six months of its launch, a government watchdog has found. The report, published Monday by the Australian government&#8217;s inspector general for the intelligence community, which oversees the government&#8217;s spy and eavesdropping agencies, said the app data [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Australia&#8217;s intelligence agencies have been caught &#8220;incidentally&#8221; collecting data from the country&#8217;s COVIDSafe contact tracing app during the first six months of its launch, a government watchdog has found.</p>
<p>The report, <a href="https://beta.documentcloud.org/documents/20416358-report-to-oaic-may-nov-2020-covidsafe-app#document/p2/a2005851">published Monday</a> by the Australian government&#8217;s inspector general for the intelligence community, which oversees the government&#8217;s spy and eavesdropping agencies, said the app data was scooped up &#8220;in the course of the lawful collection of other data.&#8221;</p>
<p>But the watchdog said that there was &#8220;no evidence&#8221; that any agency &#8220;decrypted, accessed or used any COVID app data.&#8221;</p>
<p>Incidental collection is a common term used by spies to describe the data that was not deliberately targeted but collected as part of a wider collection effort. This kind of collection isn&#8217;t accidental, but more of a consequence of when spy agencies tap into fiber optic cables, for example, which carries an enormous firehose of data. An Australian government spokesperson told one outlet, which <a href="https://www.itnews.com.au/news/covidsafe-data-incidentally-collected-by-intelligence-agencies-in-first-six-months-558129">first reported the news</a>, that incidental collection can also happen as a result of the &#8220;execution of warrants.&#8221;</p>
<p>The report did not say when the incidental collection stopped, but noted that the agencies were &#8220;taking active steps to ensure compliance&#8221; with the law, and that the data would be &#8220;deleted as soon as practicable,&#8221; without setting a firm date.</p>
<p>For some, fears that a government spy agency <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/07/nso-group-fleming-contact-tracing/">could access COVID-19 contact tracing data</a> was the worst possible outcome.</p>
<p>Since the start of the COVID-19 pandemic, countries — and states in places like the U.S. — have rushed to build contact tracing apps to help prevent the spread of the virus. But these apps vary wildly in terms of functionality and privacy.</p>
<p>Most have adopted the more privacy-friendly approach of using Bluetooth to trace people with the virus that you may have come into contact with. Many have chosen to implement <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/13/apple-google-coronavirus-tracing/">the Apple-Google system</a>, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/20/academics-contact-tracing/">hundreds of academics have backed</a>. But others, like Israel and Pakistan, are using more privacy invasive techniques, like <a href="https://slate.com/technology/2020/07/pakistan-isi-terrorism-surveillance-coronavirus.html">tracking location data</a>, which governments can also use to monitor a person&#8217;s whereabouts. In Israel&#8217;s case, the tracking was so controversial that the courts <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/israel-halts-controversial-coronavirus-surveillance-11591734875">shut it down</a>.</p>
<p>Australia&#8217;s intelligence watchdog did not say specifically what data was collected by the spy agencies. The app uses Bluetooth and not location data, but the app requires the user to upload some personal information — like their name, age, postal code, and phone number — to allow the government&#8217;s health department <a href="https://www.health.gov.au/resources/apps-and-tools/covidsafe-app">to contact</a> those who may have come into contact with an infected person.</p>
<p>Australia has seen more than 27,800 confirmed coronavirus cases and over 900 deaths since the start of the pandemic.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="g1hvjdW39j"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/coronavirus-albion-security-flaws-app/">Fearing coronavirus, a Michigan college is tracking its students with a flawed app</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fearing coronavirus, a Michigan college is tracking its students with a flawed app&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/coronavirus-albion-security-flaws-app/embed/#?secret=g1hvjdW39j" data-secret="g1hvjdW39j" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/australia-spy-agencies-covid-19-app-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078137</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Proxyclick visitor management system adapts to COVID as employee check-in platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/proxyclick-visitor-management-system-adapts-to-covid-as-employee-check-in-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/proxyclick-visitor-management-system-adapts-to-covid-as-employee-check-in-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 15:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Proxyclick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visitor management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078107</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Proxyclick began life by providing an easy way to manage visitors in your building with an iPad-based check-in system. As the pandemic has taken hold, however, customer requirements have changed, and Proxyclick is changing with them. Today the company announced Proxyclick Flow, a new system designed to check in employees during the time of COVID. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://proxyclick.com">Proxyclick</a> began life by providing an easy way to manage visitors in your building with an iPad-based check-in system. As the pandemic has taken hold, however, customer requirements have changed, and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/proxyclick" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="proxyclick">Proxyclick <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is changing with them. Today the company announced Proxyclick Flow, a new system designed to check in employees during the time of COVID.</p>
<p>&#8220;Basically when COVID hit our customers told us that actually our employees are the new visitors. So what you used to ask your visitors, you are now asking your employees &#8212; the usual probing question, but also when are you coming and so forth. So we evolved the offering into a wider platform,&#8221; Proxyclick co-founder and CEO Gregory Blondeau explained.</p>
<p>That means instead of managing a steady flow of visitors &#8212; although it can still do that &#8212; the company is focusing on the needs of customers who want to open their offices on a limited basis during the pandemic, based on local regulations. To help adapt the platform for this purpose, the company developed the Proovr smartphone app, which employees can use to check in prior to going to the office, complete a health checklist, see who else will be in the office and make sure the building isn&#8217;t over capacity.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bBC8XgJrUo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/22/proxyclick-raises-15m-series-b-for-its-visitor-management-platform/">Proxyclick raises $15M Series B for its visitor management platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Proxyclick raises $15M Series B for its visitor management platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/22/proxyclick-raises-15m-series-b-for-its-visitor-management-platform/embed/#?secret=bBC8XgJrUo" data-secret="bBC8XgJrUo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>When the employee arrives at the office, they get a temperature check, and then can use the QR code issued by the Proovr app to enter the building via Proxyclick&#8217;s check-in system or whatever system they have in place. Beyond the mobile app, the company has designed the system to work with a number of adjacent building management and security systems so that customers can use it in conjunction with existing tooling.</p>
<p>They also beefed up the workflow engine that companies can adapt based on their own unique entrance and exit requirements. The COVID workflow is simply one of those workflows, but Blondeau recognizes not everyone will want to use the exact one they have provided out of the box, so they designed a flexible system.</p>
<p>&#8220;So the challenge was technical on one side to integrate all the systems, and afterwards to group workflows on the employee&#8217;s smartphone, so that each organization can define its own workflow and present it on the smartphone,&#8221; Blondeau said.</p>
<p>Once in the building, the systems registers your presence and the information remains on the system for two weeks for contact tracing purposes should there be an exposure to COVID. You check out when you leave the building, but if you forget, it automatically checks you out at midnight.</p>
<p>The company was founded in 2010 and has raised $19.6 million. The most recent raise <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/22/proxyclick-raises-15m-series-b-for-its-visitor-management-platform/">was a $18.5 million Series B</a> in January.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/proxyclick-visitor-management-system-adapts-to-covid-as-employee-check-in-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078107</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mobile banking app Current raises $131M Series C, tops 2 million members</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/mobile-banking-app-current-raises-131m-series-c-tops-2-million-members/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/mobile-banking-app-current-raises-131m-series-c-tops-2-million-members/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 15:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[challenger bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Current]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078083</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[U.S. challenger bank Current, which has doubled its member base in less than six months, announced this morning it raised $131 million in Series C funding, led by Tiger Global Management. The additional financing brings Current to over $180 million in total funding to date, and gives the company a valuation of $750 million. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">U.S. challenger bank <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/current-6" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="current-6">Current, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> which has doubled its member base in less than six months, <a href="https://current.com/blog/current-announces-131-million-in-series-c-funding-surpasses-2-million-members/">announced</a> this morning it raised $131 million in Series C funding, led by Tiger Global Management. The additional financing brings Current to over $180 million in total funding to date, and gives the company a valuation of $750 million.</p>
<p>The round also brought in new investors, Sapphire Ventures and Avenir. Existing investors returned for the Series C, as well, including Foundation Capital, Wellington Management Company and QED.</p>
<p>Current had originally <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/05/09/current-launches-a-visa-debit-card-for-kids-that-parents-control-with-an-app/">began</a> as a teen debit card controlled by parents, but expanded to offer personal checking accounts last year, using the same underlying banking technology. The service today competes with a range of mobile banking apps, offering features like free overdrafts, no minimum balance requirements, faster direct deposits, instant spending notifications, banking insights, check deposits using your phone&#8217;s camera, and other now-standard baseline features for challenger banks.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In August 2020, Current <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/04/mobile-bank-current-launches-a-points-rewards-program-for-debit-card-users/">debuted a points rewards program</a> in an effort to better differentiate its service from the competition, which as of this month <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/google-pay-gets-a-major-redesign/">now includes Google Pay. </a></p>
<p>When Current <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/24/mobile-banking-app-current-raises-20m-series-b-tops-half-a-million-users/">raised its Series B last fall</a>, it had over 500,000 accounts on its service. Today, it touts over 2 million members. Revenue has also grown, increasing by 500% year-over-year, the company noted today.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have seen a demonstrated need for access to affordable banking with a best-in-class mobile solution that Current is uniquely suited to provide,&#8221; said Current founder and CEO Stuart Sopp, in a statement about the fundraise. &#8220;We are committed to building products specifically to improve the financial outcomes of the millions of hard-working Americans who live paycheck to paycheck, and whose needs are not being properly served by traditional banks. With this new round of funding we will continue to expand on our mission, growth and innovation to find more ways to get members their money faster, help them spend it smarter and help close the financial inequality gap,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>The additional funds will be used to further develop and expand Current&#8217;s mobile banking offerings, the company says.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/mobile-banking-app-current-raises-131m-series-c-tops-2-million-members/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078083</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 new $100M ARR club members and a call for the next generation of growth-stage startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/three-new-100m-arr-club-members-and-a-call-for-the-next-generation-of-growth-stage-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/three-new-100m-arr-club-members-and-a-call-for-the-next-generation-of-growth-stage-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 15:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[udemy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usertesting]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077734</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Time flies. It was nearly a year ago that The Exchange started keeping tabs on startups that managed to reach $100 million in annual recurring revenue, or ARR. Our goal was to determine which unicorns were more than paper horses so we could keep tabs on upcoming IPO targets. We found that Bill.com, Asana, WalkMe [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Time flies.</p>
<p>It was nearly a year ago that <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/army-air-force-exchange-service" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="army-air-force-exchange-service">The Exchange <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/10/the-100m-arr-club/">started keeping tabs</a> on startups that managed to reach $100 million in annual recurring revenue, or ARR. Our goal was to determine which unicorns were more than paper horses so we could keep tabs on upcoming IPO targets.</p>
<p>We found that Bill.com, Asana, WalkMe and Druva were impressively large and growing nicely. Since then two of the four companies from that post have gone public.</p>
<p>GitLab, Egnyte, Braze and O’Reilly Media <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/13/the-newest-members-of-the-100m-arr-club/">joined the club before 2019 was even closed</a>, with two of those companies taking part in the recent Disrupt conference, talking about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/23/scaling-to-100-million-arr-3-founders-share-their-insights/">how they managed their historical growth</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995210 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>In early 2020 we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/02/kicking-off-2020-with-4-new-members-of-the-100m-arr-club/">added Sisense, Siteminder, Monday.com and Lemonade to the club</a>, wrote about ExtraHop&#8217;s<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/14/seattles-extrahop-expects-100m-arr-in-2020-ipo/"> path to $100 million ARR</a>, Cloudinary&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/cloudinary-passes-60m-arr-without-vc-money/">epic growth sans external capital</a>, Siteminder&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/16/siteminder-raises-70m-at-750m-valuation-after-cresting-70m-arr-in-2019/">own records</a> and BounceX reaching <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/25/new-yorks-bouncex-reaches-100m-arr-rebrands/">$100 million ARR while it rebranded to Wunderkind</a>.</p>
<p>As the year rolled along, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/22/the-100m-arr-club-welcomes-four-new-members/">MetroMile, Tricentis, Kaltura and Diligent joined the club</a>. As did <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/13/adding-three-more-companies-to-the-100m-arr-club/">Recorded Future, ON24 and ActiveCampaign</a>. There were even more names: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/13/as-5-more-startups-join-the-100m-club-are-we-just-making-a-pre-ipo-list/">Movable Ink, Noom, Riskified, Seismic, ThoughtSpot,</a> along with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/03/as-q3-kicks-off-four-more-companies-join-the-100m-arr-club/">Snow Software, A Cloud Guru, Zeta Global and Upgrade</a>.</p>
<p>Today we have three more names to add to the group: <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/usertesting-com" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="usertesting-com">UserTesting, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/udemy" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="udemy">Udemy&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> business arm, and Expensify. But, more than merely adding those companies to the mix &#8212; more after the jump &#8212; I wanted to shake up our radar a bit as we head into 2021.</p>
<p>Yes, The Exchange will keep tabs on startups and other private companies that reach $100 million in ARR, or annual run rate, as the case may be. But next year we <em>also</em> want to find the startups around $50 million ARR that are growing like hell. We want to go a year or two earlier in growth histories to better watch how startups scale <em>into</em> nine-figure revenues, instead of hearing about it after the fact.</p>
<p>So, if you are a startup that is expanding aggressively and will reach the $50 million revenue mark inside the next quarter or two, <a href="mailto:alex.wilhelm@techcrunch.com">please say hello</a>. I suspect a good cut of the global unicorn market could fit this bill, and therefore might provide a window into which highly-valued startups are growing into their valuations.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a>, or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>It&#8217;s going to be fun. Now, let&#8217;s quickly chat about the latest members of the $100 million ARR club.</p>
<h2>UserTesting, Expensify and Udemy&#8217;s business arm</h2>
<p>You&#8217;ve heard of each of our $100 million ARR companies this morning, so there&#8217;s less need for prelude and introduction. Here&#8217;s the group:</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.expensify.com/">Expensify</a></strong></p>
<p>Expensify is an expense-tracking company well-known around the technology world, so it&#8217;s no real surprise that it <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20201123005455/en/Expensify-Surpasses-100-Million-Annual-Recurring-Revenue">has reached</a> the $100 million ARR threshold, a feat it announced yesterday.</p>
<p>But the company did us one better than merely dropping a single data point and racing back into the shadows. Instead, Expensify also disclosed that it has &#8220;maintained profitability for years [and] recorded its highest monthly revenue ever in October.&#8221;<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/three-new-100m-arr-club-members-and-a-call-for-the-next-generation-of-growth-stage-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077734</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>F3, a Stories-style Q&#038;A app for Gen Z teens, raises $3.9M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/f3-a-stories-style-qa-app-targeting-gen-z-teens-raises-3-9m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/f3-a-stories-style-qa-app-targeting-gen-z-teens-raises-3-9m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 15:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[F3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generation z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Q&A app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social apps]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077544</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[F3, an anonymous Q&#38;A app targeting Gen Z teens which blends a Tinder-style swipe-to-friend gamification mechanic, Stories-esque rich media responses and eye-wateringly expensive subscriptions to unlock a &#8216;Plus&#8217; version that actually lets you see who wants to friend you &#8212; has raised a $3.9M seed round, including for a planned push on the US market. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://f3.cool">F3</a>, an anonymous Q&amp;A app targeting Gen Z teens which blends a Tinder-style swipe-to-friend gamification mechanic, Stories-esque rich media responses and eye-wateringly expensive subscriptions to unlock a &#8216;Plus&#8217; version that actually lets you see who wants to friend you &#8212; has raised a $3.9M seed round, including for a planned push on the US market.</p>
<p>The Latvian team behind F3 are not new to the viral teen app game having founded the anonymous teen Q&amp;A app Ask.fm &#8212; which faced huge controversy back in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/08/19/ask-fm-safety-policy/">2013</a> over bullying and safety concerns after being linked to a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/08/12/in-wake-of-teen-suicides-ask-fm-faces-a-myspace-problem/?_ga=2.51446573.582495266.1606121626-1757155993.1533833482">number of suicides of users</a> who&#8217;d received abusive messages. Not that they&#8217;ve let that put them off the viral teen app space, clearly.</p>
<p>Investors in F3&#8217;s seed round hail from the Russian dating network Mamba (including the latter&#8217;s investor, Mail.ru Group) and a co-investor VC firm with a marketing focus, called <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/ad-ru">AdFirst</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Alex Hofmann (former <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/02/musically-tiktok/">musical.ly</a> president) and Marat Kichikov (GP at Bitfury Capital) are also named as being among those joining the round as angel investors.</p>
<p>F3, which launched its apps in 2018, has 25M registered users at this point &#8212; 85% of whom are younger than 25.</p>
<p>The typical user is a (bored) teenager, with the user base being reported as 65% female and 60% Europe / 20% LatAm / 20% Rest of World at this point. (They&#8217;re not breaking out any active user metrics but claim 80% of users have been on the app for more than three months at this point.)</p>
<p>On the safety front, F3 is using both automated tools and people for content moderation &#8212; with the founders claiming to have learnt lessons from their past experience with Ask.fm (which got acquired by IAC&#8217;s Ask.com back in <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/askcom-acquires-largest-global-qa-social-network-askfm-271234091.html">2014</a>, given them the funds to plough into F3&#8217;s development up to now).</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve been solving problem of violating content in our previous company (Ask.fm), and now at F3 we&#8217;ve used all our knowledge of solving this problem from day one. Automation tools include text analysis in all major languages with database of 250k+ patterns that is continuously being improved, and AI based image recognition algorithms for detecting violating content in photos and videos,&#8221; says the founding team &#8212; which includes CEO Ilja Terebin.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our 24/7 content moderation team (8 in-house safety experts and 30+ outsourced contractors) manually reviews user reports and items flagged by automation tools,&#8221; they add.</p>
<p>However reviews of the app that we saw included complaints from users who said they&#8217;ve being pestered by &#8216;pedophiles&#8217; asking for nudes &#8212; so claims of safety risks being &#8220;solved&#8221; seem riskily overblown.</p>
<p>Why do teens need yet another social discovery/messaging app? On that Terebin &amp; team say the app has been tailored for Gen Z from the get-go &#8212; &#8220;focusing on their needs to socialize and make new friends online, &#8216;quick&#8217; content in the form of photos and short videos, which is true and personal&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;Raw &amp; real&#8221; is another of their teen-friendly product market fit claims.</p>
<p>F3 users get a personalized URL that they can share to other social networks to solicit questions from their friends &#8212; which can be asked anonymously or not. (F3 users can also choose not to accept anonymous questions if they prefer.)</p>
<p>Instead of plain text answers users snap a photo or grab a short video, add filters, fancy fonts and backgrounds, and so on to reply in a rich-media Stories-style that&#8217;s infiltrated all social networking apps (most recently infecting Twitter, where it&#8217;s called <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/04/twitter-starts-testing-its-own-version-of-stories-called-fleets-which-disappear-after-24-hours/">Fleets</a>).</p>
<p>These rich media responses get made public on their feed &#8212; so if an F3 user chooses to answer a question they&#8217;re also engaging with the wider community by default (though they can choose not to respond as questions remain private until responded to).</p>
<p>Asked how F3 stands out in a very packed and competitive social media landscape, they argue the app&#8217;s &#8220;uniqueness&#8221; is that the Q&amp;A is photo and video based &#8212; &#8220;so the format is familiar and close to other social networks (&#8216;stories&#8217; or &#8216;snaps&#8217;) but in a Q&amp;A style back-and-forth communication&#8221;, as they put it, adding that for their Gen Z target &#8220;the outdated text-based Q&amp;A just was too boring&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;We compete for eyeballs of Gen Z with Snapchat, TikTok and Instagram. Our key strength is that through the Q&amp;A format one can make new friends and truly get to know other people on a personal level through the prism of &#8216;raw and real&#8217; content, which is not central on any of those platforms,&#8221; they also claim.</p>
<p>In terms of most similar competitors, they note <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/08/download-yolo-app/">Yolo</a> has seen &#8220;some traction&#8221; and concede there are a bunch of others also offering Q&amp;A. But here they argue F3 is more fully featured than rivals &#8212; suggesting the Q&amp;A feature is just the viral hook to get users into a wider community net.</p>
<p>&#8220;[F3] is a fully functional social platform, built around visual communication &#8212; users have content feed where they can view posts by people they follow, they can create photo/video content using editing tools in the app itself, there&#8217;s a messenger functionality for direct chats, follow-ships, content and user discovery. So for us, the anonymous messaging/Q&amp;A format is just an entry point which allows us to grow quickly and get the users on our platform, but then they make new connections and keep engaging with their unique social circle they have only on F3, making it a sustainable stand-alone social network.&#8221;</p>
<p>Again, though, user reviews tell more of a raw (and real?) story &#8212; with plenty of complaints that there&#8217;s little value in the free version of the app (while F3 Plus costs $3.99 for 7 days; $8.99 for 1 month or $19.99 for 3 months), and questions over the authenticity of some anonymous questions, as well as complaints that other users they&#8217;re able to meet aren&#8217;t nearby and/or don&#8217;t speak the same language. Other reviews aren&#8217;t wowed by more of the  same Q&amp;A format. Others complain the app just feels like a data grab. (And the F3 &#8216;<a href="https://about.f3.cool/privacy.en_US">privacy policy</a>&#8216; definitely has a detailed story to unfold vis-a-vis the tracking users are agreeing to, for anyone who bothers to dig in and read it.)</p>
<p>&#8220;This whole app is literally just like all the other apps. Just another copy cat that you still have to pay for,&#8221; runs one review from July 2020. &#8220;Don&#8217;t download.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/f3-a-stories-style-qa-app-targeting-gen-z-teens-raises-3-9m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077544</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Altana raises $7M to protect supply chains from disruptions, child labor</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/altana-raises-7m-to-protect-supply-chains-from-disruptions-child-labor/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/altana-raises-7m-to-protect-supply-chains-from-disruptions-child-labor/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 14:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amadeus Capital Partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077440</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Supply chains used to be one of those magical elements of capitalism that seemed to be designed by Apple: they just worked. Minus the occasional salmonella outbreak in your vegetable aisle, we could go about our daily consumer lives never really questioning how our fast-fashion clothes, tech gadgets, and medical supplies actually got to our [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Supply chains used to be one of those magical elements of capitalism that seemed to be designed by Apple: they just worked. Minus the occasional salmonella outbreak in your vegetable aisle, we could go about our daily consumer lives never really questioning how our fast-fashion clothes, tech gadgets, and medical supplies actually got to our shelves or homes.</p>
<p>Of course, a lot has changed over the past few years. Anti-globalization sentiment has grown as a political force, driving governments like the United States and the United Kingdom to renegotiate free trade agreements and attempt to onshore manufacturing while disrupting the trade status quo. Meanwhile, the COVID-19 pandemic placed huge stress on supply chains — with some entirely breaking in the process.</p>
<p>In short, supply chain managers suddenly went from one of those key functions that no one wants to think about, to one of those key functions that everyone thinks about all the time.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While these specialists have access to huge platforms from companies like Oracle and SAP, they need additional intelligence to understand where these supply chains could potentially break. Are there links in the supply chain that might be more brittle than at first glance? Are there factories in the supply chain that are on alert lists for child labor or environmental violations? What if government trade policy shifts — are we at risk of watching products sit in a cargo container at a port?</p>
<p>New York-headquartered <a href="https://altana.ai">Altana</a> wants to be that intelligence layer for supply-chain management, bringing data and machine learning to bear against the complexity of modern capitalism. Today, the company announced that it has raised $7 million in seed financing led by Anne Glover of London-based Amadeus Capital Partners.</p>
<p>The three founders of the startup, CEO Evan Smith, CTO Peter Swartz, and COO Raphael Tehranian, all worked together on <a href="https://panjiva.com">Panjiva</a>, a global supply chain platform that was founded in 2006, funded by Battery Ventures a decade ago, and <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/sp-global-set-to-acquire-panjiva-inc-300600797.html">sold to S&amp;P Global in early 2018</a>. Panjiva’s goal was to build a “graph” of supply chains that would offer intelligence to managers.</p>
<p>That direct experience informs Altana’s vision, which in many ways is the same as Panjiva’s but perhaps revamped using newer technology and data science. Again, Altana wants to build a supply-chain knowledge graph, provide intelligence to managers, and create better resilience.</p>
<p>The difference has to do with data. “What we continually found when we were in the data sales business was that you are kind of stuck in that place in the value chain,” Smith said. “Your customers won’t let you touch their data, because they don’t trust you with it, and other proprietary data companies don’t let you work on and manage and transform their data.”</p>
<p>Instead of trying to be the central repository for all data, Altana is “operating downstream” from all of these data sources, allowing companies to build their own supply chain graphs using their own data and whatever other data sources they have access to.</p>
<p>The company sells into procurement offices, which are typically managed in the CFO’s office. Today, the majority of customers for Altana are government clients such as border control, where “the task is to pick the needles out of the haystack as the ship arrives and you’ve got to pick the illicit shipments from the safe ones and actually facilitate the lawful trade,” Smith said.</p>
<p>The company’s executive chairman is Alan Bersin, who is a former commissioner of the U.S. Customs and Border Protection agency currently working as a policy consultant for Covington &amp; Burling, which has been one of the premier law firms on trade issues like CFIUS during the Trump administration.</p>
<p>Altana allows one-off investigations and simulations, but its major product goal is to offer real-time alerts that give supply chain managers substantive visibility into changes that affect their business. For instance, rather than waiting for an annual labor or environmental audit to find issues, Altana hopes to provide predictive capabilities that allow companies to solve problems much faster than before.</p>
<p>In addition to Amadeus, Schematic Ventures, AlleyCorp, and the Working Capital &#8211; The Supply Chain Investment Fund also participated.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/altana-raises-7m-to-protect-supply-chains-from-disruptions-child-labor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077440</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Two-year-old Day One Ventures raises new $52.5M fund to invest in Valley startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/two-year-old-day-one-ventures-raises-new-52-5m-fund-to-invest-in-valley-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/two-year-old-day-one-ventures-raises-new-52-5m-fund-to-invest-in-valley-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 14:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078056</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Back in 2018 Day One Ventures launched in Silicon Valley specifically designed to be both a VC and an investor that would also lead marketing and communications for its portfolio. Two years on, Day One has invested in numerous startups to do just that and has today filed with the SEC its new $52.5M fund. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/06/day-one-ventures-launches-fund-which-wraps-vc-and-pr-into-one/">Back in 2018</a> <a href="https://www.dayoneventures.com/">Day One Ventures</a> launched in Silicon Valley specifically designed to be both a VC <em>and</em> an investor that would also lead marketing and communications for its portfolio. Two years on, Day One has invested in numerous startups to do just that and has today filed with the SEC its new $52.5M fund.</p>
<p>The new fund is similar to the first one: investing across industries from pre-seed to seed, with occasional series A investments (from $100K to $5M).</p>
<p>The fund was founded and is headed by Russian émigré Masha Drokova, who, since arriving in the US a few years ago, has been variously a PR and angel investor, but <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-story-of-masha-drokova-a-putin-acolyte-turned-silicon-valley-investor-1494502202">famously dumped her former life</a> in Russia as a politician and TV reporter.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Drokova says the fund focuses on ‘day one’ companies, as defined by Jeff Bezos, which have &#8216;customer obsession&#8217; in-built into their company culture.</p>
<p>She says the fund was raised during the pandemic over zoom with $45 million coming from LPs in the first fund. More than 30% of the capital is invested in POC founders; it has 25 female founders in its portfolio; and 33% of its capital is invested in high-growth ‘impact’ companies. Day one has frequently co-invested with Andreessen, Index Ventures, Founders Fund, and Lightspeed.</p>
<p>The fund has had three exits so far: Lvl5, Acquired, Feastly and has invested in Remote.com (with Index and Sequoia).</p>
<p>So far among its portfolio is:</p>
<p>• <a href="https://donotpay.com/">DoNotPay</a>: British founder Joshua Browder, started a chatbot that pays your parking ticket, cancels subscriptions and gets refunds for you. This raised a $15M series A led by Coatue and Andreessen.<br />
• <a href="https://superhuman.com">Superhuman</a>: An AI-based email client for execs founded by Brit Rahul Vohra &#8211; it has raised $35M series B from Andreessen.<br />
• <a href="https://mschf.xyz">MSCHF</a>: This creates viral and controversial products on a Supreme-drop-like model, invested with Founders Fund.<br />
• <a href="https://www.truebill.com">Truebill</a>: a personal finance &amp; savings app.</p>
<p>The fund says its portfolio companies have now raised $825 million in aggregate; over 25% of its capital is in fintech companies; over 30% in AI-powered startups; and it claims to have hit over 500 media publications for its portfolio.</p>
<p>Speaking to TechCrunch, Drakova said &#8220;We choose startups with &#8216;customer obsession&#8217; as the main focus for selection. Secondly, our value add in communications means we have people like Jack Randall who did comms for Robin Hood on our team. Not many women immigrants to the US have raised as much as this, as fast as this. So it’s a good sign for the market.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/two-year-old-day-one-ventures-raises-new-52-5m-fund-to-invest-in-valley-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078056</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adobe expands customer data platform to include B2B sales</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/adobe-expands-customer-data-platform-to-encompass-b2b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/adobe-expands-customer-data-platform-to-encompass-b2b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 14:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[b2b sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Data Platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer experience management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078041</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The concept of the customer data platform (CDP) is a relatively new one. Up until now, it has focused primarily on pulling data about an individual consumer from a variety of channels into a super record, where in theory you can serve more meaningful content and deliver more customized experiences based on all this detailed [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The concept of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/26/adobe-and-salesforce-announce-customer-data-platforms-to-pull-data-into-single-view/">the customer data platform</a> (CDP) is a relatively new one. Up until now, it has focused primarily on pulling data about an individual consumer from a variety of channels into a super record, where in theory you can serve more meaningful content and deliver more customized experiences based on all this detailed knowledge. <a href="http://adobe.com">Adobe</a> announced its intention today to create such a product for business to business (B2B) customers, a key market where this kind of data consolidation had been missing.</p>
<p>Indeed Brian Glover, Adobe&#8217;s director of product marketing for Marketo Engage, who has been put in charge of this product, says that these kinds of sales are much more complex and B2B sales and marketing teams are clamoring for a CDP.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have spent the last couple of years integrating Marketo Engage across Adobe Experience Cloud, and now what we&#8217;re doing is building out the next generation of new and complimentary B2B offerings on the Experience platform, the first of which is the B2B CDP offering,&#8221; Glover told me.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He says that they face unique challenges adapting CDP for B2B sales because they typically involve buying groups, meaning you need to customize your messages for different people depending on their role in the process.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pBi4IP86uk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/26/adobe-and-salesforce-announce-customer-data-platforms-to-pull-data-into-single-view/">Adobe and Salesforce announce Customer Data Platforms to pull data into single view</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Adobe and Salesforce announce Customer Data Platforms to pull data into single view&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/26/adobe-and-salesforce-announce-customer-data-platforms-to-pull-data-into-single-view/embed/#?secret=pBi4IP86uk" data-secret="pBi4IP86uk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>An individual consumer usually knows what they want and you can prod them to make a decision and complete the purchase, but a B2B sale is usually longer and more complex involving different levels of procurement. For example, in a technology sale, it may involve the CIO, a group, division or department who will be using the tech, the finance department, legal and others. There may be an RFP and the sales cycle may span months or even years.</p>
<p>Adobe believes this kind of sale should still be able to use the same customized messaging approach you use in an individual sale, perhaps even more so because of the inherent complexity in the process. Yet B2B marketers face the same issues as their B2C counterparts when it comes to having data spread across an organization.</p>
<p>&#8220;In B2B that complexity of buying groups and accounts just adds another level to the data management problem because ultimately you need to be able to connect to your customer people data, but you also need to be able to connect the account data too and be able to [bring] the two together,&#8221; Glover explained.</p>
<p>By building a more complete picture of each individual in the buying cycle, you can, as Glover puts it, begin to put the bread crumbs together for the entire account. He believes that a CRM isn&#8217;t built for this kind of complexity and it requires a specialty tool like a CDP built to support B2B sales and marketing.</p>
<p>Adobe is working with early customers on the product and expects to go into beta before the end of next month with GA some time in the first half of next year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3F5TwTU893"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/20/adobe-gets-its-company-snaring-marketo-for-4-75-billion/">Adobe gets its company, snaring Marketo for $4.75 billion</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Adobe gets its company, snaring Marketo for $4.75 billion&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/20/adobe-gets-its-company-snaring-marketo-for-4-75-billion/embed/#?secret=3F5TwTU893" data-secret="3F5TwTU893" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/adobe-expands-customer-data-platform-to-encompass-b2b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078041</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India bans 43 more Chinese apps over cybersecurity concerns</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/india-bans-another-43-chinese-apps/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/india-bans-another-43-chinese-apps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 13:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PUBG Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078051</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[India is not done banning Chinese apps. The world’s second largest internet market, which has banned over 175 apps with links to the neighboring nation in recent months, said on Tuesday it was banning an additional 43 such apps. Like with the previous orders, India cited cybersecurity concerns to block these apps. “This action was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">India is not done banning Chinese apps. The world’s second largest internet market, which has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/india-bans-pubg-and-over-100-additional-chinese-apps/">banned over 175 apps with links to the neighboring nation in recent months</a>, said on Tuesday it was banning an additional 43 such apps.</p>
<p>Like with the previous orders, India <a href="https://www.pib.gov.in/PressReleasePage.aspx?PRID=1675335">cited</a> cybersecurity concerns to block these apps. “This action was taken based on the inputs regarding these apps for engaging in activities which are prejudicial to sovereignty and integrity of India, defence of India, security of state and public order,” said India’s IT Ministry in a statement.</p>
<p>The ministry said it issued the order to block these apps “based on the comprehensive reports received from Indian Cyber Crime Coordination Center, Ministry of Home Affairs.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The apps that have been banned include popular short video service Snack Video, which had surged to the top of the chart in recent months, as well as e-commerce app AliExpress, delivery app Lalamove, and shopping app Taobao Live. Full list <a href="https://www.pib.gov.in/PressReleasePage.aspx?PRID=1675335">here</a>. At this point, there doesn&#8217;t appear to be any Chinese app left in the top 500 apps used in India.</p>
<p>Tuesday order comes as a handful of apps including PUBG Mobile and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/tiktok" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="tiktok">TikTok, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> both of which identified India as their biggest overseas market, are exploring ways to make a return to the country. In recent weeks, PUBG has registered a local entity in India, partnered with Microsoft for computing needs, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/pubg-mobile-announces-return-to-india-new-game-100-million-investment/">publicly vowed to invest $100 million in the country</a>. It is yet to hear from the government, people familiar with the matter told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Tensions between the world’s two most populous nations escalated after more than 20 Indian soldiers were killed in a military clash in the Himalayas in June. Ever since, “Boycott China” sentiment has trended on social media in India as a growing number of people post videos demonstrating destruction of Chinese-made smartphones, TVs and other products.</p>
<p>In April, India also made a change to its foreign investment policy that requires Chinese investors — who have ploughed billions of dollars into Indian startups in recent years — to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/18/to-avoid-hostile-takeovers-amid-covid-19-india-mandates-approvals-on-chinese-investments/">take approval from New Delhi</a> before they could write new checks to Indian firms. The move has significantly reduced Chinese investors’ presence in Indian startups’ deal flows in the months since.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7IdE6qQpNX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/is-a-new-game-and-100m-investment-enough-for-south-koreas-pubg-to-return-to-india/">Is a new game and $100M investment enough for South Korea&#8217;s PUBG to return to India?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Is a new game and $100M investment enough for South Korea&#8217;s PUBG to return to India?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/is-a-new-game-and-100m-investment-enough-for-south-koreas-pubg-to-return-to-india/embed/#?secret=7IdE6qQpNX" data-secret="7IdE6qQpNX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/india-bans-another-43-chinese-apps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078051</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 top investors in Dutch startups discuss trends, hopes and 2020 opportunities</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/5-top-investors-in-dutch-startups-discuss-trends-hopes-and-2020-opportunities/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/5-top-investors-in-dutch-startups-discuss-trends-hopes-and-2020-opportunities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 13:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amsterdam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deep tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unicorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vc survey]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Netherlands’ ecosystem has been flourishing; more than $85 million was invested in regional startups in 2019 alone. The nation&#8217;s proximity to the U.K., Belgium, France and Germany makes Amsterdam a natural gateway to those markets. Long ago the savvy Dutch realized this, and built up Schiphol to become the world&#8217;s twelfth-busiest airport. Indeed, Amsterdam’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Netherlands’ ecosystem has been flourishing; more than $85 million was invested in regional startups in 2019 alone. The nation&#8217;s proximity to the U.K., Belgium, France and Germany makes Amsterdam a natural gateway to those markets. Long ago the savvy Dutch realized this, and built up Schiphol to become the world&#8217;s twelfth-busiest airport. Indeed, Amsterdam’s logistical and social connectedness is ranked number one in DHL’s Global Connectedness Index.</p>
<p>Plenty of good funding rounds, a highly skilled workforce and a strong entrepreneurial culture have given Amsterdam a booming startup ecosystem. And Brexit is helping: The Dutch are highly proficient in English and Dutch law is similar to English law, which means U.K.-based tech founders are welcomed with open arms.</p>
<p>In 2020, the venture industry continued to invest in startups, despite the COVID-19 crisis. According to <a href="https://nltimes.nl/2020/10/25/venture-capitalists-still-investing-startups-despite-covid-crisis">a study by KPMG and and NL Times</a>, startups raised $591.2 million in the third quarter, more than double the $252.4 million raised in the quarter before.</p>
<p>For obvious reasons, this year has seen more cash go into companies that were able to adapt to the pandemic. KPMG found that while the total amount of investment increased in the past six months, the number of overall investments decreased. New startups pulled in fewer investments, KPMG sees this trend continuing and likely leading to consolidation amongst startups in similar sectors.</p>
<p>According to a report by Dealroom.co and StartupAmsterdam, there are 1,661 tech companies in Amsterdam, while the city ranked fifteenth in Startup Genome’s 2019 report “Global Startup Ecosystem Report,” moving up four places since 2017. The median seed round is $500,000 (above the global average of $494,000) and a median Series A round for a startup is $2.4 million. The average salary for a software engineer is around €54,000.</p>
<p>Amsterdam has tech industry &#8220;schools&#8221; such as <a href="https://growthtribe.io/en/">Growth Tribe</a>, <a href="https://www.thetalentinstitute.nl/">The Talent Institute</a> and THNK for educational courses, as well as accelerators like Rockstart, Startupbootcamp and <a href="https://fashionforgood.com/">Fashion for Good</a>. Co-working is well-catered for with TQ, Startup Village and B.Amsterdam, and workers can cycle everywhere in minutes.</p>
<p>While taxes are high, entrepreneurs won&#8217;t find the staggering income inequality so often seen in cities like San Francisco and New York. In Amsterdam, rich people take public transport, not private buses.</p>
<p>During COVID-19, the Dutch government has also announced support packages such as tax deferrals, temporary employment bridging schemes and other initiatives. It also launched a national program, <a href="http://TechLeap.NL">TechLeap.NL</a>, to boost the ecosystem with more international investor visibility. StartupDelta, a Dutch startup lobby group, keeps the pressure on the politicians.</p>
<p>The Netherlands&#8217; most famous unicorns include Booking.com, Adyen, Virtuagym, MessageBird, Swapfiets, Backbase, Picnic and Takeaway, among several others.</p>
<p>Adyen launched in 2006, and in June 2018, it was listed as one of Europe’s largest tech IPOs with a value of €7 billion. Booking.com started in 1996 and was later acquired by Priceline Group (now called Booking Holdings) in 2005. Elastic, the provider of subscription-based data search software used by Dell, Netflix, The New York Times and others, was another gangbuster IPO in 2018.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">For this survey, we interviewed the following Amsterdam-focused investors:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">• Janneke Niessen, partner, </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://capitaltvc.com">CapitalT VC</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stefanvanduin">• Stefan van Duin</a>, partner, <a href="http://Borskifund.com">Borski Fund</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/nikos-kalliagkopoulos">• Nick Kalliagkopoulos</a>, partner, <a href="http://www.primeventures.com">Prime Ventures</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/bas-godska">• Bas Godska</a>, founder, <a href="http://www.acrobator.vc">Acrobator Ventures</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/renaat-berckmoes">• Renaat Berckmoes</a>, partner, <a href="https://www.fortino.be/">Fortino</a></p>
<h4></h4>
<h2>Janneke Niessen, partner, CapitalT VC</h2>
<p><strong>What trends are you most excited about investing in, generally?</strong><br />
Digital health, education, B2B SaaS.</p>
<p><strong>What’s your latest, most exciting investment?</strong><br />
Wizenoze.</p>
<p><strong>Are there startups that you wish you would see in the industry but don’t? What are some overlooked opportunities right now?</strong><br />
More overlooked founders than opportunities.</p>
<p><strong>What are you looking for in your next investment, in general?</strong><br />
A great team.</p>
<p><strong>Which areas are either oversaturated or would be too hard to compete in at this point for a new startup? What other types of products/services are you wary or concerned about?</strong><br />
Delivery, taxis, scooters.</p>
<p><strong>How much are you focused on investing in your local ecosystem versus other startup hubs (or everywhere) in general? More than 50%? Less?</strong><br />
Less.</p>
<p><strong>Which industries in your city and region seem well-positioned to thrive, or not, long term? What are companies you are excited about (your portfolio or not), which founders?</strong><br />
NL seems well-positioned for fintech, deep tech. I am really excited about Tracy Chou and Diane Janknegt, two incredible founders.</p>
<p><strong>How should investors in other cities think about the overall investment climate and opportunities in your city?</strong><br />
Very positive. Lots of innovation, great infrastructure, good talent.<br />
<strong>Do you expect to see a surge in more founders coming from geographies outside major cities in the years to come, with startup hubs losing people due to the pandemic and lingering concerns, plus the attraction of remote work?</strong><br />
I think startups have always been there, investors just don&#8217;t tend to look at them. I think the opportunity is more that they now will.</p>
<p><strong>Which industry segments that you invest in look weaker or more exposed to potential shifts in consumer and business behavior because of COVID-19? What are the opportunities startups may be able to tap into during these unprecedented times?</strong><br />
None. We look at digital health, education and SaaS and they all thrive in this climate. Of course an economic crisis will have an impact on spending in general.</p>
<p><strong>How has COVID-19 impacted your investment strategy? What are the biggest worries of the founders in your portfolio? What is your advice to startups in your portfolio right now?</strong><br />
It has confirmed our approach. We have a data-driven approach to teams, which is great when people cannot meet.</p>
<p><strong>Are you seeing “green shoots” regarding revenue growth, retention or other momentum in your portfolio as they adapt to the pandemic?</strong><br />
We invest so early that companies are growing regardless.</p>
<p><strong>What is a moment that has given you hope in the last month or so? This can be professional, personal or a mix of the two.</strong><br />
When I explained to my little boy what racism is and he answered: Mummy that is just really weird. That gives me hope that the generations after us might do better.</p>
<h2>Stefan van Duin, partner, Borski Fund<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/5-top-investors-in-dutch-startups-discuss-trends-hopes-and-2020-opportunities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077454</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Europe&#8217;s data strategy aims to tip the scales away from big tech</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/europes-data-strategy-aims-to-tip-the-scales-away-from-big-tech/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/europes-data-strategy-aims-to-tip-the-scales-away-from-big-tech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Governance Act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital Markets Act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital Services Act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EU data strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thierry-breton]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077991</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google wants to organize the world&#8217;s information but European lawmakers are in a rush to organize the local digital sphere and make Europe &#8220;the most data-empowered continent in the world&#8221;, internal market commissioner Thierry Breton said today, setting out the thinking behind the bloc&#8217;s data strategy during a livestreamed discussion organized by the Brussels-based economic think tank, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google wants to organize the world&#8217;s information but European lawmakers are in a rush to organize the local digital sphere and make Europe &#8220;the most data-empowered continent in the world&#8221;, internal market commissioner <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/thierry-breton" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="thierry-breton">Thierry Breton <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> said today, setting out the thinking behind the bloc&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/europe-sets-out-plan-to-boost-data-reuse-and-regulate-high-risk-ais/">data strategy</a> during a <a href="https://vimeo.com/481139367">livestreamed discussion</a> organized by the Brussels-based economic think tank, <a href="https://www.bruegel.org">Bruegel</a>.</p>
<p>Rebalancing big data power dynamics to tip the scales away from big tech is another stated aim.</p>
<p>Breton likened the EU&#8217;s ambitious push to encourage industrial data sharing and rebalance platform power to work done in the past to organize the region&#8217;s air space and other physical infrastructure &#8212; albeit, with a lot less time to get the job done given the blistering pace of digital innovation.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;This will require of course political vision &#8212; that we have &#8212; and willingness, that I believe we have too, and smart regulation, hopefully you will judge, to set the right rules and investment in key infrastructure,&#8221; said Breton.</p>
<p>During the talk, he gave a detailed overview of how the flotilla of legislative proposals which are being worked on by EU lawmakers will set rules intended to support European businesses and governments to safely unlock the value of industrial and public data and drive the next decades of economic growth.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have been brave enough to set our rules in the personal data sphere and this is what we need to do now for government and public and industrial data. Set the rules. The European rules. Everyone will be welcome in Europe, that&#8217;s extremely important &#8212; provided they respect our rules,&#8221; said Breton.</p>
<p>&#8220;We don&#8217;t have one minute to lose,&#8221; he added. &#8220;The battle for industrial data is starting now and the battlefield may be Europe so we need to get ready &#8212; and this is my objective.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QTF7owq2zw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/europe-sets-out-plan-to-boost-data-reuse-and-regulate-high-risk-ais/">Europe sets out plan to boost data reuse and regulate &#8216;high risk&#8217; AIs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe sets out plan to boost data reuse and regulate &#8216;high risk&#8217; AIs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/europe-sets-out-plan-to-boost-data-reuse-and-regulate-high-risk-ais/embed/#?secret=QTF7owq2zw" data-secret="QTF7owq2zw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>EU lawmakers are drafting rules for how (non-personal) data can be used and shared; who will get access to them; and how rights can be guaranteed under the framework, per Breton. And he argued that <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">concerns raised by European privacy challenges to international data transfers &#8212; reflected in the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/16/europes-top-court-strikes-down-flagship-eu-us-data-transfer-mechanism/">recent Schrems II ruling</a> &#8212; are not limited to privacy and personal data. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;These worries are in fact at the heart of the Single Market for data that I am building,&#8221; he said. &#8220;These worries are clear in the world we are entering when individuals or companies want to keep control over its data. The key question is, therefore, how to organize this control while allowing data flow &#8212; which is extremely important in the data economy.&#8221;</p>
<p>An open single European market for data must recognize that not all data are the same &#8212; &#8220;in terms of their sensitivity&#8221; &#8212; Breton emphasized, pointing to the EU&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (<a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/gdpr" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="gdpr">GDPR) <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> data protection framework as &#8220;the proof of that&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;Going forward, there are also sensitive industrial data that should benefit from specific conditions when they are accessed, used or shared,&#8221; he went on. &#8220;This is a case for instance for some sensitive public data [such as] from public hospitals, but also anonymized data that remains sensitive, mixed data which are difficult to handle.&#8221;</p>
<p>At one point during the talk he gave the example of European hospitals during the pandemic not being able to share data across borders to help in the fight against the virus because of the lack of a purpose-built framework to securely enable such data flows.</p>
<p>&#8220;I want our SMEs and startups, our public hospitals, our cities and many other actors to use more data &#8212; to make them available, to value them, to share them &#8212; but for this we need to generate the trust,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>The first legislative plank of the transformation to a single European data economy is a Data Governance Act (DGA) &#8212; which Breton said EU lawmakers will present tomorrow, after a vote on the proposal this afternoon.</p>
<p>&#8220;With this act we are defining a European approach to data sharing,&#8221; he noted on the DGA. &#8220;This new regulation will facilitate data sharing across sectors and Member States. And it will put those who generate the data in the driving seat &#8212; moving away from the current practices of the big tech platforms.</p>
<p>&#8220;Concretely, with this legislation, we create the conditions to allow access to a reuse of sensitive public data, creating a body of harmonized rules for the single market.&#8221;</p>
<p>A key component of building the necessary trust for the data economy will mean creating rules that state &#8220;European highly sensitive data <em>should</em> be able to be stored and processed in the EU&#8221;, Breton also said, signalling that data localization will be a core component of the strategy &#8212; in line with<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> a number of <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/breton-wants-tiktok-data-to-stay-in-europe/">recent public remarks</a> in which he&#8217;s argued it&#8217;s not protectionist for European data to be stored in Europe. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;Without such a possibility Member States will never agree to open their data hold,&#8221; Breton went on, saying that while Europe will be &#8220;open&#8221; with data, it will not be offering a &#8220;naive&#8221; data free-for-all.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2g8FGOKcFi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/11/europe-puts-out-advice-on-fixing-international-data-transfers-thats-cold-comfort-for-facebook/">Europe puts out advice on fixing international data transfers that&#8217;s cold comfort for Facebook</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe puts out advice on fixing international data transfers that&#8217;s cold comfort for Facebook&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/11/europe-puts-out-advice-on-fixing-international-data-transfers-thats-cold-comfort-for-facebook/embed/#?secret=2g8FGOKcFi" data-secret="2g8FGOKcFi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The Commission also wants the data framework to support an ecosystem of data brokers whose role Breton said will be to connect data owners and data users &#8220;in a neutral manner&#8221; &#8212; suggesting this will empower companies to have stronger control over the data they generate, (i.e the implication being rather than the current situation where data-mining platform giants can use their market power to asset-strip weaker third parties).</p>
<p>&#8220;We are shifting here the product,&#8221; he said. &#8220;And we promote also data altruism &#8212; the role of sharing data, industrial or personal, for common good.&#8221;</p>
<p>Breton also noted that the forthcoming data governance proposal will include a shielding provision &#8212; meaning data actors will be required to take steps to avoid having to comply with what he called &#8220;abusive and unlawful&#8221; data access requests for data held in Europe from third countries.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is a major point. It is not a question of calling into question our international judicial or policy cooperation. We cannot tolerate abuses,&#8221; he said, specifying three off-limits examples (&#8220;unauthorized access; access that do offer sufficient legal guarantees; or fishing expeditions), adding: &#8220;By doing so we are ensuring that European law and the guarantees it carries is respected. This is about enforcing our own rules.&#8221;</p>
<p>Breton also touched on other interlocking elements of the policy strategy which regional lawmakers see as crucial to delivering a functional data framework: Namely the Digital Services Act (DSA) and Digital Markets Act (DMA) &#8212; which are both due to be set out in detail early next month.</p>
<p>The DSA will put &#8220;a clear responsibility and obligation on platforms and the content that is spread&#8221;, said Breton.</p>
<p>While the companion <em>ex ante</em> regulation, the DMA, will &#8220;frame the behaviours of gatekeepers &#8212; of systemic actors in the Single Market &#8212; and target their behaviors against their competitors or customers&#8221;; aka further helping to pin and clip the wings of big tech.</p>
<p>&#8220;With this set of regulation I just want to set up the rules and that the rules are clear &#8212; based on our values,&#8221; he added.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="amZmo0mRzN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/europe-to-limit-how-big-tech-can-push-its-own-services-and-use-third-party-data/">Europe to limit how big tech can push its own services and use third-party data</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe to limit how big tech can push its own services and use third-party data&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/europe-to-limit-how-big-tech-can-push-its-own-services-and-use-third-party-data/embed/#?secret=amZmo0mRzN" data-secret="amZmo0mRzN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>He also confirmed that interoperability and portability will be a key feature of the EU&#8217;s hoped for data transformation.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are working on this on several strands,&#8221; he said on this. &#8220;The first is standards for interoperability. That&#8217;s absolutely key for sectoral data spaces that we will create and very important for the data flows. You will see that we will create a European innovation data board &#8212; set in the DGA today &#8212; which will help the Commission in setting and working the right standards.&#8221;</p>
<p>While combating &#8220;blocking efforts and abusive behaviors&#8221; by platform gatekeepers &#8212; which could otherwise put an artificial limit on the value of the data economy &#8212; will be &#8220;the job of the DMA&#8221;, he noted.</p>
<p>A fourth pillar of the data strategy &#8212; which Breton referred to as a &#8220;data act&#8221; &#8212; will be introduced in 2021, with the aim of &#8220;increasing fairness in the data economy by clarifying data usage rights in business to business and business to government settings&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;We will also consider enhanced data portability rights to give individuals more control &#8212; which is extremely important &#8212; over the data they produce,&#8221; he added. &#8220;And we will have a look at the intellectual property rights framework.&#8221;</p>
<p>He also noted that key infrastructure investments will be vital &#8212; pointing to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/europe-will-go-it-alone-on-digital-tax-reform-in-2021-if-it-must-says-eu-president-as-bloc-directs-e150bn-in-covid-19-relief-toward-cloud-ai-and-broadband/">Commission&#8217;s plan</a> to build a European industrial cloud and related <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/07/tech-driven-change-a-key-priority-for-new-ec-president/">strategic tech investment priorities</a> such as in compute power capacity, building out next-gen connectivity and support for cutting edges technologies like quantum encryption.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xJ0qhpDHTP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/europe-will-go-it-alone-on-digital-tax-reform-in-2021-if-it-must-says-eu-president-as-bloc-directs-e150bn-in-covid-19-relief-toward-cloud-ai-and-broadband/">Europe will go it alone on digital tax reform in 2021 if it must, says EU president, as bloc directs €150BN in COVID-19 relief toward cloud, AI and broadband</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe will go it alone on digital tax reform in 2021 if it must, says EU president, as bloc directs €150BN in COVID-19 relief toward cloud, AI and broadband&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/europe-will-go-it-alone-on-digital-tax-reform-in-2021-if-it-must-says-eu-president-as-bloc-directs-e150bn-in-covid-19-relief-toward-cloud-ai-and-broadband/embed/#?secret=xJ0qhpDHTP" data-secret="xJ0qhpDHTP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Privacy campaigner Max Schrems, who had been invited as the other guest speaker, raised the issue of enforceability &#8212; pointing out that Ireland&#8217;s data protection authority, which is responsible for overseeing a large number of major tech companies in the region, still hasn&#8217;t issued any decisions on cross-border complaints filed under the 2.5 year old GDPR framework.</p>
<p>Breton agreed that enforcement will be a vital piece of the puzzle &#8212; claiming EU lawmakers are alive to the problem of enforcement &#8220;bottlenecks&#8221; in the GDPR.</p>
<p>&#8220;We need definitely clear, predictable, implementable rules &#8212; and this is what is driving me when I am regulating against the data market. But also what you will find behind the DSA and the DMA with an ex ante regulation to be able to apply it immediately and everywhere in Europe, not only in one country, everywhere at the same time,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Just to be able to make sure that things are happening quick. In this digital space we have to be fast.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;So we will again make sure in DSA that Member State authorities can ask platforms to remove immediately content cross-border &#8212; like, for example, if you want an immediate comparison, the European Arrest Warrant.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Commission will also have the power to step in via cooperation at the European level, Breton further noted.</p>
<p>&#8220;So you see we are putting in rules, we are not naive, we understand pretty well where we have the bottleneck &#8212; and again we try to regulate. And also, in parallel, that&#8217;s very important because like everywhere where you have regulation you need to have sanctions &#8212; you will have appropriate sanctions,&#8221; he said, adding: &#8220;We learn the lessons from the GDPR.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RzlwSx0W8I"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/">GDPR&#8217;s two-year review flags lack of &#8216;vigorous&#8217; enforcement</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GDPR&#8217;s two-year review flags lack of &#8216;vigorous&#8217; enforcement&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/embed/#?secret=RzlwSx0W8I" data-secret="RzlwSx0W8I" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/europes-data-strategy-aims-to-tip-the-scales-away-from-big-tech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077991</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Looking to emulate Venmo, JoomPay preps a Euro launch for easy bill splitting and cash payments</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/looking-to-emulate-venmo-joompay-preps-a-euro-launch-for-easy-bill-splitting-and-cash-payments/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/looking-to-emulate-venmo-joompay-preps-a-euro-launch-for-easy-bill-splitting-and-cash-payments/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 12:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monzo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[N26]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peer to peer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Revolut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venmo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078012</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[JoomPay, a startup with a similar product to PayPayl-owned Venmo in the US, is set to launch in Europe shortly after being granted a Luxembourg Electronic Money Institution (EMI) license. The app allows people to send and receive money with anyone, instantly and for free. “Venmo me” has become a common phrase in the US, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://joompay.com/">JoomPay</a>, a startup with a similar product to PayPayl-owned Venmo in the US, is set to launch in Europe shortly after being granted a Luxembourg Electronic Money Institution (EMI) license. The app allows people to send and receive money with anyone, instantly and for free. “<a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/venmo" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="venmo">Venmo <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> me” has become a common phrase in the US, where people use it to split bills in restaurants or similar. Venmo is in common use in the US, but it’s not available in Europe, although dozens of other innovative mobile peer to peer transfer options exist, such as Revolut, N26, Monese and Monzo. The waitlist for the app&#8217;s beta is open now (<a href="https://apps.apple.com/mt/app/joompay-mobile-finance/id1480381529">iOS</a>, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.joompay.wallet&amp;hl=en&amp;gl=US">Android</a>).</p>
<p>Europe leads the world&#8217;s instant payments industry, with $18 trillion in worldwide volume predicted by 2025 up from $3 trillion in 2020 – a growth of over 500%. Western Europe &#8211; and COVID-19 &#8211; is now driving that innovation and will account for 38% of instant payment transaction value by 2025. While Europe lacks simple peer-to-peer payments solutions such as <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/venmo" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="venmo">Venmo <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> or Square Cash App in the US, challenger banks have stepped up to provide similar kinds of services. JoomPay’s opportunity lies in being able to be a middle-man between these various banking systems.</p>
<p>Shopping app <a href="http://Joom.com">Joom</a>, which has been downloaded 150M times in Europe, has spun-off JoomPay to solve this problem. The app allows users to send and receive money from any person, regardless of whether they use JoomPay or not – and you only need to know their email or the phone number. JoomPay connects to any existing debit/credit card or a bank account. It also provides its users with a European IBAN and an optional free JoomPay card with cashback and bonuses.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Yuri Alekseev, CEO and co-founder of JoomPay, said: &#8220;Since COVID-19 started, we’ve seen a significant decline in cash usage. People can’t meet as easily as before but still need to send money, and we offer a viable alternative.”</p>
<p>JoomPay may have an uphill struggle. Its main competitors in Europe are the huge TransferWise, Paysend, and of course <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/paypal" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="paypal">PayPal <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> itself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/looking-to-emulate-venmo-joompay-preps-a-euro-launch-for-easy-bill-splitting-and-cash-payments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078012</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New TikTok feature allows users to avoid videos with epileptic seizure triggers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/new-tiktok-feature-allows-users-to-avoid-videos-with-epileptic-seizure-triggers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/new-tiktok-feature-allows-users-to-avoid-videos-with-epileptic-seizure-triggers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 12:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accessibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photosensitive epilepsy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seizures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TikTok announced today it is rolling out a new feature that will allow people with photosensitive epilepsy to automatically skip videos that can trigger seizures. The &#8220;Skip All&#8221; option will be introduced to all users over the next few weeks and comes a few months after TikTok began automatically warning creators if a video contains [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/tiktok" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="tiktok">TikTok <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/making-tiktok-more-accessible-to-people-with-photosensitive-epilepsy">announced</a> today it is rolling out a new feature that will allow people with photosensitive epilepsy to automatically skip videos that can trigger seizures.</p>
<p>The &#8220;Skip All&#8221; option will be introduced to all users over the next few weeks and comes a few months after TikTok began automatically warning creators if a video contains effects, like flashing lights or certain visual patterns, that can be harmful to people with photosensitive epilepsy. If they upload those videos, TikTok automatically prefaces them with a warning screen.</p>
<p>Once a user turns on the &#8220;Skip All&#8221; option, they won&#8217;t see any videos TikTok has identified as potential triggers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2077978" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Photosensitivity-Warning.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2077978" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2077978 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Photosensitivity-Warning.png?w=314" alt="TikTok's warning for videos with content that can trigger epileptic seizures" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Photosensitivity-Warning.png 750w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Photosensitivity-Warning.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Photosensitivity-Warning.png?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Photosensitivity-Warning.png?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Photosensitivity-Warning.png?resize=709,1536 709w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Photosensitivity-Warning.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2077978" class="wp-caption-text">TikTok&#8217;s warning for videos with content that can trigger epileptic seizures</p></div></p>
<p>According to the Epilepsy Foundation, one of several organizations TikTok consulted with, the condition affects about 65 million people worldwide.</p>
<p>While <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-47943607">advocates have called on social media platforms</a>, including YouTube and Facebook, to place warnings before content with potential triggers, the task often falls to individual creators. For example, if a video has flashing lights, they might mention that at the beginning or in its description. But not all creators are aware of photosensitive epilepsy or its triggers.</p>
<p>Furthermore, online trolls have posted harmful content on purpose, sometimes tagging them with keywords related to epilepsy. The Epilepsy Society, another organization that worked with TikTok, <a href="https://www.epilepsysociety.org.uk/zachslaw">has called for malicious posts</a> to be covered by the United Kingdom’s Online Harms bill.</p>
<p>In a statement published with TikTok’s announcement, Nicola Swanborough, the Epilepsy Society’s acting head of external affairs, said &#8220;social media can be a lifeline for many people with epilepsy, allowing them to connect with others with the condition from around the world,&#8221; and that the organization hopes &#8220;other platforms will follow TikTok’s lead in ensuring greater inclusivity.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/new-tiktok-feature-allows-users-to-avoid-videos-with-epileptic-seizure-triggers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077971</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Industrial drone maker Percepto raises $45M and integrates with Boston Dynamics&#8217; Spot</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/industrial-drone-maker-percepto-raises-45m-and-integrates-with-boston-dynamics-spot/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/industrial-drone-maker-percepto-raises-45m-and-integrates-with-boston-dynamics-spot/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 11:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[industrial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[industrial drones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[percepto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPOT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077990</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Consumer drones have over the years struggled with an image of being no more than expensive and delicate toys. But applications in industrial, military and enterprise scenarios have shown that there is indeed a market for unmanned aerial vehicles, and today, a startup that makes drones for some of those latter purposes is announcing a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Consumer drones have over the years struggled with an image of being no more than expensive and delicate toys. But applications in industrial, military and enterprise scenarios have shown that there is indeed a market for unmanned aerial vehicles, and today, a startup that makes drones for some of those latter purposes is announcing a large round of funding and a partnership that provides a picture of how the drone industry will look in years to come.</p>
<p><a href="http://percepto.co" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Percepto</a>, which makes drones &#8212; both the hardware and software &#8212; to monitor and analyze industrial sites and other physical work areas largely unattended by people, has raised $45 million in a Series B round of funding.</p>
<p>Alongside this, it is now working with <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/boston-dynamics" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="boston-dynamics">Boston Dynamics  <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and has integrated its Spot robots with Percepto&#8217;s Sparrow drones, with the aim being better infrastructure assessments, and potentially more as Spot&#8217;s agility improves.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The funding is being led by a strategic backer, <a href="https://www.kochind.com/companies/koch-disruptive-technologies" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Koch Disruptive Technologies</a>, the investment arm of industrial giant <a href="https://www.kochind.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Koch Industries</a> (which has interests in energy, minerals, chemicals and related areas), with participation also from new investors State of Mind Ventures, Atento Capital, Summit Peak Investments, Delek-US. Previous investors U.S. Venture Partners, Spider Capital and Arkin Holdings also participated. (It appears that Boston Dynamics and SoftBank are not part of this investment.)</p>
<p>Israel-based Percepto has now raised $72.5 million since it was founded in 2014, and it&#8217;s not disclosing its valuation, but CEO and founder Dor Abuhasira described as &#8220;a very good round.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;It gives us the ability to create a category leader,&#8221; Abuhasira said in an interview. It has customers in around 10 countries, with the list including ENEL, Florida Power and Light and Verizon.</p>
<p>While some drone makers have focused on building hardware, and others are working specifically on the analytics, computer vision and other critical technology that needs to be in place on the software side for drones to work correctly and safely, Percepto has taken what I referred to, and Abuhasira confirmed, as the &#8220;Apple approach&#8221;: vertical integration as far as Percepto can take it on its own.</p>
<p>That has included hiring teams with specializations in AI, computer vision, navigation and analytics as well as those strong in industrial hardware &#8212; all strong areas in the Israel tech landscape, by virtue of it being so closely tied with its military investments. (Note: Percepto does not make its own chips: these are currently acquired from Nvidia, he confirmed to me.)</p>
<p>&#8220;The Apple approach is the only one that works in drones,&#8221; he said. &#8220;That&#8217;s because it is all still too complicated. For those offering an Android-style approach, there are cracks in the complete flow.&#8221;</p>
<p>It presents the product as a &#8220;drone-in-a-box&#8221;, which means in part that those buying it have little work to do to set it up to work, but also refers to how it works: its drones leave the box to make a flight to collect data, and then return to the box to recharge and transfer more information, alongside the data that is picked up in real time.</p>
<p>The drones themselves operate on an on-demand basis: they fly in part for regular monitoring, to detect changes that could point to issues; and they can also be launched to collect data as a result of engineers requesting information. The product is marketed by Percepto as &#8220;AIM&#8221;, short for autonomous site inspection and monitoring.</p>
<p>News broke last week that Amazon has been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/amazons-drone-delivery-team-hit-with-layoffs-amid-reorganization/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reorganising</a> its Prime Air efforts &#8212; one sign of how some more consumer-facing business applications &#8212; despite many developments &#8212; may still have some turbulence ahead before they are commercially viable. Businesses like Percepto&#8217;s stand in contrast to that, with their focus specifically on flying over, and collecting data, in areas where there are precisely no people present.</p>
<p>It has dovetailed with a bigger focus from industries on the efficiencies (and cost savings) you can get with automation, which in turn has become the centerpiece of how industry is investing in the buzz phrase of the moment, &#8220;digital transformation.&#8221;</p>
<p>“We believe Percepto AIM addresses a multi-billion-dollar issue for numerous industries and will change the way manufacturing sites are managed in the IoT, Industry 4.0 era,” said Chase Koch, President of Koch Disruptive Technologies, in a statement. “Percepto’s track record in autonomous technology and data analytics is impressive, and we believe it is uniquely positioned to deliver the remote operations center of the future. We look forward to partnering with the Percepto team to make this happen.”</p>
<p>The partnership with Boston Dynamics is notable for a couple of reasons: it speaks to how various robotics hardware will work together in tandem in an automated, unmanned world; and it speaks to how Boston Dynamics is pulling up its socks.</p>
<p>On the latter front, the company has been making waves in the world of robotics for years, specifically with its agile and strong dog-like (with names like &#8220;Spot&#8221; and &#8220;Big Dog&#8221;) robots that can cover rugged terrains and handle tussles without falling apart.</p>
<p>That led it into the arms of Google, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/12/14/google-buys-boston-dynamics-creator-of-big-dog/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">acquired it</a> as part of its own secretive moonshot efforts, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/12/14/google-buys-boston-dynamics-creator-of-big-dog/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in 2013</a>. That never panned out into a business, and probably gave Google more complicated optics at a time when it was already being seen as too powerful. Then, SoftBank stepped in to pick it up, along with other robotics assets, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/08/softbank-is-buying-robotics-firm-boston-dynamics-and-schaft-from-alphabet/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in 2017</a>. That hasn&#8217;t really gone anywhere either, it seems, and just this month it was reported that Boston Dynamics was reportedly facing yet another suitor, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/hyundai-reportedly-in-talks-to-buy-softbank-owned-boston-dynamics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hyundai</a>.</p>
<p>All of this is to say that partnerships with third parties that are going places (quite literally) become strong signs of how Boston Dynamics&#8217; extensive R&amp;D investments might finally pay off with enterprising dividends.</p>
<p>Indeed, while Percepto has focused on its own vertical integration, longer term and more generally there is an argument to be made for more interoperability and collaboration between the various companies building &#8220;connected&#8221; and smart hardware for industrial, physical applications.</p>
<p>It means that specific industries can focus on the special equipment and expertise they require, while at the same time complementing that with hardware and software that are recognised as best-in-class. Abuhasira said that he expects the Boston Dynamics partnership to be the first of many.</p>
<p>That makes this first one an interesting template. The partnership will see Spot carrying Percepto’s payloads for high resolution imaging and thermal vision &#8220;to detect issues including hot spots on machines or electrical conductors, water and steam leaks around plants and equipment with degraded performance, with the data relayed via AIM.&#8221; It will also mean a more thorough picture, beyond what you get from the air. And, potentially, you might imagine a time in the future when the data that the combined devices source, results even in Spot (or perhaps a third piece of autonomous hardware) carrying out repairs or other assistance.</p>
<p>“Combining Percepto’s Sparrow drone with Spot creates a unique solution for remote inspection,” said Michael Perry, VP of Business Development at Boston Dynamics, in a statement. “This partnership demonstrates the value of harnessing robotic collaborations and the insurmountable benefits to worker safety and cost savings that robotics can bring to industries that involve hazardous or remote work.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/industrial-drone-maker-percepto-raises-45m-and-integrates-with-boston-dynamics-spot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077990</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calling VCs in Israel: Be featured in The Great TechCrunch Survey of European VC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/calling-vcs-in-israel-be-featured-in-the-great-techcrunch-survey-of-european-vc/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/calling-vcs-in-israel-be-featured-in-the-great-techcrunch-survey-of-european-vc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 11:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077995</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TechCrunch is embarking on a major new project to survey the venture capital investors of Europe, and their cities. Our &#60;a href=&#8221;https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6”>survey of VCs in Israel will capture how the country is faring, and what changes are being wrought amongst investors by the coronavirus pandemic. The Israeli VC eco-system is closely aligned with the European [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TechCrunch is embarking on a major new project to <a href="https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6">survey</a> the venture capital investors of Europe, and their cities.</p>
<p>Our &lt;a href=&#8221;https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6”>survey of VCs in Israel will capture how the country is faring, and what changes are being wrought amongst investors by the coronavirus pandemic. The Israeli VC eco-system is closely aligned with the European one, with many VCs co-investing with VCs in Israel, hence their inclusion in this survey.</p>
<p>We’d like to know how Israel&#8217;s startup scene is evolving, how the tech sector is being impacted by COVID-19, and, generally, how your thinking will evolve from here.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Our survey will only be about investors, and <strong>only the contributions of VC investors will be included.</strong> More than one partner is welcome to fill out the survey. (Please note, if you have filled the survey out already, there is no need to do it again).</p>
<p>The shortlist of questions will require only brief responses, but the more you can add, the better.</p>
<p><a href="https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6"><strong>You can fill out the survey here.</strong></a></p>
<p>Obviously, investors who contribute will be featured in the final surveys, with links to their companies and profiles.</p>
<p>What kinds of things do we want to know? Questions include: Which trends are you most excited by? What startup do you wish someone would create? Where are the overlooked opportunities? What are you looking for in your next investment, in general? How is your local ecosystem going? And how has COVID-19 impacted your investment strategy?</p>
<p>This survey is part of a broader <a href="https://techcrunch.com/extra-crunch/investor-surveys/">series of surveys</a> we’re doing to help founders find the right investors.</p>
<p>https://techcrunch.com/extra-crunch/investor-surveys/</p>
<p>For example, here is the recent <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/14-vcs-discuss-covid-19-and-londons-future-as-a-tech-hub/">survey of London</a>.</p>
<p>You are not in Israel, but would like to take part? That&#8217;s fine! Any European VC investor can STILL fill out the survey, as we probably will be putting a call out to your country next anyway! And we will use the data for future surveys on vertical topics.</p>
<p>The survey is covering almost every country on in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Union_for_the_Mediterranean">Union for the Mediterranean</a>, so just look for your country and city on the <a href="https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6">survey</a> and please participate (<em>if</em> you&#8217;re a venture capital investor).</p>
<p>Thank you for participating. If you have questions you can email mike@techcrunch.com</p>
<p>(Please note: Filling out the survey is not a guarantee of inclusion in the final published piece).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/calling-vcs-in-israel-be-featured-in-the-great-techcrunch-survey-of-european-vc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077995</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kahoot drops $50M on Drops to add language learning to its gamified education stable</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/kahoot-drops-50m-on-drops-to-add-language-learning-to-its-gamified-education-stable/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/kahoot-drops-50m-on-drops-to-add-language-learning-to-its-gamified-education-stable/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 09:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kahoot!]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Languages]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After raising $215 million from SoftBank to double down on the surge of interest in online learning, Kahoot has made an acquisition to expand the scope of subjects that it covers. The popular startup, which lets people build and share educational games, has picked up Drops, a startup that helps people learn languages by way [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After raising <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/13/kahoot-picks-up-215m-from-softbank-for-its-user-generated-gamified-e-learning-platform/">$215 million from SoftBank</a> to double down on the surge of interest in online learning, Kahoot has made an acquisition to expand the scope of subjects that it covers. The popular startup, which lets people build and share educational games, has picked up Drops, a startup that helps people learn languages by way of short picture- and word-based games. The plan is to integrate more Kahoot features into <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/drops-8841" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="drops-8841">Drops&#8217; <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> apps, and to bring some of Drops&#8217; content into the main Kahoot platform.</p>
<p>Kahoot, which trades a part of its shares through Norway&#8217;s alternative exchange the Merkur Market and currently has a <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/KAHOOT-ME.OL?p=KAHOOT-ME.OL&amp;.tsrc=fin-srch" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">market cap of over $3 billion</a>, said in an <a href="https://kahoot.com/press/2020/11/24/kahoot-acquires-drops-to-make-language-learning-awesome/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">announcement</a> that it would pay $31 million in cash, plus up to $19 million more in cash and shares, based on Drops meeting certain targets between now and 2022. The deal is expected to close this month, and is the company&#8217;s biggest to date.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Drops makes three main apps. First in an eponymous freemium app, with free and paid features, that helps adults learn new languages, currently some 42 in all, with a focus on vocabulary, built around five-minute, &#8220;snackable&#8221; sessions. A second app, Scripts, is aimed at learning to read, write and sign, and it covers four alphabets and four character-based writing systems. A third, Droplets, is aimed specifically at language learning for learners aged between eight and 17. Altogether Drops has clocked up 25 million users.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Notably, one reason it might be off TechCrunch&#8217;s (and the startup world&#8217;s) radar is that it was bootstrapped. (It did go through an accelerator, <a href="http://www.gamefounders.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GameFounders</a>.) But it has had some notable accolades, including getting named app of the year by Google in 2018.</span></p>
<p>The startup was founded in Estonia and has 21 employees with no &#8220;head office&#8221; as such, with the team spread across Estonia, US, UK, Spain, Italy, France, Germany, Sweden, the Netherlands, Hungary, Ukraine and Russia. This could be one reason why it&#8217;s kept costs low: in 2019 it reported gross revenues of $7.5 million (€6.3 million), with cash conversion of 40%.</p>
<p>For some more context, Kahoot &#8212; which is also backed by the likes of Microsoft, Disney and Northzone &#8212; says that in the last 12 months, more than 1 billion participating players in over 200 countries attended over 200 million Kahoot! sessions. That figure includes both educational users of its free services, as well as enterprises, which pay to build and use games (for example related to professional development or business compliance) on the platform.</p>
<p>“We are thrilled to welcome Drops to the expanding Kahoot! family as we advance towards our vision to become the leading learning platform in the world,” said Eilert Hanoa, the CEO of Kahoot, in a statement. “Drops’ offerings and innovative learning model are a perfect match to Kahoot!’s mission of making learning awesome through a simple, game-based approach. Drops and language learning becomes the latest addition to our growing offering of learning apps for learners of all ages and abilities. We will continue to expand in new areas to make Kahoot! the ultimate learning destination, at home, school or work, and to make learning awesome!”</p>
<p>The Covid-19 pandemic has led to a bonanza for educational apps, which are collectively seeing a huge rush of usage in the last year.</p>
<p>For students, educators and parents, they have become a way of connecting and teaching at a time when physical schools are either closed, or drastically curtailed in what they can do, in order to help limit the spread of the novel coronavirus.</p>
<p>Businesses and other organizations, on the other hand, are leaning on e-learning as a way of keeping connected with staff, engaging them, and training them at a time when many are working from home.</p>
<p>It might seem ironic that at a time when travel has been drastically limited, if not completely halted altogether, for many of us, that language learning has seen an especially big boom.</p>
<p>Maybe it&#8217;s about making hay &#8212; that is, using the moment to get yourself ready for a time in the future when you might actually get to use your newly acquired foreign language skills. Or maybe it&#8217;s just another option for distracting or occupying ourselves in a more constructive way. Whatever might be the motivation or cause, the effect is that language learning is on the up.</p>
<p>Most recently, Duolingo &#8212; which incidentally also uses game-based concepts, where you enter a leaderboard for your learning and your daily sessions become winning streaks &#8212; raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/language-learning-app-duolingo-confirms-it-has-raised-35m-on-a-2-4b-valuation/\" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$35 million on a $2.4 billion valuation</a>, a huge jump for the company.</p>
<p>Kahoot cites <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/948857/digital-language-learning-global-market-size-language/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">figures</a> that predict that digital language learning will be an $8 billion+ market by 2025 as describes Drops as &#8220;one of the fastest-growing language platforms in the world.&#8221;</p>
<p>“The entire Drops team has spent the last five years building a new way to learn language, and we’re just getting started,” said Daniel Farkas, co-founder and CEO, Drops, in a statement. “We’ve introduced millions of users across the globe to our playful, dynamic approach to language learning. Kahoot! is doing the same for all types of learning. We’re excited to work with such a mission-aligned company to introduce the Drops platform to game-loving learners everywhere.”</p>
<p>This is Kahoot&#8217;s <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/kahoot-/company_financials" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">fourth acquisition</a>, and its biggest to date. As with Drops, previous M&amp;A deals were made to bolt on new areas of expertise to the platform, such <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/08/educational-gaming-platform-kahoot-acquires-math-app-maker-dragonbox-for-18m/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">maths learning</a> for students and more tools to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/user-generated-e-learning-site-kahoot-acquires-actimo-for-up-to-33m-to-double-down-on-corporate-sector/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">manage enterprise users</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/kahoot-drops-50m-on-drops-to-add-language-learning-to-its-gamified-education-stable/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077983</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
