<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 06:08:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>ByteDance to cut jobs in India amid TikTok ban</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/bytedance-to-cut-jobs-in-india-amid-tiktok-ban/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/bytedance-to-cut-jobs-in-india-amid-tiktok-ban/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 06:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101080</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chinese internet giant ByteDance has told employees in India that it will be reducing the size of its team in the country after New Delhi retained ban on TikTok and other Chinese apps in the country, a source familiar with the matter told TechCrunch. The company shared the news with employees in the country at [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Chinese internet giant ByteDance has told employees in India that it will be reducing the size of its team in the country after New Delhi retained ban on TikTok and other Chinese apps in the country, a source familiar with the matter told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The company shared the news with employees in the country at 10am local time and said only critical jobs will be retained in the country. ByteDance said the Indian government has offered no clear direction on when the app would be able to make a return, the source said on the condition of anonymity.</p>
<p>ByteDance did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This is breaking news. Check back for more information.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/bytedance-to-cut-jobs-in-india-amid-tiktok-ban/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101080</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Will this time be any different for Twitter?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/will-this-time-be-any-different-for-twitter/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/will-this-time-be-any-different-for-twitter/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jack dorsey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100223</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As Twitter seems to buy its way into competing with Clubhouse and Substack, one wonders whether the beleaguered social media company is finally ready to move past its truly awful track record of seizing opportunities. Twitter&#8217;s pace of product ambition has certainly seemed to speed in the past several months, conveniently following shareholder action to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As Twitter seems to buy its way into competing with Clubhouse and Substack, one wonders whether the beleaguered social media company is finally ready to move past its truly awful track record of seizing opportunities.</p>
<p>Twitter&#8217;s pace of product ambition has certainly seemed to speed in the past several months, conveniently following shareholder action <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/02/activist-investors-want-to-crank-up-the-twitter-revenue-machine/">to oust CEO Jack Dorsey last year. </a>They&#8217;ve finally rolled out their <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/twitter-rolls-out-stories-aka-fleets-to-all-users-will-also-test-a-clubhouse-rival/">Stories product Fleets</a>, they&#8217;ve embraced audio both in the traditional feed and with their <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/twitter-launches-its-voice-based-spaces-social-networking-feature-into-beta-testing/">beta Spaces feature,</a> and they&#8217;ve taken some much-publicized steps to reign in disinformation and content moderation woes (though there&#8217;s still plenty to be done there).</p>
<p>In the past few weeks, Twitter has also made some particularly interesting acquisitions. Today, it was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitter-acquires-revue/">announced that they were buying Revue</a>, a newsletter management startup. Earlier this month, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/04/twitter-acquires-social-podcasting-app-breaker-team-to-help-build-twitter-spaces/">they bought Breaker</a>, a podcasting service. Last month, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/twitter-acquires-screen-sharing-social-app-squad/">they bought Squad</a>, a social screen-sharing app.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zQziU969zS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitter-acquires-revue/">Twitter acquires newsletter platform Revue</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter acquires newsletter platform Revue&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitter-acquires-revue/embed/#?secret=zQziU969zS" data-secret="zQziU969zS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>It&#8217;s an aggressive turn that follows Twitter&#8217;s announcement that it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/periscope-will-shut-down-by-march-twitter-confirms/">will be shutting down Periscope</a>, a live video app that was purchased and long-neglected by Twitter despite the fact that the company&#8217;s current product chief was its founder.</p>
<p>TikTok&#8217;s wild 2020 success in fully realizing the broader vision for Vine, which Twitter shut down in 2017, seems to be a particularly embarrassing stain on the company&#8217;s history; it&#8217;s also the most crystallized example of Twitter shooting itself in the foot as a result of not embracing risk. And while Twitter was ahead of that curve and simply didn&#8217;t make it happen, Substack and Clubhouse are two prime examples of competitors which Twitter could have prevented from reaching their current stature if it had just been more aggressive in recognizing adjacent social market opportunities and sprung into action.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">I remember Vine, and I certainly remember Periscope :) You’re not wrong about our past. But challenge accepted on our ability to learn from our mistakes. A lot is different now.</p>
<p>&mdash; Kayvon Beykpour (@kayvz) <a href="https://twitter.com/kayvz/status/1354176709679964161?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 26, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>It&#8217;s particularly hard to reckon in the shadow of Facebook&#8217;s ever-swelling isolation. Once the eager enemy of any social upstart, Facebook finds itself desperately complicated by global politics and antitrust woes in a way that may never strike it down, but have seemed to slow its maneuverability. A startup like Clubhouse may once seemed like a prime acquisition target, but it&#8217;s too complicated of a purchase for Facebook to even attempt in 2021, leaving Twitter a potential competitor that could scale to full size on its own.</p>
<p>Twitter is a much smaller company than Facebook is, though it&#8217;s still plenty big. As the company aims to move beyond the 2020 US election that ate up so much of its attention and expand its ambitions, one of its most pertinent challenges will be reinvigorating a product culture to recognize opportunities and take on rising competitors &#8212; though another challenge might be getting its competition to take it seriously in the first place.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">General Motors announces the Bolt. <a href="https://t.co/UndFpsBDU5">https://t.co/UndFpsBDU5</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Hamish McKenzie (@hamishmckenzie) <a href="https://twitter.com/hamishmckenzie/status/1354168607287066624?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 26, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5CytH42bPO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/twitters-vision-of-decentralization-could-also-be-the-far-rights-internet-endgame/">Twitter’s decentralized future</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter’s decentralized future&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/twitters-vision-of-decentralization-could-also-be-the-far-rights-internet-endgame/embed/#?secret=5CytH42bPO" data-secret="5CytH42bPO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/will-this-time-be-any-different-for-twitter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100223</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sila Nanotechnologies raises $590M to fund battery materials factory</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/sila-nanotechnologies-raises-590m-to-fund-battery-materials-factory/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/sila-nanotechnologies-raises-590m-to-fund-battery-materials-factory/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 23:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BMW]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daimler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rivian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sila Nanotechnologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sila Nanotechnologies, a Silicon Valley battery materials company, has spent years developing technology designed to pack more energy into a cell at a lower cost — an end game that has helped it lock in partnerships with Amperex Technology Limited as well as automakers BMW and Daimler. Now, Sila Nano, flush with a fresh injection [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Sila Nanotechnologies, a Silicon Valley battery materials company, has spent years developing technology designed to pack more energy into a cell at a lower cost — an end game that has helped it lock in partnerships with Amperex Technology Limited as well as automakers BMW and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/16/sila-nanos-battery-tech-is-now-worth-over-1-billion-with-daimler-partnership-and-150-million-investment/">Daimler</a>.</p>
<p>Now, Sila Nano, flush with a fresh injection of capital that has pushed its valuation to $3.3 billion, is ready to bring its technology to the masses.</p>
<p>The company, which was founded nearly a decade ago, said Tuesday it has raised $590 million in a Series F funding round led by Coatue with significant participation by funds and accounts advised by T. Rowe Price Associates, Inc. Existing investors 8VC, Bessemer Venture Partners, Canada Pension Plan Investment Board, and Sutter Hill Ventures also participated in the round.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Sila Nano plans to use the funds to hire another 100 people this year and begin to buildout a factory in North America capable of producing 100 gigawatt-hours of silicon-based anode material, which is used in batteries for the smartphone and automotive industries. While the company hasn&#8217;t revealed the location of the factory, it does have a timeline. Sila Nano said it plans to start production at the factory in 2024. Materials produced at the plant will be in electric vehicles by 2025, the company said.</p>
<p>&#8220;It took eight years and 35,000 iterations to create a new battery chemistry, but that was just step one,&#8221; Sila Nano CEO and co-founder Gene Berdichevsky said in a statement. &#8220;For any new technology to make an impact in the real-world, it has to scale, which will cost billions of dollars. We know from our experience building our production lines in Alameda that investing in our next plant today will keep us on track to be powering cars and hundreds of millions of consumer devices by 2025.&#8221;</p>
<h2><strong>The tech</strong></h2>
<p>A lithium-ion battery contains two electrodes. There’s an anode (negative) on one side and a cathode (positive) on the other. Typically, an electrolyte sits in the middle and acts as the courier, moving ions between the electrodes when charging and discharging. Graphite is commonly used as the anode in commercial lithium-ion batteries.</p>
<p>Sila Nano has developed a silicon-based anode that replaces graphite in lithium-ion batteries. The critical detail is that the material was designed to take the place of graphite in without needing to change the battery manufacturing process or equipment.</p>
<p>Sila Nano has been focused on silicon anode because the material can store a lot more lithium ions. Using a material that lets you pack in more lithium ions would theoretically allow you to increase the energy density — or the amount of energy that can be stored in a battery per its volume — of the cell. The upshot would be a cheaper battery <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">that contains more energy in the same space.</span></p>
<h2>The opportunity</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s a compelling product for automakers attempting to bring more electric vehicles to market. Nearly every global automaker has announced plans or is already producing a new batch of all-electric and plug-in electric vehicles, including Ford, GM, Daimler, BMW, Hyundai and Kia. Tesla continues to ramp up production of its Model 3 and Model Y vehicles as a string of newcomers like Rivian prepare to bring their own EVs to market.</p>
<p>In short: the demand of batteries is climbing; and automakers are looking for the next-generation tech that will give them a competitive edge.</p>
<p>Battery production sat at about 20 GWh per year in 2010. Sila Nano expects it to jump to 2,000 GWh per year by 2030 and 30,000 GWh per year by 2050.</p>
<p>Sila Nano started building the first production lines for its battery materials in 2018. That first line is capable of producing the material to supply the equivalent of 50 megawatts of lithium-ion batteries.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/sila-nanotechnologies-raises-590m-to-fund-battery-materials-factory/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100993</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Calendly valued at $3B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/daily-crunch-calendly-valued-at-3b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/daily-crunch-calendly-valued-at-3b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 23:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101011</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A popular scheduling startup raises a big funding round, Twitter makes a newsletter acquisition and Beyond Meat teams up with PepsiCo. This is your Daily Crunch for January 26, 2021. The big story: Calendly valued at $3B Calendly, which helps users schedule and confirm meeting times, has raised $350 million from OpenView Venture Partners and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A popular scheduling startup raises a big funding round, Twitter makes a newsletter acquisition and Beyond Meat teams up with PepsiCo. This is your Daily Crunch for January 26, 2021.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: Calendly valued at $3B</strong></p>
<p>Calendly, which helps users schedule and confirm meeting times, has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/how-atlantas-calendly-turned-a-scheduling-nightmare-into-a-3b-startup/">raised $350 million</a> from OpenView Venture Partners and Iconiq.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Until now, the Atlanta-based startup had only raised $550K, but the company says it has 10 million monthly users, with $70 million in subscription revenue last year.</p>
<p>&#8220;Calendly has a vision increasingly to be a central part of the meeting life cycle,&#8221; said OpenView&#8217;s Blake Bartlett.</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitter-acquires-revue/">Twitter acquires newsletter platform Revue</a> — Twitter is getting into the newsletter business.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/tiktok-is-being-used-by-vape-sellers-marketing-to-teens/">TikTok is being used by vape sellers marketing to teens</a> — Sellers are offering flavored disposable vapes, parent-proof &#8220;discreet&#8221; packaging and no ID checks.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/pepsico-and-beyond-meat-launch-poorly-named-joint-venture-for-new-plant-based-food-and-drinks/">PepsiCo and Beyond Meat launch poorly named joint venture for new plant-based food and drinks</a> — The name? The PLANeT Partnership.</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/fast-raises-102m-as-the-online-checkout-wars-continue-to-attract-huge-investment/">Fast raises $102M as the online checkout wars continue to attract huge investment</a> — The new funding was led by Stripe.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/setsail-nabs-26m-series-a-to-rethink-sales-compensation/">SetSail nabs $26M Series A to rethink sales compensation</a> — SetSail says salespeople should be paid them throughout the sales cycle.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/mealco-raises-7m-to-launch-new-delivery-centric-restaurants/">Mealco raises $7M to launch new delivery-centric restaurants</a> — By launching a restaurant with Mealco, chefs don&#8217;t sign a lease or pay any other upfront costs.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/9-vcs-say-interactivity-regulation-and-independent-creators-will-reshape-digital-media-in-2021/">Ten VCs say interactivity, regulation and independent creators will reshape digital media in 2021</a> — We asked about the likelihood of further industry consolidation, whether we’ll see more digital media companies take the SPAC route and, of course, what they’re looking for in their next investment.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/the-5-biggest-mistakes-i-made-as-a-first-time-startup-founder/">The five biggest mistakes I made as a first-time startup founder</a> — Finmark CEO Rami Essaid has some regrets.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/does-a-27-or-29-billion-valuation-make-sense-for-databricks/">Does a $27B or $29B valuation make sense for Databricks?</a> — A look at Databricks’ growth history, economics and scale.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/president-joe-biden-commits-to-replacing-entire-federal-fleet-with-electric-vehicles/">President Joe Biden commits to replacing entire federal fleet with electric vehicles</a> — His commitment is tied to a broader campaign promise to create 1 million new jobs in the American auto industry and supply chains.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/meet-the-early-stage-founder-community-at-tc-early-stage-2021/">Meet the early-stage founder community at TC Early Stage 2021</a> — Early Stage part one focuses on operations and fundraising and takes place on April 1-2, while Early Stage part two focusing on marketing, PR and fundraising and runs July 8-9.</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/daily-crunch-calendly-valued-at-3b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101011</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple just had its best quarter in India</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/apple-india-q4-2020/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/apple-india-q4-2020/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 23:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone 11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone 12]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone SE]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101010</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When Apple reports its earnings on Wednesday, you can expect mentions of India on the call. Apple shipped more than 1.5 million iPhone units in India in the quarter that ended in December, up 100% year-on-year, making this its best quarter in the world’s largest smartphone market to date, according to research firms Counterpoint and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When Apple reports its earnings on Wednesday, you can expect mentions of India on the call.</p>
<p>Apple shipped more than 1.5 million iPhone units in India in the quarter that ended in December, up 100% year-on-year, making this its best quarter in the world’s largest smartphone market to date, according to research firms Counterpoint and CyberMedia.</p>
<p>Thanks to the improved sales of older generation iPhone 11, iPhone XR, iPhone 12 and the newer iPhone SE, Apple doubled its market share in India to 4% in the quarter, the research firms said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Overall, Apple shipped more than 3.2 million iPhone units in India in 2020, up 60% year-on-year, Counterpoint said.</p>
<p>The shipment growth comes months after Apple <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/22/apple-launches-its-online-store-in-india/">launched its online store in the country</a> and offered customers a wide-range of financing and upgrade options, AppleCare+, and lucrative perks such as a free set of AirPods with the purchase of iPhone 11. The company plans to open its<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/26/apple-to-begin-online-sales-in-india-this-year-open-first-retail-store-in-2021/"> first physical retail store in the country later this year</a>.</p>
<p>For more than a decade, Apple has struggled to sell its handsets in India because of the expensive price tags they carry. Most smartphones that ship in India are priced between $100 to $200. Samsung, and a group of Chinese smartphone vendors including Xiaomi, Oppo, and Vivo <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/22/smartphone-shipments-rebound-to-hit-an-all-time-high-in-india/">flooded the market in the past decade</a> with their affordable smartphones.</p>
<p>None the less, in recent years Apple has visibly grown more interested in the country that is also one of the world’s fastest growing smartphones markets. The company’s contract manufacturers today locally <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/24/apple-begins-assembling-iphone-11-in-india/">assemble a range of iPhone models and some accessories</a> — an effort the company kickstarted more than two years ago. (A recent <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/19/apple-puts-contract-partner-wistron-on-probation-after-violence-at-india-plant/">violent event at an Indian facility of Wistron</a>, one of Apple&#8217;s contract manufacturers, however, underscored some of the challenges Apple will grapple with as it looks to scale its local production efforts in the country.)</p>
<p>That move has allowed Apple to lower prices of some older generation iPhone models in India, where for years the company has passed import duty charges to customers. The starting price of the iPhone 12 Pro Max is $1,781 in India, compared to $1,099 in the U.S. (Apple has yet to start locally assemble the iPhone 12 units.) The AirPods Pro, which sells at $249 in the U.S., was made available in India at $341 at the time of launch. AirPods Max, similarly, is priced at $815 in India, compared to $549 in the U.S. (It doesn&#8217;t help that an average person in India makes $2,000 a year.)</p>
<p>Unlike most foreign firms that offer their products and services for free in India or at some of the world’s cheapest prices, Apple has focused entirely on a small fraction of the population that can afford to pay big bucks, Jayanth Kolla, chief analyst at Convergence Catalyst, told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>That’s not to say that Apple has not made some changes to its price strategy for India. The monthly cost of Apple Music is $1.35 in India, compared to $9.99 in the U.S. Its Apple One bundle, which includes Apple Music, TV+, Arcade and iCloud, costs $2.65 a month in India.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/apple-india-q4-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101010</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ClassDojo&#8217;s second act comes with first profits</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/classdojos-second-act-comes-with-first-profits/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/classdojos-second-act-comes-with-first-profits/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 22:27:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B2B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ClassDojo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sam Chaudhary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signalfire]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ClassDojo’s first eight years as an edtech consumer startup could look like failure: zero revenue; no paid users; and a team that hasn’t aggressively grown in years. But the company, which helps parents and teachers communicate about students, has raised tens of millions in venture capital from elite Silicon Valley investors including Y Combinator, GSV, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.classdojo.com/">ClassDojo</a>’s first eight years as an edtech consumer startup could look like failure: zero revenue; no paid users; and a team that hasn’t aggressively grown in years. But the company, which helps parents and teachers communicate about students, has raised tens of millions in venture capital from elite Silicon Valley investors including Y Combinator, GSV, SignalFire and General Catalyst over its life.</p>
<p>If you ask co-founder<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/samchaudhary"> Sam Chaudhary</a> to explain how the startup survived so long without bringing in money, he responds simply: &#8220;When you have something that you think will be for the long term you can put [in] a lot of energy. So, we always kind of maintained the belief that like bringing people together and helping them be connected, especially last year when they needed to be apart, physically apart, was going to be really important.&#8221;</p>
<p>In layman’s terms: ClassDojo has been playing the long-game in edtech since 2011, quietly aggregating free users-turned-fans across the world’s public schools, which are notoriously hard to sell due to tight budgets. Every engineer on the team serves a population that is the size of the city of San Francisco. The company has been intentionally frugal throughout the process. Its core service, which is an interface that allows parents and teachers to communicate updates and stay involved in the classroom, is free for anyone to download.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Our view from the start was actually that the idea of districts isn&#8217;t the customer of education, [that’s] kind of backwards,” he said. “It’s like Airbnb saying we’re going to transform travel by selling to hotels.” The route has helped ClassDojo gain traction with 51 million users across 180 countries.</p>
<p>Two years ago, ClassDojo tested this customer love. It launched its<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/28/classdojo-an-app-to-help-teachers-and-parents-communicate-better-raises-35m/"> first monetization attempt in 2019</a>: Beyond School, a service that complements in-school learning with at-home tutorials. Within four months of launching the paid service, ClassDojo hit profitability. In 2020, the added dimension of COVID-19 helped ClassDojo triple its revenue and grow to have hundreds of thousands of paying subscribers.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2100933" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/DojoGrowth.gif" alt="" width="640" height="360" /></p>
<p>It&#8217;s a lesson in how a venture-backed startup can successfully live for years without any plans to monetize, grow a super-fan user base, and eventually turn those users into paying customers if the fit is right.</p>
<p>The acceleration of ClassDojo’s business got noticed by Josh Buckley, the new CEO of Product Hunt and a solo capitalist.</p>
<p>“For years, they’ve quietly been building the most adored brand in the industry; kids, teachers and families they serve love it. Their business model follows that vision; they’re focused on serving the consumers, not the ‘system’” Buckley said.</p>
<p>Buckley led a new $30 million financing round for ClassDojo, he tells TechCrunch. The round also includes Superhuman CEO Rahul Vohra, Coda CEO and former Youtube head of product and engineering Shishir Mehrotra, former product lead of growth for Airbnb Lenny Rachitsky, and others.</p>
<p>The financing comes nearly two years after ClassDojo<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/28/classdojo-an-app-to-help-teachers-and-parents-communicate-better-raises-35m/"> raised a $35 million Series C</a> round led by GSV. When new capital is less than the preceding round it usually signals a downround, but Chaudhary says that ClassDojo had a “significant markup on valuation” with the extension round. The trend of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/making-sense-of-3-edtech-extension-rounds/">opportunistic extension rounds</a> has grown for edtech startups recently as the pandemic underscores the need for remote learning innovation.</p>
<h2><strong>ClassDojo’s next act</strong></h2>
<p>With new financing and massive scale, ClassDojo is now trying to evolve from a communication app into a platform that can help students get better learning experiences beyond the one they get from schools.</p>
<p>Chaudhary says that they plan to double ClassDojo’s 55-person team, invest in product, and enter new markets.</p>
<p>“For me, I’d always thought ClassDojo could enable a better future, specifically one where kids&#8217; outcomes aren’t entirely determined by what their ZIP code can offer them,” Chaudhary said. “That’s the kind of future we’ve been building toward.” He likened ClassDojo’s goal as similar to Netflix: provide a broad scope of material for a broad scope of people, not just on-demand political dramas.</p>
<p>ClassDojo is already creating content around topics not discussed in school such as how to fail and how to become an empathetic person, as part of its<a href="https://ideas.classdojo.com/"> Big Idea series.</a> The Beyond School offering helps students set goals and track activities, as well as find activities such as dinner table discussion starters or bedtime meditations.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100905" style="width: 1635px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100905" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2100905 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-screens-2.jpg" alt="" width="1625" height="1112" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-screens-2.jpg 1625w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-screens-2.jpg?resize=150,103 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-screens-2.jpg?resize=300,205 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-screens-2.jpg?resize=768,526 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-screens-2.jpg?resize=680,465 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-screens-2.jpg?resize=1536,1051 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-screens-2.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1625px) 100vw, 1625px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100905" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> ClassDojo</p></div></p>
<p>ClassDojo charges $7.99 a month, or $59.99 annually, for its premium content. The platform is finding small ways to add personalization and spice to its content, such as customized avatars, but further innovation will be key in making its next phase work.</p>
<p>While ClassDojo certainly has a strong user engine to monetize off of, the content game is difficult to win at. Content, to an extent,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/02/booming-edtech-ma-activity-brings-consolidation-to-a-fragmented-sector/"> is commoditized.</a> If you can find a free tutorial on YouTube or Khan Academy, why buy a subscription to an edtech platform that offers the same solution? The commodification of education is good for end-users and is often why startups have a freemium model as a customer acquisition strategy. To convert free users into paying subscribers, edtech startups need to offer differentiated and targeted content.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PJjehnhQsq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/02/booming-edtech-ma-activity-brings-consolidation-to-a-fragmented-sector/">Booming edtech M&#038;A activity brings consolidation to a fragmented sector</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Booming edtech M&#038;A activity brings consolidation to a fragmented sector&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/02/booming-edtech-ma-activity-brings-consolidation-to-a-fragmented-sector/embed/#?secret=PJjehnhQsq" data-secret="PJjehnhQsq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The United States continues to be a dominant market for ClassDojo, which also has users in the United Kingdom, Ireland, United Arab Emirates and more. While some in edtech express concern that United States consistently lags in consumer spending in education, Chaudhary thinks it’s an unfair assessment.</p>
<p>“To believe that, you have to believe that families don&#8217;t care all that much about their kids. And I just don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s true,” he said. “All the ways that American people express their care for children, there’s such a range, from extracurricular to sports camp to moving to the right zip code.”</p>
<p>And with that mindset, ClassDojo thinks that it can become the brand that families turn to when they think about a child’s education.</p>
<p>“I think there’s just like a missing brand in the world right now,” Chaudhary said. “There’s a blank, a lot of fear, uncertainty, and doubt.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JzDFtpwB3n"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/to-win-post-pandemic-edtech-needs-to-start-thinking-big/">To win post-pandemic, edtech needs to start thinking big</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;To win post-pandemic, edtech needs to start thinking big&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/to-win-post-pandemic-edtech-needs-to-start-thinking-big/embed/#?secret=JzDFtpwB3n" data-secret="JzDFtpwB3n" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/classdojos-second-act-comes-with-first-profits/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100899</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The 5 biggest mistakes I made as a first-time startup founder</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/the-5-biggest-mistakes-i-made-as-a-first-time-startup-founder/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/the-5-biggest-mistakes-i-made-as-a-first-time-startup-founder/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 21:33:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100961</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[First-time entrepreneurs are bound to make some major mistakes. The true measure of a serial entrepreneur, I’d submit, is the ability to recognize those mistakes and adapt.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Rami Essaid</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/ramiessaid">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ramiessaid">Rami Essaid</a> is co-founder and CEO at <a href="https://finmark.com/">Finmark</a>, a technology company that provides financial planning and modeling software for startups. He previously was co-founder and CEO at Distil Networks, a bot attack mitigation company acquired by Imperva.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/04/26/internet-privacy-is-the-wrong-conversation/">Internet Privacy Is The Wrong Conversation</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">June 4, 2019 should have been one of the happiest days of my life.</p>
<p>At 11:30 a.m., a <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20190604005577/en/Imperva-to-Acquire-Distil-Networks-the-Industry-Recognized-Leader-in-Bot-Management">press release</a> hit the wire announcing that the cybersecurity company I had spent more than eight years building was being acquired by a larger cybersecurity player.</p>
<p>What’s not to love about a successful exit? I’d be set financially, the investors who had given us $70 million would make money, and the technology we created would get new legs in an organization with broader reach and resources.</p>
<p>Still, I had regrets. For one thing, I initially hadn’t wanted to sell. (More on that later.) For another, I was nagged by the feeling that our company had fallen short of its true potential, and that the reason was me &#8212; specifically, several rookie mistakes I made as a first-time entrepreneur.</p>
<p>I don’t stew about those errors any longer. In fact, I believe my miscues at my first startup will help define my career from here on out. That’s why, as I grow my next company, I’m thinking about not only the things I want to do but those I’d never do again.</p>
<p>Here are five of them.</p>
<h2>Trying to do too much myself</h2>
<p>In management theory terms, I was a “pacesetter.” I’d be the first to jump into any project or task, I’d execute it as quickly as possible and I expected everyone else to keep up. I thought that was how a startup leader acted — super helpful and scrappy.</p>
<p>But it came at a big price: disempowerment of the team. I was hoarding not only control — nobody felt like they personally owned anything &#8212; but also the institutional knowledge that needs to be spread around as a company grows. I became a human GPS: People could follow my directions, but they struggled to find the way themselves. Independent thinking suffered.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			I became a human GPS: People could follow my directions, but they struggled to find the way themselves. Independent thinking suffered.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</span></p>
<p>After a few years, I had a frustrating sense that I had all the answers and no one else did. Well, no wonder.</p>
<p>I’m now leaving the pacesetting to NASCAR and marathons.</p>
<h2>Thinking people can read my mind</h2>
<p>I believed all I had to do was say something once and everyone would get it. I became irritated when that didn’t happen. “We talked about this three months ago,” I’d bark. Intimidated team members would say to themselves, “Yeah, but we really only got 50% of it.”<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/the-5-biggest-mistakes-i-made-as-a-first-time-startup-founder/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100961</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8216;Anti-superficial&#8217; dating app S&#8217;More raises $2.1M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/smore-seed-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/smore-seed-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 21:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adam cohen aslatei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Benson Oak Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dating Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[george church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smore]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[S&#8217;More, a dating app that&#8217;s focused on helping users find more meaningful relationships, announced today that it has raised $2.1 million in seed funding. S&#8217;More (short for &#8220;something more&#8221;) ensures that users can&#8217;t focus on physical appearance, because photos are  initally blurred — they gradually un-blur as you interact with someone. The startup has introduced new [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.smoredate.com">S&#8217;More</a>, a dating app that&#8217;s focused on helping users find more meaningful relationships, announced today that it has raised $2.1 million in seed funding.</p>
<p>S&#8217;More (short for &#8220;something more&#8221;) ensures that users can&#8217;t focus on physical appearance, because photos are  initally blurred — they gradually un-blur as you interact with someone. The startup has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/03/dating-app-smore-adds-blurred-video-chat-and-launches-in-la/">introduced new features like video chat</a> (also blurred initially), and it launched a redesigned app of the beginning of this month — CEO Adam Cohen-Aslatei said it&#8217;s a &#8220;completely rebuilt product&#8221; with new features like real-time conversation prompts and the ability to pay to promote your profile.</p>
<p>Cohen-Aslatei also said that S&#8217;More&#8217;s focus on &#8220;anti-superficial relationships&#8221; is attracting a real audience, with 160,000 downloads in its first year and &#8220;thousands&#8221; of paying users, including a 50% increase in subscriptions after launching the new app in January.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Looking at how dating will evolve after the pandemic, Cohen-Aslatei suggested, &#8220;I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re going back to the way things were.&#8221; He pointed to a<a href="https://www.smoredate.com/q4-smore-survey-2020"> recent survey of S&#8217;More users</a> in which 80% of respondents said they hadn&#8217;t gone on a single live, in-person date in 2020.</p>
<p>&#8220;Do you want to meet for casual encounter on Tinder, or do you have to want to have a conversation get to know a real person on S&#8217;More?&#8221; he said. Assuming that many people will choose the latter, the next question is: &#8220;How do you make discovery fun? There&#8217;s got to be multimedia, video, audio, games, all of those features are part of our product roadmap &#8230; S&#8217;More will feel like Hinge meets Nextdoor.&#8221; (Apparently, there&#8217;s &#8220;a huge cohort&#8221; of users on Nextdoor who are single and looking for relationships.)</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100976" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100976" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2100976" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SMoreApp-Full-Screen-1-1.jpg?w=680" alt="S'More" width="680" height="376" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SMoreApp-Full-Screen-1-1.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SMoreApp-Full-Screen-1-1.jpg?resize=150,83 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SMoreApp-Full-Screen-1-1.jpg?resize=300,166 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SMoreApp-Full-Screen-1-1.jpg?resize=768,425 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SMoreApp-Full-Screen-1-1.jpg?resize=680,376 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SMoreApp-Full-Screen-1-1.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100976" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> S&#8217;More</p></div></p>
<p>The new funding comes from a long list of investors: Benson Oak Ventures, Mark Pincus&#8217; Workplay Ventures, Gaingels VC, Loud Capital/Pride Fund<br />
SideCar Angels, AppLovin Chairman Rafael Vivas, Joshua Black of Apollo Management, Plus Grade CEO Ken Harris, Harvard geneticist George Church, former Meet Group CEO John Abbott, former IMAX CEO Brad Weschler, Aaron and Sharon Stern, Justen Stepka/Enterprise Fund, Boston Harbor Angels, Grit Daily CEO Jordan French, Kind.Fund founder Marty Isaac, Craig Mullett and Dating Group.</p>
<p>Cohen-Asletai told me the funding has already allowed him to hire what he&#8217;s calling a &#8220;founding team,&#8221; including chief architect Long Nguyen, head of operations Sneha Ramanchandran, head of product and design Regina Guinto and senior developer David Lichy.</p>
<p>S&#8217;More is also announcing that it has signed a production deal with producers Elvia Van Es Oliva and Jack Tarantino, who have worked on shows like &#8220;90 Day Fiancé.&#8221; Cohen-Asletai said the startup will work with them to create &#8220;anti-superficial&#8221; dating content for digital platforms and TV networks.</p>
<p>This deal builds on the success of <a href="https://www.instagram.com/smoredate/?hl=en">S&#8217;More Live,</a> the startup&#8217;s celebrity dating show on Instagram Live, which has aired 60 episodes so far.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’re using that show to build our brand, to gain awareness and then &#8230; we&#8217;re actually able to leverage all of the viewers and retarget them with content from S&#8217;More, which has made our cost to acquire a user [very affordable],&#8221; Cohen-Asletai said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="f6gF116wIC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/12/smore-is-a-new-dating-app-that-looks-to-suspend-physical-attraction-for-something-more/">S&#8217;More is a new dating app that looks to suspend physical attraction for something more</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;S&#8217;More is a new dating app that looks to suspend physical attraction for something more&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/12/smore-is-a-new-dating-app-that-looks-to-suspend-physical-attraction-for-something-more/embed/#?secret=f6gF116wIC" data-secret="f6gF116wIC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/smore-seed-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100936</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple says iOS 14.4 fixes three security bugs &#8216;actively exploited&#8217; by hackers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/apple-says-ios-14-4-fixes-three-security-bugs-under-active-attack/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/apple-says-ios-14-4-fixes-three-security-bugs-under-active-attack/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 20:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tablet computers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vulnerability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100914</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple has released iOS 14.4 with security fixes for three vulnerabilities, said to be under active attack by hackers. The technology giant said in its security update pages for iOS and iPadOS 14.4 that the three bugs affecting iPhones and iPads &#8220;may have been actively exploited.&#8221; Details of the vulnerabilities are scarce, and an Apple [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple has released iOS 14.4 with security fixes for three vulnerabilities, said to be under active attack by hackers.</p>
<p>The technology giant said in <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212146">its security update pages for iOS and iPadOS 14.4</a> that the three bugs affecting iPhones and iPads &#8220;may have been actively exploited.&#8221; Details of the vulnerabilities are scarce, and an Apple spokesperson declined to comment beyond what&#8217;s in the advisory.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not known who is actively exploiting the vulnerabilities, or who might have fallen victim. Apple did not say if the attack was targeted against a small subset of users or if it was a wider attack. Apple granted anonymity to the individual who submitted the bug, the advisory said.</p>
<p>Two of the bugs were found in WebKit, the browser engine that powers the Safari browser, and the Kernel, the core of the operating system. Some successful exploits use sets of vulnerabilities chained together, rather than a single flaw. It&#8217;s not uncommon for attackers to first target vulnerabilities in a device&#8217;s browsers as a way to get access to the underlying operating system.</p>
<p>Apple said additional details would be available soon, but did not say when.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a rare admission by Apple, which prides itself on its security image, that its customers might be under active attack by hackers.</p>
<p>In 2019, Google security researchers <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/29/google-iphone-secretly-hacked/">found a number of malicious websites</a> laced with code that quietly hacked into victims&#8217; iPhones. TechCrunch revealed that the attack was part of an operation, likely by the Chinese government, to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/31/china-google-iphone-uyghur/">spy on Uyghur Muslims</a>. In response, Apple disputed some of Google&#8217;s findings in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/06/apple-doesnt-want-google-stoking-fear-about-serious-ios-security-exploits/">an equally rare public statement</a>, for which Apple faced more criticism for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/06/apple-doesnt-want-google-stoking-fear-about-serious-ios-security-exploits/">underplaying the severity</a> of the attack.</p>
<p>Last month, internet watchdog Citizen Lab found dozens of journalists had their iPhones hacked with a previously unknown vulnerability <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/20/citizen-lab-iphone-nso-group/">to install spyware</a> developed by Israel-based NSO Group.</p>
<p>In the absence of details, iPhone and iPad users should update to iOS 14.4 as soon as possible.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IQ7B0P2qc8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/20/citizen-lab-iphone-nso-group/">Dozens of journalists&#8217; iPhones hacked with NSO &#8216;zero-click&#8217; spyware, says Citizen Lab</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Dozens of journalists&#8217; iPhones hacked with NSO &#8216;zero-click&#8217; spyware, says Citizen Lab&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/20/citizen-lab-iphone-nso-group/embed/#?secret=IQ7B0P2qc8" data-secret="IQ7B0P2qc8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/apple-says-ios-14-4-fixes-three-security-bugs-under-active-attack/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100914</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tweetbot 6 released with new subscription pricing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/tweetbot-6-released-with-new-subscription-pricing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/tweetbot-6-released-with-new-subscription-pricing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 20:02:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tapbots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tweetbot]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100922</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tapbots, the company behind Tweetbot, has released a major update for the iPhone and iPad. Tweetbot 6 is now available in the App store. While there aren’t a lot of visual changes, there are a couple of important things happening under the hood. First, Tweetbot 6 is using Twitter’s API v2. An API is an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tapbots, the company behind Tweetbot, has released a major update for the iPhone and iPad. <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/tweetbot-6-for-twitter/id1527500834">Tweetbot 6</a> is now available in the App store. While there aren’t a lot of visual changes, there are a couple of important things happening under the hood.</p>
<p>First, Tweetbot 6 is using <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/16/twitter-introduces-a-new-fully-rebuilt-developer-api-launching-next-week/">Twitter’s API v2</a>. An API is an interface that lets two applications or services interact with each other. In today’s case, Tweetbot uses Twitter’s API to interact with the service.</p>
<p>And third-party developers can only do what Twitter lets them do. For many years, Twitter’s API has been somewhat limited, especially if you’ve been trying to build a full-fledged Twitter client. But API v2 surfaces some missing features.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For instance, Tweetbot 6 can now display polls. Before that, polls simply didn’t appear in the timeline. Similarly, Tweetbot 6 displays preview cards, which let you preview linked content without having to click on them. Some features are still missing, such as stories.</p>
<p>There are some minor changes with Tweetbot 6, such as new interface themes, a new feature that lets you select Chrome or Firefox as browser options for links and some tweaks in the app design.</p>
<p>The business model is changing as well. Instead of paying to download the app, you can now download a free app with many restrictions — for instance, you can’t tweet. When you’re ready, you can subscribe to unlock all features for $0.99 per month or $5.99 per year.</p>
<p>This change should ensure the future of the app. Tapbots says Tweetbot 6 is currently in early access. The company plans to add more features down the road.</p>
<p>And if you’re using Tweetbot 5 right now, the app is still working fine. You can re-download the app from the ‘Purchased’ section in the App Store.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Tweetbot-6.png" alt="" width="1024" height="869" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2100930" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Tweetbot-6.png 1980w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Tweetbot-6.png?resize=150,127 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Tweetbot-6.png?resize=300,255 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Tweetbot-6.png?resize=768,652 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Tweetbot-6.png?resize=680,577 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Tweetbot-6.png?resize=1536,1303 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Tweetbot-6.png?resize=50,42 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IdENlcY88a"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/16/twitter-introduces-a-new-fully-rebuilt-developer-api-launching-next-week/">Twitter introduces a new, fully rebuilt developer API, launching next week</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter introduces a new, fully rebuilt developer API, launching next week&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/16/twitter-introduces-a-new-fully-rebuilt-developer-api-launching-next-week/embed/#?secret=IdENlcY88a" data-secret="IdENlcY88a" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/tweetbot-6-released-with-new-subscription-pricing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100922</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sony tempts professionals with the top-shelf, top-tier Alpha 1</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/sonys-tempts-professionals-with-the-top-shelf-top-tier-alpha-1/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/sonys-tempts-professionals-with-the-top-shelf-top-tier-alpha-1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 19:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cameras]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sony alpha]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100818</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sony is making a play for the top end of the professional digital camera world, where videographers and sports photographers demand immaculate image quality at high resolutions in short order. The new Alpha 1 beats pretty much everything on the market on paper, but it&#8217;ll set you back a cool $6,500. This is, of course, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Sony is making a play for the top end of the professional digital camera world, where videographers and sports photographers demand immaculate image quality at high resolutions in short order. The new Alpha 1 beats pretty much everything on the market on paper, but it&#8217;ll set you back a cool $6,500.</p>
<p>This is, of course, well above the price range for ordinary consumers and even spendy enthusiasts and &#8220;prosumers.&#8221; It&#8217;s a professional tool, and in this range Canon has historically been the go-to with its 1D series, and more recently its R5, a full-frame mirrorless that leapfrogged the competition <a href="https://www.dpreview.com/reviews/buying-guide-best-cameras-over-2500">to great acclaim last year</a>. But Sony clearly means to leapfrog the R5 in turn.</p>
<p>The Canon R5 ticked all the right boxes: full frame sensor, 45 megapixels at 20 frames per second, an excellent EVF, in-body image stabilization, and 8K video. Sony ticks them all too&#8230; but harder.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2100898" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_tilt_low.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100898" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2100898" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_tilt_low.jpg" alt="Rear view of the Sony Alpha 1 camera showing its screen and viewfinder." width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_tilt_low.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_tilt_low.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_tilt_low.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_tilt_low.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_tilt_low.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_tilt_low.jpg?resize=1536,964 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_tilt_low.jpg?resize=2048,1285 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_tilt_low.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2100898" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sony</p></div></p>
<p>The Alpha 1 will send down its 50 megapixel stills at 30 frames per second and with no viewfinder blackout (plus the backside-illuminated sensor will be more sensitive); its EVF has nearly twice the pixels and can refresh twice as fast, 240 fps; its 8K video is born at a higher resolution (the Sony uses the full 8.6K and downrezzes); it&#8217;ll shoot for half an hour without overheating (an R5 quirk); and so on and so forth.</p>
<p>Sony seems to have deliberately outdone Canon&#8217;s flagship in every way possible, though with no consideration for cost: the R5 goes for about $3800, while the A1 is $6500.</p>
<p>Yet photographers are no strangers to spending that kind of cash on a tool of the trade (a lens can run you as much or more). Anyone who shoots sports or nature knows that 30 fps instead of 20 fps may mean the difference between getting a cover shot and nothing at all. Visual effects artists who work closely with footage peep pixels all day will be able to tell an R5 8K from an A1 8K. Will it matter? Maybe, maybe not. Would you take the risk or pay extra to eliminate it?</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100900" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_top.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100900" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2100900" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_top.jpg" alt="Top view of the Sony Alpha 1 camera showing its controls." width="1024" height="631" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_top.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_top.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_top.jpg?resize=300,185 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_top.jpg?resize=768,473 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_top.jpg?resize=680,419 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_top.jpg?resize=1536,946 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_top.jpg?resize=2048,1262 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Alpha1_top.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2100900" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sony</p></div></p>
<p>If it&#8217;s merely a question of money to get <em>the best</em> instead of <em>almost the best</em>, there are a lot of people out there who will write that check without a second thought. Of course, the R5 was released half a year ago and its successor (the &#8220;Mark II&#8221;) may change that calculus again.</p>
<p>To be clear, the R5 and A1 are both far more camera than most people will ever need. They&#8217;re the bleeding edge of the industry — an industry that has been shrinking steadily for years. Battling fiercely now over professionals may have long-lasting effects as bit players get edged out, unable to compete. It&#8217;s an investment in the markets that they think will last despite the constant creeping encroachment of smartphones.</p>
<p>More importantly for the rest of us, competition like this in the camera industry is good because it produces advances that trickle down to the models we can actually afford. Not that anyone really needs 8K, but that improved sensor readout and EVF sure would be nice to have.</p>
<p><a href="https://pressroom.pixelshift.studio/groundbreaking-sony-alpha-1-camera-marks-a-new-era-in-professional-imaging#">You can read more about the Alpha 1&#8217;s specs here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/sonys-tempts-professionals-with-the-top-shelf-top-tier-alpha-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100818</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Get feedback on your pitch deck from tech leaders on Extra Crunch Live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/get-feedback-on-your-pitch-deck-from-tech-leaders-on-extra-crunch-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/get-feedback-on-your-pitch-deck-from-tech-leaders-on-extra-crunch-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 19:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch live announcement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100826</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Live 2.0 launches next week! Among several improvements, we&#8217;re thrilled to ramp up the Pitch Deck Teardown. In short, folks can submit their pitch decks to get feedback from investors and founders alike. The importance of the pitch deck can&#8217;t be underestimated. It is often the first point of contact between a company [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/06/extra-crunch-live-is-back-in-2021-connecting-founders-with-tech-giants-and-each-other/">Extra Crunch Live 2.0</a> launches next week! Among several improvements, we&#8217;re thrilled to ramp up the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/what-vcs-want-in-a-pitch-deck/">Pitch Deck Teardown</a>.</p>
<p>In short, folks can <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/Lutrgz8Q">submit their pitch decks</a> to get feedback from investors and founders alike.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary">The importance of the pitch deck can&#8217;t be underestimated. It is often the first point of contact between a company and venture investors, but how investors consume a pitch deck (and what they <em>really</em> think) is also a bit of a black box.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Are they speed-flipping through the slides or taking their time? Do they prefer more information on the team or context on the industry? More numbers or more words? How many slides is the right number of slides?</p>
<p>There are too many questions to count, and often very few answers. But we’re popping the lid off of that black box with the Pitch Deck Teardown. We’ve done Pitch Deck Teardowns at events like Disrupt and Early Stage 2020, and this year we’re cranking it up a notch.</p>
<p>Anyone can submit their pitch deck and hear what our guests, tech leaders across the industry, think of them. (Important note: Extra Crunch members will be prioritized on the list of decks we choose to show during the episode.)</p>
<p>We recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/06/extra-crunch-live-is-back-in-2021-connecting-founders-with-tech-giants-and-each-other/">shared what you can expect from Extra Crunch Live in 2021</a>. Here’s a refresher:</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Series A</b> – Learn how others have fundraised! We’ll have a segment dedicated to hearing from founder/investor duos who walk us through the Series A pitch deck that led to investment.</li>
<li><b>Pitch Deck Teardowns</b> – Folks will have the opportunity to submit their pitch deck and get feedback from our guests, which will include VCs and founders (<a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/Lutrgz8Q">You can submit their pitch decks right here!</a>).</li>
<li><b>Live Pitch-offs</b> – Audience members can raise their hand to practice their elevator pitch in front of the audience and get real-time feedback from VCs.</li>
<li><b>Networking!!</b> – The Extra Crunch membership is a community. ECL will be an opportunity to meet your fellow audience members, even in a virtual environment. Who knows? Maybe you’ll meet your next co-founder or investor!</li>
<li><b>Consistency</b> – ECL will always be at <b>12pm PT/3pm ET on Wednesdays</b>. When it comes to your calendar, set it and forget it.</li>
</ul>
<p>We&#8217;ll announce all the speakers joining us in February tomorrow! Stay tuned!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/get-feedback-on-your-pitch-deck-from-tech-leaders-on-extra-crunch-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100826</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mealco raises $7M to launch new delivery-centric restaurants</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/mealco-raises-7m-to-launch-new-delivery-centric-restaurants/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/mealco-raises-7m-to-launch-new-delivery-centric-restaurants/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 19:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100822</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mealco, a startup promising to help chefs launch new restaurants designed around delivery, is announcing that it has raised $7 million in seed funding. It&#8217;s probably not news to anyone reading this that opening a restaurant can be an expensive, risky proposition — and of course, many restaurants have gone out of business during the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.mealco.co">Mealco</a>, a startup promising to help chefs launch new restaurants designed around delivery, is announcing that it has raised $7 million in seed funding.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s probably not news to anyone reading this that opening a restaurant can be an expensive, risky proposition — and of course, many restaurants have gone out of business during the pandemic.</p>
<p>But founder and CEO Daniel Simon (who was previously a developer and product lead at Applicaster, and has also worked with Tel Aviv restaurant group R2M) said that even in the best of times, it can take $1 or $2 million to get started, and &#8220;if you want to hit the ground running, 98% of your focus is not on the food or the customers.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>With Mealco, on the other hand, there&#8217;s no need to sign a lease or any other upfront costs for the chefs, and they get to focus on actually creating the dishes and the menu. Mealco locally sources the ingredients, which are then cooked using the startup&#8217;s kitchen infrastructure and offered for delivery via the standard delivery apps — Uber Eats, DoorDash, Postmates and Seamless.</p>
<p>Simon said that with Mealco, the process of getting a new restaurant up and running only takes six to eight weeks: &#8220;We tell [the chefs] they don’t need to chop any more onions or tomatoes. There&#8217;s Mealco software that can tell employees at the Mealco kitchen how to prepare [each dish].&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100860" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100860" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2100860" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3588.jpg?w=680" alt="Cayenne" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3588.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3588.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3588.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3588.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3588.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3588.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3588.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3588.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3588.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/IMG_3588.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100860" class="wp-caption-text">Cayenne. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Mealco</p></div></p>
<p>Mealco also provides support around branding, marketing and social media, and gives chefs access to a dashboard with real-time data about menu performance and customer feedback, which can allow them to quickly make adjustments as needed. The chef, he said, can &#8220;manage the restaurant from their mobile phone.&#8221;</p>
<p>The startup has already launched two restaurants delivering in Manhattan, Brooklyn and Queens — Mexican restaurant <a href="https://tributo.com">Tributo</a> and Nashville hot chicken restaurant <a href="https://eatcayenne.com">Cayenne</a> (the latter with chef Hillary Sterling). And it says there are 50 chefs on the waitlist.</p>
<p>Asked whether any of Mealco&#8217;s partners mind being separated from the food preparation and the dining experience, Simon said it depends on the chef.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you want to open a single location and be in the kitchen every morning,&#8221; then he said Mealco isn&#8217;t for you. &#8220;That not wrong or right, it&#8217;s a preference … But most chefs are creators, they&#8217;re artists. They express themselves through food.&#8221; And in his view, Mealco allows them to focus on that creativity.</p>
<p>Rucker Park Capital led the round with participation from FJLabs, Reshape, 2048.vc, Oceans Ventures, WLP and angel investors including former Seamless CEO Jonathan Zabusky. Simon said the plan is to launch throughout New York City and surrounding areas this year, before moving on to new cities next year.</p>
<p>&#8220;We had the opportunity to see the evolution of the food ecosystem firsthand in the past few years,&#8221; said Wes Tang-Wymer, general partner at Rucker Park Capital, in a statement. &#8220;The time is ripe to embrace all these advances to launch new brands in a new format. In Mealco, we found the most compelling model to push the frontier of restaurant innovation further by empowering chefs to take &#8216;idea-to-table&#8217; faster and cheaper than ever before.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="D27ift5NxU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/justkitchen-is-using-cloud-kitchens-to-create-the-next-generation-of-restaurant-franchising/">JustKitchen is using cloud kitchens to create the next generation of restaurant franchising</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;JustKitchen is using cloud kitchens to create the next generation of restaurant franchising&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/justkitchen-is-using-cloud-kitchens-to-create-the-next-generation-of-restaurant-franchising/embed/#?secret=D27ift5NxU" data-secret="D27ift5NxU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/mealco-raises-7m-to-launch-new-delivery-centric-restaurants/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100822</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter&#8217;s new API platform now opened to academic researchers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitters-new-api-platform-now-opened-to-academic-researchers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitters-new-api-platform-now-opened-to-academic-researchers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 19:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[researchers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100686</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter today is rolling out a new product track on its API platform, as part of its ongoing efforts to rebuild the Twitter API from the ground up. The track, which aims to serve the needs of the academic research community&#8217;s efforts, offers broader access to the Twitter archive and fewer restrictions on tweet retrievals, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter today is <a href="https://twittercommunity.com/t/introducing-the-new-academic-research-product-track/148632">rolling out</a> a new product track on its API platform, as part of its ongoing efforts to <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/developer/en_us/topics/tools/2020/introducing_new_twitter_api.html">rebuild the Twitter API</a> from the ground up. The track, which aims to serve the needs of the academic research community&#8217;s efforts, offers broader access to the Twitter archive and fewer restrictions on tweet retrievals, so researchers can access the entire history of the public conversation on Twitter&#8217;s platform.</p>
<p>In addition to gaining access to all the Twitter API v2 endpoints released to date and elevated access, researchers will gain access to more precise filtering capabilities.</p>
<p>Specifically, they&#8217;ll be able to access the full-archive search endpoint, which offers access to everything being said on Twitter. They can narrow searches for these historical tweets using start time and end time parameters.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2100706" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100706" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2100706" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.30-AM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="398" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.30-AM.jpg 2694w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.30-AM.jpg?resize=150,88 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.30-AM.jpg?resize=300,176 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.30-AM.jpg?resize=768,449 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.30-AM.jpg?resize=680,398 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.30-AM.jpg?resize=1536,899 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.30-AM.jpg?resize=2048,1198 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.30-AM.jpg?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100706" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twitter</p></div></p>
<p>Researchers will also gain a significantly higher monthly cap on the number of tweets they can pull using the Twitter API v2. While on the Basic level of API access, this cap is set to 500,000. The Basic level of access on the Academic Research track is an initial monthly cap of up to 10 million tweets. This applies to the Recent Search, Filtered Stream, Full-archive search, and user tweet and mentions timelines endpoints, Twitter says.</p>
<p>The Academic Research track will gain access to certain operators that aren&#8217;t otherwise available, too, with the goal of helping them pull more precise user data. Today, these include: <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">$ (aka cashtag), bio, bio_name, bio_location, place, place_country, point_radius, bounding_box, -is:nullcast, has:cashtags and has:geo. </span></p>
<p>Researchers can also add 1,000 concurrent rules when using the filter stream endpoint, instead of the limit of 25 available in the Standard track. Queries in the recent search endpoint can be 1,024 characters long, compared with 512 characters in the Standard track.</p>
<p>Because of the elevated levels of access, those who want to gain access to the Academic Research product track have to first <a href="https://developer.twitter.com/en/portal/petition/use-case">submit an application</a>.</p>
<p>All applicants have to either be a master’s student, doctoral candidate, post-doc, faculty or research-focused employee at an academic institution or university. They will also <a href="https://developer.twitter.com/en/solutions/academic-research/application-info">need to have</a> a clearly defined research objective and must be able to detail their specific plans for how they intend to use, analyze and share Twitter data from their research.</p>
<p>Plus, the data used from the Academic Research product track can&#8217;t be used for any <a href="https://developer.twitter.com/en/developer-terms/commercial-terms">commercial</a> purposes, Twitter notes.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100707" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100707" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2100707" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.48-AM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="382" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.48-AM.jpg 2830w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.48-AM.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.48-AM.jpg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.48-AM.jpg?resize=768,431 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.48-AM.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.48-AM.jpg?resize=1536,862 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.48-AM.jpg?resize=2048,1149 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-26-at-10.42.48-AM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100707" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twitter</p></div></p>
<p>Academic researchers have been taking advantage of the Twitter API since its first introduction in 2006 and have used the data to study a variety of topics, Twitter says, like <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">​<a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2020/disclosing-removed-networks-to-our-archive-of-state-linked-information.html">state-backed efforts to disrupt the public conversation</a>​, ​<a href="https://developer.twitter.com/en/use-cases/success-stories/uc-davis-max-planck-institute">floods and climate change</a>, ​<a href="https://developer.twitter.com/en/use-cases/success-stories/penn">attitudes and perceptions about COVID-19​</a> and​ ​<a href="https://developer.twitter.com/en/use-cases/success-stories/hatelab">efforts to promote healthy conversation online</a>​.</span></p>
<p>However, the earlier version of the Twitter API didn&#8217;t make it easy for researchers to gain access to Twitter data &#8212; something the company wanted to correct with API v2.</p>
<p>Twitter to date has catered to the research community in other ways, with additions like a website dedicated to academic research, updates to its developer policy to make it easier to reproduce and validate others&#8217; research, and even special endpoints, like <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/developer/en_us/topics/tools/2020/covid19_public_conversation_data.html">the COVID-19 stream endpoint</a> released in April 2020. But it hasn&#8217;t fully thought through, until the API v2, how it could build tools that would actually aid researchers in doing their work, instead of the researchers having to figure out ways to work around Twitter&#8217;s limitations.</p>
<p>The Academic Research product track was tested in private beta starting in Oct. 2020, and now this is being opened more broadly, where it will be made freely available.</p>
<p>Twitter says it&#8217;s planning to add higher levels of access across all its product tracks in the future, including this one, in time. The later levels will help researchers who need even more data than what&#8217;s being offered with today&#8217;s launch. Twitter also noted it&#8217;s looking into adding flexible access as well, which would help account for times when developers were consuming more or less data throughout the year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9KyubSxmQz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitter-acquires-revue/">Twitter acquires newsletter platform Revue</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter acquires newsletter platform Revue&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitter-acquires-revue/embed/#?secret=9KyubSxmQz" data-secret="9KyubSxmQz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitters-new-api-platform-now-opened-to-academic-researchers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100686</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>These investors want to back &#8216;ridiculously early&#8217; female-led African startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/these-investors-want-to-back-ridiculously-early-female-led-african-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/these-investors-want-to-back-ridiculously-early-female-led-african-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 18:59:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eloho omame]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firstcheck africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[odunayo eweniyi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In 2019, female-led companies received less than 5 percent of the global venture capital. Bringing it to Africa, only 10 percent of the West African startups that cumulatively raised $1 million had at least one female co-founder in the past decade. There are many stats to back up the underrepresentation of women in starting a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2019, female-led companies </span><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/elizahaverstock/2020/12/08/covid-economy-hits-women-harder-in-yet-another-area-venture-capital-funding/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">received less than 5 percent </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">of the global venture capital. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bringing it to Africa, only </span><a href="https://techpoint.africa/2020/10/28/only-10-of-female-founded-startups-in-west-africa-have-raised-up-to-1-million-since-2010/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">10 percent of the West African startups</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">cumulatively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> raised $1 million had at least one female co-founder in the past decade</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are many stats to back up the underrepresentation of women </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">starting a company, raising money and general involvement in technology where the global tech workforce comprises 28.8% women</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a male-dominated space, programs geared toward supporting female entrepreneurs have emerged to close the gap on all fronts</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, for those centered around female founders, most are quick to offer mentorship and training but tend to ignore the importance of raising money</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://www.firstcheck.africa/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">FirstCheck Africa</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a female-focused angel fund that launched yesterday, is hoping to address this challenge</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the fund, &#8220;fixing capital access for female tech entrepreneurs in Africa needs an intentional, female-led approach</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">FirstCheck Africa </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was founded by</span> <a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/elohogm"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eloho Omame</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/odunayoeweniyi"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Odunayo Eweniyi</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Omame is the MD of </span><a href="https://endeavornigeria.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Endeavor</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Nigeria</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a program for high-impact entrepreneurs, and Eweniyi is the co-founder and COO of </span><a href="https://www.piggyvest.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Piggyvest</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a Nigerian fintech startup</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Omame&#8217;s experience working with founders and managing a VC firm (Amari Ventures) and Odunayo&#8217;s as a founder will prove vital to what FirstCheck Africa hopes to achieve: Making it easy for African women to raise capital and invest in tech</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fund will provide between $15,000 to $25,000 in six women this year in exchange for modest equity. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">FirstCheck Africa plans to see each woman or female-led team through the ideation stage to a significant pre-seed round within 12 months</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We know we can generate solid long-term returns by investing in women, so we&#8217;ll write female founders&#8217; first checks and be their earliest believers</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. We&#8217;re not afraid to invest </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ridiculously</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> early in great women,&#8221; an excerpt in the <a href="https://firstcheckhq.medium.com/announcing-firstcheck-africa-dbc72b1f7180" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">statement</a> read.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fund also specifies that it is open to investing in mixed co-founder teams, with at least one woman. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">But the caveat is &#8220;only where it’s clear that the woman is a true partner and decision-maker, with a significant, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">equitable</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> split of the founder equity</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Already, FirstCheck has received over 600 applications from African female-led startups, Omame told TechCrunch</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">But she iterates that while only six will </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be selected</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, FirstCheck is in no hurry to announce the deals when asked how soon the firm expects to write its first check</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We’ve been transparent with our investment goal as we’re backing up to six women-led, technology-driven businesses this year,&#8221; she said</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. &#8220;Outside that, there’s little interest from Odun or me to rush to announce deals. The work we’re doing is important and necessary, but it will take time.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you think about it, backing six startups in its first year is an impressive goal. For context, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/early-stage-african-vc-firm-microtraction-reports-portfolio-boom-despite-the-weight-of-covid-19/">Microtraction, an already established early-stage VC firm</a>, invested in seven startups last year. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">To</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> achieve that, FirstCheck will need to garner support from local and international investors that are intentional about closing the gender funding gap on the continent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Without providing specifics around how much the fund is looking to raise, Omame says this is already happening</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That said, FirstCheck will be building a female-led investor community for women interested in backing startups by writing smaller checks</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The notion behind this is to create opportunities for women around the continent to invest at more comfortable levels. And f</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">or African female entrepreneurs who need pre-seed and seed funding, the launch of FirstCheck is a plus to their selection pool</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The firm now joins Rising Tide Africa and SA-based Dazzle Angels among others as one of the few angel funds targeted to African female-led startups</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/these-investors-want-to-back-ridiculously-early-female-led-african-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100611</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google open sources Tilt Brush VR software as it shuts down internal development</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/google-open-sources-tilt-brush-vr-software-as-it-shuts-down-the-tools-internal-development/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/google-open-sources-tilt-brush-vr-software-as-it-shuts-down-the-tools-internal-development/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 18:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Augmented Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tilt Brush]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100812</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As Facebook and Apple begin to fire up more projects in the AR/VR world, Google has spent the last year shutting down most of their existing projects in that space. Today, the folks at Google announced they had ended active development of Tilt Brush, a VR painting app that was one of virtual reality&#8217;s early [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As Facebook and Apple begin to fire up more projects in the AR/VR world, Google has spent the last year shutting down most of their existing projects in that space.</p>
<p>Today, the folks at Google announced they had ended active development of Tilt Brush, a VR painting app that was one of virtual reality&#8217;s early hit pieces of software. The app allowed users to use virtual reality controllers as brushes to construct digital sculptures and environments.</p>
<p>While the company will not be pushing any new updates to the app, they did announce that they will be open sourcing the code on github for developers to build their own experiences and customizations. Google also notes that the app will continue to be available in the app stores on VR headsets.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;[W]e want to continue supporting the artists using Tilt Brush by putting it in your hands,&#8221;a blog post from Google reads. &#8220;This means open sourcing Tilt Brush, allowing everyone to learn how we built the project, and encouraging them to take it in directions that are near and dear to them.&#8221;</p>
<p>Google acquired the small studio behind Tilt Brush called Skillman &amp; Hackett back in 2015.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Tilt Brush co-creator Patrick Hackett announced he was leaving Google and would be joining the studio I-Illusions, the game studio behind VR title Space Pirate Trainer. According to LinkedIn, co-founder Drew Skillman stopped working on the VR project back in 2018 and now is part of the Stadia team at Google.</p>
<p>Last month, Google <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/google-shutting-down-poly-3d-content-platform/">shut down Poly</a>, its 3D object library which allowed users to share digital art including design made in the Tilt Brush software.</p>
<p>A Google spokesperson declined to comment further.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Annddd here we go:<a href="https://t.co/dRfC5jR5Yg">https://t.co/dRfC5jR5Yg</a></p>
<p>To some, this may look like the end of Tilt Brush.  To me, this is immortality.<br />Cheers to the team who helped get us here!</p>
<p>&mdash; Patrick Hackett (@phacktweets) <a href="https://twitter.com/phacktweets/status/1354113177546416128?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 26, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/google-open-sources-tilt-brush-vr-software-as-it-shuts-down-the-tools-internal-development/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100812</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Tula Mic is a powerful portable recorder that doubles as a great USB-C microphone</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/the-tula-mic-is-a-powerful-portable-recorder-that-doubles-as-a-great-usb-c-microphone/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/the-tula-mic-is-a-powerful-portable-recorder-that-doubles-as-a-great-usb-c-microphone/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 18:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile devices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recording]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USB-C]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100770</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tula is a new company founded with the specific purpose of developing user-friendly hardware and software for sound capture, and its debut product, the Tula Mic, is now shipping after a successful crowdfunding campaign last year. Tula Mic is both a USB-C microphone input for computers and mobile devices, and also a dedicated recorder that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tula is a new company founded with the specific purpose of developing user-friendly hardware and software for sound capture, and its debut product, the Tula Mic, is now shipping after a successful crowdfunding campaign last year. <a href="https://tulamics.com">Tula Mic</a> is both a USB-C microphone input for computers and mobile devices, and also a dedicated recorder that has built-in storage and its own battery that can provide up to 14 hours of continuous use. It&#8217;s a strong intro offering that fits a lot of user needs at an attractive price point.</p>
<h2>Basics</h2>
<p>The Tula Mic is small — it&#8217;s definitely best described as &#8220;hand-held,&#8221; taking up roughly the size and surface area of a deck of cards. The physical design includes microphone capsules up top, with control buttons running along either side, and a USB-C charging port in the middle of the back of the hardware. The top-left side also features a standard 3.5mm port, which can be used not only for headphones for monitoring and playback, but also for input for lavalier microphones, effectively turning the Tula into a body pack.</p>
<p>Just below the grill that contains the recording capsule, there are two lights on the face of the Tula Mic. These include a gain/peaking indicator and a recording indicator, providing you with simple but effective visual feedback. There&#8217;s 8 GB of built-in memory on board, and that built-in rechargeable battery offers up to 14 hours of continuous recording. Inside, there are not just one, but two recording capsules, including one with a cardioid recording pattern for capturing audio from one user speaking toward the mic, and one with an omni pickup pattern for recording room sound, best for events or interviews.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Tula Mic comes with a stand attached, which folds up and attaches magnetically to its midsection for easy transport. This is also removable and can be swapped out for a standard microphone-mount threaded attachment point. It&#8217;s a simple and elegant design that proves very handy in active use, but the proprietary mounting method here means that if you ever lose one or the other of these accessories, you can&#8217;t just pick up a generic one like you could if they&#8217;d used a standard tripod thread instead, for instance.</p>
<h2>Design and performance</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2100814" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100814" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2100814" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/tula-mic.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="685" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/tula-mic.jpg 1598w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/tula-mic.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/tula-mic.jpg?resize=300,201 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/tula-mic.jpg?resize=768,514 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/tula-mic.jpg?resize=680,455 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/tula-mic.jpg?resize=1536,1028 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/tula-mic.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100814" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Darrell Etherington</p></div></p>
<p>The Tula Mic&#8217;s design definitely conveys retro aesthetics, and its flat-sided oval shape is immediately eye-catching and recognizable. The unique look also provides great hand-holdability, and when used in stand mode, it&#8217;s immediately clear how a user should address the mic in use. The flip-down stand is elegant and keeps the mic firmly in place, thanks to its weighted metal construction.</p>
<p>The controls located down either side of the Tula Mic are each labelled, but I found that I definitely had to repeatedly reference the included user guide before I could consistently remember what each of them did. The icons are helpful, but not necessarily immediately intuitive. It&#8217;s nice to have physical controls, however, rather than touch sensitive surfaces or a screen for input.</p>
<p>The most important thing to note about the Tula Mic&#8217;s performance is that it sounds great, in both wired USB-C and standalone recorder mode. Having the ability to switch between omni and cardioid pickup patterns is also immensely useful in terms of the mic&#8217;s versatility as a one-size-fits-most solution, since you can use it for podcasting, for recording a class or lecture, and for recording a two-person interview all with equal ease and very high-quality results.</p>
<p>Lastly, Tula includes a built-in local noise cancellation algorithm, which allows you to capture a brief recording of room tone in order to automatically remove it from your subsequent recording. It&#8217;s a very handy and surprisingly effective feature, and one that should provide big benefits in terms of later using recordings from the mic with transcription services like Otter.ai.</p>
<h2>Bottom line</h2>
<p>At $199, the <a href="https://tulamics.com">Tula Mic</a> is already priced to match many of the leading USB microphones on the market today. The fact that it&#8217;s also a full-featured standalone digital recorder, many of which are also priced at or near that mark, really makes it an obvious choice for anyone looking for portable recording flexibility in a compact package.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gUcqN1UiBj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/sennheisers-mke-200-on-camera-microphone-is-the-perfect-home-videoconferencing-upgrade/">Sennheiser&#8217;s MKE 200 on-camera microphone is the perfect home videoconferencing upgrade</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Sennheiser&#8217;s MKE 200 on-camera microphone is the perfect home videoconferencing upgrade&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/sennheisers-mke-200-on-camera-microphone-is-the-perfect-home-videoconferencing-upgrade/embed/#?secret=gUcqN1UiBj" data-secret="gUcqN1UiBj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/the-tula-mic-is-a-powerful-portable-recorder-that-doubles-as-a-great-usb-c-microphone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100770</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zero, a plastic-free grocery-delivery startup, to launch in LA</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/zero-a-plastic-free-grocery-delivery-startup-to-launch-in-la/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/zero-a-plastic-free-grocery-delivery-startup-to-launch-in-la/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Megan Rose Dickey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 18:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Include company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zero]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100198</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Plastic-free grocery-delivery startup Zero is gearing up to launch in Los Angeles on February 10, after solely operating in the San Francisco Bay Area. Zero works directly with suppliers to sell food and other household items in jars, boxes and other types of sustainable packaging, and offers next-day delivery. Zero works with both big-name brands [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Plastic-free grocery-delivery startup <a href="https://www.zerogrocery.com/">Zero</a> is gearing up to launch in Los Angeles on February 10, after solely operating in the San Francisco Bay Area. Zero works directly with suppliers to sell food and other household items in jars, boxes and other types of sustainable packaging, and offers next-day delivery.</p>
<p>Zero works with both big-name brands like Sightglass Coffee, Annie&#8217;s and Newman&#8217;s Own, as well as emerging vendors that are focused on sustainability, like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/with-another-2-5-million-in-funding-julia-collins-planet-fwd-launches-climate-friendly-snack-brand/">Planet FWD, founded by Zume co-founder Julia Collins</a>.</p>
<p>Zero members pay $25 per month to access discounted prices on food along with free deliveries. Zero is also available without a subscription, but prices on individual items cost a bit more, and delivery costs $7.99.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>I&#8217;ve used Zero a couple of times and overall had a pleasant experience. The selection of food is pretty good, but I wasn&#8217;t able to find certain types of items like tortilla chips and mandarin oranges. On the plus side, Zero sells my favorite candy of all-time, Tony&#8217;s Chocolonely.</p>
<p>In total, Zero founder and CEO Zuleyka Strasner says there are just over 1,100 different items available in the store.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s partly because of the leg work that&#8217;s required to ensure the food manufactures are meeting Zero&#8217;s internal standards for packaging. In the case of chicken, Zero has worked directly with butchers to ensure they package it in compostable paper, which then goes into a compostable resealable bag, Strasner said. That took a lot of time, effort, energy and technology, she said.</p>
<p>Zero does allow plastic at some point in the supply chain process but ensures that plastic is not passed on to consumers. Using chicken as an example again, the chicken starts at the farm and then must travel to one of Zero&#8217;s butcher networks and then to a facility to get packaged and processed.</p>
<p>&#8220;So those farms and those parts of that transportation process do oftentimes involve plastic in there,&#8221; Strasner said. &#8220;And as the company grows, we get involved more and more and more into changing more and more of the processes and removing more and more of the plastic for each of our new manufacturing suppliers. So it&#8217;s always a journey for each farm, to start with that product going out to the customer plastic-free and then working backwards backwards backwards to removing more and more and more plastics.&#8221;</p>
<p>While it would be ideal for all of Zero&#8217;s partners to operate fully plastic-free, Strasner said it was important to make it as easy as possible for farms, suppliers and other stakeholders to get on board, &#8220;rather than setting up a set of rules and regulations that say either you&#8217;re plastic-free from the minute the chicken gets slaughtered all the way to getting it to the customer,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>&#8220;That would not create the shift in the industry that we&#8217;re looking to create.&#8221;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2100243 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Zero-Photography-8-e1611603840201.jpeg" alt="" width="1920" height="1080" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Zero-Photography-8-e1611603840201.jpeg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Zero-Photography-8-e1611603840201.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Zero-Photography-8-e1611603840201.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Zero-Photography-8-e1611603840201.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Zero-Photography-8-e1611603840201.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Zero-Photography-8-e1611603840201.jpeg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Zero-Photography-8-e1611603840201.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></p>
<p>The idea for Zero started to come into fruition for Strasner<strong> </strong>during her honeymoon in the Corn Islands in Nicaragua. During her trip, she was shocked at how much single-use plastic washed up on the shore, she told TechCrunch. Meanwhile, she had seen the zero-waste, anti-plastic movement growing and began to wonder what would happen if she went plastic-free. Going plastic-free made her think more about the supply chain and how foods are packed in the country, she said.</p>
<p>Given her background in technology, she began to think about how technology could be applied to the problem of plastic waste, &#8220;which must be solved within the next seven to 10 years,&#8221; she said. &#8220;Time is truly finite here and that&#8217;s the mission I decided to undertake.&#8221;</p>
<p>Zero began testing in 2018 and officially launched in November 2019. The majority of Zero&#8217;s customers are members and, overall, the company has &#8220;many, many thousands of customers,&#8221; Strasner said.</p>
<p>To date, Zero has raised $4.7 million in funding from investors like Precursor Ventures, Backstage Capital, 1984 and others.</p>
<p>&#8220;We aim to be and we will be the largest sustainability platform in this country,&#8221; Strasner said. &#8220;So whatever you need and desire &#8212; food, homewares or otherwise, certainly plastic-free but also just sustainable in general &#8212; you would come to us. Zero really is a movement beyond just food.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/zero-a-plastic-free-grocery-delivery-startup-to-launch-in-la/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100198</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Airbyte is an open-source data pipeline platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/airbyte-is-an-open-source-data-pipeline-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/airbyte-is-an-open-source-data-pipeline-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 17:52:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbyte]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you’re working for a company that handles a ton of data, chances are your company is constantly moving data from applications, APIs and databases and sending it to a data warehouse or a data lake. There are a few well-known platforms to extract, load and transform data, such as Fivetran and Stitchdata. Airbyte is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If you’re working for a company that handles a ton of data, chances are your company is constantly moving data from applications, APIs and databases and sending it to a data warehouse or a data lake. There are a few well-known platforms to extract, load and transform data, such as <a href="https://fivetran.com">Fivetran</a> and <a href="https://www.stitchdata.com">Stitchdata</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://airbyte.io">Airbyte</a> is building an open-source data pipeline platform. An open-source alternative to Fivetran or Stitchdata is interesting because building and maintaining connectors require a ton of resources. If you’re just starting out with your data pipeline and you don’t have a big team, it creates a barrier to entry.</p>
<p>Sure, existing data pipeline platforms already provide dozens of integrations with popular sources and destinations. Popular sources include Salesforce, Stripe, Marketo, SendGrid, etc. Popular destinations include Redshift, Snowflake and BigQuery.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>But there are a ton of small services that aren’t supported on traditional data pipeline platforms. If you can’t import <em>all</em> your data, you may only have a partial picture of your business.</p>
<p>A lot of companies end up building custom connectors for their applications. With this open-source approach, Airbyte thinks it can foster a community of users to build and maintain thousands of open-source connectors. When a company builds a custom connector, another company can use it, improve it and give back to the community.</p>
<p>“The open-source approach is the right approach,” co-founder and CEO Michel Tricot told me. “If somebody using a connector realizes that it’s broken, they can fix it for the entire community.”</p>
<p>The team behind Airbyte originally started with a product focused on marketing data. They attended Y Combinator and later pivoted because of the coronavirus outbreak. “In a COVID world, there’s no marketing budget,” co-founder John Lafleur told me.</p>
<p>Airbyte connectors run in Docker containers, which means they all operate independently from each other. You can schedule updates, refresh your connectors manually and monitor them individually.</p>
<p>Right now, there are <a href="https://github.com/airbytehq/airbyte/blob/master/docs/integrations/connector-health.md">46 connectors</a> — Airbyte is currently working on certifying them to make sure they’re production-ready. 250 companies are currently using Airbyte.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YQH3BmoxKS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/ex-uber-team-raises-6m-seed-for-geospatial-analytics-platform-unfolded-ai/">Ex-Uber team raises $6M seed for geospatial analytics platform Unfolded.ai</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ex-Uber team raises $6M seed for geospatial analytics platform Unfolded.ai&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/ex-uber-team-raises-6m-seed-for-geospatial-analytics-platform-unfolded-ai/embed/#?secret=YQH3BmoxKS" data-secret="YQH3BmoxKS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/airbyte-is-an-open-source-data-pipeline-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100791</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The long road to the Qualtrics IPO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/qualtrics-ipo-everything-you-need-to-know/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/qualtrics-ipo-everything-you-need-to-know/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 17:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qualtrics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sap]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100290</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Speculation around the Qualtrics public offering is nothing new. All the way back in 2016, CEO Ryan Smith was dropping not-so-subtle hints about his intentions to file for IPO. After a decade bootstrapping, and growing to $50 million in annual revenue, the company was swayed into taking outside capital from Sequoia, and then again from [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Speculation around the Qualtrics public offering is nothing new. All the way back in 2016, CEO Ryan Smith was dropping not-so-subtle hints about his intentions to file for IPO. After a decade bootstrapping, and growing to $50 million in annual revenue, the company was swayed into taking outside capital from Sequoia, and then again from Sequoia, Accel, and Insight Venture Partners.</p>
<p>TechCrunch has written about the entire journey, and considering the unusual circumstances of the public offering paired with Qualtrics&#8217; position outperforming its peer group, we thought it smart to take a look back at how the whole thing came together.</p>
<hr />
<h2 style="text-align: center;">2017</h2>
<p>After years of dodging the question, or offering up vague answers, Smith said the following in an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/10/is-qualtrics-about-to-go-public-a-chat-with-founder-ryan-smith-on-the-ipo-question/">interview with TechCrunch back in 2017</a>:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<blockquote><p>We know that there’s a huge opportunity here and we’re being very thoughtful about it because it’s not about going public. Going public is super easy to do. Just file the S-1 and we’re out,” Smith told [TechCrunch]. “It’s about being public and how that works and getting the house in order to make sure that that’s the case. We’re going to be a great public company. We’re going public.</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TnO1Ipyxxi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/10/is-qualtrics-about-to-go-public-a-chat-with-founder-ryan-smith-on-the-ipo-question/">Is Qualtrics about to go public? A chat with founder Ryan Smith on the IPO question</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Is Qualtrics about to go public? A chat with founder Ryan Smith on the IPO question&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/10/is-qualtrics-about-to-go-public-a-chat-with-founder-ryan-smith-on-the-ipo-question/embed/#?secret=TnO1Ipyxxi" data-secret="TnO1Ipyxxi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Just a couple days later, literally, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/12/qualtrics-waits-on-that-ipo-raises-180-million-at-a-2-5-billion-valuation-instead/">Qualtrics raised $180 million at a $2.5 billion valuation</a>, again from Sequoia, Accel, and Insight Venture Partners. At the time, it was the biggest investment Accel had ever made. The growth of the company was staggering — the experience management startup had gone from $50 million in revenue in 2012 to $250 million in revenue in 2017.</p>
<p>TechCrunch and many others speculated that the massive raise may not signal a delayed IPO, but rather a final financial push before listing on the public markets.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="l1cmVXAYs8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/12/qualtrics-waits-on-that-ipo-raises-180-million-at-a-2-5-billion-valuation-instead/">Qualtrics waits on that IPO, raises $180 million at a $2.5 billion valuation instead</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Qualtrics waits on that IPO, raises $180 million at a $2.5 billion valuation instead&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/12/qualtrics-waits-on-that-ipo-raises-180-million-at-a-2-5-billion-valuation-instead/embed/#?secret=l1cmVXAYs8" data-secret="l1cmVXAYs8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Smith was coy about whether that speculation was warranted:</p>
<blockquote><p>We raised the money because we can. An IPO isn’t an exit. It should be the beginning and we wouldn’t be going out if we didn’t think that more wealth could be created post-IPO.</p></blockquote>
<p>The company also launched its XM platform in 2017, an experience management platform that Smith implied would one day be as ubiquitous as Workday or Salesforce software in every office, but for managing internal feedback and helping organizations uncover key business drivers, predict future customer needs, and retain employees.</p>
<p>Sequoia Capital partner Bryan Schreier said at the time:</p>
<blockquote><p>Qualtrics is an outlier. They have delivered outstanding, accelerating growth at nine-digit revenue numbers all while staying cash flow positive. That is practically unheard of. It’s an incredible sign of confidence in Qualtrics’ continued growth trajectory and the huge market for its new XM Platform that all of its investors have come back to buy as many shares as they could at this new valuation.</p></blockquote>
<hr />
<h2 style="text-align: center;">2018</h2>
<p>In October of 2018, Qualtrics filed its S-1, which included <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/utah-nicorn-qualtrics-updates-its-ipo-filing-with-strong-q3-results/">third quarter results for the firm</a>. Revenue was more than $100 million (up $8 million from the quarter before) and nearly 75 percent of that was gross profit. It was a strong quarterly performance and the perfect primer for a public offering.</p>
<p>The original plan was to sell 20.5 million shares in its debut for $18 to $21, which would have grossed up to $495 million, putting its valuation between $3.9 billion and $4.5 billion.</p>
<p>And then the unexpected happened.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/11/sap-agrees-to-buy-qualtrics-for-8b-in-cash-just-before-the-survey-software-companys-ipo/">SAP swooped in with an $8 billion acquisition offer.</a> An offer that Qualtrics did not refuse. Its public offering was delayed (or scrapped, depending on how you look at it) yet again.</p>
<p>The idea was that SAP&#8217;s operational data combined with Qualtrics&#8217; customer and user data would be a devastating blow to the competition and give the duo an unmatched level of power. Think Facebook&#8217;s acquisition of Instagram. Think Eye of Sauron.</p>
<p>SAP CEO Bill McDermott said at the time:</p>
<blockquote><p>The legacy players who carried their ‘90s technology into the 21st century just got clobbered. We have made existing participants in the market extinct.</p></blockquote>
<p>If it wasn&#8217;t clear, he was talking about competitors like Oracle, Salesforce, Microsoft and IBM.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xDbZSXakDL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/11/sap-agrees-to-buy-qualtrics-for-8b-in-cash-just-before-the-survey-software-companys-ipo/">SAP agrees to buy Qualtrics for $8B in cash, just before the survey software company&#8217;s IPO</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SAP agrees to buy Qualtrics for $8B in cash, just before the survey software company&#8217;s IPO&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/11/sap-agrees-to-buy-qualtrics-for-8b-in-cash-just-before-the-survey-software-companys-ipo/embed/#?secret=xDbZSXakDL" data-secret="xDbZSXakDL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As part of the acquisition announcement, Qualtrics offered yet another revenue update, saying it expected excess of $400 million in revenue for 2018 and a forward growth rate of more than 40 percent, synergies from the acquisition notwithstanding.</p>
<hr />
<h2 style="text-align: center;">2020</h2>
<p>Post-acquisition Qualtrics was a quieter Qualtrics, so we&#8217;ll skip past 2019 to 2020. Just 20 short months after being acquired, another twist in the plot: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/26/sap-will-spin-out-its-8b-spin-in-qualtrics-acquisition/">SAP announced it would spin out Qualtrics in a new IPO</a>.</p>
<p>Noting the company&#8217;s cloud growth had been in excess of 40 percent, SAP said the company would continue to be run by founder Ryan Smith and, interestingly, mentioned that Smith intends to be Qualtrics&#8217; largest individual shareholder. SAP, of course, would retain majority ownership of the company.</p>
<p>Though the announcement lacked much meat with its potatoes, it implied that Qualtrics could grow even more rapidly if not encircled by SAP&#8217;s corporate arms.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="S1jDeoZEqQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/26/sap-will-spin-out-its-8b-spin-in-qualtrics-acquisition/">SAP will spin out its $8B spin-in Qualtrics acquisition</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SAP will spin out its $8B spin-in Qualtrics acquisition&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/26/sap-will-spin-out-its-8b-spin-in-qualtrics-acquisition/embed/#?secret=S1jDeoZEqQ" data-secret="S1jDeoZEqQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The spin-out strategy was a rare move for a company like SAP.</p>
<p>As my colleague Danny Crichton wrote at the time:</p>
<blockquote><p>While private equity firms will take a company private and sometimes quickly turn it around in an IPO, it is rare to see a large company like SAP make such a dramatic last-minute bid for a company only to reverse that decision just months later.</p></blockquote>
<p>Here at TechCrunch we were excited about the impending IPO. Here was a company that had nearly gone public, now going public again.</p>
<p>And just as the year was coming to a close, Qualtrics dropped its first (second, technically) S-1 filing. After <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/28/unpacking-qualtrics-brand-new-s-1-filing/">digging through the numbers</a> this was our takeaway from the data:</p>
<blockquote><p>Qualtrics is growing at over 30%, and after enduring some post-acquisition costs that appear at least partially related to how SAP handled equity compensation, is back to a more acceptable level of losses on a GAAP basis and is doing perfectly fine when we observe its adjusted (non-GAAP) results.</p></blockquote>
<p>As often happens when a company goes public while having a large corporate owners, Qualtrics&#8217; accounting was harder to parse the second time around, but the bones of a nicely growing software company at scale were still there. How investors would value Utah&#8217;s giant was the next question.</p>
<hr />
<h2 style="text-align: center;">2021</h2>
<p>A few weeks later, Qualtrics dropped what would prove to be its first IPO pricing interval, targeting a range of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/a-first-look-at-qualtrics-ipo-pricing/">$22 and $26</a> per share, giving the company a far larger value than it had targeted during its first run at the public markets.  Of course, Qualtrics was not only benefiting from its own growth and whatever boost it received from synergies with SAP, but also from frothy SaaS valuations and a frenetic public market.</p>
<p>At that price, with 50 million shares up for grabs, the target raise was north of $1 billion. If that sounds high recall that Qualtrics posted a revenue run rate of around $800 million. The company&#8217;s growth has kept up as well, with the company&#8217;s Q4 2020 midpoint revenue expanding more than 23% compared to its Q4 2019 performance.</p>
<p>All said and done, the S-1/A pegged Qualtrics&#8217; early 2021 valuation at anywhere from $11.2 billion to $13.3 billion. Alex Wilhelm is much better at breaking down the numbers than me (or anyone, really) so I urge you to take a look at his coverage.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="glXJa2iOif"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/a-first-look-at-qualtrics-ipo-pricing/">A first look at Qualtrics&#8217; IPO pricing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A first look at Qualtrics&#8217; IPO pricing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/a-first-look-at-qualtrics-ipo-pricing/embed/#?secret=glXJa2iOif" data-secret="glXJa2iOif" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Wilhelm was also astute enough to recognize that the share pricing for Qualtrics&#8217; IPO would likely be adjusted higher. And it was!</p>
<p>Yesterday, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/qualtrics-raises-ipo-pricing-ahead-of-debut/">Qualtrics raised its share price from $22 &#8211; $26 to between $27 and $29</a>, putting the valuation range between $13.8 billion to $14.8 billion. Yowzah!</p>
<ul>
<li>New Qualtrics low-end IPO run rate multiple: 16.2x.</li>
<li>New Qualtrics high-end IPO run rate multiple: 17.4x.</li>
</ul>
<p>Wilhelm noted that the Qualtrics share price may go up yet again, but also explained that while the multiples in play may feel low, it&#8217;s tough to be certain:</p>
<blockquote><p>Those do not seem to be particularly high multiples for Qualtrics, given recent market norms. However, trying to decipher the public market lately has been similar to reading the Rosetta Stone, but written in Wingdings. While on acid. So, you never know what is going to happen when a company starts to trade.</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hK89Y0apap"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/qualtrics-raises-ipo-pricing-ahead-of-debut/">Qualtrics raises IPO pricing ahead of debut</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Qualtrics raises IPO pricing ahead of debut&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/qualtrics-raises-ipo-pricing-ahead-of-debut/embed/#?secret=hK89Y0apap" data-secret="hK89Y0apap" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>There is one thing we know for sure: Qualtrics has showed growth in revenue and more profitability than most software companies during its entire existence. We&#8217;ve been waiting for this IPO for years now, literally, and while many pieces of the puzzle are uncertain, we&#8217;ll get our answers soon enough.</p>
<p>Unless of course some giant firm swoops in with a $20 billion acquisition offer. Now wouldn&#8217;t that be fitting?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/qualtrics-ipo-everything-you-need-to-know/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100290</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
