<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 08:57:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>With an Apple Store designer on board, Juno raises $20M to build apartments more sustainably</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/juno-raises-20m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/juno-raises-20m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 11:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199947</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Juno, a proptech startup which aims to build more sustainable and affordable apartment buildings, has raised $20 million in a Series A funding round. Comcast Ventures, Khosla Ventures and Real Estate Technology (RET) Ventures co-led the financing, which brings the company’s total raised to $32 million since its 2019 inception. JLL Spark, Vertex Ventures, Anim, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://juno.co/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Juno</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a proptech startup which aims to build more sustainable and affordable apartment buildings, has raised $20 million in a Series A funding round.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Comcast Ventures, Khosla Ventures and Real Estate Technology (RET) Ventures co-led the financing, which brings the company’s total raised to $32 million since its 2019 inception. JLL Spark, Vertex Ventures, Anim, K50, Foundamental and Green D Alumni Ventures also participated in the Series A investment.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Juno co-founder and CEO Jonathan Scherr said the San Francisco-based startup plans to build all electric properties by </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">assembling “the first OEM ecosystem for ground-up development.” (For the unacquainted, OEM stands for “original equipment manufacturer.&#8221;)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re&#8230;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">treating housing development like product development, a process we call ‘productization,’ ” he told TechCrunch. “By creating buildings that are worthy of being repeated, tools and systems can be created to enable continuous improvement and increase efficiency. If buildings are considered or designed in a one-off context, then the learnings from one project to the next will fail to exist.”</span></p>
<p>Note that Juno&#8217;s productization could be considered similar to the more commonly used term prefabrication in some aspects. While prefab construction company Katerra <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/01/softbank-backed-construction-giant-katerra-said-to-be-shutting-down-after-raising-billions/">crashed and burned</a>, a number of other companies in the space continue to raise money and grow, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/abodu-raises-20m-to-build-prefabricated-backyard-homes/">Abodu</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/khosla-backs-construction-tech-startup-mighty-buildings-plans-to-create-3d-printed-homes/">Mighty Buildings,</a> which is also backed by Khosla but is more focused accessory dwelling units and single-family homes. There is also North Carolina-based <a href="https://prescientco.com/">Prescient</a>, which is also  constructing multifamily housing and hotels through prefabrication.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199953" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199953" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2199953 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199953" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Rendering of Austin project; Engraff Studio / Juno</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Juno&#8217;s theory is that via &#8220;productization,&#8221; it can create the tools, systems and processes that can lead to things like reduced design timelines, increased precision in estimation and scheduling and a “significantly accelerated” construction process. All this, Scherr said, can result in more affordable housing options for people all over the United States. Also, Juno claims that its design process, for example, is 60% faster than in traditional real estate development.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like other players in the space, Juno of course touts an approach that it says is far more sustainable than traditional construction methods.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Today, construction refuse is literally 2x that of all municipal refuse combined in the U.S.,” Scherr told TechCrunch. “The Juno system creates efficiency in the design, supply chain, and construction of buildings that reduce waste and energy usage.” Features include low-carbon, all timber construction, more exposed wood (which Juno says is anti-microbial) and entirely gasless buildings, for example.</span></p>
<p>Thanks to its focus on all-electric buildings in cities that have established roadmaps to clean energy generation, the Juno residential system is trending toward a net zero target for embodied carbon in its multifamily residential units, Scherr said.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Scherr founded Juno with BJ Siegel, who was a designer of the original Apple Store, and Chester Chipperfield, who currently serves as an advisor to the company. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chipperfield previously served as global creative director at Tesla, head of special projects at Apple and head of digital at Burberry. Scherr has worked as a venture investor and advisor to a number of companies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“As the concept architect for Apple’s retail program going back as far as 1999, BJ [Siegel] had thought about how to create an identity for the built environment that deserved to be repeated,” Scherr said. “By doing so, he and his colleagues at Apple began to think about Apple retail more like Apple’s products: grounded in a decentralized supply chain.”</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199963" style="width: 328px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199963" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2199963 " src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/founders-2.jpg?w=200" alt="" width="318" height="478" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/founders-2.jpg 1363w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/founders-2.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/founders-2.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/founders-2.jpg?resize=768,1154 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/founders-2.jpg?resize=453,680 453w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/founders-2.jpg?resize=1022,1536 1022w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/founders-2.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 318px) 100vw, 318px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199963" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> From left to right: Chester Chipperfield, co-founder and advisor Jonathan Scherr, co-founder and CEO BJ Siegel, co-founder and Head of Design / Juno</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Juno was created with a similar model in mind: with the goal of designing &#8220;better&#8221; housing that could be replicated so that the company is able “to build out a supply chain and lay the groundwork for learning systems in ways that have never been possible before,” said Scherr, whose father was a real estate developer.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Juno is starting out by building what it describes as the first national network of mass timber apartment buildings at scale with all-electric buildings in cities across the United States. And it’s partnering with </span><a href="https://swinerton.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Swinerton</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and</span><a href="http://www.ennead.com/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Ennead Architects</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to put its model into practice. The startup has also broken ground on its first project &#8212; an apartment building in East Austin &#8212; and currently has more than 400 units in development. The East Austin building is slated to open in 2022. Juno also has sites planned for Seattle and Denver.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looking ahead, the company plans to use its new capital to continue to build out its product, break ground on its first cohort of projects and engage with more developers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Juno&#8217;s investors are naturally bullish on what the company is doing, and plans to do.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Evan Moore, partner at Khosla Ventures, said he does not generally invest in real estate development companies or builders or architects.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“But when a strong team is working on a dramatically different product in an important industry, I&#8217;ll get behind it,” he wrote via email.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Historically, Moore added, apartment development has been a finance-driven industry, rather than product-driven, despite the fact that apartments are consumer products and derive their value from their use. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“So there&#8217;s a tremendous opportunity to design buildings with the customer experience at the forefront,” he said. “What if Apple built apartment buildings? To me, that means working backwards from the experience you want to create, designing the components, supply chain and systems to support it, and working within cost as a constraint. That&#8217;s an ambitious idea, and an experiment worth undertaking.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sheena Jindal, principal at Comcast Ventures, notes that America’s housing stock is increasingly aged and in short supply &#8212; making it more difficult for people to buy houses. Her firm, she said, believes that everyone deserves access to an affordable home.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“When we first met the Juno team, we were struck by their first principles approach to building,” she wrote via email. “Juno fundamentally understood what was broken in multifamily housing production and tackled it head on by focusing earlier in the value chain with its design and OEM sourcing strategy. Juno partners with existing players in the value chain, rather than displacing them.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="p1tOMCYvQA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/fifth-walls-brendan-wallace-and-hippos-assaf-wand-discuss-proptechs-biggest-opportunities/">Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand discuss proptech&#8217;s biggest opportunities</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand discuss proptech&#8217;s biggest opportunities&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/fifth-walls-brendan-wallace-and-hippos-assaf-wand-discuss-proptechs-biggest-opportunities/embed/#?secret=p1tOMCYvQA" data-secret="p1tOMCYvQA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/juno-raises-20m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199947</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Digital therapeutics startup Neuroglee raises $10M to help people with neurodegenerative conditions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/digital-therapeutics-startup-neuroglee-raises-10m-to-help-people-with-neurodegenerative-conditions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/digital-therapeutics-startup-neuroglee-raises-10m-to-help-people-with-neurodegenerative-conditions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 10:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alzheimer's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital therapeutics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neurodegenerative disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neuroglee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neuroglee Therapeutics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2200003</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Neuroglee Therapeutics, a startup developing digital therapeutics for people with neurodegenerative diseases, has raised a $10 million Series A led by Openspace Ventures and EDBI. The funding will be used to launch virtual neurology clinics and to support Neuroglee’s move to Boston. Other participants included Ramen Singh, the former chief executive officer of Mundipharma; Biofourmis [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://neuroglee.com/">Neuroglee Therapeutics</a>, a startup developing digital therapeutics for people with neurodegenerative diseases, has raised a $10 million Series A led by Openspace Ventures and EDBI. The funding will be used to launch virtual neurology clinics and to support Neuroglee’s move to Boston. Other participants included Ramen Singh, the former chief executive officer of Mundipharma; Biofourmis co-founders Kuldeep Singh Rajput and Wendou Liu; and Eisai Co., the Japanese pharmaceutical that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/neuroglee-gets-2-3-million-to-develop-digital-therapeutics-for-neurodegenerative-diseases/">led Neuroglee’s last round last year</a>.</p>
<p>In an email, founder and chief executive officer Aniket Singh Rajput told TechCrunch that the company is moving to Boston because the city “is one of the largest digital health hubs in the world. As a company devoted to developing our first line of solutions for treating mild cognitive impairment related to difficult-to-treat neurodegenerative conditions such as Alzheimer’s disease, we believe Boston will offer us the strategic support in order to do so.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="m7gOzSRZPH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/neuroglee-gets-2-3-million-to-develop-digital-therapeutics-for-neurodegenerative-diseases/">Neuroglee gets $2.3 million to develop digital therapeutics for neurodegenerative diseases</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Neuroglee gets $2.3 million to develop digital therapeutics for neurodegenerative diseases&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/neuroglee-gets-2-3-million-to-develop-digital-therapeutics-for-neurodegenerative-diseases/embed/#?secret=m7gOzSRZPH" data-secret="m7gOzSRZPH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Neuroglee and the Mayo Clinic are currently working together on a new platform called Neuroglee Connect. Based on the Mayo Clinic’s 10-day in-person program HABIT (Health Action to Benefit Independence and Thinking) for people with mild cognitive impairment from possible neurodegenerative conditions, Neuroglee’s technology will enable HABIT to scale, making it available to patients and caregivers in their homes. Neuroglee Connect users will also have access to health navigators who are available 24 hours and clinical care teams for assessments and interventions.</p>
<p>Neuroglee&#8217;s product pipeline also includes digital therapeutics for Parkinson’s disease and strokes.</p>
<p>Since Neuroglee’s previous funding announcement in December 2020, Rajput said it has hit milestones like the successful product development of NG-001, its prescription digital therapy software for Alzheimer’s, and began work on its proof-of-concept study to earn NG-001 a Breakthrough Designation from the Federal Drug Administration.</p>
<p>Neuroglee’s adaptive learning tech uses machine learning and biomarkers related to cognitive function, mood and behavior to automatically personalize therapy plans for each patient, who access the software through a smartphone or tablet.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“For example, adjustments will be made to the number and type of tasks and games that are offered, based on the speed of the patient’s finger movements, time to complete games or tasks, and their facial expression identified through the device camera,” said Rajput. “The solution also incorporates reminiscence therapy, which uses images from the patient’s past to evoke positive memories and emotions, which have been shown to improve cognitive functioning.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OIJdvOtEXz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/softbank-vision-fund-2-leads-100-million-series-c-in-digital-therapeutics-company-biofourmis/">SoftBank Vision Fund 2 leads $100 million Series C in digital therapeutics company Biofourmis</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SoftBank Vision Fund 2 leads $100 million Series C in digital therapeutics company Biofourmis&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/softbank-vision-fund-2-leads-100-million-series-c-in-digital-therapeutics-company-biofourmis/embed/#?secret=OIJdvOtEXz" data-secret="OIJdvOtEXz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BrnMDt9asv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/03/venture-investing-in-eldertech/">Venture investing in elder tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Venture investing in elder tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/03/venture-investing-in-eldertech/embed/#?secret=BrnMDt9asv" data-secret="BrnMDt9asv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/digital-therapeutics-startup-neuroglee-raises-10m-to-help-people-with-neurodegenerative-conditions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2200003</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft confirms investment in India&#8217;s Oyo in a multi-year strategic deal to co-develop travel and hospitality products</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/microsoft-confirms-investment-in-indias-oyo-in-a-multi-year-strategic-deal-to-co-develop-travel-and-hospitality-products/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/microsoft-confirms-investment-in-indias-oyo-in-a-multi-year-strategic-deal-to-co-develop-travel-and-hospitality-products/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 08:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oyo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2200000</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft has entered a “multi-year strategic alliance” with Oyo to work with the Indian startup to co-develop &#8220;next-generation&#8221; travel and hospitality products and tech. Thursday’s announcement confirms a late July TechCrunch report. TechCrunch had reported that Microsoft was in talks to invest in Oyo and was exploring ways to provide its technologies to the Indian [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Microsoft has entered a “multi-year strategic alliance” with Oyo to work with the Indian startup to co-develop &#8220;next-generation&#8221; travel and hospitality products and tech.</p>
<p>Thursday’s announcement confirms <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/microsoft-in-talks-to-back-india-oyo/">a late July TechCrunch report</a>. TechCrunch had reported that Microsoft was in talks to invest in Oyo and was exploring ways to provide its technologies to the Indian startup, which is one of the most valuable in the South Asian market.</p>
<p>In a press statement, Microsoft confirmed that it has also made a strategic equity investment in Oyo, but didn’t disclose the amount. A regulatory filing showed last month that the Windows-maker had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/microsoft-backs-indias-oyo-at-9-6-billion-valuation/">invested $5 million in the Indian startup</a>. The investment valued Oyo at $9.6 billion.</p>
<p>Oyo will switch to Microsoft Azure for its cloud-based needs and co-develop solutions with the American giant to “benefit patrons who operate small and medium hotel and home storefronts,” the firms said. &#8220;As part of this alliance, OYO will develop Smart Room experiences for travelers on the OYO platform, such as premium and customized in-room experiences for its guests. Using Microsoft’s Azure IoT, the experience will include self-check-in supported by a digital register of arrivals and departures and self-Know Your Customer (KYC) along with IoT-managed smart locks and virtual assistance,&#8221; the firms said.</p>
<p>“Combining the power of Azure with the tech and product stack developed by OYO, we are looking forward to accelerating innovation in travel and hospitality,” said Anant Maheshwari, President of Microsoft India, in a statement. “It is inspiring to see how the Microsoft cloud is empowering digital natives like OYO to accelerate industry transformation and innovations, turning the challenges of a post-pandemic era into opportunities for the future.”</p>
<p>Oyo has emerged as one of the largest hotel chains in the world, with presence in India, Southeast Asia, Europe and the U.S. But <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/02/technology/oyo-softbank-india.html">some of its missteps</a> in its pursuit of aggressive expansion — “toxic culture,” lapse in governance and relationship with many hotel owners — have scarred its growth.</p>
<p>Just as the startup was pledging to improve its relationship with hotel owners, the pandemic arrived. In response, Oyo slowed its growth and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/04/softbank-backed-indian-startup-oyo-to-cut-5000-jobs-globally/">laid off thousands of employees globally</a> earlier this year as nations across the world enforced lockdowns.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The pandemic hit the seven-year-old startup like a “cyclone,” CEO Ritesh Agarwal told Bloomberg TV in July. “We built something for so many years and it took just 30 days for it drop by over 60%,” he said, adding that the firm had not made any decision on exploring the public markets.</p>
<p>Airbnb-backed Oyo had between $780 million to $800 million in its bank, Agarwal said at a virtual conference recently, and had pared its “monthly burn” across all businesses to $4 million to $5 million. (The startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/despite-everything-oyo-still-has-1-billion-in-cash/">had about $1 billion in the bank</a> in December 2020.)</p>
<p>In July — after Agarwal’s remarks at the aforementioned conference — Oyo said it had raised $660 million in debt. That debt was used to pay off the previous debt, according to a person familiar with the matter.</p>
<p>As for Microsoft, Oyo is the latest of several strategic investments it has made in the country. The firm has backed a handful of startups in the South Asian market, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/google-leads-145-million-investment-in-indias-glance/">news aggregator and short-video platform DailyHunt,</a> e-commerce giant <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/10/flipkart-1-4-billion/">Flipkart</a>, and logistics <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/indian-logistics-saas-startup-fareye-bags-13-million/">SaaS firm FarEye</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/microsoft-confirms-investment-in-indias-oyo-in-a-multi-year-strategic-deal-to-co-develop-travel-and-hospitality-products/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2200000</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Two UK tech figures plan to row the Atlantic for charity supporting minority entrepreneurs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/two-uk-tech-figures-plan-to-row-the-atlantic-for-charity-supporting-minority-entrepreneurs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/two-uk-tech-figures-plan-to-row-the-atlantic-for-charity-supporting-minority-entrepreneurs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 07:01:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199542</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two UK tech figures are to row across the Atlantic Ocean to raise money for a charity that funds social entrepreneurs from minority backgrounds. Guy Rigby, founder and now Chair of the Entrepreneurial Services Group at Smith &#38; Williamson, and entrepreneur, investor David Murray will raise money for UnLtd which has supported over 15,000 social [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Two UK tech figures are to row across the Atlantic Ocean to raise money for a charity that funds social entrepreneurs from minority backgrounds.</p>
<p>Guy Rigby, founder and now Chair of the Entrepreneurial Services Group at Smith &amp; Williamson, and entrepreneur, investor David Murray will raise money for <a href="https://www.unltd.org.uk/impact2020">UnLtd</a> which has supported over 15,000 social entrepreneurs in the UK.</p>
<p>The pair have so far secured around £350,000 for UnLtd, with support from the UK’s Tech Nation, Founders Forum, and London Tech Week. You can donate to their fund-raising efforts on the &#8216;<a href="https://theentrepreneurship.co.uk/">The Entrepreneur Ship&#8217; here.</a>, will also be part of the <a href="https://theentrepreneurship.co.uk/sponsorship/">Talisker Whisky Atlantic Challenge</a>. Other tech orgs are invited to sponsor their efforts.</p>
<p>UnLtd has previously backed startup firms including <a href="https://patchworkhub.org/">Patchwork Hub</a> which built an accessible employment platform run by disabled people, as well as <a href="https://www.edukit.org.uk/">EduKit</a>, which developed an app to help school staff understand and address the mental health needs of their students.</p>
<p>Over the last year, UnLtd supported 662 social entrepreneurs, 42% of whom identified as being from a Black, Asian, or minority ethnic background and/or having a disability.</p>
<p>Rigby and Murray will row the 3,000 miles in December 2021 from the Canaries to Antigua, which they hope to reach in February 2022, rowing individually, 2 hours on, 2 hours off, around the clock for the duration of the crossing.</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/two-uk-tech-figures-plan-to-row-the-atlantic-for-charity-supporting-minority-entrepreneurs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199542</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>China&#8217;s WeRide unveils Robovan, its first electric, autonomous cargo van</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/weride-jiangling-motors-and-zto-express-unveil-robovan-an-autonomous-cargo-van/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/weride-jiangling-motors-and-zto-express-unveil-robovan-an-autonomous-cargo-van/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 06:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chinese autonomous driving company WeRide has unveiled its first cargo van, the vessel upon which it will self-drive into the world of urban logistics. WeRide will work with Chinese automobile manufacturer Jiangling Motors (JMC) and Chinese express delivery company ZTO Express to commercialize its first self-driving van at scale. The deal was signed on Wednesday [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Chinese autonomous driving company WeRide has unveiled its first cargo van, the vessel upon which it will self-drive into the world of urban logistics. WeRide will work with Chinese automobile manufacturer Jiangling Motors (JMC) and Chinese express delivery company ZTO Express to commercialize its first self-driving van at scale.</p>
<p>The deal was signed on Wednesday by Tony Han, founder and CEO of WeRide, Wenhui Jin, executive vice president of JMC, and Renqun Jin, vice president of ZTO, during WeRide&#8217;s latest online press conference dubbed &#8220;The Next.&#8221; As part of the agreement, WeRide and JMC will jointly design purpose-built models of the Robovan for mass production on JMC&#8217;s assembly lines, and ZTO will put the Robovans to good use in their urban logistics service, according to a statement released by the company. A WeRide spokesperson told TechCrunch that the Robovans will be based on JMC&#8217;s battery electric vehicle model with a fully-redundant vehicle platform, combined with WeRide&#8217;s full-stack software and hardware autonomous driving (AD) solutions.</p>
<p>WeRide has been raking in cash over the past year on its route to commercialization, with ove<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/weride-310-million-series-c/">r $600 million</a> raised from Series B and C rounds in the span of five months and a current $3.3 billion valuation. In June, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/07/20/chinas-weride-makes-first-acquisition-an-autonomous-trucking-firm.html">the company acquired MoonX.AI</a>, a Guangzhou-based autonomous trucking company, although it hasn&#8217;t yet committed to developing a commercial product in that space yet. Either way, having <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/weride-310-million-series-c/">ride-hailing</a>, autonomous <a href="https://www.weride.ai/en/mini-robobus-en/">busing</a>, urban logistics and even just a hint of self-driving trucks in the pipeline means WeRide&#8217;s moves to diversify its autonomous portfolio are edging it ahead of the competition.</p>
<p>Chinese search engine Baidu&#8217;s self-driving unit mainly focuses on robotaxi and, as of <a href="https://www.barrons.com/articles/baidu-gets-green-light-for-commercial-self-driving-bus-service-in-china-51618390800">April this year</a>, buses. Alongside its robotaxis, Pony.AI has at least p<a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-pony-ai/toyota-backed-pony-ai-to-offer-autonomous-delivery-service-in-california-idUSKBN21Y3GK">iloted last-mile logistics</a> and just recently got the <a href="https://autonews.gasgoo.com/icv/70018226.html">go-ahead to test its trucks out in China</a>, but so far no buses. Waymo Via knocks both <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/waymo-via-is-scaling-up-autonomous-trucking-operations-in-texas-arizona-california/">last-mile and trucking off the list</a>, and its autonomous taxis make for a very long feather in the company&#8217;s cap, but Waymo hasn&#8217;t yet released any news about self-driving buses. GM-backed Cruise seems to be sticking with small vehicles and all they can provide, which includes <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/cruise-secures-5b-credit-line-to-buy-electric-autonomous-cruise-origin-vehicles-from-gm/">rideshare</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/10/21557603/cruise-walmart-autonomous-vehicles-delivery-arizona">delivery</a>.</p>
<p>WeRide says its van already has Level 4 autonomous capabilities, which the <a href="https://www.sae.org/news/press-room/2018/12/sae-international-releases-updated-visual-chart-for-its-%E2%80%9Clevels-of-driving-automation%E2%80%9D-standard-for-self-driving-vehicles">Society of Automotive Engineers</a> defines as a car that takes the wheel and doesn&#8217;t require human interaction in most cases, although a human still has the option to manually override. Level 4 vehicles can only operate in limited areas, which is why they have most recently catered to ridesharing, but delivery vehicles could conceivably operate within a geofence, as well.</p>
<p>Because WeRide already has two years of experience testing out its Robotaxi service with the public, the company says it&#8217;s confident that the Robovan will be able to handle itself in a variety of different traffic scenarios, from innercity to tunnels to highways, across ZTO&#8217;s network, which covers over 99% of China&#8217;s cities and counties, according to ZTO.</p>
<p>A WeRide spokesperson said the Robovan has already been built and has been quietly tested in China for some time now. It&#8217;s still too early in the process to provide a detailed timeline on when WeRide and JMC will begin mass production, but the spokesperson said the next step for WeRide will be to pick one to three locations to conduct pilot testing to verify the vehicles and the system&#8217;s stability.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Right after that, we aim for being true driverless in a few areas and build up our know-how of operating Robovans in urban logistics application,&#8221; the spokesperson told TechCrunch. &#8220;Considering both Robovan and Robotaxi are operating in urban cities, Robovan shares similar regulatory support as Robotaxi. Regulation in China is progressing step by step to catch up with the development of self-driving technology. You will see the application of true driverless Robovan in three to five years.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/weride-jiangling-motors-and-zto-express-unveil-robovan-an-autonomous-cargo-van/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199980</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Printify bags $45M, led by Index, to ride the custom printing boom</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/printify-bags-45m-led-by-index-as-it-rides-the-custom-printing-boom/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/printify-bags-45m-led-by-index-as-it-rides-the-custom-printing-boom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 05:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[merchant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[print on demand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[printful]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Printify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[printing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TransferWise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virgin group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Will Smith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zazzle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2198603</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The creator economy loves merch which is great news for on-demand custom printing startups such as Latvia-based Printify &#8212; today it&#8217;s announcing a $45 million Series A round, led by Index Ventures, off the back of rising demand for its services. The mission: To keep growing its global marketplace of print shops to meet rising [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The creator economy loves merch which is great news for on-demand custom printing startups such as Latvia-based <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/09/printify-raises-3m-to-expand-its-marketplace-for-custom-printing/">Printify</a> &#8212; today it&#8217;s announcing a $45 million Series A round, led by Index Ventures, off the back of rising demand for its services.</p>
<p>The mission: To keep growing its global marketplace of print shops to meet rising demand for custom wares, shipped.</p>
<p>Also participating in the funding round: H&amp;M Group, Virgin Group, plus the founders of Transferwise, Vinted, Squarespace, RedHat, and entertainment industry investors including Will Smith’s Dreamers VC and <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">at least one other person who Printify has asked us not to name for </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">unspecified legal reasons.</span></p>
<p>TechCrunch understands Printify’s post-money valuation is just over $300M.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Ecommerce and creator-focused platforms like Patreon and Shopify &#8212; which cater to micro-brand creating individual sellers (be they designers, content creators, ecommerce entrepreneurs or other highly online hustlers) &#8212; are helping to fire up demand for custom products like t-shirts, mugs, stickers etc, expanding the market for on-demand printing and shipping.</span></p>
<p>Printify says it&#8217;s now connecting some two million merchants with <span class="il">print</span> providers all over the world &#8212; and shipping a million units per month.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also grown to employ close to 500 people &#8212; doubling its headcount over the past year, now with a plan to add a further 200 positions by the end of the year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Our main audiences are creators, entrepreneurs; most of our merchants are people who want to build a side-business and earn money in addition to their main income, however, we also see a high growth of creators and entrepreneurs who use Printify as a service that helps building their core business,&#8221; the startup tells TechCrunch.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s one of a number of custom printing startups that have positioned themselves to step in to tackle the printing and shipping piece at scale, often building up businesses over several years from a far smaller base. (Others in the space include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/07/16/printful/">Printful</a>, <a href="https://www.gelato.com">Gelato</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/09/07/zazzle-instant-iphone/">Zazzle</a>.)</p>
<p>The 2015-founder Printify has slightly fewer years in the business than some of its rivals but it argues that&#8217;s allowed it to be more focused on serving the micro-brand building merchants who are now sparking such a boom in demand custom wares.</p>
<p>&#8220;Printify gives the ability for everyone to earn additional income,&#8221; it says when asked about the competitive mix &#8212; touting a focus on product selection, quality and price as its special sauce, in addition to its marketplace&#8217;s global footprint, meaning it can print and ship products to meet demand from merchants all over the world.</p>
<p>&#8220;Those are the key aspects our merchants are looking for,&#8221; it adds. &#8220;Printify provides the largest selection of on-demand printed products for creators and merchants to sell online. Furthermore, Printify provides lowest prices, while ensuring reliable high quality standards.&#8221;</p>
<p>The most popular products being sold by merchants using its marketplace are &#8220;the classics&#8221; &#8212; aka T-shirts, hoodies, stickers, mugs, posters and hats.</p>
<p>&#8220;We also see a fast-growing market for baby and children&#8217;s products, sportswear, pet products and drinkware,&#8221; it adds. &#8220;Most merchants choose Printify because of our wide selection and geographical flexibility &#8212; we have 370+ products in our catalog and adding several each week, printed in 100+ locations all over the world.&#8221;</p>
<p>Commenting on the Series A funding in a statement, Dino Becirovic, principal at Index Ventures, said: &#8220;Printify is the leading marketplace for on-demand manufacturing, offering the largest selection of products and print providers. They have removed all the barriers to product creation and enabled over 2 million creators to launch successful merchandise businesses at the push of a button. Over time, as more manufacturers come online and more methods become available, Printify will allow any creator to bring their wildest product ideas to reality.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>This report was updated to remove the name of an investor after Printify told us the person in question had requested not to be mentioned in the funding announcement &#8220;due to legal reasons&#8221;</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yheqHGOzeH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/09/printify-raises-3m-to-expand-its-marketplace-for-custom-printing/">Printify raises $3M to expand its marketplace for custom printing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Printify raises $3M to expand its marketplace for custom printing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/09/printify-raises-3m-to-expand-its-marketplace-for-custom-printing/embed/#?secret=yheqHGOzeH" data-secret="yheqHGOzeH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AjRMmc9XAY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/facebook-creator-bonuses/">Facebook will lure creators with $1 billion in payments</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook will lure creators with $1 billion in payments&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/facebook-creator-bonuses/embed/#?secret=AjRMmc9XAY" data-secret="AjRMmc9XAY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/printify-bags-45m-led-by-index-as-it-rides-the-custom-printing-boom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2198603</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The newest Roomba gets smarter as it vacuums</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/the-newest-roomba-gets-smarter-as-it-vacuums/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/the-newest-roomba-gets-smarter-as-it-vacuums/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 04:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iRobot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roomba]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199708</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Roomba is easily among the most ubiquitous robots in the world &#8212; but it has never been one of the smartest. On the whole, that’s not a major issue. The top-selling vacuum is good at what it does: cleaning floors. But a roboticist’s work is never done; iRobot has turned the vast majority of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Roomba is easily among the most ubiquitous robots in the world &#8212; but it has never been one of the smartest. On the whole, that’s not a major issue. The top-selling vacuum is good at what it does: cleaning floors. But a roboticist’s work is never done; iRobot has turned the vast majority of its attention and resources on the line for good reason, and the company has spent virtually every generation improving the robot’s ability to perform its very specific task.</p>
<p>This time out, that means using on-board sensors to remember areas of the home and layout, along with areas that need a little extra cleaning time.</p>
<p>“We’ve turned on continuous learning, so that if you’ve changed things in your home, Roomba will figure it out,” CEO Colin Angle tells TechCrunch. “If you open a door that you’ve never opened before, the Roomba will go explore it. If you moved a couch, it will understand that the home is a bit different than it used to be, and that’s okay. The information that we’re gathering grows in richness.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199714" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199714" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2199714" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_Dirt-Disposal-Bag.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_Dirt-Disposal-Bag.jpg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_Dirt-Disposal-Bag.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_Dirt-Disposal-Bag.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_Dirt-Disposal-Bag.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_Dirt-Disposal-Bag.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_Dirt-Disposal-Bag.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_Dirt-Disposal-Bag.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199714" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> iRobot</p></div></p>
<p>The other big piece of that puzzle is identifying and avoiding specific objects. The company says it has worked on identifying hundreds of potential objects, but is starting with two specific problem areas: cords and poop. Both are big potential problem areas for a robotic vacuum system, albeit for dramatically different reasons. In either case, you don’t want to have to get down on your hands and knees and deal with the fallout.</p>
<p>In the case of the former, iRobot made an acronym &#8212; and a guarantee. With Pet Owner Official Promise (P.O.O.P.), the company says it will replace any j7+ that runs over animal dookie. (Fine print: Offer valid for 1 year from purchase and covers replacement product only. Available in limited jurisdictions, additional terms and conditions apply.)</p>
<p>“You can Google this and see some not so pleasant examples of robots running over poop,” says iRobot’s director of Product Management, Hooman Shahidi. “We’ve solved this problem with consumers. If we see animal poop, we avoid it and inform the consumers that we saw it.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2199711" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199711" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2199711" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_j7_Object-Detection_Pet-Waste.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_j7_Object-Detection_Pet-Waste.jpg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_j7_Object-Detection_Pet-Waste.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_j7_Object-Detection_Pet-Waste.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_j7_Object-Detection_Pet-Waste.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_j7_Object-Detection_Pet-Waste.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_j7_Object-Detection_Pet-Waste.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_j7_Object-Detection_Pet-Waste.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199711" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> iRobot</p></div></p>
<p>Angle adds, “The glorious career of roboticists may not have been fully realized when we were sending people home and creating hundreds of models of poo. Sending people around to photograph and create synthetic models of poo. I don’t know how many tens of thousands of images of all different shapes and sizes of synthetic images were required, but this is not demo code, clearly. We can’t do pee. It has to have some 3D aspects to it, but it is something we believe you can count on for the robot to identify and avoid.&#8221;</p>
<p>The third piece is scheduling, with the system adapting to a user’s activities. That could mean cleaning while you’re away (using your phone as a trigger for proximity) or making sure it avoids rooms you’re in. If the robot has to traverse the house, it will drive quietly and not start up until it actually begins its job. The system also now offers a clean-time estimate to let the user know how long the job will take.</p>
<p>The j7 is available now in the U.S. and Canada for $649. The j7+, which includes a more compact cleaning base, will run $849. They’re also available in Europe and will be rolling out to additional markets next year. Genius 3.0, meanwhile, will be available as an OTA update for the rest of the company’s connected robots.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/the-newest-roomba-gets-smarter-as-it-vacuums/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199708</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sequoia&#8217;s Pat Grady says it isn&#8217;t clear startups &#8220;should be accelerating&#8221; right now &#8212; here&#8217;s why</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/sequoias-pat-grady-a-fog-has-descended-and-it-isnt-clear-startups-should-be-accelerating-right-now/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/sequoias-pat-grady-a-fog-has-descended-and-it-isnt-clear-startups-should-be-accelerating-right-now/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[late-stage venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[noom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pat Grady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scouts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stripe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199885</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier today, we joined friend and former colleague Jon Fortt of CNBC in interviewing partner Pat Grady of Sequoia Capital, and it proved a wide-ranging conversation. You can check out the video below, but we thought there were some highlights worth pulling out for some of you, including as it pertains to the current market, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Earlier today, we joined friend and former colleague Jon Fortt of CNBC in interviewing partner Pat Grady of Sequoia Capital, and it proved a wide-ranging conversation. You can check out the video below, but we thought there were some highlights worth pulling out for some of you, including as it pertains to the current market, which has never felt frothier.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s more than anecdotal. According to a recent <a href="https://www.wsgr.com/a/web/26202/EntrepreneursReport-Q1-2020.pdf">Wilson Sonsini report</a>, during the first quarter of this year, the median pre-money valuation for Series C and later financings hit a record $675 million &#8212; more than double the full year 2020 median of $315 million. Meanwhile, senior liquidation preferences in so-called up rounds dropped from appearing in 35% of related deals in 2017 to 20% in the first quarter &#8212; a trend that suggests that investors are removing terms in order to win deals. In some cases, founders are feeling so empowered that they are <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/bessemer-replaces-board-member-at-hinge-health-following-competitive-tensions/">calling out investor behavior</a> that makes them uncomfortable, which is something you didn&#8217;t see until more recently.</p>
<p>But Grady said not all is what it seems to those of us on the sidelines. Indeed, he said that while Sequoia&#8217;s advice to founders as recently as March of this year was to hit the gas, things have changed more recently. Specifically, he said, &#8220;In the last couple of months, a rollout of the vaccines has kind of kind of tapered, so I would say that fog has descended onto the road [and] it&#8217;s not so clear the company should be accelerating anymore.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>On how COVID has impacted Sequoia&#8217;s outlook compared with the financial crisis of 2008, when Sequoia famously published its now-famous &#8220;<a href="https://www.sequoiacap.com/article/rip-good-times">RIP: Good Times</a>&#8221; memo:</strong></p>
<p>PG: If you go back to that RIP memo, I&#8217;d been at Sequoia for a year or so. It was the first major disruption that I had seen &#8212;  it was the first major disruption that a lot of our founders had seen. So the question we were getting was, &#8216;What does this mean for us?&#8217; It was the same sort of thing that happened in March of 2020 that caused us to put out the &#8216;<a href="https://medium.com/sequoia-capital/coronavirus-the-black-swan-of-2020-7c72bdeb9753">Black Swan</a>&#8216; memo [when] what we said was, &#8216;Hey, you need to brake when you&#8217;re going into the curve, so slow down [and] make sure you kind of have your bearings.&#8217;</p>
<p>In March of this year what we said was, &#8216;Okay, now that we&#8217;re coming out of the curve, go and accelerate.&#8217; Unfortunately, in the last couple of months, a rollout of the vaccines has kind of kind of tapered and so I would say that fog has descended onto the road [and] it&#8217;s not so clear the company should be accelerating anymore. We&#8217;re probably in the midst of more indecision now than we were a few months ago or even a year ago . . .we&#8217;re kind of stuck in the middle. And so what we&#8217;ve been telling companies today is focus on the basics.</p>
<p><strong>On the signals that suggest a slight slowdown to Sequoia, despite the current funding environment:</strong></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>We don&#8217;t pay that much attention to the fundraising numbers, but we do pay attention to employees and we do pay attention to customers, and if you look across not just our portfolio but also public companies in the market at large, attrition has spiked dramatically. There are a lot of people who said, &#8216;Hey, I hunkered down, I worked hard, I put in my time, but now that the world is starting to open up a little bit again, I&#8217;m going to take some time off. I&#8217;m going to travel on the see family. I&#8217;m going to find a new job. I&#8217;m going to start a company.&#8217; And so attrition numbers are actually spiking across the board.</p>
<p>If we look at the customer side of things &#8211;and this is not a number that you can get out of public companies because of the way they report [but it&#8217;s a number] you can see in private companies &#8212; a lot of companies added less revenue in the second quarter than they added in the first. So we actually have seen a little bit of a pullback on the customer side of things [and] that hasn&#8217;t necessarily shown up in the fundraising numbers.</p>
<p><strong>On whether that pullback is good, bad, or neutral for founders and investors:</strong></p>
<p>The good news is the whole reason startups exist is to solve important problems in the world, and never have we had a broader array of important problems to be solved than we do right now, because both consumer behavior and the way that businesses operate has changed so dramatically in the last 12 or 18 months. So if what I just said sounds like bad news, we actually think that on balance, it&#8217;s great news, because we see these jobs opening up in the world that founders are rushing to fill. I think that&#8217;s probably why the fundraising numbers are what they are, because everybody sees all those opportunities and they&#8217;re eager to jump in.</p>
<p><strong>On what happens when some of these many new opportunities invariably start to converge &#8212; given the current pace of startup funding &#8212;  and portfolio companies begin to collide, as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/09/sequoia-is-giving-away-21-million-to-a-payments-startup-it-funded-as-it-walks-away-from-deal/">happened to Sequoia</a> in March of last year:</strong></p>
<p>We have always had a policy that we do not invest in direct competitors. What defines a direct competitor? Two companies who are going after the same customers in the same market at the same moment in time. Now, if we have a company here in the U.S. going out to the US market, and our partners in India or China or Southeast Asia have a company in their market that does something similar for their market, that&#8217;s okay, and maybe someday, down the road, they all end up targeting the same sort of customers. But as long as they&#8217;re distinct markets at time zero and they don&#8217;t look like they&#8217;re converging, that&#8217;s okay.</p>
<p>When we&#8217;ve ended up in companies that had conflicts, either we&#8217;ve done the right thing as in the situation you referenced, or when two companies have kind of converged over time, we&#8217;ve set up information barriers and done our best to act in good faith.</p>
<p>There are two products in this market. There&#8217;s a product that is faster and cheaper money. And then there&#8217;s a product that is unfair advantage. The unfair advantage could be nothing more than that Sequoia doesn&#8217;t invest in a lot of companies. We don&#8217;t invest in a new company every day. We might partner with 15 to 20 new founders in any given year, and there&#8217;s some information value in the fact that Sequoia has gotten into business with a company. So if your unfair advantage is nothing more than the fact that Sequoia chose you, so to speak, that&#8217;s still a pretty good advantage when it comes to landing customers [and] landing employees. If your product is money, feel free to give it to competitive companies, because they&#8217;re going to get money from somewhere anyway.</p>
<p><em>[Editor&#8217;s note: We also talked about whether companies can forever stay distributed, Tiger Global, and why one of Sequoia&#8217;s biggest portfolio companies, the payments giant Stripe, isn&#8217;t a public company yet. You can find that in the video below.]</em></p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ssn1tMlTdEA?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/sequoias-pat-grady-a-fog-has-descended-and-it-isnt-clear-startups-should-be-accelerating-right-now/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199885</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rocket Lab&#8217;s order backlog tops $141M as the company inks five-launch deal with Kinéis</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/rocket-labs-order-backlog-tops-141m-as-the-company-inks-five-launch-deal-with-kineis/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/rocket-labs-order-backlog-tops-141m-as-the-company-inks-five-launch-deal-with-kineis/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 22:48:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Electron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neutron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peter beck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satellites]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199816</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It was a busy first half of the year for U.S.-New Zealand company Rocket Lab, which posted earnings for the first six months of 2021 on Wednesday – the first such reporting since the company went public last month. Rocket Lab reported revenues for the six-month period of $29.5 million. Its order backlog also grew [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It was a busy first half of the year for U.S.-New Zealand company Rocket Lab, which posted earnings for the first six months of 2021 on Wednesday – the first such reporting since the company went public last month.</p>
<p>Rocket Lab reported revenues for the six-month period of $29.5 million. Its order backlog also grew to $141.4 million as of June 30, up 136% from $59.9 million compared to the same period last year.</p>
<p>While the general trend seems to be positive, executives emphasized the continued impact of COVID-19 restrictions in New Zealand, the site of one of the company’s key launch facilities. CFO Adam Spice said the third quarter has already been impacted by the pandemic, after New Zealand introduced strict lockdown restrictions in response to an 855-person outbreak of the Delta variant. Those restrictions resulted in “no further launch activity planned” for the quarter, Spice said, and will likely result in a $10-15 million impact on revenues for the year.</p>
<p>Despite these setbacks, executives said they anticipated a yearly revenue of $50-54 million. GAAP operating expenses, meanwhile, hit $29.3 million for the six-month period, up from $11.9 million for the first half of last year. The majority of that increase was from R&amp;D spending, including the development of an automated flight termination system and the Neutron launch vehicle, Spice added.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="E9fMN78VUz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/peter-beck-on-rocket-labs-public-listing-debut-space-spacs-and-the-neutron-rocket/">Peter Beck on Rocket Lab&#8217;s public listing debut, space SPACs and the Neutron rocket</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Peter Beck on Rocket Lab&#8217;s public listing debut, space SPACs and the Neutron rocket&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/peter-beck-on-rocket-labs-public-listing-debut-space-spacs-and-the-neutron-rocket/embed/#?secret=E9fMN78VUz" data-secret="E9fMN78VUz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Rocket Lab, which started as a launch company, has significantly branched out since its founding in 2006. The company now fashions itself as an end-to-end space company, providing launch services, as well as the design, manufacturing and operation of spacecraft.</p>
<p>It is this latter business area that Rocket Lab has aggressively grown over the past eighteen months; some recent milestones include an agreement to develop three of Rocket Lab&#8217;s Photon spacecraft for space manufacturing company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/space-manufacturing-startup-varda-inks-deal-with-rocket-lab-for-three-spacecraft/">Varda Space Industries</a> and plans to send two <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/rocket-labs-mars-mission-gets-green-light-from-nasa/">Photons to Mars</a> on an upcoming space mission. The growth of its space systems division reflects these developments; for the six-month period, space systems made up a $5.4 million share of revenue, up from just $300,000 in the same quarter last year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Rocket Lab also said it would start manufacturing satellite components at scale by the end of this year, starting with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/rocket-lab-boosts-its-space-systems-divison-in-quest-to-become-an-end-to-end-space-company/">reaction wheels</a>, a critical attitude and stability control system. Rocket Lab will be opening a new facility that will be capable of producing up to 2,000 reaction wheels annually, a massive increase in volumes compared to what’s ever been available to the space industry before.</p>
<p>“Satellite components typically have been produced in small numbers which has really limited the speed and scale of constellation development,” CEO Peter Beck said during an investor call Wednesday. “The [reaction wheel production] line has been built to solve that, enabling production at scale to meet the growing needs of customers in the industry at large.”</p>
<p>Rocket Lab’s space systems division was given a huge boost by the acquisition of major satellite hardware manufacturer Sinclair Interplanetary last year, and it likely won’t be the company’s last purchase. Rocket Lab has around a half dozen deals it’s actively investigating, Spice told investors Wednesday. “The Sinclair acquisition has really emboldened us to lean forward and look at opportunities.”</p>
<p>“What&#8217;s interesting about this market right now is it does really feel like it&#8217;s ripe for consolidation,” he said. “Not consolidation in the sense of large companies necessarily getting together but the fact [that] the invest-ability of space is a relatively new phenomenon,” he said.</p>
<p>Company executives stayed largely mum on the Neutron rocket, with Beck simply noting that it “continues to develop really well” and that the company will provide a more detailed development in the coming months.</p>
<p>“Neutron is a vehicle that is not an increment on Electron,” he said. “It is something that really sets a new standard within the space industry.”</p>
<p>Rocket Lab also announced today that it has inked a multi-launch contract with Kinéis, a French connectivity provider for Internet of Things devices, to deploy its satellite constellation across five Electron missions. Kinéis’ investors include the French space agency Centre National d’Études Spatiales and French space company Collecte Localisation Satellites.</p>
<p>The constellation will consist of 25 satellites in total, adding to the over 100 satellites Rocket Lab has launched on its Electron rocket to date. The launches are scheduled for the second quarter 2023.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Five Electron launches, 25 satellites, 1 entire constellation: we’ve signed a deal with <a href="https://twitter.com/KineisIoT?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KineisIoT</a> to deliver their internet-of-things constellation to space on Electron. <a href="https://t.co/8UtjGQS0gm">pic.twitter.com/8UtjGQS0gm</a></p>
<p>— Rocket Lab (@RocketLab) <a href="https://twitter.com/RocketLab/status/1435697181785149441?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 8, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>This is just the latest multi-launch deal Rocket Lab has inked in recent months, including a contract with satellite analytics company BlackSky for five launches.</p>
<p>Rocket Lab has continued to rise, closing Wednesday at $15.09. That represents a nearly 50% increase since the company’s public debut at the end of August.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/rocket-labs-order-backlog-tops-141m-as-the-company-inks-five-launch-deal-with-kineis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199816</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The 4 things needed to reach Biden&#8217;s ambitious 2050 solar goal</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/the-4-things-needed-to-reach-bidens-ambitious-2050-solar-goal/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/the-4-things-needed-to-reach-bidens-ambitious-2050-solar-goal/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 22:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar energy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199772</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A report on the future of solar energy from the Department of Energy paints a sunny picture, if you will, of the next three decades, at the end of which nearly half the country&#8217;s energy will be provided by the sun. But for that to happen, big pushes need to happen along four major lines: [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-releases-solar-futures-study-providing-blueprint-zero-carbon-grid">A report on the future of solar energy from the Department of Energy</a> paints a sunny picture, if you will, of the next three decades, at the end of which nearly half the country&#8217;s energy will be provided by the sun. But for that to happen, big pushes need to happen along four major lines: better photovoltaics, more energy storage, lower soft costs, and putting about a million people to work.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s what the report says needs to happen in each of these sectors in order to meet the ambitious goals it sets out.</p>
<h3>Better photovoltaics</h3>
<p>The solar cells themselves will need to continue to improve in both cost and efficiency in order to achieve the kind of installation volumes hoped for by the DOE. For reference, 2020 saw 15 gigawatts worth of solar installed, the most ever — but we&#8217;re going to need to double that installation rate by 2025, then double it again by 2030.</p>
<p>If photovoltaics don&#8217;t improve in efficiency, that means these already ambitious numbers need to go even higher to account for that. And if they stay at today&#8217;s prices, the costs will be too high to achieve those volumes as well.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199837" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PV-efficiencies.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199837" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2199837 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PV-efficiencies.png" alt="" width="1024" height="555" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PV-efficiencies.png 1429w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PV-efficiencies.png?resize=150,81 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PV-efficiencies.png?resize=300,163 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PV-efficiencies.png?resize=768,417 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PV-efficiencies.png?resize=680,369 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PV-efficiencies.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2199837" class="wp-caption-text">Photovoltaics have come a long way, but they also have a long way to go.</p></div></p>
<p>Fortunately efficiency is going up and cost is going down already. But it&#8217;s not like that just happens naturally. Companies and researchers across the globe have spent millions on new manufacturing processes, new materials, and other improvements, incremental individually but which add up over time. This basic research and advancement of the science and methods around solar <em>must</em> continue at or beyond the pace that they have over the last two decades.</p>
<p>The DOE suggests that research along the lines of making more exotic PVs cheaper, or stacking cells to minimize bandgap-related losses could be crucial. Flexible and tile- or shingle-like substrates or semi-transparent installations that pass light through to crops or building interiors may also figure. Altogether the plan calls for a reduction of the overall cost to drop by almost half from $1.30/watt today on average to $0.70 by 2030 and more after that.</p>
<p>Solar concentrators get their own heading in the report, and many companies are looking into these to replace industrial processes. These will not likely be used to support the grid at large but will nevertheless replace many fossil fuel based processes.</p>
<h3>More energy storage</h3>
<p>An unavoidable consequence of getting your energy from the sun is that at night you must rely on stored energy in some form or another, originally nuclear or coal but increasingly a form of storage that collects excess power collected during the daytime. With more of peak usage being covered by renewables, cities can safely transition away from carbon-based energy sources.</p>
<p>While we often think of energy storage in terms of batteries, and certainly they will be present, but the amount of energy that must be stored rules out something like lithium-ion batteries as the primary storage mechanism. Instead, the excess energy can be put towards powering energy-hungry renewable fuel production, like hydrogen fuel cells. This fuel can then be used to generate power when solar can&#8217;t meet demand.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199844" style="width: 891px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/load-chart.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199844" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2199844" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/load-chart.png" alt="" width="881" height="503" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/load-chart.png 881w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/load-chart.png?resize=150,86 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/load-chart.png?resize=300,171 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/load-chart.png?resize=768,438 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/load-chart.png?resize=680,388 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/load-chart.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 881px) 100vw, 881px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2199844" class="wp-caption-text">The diagram shows how demand would normally go (purple) then how it would go with solar (orange) and how energy storage could mitigate that load (solid colors).</p></div></p>
<p>That&#8217;s just the &#8220;off the top of the head&#8221; answer. As the report states: &#8220;Thermal, chemical, and mechanical storage technologies are under various stages of development, including pumped thermal storage, liquid air energy storage, novel gravity-based technologies, and geological hydrogen storage.&#8221;</p>
<p>No doubt there will be a variety of new and old technologies working to provide the various levels of energy redundancy and storage duration needs of the country. These will go a long way towards making solar and other renewable energy sources capable of being relied on for a greater proportion of demand.</p>
<h3>Lower soft costs</h3>
<p>If we&#8217;re going to double and redouble the rate of solar cell deployment, the costs have to come down not just for the cells themselves, but the whole end-to-end process: assessment, accounting, labor, and of course the profit due to the companies that will be doing the actual work.</p>
<p>Lowering non-hardware costs is already the goal of many startups, like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/aurora-solar-aims-to-power-the-growing-solar-industry-with-a-250m-round-c/">Aurora Solar</a>, which clearly saw the writing on the wall and started making it as easy as possible to plan, visualize, and sell solar installations entirely online.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="N4DQbUzFzr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/aurora-solar-aims-to-power-the-growing-solar-industry-with-a-250m-round-c/">Aurora Solar aims to power the growing solar industry with a $250M round C</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Aurora Solar aims to power the growing solar industry with a $250M round C&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/aurora-solar-aims-to-power-the-growing-solar-industry-with-a-250m-round-c/embed/#?secret=N4DQbUzFzr" data-secret="N4DQbUzFzr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Right now the all-in cost of a solar roof might be twice the cost of the hardware or more. There are several contributors to this, from financing to regulations to markets, and each has its own intricacies beyond the scope of this article. Suffice it to say that if you can shave one percent off the cost of a solar installation by streamlining the time or cost involved in any of these areas, there will be more than enough volume to turn that one point into a major sum. It will take the combined efforts of many organizational and commercial minds to make this happen, just as it takes the efforts of many scientific ones to improve PVs.</p>
<h3>A million jobs</h3>
<p>Last but certainly not least, someone has to <em>actually do</em> all this work. That means a whole lot of labor — several times the quarter million people currently estimated to be attached to the solar industry in the country today.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1954598" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1954598" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1954598" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg" alt="Workers install solar panels on the roofs of homes under construction in California." width="1024" height="694" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg 5000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg?resize=150,102 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg?resize=300,203 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg?resize=768,520 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg?resize=680,461 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg?resize=1536,1041 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg?resize=2048,1388 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1954598" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=editorial&amp;photographer=MediaNews+GroupInland+Valley+Daily+Bulletin+via+Getty+Images" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Will Lester/Inland Valley Daily Bulletin <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Jobs in this sector will run the gamut, from skilled workers with construction experience to energy professionals who&#8217;ve managed grids to public-private partnership wizards who connect commerce to the government&#8217;s inevitable top-down incentives. The additional half a million to a million jobs will almost certainly comprise many brand new companies and sub-industries, but the general breakdown so far has been about 65 percent installation and project development, 25 percent sales and manufacturing, and the rest in miscellaneous roles.</p>
<p>It is worth noting, however, that energy concerns currently clinging with white knuckles to aging oil and coal infrastructure will need to do right by the tens of thousands they still employ, and the renewable energy sector is a perfect transition space. &#8220;Throughout the transition, certain fossil fuel companies may come under increasing financial distress,&#8221; the report reads, which is something of an understatement. The authors strongly suggest funding transition programs that cover training, relocation, and guarantees of existing financial benefits like pensions.</p>
<p>The report points out that the solar industry is overwhelmingly white and male, like a few others we could name, so it is probably worth putting in work on that front if the million hires are to be at all equitable.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.energy.gov/eere/solar/solar-futures-study">You can browse the full study here.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/the-4-things-needed-to-reach-bidens-ambitious-2050-solar-goal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199772</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Google rolls out new Workspace features for all users</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/daily-crunch-59/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/daily-crunch-59/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 22:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199693</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hi friends!</p>
<p>Welcome to the Daily Crunch for Wednesday, September 8, 2021. <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> is still out, so I&#8217;ll be steering this ship for a few more days while (I hope) he stares at trees, or the ocean, or really anything but words on a computer screen. Alex, if you&#8217;re reading this, please put your phone in airplane mode and do something cool. &#8212; <a href="https://twitter.com/grg">Greg</a></p>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/wright-tests-its-2-megawatt-electric-engines-for-passenger-planes/">Wright tests its electric engine for passenger planes:</a></strong> Electric planes face challenges that electric cars don&#8217;t, like … you know, needing to get off the ground. Current battery tech is just too heavy for existing engines to get up in the air efficiently. Devin Coldewey has a profile on Wright, a startup looking to tackle this by making an electric engine that produces more thrust from less energy. They&#8217;re currently testing it at sea level, with plans to get it up to flying heights sometime next year.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/howard-university-cancels-classes-after-ransomware-attack/">Howard University cancels classes after ransomware attack:</a></strong> &#8220;Sorry class, lessons are canceled for the day because we got hacked.&#8221; It&#8217;s the oh-so-2021 version of a snow day. Snow Crash Day?</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/sec-wants-to-regulate-coinbases-crypto-yield-product-coinbase-disagrees/">SEC threatens to sue Coinbase:</a></strong> Looks like there&#8217;s a bit of a battle potentially brewing between Coinbase and the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. Coinbase wants to launch a service that would let users loan out crypto assets to a lending pool and gain interest (noting that others already have launched similar services). Coinbase gave the SEC a heads-up … which, according to Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong, led to the SEC threatening to sue Coinbase if it moved forward.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/indian-fintech-slice-launches-27-credit-limit-cards-to-tap-200-million-users/">The credit card with a $27 limit:</a></strong> &#8220;The relatively young credit-rating system in India covers only a tiny fraction of the nation’s population,&#8221; writes Manish Singh. As a result, an equally tiny fraction of the population has access to credit cards. Slice, a startup out of Bangalore, is looking to help young people in the region start to slowly build their credit by introducing a card with a cap of 2,000 Indian rupees — or about $27.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/tiktok-and-snap-alums-launch-mayk-it-a-social-music-creation-app-with-4m-in-seed-funding/"><strong>A social network for making music:</strong></a> TikTok remixed the concept of the remix, allowing users to take another user&#8217;s video and remold it into their own thing. Mayk.it, a new social app founded by TikTok/Snap alums, wants to bring the focus back to music. One user makes a beat, others add vocals and everyone crosses their fingers for a hit. The app launched this week, simultaneously announcing it had raised $4 million in seed funding.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/paypal-acquires-japans-paidy-for-2-7b-to-crack-the-buy-now-pay-later-market-in-asia/">PayPal buys Paidy:</a></strong> $2.7 billion! That&#8217;s how much PayPal is dropping on Paidy, a popular buy now, pay later service from Japan. Kate Park writes that this move should help PayPal dive right into deferred payments in the country — which, as she points out, is the third largest e-commerce market in the world.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Debt versus equity: When do non-traditional funding strategies make sense?</h2>
<p>Many potential founders are well versed in startup economics — and many are completely green.</p>
<p>When it comes to raising funds, understanding the relative benefits (and limitations) of debt and equity financing is required knowledge, however.</p>
<p>Founders who are less willing to dilute their control may be willing to use debt financing to fund their capital expenditures, &#8220;but it doesn&#8217;t make sense for everyone,&#8221; says six-time entrepreneur David Friend.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QASQt316We"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/debt-versus-equity-when-do-non-traditional-funding-strategies-make-sense/">Debt versus equity: When do non-traditional funding strategies make sense?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Debt versus equity: When do non-traditional funding strategies make sense?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/debt-versus-equity-when-do-non-traditional-funding-strategies-make-sense/embed/#?secret=QASQt316We" data-secret="QASQt316We" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/microsoft-launches-a-personalized-news-service-microsoft-start/">Microsoft launches a personalized news service:</a></strong> Microsoft is taking a swing at the Apple News/Flipboard concept with Microsoft Start, a site/app that aggregates content from your favorite news sources. You can thumbs up/down things to tune the algorithm over time, because what the world needs is more robots telling us what to read. I miss Google Reader.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/google-workspace-opens-up-spaces-for-all-users/"><strong>Google opens Spaces for all:</strong></a> Last year Google rebranded its built-for-work toolset from G Suite to Google Workspace. Around the same time, it started testing new features that makes the myriad Workspace tools (Gmail, Docs, Meet, etc.) work more cohesively, retuning them with the sudden work-from-home spike in mind. As of today, those features are rolling out to everyone.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/twitter-full-width-image-tweets-test/">Twitter is testing big ol&#8217; full-width photos and videos:</a></strong> &#8220;While the result looks like a win to us, any change to Twitter’s design is likely to inspire a vocal subset of users to hate-tweet about it for a day or so before forgetting the changes altogether,&#8221; Taylor Hatmaker so perfectly sums up.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants to help startups find the right expert for their needs. To do this, we’re building a shortlist of the top growth marketers. We’ve received great recommendations for growth marketers in the startup industry since we launched our survey.</p>
<p>We’re excited to read more responses as they come in! <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">Fill out the survey here.</a></p>
<p>Our editorial coverage about growth marketing includes articles from the TechCrunch team, guest columns, and posts like “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/use-cohort-analysis-to-drive-smarter-startup-growth/">Use cohort analysis to drive smarter startup growth</a>” by <a href="https://twitter.com/metrickmind">Jonathan Metrick</a> on Extra Crunch.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dZSc1bA1Cu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/use-cohort-analysis-to-drive-smarter-startup-growth/">Use cohort analysis to drive smarter startup growth</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Use cohort analysis to drive smarter startup growth&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/use-cohort-analysis-to-drive-smarter-startup-growth/embed/#?secret=dZSc1bA1Cu" data-secret="dZSc1bA1Cu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/daily-crunch-59/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199693</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tape It launches an AI-powered music recording app for iPhone</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/tape-it-launches-an-a-i-powered-music-recording-app-for-iphone/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/tape-it-launches-an-a-i-powered-music-recording-app-for-iphone/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 21:32:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[a.i.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accenture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[audio engineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sonalytic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soundcloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soundtrap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stockholm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tape It]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199685</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier this year, Apple officially discontinued Music Memos, an iPhone app that allowed musicians to quickly record audio and develop new song ideas. Now, a new startup called Tape It is stepping in to fill the void with an app that improves audio recordings by offering a variety of features, including higher-quality sound, automatic instrument [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Earlier this year, Apple <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/03/02/apple-music-memos-voice-memos-integration/">officially discontinued</a> Music Memos, an iPhone app that allowed musicians to quickly record audio and develop new song ideas. Now, a new startup called <a href="https://tape.it/">Tape It</a> is stepping in to fill the void with an app that improves audio recordings by offering a variety of features, including higher-quality sound, automatic instrument detection, support for markers, notes and images, and more.</p>
<p>The idea for Tape It comes from two friends and musicians, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tcwalther/">Thomas Walther</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jan-n-2559b2116/">Jan Nash</a>.</p>
<p>Walther had previously spent three and a half years at Spotify, following its 2017 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/07/spotify-acquires-audio-detection-startup-sonalytic/">acquisition of the audio detection startup Sonalytic</a>, which he had co-founded. Nash, meanwhile, is a classically trained opera singer, who also plays bass and is an engineer.</p>
<p>They&#8217;re joined by designer and musician <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/christiancrusius/">Christian Crusius</a>, previously of the design consultancy Fjord, which was <a href="https://newsroom.accenture.com/industries/communications/accenture-completes-acquisition-of-fjord-expanding-digital-and-marketing-capabilities.htm">acquired</a> by Accenture.</p>
<p>The founders, who had played in a band together for many years, were inspired to build Tape It because it was something they wanted for themselves, Walther says. After ending his stint at Spotify working in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/17/spotify-acquires-online-music-studio-soundtrap/">their new Soundtrap division</a> (an online music startup Spotify also bought in 2017), he knew he wanted to work on a project that was more focused on the music-making side of things. But while Soundtrap worked for some, it wasn&#8217;t what either Walther or his friends had needed. Instead, they wanted a simple tool that would allow them to record their music with their phone &#8212; something that musicians often do today using Apple&#8217;s Voice Memos app and, briefly, Music Memos &#8212; until its demise.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199782" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199782" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2199782" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-3.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="510" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-3.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-3.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-3.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-3.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-3.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-3.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-3.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199782" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Tape It</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Regardless of whether you&#8217;re an amateur or even like a touring professional&#8230;you will record your ideas with your phone, just because that&#8217;s what you have with you,&#8221; Walther explains. &#8220;It&#8217;s the exact same thing with cameras &#8212; the best camera is the one you have with you. And the best audio recording tool is the one you have with you.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That is, when you want to record, the easiest thing to do is not to get out your laptop and connect a bunch of cables to it, then load up your studio software &#8212; it&#8217;s to hit the record button on your iPhone.</p>
<p>The Tape It app allows you to do just that, but adds other features that make it more competitive with its built-in competition, Voice Memos.</p>
<p>When you record using Tape It, the app leverages AI to automatically detect the instrument, then annotate the recording with a visual indication to make those recordings easier to find by looking for the colorful icon. Musicians can also add their own markers to the files right when they record them, then add notes and photos to remind themselves of other details. This can be useful when reviewing the recordings later on, Walther says.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199783" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199783" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2199783" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-2.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="510" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-2.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-2.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-2.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-2.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-2.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-2.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-2.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199783" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Tape It</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;If I have a nice guitar sound, I can just take a picture of the settings on my amplifier, and I have them. This is something musicians do all the time,&#8221; he notes. &#8220;It&#8217;s the easiest way to re-create that sound.&#8221;</p>
<p>Another novel, but simple, change in Tape It is it that breaks longer recordings into multiple lines, similar to a paragraph of text. The team calls this the &#8220;Time Paragraph,&#8221; and believes it will make listening to longer sessions easier than the default &#8212; which is typically a single, horizontally scrollable recording.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199785" style="width: 333px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199785" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2199785" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png?w=323" alt="" width="323" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png 1580w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png?resize=71,150 71w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png?resize=142,300 142w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png?resize=768,1618 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png?resize=323,680 323w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png?resize=729,1536 729w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png?resize=972,2048 972w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png?resize=24,50 24w" sizes="(max-width: 323px) 100vw, 323px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199785" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Tape It</p></div></p>
<p>The app has also been designed so it&#8217;s easier to go back to the right part of recordings, thanks to its smart waveforms, in addition to the optional markers and photos. And you can mark recordings as favorites so you can quickly pull up a list of your best ideas and sounds. The app offers full media center integration as well, so you can play back your music whenever you have time.</p>
<p>However, the standout feature is Tape It&#8217;s support for &#8220;Stereo HD&#8221; quality. Here, the app takes advantage of the two microphones on devices like the iPhone XS, XR, and other newer models, then improves the sound using AI technology and other noise reduction techniques, which it&#8217;s developed in-house. This feature is part of its $20 per year premium subscription.</p>
<p>Over time, Tape It intends to broaden its use of AI and other IP to improve the sound quality further. It also plans to introduce collaborative features and support for importing and exporting recordings into professional studio software. This could eventually place Tape It into the same market that SoundCloud had initially chased before it shifted its focus to becoming more of a consumer-facing service.</p>
<p>But first, Tape It wants to nail the single-user workflow before adding on more sharing features.</p>
<p>&#8220;We decided that it&#8217;s so important to make sure it&#8217;s useful, even just for you. The stuff that you can collaborate on &#8212; if you don&#8217;t like using it yourself, you&#8217;re not going to use it,&#8221; Walther says.</p>
<p>Tape It&#8217;s team of three is based in Stockholm and Berlin and is currently bootstrapping.</p>
<p>The app itself is a free download on <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/tape-it-songwriting/id1576341885">iOS</a> and will later support desktop users on Mac and Windows. An Android version is not planned.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/tape-it-launches-an-a-i-powered-music-recording-app-for-iphone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199685</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI-driven voice assistant PolyAI raises $14M round led by Khosla Ventures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/ai-driven-voice-assistant-polyai-raises-14m-round-led-by-khosla-ventures/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/ai-driven-voice-assistant-polyai-raises-14m-round-led-by-khosla-ventures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 21:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alexa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cambridge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chatbots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer satisfaction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instant Messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interactions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Khosla Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nikola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nuance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Passion Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Point72 Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PolyAI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Replicant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sands Capital Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starling bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[university of cambridge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[user interfaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[viasat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vinod Khosla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual assistant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voice assistant]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199776</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“Conversational AI” startup PolyAI, based out of London, has raised $14 million in a funding round led by Silicon Valley&#8217;s Khosla Ventures, with participation from existing investors (Point72 Ventures, Amadeus Capital, Sands Capital Ventures, Passion Capital and Entrepreneur First). This follows their $12 million Series A, and will provide resources for further U.S. expansion beyond [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">“Conversational AI” startup <a href="https://poly-ai.com/">PolyAI</a>, based out of London, has raised $14 million in a funding round led by Silicon Valley&#8217;s Khosla Ventures, with participation from existing investors (Point72 Ventures, Amadeus Capital, Sands Capital Ventures, Passion Capital and Entrepreneur First). This <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/08/polyai/">follows</a> their $12 million Series A, and will provide resources for further U.S. expansion beyond its existing U.S. team. The startup has now raised $28 million to date.</p>
<p>PolyAI builds and deploys voice assistants for automating customer services, which, claims the startup, sound like real humans. This helps companies get an infinite and cheaper supply of their best human voice operators, which reduces customer waiting times, and increases customer satisfaction and retention, says the company.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EVQBuQ8Vyf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/31/how-artificial-intelligence-will-be-used-in-2021/">How artificial intelligence will be used in 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How artificial intelligence will be used in 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/31/how-artificial-intelligence-will-be-used-in-2021/embed/#?secret=EVQBuQ8Vyf" data-secret="EVQBuQ8Vyf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Co-founder Dr Nikola Mrkšić said: “The technical term for our technology is ‘multi-turn conversational AI’, but all the caller has to do is talk to it, like they would to a human. Compared to existing call centers, our assistants can boost customer satisfaction (CSAT) scores by up to 40% and reduce handling times by up to five minutes.”</p>
<p>“We build these systems very quickly (relative to the competition) — we get experiences like these up and running in 2-4 weeks thanks to our transformer-based language understanding models and the underlying dialog management platform,” he added.</p>
<p>In a statement, Vinod Khosla said: “PolyAI is one of the first AI companies using the newest generation of large pre-trained deep learning models (akin to BERT and GPT-3) in a real-world enterprise product. This means they can deploy automated AI agents in as little as two weeks, where incumbent providers of voice assistants would take up to six months to deploy an older version of this technology.”</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tZTO_-nWRHM?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A spinout from the University of Cambridge, PolyAI says it is effectively &#8220;pushing at an open door&#8221; as the pandemic has led to staffing shortages in call centers, driving more companies to deploy smart voice assistants, which appear not to have been replaced chatbots at all, as consumers generally prefer to speak than type.</p>
<p>“We were expecting the system to handle 40% of calls, but at launch it handled 80%, and within two weeks it was up to 87%,” said Brian Jeppesen of Landry’s Golden Nugget Hotels &amp; Casinos. “Callers think the AI agent is human”, Jeppesen continued, “which is great because the voice assistant never has a bad day, and is on 24/7. I wish I could hire more agents like that!”</p>
<p>Competitors include Nuance (recently acquired by Microsoft), Isoft, Interactions, SmartAction and Replicant. But PolyAI says its voice assistant can be turned live more quickly, in more languages, and charges on a per-minute basis.</p>
<p>Founded by Nikola Mrkšić (CEO), Tsung-Hsien Wen (CTO) and Pei-Hao Su (Engineering Director), the three met while doing PhDs with Professor Steve Young, a leader in spoken dialog systems who pioneered many technologies that underpin voice assistants like Siri, Google Assistant and Alexa.</p>
<p>Recent PolyAI clients include Landry’s Entertainment, Greene King, Starling Bank and Viasat.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/ai-driven-voice-assistant-polyai-raises-14m-round-led-by-khosla-ventures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199776</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reid Hoffman&#8217;s latest book gives us 10 ways to rethink entrepreneurship</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/reid-hoffmans-masters-of-scale-book/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/reid-hoffmans-masters-of-scale-book/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 21:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reid Hoffman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199605</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When you’re in the mood for a pep talk, who better to turn to than a well-networked, optimistic mentor who is naturally in your corner? That friendly shoulder is the role that &#8220;Masters of Scale&#8221; wants to play. Inspired by LinkedIn co-founder and Greylock partner Reid Hoffman’s hit podcast, the new book, co-authored by Hoffman [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When you’re in the mood for a pep talk, who better to turn to than a well-networked, optimistic mentor who is naturally in your corner? That friendly shoulder is the role that &#8220;Masters of Scale&#8221; wants to play.</p>
<p>Inspired by LinkedIn co-founder and Greylock partner Reid Hoffman’s hit podcast, the new book, co-authored by Hoffman along with podcast executive producers June Cohen and Deron Triff, came out this week. Riddled with anecdotes and actionable takeaways, the book’s strength is wholly related to the sheer diversity of entrepreneurs that are represented in the text. Beyond sticking to tech leaders, the book draws lessons from Spanx founder Sara Blakely, Starbucks founder Howard Schultz and Union Square Hospitality Group CEO Daniel Meyer. Like any good mentor, the book is realistic. Mentors know you aren’t Bumble’s Whitney Wolfe Herd or Airbnb’s Brian Chesky yet, but can extract universally applicable lessons from those leaders so that you can relate to them.</p>
<p>While press wasn’t a main character in the book, &#8220;Master of Scale&#8221; has already changed my perspective on how I interview founders. Lessons from Tristan Walker made me want to ask more questions about founders, and their most controversial beliefs, rather than how they plan to spend their new round of funding. A note from Andrés Ruzo made me realize that a startup that makes too much sense might be a comfortable read, but it might not be a moonshot that disrupts the world; in other words, pursue the startups that have too much seemingly foolish ambition &#8212; because they may be where the best strides, and stories, are made. Finally, it confirmed my belief that the best litmus test for a founder is if they are willing to talk about the hardships ahead of them in an honest, humble way.</p>
<p>Through every feel-good story, I waited for the pandemic to be addressed. The pandemic’s impact on startup advice was largely isolated to a single chapter about the art of the pivot. Instead of interspersing advice on how to deal with the pandemic’s impact on venture capital, funding and markets more broadly, the book limited its references to the cataclysmic event. This choice keeps the advice smartly evergreen. That said, I felt like the book’s choice to not talk much about the ugly within startupland creates an imbalance of sorts. It would have benefitted from talking directly about divisive dynamics, ranging from how WeWork’s Adam Neumann impacted the way we talk about visionary founders, Brian Armstrong’s Coinbase memo and what it means for startup culture, or even the role of the tech press today. One could argue that the book never claims to be journalistic, and instead wanted to play the role of a cheerleading mentor, not a cynical one.</p>
<p>Writing a book based on a hit podcast isn’t necessarily a walk in the park. Audio is an entirely different medium from written text, and it takes a certain finesse to translate into text the charisma and humility of vocal banter. Hoffman and the authors thus certainly shine brighter in some stories than others, leaning heavily on a repeated, yet effective storytelling arc throughout the text: introduce problem, present aha moment, offer solutions and share universal lessons.</p>
<p>I read the book over a weekend; I recommend the same move for any aspiring entrepreneur, techie or startup journalist looking to pick up a copy. Reid and the coauthors will do a fantastic job connecting the dots of over 70 entrepreneurs for you, but the real magic will come from what happens when you pause in between the stories &#8212; either to Google a founder you resonate with, to change up your interview style or to finally start working on the idea you one day may just blitzscale.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2199607" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MastersofScale_3D_bookshot_facing.png" alt="" width="1000" height="844" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MastersofScale_3D_bookshot_facing.png 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MastersofScale_3D_bookshot_facing.png?resize=150,127 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MastersofScale_3D_bookshot_facing.png?resize=300,253 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MastersofScale_3D_bookshot_facing.png?resize=768,648 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MastersofScale_3D_bookshot_facing.png?resize=680,574 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MastersofScale_3D_bookshot_facing.png?resize=50,42 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/reid-hoffmans-masters-of-scale-book/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199605</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fintech is transforming the world&#8217;s oldest asset class: Farmland</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/fintech-is-transforming-the-worlds-oldest-asset-class-farmland/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/fintech-is-transforming-the-worlds-oldest-asset-class-farmland/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 19:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Food Climate and Sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food supply]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199480</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While farmland is among the oldest investment classes around, the average investor hasn’t had access to farmland the way that billionaires and institutional investors have. That's changing.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Artem Milinchuk</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/artem_milinchuk">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Artem Milinchuk is the founder and CEO of <a href="https://farmtogether.com/">FarmTogether</a>, a fintech platform channeling funding into natural assets, starting with U.S. farmland.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Farmland as an asset class has proven itself to be a stable investment decade after decade. <a href="https://farmland.illinois.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Correlation-Farmland-Utility-Center-2021.xlsm">Farmland’s negative correlation</a> with the Dow Jones Industrial Average sits at an eye-popping -43% for a three-year hold period, making it an excellent hedge against market volatility.</p>
<p>The asset has also been a steady <a href="https://www.nass.usda.gov/Publications/Trends_in_U.S._Agriculture/Land_Values/index.php">appreciator since 1987</a>, when institutional investors began incorporating farmland into their portfolios. Equally, investments into sustainably managed farmland have the potential to transform agriculture from one of the largest sources of greenhouse gas emissions to one of the largest carbon sinks.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			While farmland investments can provide passive income and a hedge during just about any economic condition, direct investments into the asset have been largely inaccessible to date.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>However, while farmland is among the oldest investment classes around, the average investor hasn’t had access to farmland the way that billionaires and institutional investors have.</p>
<p>Revolutions in fintech and a host of startups are changing this.</p>
<h2>Why farmland?</h2>
<p>COVID-19 affected the world in ways we couldn’t have predicted, and the markets were no exception. The <a href="https://voxeu.org/article/stock-market-and-economy-insights-covid-19-crisis">S&amp;P 500 plummeted in mid-March</a> and shed 34% of its pre-COVID peak value. But unlike past crises, the index rebounded just a month later.</p>
<p>This doesn’t mean that financial markets have fully recovered, however. We’ve seen <a href="https://www.morganstanley.com/articles/how-to-handle-volatility">plenty of volatility</a> since, both in the form of rallies and losses. This has caused many investors to move some of their portfolio out of equities.</p>
<p>This is where farmland entered the discussion.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199597" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199597" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2199597" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png?w=680" alt="Farmland price per acre compared to the S&amp;P &amp; DJIA EOY close price" width="2000" height="1081" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png 5418w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png?resize=150,81 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png?resize=300,162 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png?resize=768,415 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png?resize=680,367 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png?resize=1536,830 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png?resize=2048,1107 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199597" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://farmtogether.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FarmTogether <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<h2>A historically stable asset class</h2>
<p>Wild stock market fluctuations existed well before COVID-19. The <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/goldilocks-keynes-and-fluctuations-in-the-stock-market">latest era of volatility</a> began in 2018 and continued even as the economy grew prior to the pandemic. Given the unpredictability of the equities market, investors need to counterbalance what’s in store for stocks and funds.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/fintech-is-transforming-the-worlds-oldest-asset-class-farmland/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199480</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Debt versus equity: When do non-traditional funding strategies make sense?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/debt-versus-equity-when-do-non-traditional-funding-strategies-make-sense/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/debt-versus-equity-when-do-non-traditional-funding-strategies-make-sense/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 17:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unicorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture debt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199383</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How can debt be stable and reliable? Seems like an oxymoron, but the reality is that while equity investors are looking for growth, debt investors just want to get paid back with interest.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">David Friend</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/wasabi_cloud">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		David Friend is a serial entrepreneur, six-time founder, and the current co-founder and CEO of cloud storage company, <a href="https://wasabi.com/">Wasabi Technologies</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/16/brand-power-vs-product-power/">Brand power vs. product power</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/25/the-herd-sours-on-unprofitable-unicorns-again/">The herd sours on unprofitable unicorns again</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The U.S. produces more new <a href="https://www.statista.com/topics/4733/startups-worldwide/">startups and unicorns</a> each year than any other country in the world, but <a href="https://www.failory.com/blog/startup-failure-rate">90% of startups fail</a>, with cash flow often being a major challenge.</p>
<p>Entrepreneurs trying to raise funding for their new businesses are faced with a maze of options, with most taking the common route of equity rounds. There’s clearly <a href="https://www.abladvisor.com/news/30176/vc-investment-in-u-s-hits-new-record-high-in-2020-kpmg">a lot of venture money</a> to be raised — and most tech entrepreneurs happily take it in exchange for equity. This works for some, but too often founders find themselves diluting their equity to unrecoverable portions rather than considering other financing options that allow them to hold on to their company — options like debt capital.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Even if you’re growing quickly, not all founders want to set a valuation for their company. In that case, you can offer investors &#8220;convertible debt.&#8221;					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Despite the VC flurries of 2020 creating an ecosystem of seemingly endless equity, it’s important for entrepreneurs and founders to understand that there is no one-size-fits-all model for raising capital. Debt capital, which refers to capital raised by taking out a loan, is an alternative route that entrepreneurs should consider.</p>
<p>Understanding the real cost of venture debt and when it makes more sense than the traditional equity route relies on an understanding of what you and your company hope to achieve.</p>
<h2>Understanding your goals</h2>
<p>We mainly see two kinds of startups today: Those that want to try something new, and the ones that focus on making things faster, cheaper or simpler. Facebook, Twitter and Instagram are good examples of the first kind — social media didn’t exist before the internet. Discount airlines, cell phones (not smartphones) and integrated circuits are good examples of the “faster, cheaper, simpler” variety, because they simply displaced familiar incumbents.</p>
<p>Many entrepreneurs are eager to be the next “try something new” success story, and I applaud them for feeling that way. Carving out your own market is a fast-track to entrepreneurial stardom if you’re successful. But unless your main goal is to be famous, it’s often impractical and distracting.</p>
<p>People tend to think that category creation is less risky than incumbent disruption. However, as long as you’re truly faster, cheaper and simpler, patience and strategy can propel you to where you want to be.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Just as there are different market approaches, there are a number of funding strategies that work best for your goals. Landing investments from leading VC firms has benefits and is a good avenue to opt for if you’re a young startup carving out a market and in need of validation and experience. These firms bring trusted advisers that are laser-focused on growth and have the resources and experience to navigate the murky waters of category creation.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/debt-versus-equity-when-do-non-traditional-funding-strategies-make-sense/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199383</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SEC wants to regulate Coinbase’s crypto yield product, Coinbase disagrees</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/sec-wants-to-regulate-coinbases-crypto-yield-product-coinbase-disagrees/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/sec-wants-to-regulate-coinbases-crypto-yield-product-coinbase-disagrees/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 17:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lending pool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199554</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong has reacted strongly to the company’s current relationship with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. According to him, the SEC is threatening to sue the cryptocurrency exchange if it launches its yield-generating product called Coinbase Lend. With this new product, Coinbase wants to compete with popular decentralized finance (DeFi) products, such [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.coinbase.com">Coinbase</a> CEO Brian Armstrong has reacted strongly to the company’s current relationship with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. According to him, the SEC is threatening to sue the cryptocurrency exchange if it launches its yield-generating product called <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/lend">Coinbase Lend</a>.</p>
<p>With this new product, Coinbase wants to compete with popular decentralized finance (DeFi) products, such as <a href="https://compound.finance">Compound</a> and <a href="https://aave.com">Aave</a>. The company wants to operate a lending pool focused on USD Coin (USDC), a stablecoin that is pegged to USD.</p>
<p>If the company manages to launch Coinbase Lend, users will be able to contribute to the lending pool by sending crypto assets to Coinbase Lend. Eventually, the company plans to lend out those crypto assets. Coinbase users get high interest rates in exchange to contributing to the lending pool. Coinbase promises 4% APY on its <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/lend">preview page</a>.</p>
<p>According to Brian Armstrong, the company reached out to the SEC before releasing it. “They responded by telling us this lend feature is a security,” he said <a href="https://twitter.com/brian_armstrong/status/1435439543692365828">on Twitter</a>.</p>
<p>“They refuse to tell us why they think it&#8217;s a security, and instead subpoena a bunch of records from us (we comply), demand testimony from our employees (we comply), and then tell us they will be suing us if we proceed to launch, with zero explanation as to why,” he <a href="https://twitter.com/brian_armstrong/status/1435439621190471683">added</a>.</p>
<p>Coinbase’s Chief Legal Officer Paul Grewal also wrote about the events on the <a href="https://blog.coinbase.com/the-sec-has-told-us-it-wants-to-sue-us-over-lend-we-have-no-idea-why-a3a1b6507009">company’s blog</a>. It appears that the company decided to move forward and pre-announce the new feature despite the SEC saying that Coinbase’s Lend program is a security.</p>
<p>“The SEC told us they consider Lend to involve a security, but wouldn’t say why or how they’d reached that conclusion. Rather than get discouraged, we chose to continue taking things slowly. In June, we announced our Lend program publicly and opened a waitlist but did not set a public launch date,” Grewal <a href="https://blog.coinbase.com/the-sec-has-told-us-it-wants-to-sue-us-over-lend-we-have-no-idea-why-a3a1b6507009">wrote</a>.</p>
<p>Here’s a pro tip for entrepreneurs reading this post: If the SEC tells you that you can’t launch something, don’t put up a waitlist with the words &#8220;coming soon.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>To no one’s surprise, Coinbase says that the SEC decided to open a formal investigation after that. <em>One</em> employee also had to spend a day with the SEC to answer questions.</p>
<p>“They asked for documents and written responses, and we willingly provided them. They also asked for us to provide a corporate witness to give sworn testimony about the program. As a result, one of our employees spent a full day in August providing complete and transparent testimony about Lend,” Grewal wrote.</p>
<p>As a result, Coinbase is now mad and has chosen to launch a PR campaign against the SEC. Brian Armstrong’s main argument is that other companies have been offering lending pools already, so there’s no reason why some companies can offer such a product and not Coinbase.</p>
<p>“Meanwhile, plenty of other crypto companies continue to offer a lend feature, but Coinbase is somehow not allowed to,” he <a href="https://twitter.com/brian_armstrong/status/1435440007787921413">tweeted</a>.</p>
<p>This is a risky strategy as Coinbase could end up alienating the crypto ecosystem at large. There could be increased scrutiny on DeFi and industrywide enforcement of stricter rules, as Sar Haribhakti <a href="https://twitter.com/sarthakgh/status/1435629740392652802">pointed out</a>.</p>
<p>“Ostensibly the SEC&#8217;s goal is to protect investors and create fair markets. So who are they protecting here and where is the harm? People seem pretty happy to be earning yield on these various products, across lots of other crypto companies,” Brian Armstrong <a href="https://twitter.com/brian_armstrong/status/1435440225560371200">said</a>.</p>
<p>If you read the fine print, Coinbase doesn’t protect investors with its Lend program. Here’s what it says <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/lend">at the bottom of the Coinbase Lend page</a>: “Lend is not a high-yield USD savings account, and Coinbase is not a bank. Your loaned crypto is not protected by FDIC or SIPC insurance.”</p>
<p>That’s not very reassuring for investors. At some point, Coinbase and the SEC will have to sit at the same table to discuss crypto lending products because a tweetstorm won&#8217;t solve the issue.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/sec-wants-to-regulate-coinbases-crypto-yield-product-coinbase-disagrees/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199554</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter wants you to tweet to interest-based communities, not just followers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/twitter-communities/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/twitter-communities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 17:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199450</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter is a useful place for following breaking news and keeping up with what the people you&#8217;re already interested in are doing, but its relative dearth of discovery features and a lack of organized community spaces make it pretty hard to connect with anyone you aren&#8217;t actively seeking out. The company is thinking about changing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter is a useful place for following breaking news and keeping up with what the people you&#8217;re already interested in are doing, but its relative dearth of discovery features and a lack of organized community spaces make it pretty hard to connect with anyone you aren&#8217;t actively seeking out.</p>
<p>The company is thinking about changing that. Twitter is on a tear with new features lately and its latest experiment, called Communities, is designed to make it easier to connect around shared interests. Users will be able to join these new social hubs and tweet directly to other people with shared interests rather than their regular group of followers. Those tweets will still be public, but replies will be limited to other community members.</p>
<p>Communities will be user generated, though Twitter says that will be &#8220;limited,&#8221; for now, so most people will have to wait a few months before starting their own groups. The earliest Communities will center around popular and generally benign topics on Twitter including &#8220;dogs, weather, sneakers, skincare, and astrology.&#8221; Twitter&#8217;s example images also include cryptocurrency, plants and Black women photographers.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2199470" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/twitter-communities.gif?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" /></p>
<p>The test begins Wednesday and will show up in a dedicated spot at the bottom of the iOS app or in the side menu on Twitter.com. Twitter says that Android users will be able to read Community tweets too, though &#8220;more functionality&#8221; is on the way soon — presumably a dedicated app tab and the ability to join and participate in the new groups.</p>
<p>Communities will be created and maintained by designated moderators, who will have the ability to invite other users to the group via DM and remove content posted within the group. Initially invites will be the only way into a Community, but it sounds like Twitter has some grand plans for discovery features that make it easier for people to find places they might want to hang out.</p>
<p>&#8220;Some conversations aren’t for everyone, just the people who want to talk about the thing you want to talk about,&#8221; Twitter Staff Product Manager David Regan wrote in a blog post announcing the feature. &#8221; … We want to continue to support public conversation and help people find Communities that match their interests, while also creating a more intimate space for conversation.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2199474" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/twitter-communities-2.gif?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" /></p>
<p>With any user-driven community space on social media — particularly one where algorithmic discovery factors in — moderation is the big concern. Twitter says that anyone will be able to read, report and quote content posted in a Community, so you don&#8217;t have to be a member of a community to flag harmful content like you would in a private Facebook group. Twitter says that it is working on &#8220;new reporting flows, and bespoke enforcement actions&#8221; to proactively identify problem Communities.</p>
<p>The introduction of Communities pairs well with Twitter&#8217;s recent efforts to court creator communities. The company rolled out <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/twitter-super-follows-monetization/">Super Follows</a>, its paid subscription tool, earlier this month and also recently invited some users to sell tickets for audio rooms with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/twitter-starts-to-roll-out-paid-ticketed-spaces-on-ios/">Ticketed Spaces</a>. It&#8217;s also testing one-time payments with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/twitter-tip-jar-lets-you-pay-people-for-good-tweetin/">a feature called Tip Jar</a> that&#8217;s currently only available for a subset of accounts.</p>
<p>Communities are a pretty big departure for Twitter, which is obviously in the throes of reimagining the platform as a more dynamic place for community building. By carving out substantial space for subcommunities on Twitter, the company seems to be inching in the direction of a platform like Discord or Reddit, where everything revolves around self-moderating interest-based communities. Those platforms grapple with their own moderation headaches, but specific, interest-driven communities invite users to go deep in a way that makes interactions on Twitter look shallow by comparison.</p>
<p>The introduction of Communities is an interesting direction for a prominent social network that&#8217;s remained largely unchanged for more than a decade at this point. If the test sticks, Communities could build connective tissue between users and make the social network generally a more dynamic place to hang out — but that&#8217;s only possible if Twitter can strike the right balance between encouraging its newly imagined subcommunities to grow and keeping them safe.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Gunb7Vk6uf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/twitter-tests-a-safety-feature-on-web-to-remove-followers-without-blocking-them/">Twitter tests a safety feature on web to remove followers without blocking them</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter tests a safety feature on web to remove followers without blocking them&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/twitter-tests-a-safety-feature-on-web-to-remove-followers-without-blocking-them/embed/#?secret=Gunb7Vk6uf" data-secret="Gunb7Vk6uf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WLPFgrX1Y9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/twitter-full-width-image-tweets-test/">Twitter is testing big ol&#8217; full-width photos and videos</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter is testing big ol&#8217; full-width photos and videos&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/twitter-full-width-image-tweets-test/embed/#?secret=WLPFgrX1Y9" data-secret="WLPFgrX1Y9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/twitter-communities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199450</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Headout raises $12M, plans to hire 150+ people as domestic travel rebounds</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/headout-raises-12m-plans-to-hire-150-people-as-domestic-travel-rebounds/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/headout-raises-12m-plans-to-hire-150-people-as-domestic-travel-rebounds/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 17:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domestic travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[headout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199228</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The travel industry was one of the hardest hit by the pandemic, and startup Headout was no exception. A marketplace that let tourists make same-day bookings for tours, events and activities, the app expanded around the world after launching in 2015. Then COVID-19 hit. But business is growing again thanks to rebounds in domestic travel and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p3">The travel industry was <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/05/06/coronavirus-pandemics-impact-on-travel-tourism-in-5-charts.html">one of the hardest hit by the pandemic</a>, and startup <a href="https://www.headout.com/">Headout</a> was no exception. A marketplace that let tourists make same-day bookings for tours, events and activities, the app expanded around the world after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/04/24/headout-raises-1-8-million-for-its-travel-app-that-puts-a-concierge-in-your-pocket/">launching in 2015. </a>Then COVID-19 hit.</p>
<p class="p3">But business is growing again thanks to rebounds in domestic travel and Headout claims it has grown 800% since January 2021. The company announced today it has raised $12 million led by Glade Brook Capital, which has also invested in marketplaces like Airbnb, Meituan, Uber and Instacart. The round included participation from returning investors Version One Ventures, Nexus Venture Partners, FJ Labs, 500 Startups, Haystack and Ludlow Ventures, and new investors Espresso Capital and Practical VC.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">Headout says it reached profitable EBITDA (earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization) in July. The new funding will be used to expand into 300 cities, product development and its product, business, marketing and operations teams. Headout plans to hire more than 150 employees around the world and is also looking for opportunities to acqui-hire travel and entertainment startups.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">This represents a massive turnaround from the beginning of the pandemic. In an email, co-founder and chief executive officer Varun Khona told TechCrunch, “the pandemic was devastating as you’d imagine. Our business went from doing $250 million+ to negligible scale in a matter of weeks.”<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SelFNwUHX9"><p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/29/travel-activities-platform-kkday-raises-75-million-series-c-as-it-focuses-on-staycations/">Travel activities platform KKday raises $75 million Series C as it focuses on &#8216;staycations&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Travel activities platform KKday raises $75 million Series C as it focuses on &#8216;staycations&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/29/travel-activities-platform-kkday-raises-75-million-series-c-as-it-focuses-on-staycations/embed/#?secret=SelFNwUHX9" data-secret="SelFNwUHX9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p class="p3">But as travel gradually resumes, Headout identified “two massive tailwinds.” The first is an unprecedented demand for domestic travel. The second are travel experience providers who are digitizing for the first time. The company began focusing on domestic tourism in the last quarter of 2020. It’s seeing the highest demand in places with relatively high vaccination rates, like the United States, the United Kingdom, the European Union and the United Arab Emirates.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">“To win this space, we prioritized onboarding new experiences that are more diverse, local and niche to attract domestic travelers. We standardized these mom-and-pop experience providers, upgraded their services and brought them online,” said Khona. “In conjunction, we worked hard on making Headout available in local languages — not just with machine translation but by actually ensuring we create content that is compelling and inspiring.” For example, 85% of bookings in Spain are sold in Spanish.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p class="p3">When asked how Headout differentiates from other on-demand booking marketplaces, Khona said in 2018 it evolved from a traditional listings oriented marketplace, like <a href="http://Booking.com"><span class="s1">Booking.com</span></a>, to a “more managed marketplace” by standardizing, upgrading and branding experiences to ensure consistent quality. This increased conversion rates, which in turn “helped us provide more sales to our partners and hence command a higher take rate,” leading to profitable unit economics.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0fXR1Auuh5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/travelperk-raises-160m-in-equity-and-debt-after-a-year-of-derailed-business-trips/">TravelPerk raises $160M in equity and debt after a year of derailed business trips</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TravelPerk raises $160M in equity and debt after a year of derailed business trips&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/travelperk-raises-160m-in-equity-and-debt-after-a-year-of-derailed-business-trips/embed/#?secret=0fXR1Auuh5" data-secret="0fXR1Auuh5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BRoClpvxuk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/17/hopper-raises-170m-on-3-5b-valuation-as-travel-surges-and-its-fintech-tools-help-offset-variant-concerns/">Hopper raises $175M at $3.5B+ valuation as travel surges and its fintech tools help offset variant concerns</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hopper raises $175M at $3.5B+ valuation as travel surges and its fintech tools help offset variant concerns&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/17/hopper-raises-170m-on-3-5b-valuation-as-travel-surges-and-its-fintech-tools-help-offset-variant-concerns/embed/#?secret=BRoClpvxuk" data-secret="BRoClpvxuk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/headout-raises-12m-plans-to-hire-150-people-as-domestic-travel-rebounds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199228</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Peloton’s CEO and chief content officer are coming to Disrupt</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/pelotons-ceo-and-chief-content-officer-are-coming-to-disrupt/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/pelotons-ceo-and-chief-content-officer-are-coming-to-disrupt/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 16:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[connected fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peloton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2197137</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s been a wildly unprecedented year and a half by any metric. The pandemic has utterly transformed many industries and made or broken others. In the world of technology, however, few categories were as well positioned to embrace a changed world than connected fitness. The space was well on its way prior to the arrival [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It’s been a wildly unprecedented year and a half by any metric. The pandemic has utterly transformed many industries and made or broken others. In the world of technology, however, few categories were as well positioned to embrace a changed world than connected fitness.</p>
<p>The space was well on its way prior to the arrival of COVID-19, of course, and Peloton was largely seen as the tip of that spear. Founded in 2012, the company’s connected stationary bicycles have redefined the landscape for home workouts, through instructor-led live courses.</p>
<p>Demand for Peloton’s growing selection of fitness equipment saw a sharp spike as gyms all over the world shut down for indefinite periods, leaving many stuck at home to reimagine their workout experience.</p>
<p>But the period arrived with its share of challenges for Peloton’s executives. Increased demand saw the company battling supply chain issues, while in May, its treadmills were met with a pair of recalls over injury concerns.</p>
<p>On <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021?display=true&amp;promo=pelotonpost">September 21-23 at Disrupt</a>, Peloton CEO John Foley and Chief Content Office Jennifer Cotter will join us to discuss the company’s rise and successes and struggles amid the pandemic.</p>
<p>Foley is the former CEO of Evite.com and Pronto.com, and former president of BarnesandNoble.com. He co-founded Peloton in June 2012 and has served as CEO since its inception. Cotter joined the company in 2019 to oversee Peloton’s streaming content. Her background in television programming includes stints at the Home Shopping Network and Oxygen Media.</p>
<p>Foley and Cotter join a growing list of great guests, including Canva CEO Melanie Perkins, investor Chamath Palihapitiya, Calendly CEO Tope Awotona and Slack CEO Stewart Butterfield. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021?display=true&amp;promo=pelotonpost">Get your ticket </a>for less than $100 for a limited time!</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			width="99%"
			height="1300"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/pelotons-ceo-and-chief-content-officer-are-coming-to-disrupt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2197137</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
