<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 15:00:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>In a YC “power” play, Gridware girds $5.3M to save humanity from weather</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/gridware-seed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/gridware-seed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 15:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disaster response]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fifty years]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gridware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[power grid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seth Bannon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[True Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156413</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You might have thought that with more than 300 companies joining this year’s winter batch of Y Combinator, the investor interest might have thinned. Well, it’s 2021 and investors are hopping around like crazy to invest in ideas that push the boundaries in fields far flung from enterprise SaaS. Case in point today: Gridware. It’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">You might have thought that with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/our-favorite-companies-from-y-combinators-w21-demo-day-part-1/">more than 300 companies joining this year’s winter batch of Y Combinator</a>, the investor interest might have thinned. Well, it’s 2021 and investors are hopping around like crazy to invest in ideas that push the boundaries in fields far flung from enterprise SaaS.</p>
<p>Case in point today: <a href="https://www.gridware.io">Gridware</a>. It’s a startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/gridware-is-building-early-detection-sensors-for-power-grid-failures-and-wildfires/">I profiled earlier this year when it had just started up in its YC batch</a>. As I wrote about how it wants to save our power grids from the ravages of climate change:</p>
<blockquote><p>Its approach is to use a small, sensor-laden box that can be installed to a power pole with just four screws. Gridware’s package contains microphones and other sensors to sense the ambient environment around a power pole, and it uses on-board AI/ML processing to listen for anomalies and report them to the relevant managers as appropriate.</p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Hardware, IoT, infrastructure, utilities and government are five keywords you probably most would have wanted to avoid when pitching investors even a few years ago. But with power disappearing in states like California and Texas for stretches of time, investors have perhaps finally realized there is an opportunity to save the planet and make a bit of money here.</p>
<p>Gridware today announced that it has raised $5.3 million in a seed round led by Priscilla Tyler of True Ventures and Seth Bannon and Shu Yang of Fifty Years. CEO and co-founder Tim Barat said fundraising was quite fierce. “We had 130 investors reach out to us, and I wasn’t even able to get back to some of them yet … [I’m] still going back through the emails,” he said. “Even before Demo Day, we had raised a significant portion of our round.”</p>
<p>For him and the Gridware team, they were looking for investors who were mission-driven and really understood the timeline it would take to build the company. “You see a lot of investors say they are mission-driven … but when it comes time to put their money where their mouth is, it often goes to consumer technology where it is safer,” he said. Tyler at True leads climate investing for the firm, and True has made a variety of bets in the space. Fifty Years focuses on startups tackling the <a href="https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/">UN’s list of 17 Sustainable Development Goals</a>.</p>
<p>You can <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/gridware-is-building-early-detection-sensors-for-power-grid-failures-and-wildfires/">read more about the company’s product and market in my profile from three months ago</a>, but with the new funding, Gridware wants to double down on building a very intentional team capable of tackling this tough market. “Dealing with this multi-stakeholder business model is very challenging, so bringing on people with the experience, knowledge and wits to deal with this kind of environment is key,” Barat said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9UcKSNXt3J"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/gridware-is-building-early-detection-sensors-for-power-grid-failures-and-wildfires/">Gridware is building early-detection sensors for power grid failures and wildfires</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gridware is building early-detection sensors for power grid failures and wildfires&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/gridware-is-building-early-detection-sensors-for-power-grid-failures-and-wildfires/embed/#?secret=9UcKSNXt3J" data-secret="9UcKSNXt3J" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As I explored recently, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/01/the-most-disastrous-sales-cycle-in-the-world/">the disaster response space is probably one of the toughest markets in the world to sell into</a>. Barat acknowledged the intrinsic difficulty, but sees huge potential in the long run. “One of the things that I have observed with the companies being successful — they really spend the time to meet as many stakeholders as possible,” he said. “With consumer, you can stand in front of a shopping mall and talk to 100 customers in a day [but] in govtech, getting 100 meetings even within a year is a huge accomplishment.”</p>
<p>The company will be re-opening its Bay Area office in Walnut Creek next week on June 1.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FSnQ4bA69Y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/01/the-most-disastrous-sales-cycle-in-the-world/">The most disastrous sales cycle in the world</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The most disastrous sales cycle in the world&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/01/the-most-disastrous-sales-cycle-in-the-world/embed/#?secret=FSnQ4bA69Y" data-secret="FSnQ4bA69Y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/gridware-seed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156413</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>US towns are buying Chinese surveillance tech tied to Uighur abuses</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/united-states-towns-hikvision-dahua-surveillance/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/united-states-towns-hikvision-dahua-surveillance/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 15:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dahua]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hikvision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surveillance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. government]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156080</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This story was reported in partnership with video surveillance news site IPVM. At least a hundred U.S. counties, towns, and cities have bought China-made surveillance systems that the U.S. government has linked to human rights abuses, according to contract data seen by TechCrunch. Some municipalities have spent tens of thousands of dollars or more to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="contributor-byline__bio">This story was reported in partnership with video surveillance news site <a href="https://ipvm.com/reports/hikua-us-map">IPVM.</a></div>
</div>
<p id="speakable-summary">At least a hundred U.S. counties, towns, and cities have bought China-made surveillance systems that the U.S. government has linked to human rights abuses, according to contract data seen by TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Some municipalities have spent tens of thousands of dollars or more to buy surveillance equipment made by two Chinese technology companies, Hikvision and Dahua, after the companies <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/07/eight-chinese-tech-firms-placed-on-u-s-entity-list-for-their-role-in-human-rights-violations-against-muslim-minority-groups/">were added</a> to the U.S. government&#8217;s economic backlist in 2019 after the companies were linked to China&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/02/china-surveillance-app/">ongoing efforts to suppress ethnic minorities</a> in Xinjiang, where most Uighur Muslims live. Congress <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/13/new-defense-bill-bans-the-u-s-government-from-using-huawei-and-zte-tech/">also banned</a> U.S. federal agencies from buying new Hikvision and Dahua technology or renewing contracts over fears that it could help the Chinese government to conduct espionage.</p>
<p>But those federal actions broadly do not apply at the state and city level, allowing local governments to buy these China-made surveillance systems — including video cameras and thermal imaging scanners — largely uninhibited, so long as federal funds are not used to buy the equipment.</p>
<p>Details of the contracts were provided by <a href="https://govspend.com/">GovSpend</a>, which tracks federal and state government spending, to TechCrunch via <a href="https://ipvm.com/reports/hikua-us-map">IPVM</a>, a leading news publication on video surveillance, which has followed the Hikvision and Dahua bans closely.</p>
<p>The biggest spender, according to the data and as <a href="https://ipvm.com/reports/hik-faye">previously reported by IPVM</a>, showed that the Board of Education in Fayette County, Georgia spent $490,000 in August 2020 on dozens of Hikvision thermal cameras, used for temperature checks at its public schools.</p>
<p>A statement provided by Fayette County Public Schools spokesperson Melinda Berry-Dreisbach said the cameras were purchased from its longtime security vendor, authorized dealer for Hikvision. The statement did not address whether the Board of Education was aware of Hikvision&#8217;s links to human rights abuses. Berry-Dreisbach did not respond to our follow-up questions.</p>
<p>IPVM research <a href="https://www.spiedigitallibrary.org/journals/journal-of-biomedical-optics/volume-26/issue-04/043009/Globally-deployed-COVID-19-fever-screening-devices-using-infrared-thermographs/10.1117/1.JBO.26.4.043009.full?SSO=1&amp;tab=ArticleLinkFigureTable">found</a> many thermal scanners, including Hikvision and Dahua models, produced inaccurate readings, prompting the U.S. Food and Drug Administration to issue a public health alert warning that misreported readings <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/03/05/fever-scanner-flaws-covid/">could present</a> &#8220;potentially serious public health risks.&#8221;</p>
<p>Nash County in North Carolina, which has a population of 95,000 residents, spent more than $45,000 between September and December 2020 to buy Dahua thermal cameras. County Manager Zee Lamb forwarded emails that confirmed the purchases and that the gear was deployed at the county&#8217;s public schools, but did not comment.</p>
<p>The data also shows that the Parish of Jefferson in Louisiana, which includes part of the city of New Orleans, spent $35,000 on Hikvision surveillance cameras and video storage between October 2019 and September 2020. A parish spokesperson did not comment.</p>
<p>Only one municipality we contacted addressed the links between the technology they bought and human rights abuses. Kern County in California spent more than $15,000 on Hikvision surveillance cameras and video recording equipment in June 2020 for its probation department offices. The contract data showed a local vendor, Tel Tec Security, supplied the Hikvision technology to the county.</p>
<p>Ryan Alsop, chief administrative officer for Kern County, said he was &#8220;not familiar at all with the issues you&#8217;re referencing with regard to Hikvision,&#8221; when asked about Hikvision&#8217;s links to human rights abuses.</p>
<p>&#8220;Again, we didn&#8217;t contract with Hikvision, we contracted with Tel Tec Security,&#8221; said Alsop.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2156104" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2156104" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2156104 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/kern-county-calif.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="342" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/kern-county-calif.jpg 1918w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/kern-county-calif.jpg?resize=150,50 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/kern-county-calif.jpg?resize=300,100 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/kern-county-calif.jpg?resize=768,257 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/kern-county-calif.jpg?resize=680,227 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/kern-county-calif.jpg?resize=1536,513 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/kern-county-calif.jpg?resize=50,17 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2156104" class="wp-caption-text">Kern County spent more than $15,000 on Hikvision equipment at its county probation service offices. (Data: <a href="https://govspend.com/">GovSpend</a>/supplied)</p></div></p>
<p>A spokesperson for the City of Hollywood in Florida, which spent close to $30,000 on Hikvision thermal cameras, said the Chinese technology maker &#8220;was the only major manufacturer with a viable solution that was ready for delivery; would serve the defined project scope; and was within the project budget.&#8221; The cameras were used to take employees&#8217; body temperatures to curb the spread of COVID-19. The spokesperson did not address the links to human rights abuses but noted that the federal ban did not apply to the city.</p>
<p>Maya Wang, a senior researcher at Human Rights Watch, said a lack of privacy regulations at the local level contributed to municipalities buying this technology.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of the problems is that these kinds of cameras, regardless of the country of origin and regardless of whether or not they&#8217;re even linked to human rights abuses, have been introduced to various parts of the country — especially at state and city levels — without any kind of regulation to ensure that they comply with privacy standards,&#8221; said Wang in a call. &#8220;There is, again, no kind of regulatory framework to vet the companies based on their track record, whether or not they have abused human rights in their practices, such that we can evaluate or choose better companies, and encourage the ones with better privacy protections to win, essentially.&#8221;</p>
<p>Chief among the U.S. government&#8217;s allegations are that Beijing has relied heavily on Hikvision, Dahua, and others to supply the surveillance technology it uses to monitor the Uighur population as part of the government&#8217;s ongoing efforts to suppress the ethnic group, which it has repeatedly denied.</p>
<p>United Nations watchdogs say Beijing has detained more than a million Uighurs in internment camps in recent years as part of these efforts, which led to the U.S. blacklisting of the two surveillance technology makers.</p>
<p>In adding the companies to the government&#8217;s economic blacklist, the Commerce Department said Hikvision and Dahua &#8220;have been implicated in human rights violations and abuses in the implementation of China’s campaign of repression, mass arbitrary detention, and high-technology surveillance against Uighurs, Kazakhs, and other members of Muslim minority groups.&#8221; The Biden administration <a href="https://www.state.gov/reports/2020-country-reports-on-human-rights-practices/china/">called</a> the human rights abuses a &#8220;genocide.&#8221;</p>
<p>IPVM has also reported extensively on how the companies&#8217; surveillance technology has been used to suppress the Uighurs. Dahua was found to have <a href="https://ipvm.com/reports/dahua-uyghur-warning">race detection in its code</a> for providing &#8220;real-time Uighur warnings&#8221; to police.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the Thomson Reuters Foundation <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-britain-tech-china/exclusive-half-london-councils-found-using-chinese-surveillance-tech-linked-to-uighur-abuses-idUSKBN2AI0QJ">found half of London&#8217;s councils</a> and the largest 20 U.K. cities were using the technology linked to Uighur abuses. The Guardian also <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/sep/21/chinese-spy-tech-firm-linked-uighur-abuses-increases-uk-presence">found</a> that Hikvision surveillance technology was used in U.K. schools.</p>
<p>When reached, Dahua pointed to <a href="https://us.dahuasecurity.com/?page_id=60083">a blog post</a> with a statement, and claimed that &#8220;contrary to some reporting in the media, our company has never developed any technology or solution that seeks to target a specific ethnic group.&#8221; The statement added: &#8220;Claims to the contrary are simply false and we are aware of no evidence that has ever been put forward to support such claims.&#8221;</p>
<p>Hikvision did not respond to a request for comment.</p>
<hr />
<p><em>Send tips securely over Signal and WhatsApp to +1 646-755-8849. You can also send files or documents using our SecureDrop. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/techcrunch-launches-securedrop/">Learn more</a>. </em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3ClJwryDE1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/03/china-smart-city-exposed/">Security lapse exposed a Chinese smart city surveillance system</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Security lapse exposed a Chinese smart city surveillance system&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/03/china-smart-city-exposed/embed/#?secret=3ClJwryDE1" data-secret="3ClJwryDE1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/united-states-towns-hikvision-dahua-surveillance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156080</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sensor Tower makes its first acquisition with deal for market intelligence company, Pathmatics</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/sensor-tower-makes-its-first-acquisition-with-deal-for-market-intelligence-company-pathmatics/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/sensor-tower-makes-its-first-acquisition-with-deal-for-market-intelligence-company-pathmatics/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 15:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app stores]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[competitive intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pathmatics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[riverwood capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensor tower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156382</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mobile app market intelligence firm Sensor Tower has made its first acquisition. The company this morning announced it&#8217;s acquiring Pathmatics, a market intelligence company which will now combine its paid digital and social media platform with Sensor Tower&#8217;s business. Deal terms were not detailed but include an undisclosed growth investment from Riverwood Capital into Pathmatics. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Mobile app market intelligence firm Sensor Tower has made its first acquisition. The company this morning announced it&#8217;s acquiring Pathmatics, a market intelligence company which will now combine its paid digital and social media platform with Sensor Tower&#8217;s business. Deal terms were not detailed but include an undisclosed growth investment from Riverwood Capital into Pathmatics.</p>
<p>The acquisition will allow the companies to offer an expanded set of digital and mobile advertising insights to their respective customers, including new social insights for TikTok, YouTube mobile, and Snap this year, powered by Sensor Tower.</p>
<p>They companies will also introduce digital TV (over-the-top) insights, expanded coverage for mobile apps and ad insights, and will extend Pathmatics&#8217; social and digital coverage globally.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The deal follows Sensor Tower&#8217;s first <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/04/sensor-tower-raises-45m-as-demand-for-app-data-grows/">significant fundraising last year</a>, with $45 million also from Riverwood Capital. Though Sensor Tower had been profitable since its launch, now serving more than 350 enterprise-level customers for its app and ad intelligence products, it chose to raise the additional capital in order to further grow its business, with investments in hiring, marketing, infrastructure and other expansions.</p>
<p>With Pathmatics, it&#8217;s buying a company that&#8217;s also been on its way up. The company had seen over 100% year-over-year growth for its own market intelligence business since launching in 2011. It now has over 250 brands, media and advertising agencies as customers, as well as over 7,000 users of its platform, representing over 200% software-as-a-service growth since 2018.</p>
<p>The two businesses are teaming up at a time when digital advertising is also on the rise, in part due to the shifts in the market attributed to the pandemic. As more businesses began operating online last year, advertisers increased their digital ad spending by 12.7% to $368 billion, per eMarketer. And digital advertising will account for 58% of media spending in 2021.</p>
<p>We understand Sensor Tower acquired both the IP and its over 60-person team from Pathmatics as a result of the acquisition. The entire team will join Sensor Tower with the executive suite now being a combination of both of the company&#8217;s leaders. Sensor Tower co-founder Alexey Malafeev will remain as CEO while Gabe Gottlieb, CEO and co-founder of Pathmatics, will become Chief Strategy Officer.</p>
<p>Historically, Pathmatics had provided brands and agencies with all creative used by advertisers, spend and impression, and path to publisher and viewer, to help them reduce waste from their budgets, improve their own marketing, and predict their competitors&#8217; next move.</p>
<p>Going forward, both sets of customers will be able to opt into the other company&#8217;s solutions, including mobile, social media, and digital insights. Longer-term, the two companies will work together to bring more products to the market for their over 600 combined customers across 50 countries. Among these is a plan to add Pathmatics&#8217; Facebook, Instagram, Twitter and other digital ad intelligence capture into Sensor Tower, as well as an effort to augment Sensor Tower&#8217;s dataset with ad insights beyond app installs.</p>
<p>These features will make the product a better fit for larger brands looking into all aspects of the competitors&#8217; campaigns, ranging from how they&#8217;re advertising for app installs to how they&#8217;re building brand awareness.</p>
<p>The deal officially closed on May 17, 2021, Sensor Tower says.</p>
<p>Santa Monica-based Pathmatics had raised $7.7 million to date from Upfront Ventures, BDMI and Baroda Ventures.</p>
<p>&#8220;As the global economy increasingly shifts to digital, it&#8217;s imperative that companies can understand and<br />
navigate the entire digital landscape &#8212; from mobile to web and desktop &#8212; using accurate and insightful data,&#8221; noted Ramesh Venugopal, Principal at Riverwood Capital, in a statement about the acquisition. &#8220;The combination of Sensor Tower and Pathmatics presents a unique and valuable offering to customers allowing them to take advantage of a broad range of datasets with increased focus on consumer privacy and deep digital insights that leaders in every industry will need,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/sensor-tower-makes-its-first-acquisition-with-deal-for-market-intelligence-company-pathmatics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156382</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beacons raises $6 million for its link-in-bio homepage builder that lets creators monetize</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/beacons-seed-round-creator-profiles/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/beacons-seed-round-creator-profiles/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atelier Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beacons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Linktree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156243</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mobile landing page builder Beacons has raised $6 million seed round to expand its vision for empowering creators to make money beyond the cramped confines of their social media profiles. The company, co-founded by Neal Jean, Jesse Zhang, Greg Luppescu and David Zeng, provides anyone who uses social media a single, mobile-optimized link hub to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Mobile landing page builder <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/beacons-debuts-a-link-in-bio-mobile-website-builder-that-helps-creators-make-money-not-just-list-links/">Beacons</a> has raised $6 million seed round to expand its vision for empowering creators to make money beyond the cramped confines of their social media profiles. The company, co-founded by Neal Jean, Jesse Zhang, Greg Luppescu and David Zeng, provides anyone who uses social media a single, mobile-optimized link hub to display to their followers.</p>
<p>Like<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/link-in-bio-company-linktree-raises-45m-series-b-for-its-social-commerce-features/"> competitor Linktree</a>, <a href="https://beacons.ai/">Beacons</a> gives people a way to link out to other sites directly from their TikTok, Instagram, or Twitter profile, including pointing followers toward potential income streams like donations and affiliate links. <span style="font-weight: 400;">Other companies in the “link in bio” space include </span><a href="https://dash.shorby.com/smartpage?&amp;lp"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shorby</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://milkshake.app/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Milkshake</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://tap.bio/@tap.bio"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tap.bio</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://linkinprofile.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Link in Profile</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://bio.fm/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">bio.fm</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://campsite.bio/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Campsite</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p>Beacons launched in private beta in September 2020 after emerging out of Y Combinator’s Summer 2019 cohort. Andreessen Horowitz will lead the seed round and is joined by <a href="https://www.atelierventures.co/team">Atelier Ventures</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/15/the-chainsmokers-just-closed-their-debut-venture-fund-mantis-with-35-million/">The Chainsmokers’ Mantis Fund</a>, Night Media Ventures and LOUDgg, the Brazilian esports group.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The $6 million seed round will build on $600,000 that Beacons raised in an angel round, allowing the team to hire more engineers and designers to grow its small four-person team of first-time founders.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I think where we&#8217;re really different than Linktree is we let creators customize and personalize their pages all for free and we offer a lot more of those options on our free plan,” Beacons co-founder and CEO Neal Jean told TechCrunch. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“&#8230;Creators care a lot about how their website looks so that&#8217;s been a good way for us to give creators the features that they want and help us grow our share in the market too.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To keep creators locked into their own platforms and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/twitter-tip-jar-lets-you-pay-people-for-good-tweetin/">forthcoming monetization schemes</a>, social media companies don’t offer much support for embedded links, particularly on individual pieces of content. Many also restrict users to one URL in their profiles, putting pressure on creators to maximize the utility of a single link. Beacons reasonably argues that the restrictive design of most social platforms stunts the ability of creators to easily and flexibly make money from their content.</span></p>
<p>“In the beginning we’re basically building all these different kinds of features for creators to use but I think in the long run the way to make that more scalable is to turn into more of a platform or an ecosystem that lots of people can build on,” Jean said.</p>
<p>“Today, I think we’re probably more like a Wix or a Squarespace for content creators, but in the future I think we want to be a little bit more like Shopify for creators.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FdLMyLHGZl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/twitter-tip-jar-lets-you-pay-people-for-good-tweetin/">Twitter Tip Jar lets you pay people for good tweetin&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter Tip Jar lets you pay people for good tweetin&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/twitter-tip-jar-lets-you-pay-people-for-good-tweetin/embed/#?secret=FdLMyLHGZl" data-secret="FdLMyLHGZl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Building on Beacons</h3>
<p>Beacons lets users choose between free and premium tiers. At $10 per month, the “entrepreneur” tier offers a couple of killer features worth considering, including support for custom domains and additional “blocks” — the link, text and image slots that comprise a Beacons page.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2111825" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/beacons.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="478" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/beacons.jpg 1370w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/beacons.jpg?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/beacons.jpg?resize=300,211 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/beacons.jpg?resize=768,540 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/beacons.jpg?resize=680,478 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/beacons.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>Beyond premium pricing, Beacons makes money by taking a cut of sales through its handful of monetization-focused blocks, like a shopping-enabled TikTok feed, a digital storefront for videos and ebooks, and a “requests” block that lets creators sell custom content directly to their followers. Beacons’ free plan charges a 9% fee on transactions, while the premium plan cuts that down to 5%.</p>
<p>Landing sites built through Beacons are deeply customizable, hearkening back to the MySpace era of media-rich, curated homepages. The company recently added what it calls the “community block,” a designated place where creators can highlight collaborators they might team up with often on a collab-obsessed platform like TikTok. The company currently counts Sia, Green Day and Russell Brand among its high profile users.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beacons also supports mobile marketing through email and SMS and analytics to help creators understand their audiences. The company says that its user base has grown by 70% every month since its October launch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today’s content creators and consumers have more sophisticated expectations than existing social platforms allow,” Jean said in the funding announcement. “&#8230;With Beacons, creators can control their destiny by directing online traffic to a custom domain that looks awesome, is shareable and ultimately generates revenue.” </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cqa3tD0Zct"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/beacons-debuts-a-link-in-bio-mobile-website-builder-that-helps-creators-make-money-not-just-list-links/">Beacons debuts a &#8216;link in bio&#8217; mobile website builder that helps creators make money, not just list links</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Beacons debuts a &#8216;link in bio&#8217; mobile website builder that helps creators make money, not just list links&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/beacons-debuts-a-link-in-bio-mobile-website-builder-that-helps-creators-make-money-not-just-list-links/embed/#?secret=cqa3tD0Zct" data-secret="cqa3tD0Zct" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XuJOOmPuO3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/link-in-bio-company-linktree-raises-45m-series-b-for-its-social-commerce-features/">&#8216;Link-in-bio&#8217; company Linktree raises $45M Series B for its social commerce features</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;&#8216;Link-in-bio&#8217; company Linktree raises $45M Series B for its social commerce features&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/link-in-bio-company-linktree-raises-45m-series-b-for-its-social-commerce-features/embed/#?secret=XuJOOmPuO3" data-secret="XuJOOmPuO3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/beacons-seed-round-creator-profiles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156243</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Station: London scooter winners and Ford&#8217;s most important EV</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/the-station-london-scooter-winners-and-fords-most-important-ev/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/the-station-london-scooter-winners-and-fords-most-important-ev/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 14:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EV6]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyundai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scooters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tier Mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toyota]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156391</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Station is a weekly newsletter dedicated to all things transportation. Sign up here — just click The Station — to receive it every weekend in your inbox. Hello and welcome back to The Station, a weekly newsletter dedicated to all the ways people and packages move (today and in the future) from Point A to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>The Station is a weekly newsletter dedicated to all things transportation. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">Sign up here — just click The Station — to receive it every weekend in your inbox</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to The Station, a weekly newsletter dedicated to all the ways people and packages move (today and in the future) from Point A to Point B.</p>
<p>I want to point to two Extra Crunch articles before jumping into the rest of the news and analysis. Yes, Extra Crunch requires a subscription. We&#8217;re ramping up the transportation analysis and features in EC and I hope you find it worthwhile.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>We&#8217;re ramping up our founder Q&amp;A series. The first one was an interview with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/revels-frank-reig-shares-how-he-built-his-business-and-what-hes-planning/"><strong>Revel</strong> founder and CEO Frank Reig</a>. This time, it is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/arrivals-denis-sverdlov-on-the-new-era-of-car-manufacturing/"><strong>Arrival</strong> founder Denis Sverdlov</a>, who founded his first company at 22 selling IT consulting software to enterprise customers. Since then, he has built and exited multiple companies, most notably telecommunications operator Yota Group. He also founded Roborace.</p>
<p>We have two more interviews coming up with <strong>Veo</strong> co-founder and CEO Candice Xie and <strong>Refraction AI</strong> co-founder Matthew Johnson-Roberson.</p>
<p>Finally, we published a piece that examines <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/the-battle-for-voice-recognition-inside-vehicles-is-heating-up/">voice recognition in vehicles</a>, a marketplace that has tech giants like Google and Amazon competing for space with a few up and comers and established suppliers like Cerence.</p>
<p>A friendly reminder that my email inbox is always open — and yes, I do read your messages. Email me at <a href="mailto:kirsten.korosec@techcrunch.com">kirsten.korosec@techcrunch.com</a> to share thoughts, criticisms, offer up opinions or tips. You can also send a direct message to me at Twitter — <a href="https://twitter.com/kirstenkorosec">@kirstenkorosec</a>.</p>
<h2>Micromobbin&#8217;</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1999054 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png" alt="" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Dott</strong>, <strong>Lime</strong> and <strong>TIER</strong> have won the long-awaited, much-coveted bid to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/dott-lime-and-tier-selected-for-london-e-scooter-trial/">operate e-scooter shares in London</a>. The pilot, which will run for up to 12 months, will begin June 7 in some of London&#8217;s boroughs, including Canary Wharf and the City of London. More neighborhoods are expected to join as the year progresses, according to TfL. Lambeth and Southwark are also seeking participation. Between 60 to 150 scooters will be available initially in each borough.</p>
<p>This announcement is significant not only because London is one of the biggest targets for micromobility shares, but also because Transport for London is very keen on collecting data from the scooter companies that will help determine how e-scooters could be integrated into a sustainable transport pandemic recovery plan.</p>
<h3>Can micromobility address the racial wealth gap?</h3>
<p>The Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation released a report entitled <a href="https://documentcloud.adobe.com/link/review?uri=urn:aaid:scds:US:cdef00e5-a376-4223-ad27-4d242abcbee8#pageNum=1">Cementing an Equity Framework for Micro Mobility</a> that talks about next steps for its NYC Better Bike Share Partnership and outlines goals for fostering equity and opportunity for communities of color through public transportation.</p>
<p>&#8220;Creating a truly equitable bikeshare system is about more than just placement of stations and the price of fares. It requires deep partnerships with the community and empowering the voices of those who have been traditionally underserved,&#8221; said Laura Fox, General Manager of Citi Bike. &#8220;We are grateful to the Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation for their leadership and ongoing efforts to create a culture of cycling, particularly by addressing street safety. As this progress report highlights, we have many accomplishments to be proud of and we look forward to continued partnership to build on these successes.&#8221;<br />
Accessible mobility is one of the major drivers of wealth, and I&#8217;m a big proponent of the potential for active forms of mobility, from e-scooters to push bikes and everything in between, to both help cities cut emissions and help residents stay healthy.</p>
<p>From a startup&#8217;s perspective, can you even contribute to this equitable goal and also make money? I&#8217;ll be discussing this in a few weeks at our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/announcing-the-agenda-for-tc-sessions-mobility-2021/">TC Mobility Event on June 9</a> with advocate and consultant Tamika Butler, CEO and co-founder at Remix, Tiffany Chu, and CEO and co-founder of Revel, Frank Reig.</p>
<h3>Spinning tales of SPACs&#8230;</h3>
<p>The aftereffects of Bird going SPAC last week is that now we&#8217;re all wondering which micromobility company is going to go SPAC next. Will it be Lime? TIER? Or maybe Spin? Bloomberg reported<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-20/ford-is-said-to-weigh-exit-of-electric-scooter-unit-spin"> Ford is considering divesting Spin</a>, according to &#8220;people familiar with the matter.&#8221;</p>
<p>Currently, we have a lot of whisperings and speculation and not a lot of facts. Rumors circulating involve Spin spinning off from Ford or merging with a special purpose acquisition company. Spin did not want to comment, and I think that&#8217;s fair given the nebulous shape of this &#8220;news.&#8221;</p>
<h3>While we&#8217;re on the subject of Bird&#8230;</h3>
<p>Bird is working with IT Asset Partners (ITAP) to give its batteries a second life. So, when a scooter reaches the end of its life, it&#8217;s broken down for parts, with batteries shipped over to ITAP. Then ITAP breaks down each battery module to the cellular level to get as many reusable battery bits as possible.</p>
<p>This is not only an eco-friendly way to do business, but it&#8217;s also increasingly necessary in a world that&#8217;s going electric faster than supply can keep up with.</p>
<p>&#8220;The circular economy is where the world is going, and it will help determine how global businesses function over the next 10 years,&#8221; said Robert Mullaney, Director of Business Development at ITAP, in a <a href="https://www.bird.co/blog/how-bird-itap-reducing-battery-waste-through-advanced-recycling/">Bird blog post announcing the partnership</a>. &#8220;As battery technology has improved year over year, their second life potential has increased as well, allowing them to be used in broader and more advanced applications. This includes things like computers and computer chargers.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><em>— Rebecca Bellan</em></p>
<h2>Deal of the week</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1896226 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png" alt="money the station" width="1600" height="400" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=1536,384 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>Is it me or am I seeing more activity in the aviation/eVTOL sector these days? We&#8217;ve had three SPACs — Lillium, Archer and Joby — plus a smattering of other funding news in the past four months.</p>
<p>And now, there&#8217;s one more to add to the list. Electric aviation startup <strong>Beta Technologies</strong> closed a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/beta-technologies-adds-368-million-in-series-a-funding-for-its-electric-aviation-ecosystem/">$368 million Series A funding round</a> with investments from Amazon&#8217;s Climate Pledge Fund. The new capital is the second round of funding announced by the company this year, after the company raised $143 million in private capital in March. Beta&#8217;s valuation is now at $1.4 billion, putting it in a small circle of electric vertical take-off and landing (eVTOL) unicorns.</p>
<p>The funding round was led by Fidelity Management &amp; Research Company, with undisclosed additions from Amazon&#8217;s Climate Pledge Fund, a $2 billion fund established in September 2019 to advance the development of sustainable technologies. The Climate Pledge fund has also made contributions toward electric vehicle manufacturer Rivian, battery recycler Redwood Materials and ZeroAvia, a hydrogen fuel cell aviation company.</p>
<p>Beta is a bit different from other high valuation eVTOL startups. The Vermont-based company isn&#8217;t primarily focused on air taxis. Instead, it&#8217;s been targeting defense applications, cargo delivery and medical logistics, as well as building out its network of rapid-charging systems in the northeast U.S. Its debut aircraft, the ALIA-250c, was built to serve these various solutions by being capable of carrying six people or a pilot and 1,500 pounds.</p>
<p><strong>Other deals that got my attention &#8230;</strong></p>
<p><strong>Mile Auto</strong>, insurance tech startup, raised $10.3 million in a seed funding round that includes investment from Ulu Ventures, Emergent Ventures, Thornton Capital, and Sure Ventures. The company said it will use the funding to expand availability of its insurance offering to half of the U.S. auto insurance market by the end of 2021, as well as hiring, adding new distribution channels, onboarding of white-label partners and expanding its automaker network. Mile Auto has also partnered with Ford Motor to offer auto insurance to owners. Mile Auto launched a similar program with Porsche Financial Services in 2019.</p>
<p><strong>Portside</strong>, an aviation startup that is building a platform for managing the backend of a corporate flight department, charter operation, government fleet and fractional ownership operation, today announced that it has raised a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/portside-raises-17m-for-its-business-aviation-management-platform/">$17 million funding round</a> led by Tiger Global Management, with participation from existing investors I2BF Global Ventures and SOMA Capital.</p>
<p><strong>Twaice</strong>, the German battery analytics software company, raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/twaice-raised-26m-to-scale-its-battery-analytics-software/">$26 million in Series B funding</a> led by Chicago-based Energize Ventures. The company, which primarily works in the mobility and energy storage industries, now has a total financing of $45 million.</p>
<p><strong>Virtuo</strong>, a Paris-based startup that lets people rent a car for a few days, or up to a few months, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/virtuo-raises-96m-for-its-streamlined-take-on-car-rentals/">has raised $96 million</a>. The funding money will be using to invest in its tech and to expand to more markets beyond France, U.K. and Spain.</p>
<p><strong>Waybridge</strong>, a company that has created a supply chain platform for raw materials, raised $30 million in a Series B funding round co-led by Rucker Park Capital and Craft Ventures, with participation from Venrock. The company has developed a digital platform that lets customers track inventory and shipments. Waybridge&#8217;s pitch is that its product can help companies navigate disruptive events like the Suez Canal traffic jam and COVID-19.</p>
<p><strong>WeaveGrid</strong> raises <a href="https://www.weavegrid.com/blog">$15 million Series A round</a> to enable widescale adoption of EVs on the electric grid. Coatue and Breakthrough Energy Ventures will join existing investors to drive software innovation at intersection of utility and automotive sectors.</p>
<p><strong>Wejo</strong>, the British automotive-data startup backed by General Motors, is in talks to go public through a merger with Virtuoso Acquisition Corp., <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-21/gm-backed-wejo-said-to-be-in-spac-merger-talks-with-virtuoso?sref=gni836kR">Bloomberg reported</a>.</p>
<h2>Policy corner</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-2037863 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png" alt="the-station-delivery" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>Welcome back to Policy Corner! A decision from a little-known but very powerful California regulator caught my eye this week. The <strong>California Air Resources Board</strong>, which regulates air quality in the state, adopted new rules on Thursday that will require 90% of ride-share trips to be completed by electric vehicles by 2030.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s important to remember that ride-sharing giants Uber and Lyft have both vowed to go 100% electric fleets by that year, but this is the first time that a state has adopted EV requirements for ride-share companies. In written comments submitted ahead of the hearing, both Uber and Lyft urged the Board to create EV rebates that are specifically targeted at high-mileage drivers and fleets, and to install EV chargers in &#8220;urban and traditionally underserved areas.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;California&#8217;s EV incentive programs and EV infrastructure investments over the past decade have served an exclusive population―wealthy, white, homeowners―that does not reflect Lyft&#8217;s driver population,&#8221; Paul Augustine, Lyft&#8217;s senior manager of sustainability, <a href="https://www.arb.ca.gov/lists/com-attach/7-cleanmilesstandard-VzZTIFQyAiQGcwF1.pdf">said in submitted comments</a>.</p>
<p>Back over in Washington, there was a hearing at the <a href="https://energycommerce.house.gov/committee-activity/hearings/hearing-on-promises-and-perils-the-potential-of-automobile-technologies">House Committee on Energy and Commerce</a> about the ways in which new automotive technologies (like autonomous driving) might enhance vehicle safety and help cut down on the many thousands of automotive deaths that occur on U.S. roads each year.</p>
<p>AV proponents like the Self Driving Coalition point to the many possible safety benefits of AVs. Electrical engineer Ragunathan Rajkumar, who testified at the meeting, urged lawmakers to advance a policy framework to support innovation to ensure America stays competitive against foreign rivals in AV technology.</p>
<p>However, the committee also heard testimony from people who urged a careful and pragmatic approach to AVs. Greg Regan, in testimony representing the AFL-CIO, argued that transportation workers should have a place at the table in conversations about AV deployment. He also said that the government should enact policy to ensure that the AV manufacturing industry yields secure jobs for American workers. Jason Levine, executive director of the Center for Auto Safety, argued that other safety and design upgrades, as well as improved vehicle performance standards, could do much to save lives in the near-term.</p>
<p>&#8220;The idea that tens of thousands of unproven and unregulated AVs deployed quickly and without oversight, or a significant upgrade in highway and road infrastructure, will automatically be safer than what we have now may make for a good talking point in a quarterly earnings report &#8212; but is not good transportation policy,&#8221; he said in his testimony.</p>
<p>The issue of forced arbitration also came up during the hearing. Below is an exchange between Congressman Rush and Jason Levine, who is the executive director of the Center for Auto Safety.</p>
<p><strong>RUSH</strong>: As you know, even pedestrians may lose their right to seek justice in the courts if there is a continued proliferation of forced arbitration clauses. These clauses are often buried in terms of service agreements that waive a consumer&#8217;s right to sue in court, participate in a class action, or appeal the arbitrator&#8217;s decision. Do forced arbitration clauses related to AVs pose a danger to pedestrians? If so, why?</p>
<p><strong>LEVINE</strong>: They pose a real threat. The threat is this, as we discussed earlier, the ability to make sure you&#8217;re holding any manufacturer, AV or otherwise, responsible for something defective, a defective vehicle, is critical to safety, it is a backstop to our entire system. And so, if you are a pedestrian who has entered into an agreement unknowingly, when you downloaded an app to order a pizza maybe, and you get hit by a pizza delivery vehicle, and you said, &#8220;well I&#8217;m going to do everything from a legal standpoint through binding arbitration,&#8221; you have now lost your ability to go to court. That sounds outlandish, but it&#8217;s not actually that far from where we are in terms of binding arbitration removing our ability to hold manufacturers accountable. So that&#8217;s something that we do not want to see in an AV context.</p>
<p>Station readers: what do you think?</p>
<p style="text-align: right;"> <em>— Aria Alamalhodaei</em></p>
<h2>Notable reads and other tidbits</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1926823 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png" alt="" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>Lots to get to this week.</p>
<h3>Autonomous vehicles</h3>
<p><strong>May Mobility</strong> announced it is launching a new autonomous shuttle service in Ann Arbor, Michigan. The free shuttle service called A2GO will be available to the public starting Oct. 11, 2021. May Mobility said it will operate a fleet of five autonomous, shared, on-demand vehicles as part of the A2GO deployment. Four hybrid-electric Lexus RX 450h vehicles, which can carry three passengers, and one Polaris GEM fully electric vehicle that has capacity for one wheelchair passenger will operate in a service area that connects Kerrytown, the University of Michigan campus and the State Street corridor.</p>
<p>Chinese robotaxi startup <strong>Pony.ai</strong> has been given permission by California regulators to pilot its autonomous vehicles <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/21/chinese-startup-pony-ai-can-now-test-driverless-vehicles-in-three-california-cities/">without a human safety driver behind the wheel</a> in three cities. While dozens of companies &#8212; 55 in all &#8212; have active permits to test autonomous vehicles with a safety driver, it&#8217;s far less common to receive permission for driverless vehicles. Pony is the eighth company to be issued a driverless testing permit in the state, a list that includes Chinese companies <strong>AutoX</strong>, <strong>Baidu</strong> and <strong>WeRide</strong> as well as U.S. businesses <strong>Cruise</strong>, <strong>Nuro</strong>, <strong>Waymo</strong> and <strong>Zoox</strong>. Only Nuro has been granted a so-called deployment permit, which allows it to operate commercially.</p>
<h3>Electric vehicles</h3>
<p>It was a big week for EVs, and not just because of the Ford F-150 Lightning reveal. Although that was certainly the biggest EV reveal.</p>
<p><strong>Ars Technica</strong> had a fun and brief look at <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2021/05/a-brief-look-at-electric-vehicles-from-the-dawn-of-the-automobile-age/">electric vehicles in the beginning of the automotive age</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Canoo</strong> gave a few more details of its electric microbus-slash-van, which will be available to buy in 2022 at a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/canoos-electric-microbus-will-start-under-35000-when-it-comes-to-market-next-year/">base price of $34,750</a> before tax incentives or add-ons. The Los Angeles-based company, which debuted on the Nasdaq public exchange earlier this year, now taking preorders in the United States for the &#8220;lifestyle&#8221; vehicle, as well as for its round-top pickup truck and multi-purpose delivery van. While Canoo did not release pricing for the other two vehicles, it said that deliveries for the pickup and production for the delivery van are slated to start as early as 2023. Customers can reserve a model by placing a $100 deposit per vehicle with the company.</p>
<p>The company also disclosed in a regulatory filing that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/canoo-is-being-investigated-by-the-sec/">it is being investigated</a> by the <strong>U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission</strong>, just months after its merger with special purpose acquisition company <strong>Hennessy Capital Acquisition Corp</strong>. The investigation is broad, covering the Hennessy&#8217;s initial public offering and merger with Canoo, the company&#8217;s operations, business model, revenues, revenue strategy, customer agreements, earnings and other related topics, along with the recent departures of certain of the company&#8217;s officers, according to its first quarter earnings report. Canoo learned of the investigation on April 29. Canoo noted in the regulatory filing. The company added that it does not consider the investigation or other lawsuits it is facing to be material to its business.</p>
<p><strong>ElectReon</strong>, an inductive in-road charging technology for commercial and passenger electric vehicles, is joining the &#8220;Arena of the Future&#8221; project in Brescia, Italy where it will integrate its wireless technology to charge two Stellantis vehicles, and an IVECO bus while driving. The project aims to demonstrate contactless charging for a range of EVs as they drive on highways and toll roads as a potential pathway to decarbonizing our transportation systems along motorway transport corridors.</p>
<p><strong>Ford</strong> had a a few EV news items coinciding with the F-150 Lightning reveal. First, there was the truck&#8217;s debut, which is arguably its most important new product in years and a critical piece of the company&#8217;s $22 billion investment into electrification. This is a challenging vehicle for Ford. As I noted in my coverage, the truck will need everything that has made its gas-powered counterpart the best-selling vehicle in North America as well as new benefits that come from going electric. That means torque, performance, towing capability and the general layout has to meet the needs of its customers, many of whom use it for commercial purposes. The vehicle specs suggest that Ford has delivered on the torque and power, while keeping the same cab and bed dimensions as its gas counterpart.</p>
<p>We ran a poll the night of the reveal asking folks &#8220;which electric truck is for you?&#8221; The choices and results were 37% picked the Ford F-150 Lightning, 19.6% choose <strong>Rivian</strong> R1T and 43.4% said they&#8217;ll hodl the <strong>Tesla</strong> Cybertruck.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Which electric truck is for you?</p>
<p>(<a href="https://twitter.com/kirstenkorosec?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@kirstenkorosec</a> has the details on the Ford F-150 Lightning:) <a href="https://t.co/Od2mDYMXyz">https://t.co/Od2mDYMXyz</a>)</p>
<p>&mdash; TechCrunch (@TechCrunch) <a href="https://twitter.com/TechCrunch/status/1395197868097646597?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 20, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Ford is offering one item that some customers might find appealing. Ford said its new F-150 Lightning truck, which will come to market in spring 2022, can provide <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/ford-f-150-lightning-electric-pickup-truck-can-power-your-home-in-an-outage/">energy to a customer&#8217;s home</a> in the event of an outage.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Ford also announced that it has signed a memorandum of understanding with <strong>SK Innovation</strong> to establish a<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/ford-unveils-the-f-150-lightning-its-all-electric-pickup-truck-that-will-start-under-40000/"> joint venture to manufacture batteries</a> for electric vehicles in the United States. The new venture, dubbed BlueOvalSK, will produce around 60 GWh annually starting mid-decade. The MOU is the latest sign that Ford intends to vertically develop its battery capabilities.</p>
<p>Finally, the Verge interviewed <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22444294/ford-f150-lightning-pickup-truck-jim-farley-interview">Ford CEO Jim Farley</a>.</p>
<p><strong>UPDATE</strong>: <strong>Ford</strong> revealed Monday morning the 2022 F-150 Lightning Pro, a version of the truck designed with <a href="https://media.ford.com/content/fordmedia/fna/us/en/news/2021/05/24/all-electric-f-150-lightning-pro.html">commercial customers in mind</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Kia</strong>, which held its U.S.<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/kias-fast-charging-ev6-electric-crossover-is-coming-to-the-u-s-in-early-2022/"> reveal of the the Kia EV6</a>, an all-electric crossover that is supposed to kick off the automaker&#8217;s Plan S strategy to shift away from internal combustion engines and toward EVs. The EV6, one of 11 electric vehicles that Kia plans to deliver globally by 2026. will come to the U.S. early next year. It&#8217;s also the first dedicated battery-electric vehicle to be built on its new Electric-Global Modular Platform, which is shared with Hyundai and Genesis as part of the <strong>Hyundai Motor Group</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Lamborghini</strong> announced it is going to eventually <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/lamborghini-is-kicking-off-its-electrification-plan-with-two-gas-powered-super-sports-cars/">electrify its portfolio</a>, although it is taking a slow road to get there. The will first pay homage to combustion engines with the introduction of two new V12 luxury sports cars this year before it makes a push into electrification. The aim is to switch its full lineup of vehicles to hybrids by the end of 2024 and launch of an all-electric Lamborghini in the second half of the decade. The company said it plans to invest 1.5 billion euros ($1.82 billion) over four years to make the transition to hybrid vehicles, the largest allocation in its history.</p>
<h3>Flight</h3>
<p><strong>Volocopter</strong> revealed a new electric vertical take-off and landing aircraft targeting the suburban-to-city commuter. The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/volocopter-debuts-a-bigger-evtol-aimed-at-the-city-suburban-commute/">four-seater VoloConnect</a>, which is designed to have a range of 62 miles, is a significant departure from short urban trip aircraft called VoloCity. The two-seat VoloCity, which has to be certified, has a 22-mile range.</p>
<p>VoloConnect&#8217;s longer range indicates that the company has its sights set on markets outside of major city centers, and that it is looking to more directly compete with rival eVTOL startups. VoloConnect&#8217;s aircraft specs are in line with that of competitors <strong>Archer Aviation</strong> and <strong>Wisk Aero</strong>, which each have eVTOL designs with an anticipated range of around 60 miles.</p>
<p>Speaking of <strong>Wisk Aero</strong>, the startup filed a motion for a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/wisk-aero-files-injunction-in-trade-secret-lawsuit-against-archer-aviation/">preliminary injunction</a> in its ongoing lawsuit with rival electric air travel startup Archer Aviation. The injunction could put a wrench in Archer&#8217;s operations should the courts approve it. Wisk has asked the court to immediately prohibit Archer from using 52 trade secrets that it alleges were stolen by former employees who were later hired by Archer. The trade secrets &#8220;span the gamut of systems within the aircraft and processes for development,&#8221; a Wisk spokesperson told TechCrunch.</p>
<h3>In-car tech</h3>
<p>The <strong>Google I/O developer conference</strong> contained a few vehicle related announcements, including that it is extending its Android for Cars App Library, which is available as part of Jetpack, to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-is-making-it-easier-to-bring-android-apps-to-your-car/">support the Android Automotive operating system</a>. This is good news for developers who can now create an app that is compatible with two different, but sometimes overlapping platforms: Android OS and Android Auto. It also means developers can create one app that should work seamlessly between various makes and models of vehicles. The company is already working with so-called Early Access Partners, which includes <strong>Parkwhiz</strong>, <strong>Plugshare</strong>, <strong>Sygic</strong>, <strong>ChargePoint</strong>, <strong>Flitsmeister</strong>, <strong>SpotHero</strong> and others to bring apps in these categories to cars powered by Android Automotive OS.</p>
<p>Google also announced it is working with <strong>BMW</strong> and other automakers to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/with-android-12-google-will-turn-your-smartphone-into-a-car-key/">develop a digital key</a> that will let car owners lock, unlock and start a vehicle from their Android smartphone. The digital car keys will become available on select Pixel and Samsung Galaxy phones later this year. Google didn&#8217;t name the other automakers that it is working with, but the folks there tell me it will be available in some 2021 models and a number of 2022 model vehicles. My educated guess, based on the companies it is already working with, is that Volvo and GM brands will get the digital key.</p>
<p><strong>HERE Technologies</strong>, the location data and technology platform, will power the in-vehicle Human-Machine Interface (HMI) navigation solution in <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2021/05/19/2232153/0/en/Arrival-selects-HERE-SDK-for-its-Electric-Vehicles.html">Arrival&#8217;s upcoming electric vehicles</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Holoride</strong>, the Audi spinoff that&#8217;s creating an in-vehicle XR passenger entertainment experience, is deploying <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/holoride-deploys-elrond-blockchain-and-nfts-in-prep-for-2022-market-launch/">blockchain technology and NFTs</a> as the next stage in its preparation for a 2022 market launch. The company said it is integrating Elrond blockchain into its tech stack to bring transparency to its ecosystem of car manufacturers and content creators. The aim is to use NFTs, or non-fungible tokens, to incentivize developers into creating more content on holoride&#8217;s platform for the promise of more money earned off token purchases, and to attract passengers who want to personalize their in-car experience.</p>
<p><strong>Stellantis </strong>and <strong>Foxconn</strong> have <a href="https://media.stellantisnorthamerica.com/newsrelease.do?id=22698&amp;mid=1">formed a joint venture</a> called Mobile Drive to supply in-car and connected-car technologies. The non-binding agreement is meant to speed up the time it takes to develop and deploy in-vehicle user experiences enabled by advanced consumer electronics, HMI interfaces and services, according to the companies.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/the-station-london-scooter-winners-and-fords-most-important-ev/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156391</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Equity Monday: Crypto&#8217;s awful weekend, Apple v. Epic, and funding rounds galore</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/equity-monday-cryptos-awful-weekend-apple-v-epic-and-funding-rounds-galore/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/equity-monday-cryptos-awful-weekend-apple-v-epic-and-funding-rounds-galore/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 14:23:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aurora Solar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emitwise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Epic Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mono]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UAE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zeta]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. This is Equity Monday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/87f621d7-634d-473f-a666-c547cd536558?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>This is Equity Monday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You can follow the show on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/equitypod">here</a> and myself <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">here</a>.</p>
<p>After a somewhat quiet weekend, things are kicking off in rapid-fire fashion this week. Here&#8217;s what you need to know:</p>
<ul>
<li>The cryptocurrency selloff that was in full-swing on Friday continued over the weekend. Though bitcoin and ether managed to recoup some of their losses since they set new local minima, the value of popular cryptos is vastly depressed compared to recent highs.</li>
<li>Looking ahead, it&#8217;s the final day of arguments at the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/epic-games-takes-its-apple-app-store-fight-to-europe/">Epic Games vs. Apple trial</a>. And we&#8217;re seeing a smaller company try to crack some of the hold that a major tech incumbent enjoys over a huge piece of the digital economy. So, if you like startups, you might want to put aside your Apple fandom for a minute.</li>
<li>More than a few funding rounds are cracking off this morning, including neat rounds from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/nigerias-mono-raises-millions-to-power-the-internet-economy-in-africa/">African fintech Mono</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/zeta-unicorn-softbank/">India-and-UAE-based Zeta</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/emitwise-raises-an-extra-3-2m-from-arctern-ventures-for-its-greenhouse-gas-emissions-platform/">Emitwise raising $3.2 million</a>, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/aurora-solar-aims-to-power-the-growing-solar-industry-with-a-250m-round-c/">Aurora Solar raising $250 million</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>With a busy funding market and a yet-busy IPO cycle, it should be yet another busy week. Strap in!</p>
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 AM PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts!</i></p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/equity-monday-cryptos-awful-weekend-apple-v-epic-and-funding-rounds-galore/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156379</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Korea&#8217;s Riiid raises $175M from SoftBank to expand its AI-based learning platform to global markets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/riiid-ai-education-softbank/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/riiid-ai-education-softbank/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 14:19:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156286</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;AI is eating the world of education,&#8221; Riiid co-founder and CEO YJ Jang notes in his biographical description on his LinkedIn profile, and today his startup &#8212; which builds AI-based personalized learning, including test prep, for students &#8212; is announcing a major funding round to help it position itself as a player in that process. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">&#8220;AI is eating the world of education,&#8221; <a href="https://company.riiid.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Riiid</a> co-founder and CEO YJ Jang notes in his biographical description on his <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/yj-young-jun-jang-6b4a3111/?originalSubdomain=kr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LinkedIn profile</a>, and today his startup &#8212; which builds AI-based personalized learning, including test prep, for students &#8212; is announcing a major funding round to help it position itself as a player in that process.</p>
<p>Seoul-based Riiid has closed a funding round of $175 million, an equity round coming from a single backer, SoftBank&#8217;s Vision Fund 2.</p>
<p>The funding is coming at a high-watermark moment for edtech &#8212; with the shift to remote learning in the last year of pandemic living highlighting the opportunity to build better tools to serve that market, and a number of startups in the category subsequently raising hundreds of millions of dollars to tackle the opportunity. Riiid plans to use the investment both to expand its footprint internationally, a well as to expand its products.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Riiid is not disclosing its valuation, but this round is its biggest yet and brings the total raised by the startup to $250 million, a significant sum in the world of edtech.</p>
<p>Riiid has primarily made a name for itself through Santa, a test prep app geared towards people in non-English-language countries to practice and prepare to take the TOEIC English language proficiency exam (often a requirement to apply to English-language universities if you&#8217;re not a native English speaker), which has been used by more than 2.5 million students in Korea and Japan.</p>
<p>It has also been partnering with third parties to expand into test prep for other exams. These have included the GMAT (in partnership with Kaplan) for Korean students; an app, in partnership with <a href="https://connecme.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ConnecME Education</a> (a company that tailors educational services specifically to cater to international audiences) to help people in Egypt, UAE, Turkey, Saudi Arabia, and Jordan <a href="https://www.intelligentcio.com/me/2021/03/26/riiid-labs-and-connecme-launch-ai-enabled-act-test-preparation-mobile-app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">prepare for the ACT</a>; and a<a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/riiid-labs-signs-usd-three-million-contract-with-latin-american-education-leaders-grupo-inicie-and-casa-grande-to-deliver-personalized-ai-powered-learning-301255767.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> deal</a> to build AI-based tools for students in Latin America to prepare for their college entrance exams. The ACT development comes after Riiid said that the former CEO of ACT, Marten Roorda, was joining its international arm Riiid Labs as its &#8220;executive in residence,&#8221; so that could point to more ACT prep applications for other markets, too.</p>
<p>Beyond university entrance tests, Riiid has also been building apps for vocational education, with Santa Realtor for preparing for real estate agency exams, and a test preparation tool for insurance agent exams, both in Korea.</p>
<p>The company has been growing at a time when edtechs are seeing more business and a rise in overall credibility and urgency to fill the gap left by the temporary cessation of in-person learning. The extra element of bringing artificial intelligence into the equation is not unique: a number of companies are bringing in advances in computer vision, natural language processing and machine learning to bring more personalized experiences into what might otherwise appear like a one-size-fits-all model. What is notable here is that Riiid has also been anchoring a lot of its R&amp;D in IP. The company says it has applied for 103 domestic and international patents, and has so far had 27 of them issued.</p>
<p class="p1">“Riiid wants to transform education with AI, and achieve a true democratization of educational opportunities,” said Riiid CEO YJ Jang in a statement. “This investment is only the beginning of our journey in creating a new industry ecosystem and we will carry out this mission with global partnerships.&#8221;</p>
<p>For SoftBank, this is one of the firm&#8217;s bigger edtech investments &#8212; others have included Kahoot (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/13/kahoot-picks-up-215m-from-softbank-for-its-user-generated-gamified-e-learning-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$215 million</a>), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/indias-online-learning-platform-unacademy-raises-150-million-at-1-45-billion-valuation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Unacademy</a> in India, and <a href="https://www.mondaq.com/PressRelease/67234/MoFo-Advises-SoftBank-On-Investment-In-Brazilian-EdTech-Company-Descomplica" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Descomplica</a> in Brazil. Riiid said that this round is SoftBank&#8217;s first specifically in the area of AI built for educational applications.</p>
<p>“Riiiid is driving a paradigm shift in education, from a ‘one size fits all’ approach to personalized instruction. Powered by AI and machine learning, Riiid’s platform provides education companies, schools and students with personalized plans and tools to optimize learning potential,” said Greg Moon, Managing Partner at SoftBank Investment Advisers. “We are delighted to partner with YJ and the Riiid team to support their ambition of democratizing quality education around the world.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/riiid-ai-education-softbank/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156286</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>E-commerce startup Little Birdie lands $30M AUD pre-launch funding from Australia&#8217;s largest bank</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/e-commerce-startup-little-birdie-lands-30m-aud-pre-launch-funding-from-australias-largest-bank/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/e-commerce-startup-little-birdie-lands-30m-aud-pre-launch-funding-from-australias-largest-bank/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 14:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Commonwealth Bank of Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Little Birdie]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156275</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Melbourne-based Little Birdie, an e-commerce startup that wants to become the “new homepage of online shopping,” won’t launch until next month, but it’s already scored a major investor. Commonwealth Bank of Australia (CBA), the largest of Australia’s “Big Four” banks, has poured $30 million AUD (about $23.2 million USD) in pre-launch funding into Little Birdie, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2156280" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CBA-Lbirdie-002.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2156280" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2156280" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CBA-Lbirdie-002.jpg" alt="A photo of (left) Commonwealth Bank group executive Angus Sullivan and (right) Jon Beros, co-founder and CEO of Little Birdie, standing in front of Little Birdie’s logo" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CBA-Lbirdie-002.jpg 3661w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CBA-Lbirdie-002.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CBA-Lbirdie-002.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CBA-Lbirdie-002.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CBA-Lbirdie-002.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CBA-Lbirdie-002.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CBA-Lbirdie-002.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CBA-Lbirdie-002.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2156280" class="wp-caption-text">Commonwealth Bank group executive Angus Sullivan and Jon Beros, co-founder and CEO of Little Birdie</p></div></p>
<p>Melbourne-based <a href="https://www.littlebirdie.com.au/">Little Birdie</a>, an e-commerce startup that wants to become the “new homepage of online shopping,” won’t launch until next month, but it’s already scored a major investor. <a href="https://www.commbank.com.au/">Commonwealth Bank of Australia (CBA)</a>, the <a href="ttps://theaufinance.com/top-banks-in-australia">largest of Australia’s “Big Four” banks</a>, has poured $30 million AUD (about $23.2 million USD) in pre-launch funding into Little Birdie, and will also integrate its shopping content, including exclusive offers, into its consumer banking app, which reaches 11 million retail customers in Australia.</p>
<p>Little Birdie says this brings its valuation to $130 million AUD (about $100 million USD). Compared to the United States, where Amazon is the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/24/target-breaks-into-the-top-10-list-of-u-s-e-commerce-retailers/">largest e-commerce retailer by far</a>, Australian shoppers <a href="https://ecommerceguide.com/top/top-10-ecommerce-sites-in-australia/">spend more time choosing between several platforms</a>, including large marketplaces like eBay, Gumtree, Amazon, Woolworths and a host of smaller players.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Set to launch in mid-June, Little Birdie will aggregate over 70 million products from different online brands and stores, with the goal of being the first place shoppers look when they want to buy something. Users can use Little Birdie to track and compare products, and look for price drops, sales and offers. The SKUs come from a combination of brand partnerships and scraping e-commerce sites, with the majority from retailers’ product feeds.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TorNowJOvM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/e-commerce-fulfillment-platform-shippit-raises-22-2-million-led-by-tiger-global/">E-commerce fulfillment platform Shippit raises $22.2 million led by Tiger Global</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;E-commerce fulfillment platform Shippit raises $22.2 million led by Tiger Global&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/e-commerce-fulfillment-platform-shippit-raises-22-2-million-led-by-tiger-global/embed/#?secret=TorNowJOvM" data-secret="TorNowJOvM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Co-founder and chief executive officer Jon Beros told TechCrunch that “Australia’s e-commerce market is very competitive and quite fragmented with a lot of retailers fighting for market share. The pandemic accelerated online adoption and saw many retailers switch on an online presence, or shift their focus online. With so many players fighting for the attention of shoppers and driving up the cost of acquisition, Little Birdie can genuinely help retailers by providing a new marketing channel that delivers qualified customers leads.”</p>
<p>Commonwealth Bank will be able to access Little Birdie’s catalog of shopping content to create targeted offers for customers, including features that link savings goals to specific items through its money management tools. Beros said that Little Birdie will also seek two different types of brand partnerships: “Firstly with retailers who come on board to promote their exclusive offers and products on Little Birdie and secondly with major brands and media companies that look to integrate our shopping content into their apps or websites. These integration partners ultimately deepen the value Little Birdie offers its retail partners by helping to amplify the reach of their offers to a wider audience.”</p>
<p>The company is looking at expansion into Southeast Asia and the United States, but Beros said there is not a firm timeline for its international growth yet, since it depends on the COVID-19 pandemic situation and when borders start to reopen.</p>
<p>In a press statement, Commonwealth Bank group executive Angus Sullivan said, “We believe customers should have access to the world’s best digital experience and our partnership with Little Birdie will give customers access to exclusive industry leading deals via the CommBank app.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Kxw2sjm6vH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/una-brands-launches-with-40m-to-acquire-brands-on-multiple-asia-pacific-e-commerce-platforms/">Una Brands launches with $40M to roll up brands on multiple Asia-Pacific e-commerce platforms</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Una Brands launches with $40M to roll up brands on multiple Asia-Pacific e-commerce platforms&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/una-brands-launches-with-40m-to-acquire-brands-on-multiple-asia-pacific-e-commerce-platforms/embed/#?secret=Kxw2sjm6vH" data-secret="Kxw2sjm6vH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/e-commerce-startup-little-birdie-lands-30m-aud-pre-launch-funding-from-australias-largest-bank/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156275</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Invoca acquires DialogTech for $100M to expand its conversational intelligence tools</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/invoca-acquires-dialogtech-for-100m-to-expand-its-conversational-intelligence-tools/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/invoca-acquires-dialogtech-for-100m-to-expand-its-conversational-intelligence-tools/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 13:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[invoca]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[martech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156353</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the heels of expanding its marketing call analytics platform last year to provide more insights to help those in sales, e-commerce and customer experience, Invoca is making its first acquisition to widen the net of companies that it targets. The company has acquired DialogTech, a startup that builds tools for marketers to analyze inbound [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">On the heels of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/call-analytics-platform-invoca-expands-into-sales-e-commerce-and-customer-experience/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">expanding</a> its marketing call analytics platform last year to provide more insights to help those in sales, e-commerce and customer experience, <a href="https://www.invoca.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Invoca</a> is making its first acquisition to widen the net of companies that it targets. The company has acquired <a href="https://www.dialogtech.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DialogTech</a>, a startup that builds tools for marketers to analyze inbound phone calls and other contacts, in what TechCrunch understands to be a $100 million deal.</p>
<p>As part of the transaction, Santa Barbara-based Invoca will be divesting Swydo, a company that Chicago-based DialogTech <a href="https://www.swydo.com/swydo-acquired-dialogtech-strengthen-position-leading-omni-channel-reporting-dashboarding-tool/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired in 2018</a>. Swydo &#8212; originally from The Netherlands &#8212; will remain a partner of Invoca&#8217;s, the company said.</p>
<p>Invoca has up to now focused on larger consumer-facing enterprises &#8212; its customers include the likes of ADT, AutoNation, DISH, TELUS, and The Home Depot &#8212; providing them with an AI-based platform that lets their marketing, sales and other teams analyze calls from consumer customers and provide call tracking, coaching, and other insights in real time and in the form of post-call reports to help those teams do their jobs more easily.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Gregg Johnson, Invoca&#8217;s CEO and one of growing pool of Salesforce veterans that are reinventing the marketing and sales technology landscape, described DialogTech as &#8220;complementary&#8221; to what Invoca does, but will specifically help Invoca better target mid-market companies.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The opportunity that both Invoca and DialogTech have identified is that, despite the growth of digital media advertising, social media and other channels for brands to connect to would-be customers, inbound calls remain a very key part of how companies sell goods and services, especially when the sale is of a complex item. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;About 40% to 80% of revenues come through contact centers,&#8221; Johnson said. &#8220;Brands can do all the retargeting they want but the same strategies in digital don&#8217;t work there.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">For those working at the other end of the line, the need for tools to do their jobs better became even more pressing in the last year, a time when customers stayed home and away from physical stores, shifting all of their interactions to virtual and remote channels. Subsequently, they demanded and expected better levels of service there.</span></p>
<p>“This move enables us to be an even better partner to enterprises and agencies looking to optimize their marketing and drive sales,” said DialogTech CEO, Doug Kofoid, in a statement. “Together as Invoca, our combined company will deliver an unrivaled solution for conversation intelligence, with the most innovative technology, expertise, experience, and resources in our industry.”</p>
<p>The combined business will become one of the bigger &#8220;martech&#8221; startups focusing on conversational insights, with 2,000 customers, over 300 employees and on track to make more than $100 million this year in revenue. This is, however, just the tip of the iceberg: the conversational intelligence market was <a href="https://www.marketsandmarkets.com/Market-Reports/conversational-ai-market-49043506.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">estimated to be worth some $4.8 billion in 2020</a> and is expected to balloon to nearly $14 billion by 2025.</p>
<p>Given how many startups we&#8217;ve seen launch in the name of better sales intelligence, it&#8217;s likely that this will not be the last piece of consolidation in the area. Combining to expand the functionality of a platform, or to expand the scale and reach of a business, or simply to bring on interesting tech that is easier to acquire than build from scratch, are three areas that will likely drive more M&amp;A.</p>
<p>Invoca last raised funding in <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/invoca-raises-56m-to-help-marketers-turn-conversational-insights-into-revenue-300940456.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">October 2019</a>, a $56 million round just ahead of the world shifting into Covid-19 pandemic mode. Johnson confirmed that Invoca &#8212; which has to date raised $116 million from Accel, Upfront Ventures, H.I.G. Growth Partners, Morgan Stanley, Salesforce Ventures and others &#8212; is in a strong enough position as a business not to need to raise more for this acquisition.</p>
<p>However, I suspect that scaling up like this will help it bid for bigger money and a bigger valuation when it does, as will the fact that peers in the market like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/12/gong-raises-another-200m-on-2-2-billion-valuation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gong</a> (which Johnson described as the &#8220;B2B version of Invoca&#8221; to me) have seen their valuations catapult in the last year, spurred by the changes in how customers interact with businesses, and sales and marketing can work to better serve them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/invoca-acquires-dialogtech-for-100m-to-expand-its-conversational-intelligence-tools/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156353</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ByteDance&#8217;s video editor CapCut is the latest to top the U.S. App Store</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/capcut-bytedance-tiktok/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/capcut-bytedance-tiktok/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 13:21:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freeware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[major]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meitu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photo editor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video editor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video hosting]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156264</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From time to time, we see a Chinese app climbing to the top of Google Play and App Store in a host of Western countries. It might be a utility tool like a selfie beautifier or some casual video game, which has universal appeal and require little localization effort. But most of them tend to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">From time to time, we see a Chinese app climbing to the top of Google Play and App Store in a host of Western countries. It might be a utility tool like a selfie beautifier or some casual video game, which has universal appeal and require little localization effort. But most of them tend to be a blip on the radar.</p>
<p>The latest Chinese app to top the overseas charts is from TikTok owner ByteDance. Called CapCut, the video editing app allows users to not only add a trove of stickers, filters and effects, it also has a simple-to-use green screen function, a zooming feature that works like a Ken Burns effect, and many more &#8212; which make the app like an accessible Final Cut on the go.</p>
<p>Users won&#8217;t have to worry about paying for music, as CapCut has a library of licensed sound clips that they can use to spice up their content. Over the past year, TikTok has been beefing up its music arsenal through efforts like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/05/tiktok-music/">scouting for musicians</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/as-competition-heats-up-tiktok-announces-six-new-interactive-music-effects-for-creators/">signing deals with major labels</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Chinese tech giants are adept at attracting a large user base first by offering their services for free, and then exploring monetization models after users become sticky to the products. CapCut appears to have the same playbook.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">CapCut&#8217;s Chinese sibling Jianying has already had success among Douyin (TikTok for China) users. Now that pattern is repeating outside China, with TikTok users taking advantage of CapCut to make their videos look sleek and professional with a few taps on their phones. </span></p>
<p>Since May 21, CapCut has been the <a href="https://sensortower.com/ios/rankings/top/iphone/us/all-categories?app_id=com.lemon.lvoverseas&amp;app_name=capcut-video-editor&amp;publisher=bytedance-pte-ltd&amp;start_date=2021-02-24&amp;end_date=2021-05-24&amp;countries=US&amp;chart_type=free&amp;hourly=false&amp;selected_tab=charts&amp;date=2021-05-24&amp;search=">No. 1 free app</a> on the U.S. App Store, according to analytics company SensorTower, and it ranks <a href="https://sensortower.com/android/US/bytedance-pte-ltd/app/capcut-video-editor/com.lemon.lvoverseas/category-rankings?selected_tab=charts&amp;start_date=2021-04-25&amp;end_date=2021-05-24&amp;countries=US&amp;category=all&amp;chart_type=free&amp;device=android&amp;hourly=false&amp;date=2021-05-24">9th on Google Play</a> in the U.S. as of writing. Across the globe, it comes in first among free iOS apps in 33 countries, according to <a href="https://www.appannie.com/apps/ios/app/1500855883/app-ranking?app_slug=1500855883&amp;market_slug=ios&amp;device=iphone&amp;type=ranks&amp;date=2021-05-22">App Annie</a>.</p>
<p>All told, the app has exceeded 250 million installs globally to date from across the App Store and Google Play, and nearly 9.5 million from U.S. app stores, SensorTower says.</p>
<p>CapCut&#8217;s rise is reminiscent of the Chinese photo editor Meitu. The app was so popular that it became synonymous with a selfie beautifier in China, but it also had a solid base of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/01/19/meitu-app-collects-personal-data/">loyal users abroad</a>. The difference is CapCut&#8217;s rise is built on its sibling TikTok&#8217;s global dominance, whereas Meitu&#8217;s early attempt to foster a social network around its photo tool to increase user stickiness never really took off.</p>
<p>CapCut probably won&#8217;t be ByteDance&#8217;s last viral app. TikTok&#8217;s sprawling content empire will spawn more offshoots, whether it&#8217;s a video editor or an e-commerce service for creators to make money and for users to buy the products endorsed by their favorite influencers.</p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/capcut-bytedance-tiktok/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156264</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Seed-stage accelerator Flat6Labs closes $13.2M fund for startups in Egypt</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/seed-stage-accelerator-flat6labs-closes-13-2m-fund-for-startups-in-egypt/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/seed-stage-accelerator-flat6labs-closes-13-2m-fund-for-startups-in-egypt/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 12:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Algebra Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business incubators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cairo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flat6Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[International Finance Corporation (IFC)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sawari Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup Accelerator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tunisia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156316</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Investment activities in Egypt continue to gain steam, not for startups only but also the funds backing them. Today, seed accelerator Flat6Labs announced the second close of its Egypt fund to support early-stage startups and provide follow-up investment. The fund had a target for EGP50 million (~$3.2 million) but eventually closed at EGP207 million ($13.2 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investment activities in Egypt continue to gain steam, not for startups only but also the funds backing them</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, seed accelerator <a href="http://www.flat6labs.com/program/flat6labs-cairo/">Flat6Labs</a> announced the second close of its Egypt fund to support early-stage startups and provide follow-up investment</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The <a href="https://flat6labs.com/funds/fac/">fund</a> had a target for EGP50 million (~$3.2 million) but </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">eventually</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> closed at EGP207 million ($13.2 million).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Launched in 2011, Flat6Labs is a regional seed accelerator with offices in Egypt and Tunisia</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The accelerator launched i</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ts Cairo programme </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in 2017 to invest in more than 100 startups across Egypt over the course of five years</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Startups that get into the accelerator </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are provided</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with office space, legal and marketing help, and access to mentorship and networking, among other perks</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. They also receive between EGP500,000 and EGP750,000. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, with the close of this round, Flat6Labs has increased the check sizes to EGP1.5 million (~$95,000) and up to EGP3 million (~$191,000) in post-programme follow-on funding for selected startups</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The <a href="https://www.ifc.org/wps/wcm/connect/corp_ext_content/ifc_external_corporate_site/home">International Finance Corporation</a> (IFC), the <a href="https://www.msme.eg/ar/Pages/default.aspx">MSME Development Agency</a>, <a href="https://egyptventures.com/">Egypt Ventures</a>, and the <a href="https://www.eaefund.org/">Egyptian American Enterprise Fund</a> are the anchor investors in Flat6Labs&#8217; seed fund</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sawari Ventures, which </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">recently closed its $71 million fund, also participated in this second close, and i</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">t comes as no surprise because the firm, which is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">highly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> affiliated with the accelerator, said it would set aside 10% of its fund for Flat6Labs seed-stage companies when we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/sawari-ventures-finally-closes-71m-fund-for-north-african-startups/">covered</a> them in April</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“At Sawari Ventures, our fund strategy has always been to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">allocate</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a percentage of our fund to the seed stage, which is a completely different proposition </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in terms of</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> process, culture, and support needed,” </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wael Amin, managing Partner at Sawari Ventures, said in a statement. “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">As investors in Flat6Labs Accelerator Company, we get the opportunity to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">profitably</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">participate</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in Egyptian companies at a very early stage, get early indicators on ecosystem trends, and visibility into the ecosystem.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="X8SISbBh72"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/sawari-ventures-finally-closes-71m-fund-for-north-african-startups/">Egyptian VC firm Sawari Ventures finally closes $71M fund for North African startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Egyptian VC firm Sawari Ventures finally closes $71M fund for North African startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/sawari-ventures-finally-closes-71m-fund-for-north-african-startups/embed/#?secret=X8SISbBh72" data-secret="X8SISbBh72" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The second close of Flat6Labs&#8217; fund is the latest of four venture capital funds targeted at Egyptian startups</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shortly after Sawari Ventures&#8217; close, Algebra Ventures <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/after-its-first-54m-fund-algebra-ventures-launches-another-90m-fund-for-startups-in-egypt/">announced</a> launching a $90 million second fund</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Subsequently</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, <a href="https://www.wamda.com/2021/05/giz-launches-Euro-100-million-funding-programme-time-fund-managers">GIZ Egypt launched</a> a €100 million funding programme</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to provide up to four MENA-based fund managers between €25-30 million and is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">exclusively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> targeted at Egypt-based startups</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p>Flat6Labs is one of the continent&#8217;s active and well-known seed-stage accelerators. <span style="font-weight: 400;">Just in Egypt alone, it has run seven cycles and invested in 62 startups. The venture capital firm and seed-stage accelerator provides a filter for some early-stage investors to source what companies to back or not. A good portion of startups in Flat6Labs&#8217; portfolio has piqued investors&#8217; interests, and half of them who </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">have gone on to raise more money also received follow-up investment from Flat6Labs totalling EGP145,000,000 (~$9.25 million). </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some of the startups in Flat6Labs&#8217; portfolio include Welnes, Glued, CreditGo, and Docspert Health</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gjuWbDZmZN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/after-its-first-54m-fund-algebra-ventures-launches-another-90m-fund-for-startups-in-egypt/">After its first $54M fund, Algebra Ventures launches $90M fund for startups in Egypt</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;After its first $54M fund, Algebra Ventures launches $90M fund for startups in Egypt&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/after-its-first-54m-fund-algebra-ventures-launches-another-90m-fund-for-startups-in-egypt/embed/#?secret=gjuWbDZmZN" data-secret="gjuWbDZmZN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/seed-stage-accelerator-flat6labs-closes-13-2m-fund-for-startups-in-egypt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156316</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zeta becomes a unicorn with $250 million SoftBank-led funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/zeta-unicorn-softbank/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/zeta-unicorn-softbank/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 12:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meesho]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swiggy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zeta]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Zeta, a startup that helps banks and fintech firms launch products, is the newest to attain the coveted unicorn status after closing a financing round. The banking tech firm, co-founded by veteran Indian entrepreneur Bhavin Turakhia, said on Monday it has raised $250 million in a Series D Series C round led by SoftBank Vision [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Zeta, a startup that helps banks and fintech firms launch products, is the newest to attain the coveted unicorn status after closing a financing round.</p>
<p>The banking tech firm, co-founded by veteran Indian entrepreneur Bhavin Turakhia, said on Monday it has raised $250 million in a <s>Series D</s> Series C round led by SoftBank Vision Fund 2, confirming <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/banking-tech-zeta-fundraise-sb/">a TechCrunch report from mid-April</a>. Existing investor Sodexo also participated in the round.</p>
<p>The new round valued the startup, which has offices in Bangalore and Dubai, at $1.45 billion. That’s up from the $300 million valuation that Zeta reported <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/23/zeta-300m-sodexo/">in the second half of 2019</a>. (Turakhia said the startup incorrectly called the previous round Series C.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="http://zeta.tech">Zeta</a> has developed a technology stack that helps it engage with both banks, fintech startups, as well as other online consumer platforms. The thesis is that banks &#8212; largely operating on antiquated technologies &#8212; today don’t have the time and expertise to offer the best experience to hundreds of millions of customers and fintech firms they serve.</p>
<p>&#8220;Banks are still stuck in the &#8217;80s. Many of them still use COBOL programming language. They offer poor user experience,&#8221; said Turakhia in a press briefing Monday, adding that to make up for it, banks end up working with dozens of vendor and technology partners. &#8220;Nobody thought of building the bank stack from the ground up. Until now.&#8221;</p>
<p>Banks, which have licenses to offer financial services to customers, use Zeta’s cloud-native API and SDKs to launch credit cards, debit cards, loans and offer improved experience to customers, and also work with fintechs.</p>
<p>&#8220;Any financial service you can think of, Zeta provides it today,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The startup today serves 10 banks and 25 fintech firms, and plans to deploy the fresh capital to reach more clients and increase its headcount.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2156355" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2156355" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2156355 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/zeta-softbank-fundraise-unicorn.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="479" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/zeta-softbank-fundraise-unicorn.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/zeta-softbank-fundraise-unicorn.jpg?resize=150,70 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/zeta-softbank-fundraise-unicorn.jpg?resize=300,140 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/zeta-softbank-fundraise-unicorn.jpg?resize=768,359 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/zeta-softbank-fundraise-unicorn.jpg?resize=680,318 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/zeta-softbank-fundraise-unicorn.jpg?resize=50,23 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2156355" class="wp-caption-text">The journey of Zeta. (Image: Zeta)</p></div></p>
<p>Zeta is SoftBank Vision Fund 2&#8217;s latest investment in India. The Japanese conglomerate, which<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/04/indian-social-commerce-meesho-raises-300m-at-2-1b-valuation-softbank/"> minted another unicorn in social commerce Meesho</a> last month, is in advanced stages of talks to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/softbank-in-talks-to-invest-up-to-500-million-in-swiggy/">invest up to $500 million in food delivery giant Swiggy</a> and is also <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/tech/funding/tiger-global-in-talks-to-lead-50-75-mn-funding-round-in-whatfix/articleshow/82144685.cms?from=mdr">engaging with SaaS startup WhatFix</a>.</p>
<p>“Banking software is a $300 billion industry globally. Most banks still employ technology which is significantly older than their customers, impacting user experience and engagement,” Munish Varma, a managing partner at SoftBank Investment Advisers, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Zeta is the 14th Indian startup to become a unicorn this year as Tiger Global, Falcon Edge, and SoftBank <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/11/tiger-global-goes-super-aggressive-in-india/">accelerate their pace of funding in India</a>, the world&#8217;s second largest internet market.</p>
<p>Turakhia, with his brother Divyank, started his first venture in 1998. Along the way, they sold four web companies to Endurance for $160 million. Zeta is the third startup Bhavin has co-founded since then — the other being business messaging platform Flock and Radix.</p>
<p>&#8220;The increasingly digital world represents evolving security, privacy and data protection challenges to banks. The industry needs systems reinvented with security, privacy, scalability and reliability as the core foundations. Zeta&#8217;s Omni Stack answers that need,&#8221; said Ramki Gaddipati, co-founder and chief technology officer of Zeta, in a statement.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/zeta-unicorn-softbank/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156265</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aurora Solar aims to power the growing solar industry with a $250M round C</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/aurora-solar-aims-to-power-the-growing-solar-industry-with-a-250m-round-c/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/aurora-solar-aims-to-power-the-growing-solar-industry-with-a-250m-round-c/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 11:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aurora Solar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solar Power]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155685</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aurora Solar had one of those pitches that seemed obvious in retrospect. Instead of going to a house and measuring its roof manually for a solar panel installation, why not use aerial scans and imagery of the whole region? That smart play earned them a $20M A round, a $50M B round, and now only [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Aurora Solar had one of those pitches that seemed obvious in retrospect. Instead of going to a house and measuring its roof manually for a solar panel installation, why not use aerial scans and imagery of the whole region? That smart play earned them <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/04/aurora-solars-computer-generated-installation-maps-pull-in-a-20m-series-a/">a $20M A round</a>, a $50M B round, and now only six months later a massive $250M C as they aim to become the software platform on which the coming solar power expansion will be run.</p>
<p>The idea is simple enough to explain, but difficult to pull off. There&#8217;s lots of data out there about the topography, physical and infrastructural, of most cities. Satellite imagery, aerial lidar scans, light and power lines and usage data, and of course where and how the sun hits a given location — this information is readily available. Aurora&#8217;s innovation wasn&#8217;t just using it, but assembling it into a cohesive system that&#8217;s simple and effective enough to be used widely by solar installers.</p>
<p>&#8220;Aurora&#8217;s core value proposition is the fact that you can do things remotely much faster and more accurately than could if you traveled to the site,&#8221; explained co-founder and CRO Sam Adeyemo.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Having developed algorithms that ingest the aforementioned data, the service they offer is a very quick turnaround on the tricky question of whether a solar installation makes sense for a potential customer, and if so what it might cost and look like, down to the size and angle of the panels.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2156160" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-interface-2.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2156160" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2156160" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-interface-2.png" alt="An interface showing a solar roof design and power savings." width="1024" height="426" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-interface-2.png 1760w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-interface-2.png?resize=150,62 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-interface-2.png?resize=300,125 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-interface-2.png?resize=768,319 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-interface-2.png?resize=680,283 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-interface-2.png?resize=1536,639 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-interface-2.png?resize=50,21 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2156160" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Aurora Solar</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s not uncommon for the acquisition cost for a customer to be thousands of dollars,&#8221; said Adeyemo&#8217;s co-founder, CEO Chris Hopper. That&#8217;s partly because every installation is custom. He estimated that half the price tag of any setup is &#8220;soft cost&#8221; — that is, over and above the actual price of the hardware.</p>
<p>&#8220;If the quote is for $30K, what actually goes on your roof might be $15K, the rest is overhead, design, acquisition cost, yada yada yada,&#8221; he explained. &#8220;That&#8217;s the next frontier to make solar cost-competitive, and that&#8217;s where Aurora comes in. Every time we shave a few dollars off the price of an installation, it opens it up for new consumers.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company doesn&#8217;t do its own lidar flights or solar installations, so the $250M in funding may strike some as rather high for a company making software. Though I did my best to tease out any secret skunkworks projects under way at Aurora, Adeyemo and Hopper patiently explained that enterprise-scale software isn&#8217;t cheap, and the funding is proportional to their ambitions.</p>
<p>&#8220;The amount we raised speaks to the opportunity ahead of us,&#8221; said Hopper. &#8220;There&#8217;s a lot more solar to put on roofs.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VLV46t1E9k"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/solar-roof-tile-and-energy-startup-sunroof-closes-e4-5m-led-by-inovo-venture-partners/">Solar roof-tile and energy startup SunRoof closes €4.5M led by Inovo Venture Partners</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Solar roof-tile and energy startup SunRoof closes €4.5M led by Inovo Venture Partners&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/solar-roof-tile-and-energy-startup-sunroof-closes-e4-5m-led-by-inovo-venture-partners/embed/#?secret=VLV46t1E9k" data-secret="VLV46t1E9k" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Aurora has been used for evaluating about 5 million solar projects so far, about a fifth of which end up being built, Adeyemo estimated. And that&#8217;s just a fraction of a fraction. Solar makes up about two percent of the U.S.&#8217;s power infrastructure, right now, but that&#8217;s on track to increase by an order of magnitude in the next 20 years.</p>
<p>The new administration has thrown fuel on the fire of the industry&#8217;s optimism, and whether or not something like the Green New Deal comes to fruition, the fundamentally different approach to environmental and energy policy mean there are more eyeballs directed at clean energy and consequently a lot of checks being written.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2156159" style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-founders.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2156159" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2156159" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-founders.jpg" alt="Aurora Solar co-founders Samuel Adeyemo (left) and Chris Hopper (right)." width="400" height="414" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-founders.jpg 1330w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-founders.jpg?resize=145,150 145w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-founders.jpg?resize=290,300 290w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-founders.jpg?resize=768,795 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-founders.jpg?resize=657,680 657w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-founders.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aurora-founders.jpg?resize=48,50 48w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2156159" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Aurora Solar</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;It counts for a lot. With heightened awareness about climate change there will be more interest in ways to mitigate it,&#8221; said Adeyemo. He gave the example of Texas, which after the recent storms and blackouts had more inquiries per capita than anywhere else in the country. Renewables may be a charged issue in some ways, but solar power is bipartisan and broadly popular across the political spectrum.</p>
<p>The $250M round, led by Coatue and with participation from previous investors ICONIQ, Energize Ventures, and Fifth Wall, allows the company to go both broad and deep with their product.</p>
<p>&#8220;Historically we&#8217;ve been more of a design solution; the next phase is to broaden that into a platform that covers more of the process of going solar,&#8221; said Hopper. &#8220;We don&#8217;t believe this is going to be a niche market — going from 2 to 20 percent and beyond, that&#8217;s a huge endeavor.&#8221;</p>
<p>The co-founders would not be more specific than that scaling a SaaS company requires significant cash up front, and during the push to come they can&#8217;t be worried about whether or when they&#8217;ll need to get more capital.</p>
<p>&#8220;The first five years of the company were quasi-bootstrapped&#8230; we&#8217;d raised like a million bucks. So we know what it&#8217;s like to grow a company from that perspective, and now we know what it&#8217;s like to really need the capital to scale the business,&#8221; said Adeyemo. &#8220;If you want to be the platform for a significant percentage of the energy capacity of the country&#8230; you gotta tool up.&#8221;</p>
<p>What exactly tooling up comprises we will soon find out — the company is planning to announce more news at its <a href="https://empower.aurorasolar.com/">upcoming summit</a> in June.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PJU6618LGU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/07/sunruns-3-2-billion-vivint-solar-bid-challenges-teslas-energy-ambitions/">Sunrun&#8217;s $3.2 billion Vivint Solar bid challenges Tesla&#8217;s energy ambitions</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Sunrun&#8217;s $3.2 billion Vivint Solar bid challenges Tesla&#8217;s energy ambitions&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/07/sunruns-3-2-billion-vivint-solar-bid-challenges-teslas-energy-ambitions/embed/#?secret=PJU6618LGU" data-secret="PJU6618LGU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/aurora-solar-aims-to-power-the-growing-solar-industry-with-a-250m-round-c/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155685</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Emitwise raises an extra $3.2M from ArcTern Ventures for its greenhouse gas emissions platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/emitwise-raises-an-extra-3-2m-from-arctern-ventures-for-its-greenhouse-gas-emissions-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/emitwise-raises-an-extra-3-2m-from-arctern-ventures-for-its-greenhouse-gas-emissions-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 10:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon footprint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magnus Rausing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ryan graves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Impact Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[True Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Emitwise, a startup that claims its AI platform can measure greenhouse gas emissions from companies and their supply chains, has added to its seed funding round by $3.2 million, bringing its total seed funding raised to $6.6 million. ArcTern Ventures led the $3.2m raise. Also participating were Angel investors including Peter Harrison, the CEO of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://Emitwise.com">Emitwise</a>, a startup that claims its AI platform can measure greenhouse gas emissions from companies and their supply chains, has added to its seed funding round by $3.2 million, bringing its total seed funding raised to $6.6 million. ArcTern Ventures led the $3.2m raise. Also participating were Angel investors including Peter Harrison, the CEO of Schroders; Magnus Rausing; and Saltwater (Uber Co-Founder Ryan Graves’ investment firm). Other investors include True Ventures, Social Impact Capital, Lightbird Ventures, and others.</p>
<p>The company claims its platform will automate carbon accounting across a supply chain; identify emissions hotspots; integrate with ERP systems; and complies with auditing and disclosure systems like CDP, GHG and TCFD.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JZFav0SSpu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/softbank-demeter-and-coparion-invest-3m-into-plan-as-b2b-carbon-monitoring-and-esg-platform/">SoftBank, Demeter and Coparion invest $3M into Plan A&#8217;s B2B carbon monitoring and ESG platform</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SoftBank, Demeter and Coparion invest $3M into Plan A&#8217;s B2B carbon monitoring and ESG platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/softbank-demeter-and-coparion-invest-3m-into-plan-as-b2b-carbon-monitoring-and-esg-platform/embed/#?secret=JZFav0SSpu" data-secret="JZFav0SSpu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Mauro Cozzi, Emitwise Co-Founder and CEO, said in a statement: “With leaders set to ratchet up global climate ambition at the upcoming COP26 climate summit, there’s never been more certainty amongst corporates and investors: carbon equals cost and risk. A net zero-aligned model is a proxy for profit, efficiency and resilience and we’re committed to helping firms realize the major economic upsides of the transformation.”</p>
<p>Marc Faucher, ArcTern Ventures, said: “Enterprises face mounting pressure from customers, investors, and regulators to disclose accurate environmental data. Emitwise gives a clear line of sight to supply chain carbon which is critical for instilling effective mitigation strategies and incentives. Here at ArcTern Ventures, we believe Emitwise’s software platform is a game-changer that sets new standards in universal carbon footprint reporting.”</p>
<p>Emitwise competes to some extent with other startups in this space including Watersheds and Plan A, which also recently raised a round of funding.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/emitwise-raises-an-extra-3-2m-from-arctern-ventures-for-its-greenhouse-gas-emissions-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156276</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nigeria&#8217;s Mono raises millions to power the internet economy in Africa</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/nigerias-mono-raises-millions-to-power-the-internet-economy-in-africa/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/nigerias-mono-raises-millions-to-power-the-internet-economy-in-africa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 08:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flutterwave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mono]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Open Banking]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156186</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In February, Nigerian fintech startup Mono announced its acceptance into Y Combinator and, at the time, it wanted to build the Plaid for Africa. Three months later, the startup has a different mission: to power the internet economy in Africa and has closed $2 million in seed investment towards that goal. The investment comes nine [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In February, Nigerian fintech startup <a href="https://mono.co/">Mono</a> announced its acceptance into Y Combinator and, at the time, it wanted to build the Plaid for Africa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Three months later, the startup has a different mission: to power the internet economy in Africa and has closed $2 million in seed investment towards that goal</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The investment comes nine months after the company raised $500,000 in pre-seed last September and two months after receiving $125,000 from YC</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mono&#8217;s total investment moves up to $2.625 million, and investors in this new round include Entrée Capital (one of the investors in Kuda&#8217;s seed round), Kuda co-founder and CEO Babs Ogundeyi; Gbenga Oyebode, partner at TCVP; and Eric Idiahi, co-founder and partner at Verod Capital</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">New York but Africa-based VC Lateral Capital also invested after taking part in Mono&#8217;s pre-seed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a region where more than half of the population is</span><a href="https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/SP.POP.TOTL?locations=ZG"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">either unbanked or underbanked</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, open finance players like Mono are trying to improve financial inclusion and connectivity on the continent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Open finance thrives on the notion that access to a financial ecosystem via open APIs and new routes to move money, access financial information and make borrowing decisions reduces the barriers and costs of entry for the underbanked</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Launched</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in August 2020, t</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">he company streamlines various financial data in a single API for companies and third-party developers</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mono allows them to retrieve information like account statements, real-time balance, historical transactions, income, expense and account owner identification with users&#8217; consent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aBMFIsVLwo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/mono-a-startup-that-wants-to-build-plaid-for-africa-gets-backing-from-y-combinator/">Mono, a startup that wants to build Plaid for Africa, gets backing from Y Combinator</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Mono, a startup that wants to build Plaid for Africa, gets backing from Y Combinator&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/mono-a-startup-that-wants-to-build-plaid-for-africa-gets-backing-from-y-combinator/embed/#?secret=aBMFIsVLwo" data-secret="aBMFIsVLwo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When we covered the company early in the year, it had already secured partnerships with more than 16 financial institutions in Nigeria</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to having</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a little over a hundred businesses like Carbon, Aella Credit, Credpal, Renmoney, Autochek, and Inflow Finance access customers bank account for bank statements, identity data, and balances</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Mono has also</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> connected over 100,000 financial accounts for its partners and analysed over 66 million financial transactions so far</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mono has done impressively well in a short period. While it appears to have figured out product-market fit, CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ijbkid/">Abdul Hassan</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is quick to remind everyone that the burgeoning API fintech space is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> an entry point to its pursuit of being a data company &#8212; a case he also made in February.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;The way I see it, our market is not that big. Compare the payments market now with 2016, when Paystack and Flutterwave </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> started. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The payments space in 2016 was very small and the number of people using cards online was very small,&#8221; said Hassan, who co-founded the company with <a href="https://in.linkedin.com/in/whoisprakhar">Prakhar Singh</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;It&#8217;s the same thing for us right now. That&#8217;s why our focus isn&#8217;t only on open banking but data. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We&#8217;re thinking of how we can power the internet economy with data that isn&#8217;t </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">necessarily</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> financial data</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. For instance, think about open data for telcos. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Imagine where you can move your data from one telco to another instead of getting a new SIM card and making a fresh registration</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. That&#8217;s where I see the market going, at least for us at Mono.&#8221; </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107028" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107028" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2107028" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Mono-Founders-08-1280x853-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Mono-Founders-08-1280x853-1.jpg 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Mono-Founders-08-1280x853-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Mono-Founders-08-1280x853-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Mono-Founders-08-1280x853-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Mono-Founders-08-1280x853-1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Mono-Founders-08-1280x853-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2107028" class="wp-caption-text">Abdul Hassan (CEO) and Prakhar Singh (CTO)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He adds that the company is taking an approach of building a product one step at a time until it can </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">fully</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> diversify from financial data offerings, including connecting with payment gateways (Paystack and Flutterwave) and other fintechs like wealth management startups Piggyvest and Cowrywise</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;When you&#8217;re able to connect to all the systems, a lot of use cases will come up. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first step is how can we connect to all available data and open it up for businesses and developers,&#8221; he continued</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Therefore</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Mono will use the funding to reinforce its current financial and identity data offerings and launch new products for diverse business verticals</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, a long-overdue pan-African expansion to Ghana and Kenya is top priority</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The last time I spoke with Hassan, the end of Q1 looked </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">feasible</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to get into at least one of the two markets but it didn&#8217;t turn out that way</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">But the wait seems to be over as the company said it&#8217;d be going live in Ghana next month with a handful of existing customers from Nigeria and new ones in Ghana</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some of these partners include five banks (GTBank, Fidelity Bank and three unannounced banks) and the mobile money service arm of MTN Ghana</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Our expansion is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">mostly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> inspired by our customers looking to expand to other markets, same with some of our products</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We work with our customers to give them the right tools to build new experiences for their customers,&#8221; Hassan stated</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2156233" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2156233" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2156233" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/png.png?w=680" alt="Mono" width="680" height="361" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/png.png 820w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/png.png?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/png.png?resize=300,159 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/png.png?resize=768,407 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/png.png?resize=680,361 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/png.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2156233" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Mono</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mono is one of the three API fintech companies to have raised a seed investment this year. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last month, another Nigerian fintech Okra <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/nigerian-fintech-okra-raises-3-5m-backed-by-accenture-ventures-and-susa-ventures/">closed $3.5 million</a> while Stitch, a South African API fintech, launched</span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/stitch-emerges-from-stealth-with-4m-for-its-api-fintech-play-in-africa/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">with $4 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in February</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Back to back investments like this show that investors are </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">incredibly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> optimistic about the market</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Avil Eyal, managing partner and co-founder of Entrée Capital, one of such investors, had this to say.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We are very excited to be working with Abdul, Prakhar and the entire Mono team as they continue to build out the rails for African banking to enable the delivery of financial services to hundreds of millions of people across the African continent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.&#8221;</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VQ2iFqUnxt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/how-african-startups-raised-investments-in-2020/">How African startups raised investments in 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How African startups raised investments in 2020&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/how-african-startups-raised-investments-in-2020/embed/#?secret=VQ2iFqUnxt" data-secret="VQ2iFqUnxt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/nigerias-mono-raises-millions-to-power-the-internet-economy-in-africa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156186</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>British AI startup Faculty raises $42.5M growth round led by Apax Digital Fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/23/british-ai-startup-faculty-raises-42-5m-growth-round-led-by-apax-digital-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/23/british-ai-startup-faculty-raises-42-5m-growth-round-led-by-apax-digital-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 06:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apax Digital Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apax Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faculty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jaan Tallinn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Localglobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NHS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Red Bull]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virgin media]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156229</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[British artificial intelligence (AI) company, Faculty has raised £30 million ($42.5M) in growth funding from the Apax Digital Fund (ADF). The startup has now raised a total of £40m ($56.6M) to date. In April this year, the company announced it had won a contract to work with the UK&#8217;s NHS to better predict its future [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">British artificial intelligence (AI) company, Faculty has raised £30 million ($42.5M) in growth funding from the Apax Digital Fund (ADF). The startup has now raised a total of £40m ($56.6M) to date.</p>
<p>In April this year, the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/ai-startup-faculty-wins-contract-to-predict-future-requirements-for-the-uks-nhs/">announced</a> it had won a contract to work with the UK&#8217;s NHS to better predict its future needs. It has also picked up at least <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/may/04/vote-leave-ai-firm-wins-seven-government-contracts-in-18-months">seven other</a> UK government contracts. Its customers include the UK’s National Crime Agency, Red Bull, Virgin Media, and Moonpig.</p>
<p>The company says it now expects to create over 400 new jobs across its engineering, product and delivery teams. The investment will also be put toward the rollout of Faculty’s new learning and development programme. Founded in 2014 by Dr Marc Warner, Dr Angie Ma and Andrew Brookes, the company is noted for its fondness for hiring swathes of maths and data science PhDs.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Far from being an aloof R&amp;D AI operation, Faculty pitches more as an “AI as a Service”, applying its platform to real-world data for the purposes of real-world outcomes, such as optimizing a company’s marketing spend or forecasting demand for consumer goods. That said, Faculty became briefly notorious after applying its platform to the cause of Vote Leave during the UK referendum.</p>
<p>After helping the campaign win that fight, it’s ironically now been <a href="https://www.wired.co.uk/article/faculty-ai-brexit-fishing">awarded</a> a public contract to help the British government apply machine learning to Britain’s post-Brexit fishing waters, even as the fishing industry <a href="https://www.express.co.uk/news/politics/1427654/brexit-news-uk-eu-fishing-british-boats-crew-boris-johnson-trade-deal">comes under considerable strain</a>&#8230; because of Brexit.</p>
<p>Speaking to me over a call (a longer interview will be available later) Marc Warner, CEO, and co-founder of Faculty told me the company has no plans to work in the political sphere again: “Never again. It&#8217;s very controversial. I don&#8217;t want to make out that I think politics is unethical. Trying to make the world better, in whatever dimension you can, is a good thing… But from our perspective, it was, you know, ‘noisy’, and our goal as an organization is, despite current appearances to the contrary, is not to spend tonnes of time talking about this stuff. We do believe this is an important technology that should be out there and should be in a broader set of hands than just the tech giants, who are already very good at it.”</p>
<p>Of the investment, he said: &#8220;This is about doubling down on the UK first and then international expansion. We have learned what it takes to do important, impactful AI at scale. And we just don&#8217;t think that there&#8217;s actually much of it out there. Customers are rightly sometimes a bit skeptical. There&#8217;s been hype around this stuff for years and years. We figured out a bunch of real-world applications that actually deliver value. And so, ultimately, the money [we’ve raised] is really just about being able to build out all of the pieces to do that incredibly well for our customers.&#8221;</p>
<p>He added that Faculty plans to continue to take advantage of the UK&#8217;s talent pool: &#8220;The UK is a wonderful place to do AI. It has brilliant universities and a very dynamic startup scene. It&#8217;s actually more diverse than San Francisco. There&#8217;s government, there&#8217;s finance, there&#8217;s corporates, there&#8217;s less competition from the tech giants, so there&#8217;s a bit more of a heterogeneous ecosystem.”</p>
<p>Mark Beith, partner at Apax Digital, who joins Faculty’s board of directors, said: “Faculty is a world-leading AI company with cutting-edge technology, inspiring people and culture, and with phenomenal customer feedback. They enable customers to realize the tremendous value of AI quickly but responsibly, providing robust, fair, and explainable AI, with advanced data privacy. We have seen the power and impact of their solutions first-hand, as a client, and are thrilled to partner with Marc, Angie, Andy, and the team to support their global expansion.”</p>
<p>The Apax Digital Fund joins Faculty’s existing investors, including Guardian Media Group Ventures, LocalGlobe, and Jaan Tallinn, one of Skype’s founding engineers.</p>
<p>The Estonian investor <a href="https://fortune.com/2020/11/13/jaan-tallinn-ai-safety-bitcoin-cryptocurrency-elon-musk/">gave</a> Faculty 350 units of Ether in January 2018, worth about $434,000 at the time, and 50 Bitcoins in March 2020, worth about $316,000, according to Faculty’s financial filings at the U.K. business registry Companies House.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/23/british-ai-startup-faculty-raises-42-5m-growth-round-led-by-apax-digital-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156229</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taking Microsoft&#8217;s Surface Laptop 4 for a spin</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/23/taking-microsofts-surface-laptop-4-for-a-spin/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/23/taking-microsofts-surface-laptop-4-for-a-spin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 01:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft surface]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Surface]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156149</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[These days, the path of least resistance in laptop design is straight-up knocking off the MacBook. We’ve certainly seen our share of egregious cases over the years. Microsoft, however, has defiantly forged its own path with industrial design across the board. Its products are largely interesting and innovative &#8212; something not every hardware manufacturer can [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">These days, the path of least resistance in laptop design is straight-up knocking off the MacBook. We’ve certainly seen our share of egregious cases over the years. Microsoft, however, has defiantly forged its own path with industrial design across the board. Its products are largely interesting and innovative &#8212; something not every hardware manufacturer can say these days.</p>
<p>The company doesn’t always get it right. It swung for the fences with the Surface Duo, for example. While certainly innovative, the product came up short in enough categories that made it extremely hard to recommend. The Surface Laptop, on the other hand, while not the most groundbreaking product in the line, has pretty consistently been one of the best, marrying a Windows-ready touchscreen with a more standardized notebook design.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tdzh4iZk1T"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/microsofts-latest-surface-laptop-goes-on-sale-this-week-starting-at-999/">Microsoft’s latest Surface Laptop goes on sale this week, starting at $999</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Microsoft’s latest Surface Laptop goes on sale this week, starting at $999&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/microsofts-latest-surface-laptop-goes-on-sale-this-week-starting-at-999/embed/#?secret=tdzh4iZk1T" data-secret="tdzh4iZk1T" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The last few models have been solid, and this year’s &#8212; perhaps predictably &#8212; doesn’t present a big change. The big upgrades after about a year and a half are new chips (your choice of AMD Ryzen or an Intel Core i5 or i7) and enhanced battery life that offers a beefy additional 8.5 hours. Essentially, it&#8217;s the sort of thing you&#8217;d expect &#8212; or hope for &#8212; from a regular system refresh.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2156064" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2156064" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2156064" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9264.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9264.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9264.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9264.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9264.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9264.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9264.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9264.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9264.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2156064" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>The design language remains largely unchanged. The Surface Laptop is nothing if not unique on that front, with its tapered sides and felt-covered palm rests. The material has a nice feel to it &#8212; one that bests just straight-up metal on a cold day, though I’ve already noticed a bit of wear after some light use.</p>
<p>The keyboard remains on the soft side, with a surprising amount of give to it. Not the best keyboard I’ve seen on a laptop, but certainly not the worst (who can forget that rough run for Apple?), and like anything else, it takes a bit of getting used to.</p>
<p>You’d think I’d have learned my lesson by now. Maybe it’s the fact that Microsoft’s Surface Laptops keep coming out when the weather is nice that I always feel inclined to take them outside. But jeez is that display reflective. Almost distractingly so. Plenty of laptop screens are glossy, of course, but Microsoft’s really leaned in here, to the point I wouldn’t recommend using it in any sort of sunshine &#8212; even at full brightness, the screen can’t counteract that reflection.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2156069" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2156069" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2156069" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9258.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9258.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9258.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9258.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9258.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9258.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9258.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9258.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/CMC_9258.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2156069" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>When you can see it, the display looks great. Microsoft sent along the smaller of the two. At 13.5-inches, the screen clocks in at 2256 x 1504 at 201 ppi (you get the same pixel density on the 15-inch version, as well). Ours was the new Ice Blue color. It’s subtle, though. Honestly, I read it more as a silver/gray. The speakers sound great, and the webcam is just fine, but it’s safe to say it’s probably time to upgrade to 1080p across the board as teleconferencing remains front of mind.</p>
<p>The 13.5-inch system starts at $1,000, which gets you 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage, along with the AMD Ryzen 5 4680U process. As configured, our system runs $1,700, which doubles the RAM and storage and swaps the AMD in for an Intel Core i7. Another $600 will double the RAM and storage yet again (same processor). Geekbench scored the processor at a solid 1378 on single-core and 4876 on multi-core. Performance was solid throughout &#8212; though after spending a fair amount of time using Apple’s M1, it’s clear that Intel has its work cut out for it.</p>
<p>[gallery ids="2156063,2156069,2156068,2156067,2156066,2156064,2156062,2156061,2156060"]</p>
<p>Microsoft is still hanging onto its magnetic proprietary charging port here. I know it still has its diehard fans, but I’d much prefer to see the company go with something more universal, like adding another USB-C port &#8212; though that impacts the system’s compatibility with a slew of different Surface accessories. Around the other side you get USB-A, USB-C and a headphone jack. It’s a nice mix, but more ports would certainly be a step up.</p>
<p>I was fairly disappointed with the various corners the company cut on the Surface Laptop Go last year. Of course, the entry-level 13.5-inch Laptop is $300 more than the 12-inch Laptop Go. But if you’re looking to do more than just the basics, this is probably is a wise investment.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tAdSbGycPS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/14/microsoft-reverse-engineers-a-budget-computer-with-the-surface-laptop-go/">Microsoft Surface Laptop Go review: reverse-engineering a budget computer</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Microsoft Surface Laptop Go review: reverse-engineering a budget computer&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/14/microsoft-reverse-engineers-a-budget-computer-with-the-surface-laptop-go/embed/#?secret=tAdSbGycPS" data-secret="tAdSbGycPS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/23/taking-microsofts-surface-laptop-4-for-a-spin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156149</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Air India passenger data breach reveals SITA hack worse than first thought</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/23/air-india-passenger-data-breach-reveals-sita-hack-worse-than-first-thought/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/23/air-india-passenger-data-breach-reveals-sita-hack-worse-than-first-thought/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 17:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BigBasket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sita]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156214</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Three months after air transport data giant SITA reported a data breach, we are still learning about the damage. Air India said this week that personal data of about 4.5 million passengers had been compromised following the incident at SITA, Indian flag carrier airline’s data processor. The stolen information included  passengers’ name, credit card details, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Three months after air transport data giant SITA <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/sita-airline-passenger-breach/">reported a data breach</a>, we are still learning about the damage.</p>
<p>Air India said this week that personal data of about 4.5 million passengers had been compromised following the incident at SITA, Indian flag carrier airline’s data processor. The stolen information included  passengers’ name, credit card details, date of birth, contact information, passport information, ticket information, Star Alliance and Air India frequent flyer data, Air India <a href="http://www.airindia.in/images/pdf/Data-Breach-Notification.pdf">said in a statement</a> (PDF).</p>
<p>CVV/CVC data of credit cards were not held by SITA, said Air India as it urged passengers to change passwords “wherever applicable to ensure safety of their personal data.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The attack compromised data of passengers who had registered with the Indian airline over the past decade, between August 26, 2011 and February 3, 2021, Air India said in a statement.</p>
<p>The revelation comes months after SITA said it had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/sita-airline-passenger-breach/">suffered a data breach</a> that involved passenger data. At the time, SITA said it had notified several airlines &#8212; Malaysia Airlines, Finnair, Singapore Airlines, Jeju Air, Cathay Pacific, Air New Zealand, and Lufthansa &#8212; of the breach.</p>
<p>The Geneva, Switzerland-headquartered firm &#8212; which is said to serve 90% of the world’s airlines &#8212; had declined to reveal the specific data that had been compromised at the time of disclosure in early March, citing an investigation &#8212; which is still ongoing.</p>
<p>Air India said that it was first notified about the cyber attack by SITA on February 25, but the nature of the data was only provided to it on March 25 and April 5.</p>
<p>The struggling Indian airline, which has been surviving on taxpayer’s money, claimed that it had investigated the security incident, secured the compromised servers, engaged with unnamed external specialists, notified the credit card issuers, and had reset passwords of its frequent flyer program.</p>
<p>Air India is the latest Indian firm to disclose a data breach in recent quarters. Payments giant MobiKwik said in late March that it was investigating claims of a data breach that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/mobikwik-investigating-data-breach-after-100m-user-records-found-online/">allegedly exposed private information of nearly 100 million users</a>.</p>
<p>Alleged records of nearly 20 million BigBasket (a top grocery delivery startup in India that is now owned by local conglomerate Tata) customers <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/25/hacker-publishes-alleged-records-of-20-million-bigbasket-users/">leaked on the dark web</a> for anyone to download in late April. A security lapse at Indian telecom giant Jio Platforms <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/02/jio-coronavirus-security-lapse/">exposed results of some users</a> who had used its tool to check their coronavirus symptoms. Indian state <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/india-west-bengal-health-covid-security/">West Bengal</a> and giant blood test firm Dr Lal PathLabs <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/dr-lal-pathlabs-exposed-patient-lab-data/">suffered similar breaches</a>. Air India&#8217;s peer, Spicejet, also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/30/spicejet-breach-millions-passengers/">confirmed a data breach last year</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Read more:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/mobikwik-investigating-data-breach-after-100m-user-records-found-online/">MobiKwik investigating data breach after 100M user records found online</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/30/spicejet-breach-millions-passengers/">Breach at Indian airline SpiceJet affects 1.2 million passengers</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/dr-lal-pathlabs-exposed-patient-lab-data/">Dr Lal PathLabs, one of India’s largest blood test labs, exposed patient data</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/02/jio-coronavirus-security-lapse/">Security lapse at India’s Jio exposed coronavirus symptom checker results</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/25/hacker-publishes-alleged-records-of-20-million-bigbasket-users/">Alleged records of 20 million BigBasket users published online</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/23/air-india-passenger-data-breach-reveals-sita-hack-worse-than-first-thought/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156214</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Billboards? Nah, just buy a media company instead</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/22/billboards-nah-just-buy-a-media-company-instead/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/22/billboards-nah-just-buy-a-media-company-instead/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 18:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Startups used to be obsessed with billboards. It was the first thing I noticed when I moved to San Francisco: venture-backed companies including Eaze, Airbnb, and notoriously, Brex, would post large billboard advertisements all over the city to grab attention and eyeballs. When I dug into it more, I learned this type of old school, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Startups used to be obsessed with billboards. It was the first thing I noticed when I moved to San Francisco: venture-backed companies including Eaze, Airbnb, and notoriously, Brex, would post large billboard advertisements all over the city to grab attention and eyeballs. When I dug into it more, I learned this type of old school, outdoor advertising was a response to the increasingly crowded online channels, such as Facebook and Instagram advertisements.</p>
<p>Well, folks, years later, we have a new response to crowded marketing channels: Ditch the billboards and just buy a media company instead. There has been a recent push for startups and venture capital firms to acquire or create media companies, which I’d argue is them finding a creative way to position content marketing. This past week, Axios discovered that <a href="https://www.axios.com/coinbase-media-editor-crypto-682b8dca-11dd-4efc-93ef-ecb50ecdda35.html?utm_campaign=organic&amp;utm_medium=socialshare&amp;utm_source=twitter">Coinbase is launching a media operation</a> about cryptocurrency. At the same time, Clubhouse wants to <a href="https://twitter.com/lexinisita/status/1395091872578686980">hire freelance writers</a>, while its biggest lead investor to-date, Andreessen Horowitz, has ambitions to <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/andreessen-horowitz-looks-to-launch-opinion-publication-as-its-media-ambition-grows">open up an opinion desk.</a> Other news bits like The Skimm exploring a potential sale and Hubspot acquiring the Hustle also add to the narrative of broader media ambitions across tech.</p>
<p>We got into <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/21/linkedin-is-the-reason-apple-made-the-m1-chip/?tpcc=ECTW2020">the impact of a venture-backed media push</a> on Equity, our award-winning (!) podcast, this week. My take, as you can tell by this introduction, is that it’s not a rush to compete with journalism. It’s a rush to compete with a noisy world, and rebrand advertisements to media operations.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>I could talk about journalism and tech and media forever, but that is all on that topic today. In the rest of this newsletter, we’ll get into new IPOs, startups providing upfront revenue to other startups and tactical advice on building versus buying a tech stack. As always, you can find me podcasting <a href="https://twitter.com/EquityPod">@Equitypod</a> and tweeting at <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">@nmasc_</a>.</p>
<h2>IP(Oats)</h2>
<p>Oatly went public this week, and there entirely weren’t enough jokes or puns about it. (<a href="https://twitter.com/sarthakgh/status/1395514832154243072">Although I did appreciate this one</a>). My complaint aside, <strong>i</strong>t’s been a busy week for the public markets.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know:</strong> Marqueta, which is focused on card issuing and payments tech, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/inside-marqetas-fascinating-fintech-ipo/">has a fascinating S-1 filing</a> — including what I’d say it’s a Peloton-Affirm relationship with Square. Alex dug into the numbers and told you what to think about its filing in The Exchange.</p>
<p><em>And a splash of oat milk please:</em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/can-squarespace-dodge-the-direct-listing-value-trap/">Can Squarespace dodge the direct listing value trap?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/fast-growth-pushes-an-unprofitable-no-code-startup-into-the-public-markets-inside-monday-coms-ipo-filing/">Fast growth pushes an unprofitable no-code startup into the public markets: Inside Monday.com’s IPO filing</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/walkme-is-going-public-lets-stroll-through-its-numbers/">WalkMe is going public: Let’s stroll through its numbers</a></li>
</ul>
<p><div id="attachment_1879200" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1879200" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1879200 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-1141468846.jpg?w=680" alt="GettyImages 1141468846" width="680" height="510" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-1141468846.jpg 5067w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-1141468846.jpg?resize=150,112 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-1141468846.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-1141468846.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-1141468846.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-1141468846.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-1141468846.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-1141468846.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1879200" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Getty Images / Eugene Mymrin</p></div></p>
<h2>Build or buy?</h2>
<p>Telemedicine needs to prepare for a post-pandemic world, which comes with its own upfront costs, risks, and, as Marcela points out, opportunities. Around $3.1 billion in funding flowed into the sector in 2020 — about three times what we saw in 2019, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/telemedicine-startups-are-positioning-themselves-for-a-post-pandemic-world/">according to her latest story.</a> In order to get money and impact out, startups have some work to do.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know: </strong>It’s time for you to read <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/telemedicine-startups-are-positioning-themselves-for-a-post-pandemic-world/">a marketmap about telemedicine</a>, from its current state, to different tensions, to affordability and the out-of-pocket dynamics that no one talks about.</p>
<p><em>And here’s some dessert to finish your healthy meal:</em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/should-startups-build-or-buy-telehealth-infrastructure/">Should startups build or buy telehealth infrastructure</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/ro-acquires-modern-fertility-in-a-reportedly-225-million-deal/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Ro acquires modern fertility in a reportedly $225 million deal </a></li>
</ul>
<p><div id="attachment_2085075" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2085075" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2085075" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-124591556.jpg?w=680" alt="Close-up of spade shovel being used to dig a hole in soil" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-124591556.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-124591556.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-124591556.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-124591556.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-124591556.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-124591556.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2085075" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> MoMorad / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<h2>Pipe’s get burst</h2>
<p>Everyone is paying attention to Pipe, which just raised $250 million at a $2 billion valuation. As Mary Ann puts it, the company is claiming to be the Nasdaq for revenue, and it gives SaaS companies a way to get their revenue upfront by “pairing them with investors on a marketplace who will pay a discounted rate for the annual value of those contracts.”</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know:</strong> That wasn’t the only check that went into startups providing other startups with upfront revenue this week. Uncapped, which is the European equivalent of Pipe, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/uncapped-which-provides-upfront-revenue-to-digital-companies-raises-80m-in-funding/">raised $80 million in funding</a>. Put differently, in less than 24 hours, TechCrunch reported that nearly $330 million went into backing the concept of startups providing other startups with upfront revenue.</p>
<p><em>Other dollar signs to pay attention to:</em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/bvc_fund_nine/">Bain Capital Ventures raised $1.3 billion to fund young startups, and young VC firms, too</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/16/gojek-and-tokopedia-merge-to-form-goto-group/">Gojek and Tokopedia merge to form GoTo Group</a></li>
</ul>
<p><div id="attachment_2095186" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2095186" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2095186" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1186698642.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="454" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1186698642.jpg 2120w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1186698642.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1186698642.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1186698642.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1186698642.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1186698642.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1186698642.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1186698642.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2095186" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> MirageC / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<h2>Around TC</h2>
<p>TechCrunch is looking for 20 early-stage companies to feature in Startup Battlefield at TC Disrupt 2021 this year. Startups receive a feature article on TechCrunch.com, intensive pitch training from the TC team, the chance to win $100,000 in equity free prize money, and the attention of thousands of global press and investors.</p>
<p>So, what are you waiting for?<a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/zM4H0xNn"> Apply by May 27!</a></p>
<h2>Across the week</h2>
<h3>Seen on TechCrunch</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/16/crypto-and-blockchain-must-accept-they-have-a-problem-then-lead-in-sustainability/">Crypto and blockchain must accept they have a problem, then lead in sustainability</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/what-has-four-wheels-and-loses-money/">What has four wheels and loses money?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/twitter-opens-account-verification-applications-to-the-public-under-new-guidelines/">Twitter launches account verification applications</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/everything-google-announced-at-i-o-today/">Everything Google announced at I/O today</a></li>
</ul>
<h3>Seen on Extra Crunch</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/mapping-out-one-edtech-companys-200m-bet-on-lifelong-learning/">Mapping out one edtech company’s $200M bet on lifelong learning</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/for-companies-that-use-ml-labeled-data-is-the-key-differentiator/">For companies that use ML, labeled data is the key differentiator</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/the-battle-for-voice-recognition-inside-vehicles-is-heating-up/">The battle for voice recognition inside vehicles is heating up</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/expensify-ec1-culture/">How Expensify got to $100M in revenue by hiring ‘stem cells’ and not ‘cogs in a wheel’</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Thanks for reading! Do something that requires zero technology this week. After, of course, you share this newsletter with at least two people.</p>
<p>Always,</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">N</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/22/billboards-nah-just-buy-a-media-company-instead/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155971</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Watching startups eat markets is good fun</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/22/2156073/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/22/2156073/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 17:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The TechCrunch Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156073</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter for your weekend enjoyment.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome back to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter. It’s broadly based on </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/the-exchange/"><em>the daily column that appears on Extra Crunch</em></a><em>, but free, and made for your weekend reading. </em><em>Want it in your inbox every Saturday? Sign up </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters"><em>here</em></a><em>.</em></p>
<p><em>Ready? Let’s talk money, startups and spicy IPO rumors.</em></p>
<p>The huge sale of Utah-based startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/brex-ramp-tout-their-view-of-the-future-as-divvy-is-said-to-consider-a-sale-to-bill-com/">Divvy to Bill.com</a> is still bouncing around my head this week, not only because the $2.5 billion exit was huge for both the company and its local scene, but also because its target market is exciting to watch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Divvy competes in what we call the corporate spend market with a few other unicorns, including Ramp and Brex. Now with Divvy taken off the table, the pair of competitors are differentiating in a few ways that matter.</p>
<p>And Brex is getting back on its billboard game.</p>
<p>This week Brex <a href="https://www.brex.com/posts/integrated-marketing/">announced</a> that it is rolling out IRL advertising in a few American cities. Residents of San Francisco back when Brex was a baby will recall how the startup plastered its brand all over the city. Essentially, it was a <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/brex-corporate-card-for-startups-covers-san-francisco-with-billboards-2018-8">cheap way</a> to get a lot of impressions.</p>
<p>Now the startup is taking the strategy to Houston and Miami and D.C. Why? The Exchange caught up with Brex CEO <a href="https://twitter.com/hdubugras">Henrique Dubugras</a> this week to chat about the matter. Per the executive, his company has two goals for its renewed meatspace marketing push. First, Brex wants to talk up its software game over its initial branding as a corporate card for startups. And, second, it wants business owners to know that it works with all types of companies now, not merely those with Sand Hill Road on speed dial.</p>
<p>The push to get the Brex name out in markets less known for their startup activity than overall business climate makes sense, if the unicorn wants to attract more nonstartup customers. But it’s the software element of its efforts that unsurprisingly caught our attention.</p>
<p>That’s because Brex recently rolled out Brex Premium, a package of software services that it charges around $600 per year for. Brex and rivals like Ramp and Divvy have spent lots of energy and money in recent quarters building out increasingly sophisticated software around their traditional corporate card products. The result thus far are codebases more and more able to supplant other pieces of enterprise software, like expense software.</p>
<p>But as Brex looks to double down via an advertising push on its decision to charge for Brex Premium &#8212; which Dubugras says is performing better than his company had initially anticipated &#8212; competitor Ramp is pushing its free software as an edge.</p>
<p>Ramp CEO and co-founder <a href="https://twitter.com/eglyman">Eric Glyman</a> pointed The Exchange to his company’s refreshed pricing page, which <a href="https://ramp.com/pricing">highlights</a> its zero-cost software. And, he said in an email, the new page was “powering the fastest growth month we’ve ever had.”</p>
<p>Broadly, what we’re seeing with Ramp and Brex and Divvy &#8212; along with Airbase and others that also compete in the space &#8212; is a cohort of startups attacking an aged corporate issue with more nimble, lower-cost products. And proving while doing so that there was huge untapped demand for something different and better. The various players competing for the startup crown in the corporate spend world wouldn’t all be growing as rapidly as they are if that weren’t the case.</p>
<p>If you want more, here’s<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/why-did-bill-com-pay-2-5b-for-divvy/"> our dig into the Divvy-Bill.com deal</a>.</p>
<h2>More from startup-land</h2>
<p>The Exchange was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/21/as-zynga-impresses-rival-mobile-gaming-shop-jam-city-looks-to-list-via-spac/">lathered up</a> in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/industrial-automation-startup-bright-machines-hauls-in-435m-by-going-public-via-spac/">SPACs this week</a>, which means that we missed a host of interesting news that we otherwise would have loved to poke into. For example, here are some very neat venture rounds that it would have been fun to dig into more deeply:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>ProducePay raised a $43M Series C:</strong> LA-based <a href="https://producepay.com/">ProducePay</a> helps <em>food growers</em> access capital, software and market data, linking them to <em>food demanders (importers, etc.)</em>. Per its website, ProducePay funded a <a href="https://www.britannica.com/place/Bajio">Bajío, Mexico</a>-based asparagus growing operation to the tune of a half million dollars to hire labor and invest in its growing operation. Repayment, again per the company, starts when product ships.</li>
<li>Farming is hard, fickle, expensive and not always aligned with traditional banking requirements. Throw in an increasingly global production/consumption food network, and you can see why G2VP and IFC co-led the round.</li>
<li>Oh, and The Exchange learned that ProducePay’s reported 2020 doubling was measured in GAAP revenue terms. The startup’s gross margins “grew by over 75% from 2019 to 2020, thanks to improved underwriting policies and a more attractive cost of funds as volume scaled,” per its PR team. That’s super cool.</li>
</ul>
<p>Another neat company that raised this week was <a href="https://www.panther.co/">Panther</a>, which put together a $2.5 million round. Panther wants to help companies hire in 160 different countries. Our read of the company and its round is that, as more companies go remote-first, this sort of service is going to become a must-have. Gusto also competes in the market, so it should be an active one to watch from both VC <em>and</em> M&amp;A perspectives.</p>
<p>Panther is based in Florida, and raised funds from, per its release, “Tribe Capital, Eric Ries, Naval Ravikant and Carta Ventures.”</p>
<p>One more round: <a href="https://www.lancebank.co/">Lance</a>, a freelancer-focused neobank, raised $2.8 million this week. The round was led by, per the company, “Barclays, BDMI, Great Oaks Capital, Imagination Capital, Techstars, DFJ Frontier, New York Venture Partners” along with some angels.</p>
<p>Now that the fintech world has created Chime and other broad-remit neobanks, it’s not surprising to see more targeted efforts get put together. And Lance CEO Oona Rokyta is betting that the freelance world is set to grow further. Given how the labor market has evolved in the last few years, I’d hazard she’s making an intelligent bet.</p>
<p>To close out today, a quick note on <a href="https://alpaca.markets/">Alpaca</a>. It’s a startup that TechCrunch has dug into <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/15/alpaca-raises-10m-series-a-for-its-api-powered-equities-trading-service/">here</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/08/alpaca-stock-trading-api/">there</a>, as it fits into both our general focus on API-delivered services (on-demand pricing is hot), and it exists in the consumer fintech world (powering other companies’ equities trading services). We caught up with CEO Yoshi Yokokawa this week to chat about what’s been going on at his company since we last tracked its growth rates.</p>
<p>After all, whatever we can learn about the world of consumer investing &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/robinhoods-epic-q1-growth-explains-its-fundraising-boom/">and Robinhood told us quite a lot this week</a> &#8212; is useful given the somewhat global savings/investing boom that we’ve seen in the last year or so.</p>
<p>Per Yokokawa, Alpaca has global plans, including rolling out with new partners on a few continents in the coming months. The company is handling 1,000 new accounts daily outside the United States, which Yokokawa expects to rise sharply in the coming months. And the company recently built out a broker API to make onboarding users simpler for its partners.</p>
<p>Sounds like growth to us. More when we can milk it out of, er, the alpaca.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/22/2156073/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156073</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
