<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 14:34:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Phantom Space acquires StratSpace in pursuit of becoming a turnkey space service</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/phantom-space-acquires-stratspace-in-pursuit-of-becoming-a-turnkey-space-service/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/phantom-space-acquires-stratspace-in-pursuit-of-becoming-a-turnkey-space-service/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 14:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aerospace]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156715</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Even as 2021 shapes up to see a record number of launches, demand is growing fast. Companies like Phantom Space Corporation aim to fill it with mass manufacturing techniques never yet seen in the space industry. Now the company has acquired StratSpace, a satellite program designer and manager, Phantom Space announced Tuesday. It&#8217;s a critical [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Even as 2021 shapes up to see a record number of launches, demand is growing fast. Companies like <a href="https://phantomspace.com/">Phantom Space Corporation</a> aim to fill it with mass manufacturing techniques never yet seen in the space industry. Now the company has acquired StratSpace, a satellite program designer and manager, Phantom Space announced Tuesday. It&#8217;s a critical step towards building out a turnkey space transportation and manufacturing service, Phantom Space co-founder Michal Prywata told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>“[StratSpace] has all the know-how, all the tools, the satellite structures, communication systems that can make a spacecraft operate,” he explained. “Which is very critical for us, because we want to be one of the first companies that covers gives that full spectrum of service from start to finish.” The company declined to disclose the terms of the acquisition.</p>
<p>Phantom Space’s bet is that combining a mass rocket manufacturing strategy with acquisitions that position it as a ‘one-stop-shop’ will help bring down the cost of space access. Prywata said the company’s aiming to charge $4 million for a dedicated launch that would bring up to 450 kilograms to low Earth orbit.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“We’re talking about hundreds to potentially thousands a year,” Prywata said, referring to the number of launches the company eventually hopes to achieve. “As of right now, the market certainly supports hundreds of launches a year.”</p>
<p>They&#8217;re big aspirations for a company that has not yet begun even flight testing a rocket model. Phantom Space said it is outsourcing many components, like the engine and avionics system, that can take years to develop, to get it there. For other components and services, it&#8217;s looking to use an acquisition strategy.</p>
<p>“That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re looking at acquisitions pretty aggressively because we feel there&#8217;s an opportunity now to start integrating these types of technologies and companies within one umbrella and create this overall infrastructure of a company that can take ideas and bring them to space,” he said. That includes building satellites, integration, launch, and data communication. “We&#8217;re trying to cover that full spectrum, where we can help other companies that have some application that they want to launch into space, we can help them get there, because we have all these specific pieces that can make it all happen.”</p>
<p>Phantom Space is aiming to launch its two-stage Daytona rocket for the first time in the first quarter of 2023, with stage-level testing commencing in early 2022. Daytona, the company&#8217;s &#8220;workhorse&#8221; launch vehicle, comes in at 61 feet in height and can carry 450 kilograms to LEO on eight engines. While the Daytona is totally expendable, the company has plans to reuse its larger Laguna rocket model.</p>
<p>The company has signed a right of entry for Space Launch Complex 5 at Vandenberg Space Force Base in California, which will likely be the location of its first launches. It also just signed an agreement with the Pacific Spaceport Complex in Alaska, where Astra (another company looking toward mass rocket manufacturing) completes its launches, and it’s planning on eventually having launch agreements with Cape Canaveral Spaceport in Florida.</p>
<p>But even if flight testing goes smoothly, reaching hundreds or even thousands of launches per year is still currently impossible given the small number of spaceports in the country.</p>
<p>“That said, having launch capability just in the US isn&#8217;t enough, because you won&#8217;t be able to get to hundreds a year, just out of those three sites,” Prywata said. So, the company is also looking at a site in northern Sweden, northern Australia, and Brazil. It’s also in talks with the U.S. Federal Aviation Administration to license spaceports that are restricted to horizontal launches only to allow for vertical launch.</p>
<p>Phantom Space&#8217;s acquisition of StratSpace it’s only going to be the first of many, Prywata said. “We’re still small so we’re trying to grow aggressively,” he said. “So we’re starting with these smaller acquisitions but very key acquisitions to enable our overall strategy.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/phantom-space-acquires-stratspace-in-pursuit-of-becoming-a-turnkey-space-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156715</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>JD.com, Meituan and Neolix to test autonomous deliveries on Beijing public roads</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/meituan-jd-com-and-neolix-begin-autonomous-deliveries-in-beijing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/meituan-jd-com-and-neolix-begin-autonomous-deliveries-in-beijing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 14:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JD.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[li auto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meituan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[take out]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156951</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[People in a Beijing suburb will begin to see autonomous delivery mini-vans across their neighborhood, moving cautiously alongside human delivery riders belting down the streets. Beijing has greenlighted JD.com, Meituan, and Neolix to trial self-driving delivery vehicles on designated public roads in the Yizhuang Development Area, an economic and technological growth pilot initiated by the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">People in a Beijing suburb will begin to see autonomous delivery mini-vans across their neighborhood, moving cautiously alongside human delivery riders belting down the streets.</p>
<p>Beijing has greenlighted JD.com, Meituan, and Neolix to trial self-driving delivery vehicles on designated public roads in the Yizhuang Development Area, an economic and technological growth pilot initiated by the municipal government of the capital city, according to an announcement made by local authorities at a mobility conference on Tuesday. Yizhuang has aggressively rolled out 5G coverage in part to<a href="http://www.china.org.cn/china/2019-08/30/content_75155825.htm"> prepare the infrastructure for autonomous driving ventures</a>.</p>
<p>All three companies are using dainty box-on-wheels vehicles similar to those of Nuro to shuffle goods around. Three-year-old Neolix, backed by Chinese electric vehicle startup Li Auto, focuses on making self-driving vehicles for retail, surveillance and other city services, while both JD.com and Meituan are tech heavyweights that find unmanned delivery increasingly important to their existing core business.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2157082" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2157082" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2157082 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/46691621951315_.pic_hd.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/46691621951315_.pic_hd.jpg 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/46691621951315_.pic_hd.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/46691621951315_.pic_hd.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/46691621951315_.pic_hd.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/46691621951315_.pic_hd.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/46691621951315_.pic_hd.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2157082" class="wp-caption-text">Meituan&#8217;s self-driving delivery vehicle / Photo: Meituan via WeChat</p></div></p>
<p>Online retailer JD.com hires its own in-house delivery staff while Meituan relies on a national network of riders to bring restaurant takeout to customers. Both have been working on autonomous driving technologies internally in recent years and are also testing small fleets of delivery drones in China.</p>
<p>Neolix will place 150 delivery robots on Beijing roads by June. JD.com declined to disclose its deployment number. Meituan can&#8217;t be immediately reached for comment.</p>
<p>At the Tuesday event, authorities from the Beijing pilot zone also <a href="http://www.chinanews.com/cj/2021/05-25/9485293.shtml">laid out</a> rules for operating zero-occupant delivery vehicles in the area. The robots are categorized as &#8220;non-motor vehicles,&#8221; which suggests they will be moving next to bicycles and electric scooters instead of faster-moving cars. Road conditions in Chinese cities are often much more complicated than in the United States, even on sidewalks and bike lanes thanks to unpredictable pedestrians, unleashed pets, and reckless scooter riders.</p>
<p>Importantly, the rules also stipulate that the robots need to have safety drivers &#8220;on the spot and remotely.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2157081" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2157081" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2157081 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/46681621951252_.pic_hd.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/46681621951252_.pic_hd.jpg 1080w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/46681621951252_.pic_hd.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/46681621951252_.pic_hd.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/46681621951252_.pic_hd.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/46681621951252_.pic_hd.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/46681621951252_.pic_hd.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2157081" class="wp-caption-text">Neolix&#8217;s delivery robot / Photo: Neolix via WeChat</p></div></p>
<p class="p1">JD.com says its technology allows every remote safety driver to monitor up to 50 operating delivery robots simultaneously. Its vehicles will carry packages from logistics centers and supermarkets to nearby office buildings, residential complexes and school campuses. Customers will then fetch their order directly from the van using a pick-up code sent to them through a text message ahead of time.</p>
<p>Neolix&#8217;s vehicles in the pilot area, in comparison, act more like mobile vending machines peddling snacks and lunchboxes to workers around office complexes. Users can place their order on a little screen attached to the robot, pay by a QR code and get their warm bento or ice cream instantaneously.</p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/meituan-jd-com-and-neolix-begin-autonomous-deliveries-in-beijing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156951</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dogs of Lordstown</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/dogs-of-lordstown/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/dogs-of-lordstown/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 14:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Mobility Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lordstown Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPACs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156999</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lordstown is not the only SPAC that is going to see some daylight between its pitch and its performance. But it's a pretty stark reminder that SPAC decks are sales pitches, not promises.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The lackluster performance of shares in companies that have combined with special purpose acquisition companies (SPACs) in recent quarters took another hit yesterday when Lordstown Motors reported its first-quarter results.</p>
<p>Lordstown, part of a wave of electric-vehicle companies that raised capital and went public via SPACs, announced lower-than-expected 2021 vehicle production, higher capital expenditures (capex) for the year, and the need to raise more capital. For holders of its equity, the news was a disappointment, as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/lordstown-motors-slashes-production-forecast-for-its-electric-pickup/">TechCrunch explored after the results dropped</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money.  </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>Shares of Lordstown are down 14% in pre-market trading after falling in after-hours trading yesterday evening.</p>
<p>But there&#8217;s more to the Lordstown mess than merely a single bad quarter. What the company reported is somewhat contradicted by its SPAC deck, a document that every startup combining with a blank-check company releases. They are often cheery and full of good news. With just a little capital, the company in question is going to scale rapidly in the coming years, with improving profitability to boot.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1995210" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Then the deal is sold, capital is raised, entities combine, and the startup in question becomes public, with earnings calls commencing on a quarterly cadence. That&#8217;s where the rubber meets the road.</p>
<p>Lordstown&#8217;s earnings mess and the resulting dissonance with its own predictions are notable on their own, but they also point to what could be <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/for-startup-leaders-spacs-have-lost-their-allure-11621774800?mod=djemalertNEWS">shifting sentiment regarding SPAC combinations</a>. Returns <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/c7c0f11c-b678-491d-9173-fe49ea29b4b8">are lackluster</a>, the SEC is <a href="https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/spacs-ipos-liability-risk-under-securities-laws">worried about too-rosy forecasts</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/us-congress-hold-hearing-spacs-ramping-up-scrutiny-2021-05-21/">Congress is looking into the boom</a>.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re taking a look into Lordstown&#8217;s results this morning, but don&#8217;t think that we&#8217;re only singling out one company; others fit the bill, and more will in time.</p>
<h2>Whoops<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/dogs-of-lordstown/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156999</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taipei-based computer vision startup eYs3D gets $7M Series A</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/taipei-based-computer-vision-startup-eys3d-gets-7m-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/taipei-based-computer-vision-startup-eys3d-gets-7m-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 14:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3d sensor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computer Vision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eYs3D]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[integrated circuits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taiwan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156939</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[eYs3D Microelectronics, a fabless design house that focuses on end-to-end software and hardware systems for computer vision technology, has raised a $7 million Series A. Participants included ARM IoT Capital, WI Harper and Marubun Corporation, who will each serve as strategic investors. Based in Taipei, Taiwan, eYs3D was spun out of Etron, a fabless IC [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.eys3d.com/">eYs3D Microelectronics</a>, a fabless design house that focuses on end-to-end software and hardware systems for computer vision technology, has raised a $7 million Series A. Participants included ARM IoT Capital, WI Harper and Marubun Corporation, who will each serve as strategic investors.</p>
<p>Based in Taipei, Taiwan, eYs3D was spun out of <a href="http://www.etron.com/en/aboutus/company.php">Etron</a>, a fabless IC and system-in-package (SiP) design firm, in 2016. It will use its new funding to build its embedded chip business in new markets. The company’s technology, including integrated circuits, 3D sensors, camera modules and AI-based software, have a wide range of applications, such as robotics, touchless controls, autonomous vehicles and smart retail. eYs3D’s products have been used in the Facebook Oculus Rift S and Valve Index virtual reality headsets, and Techman Robots.</p>
<p>ARM, the microprocessor company, will integrate eYs3D’s chips into its CPU and NPUs. WI Harper, a cross-border investment firm with offices in Taipei, Beijing and San Francisco, will give eYs3D access to its international network of industrial partners. Marubun Corporation, a Japan-based company that distributes semiconductors and other electronic components, will open new distribution channels for eYs3D.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In a press statement, ARM IoT Capital chairman Peter Hsieh said, “As we look to the future, enhanced computer vision support plays a key role in ARM’s AI architecture and deployment. eYs3D’s innovative 3D computer vision capability can offer the market major benefits, and we are pleased to partner with the company and invest in the creation of more AI-capable vision processors.”</p>
<p>The new funding will also be used to expand eYs3D’s product development and launch a series of 3D computer vision modules. It will also work with new business partners to expand its platform and hire more talent.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YWVUOi3ck3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/computer-vision-software-has-the-potential-to-reinvent-the-way-cities-move/">Computer vision software has the potential to reinvent the way cities move</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Computer vision software has the potential to reinvent the way cities move&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/computer-vision-software-has-the-potential-to-reinvent-the-way-cities-move/embed/#?secret=YWVUOi3ck3" data-secret="YWVUOi3ck3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>eYs3D’s chief strategy officer James Wang told TechCrunch that the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-chip-shortage-is-bad-taiwans-drought-threatens-to-make-it-worse-11618565400">global chip shortage and Taiwan’s drought</a> haven’t significantly impacted the company’s business or production plans, because it works with Etron as its integrated circuits manufacturing service.</p>
<p>“Etron Technology is one of the major accounts for the Taiwanese foundry sector and has strong relationships with the foundries, so eYs3D can receive products for its customers as required,” he said. “Meanwhile, eYs3D works closly with its major customers to schedule a just-in-time supply chain for their production pipelines.”</p>
<p>The company’s systems combine silicon design and algorithms to manage information collected from different sensor sources, including thermal, 3D and neural network perception. Its technology is capable of supporting visual simultaneous location and mapping (vSLAM), object feature depth recognition, and gesture-based commands.</p>
<p>Yang said eYs3D can provide end-to-end services, from integrated circuit design to ready-to-use products, and works closely with clients to determine what they need. For example, it offered its chip solution to an autonomous robot company for obstacle avoidance and people-tracing features.</p>
<p>“Since their expertise is in robotic motor controls and mechanicals, they needed a more complete solution for a design module for 3D sensing, as well as object and people recognition. We provided them with one of our 3D depth camera solutions and SDK along with middleware algorithm samples for their validation,” said Yang. “The customer took our design package and seamlessly integrated our 3D depth camera solution for proof-of-concept within a short period of time. Next, we helped them to retrofit the camera design to fit in their robot body prior to commercialization of the robot.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JsjTf21dYS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/computer-vision-inches-towards-common-sense-with-facebooks-latest-research/">Computer vision inches toward &#8216;common sense&#8217; with Facebook&#8217;s latest research</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Computer vision inches toward &#8216;common sense&#8217; with Facebook&#8217;s latest research&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/computer-vision-inches-towards-common-sense-with-facebooks-latest-research/embed/#?secret=JsjTf21dYS" data-secret="JsjTf21dYS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/taipei-based-computer-vision-startup-eys3d-gets-7m-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156939</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twilio invests in adaptive communications platform Hyro</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/twilio-invests-in-adaptive-communications-platform-hyro/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/twilio-invests-in-adaptive-communications-platform-hyro/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 14:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyro]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156996</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hyro, formerly Airbud, is today announcing the close of a $10.5 million Series A financing round led by Spero Ventures, with participation from Twilio, and Mindset Ventures. Existing investors Hanaco Ventures, Spider Capital and Entrepreneurs Roundtable Accelerator also participated in the round. Hyro is an enterprise application, currently aimed at the healthcare sector but with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.hyro.ai/">Hyro</a>, formerly Airbud, is today announcing the close of a $10.5 million Series A financing round led by Spero Ventures, with participation from Twilio, and Mindset Ventures. Existing investors Hanaco Ventures, Spider Capital and Entrepreneurs Roundtable Accelerator also participated in the round.</p>
<p>Hyro is an enterprise application, currently aimed at the healthcare sector but with eyes on new verticals, that adds an intelligent layer of voice chat or text chat to any application or website.</p>
<p>The company calls itself an adaptive communications platform, which essentially means that customers use plug-and-play tools to get information to end-users in a conversational way, whether that be voice or chat. It can integrate with contact centers, chatbots, SMS and other forms of communication. Essentially, Hyro targets information-heavy industries that often have to communicate with end-users.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This type of scenario, in the words of cofounder Israel Krush, usually leads to a terrible experience for the end user and a costly, inefficient process for the organization. The problem was no more apparent than in the healthcare sector during the pandemic. End users would flood platforms for information regarding the virus, the vaccine, testing, etc., but ask those redundant questions in myriad ways. On the enterprise side, the answers to those questions were changing over time.</p>
<p>Hyro allows these organizations to easily edit and change that information and deliver it to end users in an efficient way. But perhaps most importantly, Hyro scrapes information from the website to set up its own conversational tree, so the client doesn&#8217;t have to do a lot of heavy lifting up front.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cTYqkUHMGs"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/25/airbud-raises-4-million-to-add-a-voice-interface-to-your-website/">Airbud raises $4 million to add a voice interface to your website</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Airbud raises $4 million to add a voice interface to your website&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/25/airbud-raises-4-million-to-add-a-voice-interface-to-your-website/embed/#?secret=cTYqkUHMGs" data-secret="cTYqkUHMGs" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Krush says that the problem is big, which means that the space is crowded. He views Twilio&#8217;s participation in this round of fundraising as a differentiator.</p>
<p>&#8220;The market is crowded so it&#8217;s really hard to differentiate yourself from the crowd,&#8221; said Krush. &#8220;Even though we have great technology, everyone says they have great technology. Twilio coming into this round and the partnership we&#8217;re trying to develop around contact centers really attests to the differentiation of our approach, to the scalability and the modularity of our approach.&#8221;</p>
<p>He added that Hyro is not a healthcare company &#8212; &#8220;it&#8217;s really about serving any enterprise.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hyro healthcare customers include Carroll, Wheelpros, Mercy Health, University of Rochester Medical Center and Weill Cornell Medicine, but the company plans to use this new funding to scale into more verticals, with an aim toward real estate, government, and other information-heavy industries. </span></p>
<p>This latest round brings Hyro&#8217;s total funding to $15 million.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/twilio-invests-in-adaptive-communications-platform-hyro/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156996</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blockchain startup Propy plans first-ever auction of a real apartment as a collectible NFT</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/blockchain-startup-propy-plans-first-ever-auction-of-a-real-apartment-as-a-collectible-nft/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/blockchain-startup-propy-plans-first-ever-auction-of-a-real-apartment-as-a-collectible-nft/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 14:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arrington xrp capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[auction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Decentralized Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dfj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michael arrington]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peer to peer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Propy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart contract]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tim draper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ukraine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We previously wrote about Propy using blockchain technology to smooth real-world real estate sales by introducing the concept of smart contracts. Propy was the first blockchain startup to make that work. Now the company is pushing the boundaries again, by auctioning a real apartment as an NFT. Although one might want to brush this aside [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We previously <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/02/propy-a-blockchain-verified-platform-for-selling-houses-raises-funding-from-tim-draper/">wrote about Propy</a> using blockchain technology to smooth real-world real estate sales by introducing the concept of smart contracts. Propy was <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/an-entire-real-estate-deal-takes-place-online-using-cryptocurrency-technology-1506462545">the first</a> blockchain startup to make that work. Now the company is pushing the boundaries again, by <em>auctioning a real apartment as an NFT</em>. Although one might want to brush this aside as a stunt, the event is designed to make the point that it could well be done legally. And, by golly, they are going to try.</p>
<p>The auction will be of the NFT attached to a modern, brand new, one-bedroom apartment in Kiev, Ukraine, that Propy previously made history with by making it the first-ever level blockchain-based real estate sale.</p>
<p>The NFT created by Propy will, it says, transfers real ownership of the property. Just in case you haven;t been paying attention, NFTs, or Non-Fungible Tokens, are cryptographic &#8216;tokens&#8217; that represent a unique asset — such as a piece of art, music, or other collectibles — and certify ownership digitally. NFTs have set the crypto-world alight with their potential to be applied to just about anything, including a work of art by Banksy which was <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/mar/09/nfts-flying-cats-burning-banksy-digital-art-crypto-art-bitcoin-rocketing">then burnt</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Once someone has won the NFT of the apartment at auction, the NFT will include access to the ownership transfer paperwork; a digital artwork NFT by a popular Kiev graffiti artist, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/chizz.xr/">Chizz</a> (a physical painting of the digital artwork is painted on a wall of the apartment)’ and the apartment pictures. But obviously, the apartment is the main asset here.  </p>
<p>The auction itself will happen over a 24hr period with the initial listing starting at $20,000. Details for the NFT sale are <a href="https://propy.com/browse/propy-nft/">available here</a> and will be updated with any new information as the auction proceeds.</p>
<p>The apartment in question is currently owned by <a href="https://twitter.com/arrington">Michael Arrington</a>, founder of this very news site, and now a Crypto investor with <a href="http://arringtonxrpcapital.com/">Arrington XRP Capital</a>.</p>
<p>Investors in Propy &#8211; which says it has so far processed $1bn worth of transactions via its platform &#8211; include Arrington himself <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/02/propy-a-blockchain-verified-platform-for-selling-houses-raises-funding-from-tim-draper/">and Tim Draper</a>, former founder of DFJ.</p>
<p>Natalia Karayaneva, CEO of Propy said: “This NFT will go down in history. For Propy it is a major milestone in leveraging the promise of blockchain technology and non-fungible tokens (NFT) to achieve &#8216;self-driving&#8217; real estate transactions and real estate participation in the decentralized finance economy.”</p>
<p>Here’s how this is all going to work: Arrington has signed legal papers designed by  Propy’s lawyers for the NFT to transfer ownership to a future buyer. Propy then conducts the NFT auction and receives payment in cryptocurrency. The winner in the auction becomes the owner within a minute, after filling out KYC details.</p>
<p>The Kiev property is owned by a USA-based entity, and when the auction completes, the new owner of the NFT becomes the owner of the entity and thus the property itself. This process is repeated every time the NFT attached to the property is resold. </p>
<p>In an interview with me, Karayaneva said: “We were brainstorming and this appeared to be a natural development of our white paper of 2017. And in fact, many things we transact, real estate, via property, we are actually already kind of doing NF T&#8217;s, but with our unique smart contracts. But now the NFT concept provides a different approach, where a property can be transferred between two wallets, peer to peer.”</p>
<p>“Thus we do not need to change the name of the owner in the land registry. And this applies to many countries, as well as the United States. This model will work for the United States, and overall, there is this notion of buying real estate via LLC in the United States to preserve the privacy of the owner.”</p>
<p>Over the same call, Arrington added: “Coming at this from a crypto angle, we’ve seen what happens how DeFi gets plugged into credit markets. If I have an NFT or any DeFI asset I can then borrow against it, without a middleman. Right now, if I have a real piece of real estate, there is no way for me to borrow against it, without a middleman, because I have to go through a bank and get a mortgage or whatever. And it&#8217;s also the friction all of the costs in terms of speed and how long it takes.”</p>
<p>“If we can find a way to plug real estate and other real-world assets into DeFi, I think that the amount of credit that can be created around that is in the trillions, eventually. And so I think that has to happen. The questions around this are legal and regulatory… The legal stuff around this is tough, and so Propy has done a lot of work with that. But if they do, I think that the idea of an NFT representation of a real-world asset purely from the point of view of ease of trade and ease of access to credit markets is a big idea.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/blockchain-startup-propy-plans-first-ever-auction-of-a-real-apartment-as-a-collectible-nft/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157064</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flexibits updates contacts app Cardhop, adds deeper integration with Fantastical</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/flexibits-updates-contacts-app-cardhop-adds-deeper-integration-with-fantastical/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/flexibits-updates-contacts-app-cardhop-adds-deeper-integration-with-fantastical/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 14:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[address book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CardHop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contact]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fantastical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flexibits]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157023</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Flexibits, the company behind productivity apps Fantastical and Cardhop, is releasing a new version of Cardhop for both macOS and iOS. This is the second major version of the app and it adds new features, such as business card scanning, widgets, organizational charts and a deeper integration with Fantastical. Cardhop is a clever take on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://flexibits.com">Flexibits</a>, the company behind productivity apps <a href="https://flexibits.com/fantastical" title="Learn More">Fantastical</a> and <a href="https://flexibits.com/cardhop">Cardhop</a>, is releasing a new version of Cardhop for both macOS and iOS. This is the second major version of the app and it adds new features, such as business card scanning, widgets, organizational charts and a deeper integration with Fantastical.</p>
<p>Cardhop is a clever take on contact management. It uses the same address book as the default Contacts app on your Mac, iPhone and iPad. But it lets you search, add and edit contacts much more efficiently.</p>
<p>On the Mac, Cardhop sits in the menu bar. When you click on the icon or hit a keyboard shortcut, you can see your contacts but you can also start typing. This is when it gets interesting.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As expected, you can find a contact card by typing a few letters. But you can also add information to an existing contact this way.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2157037" style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2157037" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Cardhop-2-Mac-action.png?w=400" alt="" width="400" height="277" class="size-medium wp-image-2157037" /><p id="caption-attachment-2157037" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Flexibits</p></div></p>
<p>For instance, if you type a name followed by a phone number, Cardhop automatically figures out that the phone number doesn’t exist in the existing contact entry — hit enter and the number is saved. If the person isn’t even in your address book, you can create a new contact just by dumping information in the search field.</p>
<p>The app truly shines if you think about Cardhop as a sort of command-line interface to interact with your contacts. You can type ‘call Jane’, ‘email Tom’ or ‘whatsapp Natasha’ — Cardhop parses the action for you. It can be particularly handy to initiate calls on your iPhone from your Mac.</p>
<p>With Cardhop 2, the design has been updated and there are a handful of new features. You can now create widgets with your favorite actions. On iOS, you can add it to your home screen. On macOS, you can access it from the Notification Center. Widgets have been a popular feature of iOS 14 and many users will like that new feature.</p>
<p>If you’re also using Fantastical, you can send a calendar invite to someone else from Cardhop. And if you tend to invite the same group of people to your events, you can create a group in Cardhop. The next time you want to send an invitation, you can create an event with everyone in the group from Cardhop. This is going to be a good alternative to email aliases.</p>
<p>Cardhop can now also generate organizational charts and family trees based on relationships in your contacts. And if you work for a big company with a contact directory, you could easily find the right person to talk with using this new feature.</p>
<p>On iOS, Flexibits has also added a business card scanning feature. You can add contacts just by pointing your phone at a business card. There are many apps that offer that feature already, but now it’s integrated.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2157041" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2157041" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Cardhop-2-iOS.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="733" class="size-full wp-image-2157041" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Cardhop-2-iOS.jpg 3882w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Cardhop-2-iOS.jpg?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Cardhop-2-iOS.jpg?resize=300,215 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Cardhop-2-iOS.jpg?resize=768,550 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Cardhop-2-iOS.jpg?resize=680,487 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Cardhop-2-iOS.jpg?resize=1536,1099 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Cardhop-2-iOS.jpg?resize=2048,1466 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Cardhop-2-iOS.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2157041" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Flexibits</p></div></p>
<p>Flexibits has been around for 10 years. Originally, the company released new major updates and users had to pay to download the new version. That&#8217;s how independent development companies used to charge for apps.</p>
<p>Last year, the company launched <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/29/flexibits-launches-major-fantastical-update/">a new version of Fantastical</a> with a freemium model. New users could download the app for free and would have to pay a subscription of $4.99 per month or $39.99 per year to unlock all features. Existing users could keep using the app for free as all existing features had been unlocked for them.</p>
<p>After switching to this new model, Flexibits released quite a few updates to Fantastical already. For instance, you can now join conference calls quickly with shortcuts in the menu bar and in the app. Fantastical now also supports Zoom, Google Meet and Microsoft Teams.</p>
<p>Flexibits wants to go one step further and create an ecosystem of productivity apps. Cardhop 2 is a free app with a few free features. If you want to unlock everything, you have to subscribe to the same Flexibits Premium subscription.</p>
<p>In other words, the company is bundling premium versions of Fantastical and Cardhop in a single subscription —&nbsp;and the price isn’t changing. Existing Cardhop users who don’t want to subscribe will also keep everything that was available in Cardhop 1 for free.</p>
<p>And if you’re already using Cardhop, it’s nice to see an update. It means that the app is going to be supported going forward. When you rely on an app for your work, it’s better when it’s regularly updated and keeps working as expected years after years. And I suspect many Fantastical users will try out Cardhop thanks to the new Flexibits Premium subscription.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="43debYQk5y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/18/fantastical-maker-cleverly-redefines-contact-apps-with-cardhop/">Fantastical maker cleverly redefines contact apps with Cardhop</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fantastical maker cleverly redefines contact apps with Cardhop&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/18/fantastical-maker-cleverly-redefines-contact-apps-with-cardhop/embed/#?secret=43debYQk5y" data-secret="43debYQk5y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TbdyQw9W7k"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/27/contacts-app-cardhop-comes-to-ios/">Contacts app Cardhop comes to iOS</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Contacts app Cardhop comes to iOS&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/27/contacts-app-cardhop-comes-to-ios/embed/#?secret=TbdyQw9W7k" data-secret="TbdyQw9W7k" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/flexibits-updates-contacts-app-cardhop-adds-deeper-integration-with-fantastical/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157023</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Security startup Tessian, which uses AI to fight social engineering, trousers $65M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/security-startup-tessian-which-uses-ai-to-fight-social-engineering-trousers-65m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/security-startup-tessian-which-uses-ai-to-fight-social-engineering-trousers-65m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 13:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Balderton Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Darktrace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[march capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Schroder Adveq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tessian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157004</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the latest chunky funding round out of Europe, UK-based email security startup, Tessian, has closed $65 million in Series C funding. The startup applies machine learning to build individual behavior models for enterprise email use that aims to combat human error by flagging problematic patterns which could signify risky stuff is happening &#8212; such [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In the latest chunky funding round out of Europe, UK-based email security startup, <a href="https://www.tessian.com">Tessian</a>, has closed $65 million in Series C funding. The startup applies machine learning to build individual behavior models for enterprise email use that aims to combat human error by flagging problematic patterns which could signify risky stuff is happening &#8212; such as phishing or data exfiltration.</p>
<p>The Series C round was led by March Capital. Existing investors Accel, Balderton Capital, Latitude and Sequoia Capital also participated, along with new investor Schroder Adveq.</p>
<p>The latest financing brings Tessian&#8217;s total raised to-date to $120M+, and values the company at $500M, it said today.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The 2013 founded startup last raised back in January 2019 when it closed a $40M Series B (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/16/cc-sequoia-tessian/">news that was scooped</a> by former TCer, Steve O&#8217;Hear). Prior to that it grabbed a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/18/tessian/">$13M Series A in mid 2018</a>.</p>
<p>Tessian has around 350 global customers at this stage, across the legal, financial services, healthcare and technology sectors &#8212; name-checking the likes of Affirm, Arm, Investec and RealPagem among them.</p>
<p>Over the past year there has been much coverage of the security risks associated with the pandemic-sparked remote working boom, as scores of white collars workers started logging on from home &#8212; expanding the attack surface area which enterprises needed to manage.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a risk that&#8217;s been good for Tessian&#8217;s business: The startup says it tripled its Fortune 500-level customer base last year &#8212; &#8220;as enterprises required a solution that could protect them against human layer security threats&#8221;, as it puts it.</p>
<p>It says the new funding will go on expanding its platform’s capabilities; helping companies replace their secure email gateways and legacy data loss prevention solutions; and on growing its team (it plans to triple headcount in short order with a particular focus on growing its sales team in North America).</p>
<p>The Series C funds will also support a plan to expand beyond email to offer security protections for other interfaces such as messaging, web and collaboration platforms &#8212; which it says is on the cards &#8220;soon&#8221;.</p>
<p>Commenting on the round in a statement, Jamie Montgomery, co-founder and managing partner at March Capital said: &#8220;Human activity &#8212; whether inadvertent or malicious &#8212; is the leading cause of data breaches. In Tessian, we found a best-in-class solution that automatically stops threats in real-time, without disrupting the normal flow of business. It is rare to hear such overwhelmingly positive feedback from CISOs and business users alike. We came to the same conclusion; Tessian is rapidly emerging as the leader in human layer security for the enterprise.&#8221;</p>
<p>A number of UK-based AI security startups have been building momentum in recent years, with others like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/10/25/red-sift/">Red Shift</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/19/senseon-raises-6-4m-to-tackle-cybersecurity-threats-with-an-ai-triangulation-approach/">Senseon</a> also getting traction by applying machine learning to tackle risks.</p>
<p>In April, Cambridge-based <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/26/darktrace-raises-50-million-new-funding/">Darktrace</a> &#8212; a category pioneer &#8212; led the pack by floating on the London Stock Exchange where it saw its <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/325059d4-a24c-4d4c-9fdb-0214179fc822">shares pop 32%</a> in the IPO debut.</p>
<p>While, last year, the UK government pledged to ramp up R&amp;D spending on AI as part of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/uk-to-invest-in-ai-and-cyber-as-part-of-major-defense-spending-hike/">a major defense spending hike</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="d01Sm8UzLc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/18/tessian/">Email security startup Tessian raises $13M led by Balderton and Accel</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Email security startup Tessian raises $13M led by Balderton and Accel&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/18/tessian/embed/#?secret=d01Sm8UzLc" data-secret="d01Sm8UzLc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="poYPsiRSf1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/16/cc-sequoia-tessian/">Email security company Tessian is closing in on a $40M round led by Sequoia Capital</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Email security company Tessian is closing in on a $40M round led by Sequoia Capital&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/16/cc-sequoia-tessian/embed/#?secret=poYPsiRSf1" data-secret="poYPsiRSf1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/security-startup-tessian-which-uses-ai-to-fight-social-engineering-trousers-65m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157004</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AcuityMD raises $7M to better track the evolving world of medical hardware</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/acuitymd-raises-7m-to-better-track-the-evolving-world-of-medical-hardware/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/acuitymd-raises-7m-to-better-track-the-evolving-world-of-medical-hardware/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 13:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Benchmark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HealthTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketplace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medtech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157000</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a world defined by tons of noise and little signal, startups that make it easier for consumers to make a choice just make sense. Career Karma helps students pick a tech bootcamp, Stackin’ helps millennials navigate the world of neobank and savings apps, and a new Boston-based company is helping doctors keep track of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In a world defined by tons of noise and little signal, startups that make it easier for consumers to make a choice just make sense. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/career-karma-series-a/">Career Karma helps students</a> pick a tech bootcamp, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/stackin-raises-12-6-series-b-to-help-millennials-navigate-the-crowded-fintech-space/">Stackin’ helps millennials</a> navigate the world of neobank and savings apps, and a new Boston-based company is helping doctors keep track of the most up-to-date medical devices on the market.</p>
<p><a href="https://acuitymd.com/about/">AcuityMD</a>, founded in 2019 by Mike Monovoukas, Lee Smith, and Robert Coe, is an enterprise software company that wants to unlock the often siloed world of medical device data. And to do so, it landed a $7 million seed round this week, led by Benchmark.</p>
<p>As part of the deal, Benchmark GP Eric Vishria will join AcuityMD’s board of directors. Ajax Health, which <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/ajax-health-raises-100-million-to-advance-innovations-in-medtech-300927456.html">closed $100 million in 2019</a> to back medtech companies, also participated in the round. With seed capital, Monovoukas said that AcuityMD plans to double its eight-person team by the end of the year, and invest heavily in one specific area: “product, product, product.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>AcuityMD is a data platform that tracks the entire medical device lifecycle &#8211; from the sale of an item to a patient’s outcome after a surgery. It aggregates industry and market data on individual medical devices to give a metadata of sorts on a singular product.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2157014 aligncenter" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_06.png" alt="" width="828" height="537" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_06.png 1468w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_06.png?resize=150,97 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_06.png?resize=300,195 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_06.png?resize=768,498 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_06.png?resize=680,441 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_06.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 828px) 100vw, 828px" /></p>
<p>“There are 1000s of products being launched each year and so it&#8217;s almost impossible for a surgeon, after they&#8217;ve graduated fellowship or residency to keep track of the latest and greatest medical technology out there,” Monovoukas said. “We view this as a software and coordination problem, where you have all this data out there and it’s inefficient in getting to the decision-maker.”</p>
<p>Monovoukas experienced noticed inefficiencies in medical device management first-hand when a family member needed to go through a series of surgeries.</p>
<p>“What was fascinating to me is that the manufacturer holds a lot of information about what to use, [and] sometimes that didn&#8217;t get disseminated to the right surgeon at the right point of time,” he said. “The fundamental realization I had was that the information flow in this industry was a little bit broken&#8230;It wasn&#8217;t an issue of being competent doctors or surgeons, but a lack of information transfer, which is kind of crazy in a data driven world.”</p>
<p>So, the entrepreneur, who worked at Bain &amp; Company as well as a medical device company prior, began thinking of how to use data to make medical devices more responsive to long-term patient outcomes. While doctor’s were a key stakeholder set to benefit from more information, AcuityMD’s team landed on selling to device manufacturers as their key customer.</p>
<p>Now, part of that reason might be because hospitals and doctors are notoriously a pain to sell to. The other reason, Monovoukas tells me, is that performance data on medical devices is a key signal that Sales teams within manufacturers can use to beef up, and better target, their pitches. The co-founder explained how manufacturers want visibility into the market for their products, ranging from data on where high volume surgeons might need one of their devices to long-term outcomes on certain devices over time.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2157013" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_01.png" alt="" width="521" height="468" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_01.png 1245w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_01.png?resize=150,135 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_01.png?resize=300,269 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_01.png?resize=768,690 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_01.png?resize=680,611 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ACU_Image_01.png?resize=50,45 50w" sizes="(max-width: 521px) 100vw, 521px" /></p>
<p>The data could help a sales rep pre-emptively figure out how targeting 10 surgeons for a specific product impacts the manufacturer financially and in context with the rest of the market.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>AcuityMD is teeing itself up to become a real-time database of medical devices. Long-term, it could position itself as a Same Day Shipping service connecting manufacturers to surgeons in high-demand and vital transactions. Monovaukus says that while logistics and inventory is a “visceral” problem for the medical device industry, it doesn’t have a solution in place yet. He could see the startup getting to a point in the future where they can predict inventory levels required at each facility &#8211; similar to how some companies already like <a href="https://www.medinas.com/">Medinas</a>, co-founded by Chloe Alpert, operate and manage within hospital systems.</p>
<p>But for now, AcuityMD thinks it can best use its platform and millions of venture-backed capital outside the provider system. It sources a lot of its data on hospitals and surgeons from Medicare CMS and insurance companies, so leaving no action required on the end of providers.</p>
<p>A challenge will be making sure those data sources are good enough to extract true signals. The startup is still defining good.</p>
<p>“I heard someone once say that any digital health company eventually becomes a healthcare data company,” he said. “We’re approaching things a little bit differently.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/acuitymd-raises-7m-to-better-track-the-evolving-world-of-medical-hardware/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157000</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Forter raises $300M on a $3B valuation to combat e-commerce fraud</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/forter-raises-300m-on-a-3b-valuation-for-a-platform-to-combat-e-commerce-fraud/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/forter-raises-300m-on-a-3b-valuation-for-a-platform-to-combat-e-commerce-fraud/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 12:58:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[risk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[E-commerce is on the rise, but that also means the risk, and occurrence, of e-commerce fraud is, too. Now, Forter, one of the startups building a business to tackle that malicious activity, has closed $300 million in funding &#8212; a sign both of the size of the issue, and its success in tackling it to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">E-commerce is on the rise, but that also means the risk, and occurrence, of e-commerce fraud is, too. Now, <a href="https://www.forter.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Forter</a>, one of the startups building a business to tackle that malicious activity, has closed $300 million in funding &#8212; a sign both of the size of the issue, and its success in tackling it to date.</p>
<p>The new funding, a Series F, values Forter at $3 billion &#8212; notable not least because the funding is coming only about <a href="https://www.forter.com/blog/expansion-fraud-fighting-network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">six months since Forter&#8217;s previous round</a>, a $125 million Series E that valued it at over $1.3 billion.</p>
<p>Tiger Global Management is leading this latest equity infusion, with new backers Third Point Ventures and Adage Capital Management, and existing investors Bessemer Venture Partners, Sequoia Capital, March Capital, NewView Capital, Salesforce Ventures and Scale Venture Partners, also involved.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The plan will be to use to the money to expand Forter &#8212; founded in Tel Aviv and now based in New York &#8212; geographically, to bring more functionality into its product, and to look at adjacent areas where Forter might expand its capabilities, either organically or by way of acquisition.</p>
<p>Forter today focuses mainly on identifying fraud at the point of transaction and building an AI-based platform that &#8220;learns&#8221; more behaviors to improve its accuracy; it also builds models that keep more people transacting and helps bring down the number of &#8220;false positives&#8221; where activity that appears suspicious actually is not.</p>
<p>One area on its roadmap for expansion is remediation after the fraud occurs, said Liron Damri, Forter&#8217;s co-founder and president.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our vision is to serve the merchant as the go-to trusted partner for everything, so remediation is definitely on our roadmap,&#8221; he said of potential acquisition targets.</p>
<p>Damri, who co-founded the company with Michael Reitblat, CEO, and Alon Shemesh, chief analyst, said in an interview that the startup &#8212; which works with some 350 large customers like Priceline and Instacart and a growing number of service providers like FreedomPay and Flutterwave, altogether seeing some $250 billion dollars worth of transactions globally last year &#8212; wasn&#8217;t proactively looking for more money.</p>
<p>&#8220;All we wanted to do was go back to run the company,&#8221; he said. &#8220;But in the past six months we’ve seen such a great momentum, doubling revenue and ARR, and seeing our customer volumes grow.&#8221;</p>
<p>That led to a lot of investors proactively reaching out and ask questions, he continued. He described Tiger as a &#8220;kingmaker&#8221; in the category of e-commerce, so it was an easy decision to make, and gave it the &#8220;gas&#8221; it needed to take its next growth steps.</p>
<p>E-commerce has been one of the major technology growth stories of the last year, fueled by a rush of consumers and businesses playing out their lives online at a time when it has been harder, and in some cases impossible, to transact in person.</p>
<p>While we have definitely seen a lot of growth, and growing sophistication, in the number of tools on the market to combat cybercrime, it&#8217;s in some ways an ouroboros of a problem: the more transactions that are made, the more there are that need to be monitored for suspicious activity. And in any case fraud in e-commerce is not exactly going away. It&#8217;s estimated that it will cost retailers <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210425005002/en/Juniper-Research-eCommerce-Losses-to-Online-Payment-Fraud-to-Exceed-20-Billion-Annually-in-2021" target="_blank" rel="noopener">some $20 billion in 2021</a> and is always on the rise.</p>
<p>Forter got its start in 2013 focusing first on monitoring activity on sites wherever customers happened to be to identify suspicious behavior &#8212; a sign that it might be a bot or someone on an illicit spending spree racking up a lot of items in quick succession &#8212; with the bigger concept being to build a network of activity from which to learn and help make more informed decisions over time.</p>
<p>In more recent years, the essence of the issue has expanded somewhat, and also grown more sophisticated. As companies have grown their businesses to reach beyond early adopters and core audiences, and into a more &#8220;omnichannel&#8221; environment beyond basic check-outs on their own sites, so too have the kinds of consumers coming to shop.</p>
<p>This has meant that traditional &#8220;signals&#8221; of legitimate buyers no longer were the same as before &#8212; a predicament that really rose in profile in the last year, as many newcomers came to e-commerce for the first time during the pandemic. In fact, Damri told me that in 2020 there were seven times more &#8220;newcomers&#8221; to sites than in 2019, huge growth of that segment.</p>
<p>So with most of the flagging of suspicious activity coming up at the point of transaction, Forter expanded to analyzing activity there.</p>
<p>As with a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/14/stripe-acquires-bouncer-will-integrate-its-card-authentication-into-the-radar-fraud-detection-tool/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">recent acquisition of Stripe&#8217;s, Bouncer</a>, to build out its own anti-fraud product, a large part of Forter&#8217;s attention these days is on providing tools to companies to identify suspicious purchasing, but even more than that, to make sure that the many occasions that might look suspicious are not, to help reduce the amount of &#8220;cart abandonment&#8221; and increase conversions.</p>
<p>The old way of doing things, Damri said, involved &#8220;thousands of rules and applying suspicion on everyone. You were guilty unless proved otherwise.&#8221;</p>
<p>Using its AI engine and a some risk analysis (not unlike the kind that, say, an insurance or loan provider might apply in their businesses), Forter turned the proposition on its head.</p>
<p>&#8220;We wanted to approve as much as possible. We wanted to gradually increase the trust you have of your own customers. We changed the sentiment and approach&#8230; especially in areas that were neglected, such as those who saw significant changes in life,&#8221; Damri said. &#8220;This was extremely important as Covid-19 hit.&#8221;</p>
<p>Forter&#8217;s risk tolerance model, it seems, has so far proven out. Damri said that its algorithms applied reduce the total number of declines by 80%, but also reduce the number of chargebacks &#8212; one indicator of a mistake &#8212; by 60%.</p>
<p>This implies that it&#8217;s blocking more of the &#8220;wrong&#8221; kind of purchases, and letting through more of the legitimate ones.  (That is, he pointed out, in addition to a few bad actors Forter intentionally lets buy things, just to learn how they operate. Damri referred to this as &#8220;paid-tuition.&#8221;)</p>
<p>Risk-based approvals, coupled with algorithms to learn what is truly bad, has resonated with customers, and investors.</p>
<p>“With the unprecedented rate of digital transformation and the fierce competition in creating the slickest user experience, superior fraud prevention plays an ever more critical role in e-commerce revenue growth&#8221; said John Curtius, a partner at Tiger Global Management, in a statement. &#8220;After we talked with dozens of customers of every relevant solution in this space, it was very clear to us that Forter is the clear leader in performance and scale.”</p>
<p>“As a longtime investor, it’s been incredible to see Forter’s ascent,” added Ravi Viswanathan, NewView Capital. “It’s a testament to the leadership team’s vision and execution in allowing merchants to provide the seamless experiences customers expect and to be able to accept as many transactions as possible, while still accurately identifying and blocking fraud.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/forter-raises-300m-on-a-3b-valuation-for-a-platform-to-combat-e-commerce-fraud/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156814</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Atlan raises $16M led by Insight Partners to build a collaboration hub for data-driven teams</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/atlan-raises-16m-led-by-insight-partners-to-build-a-collaboration-hub-for-data-driven-teams/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/atlan-raises-16m-led-by-insight-partners-to-build-a-collaboration-hub-for-data-driven-teams/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 12:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[auren-hoffman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bob Moore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bob muglia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[liveramp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safegraph]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snowflake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waterbridge Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Young startup Atlan, which has built a SaaS data collaboration platform and is courting customers in international markets, has now won the trust of some high-profile investors. Atlan said on Tuesday it has raised $16 million in its Series A financing round that was led by Insight Partners. Bob Muglia (former CEO of Snowflake), Bob [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Young startup Atlan, which has built a SaaS data collaboration platform and is courting customers in international markets, has now won the trust of some high-profile investors.</p>
<p>Atlan said on Tuesday it has raised $16 million in its Series A financing round that was led by Insight Partners. Bob Muglia (former CEO of Snowflake), Bob Moore and Jake Stei (founders of Stitch) and Auren Hoffman (founder of Safegraph and Liveramp), and Akshay Kothari (co-founder and COO of Notion) also invested in the round, as did existing investors Sequoia Surge and Waterbridge Ventures.</p>
<p>The startup &#8212; which was founded in India and now has teams across the U.S., Singapore, Philippines, and Nigeria &#8212; operates an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/01/atlan-socialcops/">eponymous data stack that brings together diverse data from internal and external sources</a> such as Snowflake and Databricks to one interface and allows teams to collaborate easily.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The thesis behind Atlan is that the way most people in enterprises deal with data is inefficient. This is because of the fundamental diversity of people involved &#8212; scientists, analysts, engineers, business users &#8212; who all have their own skill sets and tool preferences.</p>
<p>This makes collaboration between the teams a challenge as they struggle to find the right data at the right time, for instance.</p>
<p>It’s a challenge that the founders of Atlan &#8212; Prukalpa Sankar and Varun Banka (pictured above) &#8212; faced first hand at their first venture, SocialCops. The venture was behind several data science for social good projects including India&#8217;s National Data Platform and SDGs global monitoring in collaboration with the United Nations.</p>
<p><a href="https://atlan.com">Atlan</a> started out as an internal tool to help the data team at SocialCops carry out projects more efficiently, before being opened up to teams around the world.</p>
<p>“We are reimagining the human experience with data &#8212; why can’t data assets be shared as easily as sharing a link on Google Docs, or if Google Analytics can tell you usage on a website, why can’t we do the same for our data?” said Sankar.</p>
<p>Teddie Wardi, Managing Director at Insight Partners, likened Atlan’s relevance to companies just as Figma is crucial to design teams and Github is important to engineering teams.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1851098" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1851098" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1851098 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg?w=680" alt="Atlan Discovery 2" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg 5184w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Atlan-Discovery-2.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1851098" class="wp-caption-text">Dashboard of Atlan (Atlan)</p></div></p>
<p>In an interview with TechCrunch, Sankar said more than 60% of Atlan&#8217;s clients today are in the U.S., and the market will be a big focus as the startup scales. She declined to reveal the number of clients the startup has amassed, but said the startup has grown 16X times in the last two quarters.</p>
<p>Some of its clients include giants such as Unilever, Scripps Health, Postman, and Techstyle, one of the world’s largest membership-based fashion firms with a diverse portfolio of brands including Fabletics, Savage X Fenty, JustFab, FabKids, and ShoeDazzle.</p>
<p>“As we rolled-out our modern data platform, we were looking for a product that made it easier to democratize our data and was less dependent on someone central answering each individual analyst’s questions on a one-off basis. Legacy solutions in the market were tailored to legacy systems and approaches where IT or a single data stewardship team owns the data,&#8221; said Danielle Boeglin Ragan, Vice President of Data &amp; Analytics at Techstyle, in a statement.</p>
<p>&#8220;Atlan was the only solution that was built for a collaborative, bottom-up approach. With native integrations with our modern analytics stack like Snowflake and Tableau, Atlan was very easy to set-up &#8211; we had all of our data sources flowing within the first day.”</p>
<p>The startup plans to deploy the fresh capital to expand its team of 40 people across marketing, sales, and customer success, said Banka.</p>
<p>“Atlan has become a valuable resource for the data team to get context about data. In the long run, for our data democratization vision, we see the entire organization working towards analyzing the data and taking actions in a coherent, seamless fashion. Having Atlan in the mix of our toolchains opens the possibility of providing data context at scale, thereby enabling the entire org to be data aware and data driven.” said Prudhvi Vasa, Analytics Leader at Postman, in a statement.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/atlan-raises-16m-led-by-insight-partners-to-build-a-collaboration-hub-for-data-driven-teams/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156983</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indoor farming company Bowery raises $300M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/indoor-farming-company-bowery-raises-300m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/indoor-farming-company-bowery-raises-300m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bowery Farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fidelity Management & Research Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indoor farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vertical farming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156818</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New York City-based vertical farming startup Bowery Farming this week has announced a $300 million Series C. The round, which brings its total funding north of $472 million, values the company at $2.3 billion. Fidelity Management &#38; Research Company led the beefy round, with participation from existing investors GV (formerly Google Ventures), General Catalyst, GGV [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">New York City-based vertical farming startup Bowery Farming this week has announced a $300 million Series C. The round, which brings its total funding north of $472 million, values the company at $2.3 billion.</p>
<p>Fidelity Management &amp; Research Company led the beefy round, with participation from existing investors GV (formerly Google Ventures), General Catalyst, GGV Capital, Temasek and Groupe Artémis. Amplo and Gaingels participated, as well, along with some celebrity individual investors, including Lewis Hamilton, Chris Paul, Natalie Portman, José Andrés and Justin Timberlake.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pAEJna7Mb9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/12/bowery-an-indoor-farming-startup-raises-90-million-more-including-to-counter-a-softbank-funded-rival/">Bowery, an indoor farming startup, raises $90 million more, including to counter a SoftBank-funded rival</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bowery, an indoor farming startup, raises $90 million more, including to counter a SoftBank-funded rival&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/12/bowery-an-indoor-farming-startup-raises-90-million-more-including-to-counter-a-softbank-funded-rival/embed/#?secret=pAEJna7Mb9" data-secret="pAEJna7Mb9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The funding comes as Bowery has experienced some impressive real-world growth, touting a 750% increase in availability since January of last year. If anything, the company appears to have thrived during the pandemic. Its vertically farmed produce is now available in 850 grocery stores, including big-name chains like Albertsons (incl. Safeway and Acme), Giant Food, Walmart and Whole Foods.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2156871" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2156871" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2156871" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="1280" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg?resize=120,150 120w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg?resize=240,300 240w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg?resize=768,960 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg?resize=544,680 544w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg?resize=1229,1536 1229w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg?resize=1638,2048 1638w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Credit_BoweryFarming_Location_NottinghamFarm_2020-2.jpg?resize=40,50 40w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2156871" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bowery Farming</p></div></p>
<p>Amazon Fresh has also provided a sizable e-commerce footprint &#8212; a big must during the pandemic-fueled shutdowns of the past year.</p>
<p>“This infusion of new capital from Fidelity, other new investors, and the additional support of our long-term investor partners is acknowledgement of the critical need for new solutions to our current agricultural system, and the enormous economic opportunity that comes with supporting our mission,” CEO Irving Fain said in a release. “This funding not only fuels our continued expansion but the ongoing development of our proprietary technology, which sits at the core of our business and our ability to rapidly and efficiently scale towards an increasingly important opportunity in front of us.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2156873" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2156873" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2156873" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="819" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg 3540w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg?resize=150,120 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg?resize=300,240 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg?resize=768,614 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg?resize=680,544 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg?resize=1536,1229 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg?resize=2048,1638 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/BoweryFarming_Produce_Nov2020_ChelseaKyle.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2156873" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bowery Farming</p></div></p>
<p>The company says the massive windfall will go toward expanding its indoor farms to additional locations in the United States, as well as investing in headcount and R&amp;D. Included in the former is a new site located in an industrial area in Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, which Bowery says will be its largest to date.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yl8gcjBRJM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/bowery-farming-adds-executives-as-it-expands-to-sell-produce-in-650-stores/">Bowery Farming adds executives as it expands to sell produce in 650 stores</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bowery Farming adds executives as it expands to sell produce in 650 stores&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/bowery-farming-adds-executives-as-it-expands-to-sell-produce-in-650-stores/embed/#?secret=yl8gcjBRJM" data-secret="yl8gcjBRJM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wMjvNQNZzB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/farmland-could-be-the-next-big-asset-class-modernized-by-marketplace-startups/">Farmland could be the next big asset class modernized by marketplace startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Farmland could be the next big asset class modernized by marketplace startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/farmland-could-be-the-next-big-asset-class-modernized-by-marketplace-startups/embed/#?secret=wMjvNQNZzB" data-secret="wMjvNQNZzB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/indoor-farming-company-bowery-raises-300m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156818</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canvas lands $20M so tech&#8217;s biggest companies can find diverse talent</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/canvas-lands-20m-so-techs-biggest-companies-can-find-diverse-talent/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/canvas-lands-20m-so-techs-biggest-companies-can-find-diverse-talent/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 12:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[board member]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canvas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resource management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jumpstart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lachy Groom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Vernal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pinterest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recruitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156678</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ben Herman and Adam Gefkovicz launched Jumpstart in 2017 with a clear mission: to make the world more equitable via a more fair and balanced hiring process. The company released its “Diversity Recruitment Platform” in July of 2018 with the aim of helping people earlier in their careers get a “jumpstart&#8221; via technology. Over the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ben Herman and Adam Gefkovicz </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">launched Jumpstart in 2017 with a clear mission: to make the world more equitable via a more fair and balanced hiring process.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company released its “Diversity Recruitment Platform” in July of 2018 with the aim of helping people earlier in their careers get a “jumpstart&#8221; via technology.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the years, the startup’s mission has evolved beyond helping college grads to helping all employees &#8212; regardless of career stage &#8212; get a fair shot at jobs. And it’s doing that by teaming up with hundreds of companies &#8212; such as Airbnb, Bloomberg, Coinbase, Samsung, Lyft, Pinterest, Plaid, Roblox, Audible, Headspace and Stripe &#8212; to help them hire a more diverse pool of candidates.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FcNivBPIxm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/18/jumpstart-nabs-8-5m-led-by-sequoia-for-a-recruitment-platform-that-aims-to-increase-diversity/">Jumpstart nabs $8.5M led by Sequoia for a recruitment platform that aims to increase diversity</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Jumpstart nabs $8.5M led by Sequoia for a recruitment platform that aims to increase diversity&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/18/jumpstart-nabs-8-5m-led-by-sequoia-for-a-recruitment-platform-that-aims-to-increase-diversity/embed/#?secret=FcNivBPIxm" data-secret="FcNivBPIxm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Demand has accelerated exponentially, and the San Francisco-based startup saw its revenue grow “3x” in 2020 compared to 2019, although execs declined to provide hard figures. Considering its broadened focus, Jumpstart has rebranded to </span><a href="http://canvas.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Canvas</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and announced today that it has closed on $20 million in funding. Early Stripe employee and angel investor Lachy Groom and</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Sequoia Capital co-led the round, which included participation from Four Rivers Capital. The raise brings Canvas&#8217; total raised to $32.5 million.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We knew we were only scratching the surface of our vision, and knew we had a solution that could reimagine diversity hiring for everyone,” said co-founder and CEO Ben Herman. “You know how everyone has a CRM? We believe every company should have a DRP, which is a diversity recruitment platform. That&#8217;s the category we want to create and we want to be the largest in that space.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No doubt that the Black Lives Matter movement in the aftermath of George Floyd’s murder helped, well jumpstart, the company’s efforts. Canvas is able to sell its offering as more companies “are being held accountable for their promises of equity and hiring diverse talent,” Herman said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Hiring diverse teams is not only a matter of corporate social responsibility,” he added. “Diversity and inclusion are a competitive advantage and strategic priority for every company in today’s landscape. We believe representation is a huge part of what we stand for. So we want everyone to be able to create their own canvas, and to be able to paint their own picture.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Canvas describes its SaaS offering as a “fully virtual” recruiting platform that is based on self-reported data. About 87% of candidates on its platform disclose their demographic information (which it says is 7x the industry standard), according to the startup. Canvas also says it gives companies the ability to narrow down the priority groups and talent it wants to focus on by filtering over 75+ self-reported candidate data points. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup claims that it’s different from others in the space for that reason, among other features.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Unlike other solutions that might utilize inferred data that could be inaccurate or illegal, Canvas helps create a more accurate data set to identify diverse candidates, helping to solve the core problem of talent discovery,” Herman said. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GCHOcmhcUX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/on-the-diversity-front-2020-may-prove-a-tipping-point/">On the diversity front, 2020 may prove a tipping point</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;On the diversity front, 2020 may prove a tipping point&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/on-the-diversity-front-2020-may-prove-a-tipping-point/embed/#?secret=GCHOcmhcUX" data-secret="GCHOcmhcUX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It also &#8212; unlike some diversity hiring platforms &#8212; does not rely on artificial intelligence, a fact that Herman is actually proud of.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We don&#8217;t believe that AI is the future. It&#8217;s not about getting someone&#8217;s gender or ethnicity based off of their name, or to inform the hiring decision without candidates knowing,” Herman told TechCrunch. “It&#8217;s all about how to empower talent to self-identify&#8230;We want to enable the talent to own their data, and truly be able to represent themselves in unique ways. That’s not leveraging AI.”</span></p>
<p>Canvas also gives companies a way to design, promote and run events, such as webinars, aimed at hiring diverse talent.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup also wants to get to a place where companies are working together “to complete the diversity data gap.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The problem is about accessibility, and so we want to give equal access to anyone and everyone &#8212; from all companies to all candidates,” Herman said. “And so that is really the most important part of what we are creating &#8212; the ability for companies to share data.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, how does it measure its own success? Canvas claims that 56% of all hires on the Canvas platform are made from underrepresented groups (URGs), and that it helps employers achieve a 30% reduction in time to hire.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Herman is not your typical startup founder, having dropped out of high school and starting his own recruitment agency at the age of 21. His tenacity is one of the things that attracted Sequoia partner and Canvas board member Mike Vernal to back the company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“When we first met Ben, it was clear that he was&#8230;a natural-born talent scout,” Vernal told TechCrunch. “He thought there was a better way for the industry to work &#8212; one where companies and recruiters were more collaborative and used technology to build stronger, more diverse teams.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since its initial investment in the company, Vernal believes building diverse teams has never been more important.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Those teams create better products, make stronger business decisions, and it’s just the right thing to do,” he said. “We believe companies can do a better job sourcing underrepresented talent using Canvas than on their own.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Canvas plans to use its new capital to expand the product into other industries and verticals beyond technology and continue to address the recruiting process for later stages of people&#8217;s careers. The company currently has 70 employees and expects to have 100 by the end of 2021.</span></p>
<p>As mentioned above, hiring diverse talent is becoming a bigger priority for big tech companies (such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/hp-outlines-ambitious-diversity-goals/">HP</a>) and startups alike. Earlier this year, diverse hiring startup SeekOut <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/seekout-raises-65m/">raised $65 million</a>. The company has built out a database with hundreds of millions of profiles using its AI-powered talent search engine and “deep interactive analytics.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WOvNmRQXB5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/as-companies-prioritize-diversity-startups-are-trying-to-productize-diverse-hiring/">As companies prioritize diversity, startups are trying to productize diverse hiring</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As companies prioritize diversity, startups are trying to productize diverse hiring&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/as-companies-prioritize-diversity-startups-are-trying-to-productize-diverse-hiring/embed/#?secret=WOvNmRQXB5" data-secret="WOvNmRQXB5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/canvas-lands-20m-so-techs-biggest-companies-can-find-diverse-talent/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156678</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sinch, a Swedish customer engagement giant, raises $1.1B, SoftBank and Temasek participating</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/sinch-a-swedish-customer-engagement-giant-raises-1-1b-softbank-and-temasek-participating/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/sinch-a-swedish-customer-engagement-giant-raises-1-1b-softbank-and-temasek-participating/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 11:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[APIs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[communications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sinch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twilio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156966</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sinch &#8212; a Twilio competitor based out of Sweden that provides a suite of services to companies to build communications and specifically &#8220;customer engagement&#8221; into their services by way of APIs &#8212; has been on a steady funding and acquisitions march in the last several months to scale its business, and today comes the latest [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.sinch.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sinch</a> &#8212; a Twilio competitor based out of Sweden that provides a suite of services to companies to build communications and specifically &#8220;customer engagement&#8221; into their services by way of APIs &#8212; has been on a steady funding and acquisitions march in the last several months to scale its business, and today comes the latest development on that front.</p>
<p>The company has <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/sinch-ab-publ-sinch-completes-220300243.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that it has raised another $1.1 billion in a direct share issue, with significant chunks of that funding coming from Temasek and SoftBank, in order to continue building its business.</p>
<p>Specifically, the company &#8212; which is traded on the Swedish stock exchange Nasdaq Stockhom and currently has a market cap of around $11 billion &#8212; said that it was making a new share issue of 7,232,077 shares at SEK 1,300 per share, raising approximately SEK 9.4 billion (equivalent to around $1.1 billion at current rates).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Sinch said that investors buying the shares included &#8220;selected Swedish and international investors of institutional character,&#8221; highlighting that Temasek and SB Management (a direct subsidiary of SoftBank Group Corp.) would  respectively take SEK 2,085 million and 0.7 million shares. This works out to a $252 million investment for Temasek, and $110 million for SoftBank.</p>
<p>SoftBank last December took a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/softbank-takes-a-690m-stake-in-cloud-based-swedish-crm-company-sinch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$690 million stake in Sinch</a> (when it was valued <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/sinch-inteliquent/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">at $8.2 billion). That was just ahead of the company scooping</a> up Inteliquent in the U.S. in January for $1.14 billion to move a little closer to Twilio&#8217;s home turf.</p>
<p>Sinch is not saying much more beyond the announcement of the share issue for now, except that the raise was made to shore up its financial position ahead of more M&amp;A activity.</p>
<p>&#8220;Sinch has an active M&amp;A-agenda and a track record of successful acquisitions, making [it] well placed to drive continued consolidation of the messaging and [communications platform as a service, CPaaS] market,&#8221; it said in a short statement. &#8220;Furthermore, the increased financial flexibility that the directed new share issue entails further strengthens the Company’s position as a relevant and competitive buyer.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company is profitable and active in more than 40 markets, and <a href="https://investors.sinch.com/static-files/6d18a742-dd9f-40af-a973-ff69163aa56b" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CEO Oscar Werner said in Sinch&#8217;s most recent earnings report</a> that in the last quarter alone that its communications APIs &#8212; which works across  channels like SMS, WhatsApp, Facebook Messenger, chatbots, voice and video &#8212; handled 40 billion mobile messages.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Notably, its strategy has a strong foothold in the U.S. because of the Inteliquent acquisition. It will be interesting to see how and if it continues to consolidate to build up market share in that part of the world, or whether it focuses elsewhere, given the heft of two very strong Asian investors now in its stable. </span></p>
<p>“Becoming a leader in the U.S. voice market is key to establish Sinch as the leading global cloud communications platform,” said Werner in January.</p>
<p>While Sinch has focused much of its business, like Twilio, around an API-based model focused on communications services, its acquisition of Inteliquent also gave it access to a large, legacy Infrastructure-as-a-Service (IaaS) product set, aimed at telcos to provide off-net call termination (when a call is handed off from one carrier to another) and toll-free numbers.</p>
<p>Tellingly, when Sinch acquired Inteliquent, the two divisions each accounted for roughly half of its total business, but the CPaaS business is growing at twice the rate of IaaS, which points to how Sinch views the future for itself, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/sinch-a-swedish-customer-engagement-giant-raises-1-1b-softbank-and-temasek-participating/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156966</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google&#8217;s data terms are now in Germany&#8217;s competition crosshairs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/googles-data-terms-are-now-in-germanys-competition-crosshairs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/googles-data-terms-are-now-in-germanys-competition-crosshairs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 11:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreas Mundt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bundeskartellamt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[competition law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Court of Justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156947</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Germany&#8217;s national competition regulator, the Bundeskartellamt, has continued its investigative charge against big tech &#8212; announcing that it&#8217;s opened two proceedings into Google. The move follows earlier proceedings targeting Amazon and Facebook &#8212; both of which are also looking to determine whether their businesses are of “paramount significance for competition across markets”, as German competition law [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Germany&#8217;s national competition regulator, the <em>Bundeskartellamt</em>, has continued its investigative charge against big tech &#8212; <a href="https://www.bundeskartellamt.de/SharedDocs/Meldung/EN/Pressemitteilungen/2021/25_05_2021_Google_19a.html?nn=3591568">announcing</a> that it&#8217;s opened two proceedings into Google.</p>
<p>The move follows earlier proceedings targeting <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/amazons-market-power-to-be-tested-in-germany-in-push-for-early-action-over-antitrust-risks/">Amazon</a> and Facebook &#8212; both of which are also looking to determine whether their businesses are of “paramount significance for competition across markets”, as German competition law puts it. (The regulator is also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/facebook-hit-with-antitrust-probe-for-tying-oculus-use-to-facebook-accounts/">probing Facebook&#8217;s tying of Oculus to Facebook accounts</a>.)</p>
<p>In Google&#8217;s case, one of the <em>Bundeskartellamt&#8217;s </em>new proceedings will confirm whether amended competition rules, which came into force in January, apply in its case &#8212; which would enable the FCO to target it with proactive interventions in the interests of fostering digital competition.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The second, parallel procedure will see the Federal Cartel Office (FCO) undertake an in-depth analysis of Google&#8217;s data processing terms in a move that looks intended to avoid wasting time &#8212; i.e. that its working assumption is that Google/Alphabet&#8217;s business meets the legal bar in the GWB Digitalisation Act.</p>
<p>By running the two Google procedures in parallel the German competition regulator will be in a position to act faster &#8212; assuming the first proceeding confirms it can indeed intervene.</p>
<p>The second probe running alongside would then identify potential problems to shape any intervention &#8212; with the FCO saying for example that it will look at whether Google/Alphabet &#8220;makes the use of services conditional on the users agreeing to the processing of their data without giving them sufficient choice as to whether, how and for what purpose such data are processed&#8221;.</p>
<p>It also says it will &#8220;examine the extent to which the terms provide Google with an opportunity to process data on an extensive cross-service basis&#8221; and will seek to clarify &#8220;how the company’s data processing policy applies to the processing of user data obtained from third-party websites and apps&#8221; (such as through Google’s advertising services).</p>
<p>Another key element of the proceeding will aim to establish what choice users actually have with regard to Google’s processing of their data, with the FCO noting that protecting consumer choice is a primary aim of competition law.</p>
<p>Given those point of focus it&#8217;s possible to imagine a future order from the FCO to Google could require it to simplify how it asks users for consent, to ensure genuine choice &#8212; and also shrink its ability to link first party user data with information obtained on people elsewhere online.</p>
<p>Commenting in a statement, Andreas Mundt, president of the <em>Bundeskartellamt</em> said: &#8220;An ecosystem which extends across various markets may be an indication that a company holds such a market position [i.e. whether it is of paramount significance across markets]. It is often very difficult for other companies to challenge this position of power. Due to the large number of digital services offered by Google, such as the Google search engine, YouTube, Google Maps, the Android operating system or the Chrome browser, the company could be considered to be of paramount significance for competition across markets.”</p>
<p>“Google’s business model relies to a very large extent on processing data relating to its users. Due to its established access to data relevant for competition, Google enjoys a strategic advantage. We will therefore take a close look at the company’s data processing terms. A key question in this context is whether consumers wishing to use Google’s services have sufficient choice as to how Google will use their data,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Reached for comment on the FCO proceedings, Google said it will fully cooperate with the FCO&#8217;s process but rejected the charge that people are forced to use its services &#8212; further claiming in a statement attributed to spokesperson, Ralf Bremer, that it offers &#8220;simple controls&#8221; so people can &#8220;limit&#8221; its use of their information:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;People choose Google because it’s helpful, not because they&#8217;re forced to, or because they can&#8217;t find alternatives. German consumers have enormous choice online and we give people simple <a href="https://safety.google/privacy/ads-and-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://safety.google/privacy/ads-and-data/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1622026087917000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGWH9M-MbTvhZXYsWSJZ4Y_l-LVaw">controls</a> to manage their information and limit the use of personal data. We will cooperate fully with the German Competition Authority and look forward to answering their questions.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The <em>Bundeskartellamt</em>&#8216;s in-depth prove of Google&#8217;s data processing terms picks up on long running criticism that the tech giant relies on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/25/facebook-google-face-first-gdpr-complaints-over-forced-consent/">forced and/or manipulative consent from users</a> to obtain their data. Whereas the pan-EU legal standard if consent is used as a legal basis to process people&#8217;s information is that it should be clear, informed and freely given.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wBKkiuOA6Y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/25/facebook-google-face-first-gdpr-complaints-over-forced-consent/">Facebook, Google face first GDPR complaints over &#8216;forced consent&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook, Google face first GDPR complaints over &#8216;forced consent&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/25/facebook-google-face-first-gdpr-complaints-over-forced-consent/embed/#?secret=wBKkiuOA6Y" data-secret="wBKkiuOA6Y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Back in 2019 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/21/french-data-protection-watchdog-fines-google-57-million-under-the-gdpr/">Google was fined $57M</a> by France&#8217;s data protection watchdog under the EU&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) over a failure to provide “sufficiently clear” information to Android users when it sought their consent to use their data for targeted ads.</p>
<p>However, subsequent to the CNIL&#8217;s action, the tech giant limited its exposure to the privacy regulation by <a href="https://www.blog.google/around-the-globe/google-europe/some-changes-our-service-model-europe/">changing the legal jurisdiction</a> of where it processes European users’ data to Ireland.</p>
<p>The Irish Data Protection Commission (DPC) then became Google&#8217;s lead data supervisor under the GDPR&#8217;s one-stop-shop mechanism. And the DPC has not decided a single GDPR complaint against Google &#8212; though it has a number of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/22/googles-lead-eu-regulator-opens-formal-privacy-probe-of-its-adtech/">open investigations</a>. It continues to face high level criticism over its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/lack-of-big-tech-gdpr-decisions-looms-large-in-eu-watchdogs-annual-report/">enforcement record</a> on key cross-border cases against big tech.</p>
<p>The awakening of European competition regulators to the issue of how abuse of user privacy is an anti-competitive tactic that can lock in the dominance of digital giants by unfairly enabling them to grab and link people&#8217;s data is thus a very important development in the regulation of big tech &#8212; and one where the <em>Bundeskartellamt </em>has already been a pioneer.</p>
<p>In an earlier FCO <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/23/antitrust-case-against-facebooks-super-profiling-back-on-track-after-german-federal-court-ruling/">&#8216;super profiling&#8217; case against Facebook</a> &#8212; which predates the amendments to national digital competition law &#8212; it ordered the social media behemoth not to combine user data from across its different products.</p>
<p>Facebook has sought to block the order in the German courts. And, back in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/competition-challenge-to-facebooks-superprofiling-of-users-sparks-referral-to-europes-top-court/">March</a>, the case was referred to Europe&#8217;s top court &#8212; meaning the FCO&#8217;s order to it remains on hold pending the CJEU&#8217;s ruling (which could take years to be handed down).</p>
<p>The FCO confirmed today that the Facebook case is still pending before the court, reiterating <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">the decision of the </span><span lang="de" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" xml:lang="de">Düsseldorf</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> Higher Regional Court to refer certain issues relating to the application of the GDPR to the European Court of Justice &#8212; which means that a decision on the merits of the case &#8220;can only be rendered after these issues have been clarified&#8221;.</span></p>
<p>The <em>Bundeskartellamt&#8217;s</em> investigation of Facebook&#8217;s data practices started all the way back in in March 2016. So it&#8217;s a safe bet that the regulator&#8217;s experience of digging into the detail of how tech giants process people&#8217;s data &#8212; and how hard it is to make cases stick against them &#8212; has helped inform the amendments to Germany&#8217;s competition law that introduce ex ante powers to tackle digital giants deemed to be of “paramount significance for competition across markets”.</p>
<p>Although there is still another waiting period baked in to this approach &#8212; as the regulator must first assess whether tech giants meet that legal bar.</p>
<p>The EU has proposed a similar ex ante approach for what it dubs as digital &#8220;gatekeepers&#8221;, under the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/europe-lays-out-its-plan-to-reboot-digital-rules-and-tame-tech-giants/">Digital Markets Act</a>, which it introduced at the end of last year.</p>
<p>Although with the bloc&#8217;s co-legislative process ongoing that regulation is likely some years away from adoption and pan-EU application &#8212; meaning Germany&#8217;s national law and the energetic FCO could be a significant actor in the meanwhile.</p>
<p>The EU&#8217;s competition commission are also <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-google-antitrust-eu-idUSKBN29P23U">digging into Google&#8217;s adtech practices</a> &#8212; though they&#8217;re having to do so under existing powers, for now, which have been shown to be a painstakingly slow and not very effective route to tackle digital market power.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in Europe, the UK, which now sits outside the bloc, is also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/27/uk-to-set-up-pro-competition-regulator-to-put-limits-on-big-tech/">shaping its own an ex ante regime</a> to curb the market power of digital giants. So regardless of political cross-currents in the region &#8212; and the problem of patchy privacy enforcement &#8212; there is growing consensus that European competition authorities must be empowered to step in proactively to tackle digital market abuses.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gA1j2bLoGk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/europe-lays-out-its-plan-to-reboot-digital-rules-and-tame-tech-giants/">Europe lays out its plan to reboot digital rules and tame tech giants</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe lays out its plan to reboot digital rules and tame tech giants&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/europe-lays-out-its-plan-to-reboot-digital-rules-and-tame-tech-giants/embed/#?secret=gA1j2bLoGk" data-secret="gA1j2bLoGk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="a1ii3QU7iS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/embed/#?secret=a1ii3QU7iS" data-secret="a1ii3QU7iS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="e4NmsbIKEv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/the-uks-plan-to-tackle-big-tech-wont-be-one-sized-fits-all/">The UK&#8217;s plan to tackle big tech won&#8217;t be one-size fits all</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The UK&#8217;s plan to tackle big tech won&#8217;t be one-size fits all&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/the-uks-plan-to-tackle-big-tech-wont-be-one-sized-fits-all/embed/#?secret=e4NmsbIKEv" data-secret="e4NmsbIKEv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/googles-data-terms-are-now-in-germanys-competition-crosshairs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156947</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weight-loss platform Noom bulks up on $540 million in new funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/weight-loss-platform-noom-bulks-up-on-540-million-in-new-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/weight-loss-platform-noom-bulks-up-on-540-million-in-new-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 11:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[noom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silver lake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weight loss]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156918</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since the pandemic began last year, nearly 61% of adults in the United States gained weight, with the average adult surveyed gaining 15 pounds, according to a report from the American Psychological Association. Likely as a result of that rise in girths, Noom witnessed a surge of demand for its weight-loss app, generating $400 million in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Since the pandemic began last year, nearly 61% of adults in the United States gained weight, with the average adult surveyed gaining 15 pounds, according to <a href="https://www.apa.org/news/press/releases/stress/2021/one-year-pandemic-stress">a report</a> from the American Psychological Association. Likely as a result of that rise in girths, <a href="https://www.noom.com">Noom</a> witnessed a surge of demand for its weight-loss app, generating $400 million in revenues in 2020 — almost twice <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/monicamelton/2020/01/14/weight-loss-app-noom-quadruples-revenue-again-this-time-to-237-million/?sh=25fec78660f2">the $237 million it made the year before</a>.</p>
<p>Following on the heels of a banner year, and to fuel expansion into new categories and new countries around the globe, Noom announced this morning it had raised a $540 million Series F round led by Silver Lake. Other investors who participated in the round included Oak HC/FT, Temasek, Novo Holdings, Sequoia Capital, RRE, and Samsung Ventures.</p>
<p>“Most people want to eat healthier, exercise more, be less stressed, and get better sleep, but it’s not easy to change these behaviors,” said Saeju Jeong, co-founder and CEO of Noom in a statement. “This strategic round of funding reflects our investors’ confidence in the immense opportunity we have in building a business around helping as many people as possible live healthier lives through behavior change.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Noom also announced the addition of two new board members, Silver Lake managing director Adam Karol, and former TaskRabbit CEO Stacy Brown-Philpot.</p>
<p>The Noom app may be a success now with 45 million downloads to date in 100 countries including the U.S., UK, Canada, Australia, Ireland, and New Zealand, but cofounders Jeong and Artem Petakov officially founded their startup in 2007 as a different venture entirely, experimenting with a connected bike and calorie-counting app. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/07/05/noom-weight-loss-coach-gets-a-revamp-after-hitting-13-5m-organic-downloads-on-android/">It had some early success</a>, but it wasn’t until 2017, when Jeong and Petakov released a customer-focused and weight-loss-oriented app that the startup finally hit its stride, resonating with legions of people who longed to shed the weight they’d gained. The company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/06/heath-coaching-app-noom-will-expand-its-product-team-after-raising-58m-led-by-sequoia/">raised $58 million of funding</a> in mid-2019 led by Sequoia.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cEOHJVXy4t"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/06/heath-coaching-app-noom-will-expand-its-product-team-after-raising-58m-led-by-sequoia/">Health coaching app Noom will expand its product team after raising $58M led by Sequoia</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Health coaching app Noom will expand its product team after raising $58M led by Sequoia&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/06/heath-coaching-app-noom-will-expand-its-product-team-after-raising-58m-led-by-sequoia/embed/#?secret=cEOHJVXy4t" data-secret="cEOHJVXy4t" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“If you go and you say, ‘Hey, I can solve hypertension for you, nobody cares,” explains Noom president and co-founder Artem Petakov. “So we put our heads together, and thought, ‘how do you make it work with consumers?’ Well, weight loss is a human value proposition that’s working. Can we double-down on that?”</p>
<p>Though the Noom app enables users to count the number of calories they consume each day — a feature that other apps like MyFitnessPal, LoseIt!, and MyPlate Calorie Counter share — Noom says the key to its users keeping the weight off in the medium-to-long term lies in its use of Cognitive Behavioral Therapy, a goal-oriented psychotherapy treatment that helps people understand and combat the things that trigger negative thoughts, compulsive actions, and unwelcome consequences.</p>
<p>Whether Noom can maintain its momentum remains to be seen. According to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-18/noom-is-said-to-get-silver-lake-backing-ahead-of-potential-ipo?sref=T1S3vg3f">a Bloomberg report</a> last week, the startup has reportedly met with potential advisers to gear up for an IPO later this year or early next year with a targeted valuation of nearly $10 billion.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/weight-loss-platform-noom-bulks-up-on-540-million-in-new-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156918</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Affirm spinout Resolve raises $60M for its B2B &#8216;buy now, pay later&#8217; platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/affirm-spinout-resolve-raises-60m-for-its-b2b-buy-now-pay-later-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/affirm-spinout-resolve-raises-60m-for-its-b2b-buy-now-pay-later-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 11:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affirm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alda Leu Dennis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clocktower Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commerce ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[haystack vc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[initialized capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Max Levchin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online selling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Resolve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156852</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Buy now, pay later is everywhere these days, mostly focused on the consumer. Resolve &#8212; a San Francisco-based startup in the space specializing in &#8220;buy now, pay later&#8221; capabilities for B2B transactions &#8212; announced today that it has raised $60 million in funding. Initialized Capital led the round &#8212; the company’s first funding since its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Buy now, pay later is everywhere these days, mostly focused on the consumer.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Resolve &#8212; a San Francisco-based startup in the space specializing in &#8220;buy now, pay later&#8221; capabilities for B2B transactions &#8212; announced today that it has raised $60 million in funding. Initialized Capital led the round &#8212; the company’s first funding since its 2019 inception. KSD Capital, Haystack VC, Commerce Ventures, Clocktower Ventures and others also participated.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The funding is a combination of equity and asset funding according to co-founder and CEO Chris Tsai, although he declined to reveal the breakdown.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since launching as a spinout from Affirm in 2019, Resolve says it has seen “overwhelming” demand for its B2B buy now, pay later (BNPL) billing offering for business purchases. Notably, the two companies refer business to each other. Tsai describes Affirm founder Max Levchin as a “friend” with whom he has been working in a variety of capacities since 2012. (He’s also reportedly an investor in the company.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unlike Affirm &#8212; which is more focused on the consumer &#8212; Resolve is exclusively focused on business-to-business billing by automating the process of billing and purchasing on credit. What it’s doing is basically allowing businesses to defer payments digitally and on better terms than what they’ve seen historically via an automated underwriting process, the company claims. This, it says, can lead to faster invoice payment and thus, improved cash flow. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company also claims it can offer</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> extended payment terms with buyers not having to pay any interest or fees if accounts are repaid within the agreed-upon terms. Meanwhile, merchants receive full payment (minus any fees) as soon as an order is placed. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2TQh1NMC2E"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/in-the-buy-now-pay-later-wars-paypal-is-primed-for-dominance/">In the &#8216;buy now, pay later&#8217; wars, PayPal is primed for dominance</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;In the &#8216;buy now, pay later&#8217; wars, PayPal is primed for dominance&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/in-the-buy-now-pay-later-wars-paypal-is-primed-for-dominance/embed/#?secret=2TQh1NMC2E" data-secret="2TQh1NMC2E" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Resolve offers businesses loan terms ranging from 30 to 90 days and gives them more control of their billing and cash flow, according to Tsai. While he declined to give specifics around any growth metrics, he said the company has seen a &#8220;significant and meaningful&#8221; uptick in growth in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic because of so many businesses&#8217; shift to digital e-commerce. For example, one of its customers is a bike merchant that had to expand into online selling in the wake of the pandemic.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This is not a new transaction type, but being able to do it in this new digital or e-commerce way of buy now, pay later, like Affirm &#8212; that&#8217;s very new and in fact it&#8217;s still very much not the norm yet,” he told TechCrunch. “But we&#8217;re finding, especially post-pandemic, incredible demand for switching to more digital e-commerce payment formats.”</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2156856" style="width: 1013px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2156856" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2156856 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Resolve-Product-Images.jpg" alt="" width="1003" height="781" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Resolve-Product-Images.jpg 1003w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Resolve-Product-Images.jpg?resize=150,117 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Resolve-Product-Images.jpg?resize=300,234 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Resolve-Product-Images.jpg?resize=768,598 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Resolve-Product-Images.jpg?resize=680,529 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Resolve-Product-Images.jpg?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1003px) 100vw, 1003px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2156856" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Resolve</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Among Resolve’s features is a “Smart Credit Engine,” which the company says creates a direct sync with a merchant’s real-time data feed of past payment histories to allow for “immediate” credit line decisioning with no input required from buyers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Its embedded bill payment portal gives its B2B customers a way to pay vendor bills “while building their business credit history” bureaus, the company says.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Digital and e-commerce transformation is coming for B2B payments,” Tsai said. “Growing companies must balance heightened demand for deferring payments from their business customers with their own limited capacities to satisfy that demand.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The embedded nature of Resolve’s platform gives it an edge, Tsai believes, in that it integrates into a company’s existing financial tech stack. The benefit to the business, he said, is increased growth and sales revenue as well as optimized cash flow “while removing risk for the company.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Initialized Capital General Partner Alda Leu Dennis said she was familiar with Tsai and co-founder Brian </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nguyen</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> since their days at Celery, their prior startup. She views them as experienced and determined.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We also have conviction around the clear market need for digitizing net terms for small businesses that are increasingly moving their ordering online,” she said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In her view, Resolve&#8217;s unique differentiation is that it provides software that solves net terms billing complexity. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Businesses desperately need to manage their B2B billing operations, from helping them gauge the strength of their customers to chasing down payments,” she told TechCrunch. “Their [Resolve’s] approach of accelerating payments and collections via software and offering payment terms as an ancillary service is a powerful pairing; it provides an easy yet comprehensive way for merchants to improve their entire system of managing receivables and billing on credit.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The San Francisco startup is using the money primarily to grow its embedded billing platform.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We&#8217;re doing a lot of work to scale the platform. So we&#8217;re investing heavily in products and the customer sides of the business, given all the demand that we&#8217;ve seen,” Tsai said. “The operations software that we’ve built is very seamless for our customers, but there&#8217;s a lot going on in the background that we have to do to reduce the complexity for our customers.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="37M9ciFiug"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/tillit/">Tillit, a fintech offering buy now, pay later for B2B purchases, is closing in on investment from Sequoia</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tillit, a fintech offering buy now, pay later for B2B purchases, is closing in on investment from Sequoia&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/tillit/embed/#?secret=37M9ciFiug" data-secret="37M9ciFiug" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/affirm-spinout-resolve-raises-60m-for-its-b2b-buy-now-pay-later-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156852</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Venture capital investment in Africa predicted to reach a record high this year</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/venture-capital-investment-in-africa-predicted-to-reach-a-record-high-this-year/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/venture-capital-investment-in-africa-predicted-to-reach-a-record-high-this-year/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 10:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flutterwave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TymeBank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital investments]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Investments in African startups keep growing at a healthy pace ever since reports started keeping count in 2015. That year, publications Disrupt Africa and Partech released independently researched and contrasting figures showing that venture capital investments hit $186 million and $277 million, respectively. Those are ridiculously low figures for a continent when you consider that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investments in African startups keep growing at a healthy pace ever since reports started keeping count in 2015</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">That year, publications Disrupt Africa and Partech released independently researched and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/07/23/the-rise-of-silicon-savannah-and-africas-tech-movement/">contrasting figures</a> showing that venture capital investments hit $186 million and $277 million, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">respectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Those are </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ridiculously</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> low figures for a continent when you consider that four-year-old Snapchat raised more than $500 million in one round that same year</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. However, w</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">hile the disparity in funding between Africa and a single high-growth U.S. startup continues, the good news is that more money is coming into the continent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2019, Africa&#8217;s venture capital investments rose to an all-time high, per Partech&#8217;s report</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. According to Partech, 234 African tech companies <a href="https://partechpartners.com/documents/12/2020.01_Partech_Africa_-_2019_Africa_Tech_VC_Report_FINAL.pdf">raised $2.02 billion</a> in 250 equity rounds. This indicated a 74% increase from 2018’s figure of $1.163 billion raised by 146 startups in 164 rounds.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was shared</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> optimism that 2020 would record a new high, but that was before the pandemic struck. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For that reason, African tech ecosystem accelerator <a href="https://www.africarena.com/">AfricArena</a> predicted that venture capital funding in the continent&#8217;s startups would <a href="https://techpoint.africa/2020/05/06/african-venture-capital-to-drop-by-40-at-the-end-of-the-year/">fall between</a> $1.2 billion and $1.8 billion</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In what may </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be described</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as an educated guess or a calculated prediction by the publication, year-end reports by Partech and Briter Bridges pegged total investment raised at $1.4 billion and $1.3 billion, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">respectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XZWXCn6sf1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/how-african-startups-raised-investments-in-2020/">How African startups raised investments in 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How African startups raised investments in 2020&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/how-african-startups-raised-investments-in-2020/embed/#?secret=XZWXCn6sf1" data-secret="XZWXCn6sf1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This year, AfricArena, in <a href="https://f1d0651a-c40a-4877-b5d5-7f6204467ba9.filesusr.com/ugd/cdd60c_5d9debf5822c4e84940b69925d8d2ba2.pdf">a new report</a>, is predicting that VC funding in the continent&#8217;s startups would increase between $2.25 billion and $2.8 billion, which, if met, will surpass 2019 figures for a record high on the continent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here&#8217;s the rationale behind the prediction from an excerpt in the report:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We foresee that the first two quarters of 2021 will be similar Q4 2020 with the mix of factors. Vaccine campaigns will likely take longer than hoped to have a meaningful impact. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, this rollout – regardless of how long they will actually take &#8211; will </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">eliminate</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the major uncertainty about the end of the pandemic, which is only a question of time</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a result, we expect an </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">extremely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> strong acceleration of deals from seed to Series B as well as major growth deals, together with some IPOs (Nigeria’s Interswitch, for example), that will propel deal activity to never seen before levels of activity</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">As of April 2020, our forecast for 2021 ranged from under $1.6 billion to over $3 billion. The worst-case scenario was based on a prolonged and fragmented impact on the African economies and the best-case scenario factoring in a full recovery Q1 2021</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Based on the above observations, our views are now that 2021 will range between $2.25 and $2.8 billion.</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As of April 30, the total disclosed venture capital funding stood a <a href="https://twitter.com/MaxBayen/status/1388051116831744000">little over $800 million</a>, according to Maxime Bayen, deal tracker and senior venture builder at BFA Global</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If that pace </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is kept</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> throughout the year, African startups might raise more than $2 billion.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2156949" style="width: 585px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2156949" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2156949" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-147.png?w=575" alt="AfricArena" width="575" height="341" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-147.png 575w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-147.png?resize=150,89 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-147.png?resize=300,178 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-147.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 575px) 100vw, 575px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2156949" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> AfricArena</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2020, the number of early-stage deals increased, but there was a drop in growth deals and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">overall</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> ticket sizes, constituting the drop in funding activities</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Per <a href="https://cdn-website.partechpartners.com/media/documents/2021-02_Partech_Africa_2020_Africa_Tech_VC_Report.pdf">Partech</a>, seed rounds grew 80% year-on-year and accounted for 64% of all deals made. In total, African startups raised $220 million in seed funding, which was a 47% increase year on year. Series A and B rounds grew likewise. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Series A deals went up 9% (86 rounds), and Series B deals, 16% (29 rounds), yet their investment sizes dropped 5% ($447 million) and 8% ($449 million), </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">respectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Growth deals also dropped by 16%, and only two deals closed above $50 million compared to the 10 that took place in 2019, some of which include Interswitch, OPay, Branch and Andela</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The driving force to exceed the $2 billion mark in 2021 lies on VCs to make more deals and startups to replicate the large growth rounds of 2019</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The former appears to be in place as African startups continue to raise money week in and week out. However, there&#8217;s still work to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be done</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for the latter, as only two African startups have raised more than $100 million in a single round so far &#8212; fintech startups <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/african-payments-company-flutterwave-raises-170m-now-valued-at-over-1b/">Flutterwave</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/south-african-digital-bank-tymebank-lands-109m-from-uk-and-phillippines-investors/">TymeBank</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ln90GNnSLl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/african-countries-need-startup-acts-more-than-ever-to-support-innovation/">African countries need &#8216;startup acts&#8217; more than ever to support innovation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;African countries need &#8216;startup acts&#8217; more than ever to support innovation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/african-countries-need-startup-acts-more-than-ever-to-support-innovation/embed/#?secret=Ln90GNnSLl" data-secret="Ln90GNnSLl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/venture-capital-investment-in-africa-predicted-to-reach-a-record-high-this-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156797</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indian logistics SaaS startup FarEye raises $100 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/indian-logistics-saas-startup-fareye-raises-100-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/indian-logistics-saas-startup-fareye-raises-100-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 10:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dragoneer investment group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eight Roads Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fareye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Honeywell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TCV]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156944</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[FarEye, an Indian SaaS startup that helps firms globally optimize their supply chain and logistics operations, said on Tuesday it has raised a new financing round, its third since the pandemic broke last year, as it looks to further expand in international markets. The Noida-headquartered startup has raised $100 million in its Series E round, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">FarEye, an Indian SaaS startup that helps firms <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/14/fareye-series-d-india-logistics/">globally optimize their supply chain and logistics operations</a>, said on Tuesday it has raised a new financing round, its third since the pandemic broke last year, as it looks to further expand in international markets.</p>
<p>The Noida-headquartered startup has raised $100 million in its Series E round, which was co-led by high-profile backers TCV and Dragoneer Investment Group. Existing investors Eight Roads Ventures, Fundamentum, Honeywell also participated in the round, which takes seven-and-a-half-year-old startup’s to-date raise to about $153 million.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.getfareye.com/">FarEye</a> helps companies orchestrate, track, and optimize their logistics operations. The startup’s flagship logistics management software supports the entire supply chain &#8212; from first-mile seller pick-ups to last-mile delivery &#8212; to provide end-to-end logistics visibility, reduce operational costs and improve customer experience.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>One use case of FarEye&#8217;s technology, as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/indian-logistics-saas-startup-fareye-bags-13-million/">we wrote last year</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Say you order a pizza from Domino’s, the eatery uses FarEye’s service, which integrates into the system it is using, to quickly inform the customer how long they need to wait for the food to reach them.</p>
<p>Behind the scenes, FarEye is helping Domino’s evaluate a number of moving pieces. How many delivery people are in the vicinity? Can it bundle a few orders? What’s the maximum number of items one can carry? How experienced is the delivery person? What’s the best route to reach the customer? And, would the restaurant need the same number of delivery people the following day?</p></blockquote>
<p>The startup works with over 150 e-commerce and delivery companies globally &#8212; including popular names such as Walmart, UPS, DHL e-commerce, Domino’s, Posti, and Gordon Foods, and Amway &#8212; and processes over 100 million transactions each month.</p>
<p>More than two million vehicles and over 25,000 drivers are on FarEye&#8217;s platform today.</p>
<p>The coronavirus pandemic has helped the business as more companies, including large FMCG brands and retailers, begin to engage directly with customers, sort out their logistics and look for optimizing the cost, said Nahata in an interview.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s not like these companies didn&#8217;t knew,&#8221; Nahata said, referring to companies building and digitizing their own logistics. &#8220;Earlier this was on their three-to-five year plans, but now they want to deploy this in within a quarter.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1974650" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1974650" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1974650 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="631" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg 2687w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg?resize=150,93 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg?resize=300,185 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg?resize=768,474 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg?resize=680,419 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg?resize=1536,947 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg?resize=2048,1263 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fareye_team.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1974650" class="wp-caption-text">Gautam Kumar (left), Gaurav Srivastava (centre), and Kushal Nahata co-founded FarEye in 2013</p></div></p>
<p>“The logistics and supply chain industry is going through a long awaited software-led creative disruption, led by emerging leaders like FarEye that provide multi- tenant SaaS platforms with low code configuration to enhance visibility to the enterprise and deliver superlative last mile experiences for the end consumer. Gopi Vaddi, General Partner at TCV,</p>
<p>Customers are also beginning to place more orders online. &#8220;For existing customers, we have seen an increase in volume of orders especially in grocery and food categories,&#8221; Nahata said.</p>
<p>The firm today also has clients in several international markets including the U.S., Europe, and Singapore, that is already bringing more than half of revenues for the startup and has grown nearly three times in the past 12 months.</p>
<p>Nahata said the startup didn&#8217;t initially think that Western markets would be prone to similar logistics challenges as those in India and other Asian markets, but despite the growth of e-commerce in some markets, some common underlying issues remain.</p>
<p>Nahata also pointed out that the payments infrastructure that has emerged in India in recent years still doesn&#8217;t exist in other markets, which creates an additional challenge to tackle for the firm.</p>
<p>“FarEye’s leading delivery management platform provides impressive visibility and control across the supply chain, which has never been more critical for retailers, manufacturers and 3PLs,” said Eric Jones, Partner at Dragoneer Investment Group, in a statement. “We look forward to partnering with FarEye as they continue to redefine how products are delivered across diverse logistics networks and expand their footprint in Europe and North America.”</p>
<p>The startup recently hired a number of senior executives including a new CRO (Amit Bagga &#8212; formerly President of APAC at BlueYonder and  and strategic sales leader at Oracle), and a new CPO (Suvrat Joshi &#8212; former executive at Dropbox, Amazon, Facebook, Microsoft.) It&#8217;s looking to further expand the team and is also open to exploring acquisition of smaller firms in international markets, said Nahata.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/indian-logistics-saas-startup-fareye-raises-100-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156944</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Interactio, a remote interpretation platform, grabs $30M after seeing 12x growth during COVID-19</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/interactio-a-remote-interpretation-platform-grabs-30m-after-seeing-12x-growth-during-covid-19/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/interactio-a-remote-interpretation-platform-grabs-30m-after-seeing-12x-growth-during-covid-19/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 07:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Assistant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eight Roads Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european parliament]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interactio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jaan Tallinn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jp morgan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lithuania]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine translation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Notion Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online meetings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Practica Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silicon Valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Skype]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[storm ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Translation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Translator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[united nations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video conferencing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web conferencing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WebEX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[young sohn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156367</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Interactio, a remote interpretation platform whose customers include massive institutions like the United Nations, European Commission and Parliament along with corporates like BMW, JP Morgan and Microsoft, has closed a whopping $30 million Series A after usage of its tools grew 12x between 2019 and 2020 as demand for online meeting platforms surged during the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.interactio.io">Interactio</a>, a remote interpretation platform whose customers include massive institutions like the United Nations, European Commission and Parliament along with corporates like BMW, JP Morgan and Microsoft, has closed a whopping $30 million Series A after usage of its tools grew 12x between 2019 and 2020 as demand for online meeting platforms surged during the coronavirus pandemic.</p>
<p>The Series A funding is led by Eight Roads Ventures and Silicon Valley-based Storm Ventures, along with participation from Practica Capital, Notion Capital, as well as notable angels such as Jaan Tallinn, the co-founder of Skype, and Young Sohn, ex-chief strategy officer of Samsung.</p>
<p>The Vilnius, Lithuania-based startup offers digital tools to connect meetings with certified interpreters who carry out real-time interpretation to bridge language divides between participants. It does also offer a video conferencing platform which its customers can use to run remote meetings but will happily integrate with thirty party software like Zoom, Webex etc. (Last year it says its digital tools were used alongside 43 different video streaming platforms.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Interactio&#8217;s interpreters can be in the room where the meeting is taking place or doing the real-time interpretation entirely remotely by watching and listening to a stream of the meeting. (Or, indeed, it can support a mix of remote and on-site interpretation, if a client wishes.)</p>
<p>It can also supply all the interpreters for a meeting &#8212; and it touts a strict vetting procedure for onboarding certified interpreters to its platform &#8212; or else it will provide training to a customer&#8217;s interpreters on the use of its tools to ensure things run smoothly on the day.</p>
<p>At present, Interactio says it works with 1,000+ freelance interpreters, as well as touting &#8220;strong relations with interpretation agencies&#8221; &#8212; claiming it can easily quadruple the pool of available interpreters to step up to meet rising demand.</p>
<p>It offers its customers interpretation in any language &#8212; and in an unlimited number of languages per event. And last year it says it hosted 18,000+ meetings with 390,000 listeners spread across more than 70 countries.</p>
<p>Now, flush with a huge Series A, Interactio is gearing up for a future filled with increasing numbers of multi-lingual online meetings &#8212; as the coronavirus continues to inject friction into business travel.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we started, our biggest competition was simultaneous interpretation hardware for on-site interpretation. At that time, we were on the mission to fully replace it with our software that required zero additional hardware for attendees besides their phone and headphones. However, for institutions, which became our primary focus, hybrid meetings are the key, so we started partnering with simultaneous interpretation hardware manufacturers and integrators by working together on hybrid events, where participants use hardware on-site, and online participants use us,&#8221; a spokeswoman told us.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is how we differentiate ourselves from other platforms &#8212; by offering a fully hybrid solution, that can be integrated with hardware on-site basically via one cable.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Moreover, when we look at the market trends, we still see Zoom as the most used solution, so we compliment it by offering professional interpretation solutions,&#8221; she added.</p>
<p>A focus on customer support is another tactic that Interactio says it relies upon to stand out &#8212; and its iOS and Android apps do have high ratings on aggregate. (Albeit, there are bunch of historical complaints mixed in suggesting it&#8217;s had issues scaling its service to large audiences in the past, as well as sporadic problems with things like audio quality over the years.)</p>
<p>While already profitable, the 2014-founded startup says the  Series A will be used to step on the gas to continue to meet the accelerated demand and exponential growth it&#8217;s seen during the remote work boom.</p>
<p>Specifically, the funds will go on enhancing its tech and UX/UI &#8212; with a focus on ensuring ease of access/simplicity for those needing to access interpretation, and also on upgrading the tools it provides to interpreters (so they have &#8220;the best working conditions from their chosen place of work&#8221;).</p>
<p>It will also be spending to expand its client base &#8212; and is especially seeking to onboard more corporates and other types of customers. (&#8220;Last year’s focus was and still is institutions (e.g. European Commission, European Parliament, United Nations), where there is no place for an error and they need the most professional solution. The next step will be to expand our client base to corporate clients and a larger public that needs interpretation,&#8221; it told us.)</p>
<p>The new funding will also be used to expand the size of its team to support those goals, including growing the number of qualified interpreters it works with so it can keep pace with rising demand.</p>
<p>While major institutions like the UN are never going to be tempted to skimp on the quality of translation provided to diplomats and politicians by <em>not</em> using human interpreters (either on premise or working remotely), there may be a limit on how far professional real-time translation can scale given the availability of real-time machine translation technology &#8212; which offers a cheap alternative to support more basic meeting scenarios, such as between two professionals having an informal meeting.</p>
<p>Google, for example, offers <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/12/interpreter-googles-real-time-translator-comes-to-mobile/">a real-time translator mode</a> that&#8217;s accessible to users of its smartphone platform via the Google voice assistant AI. Hardware startups are also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/05/waverly-labs-new-wearable-translater-arrives-in-april-at-200/">trying to target real-time translation</a>. The dream of a real-life AI-powered &#8216;Babel Fish&#8217; remains strong.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, such efforts aren&#8217;t well suited to supporting meetings and conferences at scale &#8212; where having a centralized delivery service that&#8217;s also responsible for troubleshooting any audio quality or other issues which may arise looks essential.</p>
<p>And while machine translation has undoubtedly got a lot better over the years (albeit performance can vary, depending on the languages involved) there is still a risk that key details could be lost in translation if/when the machine gets it wrong. So offering highly scalable human translation via a digital platform looks like a safe bet as the world gets accustomed to more remote work (and less globetrotting) being the new normal.</p>
<p>&#8220;AI-driven translation is a great tool when you need a quick solution and are willing to sacrifice the quality,&#8221; says Interactio when we ask about this. &#8220;Our clients are large corporations and institutions, therefore, any kind of misunderstanding can be crucial. Here, the translation is not about saying a word in a different language, it’s about giving the meaning and communicating a context via interpretation.</p>
<p>&#8220;We strongly believe that only humans can understand the true context and meaning of conversations, where sometimes a tone of voice, an emotion and a figure speech can make a huge difference, that is unnoticed by a machine.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="20YWHRK3Oe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/14/zoom-launches-its-events-platform-and-marketplace-brings-apps-to-your-calls/">Zoom launches its events platform and marketplace, brings apps to your calls</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Zoom launches its events platform and marketplace, brings apps to your calls&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/14/zoom-launches-its-events-platform-and-marketplace-brings-apps-to-your-calls/embed/#?secret=20YWHRK3Oe" data-secret="20YWHRK3Oe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="A8pXo9q3Us"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/salesforce-updates-includes-sales-info-overlay-for-zoom-meetings/">Salesforce updates includes sales info overlay for Zoom meetings</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Salesforce updates includes sales info overlay for Zoom meetings&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/salesforce-updates-includes-sales-info-overlay-for-zoom-meetings/embed/#?secret=A8pXo9q3Us" data-secret="A8pXo9q3Us" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AQtCnzKROP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/otter-ais-new-assistant-can-automatically-transcribe-your-zoom-meetings/">Otter.ai&#8217;s new assistant can automatically transcribe your Zoom meetings</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Otter.ai&#8217;s new assistant can automatically transcribe your Zoom meetings&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/otter-ais-new-assistant-can-automatically-transcribe-your-zoom-meetings/embed/#?secret=AQtCnzKROP" data-secret="AQtCnzKROP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/interactio-a-remote-interpretation-platform-grabs-30m-after-seeing-12x-growth-during-covid-19/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156367</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
