<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 08:36:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>GoCardless raises another $95M as it bets on open banking alongside its recurring payments network</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/gogardless-series-f/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/gogardless-series-f/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 08:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088104</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[GoCardless, the London fintech that aims to become the one-stop shop globally for businesses that want to let customers pay via recurring bank payments, has raised $95 million in Series F funding. According to The Telegraph newspaper, this gives the company much coveted unicorn status. However, I understand the round values GoCardless at just over [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://gocardless.com/">GoCardless</a>, the London fintech that aims to become the one-stop shop globally for businesses that want to let customers pay via recurring bank payments, has raised $95 million in Series F funding.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/2020/12/14/gocardless-secures-billion-dollar-valuation-raising-95m/">According to The Telegraph newspaper</a>, this gives the company much coveted unicorn status. However, I understand the round values GoCardless at just over $970 million, meaning that the 2011-founded fintech is perhaps best described as a soonicorn (presuming these things are important to you).</p>
<p>The latest fundraise was led by Bain Capital Ventures, and follows 46% year-on-year growth for GoCardless as it benefits from an increase in e-commerce and online payments generally during the pandemic. It brings the total raised by the company to-date to $240 million.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>GoCardless says it will use the funding to accelerate its open banking strategy, which will see it combine open banking-enabled bank-to-bank payments with the global bank debit payments network it has already built out. “For the first time, merchants will be able to access the best of both worlds for recurring payments: Instant open banking payments will provide visibility and speed, while bank debit maximises cash flow and minimises churn by pulling funds automatically from payers &#8211; all at a lower cost than cards,” pitches the fintech.</p>
<p>In addition &#8212; and noteworthy &#8212; GoCardless says it will also expand its offering into the “adjacent e-commerce market” to launch a simple and secure way of making open banking-enabled bank-to-bank payments as a lower-cost alternative to cards.</p>
<p>The company has always pitched direct debits as a much better recurring payments method, especially for subscription commerce and regular B2B payments. That’s because, amongst other things, debit and credit cards expire, breaking any subsequent recurring payments. By adding bank-to-bank payments to its stack, GoCardless is continuing to push up against the card network duopoly of Visa and Mastercard.</p>
<p>“We think the magic is in the combination of open banking payments and our existing direct debit platform,” co-founder and CEO Hiroki Takeuchi tells me, when asked why GoCardless is entering the soon to be commoditized space of open banking payments.</p>
<p>“They are really complimentary as open banking is faster and more secure but direct debit is more flexible and more reliable. The combination will create something entirely new and unique that will not only make our product better for our existing customers but also enable us to go after new markets”.</p>
<p>He says that GoCardless already has the required FCA permissions to do open banking payments, and new products are actively under development. Debut products will be launching in the first half of 2021.</p>
<p>“We have been following open banking very closely but we felt it wasn’t reliable enough or slick enough for payments until quite recently,” adds Takeuchi. “This has been changing and we think now is the perfect time to focus on open banking payments”.</p>
<p>One interesting aspect of open banking is that the U.K. regulator is currently consulting with the industry on plans to make recurring payments possible via open banking, meaning that they could be used instead of direct debits. Arguably, GoCardless’ biggest moat is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/17/goamerica/">the global recurring payments network</a> it has built, and so I put it to Takeuchi that open banking is both an opportunity and a threat to GoCardless.</p>
<p>“We don&#8217;t worry about this &#8211; we are agnostic to the rails we build on,” he says, pushing back. “What we care about is getting money from one bank account to another as efficiently as possible. In fact, we processed the first (and I think maybe the only) variable recurring payment via open banking last year as part of a test we worked on with the open banking team.</p>
<p>“If open banking offers rails that replicate direct debit then we will adopt those. The reality is that the payment itself is only a small part of the overall value we provide for our merchants &#8212; there are a lot of other basics such as reconciliation, refunds, international settlement, FX etc. that are really important &#8212; so we are confident that there is still a lot for us to do”.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hJRo24pnrb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/17/goamerica/">GoCardless launches US debit payments solution and opens San Francisco office</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GoCardless launches US debit payments solution and opens San Francisco office&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/17/goamerica/embed/#?secret=hJRo24pnrb" data-secret="hJRo24pnrb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/gogardless-series-f/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088104</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google expands languages push in India to serve non-English speakers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/google-expands-languages-push-in-india-to-serve-non-english-speakers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/google-expands-languages-push-in-india-to-serve-non-english-speakers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 06:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google-Maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088418</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are over 600 million internet users in India, but only a fraction of this population is fluent in English. Most online services and much of the content on the web currently, however, are available exclusively in English. This language barrier continues to contribute to a digital divide in the world’s second largest internet market [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There are over 600 million internet users in India, but only a fraction of this population is fluent in English. Most online services and much of the content on the web currently, however, are available exclusively in English.</p>
<p>This language barrier continues to contribute to a digital divide in the world’s second largest internet market that has limited hundreds of millions of users’ rendition of the world wide web to a select few websites and services.</p>
<p>So it comes as no surprise that American tech giants, which are counting on emerging markets such as India to continue their growth. are increasingly attempting to make the web and their services accessible to more people.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Case in point: A feature that <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/google" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="google">Google <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> provides to quickly translate the content of a web page from English to Indian languages has been used more than 17 billion times by users in India in the past year.</p>
<p>Google, which has so far led this effort, on Thursday unveiled some of its new efforts. The company &#8212; which counts India as its biggest market by users, and this year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/13/google-to-invest-10-billion-in-india/">committed to invest more than $10 billion in the country</a> over the coming years &#8212; <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">said it plans to invest more in machine learning and AI efforts at Google&#8217;s research center in India and make its AI models accessible to everyone across the ecosystem. The company </span><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">also plans to partner with local startups that are serving users in local languages, and &#8220;drastically&#8221; improve the experience of Google products and services for Indian language users.</span></p>
<p>On that last part, the company today announced a range of changes it is rolling out across some of its services to make them speak more local languages and unveiled a whole new approach it’s taking to translate languages.</p>
<h2>Product changes</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2088428" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image-1.gif" alt="" width="500" height="500" /></p>
<p>Users will now be able to see search results to their queries in Tamil, Telugu, Bangla, and Marathi, in addition to English and Hindi that are currently available. The addition comes four years after Google added the Hindi tab to the search page in India. The company said the volume of search queries in Hindi grew more than 10 times after the introduction of this tab. If someone prefers to see their query in Tamil, for instance, now they will be able to set Tamil tab next to English and quickly toggle between the two.</p>
<p>Getting search results in a local language is helpful, but often people want to make their queries in those languages as well. Google says it has found that typing in non-English language is another challenge users face today. “As a result, many users search in English even if they really would prefer to see results in a local language they understand,” the company said.</p>
<p>To address this challenge, Search will start to show relevant content in supported Indian languages where appropriate even if the local language query is typed in English. The feature, which the company plans to roll out over the next month, supports five Indian languages: Hindi, Bangla, Marathi, Tamil, and Telugu.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical alignnone size-full wp-image-2088426" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/image.gif" alt="" width="300" height="583" /></p>
<p>Google is also making it easier for users to quickly change the preferred language in which they see results in an app without altering the device’s language settings. The feature, which is currently available in Discover and Google Assistant, will now roll out in Maps. Maps supports 9 Indian languages.</p>
<p>Similarly, Google Lens’s Homework feature, which allows users to take a picture of a math or science problem and then delivers its answer and walks students through the steps on how to get there, now supports Hindi language. India is the biggest market for Google Lens, said Nidhi Gupta, Senior Product Manager at Google India, at the event.</p>
<p>Jayanth Kolla, chief analyst at consultancy firm Convergence Catalyst, said the new feature of Google Lens could pose a threat to some Indian startups such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/01/two-year-old-indian-edtech-startup-doubtnut-raises-15m/">Sequoia Capital-backed Doubtnut</a> that operates in a similar space.</p>
<h2>MuRIL</h2>
<p>Google executives also detailed a new language AI model, which they are calling <a href="https://tfhub.dev/google/MuRIL/1">Multilingual Representations for Indian Languages</a> (MuRIL), that delivers more efficiency and accuracy in handling transliteration, spelling variations and mixed languages and other nuances of languages. MuRIL provides support for transliterated text when writing Hindi using Roman script, which was something missing from previous models of its kind, said Partha Talukdar, Research Scientist at Google Research India, at a virtual event Thursday.</p>
<p>The company said it trained the new model with articles on Wikipedia and texts from a dataset called Common Crawl. It also trained it on transliterated text from, among other sources, Wikipedia (fed through Google&#8217;s existing neural machine translation models). The result is that MuRIL handles Indian languages better than previous, more general language models and can contend with letters and words that have been transliterated &#8212; that is, Google is using the closest corresponding letters of a different alphabet or script.</p>
<p>Talukdar noted that the previous model Google relied on proved unscalable as the company had to build model for each language separately. &#8220;Building such language specific modeling for each and every task is not resource efficient as we often don&#8217;t have training data for tasks like this,&#8221; he said. MuRIL significantly outperforms the earlier model &#8212; by 10% on native text and 27% on transliterated text. MuRIL, which was developed by Google executives in India and is being in use for about a year, is now open source.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2088440" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2088440" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2088440 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/muril-google.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="850" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/muril-google.jpg 1160w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/muril-google.jpg?resize=150,125 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/muril-google.jpg?resize=300,249 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/muril-google.jpg?resize=768,638 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/muril-google.jpg?resize=680,565 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/muril-google.jpg?resize=50,42 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2088440" class="wp-caption-text">MuRIL supports 16 Indian languages and English.</p></div></p>
<p>One of the many tasks MuRIL is good at, is determining the sentiment of the sentence. For example, “Achha hua account bandh nahi hua” would previously be interpreted as having a negative meaning, but MuRIL correctly identifies this as a positive statement, said Talukdar. Or take the ability to classify a person versus a place: ‘Shirdi ke sai baba’ would previously be interpreted as a place, which is wrong, but MuRIL correctly interprets it as a person.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/google-expands-languages-push-in-india-to-serve-non-english-speakers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088418</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Waresix acquires Trukita to connect more of Indonesia&#8217;s fragmented logistics chain</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/waresix-acquires-trukita-to-connect-more-of-indonesias-fragmented-logistics-chain/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/waresix-acquires-trukita-to-connect-more-of-indonesias-fragmented-logistics-chain/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 03:32:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trukita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waresix]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088405</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Waresix, one of Indonesia’s largest logistics startups, has acquired Trukita, a company that focuses on the &#8220;first mile.&#8221; The term refers to the part of the supply chain where goods are transported from ports to warehouses. Both Waresix and Trukita operate by connecting businesses to shippers and warehouses, and the acquisition will enable them to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2088406" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Andree-Susanto-CEO-and-Co-Founder-of-Waresix-left-and-Ady-Bangun-CEO-and-Co-Founder-of-Trukita-e1608175845810.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2088406" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2088406" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Andree-Susanto-CEO-and-Co-Founder-of-Waresix-left-and-Ady-Bangun-CEO-and-Co-Founder-of-Trukita-e1608175845810.jpg" alt="Andree Susanto, CEO and co-founder of Waresix, left, with Ady Bangun, CEO and co-founder of Trukita" width="1024" height="677" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2088406" class="wp-caption-text">Andree Susanto, CEO and co-founder of Waresix, left, with Ady Bangun, CEO and co-founder of <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/trukita" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="trukita">Trukita</p></div></p> <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>
<p><a href="https://waresix.com/">Waresix</a>, one of Indonesia’s largest logistics startups, has acquired <a href="https://trukita.com/">Trukita</a>, a company that focuses on the &#8220;first mile.&#8221; The term refers to the part of the supply chain where goods are transported from ports to warehouses.</p>
<p>Both Waresix and Trukita operate by connecting businesses to shippers and warehouses, and the acquisition will enable them to lower customer costs. While Waresix&#8217;s platform digitizes all parts of the supply and logistics chain, its current focus is on mid-mile logistics services, or transportation from warehouses to distributors.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Trukita has an extended network of over 10,000 trucks, and the combination of the two companies means it is &#8220;now one of the largest logistics technology providers in Indonesia,&#8221; said co-founder and chief executive officer Andree Susanto.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oQOITIXz4B"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/04/waresix-raises-14-5m/">Waresix hauls in $14.5M to advance its push to digitize logistics in Indonesia</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Waresix hauls in $14.5M to advance its push to digitize logistics in Indonesia&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/04/waresix-raises-14-5m/embed/#?secret=oQOITIXz4B" data-secret="oQOITIXz4B" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Waresix, which recently announced it <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/indonesian-logistics-tech-startup-waresix-closes-cus100-million-fundraising-301126991.html">raised $100 million</a> in funding over the past year from investors like EV Growth, Jungle Ventures and SoftBank Ventures Asia, works with more than 375 warehouses and 40,000 trucks across Indonesia, the world’s fourth most populous country. It currently serves about 100 cities.</p>
<p>Indonesia’s geography creates unique challenges for logistics companies, especially those operating outside of major cities. It is an archipelago made up of more than 17,500 islands, of which 6,000 are inhabited. This means supply chains often span ships, trucks and several warehouses before goods make it to their final destination. The high costs of logistics has a sizable impact on Indonesia’s economy and the <a href="https://www.thejakartapost.com/news/2020/09/28/govt-to-proceed-with-logistics-system-reform-amid-high-costs.html">government is currently engaged in an initiative </a>to develop more infrastructure, integrate databases and simplify export-import licensing.</p>
<p>Indonesia’s complicated logistics landscape has given rise to startups like Waresix, Kargo and Ritase, which focus on removing middlemen, managing shipments in real-time and using data analytics to uncover inefficiencies in the supply chain.</p>
<p>Trukita was founded in 2017, and its investors include Astra International, EverHaüs and Plug and Play.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AVNOOuI7Ed"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/17/how-tech-can-build-more-resilient-supply-chains/">How tech can build more resilient supply chains</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How tech can build more resilient supply chains&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/17/how-tech-can-build-more-resilient-supply-chains/embed/#?secret=AVNOOuI7Ed" data-secret="AVNOOuI7Ed" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/waresix-acquires-trukita-to-connect-more-of-indonesias-fragmented-logistics-chain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088405</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AutoLeap says it will repair your lousy relationship with car shops</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/autoleap-thinks-it-will-turn-chaotic-repair-shop-experiences-into-seamless-ones/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/autoleap-thinks-it-will-turn-chaotic-repair-shop-experiences-into-seamless-ones/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 02:57:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global founders capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Liquid2 Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seed funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shift]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Threshold Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086962</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No one likes having to go to the automotive repair shop. There&#8217;s little transparency into what happens after a car is dropped off, invoices are often little more than a series of illegible bullet points, and the ordeal can feel chaotic. AutoLeap, a six-month-old, Toronto-based startup that quietly raised $5 million in seed funding in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">No one likes having to go to the automotive repair shop. There&#8217;s little transparency into what happens after a car is dropped off, invoices are often little more than a series of illegible bullet points, and the ordeal can feel chaotic.</p>
<p><a href="https://autoleap.com/">AutoLeap</a>, a six-month-old, Toronto-based startup that quietly raised $5 million in seed funding in September, thinks its team can figure out how to repair that broken experience by bringing car repair shops into the 21st century at long last. Its big idea is to help such shops organize their operations, schedule jobs, order parts, conduct digital inspections, and invoice customers in a transparent and seamless way.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not the first to try to modernize the car repair process. Among other startups, a five-year-old, Seattle-based outfit, Wrench, has already raised <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2019/wrench-raises-20m-ratchet-growth-tech-powered-car-repair-platform/">$40 million</a> toward that end, while another entrant, <a href="https://www.repairsmith.com/">RepairSmith</a>, a two-year-old, L.A.-based car repair and maintenance service, is backed by Daimler.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Still, with a global automotive repair market that&#8217;s currently valued at $700 billion, there&#8217;s clearly room for more than one player and one approach, and AutoLeap has a few things going for it.</p>
<p>For starters, it has an investor base with some useful connections. Threshold Ventures, which led AutoLeap&#8217;s seed round, has ties to the automotive world, including through its bet on the car-selling platform <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/shiftcars" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="shiftcars">Shift, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> which <a href="https://www.insurancejournal.com/news/national/2020/10/16/586738.htm">went public</a> in October via a reverse merger.</p>
<p>AutoLeap &#8212; whose other venture investors include Maple VC, Liquid2 Ventures, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/global-founders-capital" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="global-founders-capital">Global Founders Capital, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Codename Ventures &#8212; is also backed by some notable individuals that hold sway in the world that AutoLeap is entering. Among them: Shift cofounder George Arison, former General Motors CEO Rick Wagoner, and former senior Bridgestone exec Ned Aguilar.</p>
<p>More importantly, AutoLeap&#8217;s founders worked together once before to reinvigorate a stodgy business. Before launching AutoLeap, co-CEOs Rameez Ansari and Steve Lau spent four years as the co-CEOs of <a href="https://fieldedge.com/">FieldEdge</a>, a SaaS company that helps contractors to run their small businesses.</p>
<p>They two &#8212; college friends who&#8217;d met at the University of Toronto &#8212; didn&#8217;t start the company. Rather, after Lau nabbed an MBA from Wharton and Ansari nabbed his from Stanford, they joined forces to acquire and grow a neglected business after raising a so-called <a href="https://www.gsb.stanford.edu/faculty-research/centers-initiatives/ces/research/search-funds">search fund</a>. (If you aren&#8217;t familiar, it&#8217;s vehicle that&#8217;s backed by individual investors who bet on a team to find a company to buy, run it for some period of time, then sell it for far more money.)</p>
<p>It was a productive experience for all involved. After spending $20 million to acquire FieldEdge, whose software had already been around for 30 years, Lau and Ansari so dramatically improved the company&#8217;s offerings that they were able to charge seven times what the company had previously collected for its products, says Lau. Then they<a href="https://www.adventinternational.com/advent-international-acquires-merges-clearent-fieldedge-create-integrated-payments-leader/"> sold</a> it to the private equity firm Advent in 2018 for &#8220;north of $100 million,&#8221; says Lau.</p>
<p>It was a solid exit. Minus that $20 million investment, the team kept 30% of the remaining proceeds from FieldEdge&#8217;s sale, with the rest going to the search fund&#8217;s investors.</p>
<p>Even so, says Lau, he and Ansari might have kept going if not for rival <a href="https://www.servicetitan.com/">ServiceTitan</a>, which &#8220;went crazy on the fundraising front.&#8221; (The seven-year-old company has raised $400 million altogether from investors.)</p>
<p>Between ServiceTitan&#8217;s daunting war chest and &#8220;given this was a first exit for us,&#8221; Lau says, &#8220;we transitioned out instead.&#8221;</p>
<p>Today, neither Lau nor Ansari wants to repeat the scenario with AutoLeap. Indeed, though Lau says the company is &#8220;heads down&#8221; and &#8220;not in any discussions&#8221; with investors now that it has secured seed funding, one imagines it won&#8217;t take long for that to change.</p>
<p>What investors would be funding essentially is a burgeoning software platform that aims to kill off paper flyers, crumbling fax machines, and sheaves of invoices &#8212; if only it can convince car repair shops to slow down long enough to try its software.</p>
<p>It isn&#8217;t a no-brainer that they will, admits Lau. &#8220;It&#8217;s a material onboarding effort, because you become the lifeblood of their business.&#8221; The sales process also requires convincing the shops to share their existing data and take the time required to be trained on how to use it.</p>
<p>Lau isn&#8217;t dissuaded, plainly. He says the time to onboard a new customer is one to two weeks and that &#8220;once they start seeing value, they get that &#8216;aha&#8217; type of moment.&#8221; In fact, he says that <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">AutoLeap is already working with a handful of shops, including several in Toronto, one in Las Vegas, and another in Boston.</span></p>
<p>As for its expansion plans, Lau says that some of the company&#8217;s seed funding will go toward digital marketing, but it&#8217;s also relying heavily on word of mouth. It helps, he says, that garages are often clustered in a geographic area, which he believes will enable AutoLeap to spread quickly.</p>
<p>There isn&#8217;t &#8220;a lot of data&#8221; to support that assumption, offers Lau. But if AutoLeap has its way, there will be soon enough.</p>
<p><em>Above, left to right: AutoLeap co-CEOs Rameez Ansari and Steve Lau in a photo that Lau readily volunteers was Photoshopped owing to the pandemic. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/autoleap-thinks-it-will-turn-chaotic-repair-shop-experiences-into-seamless-ones/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086962</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>China&#8217;s Luckin Coffee will pay $180 million to settle accounting fraud charges</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/luckin-180-million-fine-sec/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/luckin-180-million-fine-sec/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 02:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[luckin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088383</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[China&#8217;s embattled coffee delivery startup Luckin has reached a settlement with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, agreeing to pay a $180 million penalty to settle charges that it overstated its revenues, expenses, and losses by the hundreds of millions of dollars. The announcement by the market regulator arrived Wednesday evening, months after short-seller Muddy [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">China&#8217;s embattled coffee delivery startup Luckin has reached a settlement with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, agreeing to pay a $180 million penalty to settle charges that it overstated its revenues, expenses, and losses by the hundreds of millions of dollars.</p>
<p>The announcement by the market regulator <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/chinas-luckin-coffee-to-pay-180-million-to-settle-accounting-fraud-claims-11608157731">arrived</a> Wednesday evening, months after short-seller Muddy Waters first reported the alleged fraud early this year. In response to the allegations, Luckin <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/02/luckin-coffees-board-initiates-investigation-into-300m-potential-fraud/">said</a> in April it would launch an internal probe. In June, the SEC said it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/26/luckin-coffee-will-unluckinly-delist-from-nasdaq-following-fraud-allegations/">would delist Luckin</a>, and in July, Luckin <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/01/after-grinding-investigation-luckin-coffee-confirms-300-million-revenue-fraud/">admitted</a> it did cook its books.</p>
<p>The fiasco came only a year after Luckin <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/17/chinas-luckin-coffee-raises-up-to-651m-in-upsized-us-ipo/">raised $651 million</a> through its first time sale on Nasdaq. The company was founded in October 2017, making it one of the fastest companies to go from a startup to a public company.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup, which aspired to take a piece of Starbucks&#8217; sizable market share in China, allegedly fabricated more than $300 million in sales between at least April 2019 through January 2020, said the SEC announcement. Certain employees were found attempting to conceal the fraud by inflating the firm&#8217;s expenses by more than $190 million, &#8220;creating a fake operations database, and altering accounting and bank records to reflect the false sales.&#8221;</p>
<p>Luckin neither admitted or denied these claims, which were filed in a court in the Southern District of New York. The settlement is subject to court approval and the transfer of funds to security holders will<span id="textmarker_16" class="textmarker textmarker_16"> need approval by Chinese authorities.</span></p>
<p>In September, China&#8217;s market regulator <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-luckin-coffee-investigation-fine/china-fines-luckin-coffee-and-linked-firms-a-total-of-9-million-idUSKCN26D07G">fined Luckin and 45 companies involved in Luckin&#8217;s frauds</a> a total of $9 million after an investigation revealed the coffee company faked its numbers.</p>
<p>Despite the fraudulent scandal, Luckin claims business is still as usual. Operations of the firm and its stores are currently &#8220;stable and normal,&#8221; said the company in a notice on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&#8220;Luckin will continue to cooperate with regulators and prioritize compliance. In the meantime, our management and staff will continue to ensure the firm&#8217;s stable operation.&#8221;</p>
<p>Short-sellers have been going after U.S.-listed Chinese firms this year. A <a href="https://wolfpackresearch.com/research/iq-netflix-of-china-good-luckin/">report</a> from Wolfpack Research accused iQiyi, a major Chinese video streaming service backed by Baidu, of inflating its numbers, a claim that <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/08/14/iqiyi-sec-investigation-into-fraud-allegations-shares-plunge.html">triggered an SEC probe</a>. GSX Techedu, a Chinese after-school tutoring company, was <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/sec-probes-chinas-gsx-techedu-after-short-sellers-pleas-11599046396">under a similar SEC investigation</a> after short-seller Citron Research said the company fabricated sales numbers.</p>
<p>&#8220;While there are challenges in our ability to effectively hold foreign issuers and their officers and directors accountable to the same extent as U.S. issuers and persons, we will continue to use all our available resources to protect investors when foreign issuers violate the federal securities laws,&#8221; said Stephanie Avakian, director of the SEC’s division of enforcement, in the regulator&#8217;s announcement on Luckin.</p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/luckin-180-million-fine-sec/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088383</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lydia raises another $86 million to build a European financial super app</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/lydia-raises-another-86-million-to-build-european-financial-super-app/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/lydia-raises-another-86-million-to-build-european-financial-super-app/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lydia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088150</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French fintech startup Lydia has extended its Series B round. Accel is leading the extension with all major existing shareholders also participating. Lydia first raised $45 million in January 2020 — Tencent led that investment. The startup is now raising another $86 million, which means that Lydia has raised $131 million in total as part [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French fintech startup <a href="https://lydia-app.com">Lydia</a> has extended its Series B round. <a href="https://accel.com">Accel</a> is leading the extension with all major existing shareholders also participating. Lydia first raised $45 million <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/mobile-payment-app-lydia-raises-45-million-round-led-by-tencent/">in January 2020</a> — Tencent led that investment. The startup is now raising another $86 million, which means that Lydia has raised $131 million in total as part of its Series B round.</p>
<p>While <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/lydia" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="lydia">Lydia <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> wouldn’t discuss the valuation of the round, its co-founder and CEO Cyril Chiche gave me a hint. “The value of the company has really significantly increased between the two parts of the B round,” he told me.</p>
<p>Interestingly, Amit Jhawar is heading this investment for <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/accel" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="accel">Accel <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>. He joined Accel as a venture partner <a href="https://accel.com/noteworthy/welcoming-amit-jhawar-to-accel-as-a-venture-partner">in July</a> and he’s going to join Lydia’s board of directors.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Jhawar joined payments company Braintree in 2011 as COO and CFO. Shortly after, Braintree acquired peer-to-peer payment app Venmo. “When we acquired Venmo it was only 15 people. They had just released their mobile app in April of 2012,” Jhawar told me in a phone interview.</p>
<p>PayPal later acquired Braintree and Venmo — Jhawar stuck around until early 2020 to scale Venmo to the huge fintech consumer app that 52 million people use in the U.S. Jhawar believes that peer-to-peer payments represent the beginning of a long-term consumer relationship.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="llx2VwNqiO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/mobile-payment-app-lydia-raises-45-million-round-led-by-tencent/">Mobile payment app Lydia raises $45 million round led by Tencent</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Mobile payment app Lydia raises $45 million round led by Tencent&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/mobile-payment-app-lydia-raises-45-million-round-led-by-tencent/embed/#?secret=llx2VwNqiO" data-secret="llx2VwNqiO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“You know that P2P is successful when they leave money in their account because they’re going to come back,” he said.</p>
<p>Back in 2014, when <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/02/24/lydia-is-a-fee-free-payment-app-thats-like-venmo-for-france/">I first covered Lydia</a>, I called it the Venmo for France — they had only raised €600,000 back then. It seems like Jhawar agrees with that take. Since then, Lydia has grown quite a lot and has expanded beyond peer-to-peer payments in various ways.</p>
<p>With Lydia, you can send money to another user in just a few seconds. You don’t have to enter an account number in your banking app — as long as you know their phone number, they’ll receive your payment.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kfbluqjU39"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/07/lydia-partners-with-tink-to-improve-open-banking-features/">Lydia partners with Tink to improve open banking features</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lydia partners with Tink to improve open banking features&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/07/lydia-partners-with-tink-to-improve-open-banking-features/embed/#?secret=kfbluqjU39" data-secret="kfbluqjU39" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>If you have money in your account, you can choose to spend it directly using a Visa debit card. Lydia lets you generate a virtual card that works with Apple Pay and Google Pay — you can also order a plastic card.</p>
<p>Lydia also supports direct deposit as you get your own IBAN in the app. You can also create money pots and send a link to other users, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/07/lydia-partners-with-tink-to-improve-open-banking-features/">view your bank accounts</a> in Lydia, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/06/lydia-lets-you-donate-to-hospitals-and-charities/">donate</a> money to hospitals and charities, get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/05/lydia-expands-credit-offering-in-partnership-with-younited-credit/">a credit line</a>, etc.</p>
<p>But there’s one killer feature that stands out over the rest. Bank accounts tend to be monolithic and don’t reflect how you use money. “If you look at banks today, they call the main account a checking account. It’s outdated by design,” CEO Cyril Chiche said.</p>
<p>Lydia has created flexible sub-accounts that you can use in many different ways. You can create a second sub-account and set some money aside for your bills. You can create a third one and share it with a few friends because you’re going on a vacation together.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Hs3ZOQJkiI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/05/lydia-expands-credit-offering-in-partnership-with-younited-credit/">Lydia expands credit offering in partnership with Younited Credit</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lydia expands credit offering in partnership with Younited Credit&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/05/lydia-expands-credit-offering-in-partnership-with-younited-credit/embed/#?secret=Hs3ZOQJkiI" data-secret="Hs3ZOQJkiI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>You can move money from one account to another by swiping your finger across the account grid. As you can have multiple contributors and you can change the account associated with your debit card, it means that money flows more naturally. It feels like using a messaging app, not a financial app.</p>
<p>And it’s been working well in France. The company now has more than 4 million users. Transactions have doubled over the past year, which means that usage is accelerating.</p>
<p>“Lydia has the largest P2P network in Europe outside of PayPal and has the potential to grow all across Europe with a mobile-first, customer-focused solution. This will bring demand for incremental consumer financial products and high merchant interest to accept the payment,” Jhawar told me in an email.</p>
<p>And 2020 has been a busy year for Lydia. The company has just released a complete redesign to better position the app as a super app for financial services. All the interactions and all the main tabs have been changed.</p>
<p>Lydia also re-launched its premium offering with two new premium plans that offer you higher limits over the free plan and an insurance package for the most expensive offer. Those plans are more in line with what the app offers today and should contribute to the company’s bottom line. “The next step is bringing Lydia to profitability and it’s something that has always been important for us,” Chiche said in a recent interview.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SGVTghCPsA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/06/lydia-lets-you-donate-to-hospitals-and-charities/">Lydia lets you donate to hospitals and charities</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lydia lets you donate to hospitals and charities&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/06/lydia-lets-you-donate-to-hospitals-and-charities/embed/#?secret=SGVTghCPsA" data-secret="SGVTghCPsA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Behind the scenes, Lydia has also upgraded many core features, such as migrating cards to a new infrastructure, adding alerts to account aggregation, supporting instant SEPA transfers to bank accounts, etc.</p>
<p>In 2021, the company plans to build on top of that new foundation with more financial products. “We’re going to try every single product — credit, savings, investment,” Chiche said.</p>
<p>The company is also slowly expanding to more countries. But it wants to offer a product that feels like a local product with a local card and a local IBAN to increase acceptance rates. Lydia is starting with Portugal.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/lydia-raises-another-86-million-to-build-european-financial-super-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088150</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Facebook escalates Apple criticism</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/daily-crunch-facebook-escalates-apple-criticism/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/daily-crunch-facebook-escalates-apple-criticism/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 23:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088351</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook takes aim at Apple, Texas sues Google and we interview the CEO of Boston Dynamics. This is your Daily Crunch for December 16, 2020. The big story: Facebook escalates Apple criticism Facebook took a big swing at Apple&#8217;s upcoming app tracking restrictions today with full-page ads in the print editions of The New York [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="facebook">Facebook <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> takes aim at <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/apple" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="apple">Apple, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Texas sues Google and we interview the CEO of Boston Dynamics. This is your Daily Crunch for December 16, 2020.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: Facebook escalates Apple criticism</strong></p>
<p>Facebook <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/facebook-apple-small-business/">took a big swing</a> at Apple&#8217;s upcoming app tracking restrictions today with full-page ads in the print editions of The New York Times, The Wall Street Journal and The Washington Post that argued the social networking giant is &#8220;standing up to Apple for small businesses everywhere.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In other words, while Facebook will obviously be affected by Apple&#8217;s change (apps will have to ask users for permission before it can track their IDFA identifier, which will presumably lead to a steep drop in ad targeting), the company said that small businesses relying on targeted ad campaigns will be hurt even more.</p>
<p>And while the two campaigns are very different, it&#8217;s worth noting that another initiative against Apple is also gaining steam, with major U.S. news publishers <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/major-u-s-news-publishers-join-the-coalition-for-app-fairness-advocacy-group-to-fight-the-apple-tax/">joining the Coalition for App Fairness</a>, a group fighting app store fees.</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/google-state-antitrust-lawsuit-texas-paxton/">The latest multistate antitrust lawsuit targets Google’s ad business</a> — Texas Attorney General Ken Paxton is accusing Google of maintaining an illegal monopoly in online advertising.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/following-hyundai-acquisition-boston-dynamics-ceo-discussing-the-robotics-pioneers-future/">Following Hyundai acquisition, Boston Dynamics’ CEO discusses the robotics pioneer’s future</a> — Rob Playter discusses the company’s new corporate parent, the future of Handle and Spot’s job at the NYPD.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/amazons-project-kuiper-will-seek-multiple-launch-providers-to-carry-its-satellites-to-space/">Amazon’s Project Kuiper will seek multiple launch providers to carry its satellites to space</a> — Amazon&#8217;s David Limp shared some new details about the company’s Project Kuiper broadband satellite constellation.</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/stockx-raises-275m-series-e-valuing-the-retailer-at-2-8b/">StockX raises $275M Series E, valuing the retailer at $2.8B</a> — Headquartered in downtown Detroit, Michigan, the raise marks the largest VC funding round in Michigan history.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/bigid-keeps-rolling-with-70m-series-d-on-1b-valuation/">BigID keeps rolling with $70M Series D on $1B valuation</a> — Salesforce Ventures and Tiger Global co-led the round.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/new-wave/">New Wave is a new European seed fund headed up by ex-Accel VC Pia d’Iribarne</a> — The firm&#8217;s debut fund of $56 million was raised in just three months.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/how-to-pick-an-investor-in-good-or-bad-times/">How to pick an investor in good or bad times</a> — Quiq CEO Mike Myer says you should trust your instincts.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/clickup-ceo-talks-hiring-raising-and-scaling-in-the-white-hot-productivity-space/">ClickUp CEO talks hiring, raising and scaling in the white-hot productivity space</a> — The company, which makes business productivity tools for task management, goals and docs, has reached a valuation of $1 billion.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/dear-sophie-how-did-immigration-change-for-startup-founders-in-2020/">Dear Sophie: How did immigration change for startup founders in 2020?</a> — Another edition of immigration lawyer Sophie Alcorn&#8217;s advice column answering immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which aims to democratize information about startups. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/bitcoin-passes-20k-and-reaches-all-time-high/">Bitcoin passes $20K and reaches all-time high</a> — Bitcoin’s value has rapidly increased over the past two months.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/privacy-is-the-new-competitive-battleground/">Privacy is the new competitive battleground</a> — New regulations give companies new opportunities to differentiate themselves.</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/daily-crunch-facebook-escalates-apple-criticism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088351</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>HBO Max will finally land on Roku devices tomorrow</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/hbo-max-will-finally-land-on-roku-devices-tomorrow/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/hbo-max-will-finally-land-on-roku-devices-tomorrow/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 22:20:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HBO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HBO Max]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roku]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088289</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It took an unusually long time, but HBO Max is set to launch on Roku devices tomorrow. Roku users make up a massive chunk of the cord-cutting market, so the absence of an HBO Max app for Roku nearly seven months after the service launched was pretty glaring. We&#8217;d been wondering where the Max app was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It took an unusually long time, but <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/hbo" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="hbo">HBO <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Max is set to launch on Roku devices tomorrow.</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/roku" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="roku">Roku <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> users make up a <a href="https://www.whattowatch.com/news/rokus-earnings">massive </a>chunk of the cord-cutting market, so the absence of an HBO Max app for Roku nearly seven months after the service launched was pretty glaring. We&#8217;d been wondering where the Max app was for months, its launch seemingly tied up over the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/hbo-max-reached-4-1m-subscribers-in-first-month-despite-lack-of-distribution-on-roku-and-fire-tv/">matter of where and how customers could subscribe</a>.</p>
<p>With &#8220;Wonder Woman 1984&#8221; set to debut on Max in just a few weeks, one can assume there was tremendous pressure all around to get the deal done. As part of the deal, Roku users will be able to sign up for HBO Max using Roku&#8217;s built-in payment system, Roku Pay.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This news comes about a month after HBO Max filled a similar gap by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/hbo-max-arrives-on-amazon-fire-tv-devices/">finally launching on Amazon Fire devices</a>, and days after the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/warner-bros-hbo-max-simultaneous-release/">announcement of a mega deal</a> that will see all 2021 Warner Bros. films launch on HBO Max on the same day they hit theaters.</p>
<p>With this launch, HBO Max will have most of the key bases covered, with support on iOS, Android, Chromecast, Roku, Amazon&#8217;s Fire devices, PC/Mac and all of the modern gaming consoles minus the Switch.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="St6sEFUXaH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/warner-bros-hbo-max-simultaneous-release/">All of Warner Bros.&#8217; theatrical movies will get simultaneous releases on HBO Max next year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;All of Warner Bros.&#8217; theatrical movies will get simultaneous releases on HBO Max next year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/warner-bros-hbo-max-simultaneous-release/embed/#?secret=St6sEFUXaH" data-secret="St6sEFUXaH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/hbo-max-will-finally-land-on-roku-devices-tomorrow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088289</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The StockX megaround smells like pre-IPO money</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/the-stockx-megaround-smells-like-pre-ipo-money/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/the-stockx-megaround-smells-like-pre-ipo-money/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 21:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stockx]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2087931</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An IPO? A shoe-reselling marketplace? Sure! At the numbers we know about it, why not?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Earlier today, TechCrunch reported that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/stockx-raises-275m-series-e-valuing-the-retailer-at-2-8b/">consumer reseller marketplace StockX</a> raised $275 million at a valuation of approximately $2.8 billion.</p>
<p>Selling a tenth of your company for north of a quarter-billion may be somewhat common among late-stage software startups with tremendous growth, but one known for its market share in the sneaker resale niche? Don&#8217;t laugh, the round actually makes pretty OK sense. And given the growth that <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/stockx" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="stockx">StockX <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has managed, it could have a path to the public markets in under a year.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Don&#8217;t laugh, the round actually makes pretty OK sense.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>In our piece covering the funding round, <a href="https://twitter.com/mjburnsy?lang=en">Matt Burns</a> wrote that StockX saw its nondomestic sales rise 260% in Q3 compared to the year-ago period, recording half of its 13 million transactions in the last 12 months.</p>
<p>But that wasn&#8217;t really enough to get my head around the round, so I went hunting. Here&#8217;s a grip of other, dated growth metrics that help us put the new funding into proper context:</p>
<ul>
<li> In mid-2019, when StockX became a unicorn <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/06/26/technology/trading-sneakers-stockx.html">after raising $110 million</a>, it reported $100 million or more in monthly gross merchandise volume. It had around 800 employees at the time.</li>
<li>As part of that deal, a former eBay exec and former NYSE executive vice president of the New York Stock Exchange took over as CEO and took a board seat. The man in question, Scott Cutler, remains the company&#8217;s chief executive.</li>
<li>StockX claimed more than $1 billion in gross merchandise volume <a href="https://stockx.com/news/year-in-review-2019/">in 2019</a> (the company supports streetwear and luxury resales as well as sneakers). The company closed out 2019 with around 1,000 employees.</li>
<li>In mid-2020, StockX released <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/stockx-releases-mid-year-marketplace-momentum-report-pointing-to-accelerated-growth-amidst-pandemic-surpasses-2-5-billion-in-gross-merchandise-value-301092276.html">a midyear report</a> &#8212; née &#8220;corporate brag sheet&#8221; &#8212; saying that it had surpassed $2.5 billion in gross merchandise volume, and 10 million trades, half of which had been recorded in the last year.</li>
</ul>
<p>To understand if those numbers are impressive or not, we&#8217;ll need to convert gross merchandise result into revenue. So, we&#8217;ll need to better understand StockX&#8217;s fee structure.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/the-stockx-megaround-smells-like-pre-ipo-money/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2087931</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Following Hyundai acquisition, Boston Dynamics’ CEO discusses the robotics pioneer’s future</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/following-hyundai-acquisition-boston-dynamics-ceo-discussing-the-robotics-pioneers-future/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/following-hyundai-acquisition-boston-dynamics-ceo-discussing-the-robotics-pioneers-future/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 21:51:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyundai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rob Playter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088243</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A lot can change in a year. Especially this year. For Boston Dynamics, the past 12 months have brought a number of radical changes traditionally not seen at 30-year-old businesses of its size. It’s a list that includes the first new CEO in the company’s history, wide availability of its first commercial product and, most [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A lot can change in a year. Especially this year. For <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/boston-dynamics" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="boston-dynamics">Boston Dynamics, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> the past 12 months have brought a number of radical changes traditionally not seen at 30-year-old businesses of its size. It’s a list that includes the first new CEO in the company’s history, wide availability of its first commercial product and, most recently, being acquired by its third owner in seven years.</p>
<p>Of course, no one has ever accused Boston Dynamics of being traditional.</p>
<p>Last week, the Waltham, Massachusetts-based robotics pioneer confirmed earlier rumors that it was being acquired by Hyundai. The South Korean tech giant will be taking an 80% stake in the company, leaving the other 20% or so to its former owner, Softbank Group. The deal, which values the 300-person company at $1.1 billion, is expected to close next June.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3XIIOCW6Kd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/hyundai-buys-controlling-interest-in-boston-dynamics/">Hyundai buys controlling interest in Boston Dynamics</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hyundai buys controlling interest in Boston Dynamics&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/hyundai-buys-controlling-interest-in-boston-dynamics/embed/#?secret=3XIIOCW6Kd" data-secret="3XIIOCW6Kd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“We grew from 100 people to 300 people under SoftBank,” CEO Robert Playter tells TechCrunch. “That took investment. It took encouragement from them to launch a product, launch the products that we had in mind. It was critical. So our mission, which they started us down the path of, is to launch multiple robot products that include mobility, manipulation and vision. And they really gave us power and afterburners to pursue that mission.”</p>
<p>Playter, a longtime Boston Dynamics employee, waves away unfavorable optics around the company’s quick transitions between owners. Each owner served its function for the company’s bottom line &#8212; Google offered resources for exploration, SoftBank compelled it to productize and Hyundai will deliver the sort of engineering and manufacturing know-how required to scale up its products.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2064174" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2064174" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2064174" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/BOSTON-DYNAMICS-ARM-CLIP-CONSOLIDATED.2020-10-21-13_04_24.gif" alt="" width="1024" height="576" /><p id="caption-attachment-2064174" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Boston Dynamics</p></div></p>
<p>“Ultimately [SoftBank is] an investment company, and we always expected there to be some kind of an exit,” says Playter. “The question was always when, and when is the right timing? So this isn&#8217;t really a surprise to us. And I think they saw and we saw that the time was right as our product launch grew to get a different kind of partner.”</p>
<p>The executive adds that the nature of the company’s interactions with SoftBank were ultimately limited under regulatory restrictions placed on the acquisition by the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS). “Getting through CFIUS will be a closing condition on the Hyundai deal,” he explains.</p>
<p>While SoftBank’s ownership of the company was seen as, at very least, aggressively nudging the company in the direction of commercialization after decades of operating as a research firm, the executive tells TechCrunch that Hyundai largely approved of the company’s existing roadmap. The past two years have certainly brought some profound changes for the company, but Boston Dynamics is still a fairly lean organization, and as such is designed to take a measured approach to the market.</p>
<p>
		<div class="embed breakout" id="vidible_div_0" data-pid="56faf851e4b0d3dcac2e081a" data-bcid="564f313b67b6231408bc51ee" data-video="5f63a92753fd6e6a449b49c0"></div>
		<span><script type="text/javascript" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/themes/techcrunch-2017/features/shortcodes/vidible-callback-js.php?id=0"></script></span>
		</p>
<p>Of the 300 or so employees, between 100 to 120 are currently focused on its first commercial product, Spot. Many of the company’s recent hires are focused on areas like sales, customer service and quality control &#8212; relatively unfamiliar terrain for an organization that went more than a quarter-century without releasing its first product. The team focused on its logistics robot, Handle, is significantly smaller, but growing, and will “match or exceed Spot over the course of the next year,” he adds. Handle is, after all, Boston Dynamics’ commercial launch. The company is set to unveil the commercialized version of the box-lifting machine in April. Pilot programs similar to those offered for Spot will follow and sales of the product will start at some point the following year.</p>
<p>The company has already begun to test “proof of concept” models with select partners in real-world warehouses. “These are systems for development that we&#8217;re taking onto customer sites to do proof of concept tests,” says Playter. “We&#8217;re taking learnings from that to improve the design. In parallel work, we&#8217;re designing the for-manufacture version of that robot right now. And first versions of that new generation will come online next summer.”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="breakout alignnone size-full wp-image-1885677" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/atlas-gymnastics-boston-dynamics.gif" alt="atlas gymnastics boston dynamics" width="960" height="533" /></p>
<p>Fulfilment and logistics have already been a hot category for robotics for a number of years, but interest has only grown amid the COVID-19 pandemic. Handle represents a decidedly different to-market approach than Spot, in that respect. A large part of the quadrupedal robot’s pilot program was working with customers and partners to determine which categories had the highest demand for the advanced robotics technology. Demand for Spot hasn’t been huge, but it’s been steady, with the company selling more than 400 units in the first 15 months.</p>
<p>In-demand applications include deployment in dangerous scenarios like a BP oil rig and a National Grid electric plant. Other more surprising use cases have arisen, as well. Late last year, the ACLU raised concern around video of a Spot robot featured in police training drills, which debuted at our Robotics event back in April. This October, a Spot was seen at a crime scene in Brooklyn. Playter confirmed that the NYPD is one of the company’s customers.</p>
<p>“They have a Spot and were using it, I think, to maintain a safe standoff distance when somebody (a potentially armed suspect) was barricading themselves,” he explains. “So I think getting a camera in and potentially communicating, de-escalating a potentially dangerous situation was the goal there.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="534GD0MLv6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/23/boston-dynamics-appoints-its-first-ever-new-ceo/">Boston Dynamics appoints its first-ever new CEO</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Boston Dynamics appoints its first-ever new CEO&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/23/boston-dynamics-appoints-its-first-ever-new-ceo/embed/#?secret=534GD0MLv6" data-secret="534GD0MLv6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“One of the intended purposes of Spot is to enhance the safety of our customers by removing or providing the opportunity to remove a person from a dangerous environment,” Playter adds. “And that includes public safety officials like the police. And in particular, the Massachusetts State Police have been interested in using Spot in a classic mobile robot application, investigating suspicious packages or potential bombs. So I think these are great applications of robotics and something that we support.”</p>
<p>The next year will also see Boston Dynamics continuing to expand Spot’s available markets. Under the Hyundai banner, the company will likely continue the pace of releases set by Spot and Handle.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think something like a robot every couple of years is a pace that we could manage. From clean sheet, we can build a new robot in under a year,&#8221; says Playter. “And then you have to go through an iterative process of refining that concept and starting to understand market fit. And so I would look to, I want to stabilize the launch of Spot. There&#8217;s already improvements to Spot that we want to be thinking about. So I don&#8217;t know if we&#8217;re going to go build the next generation of Spot or maybe build the next robot for the next market. And that remains to be seen. We don&#8217;t quite have the team that&#8217;s big enough to do that just yet.”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="breakout alignnone size-full wp-image-1457806" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/boston-dynamics-feb-2017.gif" alt="" width="850" height="408" /></p>
<p>The company’s research wing, which focuses on even more bleeding-edge robots like the humanoid Atlas, will also continue under Hyundai’s watch. The company stopped accepting new defense contracts in 2014, shortly after the Google acquisition, but research continues to be a key part of Boston Dynamics’ work.</p>
<p>“[W]e&#8217;re developing our own R&amp;D work with Atlas internally,” Playter says. “And so we still use that as a platform to build both advanced hardware and software. We have some exciting things that I think will come out in the near future. We&#8217;re going to show you what we&#8217;ve been up to, probably in the classic Boston Dynamics home grown video way. I don&#8217;t think we have a deadline on when that&#8217;s going to come out, but there&#8217;s something in the oven.”</p>
<p>Integrating some of Boston Dynamics’ more advanced research into far out Hyundai concepts like the recently announced Ultimate Mobility Vehicle could also be a good fit. “We think the combination of wheels on legs is really interesting. If you recall, we built the first version of Handle with wheels and legs. And so there&#8217;s some real synergy there, I think. I think they&#8217;re really going to be able to build those vehicles.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TVCusmwejN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/17/boston-robotics-delivers-plan-for-logistics-robots-as-early-as-next-year/">Boston Dynamics delivers plan for logistics robots as early as next year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Boston Dynamics delivers plan for logistics robots as early as next year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/17/boston-robotics-delivers-plan-for-logistics-robots-as-early-as-next-year/embed/#?secret=TVCusmwejN" data-secret="TVCusmwejN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/following-hyundai-acquisition-boston-dynamics-ceo-discussing-the-robotics-pioneers-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088243</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon&#8217;s Project Kuiper will seek multiple launch providers to carry its satellites to space</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/amazons-project-kuiper-will-seek-multiple-launch-providers-to-carry-its-satellites-to-space/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/amazons-project-kuiper-will-seek-multiple-launch-providers-to-carry-its-satellites-to-space/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 21:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Limp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Communications Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet service providers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff bezos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Kuiper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite constellation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space tourism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions Space 2020]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Orbit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon SVP of Devices &#38; Services David Limp joined us at TC Sessions: Space today, and he shared some new details about the company&#8217;s Project Kuiper broadband satellite constellation. Limp shared more details on the technical design challenges that the Kuiper team solved with its revolutionary customer terminal, but he also shared more info on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:4993,&quot;3&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:0},&quot;10&quot;:1,&quot;11&quot;:4,&quot;12&quot;:0,&quot;15&quot;:&quot;Arial&quot;}">
		<div class="embed breakout" id="vidible_div_1" data-pid="56faf851e4b0d3dcac2e081a" data-bcid="564f313b67b6231408bc51ee" data-video="5fda73a5b748e12cbbf28ad9"></div>
		<span><script type="text/javascript" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/themes/techcrunch-2017/features/shortcodes/vidible-callback-js.php?id=1"></script></span>
		</span></p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/amazon" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="amazon">Amazon <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> SVP of Devices &amp; Services David Limp joined us at TC Sessions: Space today, and he shared some new details about the company&#8217;s Project Kuiper broadband satellite constellation. Limp shared more details on the technical design challenges that the Kuiper team solved with its revolutionary customer terminal, but he also shared more info on the company&#8217;s plans around launching its constellation, which will number 3,236 per the current plan approved by the FCC.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re launch agnostic&#8221; Limp said. &#8220;If you know somebody who has a rocket out there, give us a call. &#8220;One of the reasons we thought the time was right to do a constellation now is because of some of the dynamics happening in the launch industry. Every day, we see a new demonstration of reusability, every day we see new demonstrations of breakthroughs in better engines, whether that&#8217;s Raptor [<a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/space-exploration-technologies" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="space-exploration-technologies">SpaceX&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> engine] or BE-4 [Blue Origin&#8217;s].&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Part of the FCC&#8217;s approval for Amazon&#8217;s constellation requires it to send up around half of its planned total constellation within the next six years, which is a significant volume and will require an aggressive launch pace to achieve. <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/space-exploration-technologies" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="space-exploration-technologies">SpaceX&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Starlink, for context, has launched 16 batches of 60 satellites each for its network, with 14 of those happening in 2020 alone. In order to achieve that pace, Limp said that while he hopes Blue Origin (the Jeff Bezos-owned private rocket launch company) can provide some of its launch capacity, they will be looking elsewhere for rides to space as well.</p>
<p>&#8220;When you have to put 3,200-plus things into space, you will need lots of launch capacity,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Our hope is that it&#8217;s not just one provider, that there will be multiple providers.&#8221;</p>
<p>Depending on the final Project Kuiper satellite spec, this could be a huge opportunity for new small satellite launchers coming on board, including companies like Astra, Relativity Space and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/virgin-orbit" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="virgin-orbit">Virgin Orbit <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> who spoke earlier today at the event on the progress their launch companies are making. It could also be a windfall for existing providers like Rocket Lab &#8212; and even potentially SpaceX. In response to a separate question, Limp noted that he doesn&#8217;t believe Project Kuiper is in direct competition with SpaceX&#8217;s Starlink, since there&#8217;s such a broad addressable market when it comes to connectivity for unserved and underserved customers globally.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RwTZbGwWcw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/amazons-project-kuiper-has-developed-a-small-low-cost-customer-terminal-for-its-broadband-satellite-network/">Amazon&#8217;s Project Kuiper has developed a small, low-cost customer terminal for its broadband satellite network</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon&#8217;s Project Kuiper has developed a small, low-cost customer terminal for its broadband satellite network&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/amazons-project-kuiper-has-developed-a-small-low-cost-customer-terminal-for-its-broadband-satellite-network/embed/#?secret=RwTZbGwWcw" data-secret="RwTZbGwWcw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/amazons-project-kuiper-will-seek-multiple-launch-providers-to-carry-its-satellites-to-space/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088253</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter will force users to delete COVID-19 vaccine conspiracy theories</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/twitter-will-force-users-to-delete-covid-19-vaccine-conspiracy-theories/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/twitter-will-force-users-to-delete-covid-19-vaccine-conspiracy-theories/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 20:57:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[misinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pandemic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088239</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With COVID-19 vaccinations just beginning, Twitter will ramp up its efforts to tamp down conspiracy theories that might discourage people from getting the vaccine. The newly expanded rules apply to debunked information about the adverse effects of getting vaccinated, misleading tweets claiming the vaccine is not necessary and conspiracies that claim COVID-19 vaccines are used [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With COVID-19 vaccinations just beginning, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/twitter" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="twitter">Twitter <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> will ramp up its efforts to tamp down conspiracy theories that might discourage people from getting the vaccine.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2020/covid19-vaccine.html">newly expanded rules</a> apply to debunked information about the adverse effects of getting vaccinated, misleading tweets claiming the vaccine is not necessary and conspiracies that claim COVID-19 vaccines are used to &#8220;intentionally cause harm to or control populations.&#8221; Twitter&#8217;s updated policy will go into effect on December 21.</p>
<p>Twitter will require users who tweet something that falls in one of those categories to delete the content before being allowed to tweet again. Addressing vaccine misinformation that doesn&#8217;t meet the threshold for removal, Twitter says that it will begin placing warning labels on &#8220;unsubstantiated rumors, disputed claims, as well as incomplete or out-of-context information about vaccines&#8221; starting in early 2021. Those tweets may also be hidden, have their engagement limited and be accompanied by public health information labels.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company said that it will prioritize removing misinformation with the greatest potential to do harm, and we&#8217;ve asked Twitter if that decision is made based on how much exposure a tweet is getting or the nature of its content. The new policies will be enforced through a hybrid approach of automation and human moderation.</p>
<p>Early in the pandemic, Twitter created a set of new content policies <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/18/twitter-coronavirus-covid-19-misinformation-policy/">specific to COVID-19 misinformation</a>, which was just beginning to take off. While bogus and potentially harmful misinformation about how the virus was transmitted <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/10/coronavirus-5g-covid-19-conspiracy-theory-misinformation/">were the big worries then</a>, the company&#8217;s new policy update will address concerns that online misinformation might lead a significant portion of the population to refuse to get vaccinated.</p>
<p>Having granular misinformation policies on the books is useful for future enforcement, but new rules aren&#8217;t worth anything if they aren&#8217;t enforced. We&#8217;ll be following misinformation around the COVID-19 vaccine as it becomes more widely available and keeping an eye out for how Twitter implements its latest effort to give conspiracies less oxygen on the platform.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="feVPF8R0yv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/18/twitter-coronavirus-covid-19-misinformation-policy/">Twitter broadly bans any COVID-19 tweets that could help the virus spread</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter broadly bans any COVID-19 tweets that could help the virus spread&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/18/twitter-coronavirus-covid-19-misinformation-policy/embed/#?secret=feVPF8R0yv" data-secret="feVPF8R0yv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/twitter-will-force-users-to-delete-covid-19-vaccine-conspiracy-theories/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088239</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Privacy is the new competitive battleground</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/privacy-is-the-new-competitive-battleground/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/privacy-is-the-new-competitive-battleground/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 20:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital identity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[identity management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal data]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088193</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By not only meeting the demands of these new regulations but exceeding them, companies have an opportunity to differentiate themselves from competitors to grow their bottom line,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Alex Andrade-Walz</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/alexmwalz">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Alex Andrade-Walz is Director of Marketing at <a href="https://www.evernym.com/">Evernym</a>, a market leader in self-sovereign identity.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">In November, Californians voted to pass <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/techtank/2020/11/17/by-passing-proposition-24-california-voters-up-the-ante-on-federal-privacy-law/">Proposition 24</a>, a ballot measure that imposes new regulations on the collection of data by businesses. As part of the California Privacy Rights Act (CPRA), individuals will now have the right to opt out of the sharing and sale of their personal information, while companies must “reasonably” minimize data collection to protect user privacy.</p>
<p>For companies like Apple, Facebook, Uber and Google, all of which are headquartered in California, these new requirements may seem like a limitation on their existing data collection capabilities.</p>
<p>Looking more closely, it’s a nuanced story: By not only meeting the demands of these new regulations but exceeding them, companies have an opportunity to differentiate themselves from competitors to grow their bottom line, thanks to new technologies that put data privacy in the hands of consumers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Take Apple, the world’s most valuable tech company, as an example. When Google and Facebook — two of Apple’s largest competitors — were under fire for exploiting customer data, CEO Tim Cook saw an opportunity to turn privacy into a competitive advantage.</p>
<p>The tech giant rolled out a suite of new privacy-maximizing features, including a new <a href="https://developer.apple.com/sign-in-with-apple/">Sign In With Apple</a> feature that allows users to securely log in to apps without sharing personal information with the apps’ developers. More recently, the company updated its <a href="https://www.apple.com/privacy/">privacy page</a> to better showcase how its flagship apps are designed with privacy in mind.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			By not only meeting the demands of these new regulations but exceeding them, companies have an opportunity to differentiate themselves from their competition.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</span></p>
<p>This doubling down on privacy took center stage in the company’s marketing campaigns, too, with “Privacy Matters” becoming the central message of its prime-time air spots and its 10,000+ billboards around the world.</p>
<p>And of course, the company could hardly resist taking the occasional jab at its data-hungry competitors:</p>
<p>&#8220;The truth is, we could make a ton of money if we monetized our customer — if our customer was our product,&#8221; said Cook in an <a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/4/6/17197754/watch-apple-ceo-tim-cook-msnbc">interview with MSNBC</a>. &#8220;We’ve elected not to do that.&#8221;</p>
<p>Apple’s commitment to privacy not only puts them in a stronger position to comply with new CPRA regulations. It also sends a strong message to an industry that has profited off of customer data, and an even stronger message to consumers: It’s time to respect personal data.</p>
<h2>The growing demand for privacy</h2>
<p>The prioritization of consumer data privacy comes out of a need to address growing consumer concerns, which have consistently made headlines in recent years. Attention-grabbing stories such as the Cambridge Analytica data privacy scandal, as well as major breaches at companies such as <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/enforcement/cases-proceedings/refunds/equifax-data-breach-settlement">Equifax</a>, have left consumers wondering whom they can trust and how they can protect themselves. And the research is pretty conclusive — consumers want more out of their businesses and governments:</p>
<ul>
<li>Only 52% of consumers feel like they can trust businesses, and only 41% worldwide trust their governments (<a href="https://www.thedrum.com/news/2017/01/16/edelman-trust-barometer-reveals-lowest-levels-trust">Edelman</a>).</li>
<li>85% of consumers believe businesses should be doing more to actively protect their data (<a href="https://newsroom.ibm.com/2018-04-15-New-Survey-Finds-Deep-Consumer-Anxiety-over-Data-Privacy-and-Security">IBM</a>).</li>
<li>61% of consumers say their fears of having personal data compromised have increased in the last two years (<a href="https://www.salesforce.com/blog/2018/06/consumer-data-privacy-research.html">Salesforce</a>).</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s hard to say exactly how this trust crisis will manifest in the global economy, but we’ve already seen several large boycotts, like the <a href="https://thenextweb.com/facebook/2018/09/05/it-turns-out-lots-of-people-actually-did-deletefacebook/">#DeleteFacebook</a> movement, and a staggering <a href="https://newsroom.ibm.com/2018-04-15-New-Survey-Finds-Deep-Consumer-Anxiety-over-Data-Privacy-and-Security">75% of consumers</a> who say they won’t purchase from a company they don’t trust with their data.</p>
<p>And it’s not just Big Tech. From loyalty programs and inventory planning to smart cities and election advertising, it’s hard to overestimate the appetite — and effect — of using data to optimize processes and drive behavioral change.</p>
<p>As we look toward a new data-driven decade, however, we’re starting to realize the cost of this big data arms race: Consumers have lost trust in both the private and public sectors.</p>
<p>Private sector initiatives like Apple’s strengthened commitment to privacy, alongside public policy legislation like the CPRA, have the potential to not only build back consumer trust but to go even further beyond the minimum requirements. Thanks to new technologies like <a href="https://www.evernym.com/blog/inevitable-return-self-sovereign-identity/">self-sovereign identity</a>, companies can transform their data privacy policies, while cutting costs, reducing fraud and improving customer experiences.</p>
<h2>The value of SSI</h2>
<p>Self-sovereign identity (or SSI) leverages a thin layer of distributed ledger technology and a dose of very advanced cryptography to enable companies to prove the identities of their customers, without putting privacy at risk.</p>
<p>At its simplest, SSI is a way of giving consumers more control over their personal information. It offers a way for consumers to digitally store and manage personal information (in the form of <a href="https://www.evernym.com/blog/gentle-introduction-verifiable-credentials/"> verifiable credentials</a>) that are issued and signed by a trusted authority (like a government, bank or university) in a way that can never be altered, embellished or manipulated. Consumers can then share this information when, where and with whom they wish as a way of proving things about themselves.</p>
<p>While sharing digital records online is nothing new, SSI changes the game in two fundamental ways:</p>
<ol>
<li>Organizations can capture the required data, without overcollection. Unlike the physical credentials we carry in our wallets, like driver’s licenses and insurance cards, a digital verifiable credential can be divided into individual attributes, which can be shared separately.</li>
</ol>
<p>The classic example is walking into a bar and showing the bouncer your driver’s license to verify that you are of legal age. The card reveals the necessary data, but it also includes information that the bar has no business knowing — such as your name and address. With verifiable credentials, we can share proof of age without revealing anything else.</p>
<p>For sensitive cases, self-sovereign identity even allows us to cryptographically prove something about ourselves without revealing the actual data. In this case, we could provide a yes/no answer to whether we are of a legal age, without revealing our date of birth.</p>
<p>For individuals, data minimization represents a great stride forward in privacy. For organizations, it’s a way of avoiding the massive liability of storing and securing excess personally identifiable information.</p>
<ol>
<li>Correlation becomes much, much harder. While there are those who say privacy is a myth and our data will all be correlated anyway, self-sovereign identity protects us against many of the leading concerns with other digital identity solutions.</li>
</ol>
<p>For example, if we look at other tools that give us some level of data portability, like single-sign-on, there is always a concern that a single player in the middle can track what we do online. There’s a reason those Facebook ads are eerily relevant: They know every site and app we have signed into using our Facebook profile.</p>
<p>With SSI, there’s no one player or centralized registry in the middle. Verifiers (those requesting an identity verification) can verify the authenticity cryptographically, meaning they don’t have to “phone home” to the original credential issuer and the credential issuer has no way of knowing when, where or to whom a credential was shared. No correlatable signatures are shared, and your digital identity is truly under your control and for your eyes only.</p>
<p>As a result, the consumer benefits from better privacy and security, while businesses benefit from:</p>
<ul>
<li>Reduced fraud, with better, more accurate data verification at the time of account creation.</li>
<li>Reduced friction, with a dramatically faster sign-up process.</li>
<li>Reduced costs, both from time savings and from smarter KYC compliance (which normally costs large banks $500 million+ each year).</li>
<li>Increased efficiency, with less back-and-forth verifying third-party data.</li>
<li>Better customer experiences, with the ability to create a personalized, omnichannel customer experience without data harvesting.</li>
</ul>
<p>And it’s not science fiction, either. Several major governments, businesses and NGOs have already launched self-sovereign solutions. These include financial institutions like<a href="https://www.culedger.com/2019/11/culedger-completes-successful-pilot-program-of-mycuid-in-three-u-s-credit-unions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.culedger.com/2019/11/culedger-completes-successful-pilot-program-of-mycuid-in-three-u-s-credit-unions/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1608228216191000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHQv0di96-a7QwLmUef8suYqh0eQA"> UNIFY, Desert Financial and TruWest</a>, healthcare organizations like <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2020/can-blockchain-heal-ails-healthcare-lumedic-launches-new-quest-digital-identity-standards/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.geekwire.com/2020/can-blockchain-heal-ails-healthcare-lumedic-launches-new-quest-digital-identity-standards/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1608228216191000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEtxsfq0S5ZO7E77fqT-ScVE0toXQ">Providence Health</a> and the NHS, and telecom and travel giants like<a href="https://www.ledgerinsights.com/koreas-lg-cns-partners-with-evernym-for-decentralized-identity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.ledgerinsights.com/koreas-lg-cns-partners-with-evernym-for-decentralized-identity/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1608228216191000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGEg_yxFlnimWxbTVzifYaQ7AcZGg"> LG</a> and the International Air Transport Association.</p>
<p>It’s not clear how soon the technology will become ubiquitous, but it is clear that privacy is quickly emerging as the next competitive battleground. Newly passed regulations like CPRA codify the measures companies need to take, but it’s consumer expectations that will drive long-term shifts within the companies themselves.</p>
<p>For those ahead of the curve, there will be significant cost savings and growth — especially as customers start to shift their loyalty toward those businesses that respect and protect their privacy. For everyone else, it will be a major wake-up call as consumers demand to take back their data.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CGBrKt3Xt0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/2020-was-a-disaster-but-the-pandemic-put-security-in-the-spotlight/">2020 was a disaster, but the pandemic put security in the spotlight</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;2020 was a disaster, but the pandemic put security in the spotlight&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/2020-was-a-disaster-but-the-pandemic-put-security-in-the-spotlight/embed/#?secret=CGBrKt3Xt0" data-secret="CGBrKt3Xt0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/privacy-is-the-new-competitive-battleground/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088193</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ClickUp CEO talks hiring, raising and scaling in the white-hot productivity space</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/clickup-ceo-talks-hiring-raising-and-scaling-in-the-white-hot-productivity-space/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/clickup-ceo-talks-hiring-raising-and-scaling-in-the-white-hot-productivity-space/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 20:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ClickUp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[document management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[player]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[project management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stephen elop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[task management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trello]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webflow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zeb Evans]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2087691</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Few young software companies have had as great a year as San Diego-based ClickUp . The company, which makes business productivity tools for task management, goals and docs, raised its first bit of outside funding in mid-2020. Just six months later, it has reached a $1 billion valuation after doubling its customer base and revenue [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Few young software companies have had as great a year as San Diego-based <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/clickup" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="clickup">ClickUp <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>. The company, which makes business productivity tools for task management, goals and docs, raised its first bit of outside funding in mid-2020.</p>
<p>Just six months later, it has reached a $1 billion valuation after doubling its customer base and revenue increased ninefold as businesses embraced remote work.</p>
<p>The new funding and valuation after just a few months of hefty growth show just how closely investors are watching the productivity software space. I spoke with ClickUp CEO <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/zeb-brian-evans" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="zeb-brian-evans">Zeb Evans <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> yesterday to get his insights on the challenges of hypergrowth and why it made sense to say &#8220;yes&#8221; to the check.</p>
<p><em>This interview has edited for length and clarity.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>TechCrunch: This has been an awfully busy year for your team. What&#8217;s happened since we talked about your Series A?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Zeb Evans:</strong> The last time we chatted with you, we were at an inflection point where we had seen a lot of growth pre-COVID and then post-COVID we saw that growth continue. So we just really kept up those growth rates and really increased in some areas. Last time we chatted we had about 100,000 teams and now we&#8217;re over double that with over 200,000 teams that use our software. I think we were at about a million users and now we&#8217;re well over two million users that use the product as well.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2087772" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2087772" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2087772 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/zebevans_headshot.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/zebevans_headshot.jpg 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/zebevans_headshot.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/zebevans_headshot.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/zebevans_headshot.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/zebevans_headshot.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/zebevans_headshot.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/zebevans_headshot.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2087772" class="wp-caption-text">CEO Zeb Evans. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> ClickUp</p></div></p>
<p><strong>That&#8217;s interesting, so it sounds like you&#8217;ve found a sweet spot in terms of team size?</strong></p>
<p>Yeah, our number of users per team ends up being around 10 people or a little bit more than that. And that&#8217;s really stayed true from six months ago to today.</p>
<p><strong><em>How has your own team&#8217;s size changed?</em></strong></p>
<p>We&#8217;re right around 200 people right now, so we&#8217;ve definitely more than doubled since the last time that we talked, and we&#8217;re going to double again hopefully in the next quarter so we&#8217;ve got an aggressive hiring plan to do that.</p>
<p><strong>Cool, so you&#8217;ve doubled your user base in six months as well as your team. How has your team adjusted to scaling so quickly?</strong></p>
<p>It&#8217;s a good question. I think that the biggest thing that we&#8217;ve always focused on is shipping a new version of ClickUp every week. That is our differentiation. We&#8217;ve kind of created these iterative cycles called natural product market fit and it&#8217;s been hard to keep up with that. I mean, we&#8217;ve done it but as you scale, you know you have many more users and more considerations to take into every feature that you change and feature that you develop.</p>
<p>I think that&#8217;s been like the biggest thing we&#8217;ve been focused on and listening to that community that that is ever-growing every week. Obviously hiring is always top of mind also, and we haven&#8217;t done that as fast as we&#8217;d like to. But we&#8217;re making improvements there and we&#8217;re getting there.</p>
<p><strong>A lot of startups raised opportunistic rounds during what&#8217;s seemed to be a very hot market, at what point did you think that it might make sense to raise even more money after closing that Series A?</strong></p>
<p>So, our Series A was our first outside capital and we didn&#8217;t really know what that would do at the time. What we saw when we raised that fund was that we were able to really accelerate our vision and our product. We&#8217;ve used these resources very efficiently and we saw great unit economics come out of that. And also as you mentioned, it&#8217;s certainly a good time and a great market to be in — the productivity market is just the hottest right now. So it was kind of a trifecta of that but the real reason to raise was certainly to be able to continue that product growth and the acceleration of scaling that comes with raising money.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/clickup-ceo-talks-hiring-raising-and-scaling-in-the-white-hot-productivity-space/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2087691</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The latest multistate antitrust lawsuit targets Google&#8217;s ad business</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/google-state-antitrust-lawsuit-texas-paxton/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/google-state-antitrust-lawsuit-texas-paxton/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 20:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antitrust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawsuits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The battle over big tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088192</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Texas announced Wednesday that it will sue Google, accusing the search giant of maintaining an illegal monopoly in online advertising. Texas will be joined by Arkansas, Indiana, Kentucky, Missouri, Mississippi, South Dakota, North Dakota, Utah and Idaho, according to reporting from Reuters. The suit was first announced in a video from Texas Attorney General Ken [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Texas announced Wednesday that it will sue <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/google" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="google">Google, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> accusing the search giant of maintaining an illegal monopoly in online advertising. Texas will be joined by Arkansas, Indiana, Kentucky, Missouri, Mississippi, South Dakota, North Dakota, Utah and Idaho, according to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-tech-antitrust-google/texas-and-nine-other-u-s-states-sue-google-for-abusing-market-power-idUSKBN28Q2RL">reporting from Reuters</a>. The suit was first announced in a video from Texas Attorney General Ken Paxton and the <a href="https://www.texasattorneygeneral.gov/sites/default/files/images/admin/2020/Press/20201216%20COMPLAINT_REDACTED.pdf">filing is now available online</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;It isn&#8217;t fair that google effectively eliminated its competition and crowned itself the head of online advertising,&#8221; Paxton said. Paxton argues that Google&#8217;s advertising practices and &#8220;anticompetitive conduct&#8221; give it too much power over the online advertising ecosystem, to the detriment of publishers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BREAKING?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BREAKING</a>: Texas takes the lead once more! Today, we’re filing a lawsuit against <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Google?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Google</a> for anticompetitive conduct.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This internet Goliath used its power to manipulate the market, destroy competition, and harm YOU, the consumer. Stay tuned… <a href="https://t.co/fdEVEWQb0e">pic.twitter.com/fdEVEWQb0e</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Texas Attorney General (@TXAG) <a href="https://twitter.com/TXAG/status/1339283520099856384?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 16, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Paxton&#8217;s name might sound familiar. He&#8217;s the state official who <a href="https://www.texastribune.org/2020/12/10/ken-paxton-donald-trump-election-lawsuit/">led a recent lawsuit</a> disputing President-elect Joe Biden&#8217;s wins in the battleground states of Georgia, Pennsylvania, Michigan and Wisconsin on behalf of Texas. The Supreme Court <a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/12/11/945617913/supreme-court-shuts-door-on-trump-election-prospects">unceremoniously rejected</a> the suit on the grounds that the state lacked the standing to file it. Paxton is also currently <a href="https://apnews.com/article/ken-paxton-austin-texas-crime-f8413d14842d848e69cf81bb4d2e87e2">under investigation by the FBI</a> for bribery allegations, making him a deeply controversial figure to lead such an effort.</p>
<p>The lawsuit from the coalition of states comes two months after the Justice Department <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/justice-department-will-reportedly-file-its-antitrust-lawsuit-against-google-today/">filed its own antitrust suit against Google</a>. The DOJ&#8217;s effort is focused on <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-sues-monopolist-google-violating-antitrust-laws">&#8220;anticompetitive and exclusionary practices&#8221;</a> in the company&#8217;s search and advertising business.</p>
<p>Last week, 46 states <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/facebook-antitrust-state-attorneys-general/">announced a lawsuit</a> against Facebook over parallel antitrust concerns. That suit, which the state of Texas is also participating in, alleges that Facebook built a monopoly through predatory business practices like buying its rivals. The FTC also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/ftc-seeks-to-break-up-facebook-alleging-illegal-monopoly/">filed its own lawsuit</a> against Facebook last week, alleging that the company is a monopoly and that its acquisition of Instagram and WhatsApp should be undone.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ijQ9zwmFd4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/ftc-seeks-to-break-up-facebook-alleging-illegal-monopoly/">FTC seeks to break up Facebook, alleging illegal monopoly</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;FTC seeks to break up Facebook, alleging illegal monopoly&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/ftc-seeks-to-break-up-facebook-alleging-illegal-monopoly/embed/#?secret=ijQ9zwmFd4" data-secret="ijQ9zwmFd4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/the-battle-over-big-tech/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/battle-over-big-tech-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/google-state-antitrust-lawsuit-texas-paxton/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088192</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook highlights small businesses as it ramps up Apple criticism</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/facebook-apple-small-business/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/facebook-apple-small-business/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 20:01:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088145</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook already made it clear that it isn&#8217;t happy about Apple&#8217;s upcoming restrictions on app tracking and ad targeting, but the publicity battle entered a new phase today. Over the summer, Apple announced that beginning in iOS 14, developers will have to ask users for permission in order to use their IDFA identifiers for ad [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="facebook">Facebook <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> already made it clear that it isn&#8217;t happy about Apple&#8217;s upcoming restrictions on app tracking and ad targeting, but the publicity battle entered a new phase today.</p>
<p>Over the summer, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/apple" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="apple">Apple <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> announced that beginning in iOS 14, developers will have to ask users for permission in order to use their IDFA identifiers for ad targeting. On one level, it&#8217;s simply giving users a choice, but because they&#8217;ll have to opt-in to participate, the assumption is that we&#8217;ll see a dramatic reduction in app tracking and targeting.</p>
<p>The actual change was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/apple-delay-ios-14-privacy-ad-tracking/">delayed until early next year</a>, but in the meantime Facebook suggested that this might <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/27/facebook-vs-apple-ad-tracking/">mean the end of its Audience Network</a> (which uses Facebook data to target ads on other websites and apps) on iOS.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Then, this morning, Facebook placed print ads in The New York Times, The Wall Street Journal and The Washington Post declaring that it&#8217;s &#8220;standing up to Apple for small businesses everywhere,&#8221; and it published <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2020/12/speaking-up-for-small-businesses/">a blog post</a> and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/apple-ios-14-speak-up-for-small-business">website</a> making the same argument.</p>
<p>While it&#8217;s easy to see all of this as an attempt to put a more sympathetic face on a PR campaign that&#8217;s really just protecting Facebook&#8217;s ad business, Dan Levy — the company&#8217;s vice president of ads and business products — got on a call with reporters today to argue otherwise.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2088221" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2088221" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2088221" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ON-RECORD_AD-Standing-up-to-Apple-for-small-business.jpg?w=374" alt="Facebook ad" width="374" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ON-RECORD_AD-Standing-up-to-Apple-for-small-business.jpg 1663w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ON-RECORD_AD-Standing-up-to-Apple-for-small-business.jpg?resize=82,150 82w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ON-RECORD_AD-Standing-up-to-Apple-for-small-business.jpg?resize=165,300 165w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ON-RECORD_AD-Standing-up-to-Apple-for-small-business.jpg?resize=768,1397 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ON-RECORD_AD-Standing-up-to-Apple-for-small-business.jpg?resize=374,680 374w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ON-RECORD_AD-Standing-up-to-Apple-for-small-business.jpg?resize=845,1536 845w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ON-RECORD_AD-Standing-up-to-Apple-for-small-business.jpg?resize=1126,2048 1126w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ON-RECORD_AD-Standing-up-to-Apple-for-small-business.jpg?resize=27,50 27w" sizes="(max-width: 374px) 100vw, 374px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2088221" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>For one thing, he said that with its &#8220;diversified&#8221; advertising business, Facebook won&#8217;t feel the impact as keenly as small businesses, particularly since it already acknowledged potential ad targeting challenges <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/facebook-q3-2020-earnings-snap/">in its most recent earnings report</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve already been factoring this into our expectations for the business,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>In contrast, Levy said small businesses rely on targeting in order to run efficient advertising campaigns — and because they&#8217;ve got small budgets, they need that efficiency. He predicted that if Apple moves forward with its plans, &#8220;Small businesses will struggle to stay afloat and many aspiring entrepreneurs may never get off the ground.&#8221;</p>
<p>Levy was joined by two small business owners, Monique Wilsondebriano of <a href="https://www.instagram.com/charlestongourmetburger/">Charleston Gourmet Burger Company</a> in South Carolina and Hrag Kalebjian of <a href="https://www.instagram.com/henryshouseofcoffee/">Henry&#8217;s House of Coffee</a> in San Francisco. Kalebjian said that while business in the coffee shop is down 40% year-over-year, his online sales have tripled, and he credited targeted Facebook campaigns for allowing him to tell personal stories about his family&#8217;s love for Armenian coffee.</p>
<p>Wilsondebriano, meanwhile, said that when she and her husband Chevalo started a business selling their homemade burger marinade, &#8220;we did not have the option to run radio ads or TV ads, we just didn’t have a budget for that&#8221; — and so they turned to Facebook and Instagram. With the marinade now available in 50 states and 17 countries, Wilsondebriano said, &#8220;It makes me sad that if this update happens, so many small businesses won’t get that same opportunity that Cheval and I had.&#8221;</p>
<p>Levy also suggested that Apple&#8217;s bottom line might benefit from the changes — if developers make less money on ads from Facebook and other platforms, they may need to rely more on subscriptions or in-app transactions (with Apple collecting its much-discussed fee), and they might turn to Apple&#8217;s own targeted advertising platform.</p>
<p>A number of ad industry groups have also taken issue with Apple&#8217;s policy, with SVP Craig Federighi fighting back in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/apple-takes-aim-at-adtech-hysteria-over-ios-app-tracking-change/">a speech criticizing what he called &#8220;outlandish&#8221; and &#8220;false&#8221; claims</a> from the adtech industry. In that speech, Federighi said Apple&#8217;s App Tracking Transparency feature is designed &#8220;to empower our users to decide when or if they want to allow an app to track them in a way that could be shared across other companies’ apps or websites.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Update:</strong> Apple sent out the following statement.</p>
<blockquote><p>We believe that this is a simple matter of standing up for our users. Users should know when their data is being collected and shared across other apps and websites — and they should have the choice to allow that or not. App Tracking Transparency in iOS 14 does not require Facebook to change its approach to tracking users and creating targeted advertising, it simply requires they give users a choice.</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QsbjJFx1pn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/27/facebook-vs-apple-ad-tracking/">Facebook isn&#8217;t happy about Apple&#8217;s upcoming ad tracking restrictions</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook isn&#8217;t happy about Apple&#8217;s upcoming ad tracking restrictions&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/27/facebook-vs-apple-ad-tracking/embed/#?secret=QsbjJFx1pn" data-secret="QsbjJFx1pn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/facebook-apple-small-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088145</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to pick an investor in good or bad times</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/how-to-pick-an-investor-in-good-or-bad-times/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/how-to-pick-an-investor-in-good-or-bad-times/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 19:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088072</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Investors put money into businesses they understand and founders they trust and respect. That is a constant at any time, COVID-19 or not.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">MIke Myer</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mikemyer/">Mike Myer</a> is CEO and founder of <a href="https://quiq.com/">Quiq</a>, a startup building a new customer service platform that allows customers to interact with companies via text messaging as easily as they would with their friends.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">In 20 years of working for startups, I&#8217;ve never seen as many plot twists and turns as I have in the last several months. Times are tough.</p>
<p>But, from the perspective of raising capital, 2020 has not been an awful time to be a startup founder. The world has changed, but the fundamentals of raising capital are the same. In the first half of the year, <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/q2-2020-global-venture-report-funding-through-the-pandemic/">VCs invested $129 billion</a>, and Q3 is up 9% year-over-year, reports Crunchbase<sup id="fnref2"></sup>.</p>
<p>After the screeching halt to business in April subsided, founders and investors, people who are generally comfortable with uncertainty, got back to work raising and investing.</p>
<p>Choosing the right VC is one of the most important decisions startup founders will make. In good times, the choice can make or break a startup. When times are bad, it&#8217;s even more likely that the wrong VC partner could be the catalyst that starts a downward spiral. With many funds still looking to make investments before the end of the year and startups jockeying for cash, founders need to know how to find the right investor.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			With many funds still looking to make investments before the end of the year and startups jockeying for cash, founders need to know how to find the right investor.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</span></p>
<p>It’s not about simply choosing an investor — you are hiring your next boss. The investor should be someone you feel comfortable working with and working for.</p>
<p>You don’t want an investor who is checked out, but too much focus isn’t good, either. And, you don’t want an investor who is completely agreeable since your best outcome will be driven by a constructively demanding advisor.</p>
<p>My company, Quiq, had several term sheets when the dust settled on our Series B pitch meetings. Since the financial terms were similar, selecting an investor was made on a more subjective basis and boiled down to two fundamental questions:<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/how-to-pick-an-investor-in-good-or-bad-times/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088072</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon&#8217;s Project Kuiper has developed a small, low-cost customer terminal for its broadband satellite network</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/amazons-project-kuiper-has-developed-a-small-low-cost-customer-terminal-for-its-broadband-satellite-network/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/amazons-project-kuiper-has-developed-a-small-low-cost-customer-terminal-for-its-broadband-satellite-network/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 19:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antenna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broadband]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Communications Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Kuiper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telecommunications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wireless spectrum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2087917</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon&#8217;s Project Kuiper is perhaps one of the company&#8217;s most ambitious projects yet: Building a globe-spanning broadband wireless network to deliver affordable connectivity to underserved communities. Project Kuiper has made progress this year with a key FCC approval, and now it&#8217;s also created a prototype of a key piece of hardware that will help its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/amazon" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="amazon">Amazon&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Project Kuiper is perhaps one of the company&#8217;s most ambitious projects yet: Building a globe-spanning broadband wireless network to deliver affordable connectivity to underserved communities. Project Kuiper has made progress this year with a key FCC approval, and now it&#8217;s also created a prototype of a key piece of hardware that will help its future customers take advantage of the satellite network on the ground.</p>
<p>This is actually a big part of what will help make Project Kuiper a service that&#8217;s broadly accessible, and a development that puts the Amazon project in an industry-leading position with a unique advantage. The prototype developed by the team communicates on the Ka-band of the wireless spectrum, and is the smallest and lightest piece of hardware that can do that. It&#8217;s able to achieve speeds of up to 400 Mbps, and Amazon says that it&#8217;ll actually get better through future iterations.</p>
<p>For technical details on how this was accomplished and what it means for the final design, Amazon explains (from a blog post describing the design process):</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<blockquote><p>Our phased array antenna takes a different approach. Instead of placing antenna arrays adjacent to one another, we used tiny antenna element structures to overlay one over the other. This has never been accomplished in the Ka-band. The breakthrough allows us to reduce the size and weight of the entire terminal, while operating in a frequency that delivers higher bandwidth and better performance than other bands. Our design uses a combination of digital and analog components to electronically steer Ka-band beams toward satellites passing overhead.</p>
<p>The result is a single aperture phased array antenna that measures 12 inches in diameter, making it three times smaller and proportionately lighter than legacy antenna designs. This order of magnitude reduction in size will reduce production costs by an equal measure, allowing Amazon to offer customers a terminal that is more affordable and easier to install.</p></blockquote>
<p><div id="attachment_2087935" style="width: 1010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2087935" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2087935" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Project-Kuiper-Customer-Terminal-Animation.2020-12-16-10_01_29.gif" alt="" width="1000" height="562" /><p id="caption-attachment-2087935" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Amazon</p></div></p>
<p>The bottom line is that Amazon&#8217;s design for Kuiper can greatly reduce the cost and complexity of building the ground-based infrastructure that will be required in order to provide access to its network to end-users. It&#8217;s also low-latency, and Amazon has found that it can provide 4K streaming capabilities even during its testing with geostationary satellites today &#8212; which are as much as 50 times farther out from where Project Kuiper satellites will eventually be positioned in low-Earth orbit.</p>
<p>Amazon isn&#8217;t yet sharing specific pricing information about what the terminal will eventually cost, beyond touting its affordability relative to existing solutions. I&#8217;ll be talking to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2020/">Amazon SVP of Devices and Services Dave Limp at TC Sessions: Space today</a>, and we&#8217;ll discuss the antenna &#8212; along with everything else about the project.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uodHjgoRQt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/amazons-project-kuiper-will-seek-multiple-launch-providers-to-carry-its-satellites-to-space/">Amazon&#8217;s Project Kuiper will seek multiple launch providers to carry its satellites to space</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon&#8217;s Project Kuiper will seek multiple launch providers to carry its satellites to space&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/amazons-project-kuiper-will-seek-multiple-launch-providers-to-carry-its-satellites-to-space/embed/#?secret=uodHjgoRQt" data-secret="uodHjgoRQt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/amazons-project-kuiper-has-developed-a-small-low-cost-customer-terminal-for-its-broadband-satellite-network/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2087917</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: How did immigration change for startup founders in 2020?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/dear-sophie-how-did-immigration-change-for-startup-founders-in-2020/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/dear-sophie-how-did-immigration-change-for-startup-founders-in-2020/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 18:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work visa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2087970</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m on an F1 OPT and am about to incorporate a startup with my two American co-founders. What were the biggest immigration changes in 2020 affecting us?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/dear-sophie-can-founders-get-visas-in-2021-through-daca-or-other-means/">Dear Sophie: Can founders get visas in 2021 through DACA or other means?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/dear-sophie-hacks-for-the-march-2021-h-1b-lottery/">Dear Sophie: Hacks for the March 2021 H-1B lottery?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>Extra Crunch members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Dear Sophie: </strong></p>
<p><strong>I’m on an F1 OPT and am about to incorporate a startup with my two American co-founders. What were the biggest immigration changes in 2020 affecting us?</strong></p>
<p><strong>—Ambitious in Albany</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Dear Ambitious:</p>
<p>Congrats on creating your startup. The Electoral College has voted and Biden is scheduled to take office on January 20, 2021. It may take him a few months to undo many of the Trump immigration changes, so there are several things for you to consider.</p>
<p>2020 gave many of us whiplash with all the things that happened! We braced for the worst in April after President Trump tweeted that he would suspend immigration to the U.S. In the end, the executive proclamations he issued in April and June fell far short of that and immigration remains possible.</p>
<p>However, these bans remain in effect until at least the end of 2020. The proclamations placed moratoriums on the issuance of green cards by the U.S. Embassies and consulates abroad, as well as H-1B, H-2B, J-1 and L-1 work visas. The Department of State has expanded the list of exceptions to these bans so many people now qualify.</p>
<p>One of the current constraints affecting the most people is that many embassies and consulates remain closed or are operating at significantly reduced capacity. Given that, we are recommending to our clients who are already in the U.S. to avoid leaving by seeking Extensions of Status, Changes of Status and Adjustments of Status with USCIS stateside.</p>
<p>The H-1B may be another promising visa option for your future as a founder. There are two ways to do it: “cap-subject” (the annual spring lottery) and “cap-exempt” (anytime of year). At a minimum, it’s easy for your startup to register you for the upcoming H-1B lottery in March 2021. It only costs $10 to register an <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/episode-11-your-startups-first-h-1b/">H-1B candidate</a>. If you’re selected, your startup could file an H-1B petition on your behalf. If you are not selected, your startup can register you again in 2022.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/dear-sophie-how-did-immigration-change-for-startup-founders-in-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2087970</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pinterest says it will adopt workplace culture recommendations</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/pinterest-says-it-will-adopt-workplace-culture-recommendations/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/pinterest-says-it-will-adopt-workplace-culture-recommendations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Megan Rose Dickey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 17:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pinterest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Include]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088074</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pinterest has committed to adopting the recommendations from its special committee of the board of directors, the company wrote in a blog post today. The committee formed earlier this year in June, shortly after two former employees, Ifeoma Ozoma and Aerica Shimizu Banks, went public with their allegations of racial and gender discrimination while working [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/pinterest" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="pinterest">Pinterest <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has committed to adopting the recommendations from its special committee of the board of directors, <a href="https://newsroom.pinterest.com/en/post/statement-from-the-special-committee-of-the-board">the company wrote in a blog post today</a>. The committee formed earlier this year in June, shortly after two former employees, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/pinterests-22-5m-settlement-highlights-techs-inequities-say-former-employees-who-alleged-discrimination/">Ifeoma Ozoma and Aerica Shimizu Banks</a>, went public with their allegations of racial and gender discrimination while working at Pinterest.</p>
<p>The committee, <a href="https://newsroom.pinterest.com/en/post/statement-by-the-board-of-directors">which retained law firm WilmerHale to conduct a workplace review</a>, spoke with more than 350 current and former employees to make its recommendations geared toward improving diversity, equity and inclusion at Pinterest. Here are a few of those recommendations:</p>
<ul>
<li>mandatory unconscious bias training for every employee, including managers and executives</li>
<li>offer additional trainings on inclusivity and unconscious bias</li>
<li>include &#8220;diverse employees&#8221; in interview panels with job candidates</li>
<li>reward employees for their efforts to support and promote DEI</li>
<li>publish a diversity report twice a year for at least two years; after two years, publish the report annually</li>
<li>establish criteria for promotion eligibility</li>
<li>enhance Pinterest&#8217;s harassment and discrimination policy</li>
<li>create a centralized workplace investigations team to ensure consistent and fair outcomes</li>
</ul>
<p>You can <a href="https://www.pinterest-assets.com/m/137b577c199a60d3/original/Special-Committee-Communication-and-Recommendations-for-Pinterest.pdf">see all of the recommendations here.</a> Pinterest, in a statement to TechCrunch, said it&#8217;s committed to making those changes.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We value our employees and know it’s our responsibility to build a diverse, equitable and inclusive environment for everyone at Pinterest,&#8221; a Pinterest spokesperson said. &#8220;Because we understand the urgency for change, we have taken actions over the past months to ensure everyone at Pinterest feels safe, welcomed and championed and believe we’re on a path to ensuring a culture where all employees feel included and supported.&#8221;</p>
<p>In a note to employees, Pinterest CEO Ben Silbermann said that everyone at the company will have an opportunity to discuss the recommendations and ask questions later this week. Silberman also said he felt encouraged that many of the suggestions &#8220;mirror efforts we already have underway to build a culture where all employees feel included and supported.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="M3VYVvmRnU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/pinterests-22-5m-settlement-highlights-techs-inequities-say-former-employees-who-alleged-discrimination/">Pinterest’s $22.5M settlement highlights tech’s inequities, say former employees who alleged discrimination</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pinterest’s $22.5M settlement highlights tech’s inequities, say former employees who alleged discrimination&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/pinterests-22-5m-settlement-highlights-techs-inequities-say-former-employees-who-alleged-discrimination/embed/#?secret=M3VYVvmRnU" data-secret="M3VYVvmRnU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Earlier this week, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/pinterest-settles-gender-discrimination-lawsuit-with-former-coo-for-22-5-million/">Pinterest settled a gender discrimination lawsuit</a> with former COO Francoise Brougher for $22.5 million. But that hefty payout highlighted some of the inequities in tech. Brougher filed her lawsuit in August, after Ozoma and Banks went public with their allegations. While Brougher walked away with millions, Ozoma and Banks received less than one year&#8217;s worth of severance.</p>
<p>“So we, like in many, many, many other cases, Black women put ourselves on the line, shared absolutely everything that happened to us, then laid the groundwork for someone else to swoop in and collect ‘progress,’ ” <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/pinterests-22-5m-settlement-highlights-techs-inequities-say-former-employees-who-alleged-discrimination/">Ozoma previously told TechCrunch</a>. “No progress has been made here because no rights have been made with people who harm has been done to.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/pinterest-says-it-will-adopt-workplace-culture-recommendations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088074</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
