<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 09:11:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Uzoma Dozie&#8217;s Sparkle raises $3.1M for personal, business neobank play in Nigeria</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/14/uzoma-dozies-sparkle-raises-3-1m-for-personal-business-neobank-play-in-nigeria/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/14/uzoma-dozies-sparkle-raises-3-1m-for-personal-business-neobank-play-in-nigeria/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 09:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banking services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sparkle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The neobank wave is beginning to take shape in Africa, particularly in Nigeria, where new fintechs are trying to take on legacy banks by providing cheaper and more personalized banking services. Sparkle, founded by an ex-CEO of a former Nigerian incumbent bank, is one such fintech, and it has closed a seed round of $3.1 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The neobank wave is beginning to take shape in Africa, particularly in Nigeria, where new fintechs are trying to take on legacy banks by providing cheaper and more personalized banking services</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sparkle, founded by an ex-CEO of a former Nigerian incumbent bank, is one such fintech, and it has closed a seed round of $3.1 million to scale operations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nigerians have a love-hate relationship with traditional banks. Even though</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the number of active bank accounts in the country is <a href="https://nairametrics.com/2020/09/10/may-2020-active-bank-accounts-in-nigeria-surge-14-41-to-111-5-million-as-covid-19-drives-account-opening/">above 100 million</a> (from a population of about 200 million), problems around inefficient service delivery, serial downtimes, and bad loans and experiences have made many people distrust banking services.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217234" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Neobanks sensed an opportunity and are vying for the attention of these banked but unsatisfied customers. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sparkle, like any neobank in the market, is counting on standard features such savings, bill payments, top-ups, requesting or sending funds, as well as less common features &#8212; like bill splitting and reviewing spending breakdowns &#8212; to attract customers in a crowded market</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We&#8217;re quite different in a way because instead of separating financial services from lifestyle, we&#8217;ve tried to bring them together, especially as we&#8217;ve seen that more people are beginning to lead more digitally-led lives,&#8221; CEO <a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/uzomadozie">Uzoma Dozie</a> said to TechCrunch in an interview</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;It means that we don&#8217;t see our customers from accounts, payments, deposits or credit perspectives, but from how can we help them do what they want to do at any particular time</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.&#8221; So that&#8217;s Sparkle&#8217;s pitch &#8212; to provide financial, lifestyle and business support services to Nigerians.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In April, the company launched Sparkle Business to acquire a different set of underserved users: small and medium businesses</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sparkle claims the new business arm has caught on well with this category, which now has access to inventory and invoice management, tax advice, and payroll and employee management services</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These businesses can access these features with a tax identification number (TIN) and an email address &#8212; the lowest form of documentation in the market for businesses</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2217958" style="width: 631px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217958" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2217958" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Sparkle-Fundraise.png?w=621" alt="Sparkle" width="621" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Sparkle-Fundraise.png 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Sparkle-Fundraise.png?resize=137,150 137w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Sparkle-Fundraise.png?resize=274,300 274w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Sparkle-Fundraise.png?resize=768,841 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Sparkle-Fundraise.png?resize=621,680 621w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Sparkle-Fundraise.png?resize=46,50 46w" sizes="(max-width: 621px) 100vw, 621px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217958" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sparkle</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sparkle&#8217;s mix of providing banking services to individuals and businesses on a single platform is unique. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other neobanks in the country &#8212; such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/kuda-the-african-challenger-bank-raises-55m-at-a-500m-valuation/">Kuda</a>, VBank, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/tiger-global-leads-42m-series-b-in-nigerian-credit-led-neobank-fairmoney/">FairMoney</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/nigerian-digital-bank-carbon-hit-240m-in-payments-processed-last-year-up-89-from-2019/">Carbon</a> &#8212; </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are known</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to offer tailored services to individuals. At the same time, platforms including Brass and Prospa cater to varying sizes of businesses</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;As a small business, I&#8217;m not carrying my bank account on my mobile. I&#8217;m carrying my business. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">So we are bringing everything about your business into one place so that you can do business wherever you are,&#8221; Dozie said. &#8220;For individuals, we&#8217;re bringing everything into one place so that you can do what you want to do quite </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">easily</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> wherever you are</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. But the bottom line is that we&#8217;re providing you with the information that you need to take spontaneous decisions.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dozie highlights some features of Sparkle that customers might hardly get with other platforms. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For instance, customers can check the transaction history with a particular beneficiary without browsing through a financial statement, confirm the location where they made each transaction,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and schedule payments</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sparkle&#8217;s design is also tailored to how most Nigerians operate their lives offline. Customers can</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> have </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">multiple</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> accounts (personal and business) and switch whenever they want to on Sparkle. They can use the platform on various</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> phones with the same enhanced security as other platforms that allow login on a single phone, Dozie said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since launching last year, the neobank has acquired over 40,000 customers on the individual banking side and 2,000 businesses. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company began charging individual customers small fees to keep their accounts running and plans to charge businesses for most features except taxation services, said Dozie</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Similar to most digital banks in the country, Sparkle has a microfinance bank license. It has also secured a partnership with Visa to allow users to make in-person or digital payments with a Visa card. Other partnerships are with companies like Network International and PwC Nigeria.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Anyone knowledgeable on how the Nigerian fintech space works knows it can take some time to secure licenses and partnerships. Sparkle has been able to do so in under a year due to its CEO&#8217;s vast experience and connections.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before Sparkle, Dozie was the CEO and last group managing director of Diamond Bank. He</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> oversaw the bank&#8217;s corporate, commercial and retail arms before its merger with Access Bank; the business is now 29 million customers strong</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p>With Sparkle, Dozie is keen on expanding the capabilities of Nigeria&#8217;s banking and retail sectors, continuing from where he left off at Diamond Bank. As an investor himself, he enlisted an all-Nigerian cast for his seed round &#8212; lead investor <span style="font-weight: 400;">Leadway Assurance, participant Trium Network and a few unnamed high-net-worth individuals. The investment comes after Sparkle closed a </span>friends and family pre-seed round of $2 million within the past year.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He opined that while he could have raised money from foreign investors, he chose to go with this group of investors because they provide the experience and market that Sparkle needs to scale in Nigeria</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. He was also keen on getting high-net-worth individuals to invest in a tech company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Collectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, as a group of investors and business builders, we are Nigerians who are bullish about Nigeria and the opportunity the country presents </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in terms of</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> building global networks and communities, all via one app,&#8221; the CEO said in a statement</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The CEO told TechCrunch that Sparkle will use the investment for two purposes: building robotic process automation to help with mundane and repetitive processes, then hiring talent across engineering, finance risk and marketing.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/14/uzoma-dozies-sparkle-raises-3-1m-for-personal-business-neobank-play-in-nigeria/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217234</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>European point of sale provider SumUp acquires customer loyalty startup Fivestars for $317M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/european-point-of-sale-provider-sumup-acquires-customer-loyalty-startup-fivestars-for-317m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/european-point-of-sale-provider-sumup-acquires-customer-loyalty-startup-fivestars-for-317m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 05:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dcm ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fivestars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[harbourvest partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[menlo ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PitchBook Data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Square]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sumup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Victor Ho]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217893</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SumUp, a European-based competitor to Square, PayPal/iZettle and others that provide mobile-powered card readers and other sales technology to merchants and small businesses, has made an acquisition in the U.S. to dig deeper into that market, and to expand the kinds of services that it provides to customers globally. The company has acquired Fivestars, which [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://sumup.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SumUp</a>, a European-based competitor to Square, PayPal/iZettle and others that provide mobile-powered card readers and other sales technology to merchants and small businesses, has made an acquisition in the U.S. to dig deeper into that market, and to expand the kinds of services that it provides to customers globally.</p>
<p>The company has acquired <a href="https://www.fivestars.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fivestars</a>, which provides loyalty, marketing, payments and other services to small merchants, used by some 70 million consumers and 12,000 businesses in the U.S.. London-based SumUp said it will be paying $317 million in a combination of cash and stock for the San Francisco startup.</p>
<p>That is a bump up on the startup&#8217;s valuation as a private company. According to <a href="https://my.pitchbook.com/profile/54557-38/company/profile#deal-history/157699-90T" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PitchBook</a>, FiveStars &#8212; which was originally incubated in Y Combinator and later backed by VCs that included Salt Partners, Lightspeed, DCM Ventures, Menlo Ventures and HarbourVest Partners &#8212; was last valued at $285 million post-money when it raised a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/15/fivestars-series-d/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Series D of $52.5 million a year ago,</a> in October 2020.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217893" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>It&#8217;s not clear why Fivestars sold up, nor whether it was proactively approached or looking for a buyer, but you can&#8217;t help but wonder what kind of an impact the last year and a half, where a lot of people turned away from shopping in person due to the pandemic, had on the company&#8217;s business &#8212; which is largely predicated on in-person transactions.</p>
<p>On a more positive note, SumUp buying Fivestars now represents how it will be doubling down on the opportunity ahead now that people and merchants <em>are</em> coming back into the physical shopping fold.</p>
<p>SumUp got its start in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/08/23/make-way-for-another-european-square-sumup-launches-with-20m-in-backing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2012</a> as one of the many Square clones emerging out of Europe at a time when the U.S. company had yet to expand outside of its home market. Since then it has diversified into online payments, invoicing and other services needed by merchants and other small businesses. And it has grown. Today the company has more than 3 million merchant users in 34 markets, scale that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/sumup-which-helps-businesses-take-card-payments-raises-895m-to-double-down-on-growth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">helped it raise nearly $900 million in debt</a> earlier this year to fuel further expansion.</p>
<p>That funding has been used both to continue building out SumUp&#8217;s platform and footprint in existing markets, as well as to move into new territories.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Although SumUp has in theory been active in the U.S. for a couple of years, its presence there is modest, admitted Andrew Helms, SumUp&#8217;s managing director in the country. So this acquisition &#8212; SumUp&#8217;s first in the country &#8212; will be used to get a deeper foothold in that market.</p>
<p>Fivestars is a popular product, and SumUp hopes to leverage that existing business, which Fivestars says drives more than $3 billion in sales and 100 million transactions per year, to grow its own relationships with merchants, specifically signing them up to SumUp&#8217;s own card readers and other sales technology. Helms confirmed that the plan will be to keep Fivestars&#8217; branding for now and to work on integrating its product more closely into SumUp&#8217;s platform.</p>
<p>Victor Ho, Fivestars&#8217; co-founder and CEO, will also be staying on, along with the rest of the company&#8217;s SF-based team.</p>
<p>&#8220;We founded Fivestars to give small businesses the opportunity to thrive in the digital economy and over the years, we&#8217;ve achieved just that,&#8221; Ho said in a statement. &#8220;Understanding that SumUp shares this mission, it was an easy decision to partner, and together, we look forward to supporting a retail market that champions small business success.&#8221;</p>
<p>Acquiring Fivestars also makes a lot of sense in the context of how SumUp has grown. Part of its strategy has always been to pursue inorganic expansion, and over the years that has including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/04/27/sumup-and-payleven-merge-as-european-square-clones-consolidate/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">merging with Payleven</a>, another Square clone originally incubated by Berlin&#8217;s Rocket Internet; and buying<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/12/sumup-acquires-multi-channel-e-commerce-platform-shoplo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> and integrating Shoplo</a> to give its merchants the ability to sell across multiple marketplaces online.</p>
<p>Notably, SumUp didn&#8217;t have a loyalty product before this, so there will likely be opportunities to bring Fivestars&#8217; technology for the first time into other markets outside of the U.S., such as in Europe and Latin America, where SumUp is already active.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/european-point-of-sale-provider-sumup-acquires-customer-loyalty-startup-fivestars-for-317m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217893</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Singapore-based insurtech startup Surer nabs seed round to bolster its product development</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/singapore-based-insurtech-startup-surer-picks-up-seed-round-to-bolster-its-products-development/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/singapore-based-insurtech-startup-surer-picks-up-seed-round-to-bolster-its-products-development/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 01:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Surer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217870</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is an imbalance between demand and supply of general insurance due to the tedious workflow and processes that insurance intermediaries and insurance companies face.  Singaporean insurtech company Surer, which automates the workflow and processes via a cloud-based platform, helps insurance intermediaries get rapid access to insurance quotations and insurers to distribute their products more efficiently. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">There is an imbalance between demand and supply of general insurance due to the tedious workflow and processes that insurance intermediaries and insurance companies face. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Singaporean insurtech company </span><a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://surer.sg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Surer</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true">, which automates the workflow and processes via a cloud-based platform, helps insurance intermediaries get rapid access to insurance quotations and insurers to distribute their products more efficiently. By digitalizing the insurance work for insurers and intermediaries, its platform enables them to save time, focus on their clients and scale their business.  </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Surer was launched in September 2020 by </span><a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gordontay87/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Gordon Tay</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true">, </span><a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/renfred/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Renfred Tay</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> and </span><a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/derren-teo-36468695/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Derren Teo</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> with a mission to solve the enormous mismatch in demand and supply in a $1.7 trillion general insurance industry. </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217870" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The company has raised a $1 million seed round to enhance its platform and scale in Asia. Norwegian investor </span><a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://www.kistefos.no/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Kistefos</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true">, Markel Digital Investment and an angel investor participated in the latest round. Antler joined in its previous funding. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">In June 2021, Surer added a new feature, the Instant Quote Marketplace, which allows users to get quotations automatically and instantaneously. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The company is currently operating its service in Singapore, but plans to enter other markets like Malaysia, Hong Kong and Taiwan, Gordon Tay said. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">“We are focusing on building a digital ecosystem that serves for parties creating (the insurers) and distributing (the intermediaries) insurance products, and we run a B2B2C model,” co-founder Gordon Tay said. It is opposed to many other insurtech companies that operate an aggregator model, going direct to the consumer (B2C), he added.  </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tbXTLvnTkC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/hong-kong-insurtech-startup-coherent-gets-14-million-series-a-led-by-cathay-innovation/">Hong Kong insurtech startup Coherent gets $14 million Series A led by Cathay Innovation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hong Kong insurtech startup Coherent gets $14 million Series A led by Cathay Innovation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/hong-kong-insurtech-startup-coherent-gets-14-million-series-a-led-by-cathay-innovation/embed/#?secret=tbXTLvnTkC" data-secret="tbXTLvnTkC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Surer claims that it has seen strong traction with more than 350 intermediary signups and demo requests. Approximately $1 million in gross written premiums (GWP) was transacted, and the company expects to generate $1.5 million in GWP transactions by the end of this year. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Asia’s general insurance market is about $564 billion, and Singapore has approximately $2.9 billion, Gordon Tay mentioned. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Similar models to Surer outside of Southeast Asia include WeFox in Europe and Turtlemint in India, which have proven successful, Gordon Tay noted. </span></p>
<p>There are other insurtech players like online brokers &#8212; including Singapore’s MoneySmart and PolicyPal, and India’s PolicyBazaar and Indonesia’s PasarPolis, and Malaysia’s PolicyStreet &#8212; which are not Surer’s competitors but can be partners. The online brokers create products underwritten by the insurers and then sell them directly to consumers through their online platform. <span data-preserver-spaces="true">They can list their products on Surer’s platform (the Instant Quote Marketplace) and leverage the Surer intermediary force as an additional distribution channel (in addition to their online channel), Tay explained. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">“Kistefos has a strong investment portfolio in Norway and Europe, including companies delivering financial services. We see huge potential in Asian markets, and Surer has shown the ability to capitalize on the trend of digital transformation in the insurance industry in the region,” Bengt Rem, CEO of Kistefos, said. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UrC8qKK1kv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/31/european-insurtech-startup-wefox-grabs-650-million-at-3-billion-valuation/">European insurtech startup Wefox grabs $650 million at $3 billion valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;European insurtech startup Wefox grabs $650 million at $3 billion valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/31/european-insurtech-startup-wefox-grabs-650-million-at-3-billion-valuation/embed/#?secret=UrC8qKK1kv" data-secret="UrC8qKK1kv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PxdV6NHAaB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/india-insurance-startup-turtlemint-raises-30-million/">India&#8217;s insurance platform Turtlemint raises $30 million</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;India&#8217;s insurance platform Turtlemint raises $30 million&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/india-insurance-startup-turtlemint-raises-30-million/embed/#?secret=PxdV6NHAaB" data-secret="PxdV6NHAaB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/singapore-based-insurtech-startup-surer-picks-up-seed-round-to-bolster-its-products-development/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217870</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hyundai Motor plans to develop its own chips</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/hyundai-motor-plans-to-develop-its-own-chips/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/hyundai-motor-plans-to-develop-its-own-chips/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 23:32:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global chip shortage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyundai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toyota]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217869</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hyundai Motor is the latest automaker to announce plans to develop its own semiconductor chips in order to reduce reliance on chipmakers, according to the company&#8217;s global chief operating officer, José Munoz. As car sales fell during the pandemic, automakers paused their orders just as electronics manufacturers began ramping up production, and snapping up the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="item--paragraph--type--body field__item">
<div class="block block-">
<div class="field--name-field-paragraph-body ">
<p id="speakable-summary">Hyundai Motor is the latest automaker to announce plans to develop its own semiconductor chips in order to reduce reliance on chipmakers, according to the company&#8217;s global chief operating officer, José Munoz.</p>
</div>
<p>As car sales fell during the pandemic, automakers paused their orders just as electronics manufacturers began ramping up production, and snapping up the existing supply of chips, to meet the raised demand in laptops and gaming consoles. When consumers started buying vehicles again, automakers were met with a global semiconductor shortage that has led to most OEMs — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/02/tesla-delivers-record-breaking-number-of-vehicles-in-third-quarter/">apart from Tesla</a> and <a href="https://pressroom.toyota.com/toyota-motor-north-america-reports-u-s-september-and-third-quarter-2021-sales-results/">Toyota</a> —<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/gm-extends-chevy-bolt-ev-production-shutdown-through-mid-october/"> idling production lines</a> that caused <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/10/01/chip-shortage-tanks-gms-third-quarter-sales-.html">a dip in car sales</a>. As most OEMs also came out with aggressive plans to go electric, the need for chips has never been stronger. Aside from Hyundai, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/top-five-highlights-of-elon-musks-tesla-ai-day/">Tesla</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/gms-china-joint-venture-develops-own-auto-chips-2021-09-15/">General Motors</a> have announced plans to produce their own chips and cut out the middle man.</p>
<p>While Hyundai&#8217;s sales this past quarter didn&#8217;t suffer too much, Munoz did say the &#8220;toughest months&#8221; were August and September, according to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/hyundai-motor-says-it-wants-develop-chips-cut-reliance-chipmakers-2021-10-13/">Reuters. </a>The South Korean automaker had to temporarily shut down some factories this year, but Munoz said the worst had passed for the chip shortage, citing Intel&#8217;s massive investments to expand capacity.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217869" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Nonetheless, Munoz told reporters Hyundai doesn&#8217;t want to get caught without a supply again and needs to be more self-reliant in the space. He acknowledged that developing chips in-house would take a lot of time and investment, but that it&#8217;s &#8220;something we&#8217;re working on,&#8221; most likely in conjunction with Hyundai Mobis, the company&#8217;s parts affiliate.</p>
<p>&#8220;The ability to secure supply may be a distinguishing feature of the successful OEMs that survive the industry shakeup and consolidation,&#8221; Bob Leigh, senior market development director of commercial markets at Real-Time Innovations, a software framing company, told TechCrunch. &#8220;It is more likely that OEMs will acquire and/or partner with the firms that can secure the supply. But, this shortage will drive the industry to adopt new <span class="il">chip</span> technologies that are more economical to produce. The <span class="il">chip</span> makers don&#8217;t want to make the legacy <span class="il">chips</span> that automakers want.&#8221;</p>
<p>Leigh also said that although many automakers will probably move in the same direction of trying to own their own chip development, it&#8217;s not necessarily feasible because they don&#8217;t have the expertise and he doesn&#8217;t think it will scale.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="item--paragraph--type--body field__item">
<div class="block block-">
<div class="field--name-field-paragraph-body ">
<div class="block block-ctools-block block-entity-fieldnodefield-paragraphs" data-block-plugin-id="entity_field:node:field_paragraphs">
<div class="field field--name-field-paragraphs field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden article-paragraph field__items">
<div class="item--paragraph--type--body field__item">
<div class="block block-">
<div class="field--name-field-paragraph-body ">
<p class="paragraph-newsletter-9">Even without its proprietary supply, Hyundai Motor is still on track to manufacture electric vehicles in the U.S. next year with potential plans to enhance its Alabama factory and increase production capacity, said Munoz. The COO, who is also president of Hyundai Motor North America, encouraged the U.S. government to extend proposed $4,500 EV tax credit incentives to vehicles made at non-union factories, as well as union ones. Aside from Hyundai&#8217;s U.S. factories, Rivian, Tesla and Toyota factories are not unionized.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/hyundai-motor-plans-to-develop-its-own-chips/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217869</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Smart growth tactics can put account-based marketing within reach for startups and SMBs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/smart-growth-tactics-can-put-account-based-marketing-within-reach-for-startups-and-smbs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/smart-growth-tactics-can-put-account-based-marketing-within-reach-for-startups-and-smbs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 23:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[account based marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HubSpot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ideal customer profile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217570</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many startups think account-based marketing is reserved for corporations that employ enterprise marketing teams and can fling about big marketing budgets. This couldn’t be further from the truth.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jonas van de Poel</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/jonasvandepoel">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jonas van de Poel is head of content marketing at <a href="https://www.unmuted.com/">Unmuted</a>, an Amsterdam-based growth marketing agency.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">For many startups and SMBs, successfully setting up account-based marketing strategies can feel like a pipe dream. Startups still struggling to find product-market fit wouldn’t dream of being able to identify and map out their ideal customer profile (ICP) clearly enough. At the same time, small and midsize businesses often lack the resources to invest in elaborate multitouch-point content marketing strategies.</p>
<p>Smaller businesses and startups usually don’t employ full-fledged marketing teams either, and their sales reps are strapped for time anyway. To them, account-based marketing (ABM) is something reserved for corporations that employ enterprise marketing teams and can fling about big marketing budgets.</p>
<p>This couldn’t be further from the truth, and both startups and SMBs can, and should, invest in ABM strategies. With a handful of smart growth tactics and clever tools, ABM strategies don&#8217;t have to break the bank to be successful.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Account-based approaches thrive when you amend your mindset and focus on long-term investments and relationship building. One way to do this is by creating a (sense of) community.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>There are, however, a few distinctive characteristics your business should probably have before investing in ABM:</p>
<ul>
<li>Larger than average deal sizes or customer value make ABM much more worthwhile. If you’re working with a long tail business model, this probably isn’t for you.</li>
<li>Businesses with long sales cycles are equally well suited to ABM strategies. The longer the sales cycle, the more important it is to cater to key accounts with personalized content and outreach across multiple channels and at multiple touch points.</li>
<li>Complex buying committees are also susceptible to being marketed to in a hyperpersonalized way. Spray-and-pray marketing won’t do you any good here.</li>
<li>ABM strategies work best when sales, marketing and service are fully aligned. Has your organization bought into the idea of RevOps? Good, ABM might be the way to go.</li>
</ul>
<p>In short, the points above sketches what might be described as the higher segment of B2B companies. Startups and SMBs that conform to these characteristics would do well to consider the growth tactics we outline below.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Help TechCrunch find the best growth marketers for startups. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">this quick survey</a> and we&#8217;ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
<hr />
<h2>What is ABM? How about ABS? And what&#8217;s this ABX business?!</h2>
<p>Before we get down to the hands-on approaches and actionable tips for getting started with ABM, let’s look at some definitions to get a clearer picture of what we’re talking about.</p>
<h3>Account-based marketing</h3>
<p>Account-based marketing is a business strategy, sometimes also referred to as key account marketing, where businesses focus marketing resources on specific targets (key accounts) in a market.</p>
<p>This is like flipping a traditional inbound marketing funnel upside down. Instead of generating leads, segmenting, activating and then selling to them, ABM takes the opposite approach. You identify specific key accounts, build relationships with these targets, and then sell to your network.</p>
<p>This also means producing highly relevant, highly personalized marketing content for all types of decision-makers along all points of the customer journey.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2217628" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217628" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2217628" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image2-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="538" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image2-2.png 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image2-2.png?resize=150,79 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image2-2.png?resize=300,158 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image2-2.png?resize=768,403 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image2-2.png?resize=680,357 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image2-2.png?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217628" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Unmuted</p></div></p>
<h3>Account-based sales (ABS)</h3>
<p>Account-based selling is a B2B sales model that takes a similar approach and focuses on selling to the same key accounts. Patience is the name of the game here. Instead of trying to get that demo scheduled as quickly as possible, your sales reps will be investing in relationships.</p>
<p>This highly personalized and strategic process builds upon the tailored marketing content we mentioned. Sales and marketing alignment is key to successful execution of account-based sales strategies.</p>
<p>Your marketing and sales teams will benefit from defining and reporting on shared goals and even KPIs.</p>
<h3>Account-based experience (ABX)</h3>
<p>Account-based revenue generation will work best when you’ve got companywide buy-in from not just sales and marketing departments, but your customer success team too. This helps serve your key accounts a personalized experience during a holistic buying journey that continues post-purchase.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/smart-growth-tactics-can-put-account-based-marketing-within-reach-for-startups-and-smbs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217570</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The importance of decentralized insurance in a destabilizing climate</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/the-importance-of-decentralized-insurance-in-a-destabilizing-climate/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/the-importance-of-decentralized-insurance-in-a-destabilizing-climate/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 22:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy consumption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food production]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parametric insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[united nations]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217598</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The beauty of decentralized parametric insurance is its simplicity: It can be understood as an “if/then” equation, which is automatically executed via a smart contract. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Michiel Berende</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/etherisc">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Michiel Berende, the chief inclusive officer at <a href="https://etherisc.com/">Etherisc</a>, believes in delivering better financial services access to those who need it most through inclusive insurance.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">What does it mean for economies, governments and communities when “once in a lifetime” weather events begin to occur on an annual basis?</p>
<p>We are witnessing an entirely new scale of natural disasters across the world. Previously, emerging economies bore the brunt of induced climate disasters, but it’s now impossible to ignore the catastrophic impacts of our changing climate, no matter what corner of the globe you reside in.</p>
<p>Wildfires in California are adding to thousands of deaths reported annually due to poor air quality, while in Germany, hundreds have lost their lives this year as a result of record flooding. Preparation for such extreme and hazardous weather conditions is now a priority for us all.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217598" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>One of many questions that emerges from the increase in such extreme weather events is this: Who will foot the bill? A<a href="http://thoughtleadership.aon.com/Documents/20212107_analytics-if-1H-global-recap.pdf"> report from AON</a> found that total economic losses from natural disasters in the first half of 2021 are estimated to be around $93 billion. As we approach the <a href="https://ukcop26.org/">2021 United Nations Climate Change Conference</a> (COP26), the economic implications of climate change loom heavily among the litany of issues to be resolved.</p>
<p>Climate change has been cited as the biggest risk to the global economy, with fears of an estimated <a href="https://www.swissre.com/institute/research/topics-and-risk-dialogues/climate-and-natural-catastrophe-risk/expertise-publication-economics-of-climate-change.html">10% drop in total economic value by 2050</a>. As always, the case is more challenging for emerging economies, with countries including Malaysia, Thailand, India, the Philippines and Indonesia standing to be the most <a href="https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2021/06/impact-climate-change-global-gdp/">negatively impacted economically</a>, with the global economy facing up to an 18% loss in GDP by 2050.</p>
<p>It is high time to assess alternative approaches to alleviating the effects of climate change. How are billions of financially excluded people in emerging economies to cope with these devastating impacts?</p>
<h2>Blockchain for good</h2>
<p>Cryptocurrencies and non-fungible tokens (NFTs) have received a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/21/the-debate-about-cryptocurrency-and-energy-consumption/">fair share of scrutiny</a> when it comes to energy consumption, and many outstanding areas still require attention and resolutions. However, looking beyond these use cases, we are seeing more blockchain-based solutions emerge that are specifically designed to protect those unfairly impacted by climate change.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Blockchain is already playing a positive role, from facilitating regenerative agriculture to encouraging conscious consumption. Another quickly emerging area of growth is decentralized parametric insurance — recognized by the <a href="https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2021/06/blockchain-can-help-us-beat-climate-change-heres-how/">World Economic Forum</a> as a means to provide a lifeline for traditionally underserved communities that are facing ever-increasing disruption due to extreme weather.</p>
<p>The beauty of decentralized parametric insurance is its simplicity: It can be understood as an “if/then” equation, which is automatically executed via a smart contract. For example, if in a given area it rains 5 inches within 24 hours, the insured farmer immediately receives a payout according to the agreed contract for flood-related damages. Very simple.</p>
<p>By removing expensive insurance assessment processes and coupling this with significant innovations in an automated payout process, parametric insurance greatly reduces transaction costs and claim cycles. Parametric insurance claims can be made via a basic phone with a network connection, enabling those in remote locations and &#8212; perhaps surprisingly &#8212; with access to only basic technology to avail themselves of blockchain-backed insurance policies.</p>
<h2>Protecting the global food chain</h2>
<p>Climate change will almost certainly raise food prices and erode many people’s ability to afford select foods in the near term. In the case of crop protection against weather risks, parametric insurance provides an extra layer of protection for farmers who are typically unable to access traditional insurance products.</p>
<p>The fate of their crop yield is intertwined with increasing carbon emissions through no fault of their own. This poses a significant threat to global food security, as well as job security for smallholder farmers. Given smallholder farmers with landholdings under 5 hectares are responsible for <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/325405959_How_much_of_the_world%27s_food_do_smallholders_produce">an average of 50%</a> of global food production, putting protections in place is a necessity for the sake of the global food supply.</p>
<p>In emerging economies today, as many as 270 million smallholder farmers are underinsured, with <a href="https://www.raflearning.org/sites/default/files/sep_2018_isf_syngneta_insurance_report_final.pdf?token=1i4u5GwD">only 20%</a> having access to agricultural insurance coverage. This number falls to a paltry 3% in sub-Saharan Africa.</p>
<p>With the global population forecast to reach nearly 10 billion by 2050, coupled with the crisis faced by farmers in emerging economies, the smallholder agricultural industry is in desperate need of new ideas for enhanced protection. Blockchain-enabled, data-driven innovations, such as decentralized parametric insurance, can serve as a multipronged solution, providing relief for those afflicted by severe weather conditions and incentivizing conscious consumption while at the same time driving capital, at scale, into climate adaption to benefit smallholder farmers and global food production.</p>
<h2>Expanding use cases and investors</h2>
<p>As our planet’s climate undergoes further destabilization, technological innovations can play a growing role in our efforts to manage destructive events and reduce the scale of their impact.</p>
<p>Countries such as the U.K. have already <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/independent-review-of-flood-insurance-published">commissioned reports</a> on the need for greater protection for those at risk of flooding due to rising sea levels. There is an opportunity to rethink and reshape how flood risks are evaluated and premiums calculated: Parametric contracts can equip insurers with well-founded data to report flood depth and produce accurate and timely payouts.</p>
<p>Decentralized insurance is not just more inclusive for those benefiting from coverage, but also opens up insurance opportunities to an entirely new class of investor who could redefine the definition of risk capital. This form of insurance is far more open, allowing a wider group of investors to get involved, not just the closed shop of high-capital investors in traditional markets.</p>
<p>Furthermore, blockchain has the potential to act as a medium for crowdfunding and insurance to intersect in the name of benevolent social and environmental impact. There is a huge appetite for investment in CSR (corporate social responsibility) and ESG (environmental, social and governance) initiatives.</p>
<p>ESG funds <a href="https://www.morningstar.com/lp/sustainable-funds-landscape-report">captured over $50 billion worth of new money during 2020</a> &#8212; more than double the prior year. Additionally, the number of ESG funds in the U.S. grew to almost 400 last year — a rise of 30% from 2019.</p>
<h2>Act now, talk later</h2>
<p>As world leaders gather for COP26 to decide their long-term strategies and approaches to tackle climate change at a national and international level, millions of people across the globe are currently suffering the consequences of years of inaction and delays to real change.</p>
<p>Right now, blockchain solutions such as decentralized parametric insurance are making tangible headway to relieve pressure on those most affected by climate change. While we await political consensus on a cohesive global approach, blockchain offers easy-to-implement solutions to help those most in need.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/the-importance-of-decentralized-insurance-in-a-destabilizing-climate/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217598</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Blue Origin&#8217;s second crewed launch includes guest star William Shatner</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/daily-crunch-76/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/daily-crunch-76/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 22:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217788</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for October 13, 2021! Today’s newsletter features fan favorites in space, a startup called “Karat,” and the final resting place of ClassPass. But before we get into the latest from startupland, if you are into the realm of digital security, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/security-takes-center-stage-at-tc-sessions-saas-this-month/">this is for you</a>. – <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ij8uNBjpWJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/security-takes-center-stage-at-tc-sessions-saas-this-month/">Security takes center stage at TC Sessions: SaaS this month</a></p></blockquote><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217788" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Security takes center stage at TC Sessions: SaaS this month&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/security-takes-center-stage-at-tc-sessions-saas-this-month/embed/#?secret=Ij8uNBjpWJ" data-secret="Ij8uNBjpWJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/payments-giant-stripe-says-its-re-entering-the-crypto-market/">Stripe gets back into crypto:</a> </strong>Online payments giant Stripe is building a crypto team despite having pulled support for bitcoin payments back in 2018. The decision by Stripe — one of the more respected global technology unicorns — to get back into the blockchain world was cheered by crypto fans. Precisely what sort of competitive impact the move may have on other companies was less clear.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/mindbody-acquires-classpass-in-all-stock-deal-and-secures-500-million-investment/">Mindbody buys ClassPass, raises $500M:</a> </strong>After a number of pivots, ClassPass stayed afloat long enough to find a new home, we learned today. Selling itself to Mindbody in an all-cash transaction likely wasn’t what ClassPass initially had in mind, but the deal has obvious synergies and with lots of fresh capital aboard, the combined corporate entity could have a neat future.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-launches-4-person-crew-including-william-shatner-to-space/"><strong>Shatner in space:</strong></a> If you are a Star Trek fan, and I have to admit that I am not, it was a big week as series actor William Shatner took a quick joyride to space aboard one of Jeff Bezos’ rockets. Naturally, market excitement at events like this will fade in the coming years as such flights become more mundane — but today, folks still do really care. There’s so much interest in space flights that, well, we can’t help but keep writing about them.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>Before we get into our usual grip of startup news items, if you are tracking the GitLab IPO, we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/gitlab-raises-ipo-range-targeting-valuation-of-as-much-as-11b/">have the latest for you</a> on what the company is worth (lots) and how its possible valuation stacks up against many market comps (well).</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/karat-raises-110m-on-a-1-1b-valuation-to-grow-its-technical-interviewing-as-a-service-platform/"><strong>Today’s Tiger round is Karat:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Yes, the technical interviewing service has raised capital from Tiger, stacking a $110 million round at a valuation of around $1.1 billion. The round is notable for a Seattle-based company and is indicative of just how hungry the market is for technical talent. Karat is hardly swimming upstream in its target market.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/from-0-in-revenue-to-a-7-25b-valuation-why-tripactions-275m-raise-has-fintech-to-thank/"><strong>How TripActions pivoted its business and rebuilt its value:</strong></a> If you think back to the early days of COVID-19, startups that provided travel-related services took a whacking as their market dried up from underneath them. One such company was TripActions. But the company is back, Mary Ann Azevedo reports for TechCrunch. And it has a new, bigger price tag to boot.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/tiktok-removed-81-million-videos-for-violations-in-q2-representing-1-of-uploads/"><strong>The scale of content moderation will surprise you:</strong></a><strong> </strong>What does it take to keep a major social platform free of gunk? Or at least free enough from crap? A lot, TikTok tells us. The company removed 81,518,334 videos in Q2 2021 <em>alone</em>. That’s probably not a cheap bit of work.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/scienceio-leaves-stealth-with-millions-to-structure-health-data/">ScienceIO is taking on messy medical data:</a></strong> And it has raised $8 million for its efforts, TechCrunch reports. ScienceIO is “using natural language processing and data analytics to create a massive database of patient data that can help stakeholders better understand, and treat, people holistically,” we wrote. ScienceIO reminds us a <em>bit</em> of what Truveta is trying to do. Truveta is a <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/scienceio-leaves-stealth-with-millions-to-structure-health-data/">major healthcare data sharing effort</a></strong> led by a former Microsoft muckety-muck that we’ve written about previously.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/weights-biases-raises-new-capital-as-developer-tools-remain-a-venture-focus-ml-matures/">Weights &amp; Biases raises huge Series C for MLOps work:</a></strong> DevOps is a well-known category of software. MLOps, or <em>machine learning operations,</em> is less established. But Weights &amp; Biases just raised nine figures for its MLOps service and has a host of major venture capital firms backing its efforts. Our read? Building tooling for technical talent is hardly a complete task.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/canadian-startup-rose-rocket-raises-series-a-to-scale-its-transport-software-business/">And, from Canada:</a> </strong>One of the best parts of covering startups is talking to folks around the world building neat new companies and products. We’re always learning about industries and markets that are less familiar to our current lives. Such is the case with Rose Rocket, a Toronto-based startup that is taking on the TMS, or transportation management system, market with new software. It turns out that the world of freight trucking is not fully digitized, and the startup wants to change that fact.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Inside Plaid’s plans to build a new, global finance network</h2>
<p>January 2020 seems like a long time ago: Billie Eilish swept the Grammy Awards, Tesla&#8217;s market cap made it America&#8217;s most valuable car company, and Visa announced plans to purchase Plaid for $5.3 billion.</p>
<p>A year later, the credit card giant balked at the deal after it attracted regulatory scrutiny, but Ryan Lawler reports that &#8220;the year wasn&#8217;t a total loss for the data connectivity startup.&#8221;</p>
<p>He spoke to CEO Zach Perret, CTO Jean-Denis Greze and COO Eric Sager about what they learned while working with Visa and looked at some new platform features designed to build customer trust while eliciting better insights.</p>
<p>“Despite the outcome not being what we predicted when we went in, I think we as a company grew a lot and learned a lot,” said Perret.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DGQyNL5EXw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/inside-plaids-plans-to-build-a-new-global-finance-network/">Inside Plaid&#8217;s plans to build a new, global finance network</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Inside Plaid&#8217;s plans to build a new, global finance network&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/inside-plaids-plans-to-build-a-new-global-finance-network/embed/#?secret=DGQyNL5EXw" data-secret="DGQyNL5EXw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/apple-watch-series-7-review/"><strong>TechCrunch’s Apple Watch Series 7 review is here:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Writing this to you while wearing an Apple Watch, I fully understand the irony of my following comment, but <em>who the hell is naming these things</em>? Apple Watch Series 7 — which, incidentally we liked — is as good a name as Microsoft Windows Vista Home Premium. Jokes aside, our own Brian Heater took some darn fine images for the above review, which we wanted to highlight and praise.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/irelands-draft-gdpr-decision-against-facebook-branded-a-joke/"><strong>Draft Irish decision against Facebook could wind up toothless:</strong></a><strong> </strong>A draft decision concerning Facebook, the Irish Data Protection Commission and GDPR could fine the social giant some $36 million. Which is akin to fining you a fiver. It’s not much of a penalty, and as far as warnings go, it’s the very opposite. Keep an eye on this space.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2217068" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217068" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217068" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg" alt="Creative knowledge illustration" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217068" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>We’re reaching out to startup founders to tell us who they turn to when they want the most up-to-date growth marketing practices. Fill out the survey <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">here.</a></p>
<p>Read one of the testimonials we’ve received below!</p>
<p><strong>Marketer:</strong> Kaveh from <a href="https://within.co/">WITHIN</a></p>
<p><strong>Recommended by: </strong>Anonymous</p>
<p><strong>Testimonial:</strong> “Kaveh is one of the most empathetic and collaborative marketers I have ever worked with. Our team was largely brand marketers and Kaveh did a great job of bridging their world and our profit-optimized media strategy seamlessly (even if it meant an after-hours marketing jam session). Not only that, but you could tell he really cared about the brand, catching small issues with the site and sharing them with the team proactively, etc.”</p>
<h2>Community</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2216368" style="width: 209px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://www.simonandschuster.com/books/The-Wires-of-War/Jacob-Helberg/9781982144432"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216368" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2216368 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/the-wires-of-war-9781982144432_xlg.jpg?w=199" alt="The Wires of War book cover" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/the-wires-of-war-9781982144432_xlg.jpg 596w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/the-wires-of-war-9781982144432_xlg.jpg?resize=99,150 99w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/the-wires-of-war-9781982144432_xlg.jpg?resize=199,300 199w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/the-wires-of-war-9781982144432_xlg.jpg?resize=450,680 450w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/the-wires-of-war-9781982144432_xlg.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2216368" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Simon &amp; Schuster, Inc.</p></div></p>
<p>Join Danny Crichton on Thursday, October 14, at 2 p.m. PDT/5 p.m. EDT for a <a href="https://twitter.com/i/spaces/1yNGaYrADdNGj?s=20">Twitter Spaces</a> interview with Jacob Helberg, author of <a href="https://www.simonandschuster.com/books/The-Wires-of-War/Jacob-Helberg/9781982144432">“The Wires of War,”</a> which will be released tomorrow.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/daily-crunch-76/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217788</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Founders should use predictive modeling to fundraise smarter</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/founders-should-use-predictive-modeling-to-fundraise-smarter/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/founders-should-use-predictive-modeling-to-fundraise-smarter/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 21:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alternative financing models]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[company founder tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debt financing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[founder advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[founder lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seed money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Even with the rampant enthusiasm for pouring bigger equity checks into startups, founders are now in a unique place in time where they can think differently about how to capitalize their companies.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Billy Libby</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Billy__Libby">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/billy-libby-76464b1/">Billy Libby</a> is the CEO and co-founder of <a href="https://www.upper90.io/">Upper90</a>, a $1.5 billion hybrid fund that provides founder-friendly credit and equity to top disruptors in e-commerce and fintech.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">More capital is flooding into growth equity at earlier stages, and it&#8217;s happening faster than ever before. But even with the rampant enthusiasm for pouring bigger equity checks into startups, founders are now in a unique place in time where they can think differently about how to capitalize their companies.</p>
<p>Just like our personal lives, where most services have become highly personalized thanks to the data our activity generates, startups that operate online create a data exhaust from their operations. In short, data has become an asset for every business, diversifying the kinds of capital that were only available to later-stage startups before.</p>
<p>Data can separate the healthy and experimental parts of all businesses, making it easier to utilize earnings, marketing ROI and inventory to make predictions about or get credit for future revenue streams.</p>
<p>So how should businesses today leverage their own data analytics for fundraising?</p>
<h2>Separate the low- and high-risk parts of your business early<strong><br />
</strong></h2>
<p>Founders should think about their business as four distinct parts.</p>
<p>There’s R&amp;D, which is high risk but yields high reward and is appropriate for equity to fund at the seed stage. You pour capital into product-market fit with the hope that your business will hit an inflection point. You can make assumptions in the early days, but it is not clear exactly what your R&amp;D will yield.</p>
<p>Then you have marketing and acquisitions. You should have a more predictable ROI on capital invested for these, meaning that every dollar spent can be measured and be expected to return a positive ROI (whether it’s a lift in brand awareness, lead generation or conversion activities).</p>
<p>There is inventory, where you are making purchases with the expectation that you are going to sell them at a future date at a certain value. And then there is equipment, where you have an upfront cost to build a product or store or service with a strong sense of the payback on that investment.</p>
<p>Know the value of each segment, so you can understand which portions of your business are higher risk (like R&amp;D, where you aren’t yet sure of the outcome) and which are more predictable (like marketing and acquisitions).</p>
<h2>Tailor your funding plan instead of financing everything</h2>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/founders-should-use-predictive-modeling-to-fundraise-smarter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217645</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ireland&#8217;s draft GDPR decision against Facebook branded a joke</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/irelands-draft-gdpr-decision-against-facebook-branded-a-joke/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/irelands-draft-gdpr-decision-against-facebook-branded-a-joke/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 19:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Mining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Data Protection Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Max Schrems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[noyb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook&#8217;s lead data protection regulator in the European Union is inching toward making its first decision on a complaint against Facebook itself. And it looks like it&#8217;s a doozy. Privacy campaign not-for-profit noyb today published a draft decision by the Irish Data Protection Commission (DPC) on a complaint made under the EU&#8217;s General Data Protection [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook&#8217;s lead data protection regulator in the European Union is inching toward making its first decision on a complaint against Facebook itself. And it looks like it&#8217;s a doozy.</p>
<p>Privacy campaign not-for-profit <a href="https://noyb.eu/en">noyb</a> today published a <a href="https://noyb.eu/sites/default/files/2021-10/IN%2018-5-5%20Draft%20Decision%20of%20the%20IE%20SA.pdf">draft decision</a> by the Irish Data Protection Commission (DPC) on a complaint made under the EU&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).</p>
<p>The DPC&#8217;s draft decision proposes to fine Facebook $36 million &#8212; a financial penalty that would take the adtech giant just over two and a half hours to earn in revenue, based on its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/facebook-q2-earnings/">second quarter earnings (of $29 billion)</a>.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217611" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Yeah, we lol&#8217;d too.</p>
<p>But even more worrying for privacy advocates is the apparent willingness of the DPC to allow Facebook to simply bypass the regulation by claiming users are giving it their data because they&#8217;re in a contract with it to get, er, targeted ads.</p>
<p>In a summary of its findings, the DPC writes: &#8220;There is no obligation on Facebook to seek to rely solely on consent for the purposes of legitimising personal data processing where it is offering a contract to a user which some users might assess as one that primarily concerns the processing of personal data. Nor has Facebook purported to rely on consent under the GDPR.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I find the Complainant’s case is not made out that the GDPR does not permit the reliance by Facebook on 6(1)(b) GDPR in the context of its offering of Terms of Service,&#8221; the DPC also writes, suggesting it&#8217;s totally <em>bona fide</em> for Facebook to claim a legal right to process people&#8217;s information for ad targeting because it&#8217;s now suggesting users actually signed up for a contract with it to deliver them ads.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Yet &#8212; simultaneously &#8212; the DPC&#8217;s draft decision <em>does</em> find that Facebook infringed GDPR transparency requirements &#8212; specifically: Articles 5(1)(a), 12(1) and 13(1)(c) &#8212; meaning that users were unlikely to have understood they were signing up for a Facebook ad contract when they clicked &#8220;I agree&#8221; on Facebook&#8217;s T&amp;Cs.</p>
<p>So the tl;dr here is that Facebook&#8217;s public-facing marketing &#8212; which claims its service &#8220;helps you connect and share with the people in your life&#8221; &#8212; appears to be missing a few critical details about the advertising contract it&#8217;s <em>actually</em> asking you to enter into, or something.</p>
<p>Insert your own facepalm emoji right here.</p>
<h2>Mind the enforcement gap</h2>
<p>The GDPR came into application across the EU back in May 2018 &#8212; ostensibly to cement and strengthen long-standing privacy rules in the region which had historically suffered from a lack of enforcement, by adding new provisions such as supersized fines (of up to 4% of global turnover).</p>
<p>However EU privacy rules have also suffered from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/">a lack of universally vigorous enforcement</a> <em>since</em> the GDPR update. And those penalties that have been issued &#8212; including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/19/french-court-slaps-down-googles-appeal-against-57m-gdpr-fine/">a handful</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/twitter-fined-550k-over-a-data-breach-in-irelands-first-major-gdpr-decision/">against</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/whatsapp-faces-267m-fine-for-breaching-europes-gdpr/">Big Tech</a> &#8212; have been far lower than that theoretical maximum. Nor has enforcement led to an obvious retooling of privacy hostile business models &#8212; yet.</p>
<p>So the reboot hasn&#8217;t exactly gone as privacy advocates hoped.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="i1OlTE5gVC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/">GDPR&#8217;s two-year review flags lack of &#8216;vigorous&#8217; enforcement</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GDPR&#8217;s two-year review flags lack of &#8216;vigorous&#8217; enforcement&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/embed/#?secret=i1OlTE5gVC" data-secret="i1OlTE5gVC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Adtech giants especially have managed to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/17/privacy-experts-slam-uks-disastrous-failure-to-tackle-unlawful-adtech/">avoid a serious reckoning in Europe</a> over their surveillance-based business models despite the existence of the GDPR &#8212; through the use of forum shopping and cynical delay tactics.</p>
<p>So while there is no shortage of GDPR complaints being filed against adtech, complaints over the lack of regulatory enforcement in this area are equally stacking up.</p>
<p>And complainants are now also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/uks-ico-faces-legal-action-after-closing-adtech-complaint-with-nothing-to-show-for-it/">resorting to</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/adtech-data-breach-gdpr-complaint-is-headed-to-court-in-eu/">legal action</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="edoX4iJVaA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/uks-ico-faces-legal-action-after-closing-adtech-complaint-with-nothing-to-show-for-it/">UK&#8217;s ICO faces legal action after closing adtech complaint with nothing to show for it</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;UK&#8217;s ICO faces legal action after closing adtech complaint with nothing to show for it&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/uks-ico-faces-legal-action-after-closing-adtech-complaint-with-nothing-to-show-for-it/embed/#?secret=edoX4iJVaA" data-secret="edoX4iJVaA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The issue is, under GDPR&#8217;s one-stop-shop mechanism, cross-border complaints and investigations, such as those targeted at major tech platforms, are led by a single agency &#8212; typically where the company in question has its legal base in the EU.</p>
<p>And in Facebook&#8217;s case (and many other tech giants&#8217;) that&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/lack-of-big-tech-gdpr-decisions-looms-large-in-eu-watchdogs-annual-report/">Ireland</a>.</p>
<p>The Irish authority has long been accused of being a bottleneck to effective enforcement of the GDPR, with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/21/irelands-data-watchdog-slammed-for-letting-adtech-carry-on-biggest-breach-of-all-time/">critics</a> pointing to a glacial pace of enforcement, scores of complaints simply dropped without any discernible activity and &#8212; in instances where the complaints aren&#8217;t totally ignored &#8212; underwhelming decisions eventually popping out the other end.</p>
<p>One such series of adtech-related GDPR complaints were filed by noyb immediately the regulation came into application three years ago &#8212; targeting a number of adtech giants (including<a href="https://noyb.eu/sites/default/files/2020-05/complaint-facebook.pdf"> Facebook</a>) over what noyb called &#8220;forced consent.&#8221; And these complaints of course ended up on the DPC&#8217;s desk.</p>
<p>noyb&#8217;s <a href="https://noyb.eu/sites/default/files/2020-05/complaint-facebook.pdf">complaint</a> against Facebook argues that the tech giant does not collect consent legally because it does not offer users a free choice to consent to their data being processed for advertising.</p>
<p>This is because under EU law consent must be freely given, specific (i.e., not bundled) and informed in order to be valid. So the substance of the complaint is not exactly as complicated as rocket science.</p>
<p>Yet a decision on noyb&#8217;s complaint has taken years to emerge from the DPC&#8217;s desk &#8212; and even now, in dilute draft form, it looks entirely underwhelming.</p>
<p>Per noyb, the Irish DPC has decided to accept what the campaign group dubs Facebook&#8217;s &#8220;trick&#8221; to bypass the GDPR &#8212; in which the company claims it switched away from relying on consent from users as a legal basis for processing people&#8217;s data for ad targeting to claiming users are actually in a contract with it to get ads injected into their eyeballs the very moment the GDPR came into force.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is painfully obvious that Facebook simply tries to bypass the clear rules of the GDPR by relabeling the agreement on data use as a &#8216;contract,'&#8221; said noyb founder and chair, Max Schrems, in a statement which goes on to warn that were such a basic wheeze allowed to stand it would undermine the whole regulation. Talk about a cunning plan!</p>
<p>&#8220;If this would be accepted, any company could just write the processing of data into a contract and thereby legitimize any use of customer data without consent. This is absolutely against the intentions of the GDPR, that explicitly prohibits to hide consent agreements in terms and conditions.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;It is neither innovative nor smart to claim that an agreement is something that it is not to bypass the law,&#8221; he adds. &#8220;Since Roman times, the Courts have not accepted such &#8216;relabeling&#8217; of agreements. You can&#8217;t bypass drug laws by simply writing &#8216;white powder&#8217; on a bill, when you clearly sell cocaine. Only the Irish DPC seems to fall for this trick.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ireland has only issued two GDPR decisions in complaints against Big Tech thus far: Last year in a case against a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/twitter-fined-550k-over-a-data-breach-in-irelands-first-major-gdpr-decision/">Twitter security breach</a> ($550,000 fine); and earlier this year in an investigation into the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/whatsapp-faces-267m-fine-for-breaching-europes-gdpr/">transparency of (Facebook-owned) WhatsApp T&amp;Cs</a> ($267 million fine).</p>
<p>Under the GDPR, a decision on these type of cross-border GDPR complaints must go through a collective review process &#8212; where other DPAs get a chance to object. It&#8217;s a check and balance on one agency getting too cosy with business and failing to enforce the law.</p>
<p>And in both the aforementioned cases objections were raised on the DPC drafts that ended up increasing the penalties.</p>
<p>So it is highly likely that Ireland&#8217;s Facebook decision will face plenty of objections that end in a tougher penalty for Facebook.</p>
<p>noyb also points to <a href="https://edpb.europa.eu/sites/default/files/files/file1/edpb_guidelines-art_6-1-b-adopted_after_public_consultation_en.pdf">guidelines</a> put out by the European Data Protection Board (EDPB) &#8212; which it says make it clear that bypassing the GDPR isn&#8217;t legal and must be treated as consent. But it quotes the Irish DPC saying it is &#8220;simply not persuaded&#8221; by the view of its European Colleagues and suggests the EDPB will therefore have to step in yet again.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our hope lies with the other European authorities. If they do not take action, companies can simply move consent into terms and thereby bypass the GDPR for good,&#8221; says Schrems.</p>
<p>noyb has plenty more barbs for the DPC &#8212; accusing the Irish authority of holding &#8220;secret meetings&#8221; with Facebook on its &#8220;consent bypass&#8221; (not for the first time); and of withholding documents it requested &#8212; going on to denounce the regulator as acting like a &#8220;&#8216;Big Tech&#8217; adviser&#8221; (not, y&#8217;know, a law enforcer).</p>
<p>&#8220;We have cases before many authorities, but the DPC is not even remotely running a fair procedure,&#8221; adds Schrems. &#8220;Documents are withheld, hearings are denied and submitted arguments and facts are simply not reflected in the decision. The [Facebook] decision itself is lengthy, but most sections just end with a &#8216;view&#8217; of the DPC, not an objective assessment of the law.&#8221;</p>
<p>We reached out to the DPC for comment on noyb&#8217;s assertions &#8212; but a spokesperson declined, citing an &#8220;ongoing process.&#8221;</p>
<p>One thing is beyond doubt at this point, over three years into Europe&#8217;s flagship data protection reboot: There will be <em>even more delay</em> in any GDPR enforcement against Facebook.</p>
<p>The GDPR&#8217;s one-stop-shop mechanism &#8212; of review plus the chance for other DPAs to file objections &#8212; already added multiple months to the two earlier DPC Big Tech decisions. So the DPC issuing another weak draft decision on a late-running investigation looks like it&#8217;s becoming a standard procedural lever to decelerate the pace of GDPR enforcement across the EU.</p>
<p>This will only increase pressure for EU lawmakers to agree alternative enforcement structures for the bloc&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">growing suite of digital regulations</a>.</p>
<p>In the meanwhile, as DPAs fight it out to try to hit Facebook with a penalty Mark Zuckerberg can&#8217;t just laugh off, Facebook gets to continue its lucrative data-mining business as usual &#8212; while EU citizens are left asking where are my rights?</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vgXOUh4Vfj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/facebooks-eu-us-data-transfers-face-their-final-countdown/">Facebook&#8217;s EU-US data transfers face their final countdown</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook&#8217;s EU-US data transfers face their final countdown&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/facebooks-eu-us-data-transfers-face-their-final-countdown/embed/#?secret=vgXOUh4Vfj" data-secret="vgXOUh4Vfj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pgwXRwkVMc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/gdpr-enforcement-must-level-up-to-catch-big-tech-report-warns/">GDPR enforcement must level up to catch big tech, report warns</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GDPR enforcement must level up to catch big tech, report warns&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/gdpr-enforcement-must-level-up-to-catch-big-tech-report-warns/embed/#?secret=pgwXRwkVMc" data-secret="pgwXRwkVMc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/irelands-draft-gdpr-decision-against-facebook-branded-a-joke/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217611</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google&#8217;s latest virtual tour lets you walk the Great Wall of China</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/googles-latest-virtual-tour-lets-you-walk-the-great-wall-of-china/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/googles-latest-virtual-tour-lets-you-walk-the-great-wall-of-china/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 19:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Arts & Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google vr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[great wall of china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual Tour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VR]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217689</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google&#8217;s Arts &#38; Culture team is today launching a new online experience that lets users virtually walk the Great Wall of China. The &#8220;Walk the Great Wall of China&#8221; experience includes an exclusive 360-degree virtual tour of one of the wall’s best-preserved sections, including 370 images of the Great Wall in total and 35 stories [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google&#8217;s Arts &amp; Culture team is today launching a <a href="https://artsandculture.google.com/project/great-wall-of-china">new online experience</a> that lets users virtually walk the Great Wall of China. The &#8220;Walk the Great Wall of China&#8221; experience includes an exclusive 360-degree virtual tour of one of the wall’s best-preserved sections, including 370 images of the Great Wall in total and 35 stories that go into architectural details about the landmark.</p>
<p>“As the largest man-made structure in the world, the Great Wall of China is one of the most iconic and popular heritage sites anywhere. Over 10 million people visit each year—but not everyone has the opportunity to see the Great Wall first-hand,” Pierre Caessa, Google Arts &amp; Cultures program manager, said in a <a href="https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-asia/walk-great-wall-china/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+blogspot%2FMKuf+%28The+Keyword+%7C+Official+Google+Blog%29">blog post</a>. “​​Today, in collaboration with renowned Great Wall expert Dong Yaohui and curators from Gubei Water Town, Google Arts &amp; Culture presents a new theme page enabling people to visit the Great Wall virtually.”</p>
<p>The experience gives users the chance to learn more about the Great Wall’s history and experience parts of it that might be otherwise hard to access. It also aims to give users a better understanding of how the Great Wall is being preserved for future generations.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217689" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The virtual experience includes a panoramic view of the wall, along with 360-degree views of the watchtower and different sections of the wall. Users can also learn more about how and when the Great Wall was built.</p>
<p>For those who want to delve even deeper into the history of the Great Wall, you can decode the walls and bricks along the wall. For instance, you can get a closer look at hidden signatures, stamps and mysterious patterns carved on the bricks.</p>
<p>Google has launched numerous 360-degree virtual tours over the past few years and continues to leverage the technology. Back in 2016, the search giant rolled out a virtual experience that allowed users to explore <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/25/google-now-lets-you-explore-u-s-national-parks-via-360-degree-virtual-tours/">U.S. national parks</a>. Since then, the company has launched similar virtual tours but has also looked at using virtual reality in different ways. For instance, Google launched a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/27/google-launches-a-virtual-reality-artwork-gallery-on-the-web/">virtual reality art gallery</a> in 2017 and also released a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/09/googles-new-tour-creator-lets-students-make-their-own-vr-tours/">&#8220;Tour Creator&#8221; tool in 2018</a> to let students create their own VR tours.</p>
<p>To try out the new experience yourself, you can visit the website &#8220;<a href="https://artsandculture.google.com/project/great-wall-of-china" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-analytics-onclick="{&quot;event&quot;:&quot;page interaction&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;in-article links&quot;,&quot;action&quot;:&quot;link click&quot;,&quot;label&quot;:&quot;https://artsandculture.google.com/project/great-wall-of-china&quot;}">Walk the Great Wall of China,&#8221;</a> or download the Google Arts &amp; Culture app for <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.cultural&amp;hl=en_GB" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-analytics-onclick="{&quot;event&quot;:&quot;page interaction&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;in-article links&quot;,&quot;action&quot;:&quot;link click&quot;,&quot;label&quot;:&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.cultural&amp;hl=en_GB&quot;}">Android</a> or <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/google-arts-culture/id1050970557?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-analytics-onclick="{&quot;event&quot;:&quot;page interaction&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;in-article links&quot;,&quot;action&quot;:&quot;link click&quot;,&quot;label&quot;:&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/google-arts-culture/id1050970557?mt=8&quot;}">iOS</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/googles-latest-virtual-tour-lets-you-walk-the-great-wall-of-china/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217689</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Instagram adds scheduling and &#8216;practice mode&#8217; features for Live creators</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/instagram-adds-scheduling-and-practice-mode-features-for-live-creators/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/instagram-adds-scheduling-and-practice-mode-features-for-live-creators/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 18:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IGTV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217675</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Instagram today says it&#8217;s launching a couple of new tools aimed at addressing the needs of Live creators. Now, creators will be able to build up buzz for their upcoming Live by scheduling it up to 90 days in advance, then share the news across Instagram to alert their fans. It&#8217;s also preparing to roll [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Instagram today says it&#8217;s launching a couple of new tools aimed at addressing the needs of Live creators. Now, creators will be able to build up buzz for their upcoming Live by scheduling it up to 90 days in advance, then share the news across Instagram to alert their fans. It&#8217;s also preparing to roll out a new feature called &#8220;Practice Mode,&#8221; which allows creators to join their guests ahead of the scheduled event to test their connection, lighting and manage any other pre-show prep that may be needed.</p>
<p>The latter is a feature creators have been asking to have for some time, Instagram told us.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the ability to schedule Instagram Live videos puts Instagram on a more even footing with other live platforms, like YouTube and TikTok, as well as Instagram parent, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/tiktok-expands-live-platform-with-new-features-for-creators-and-fans/">Facebook</a>.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217675" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>YouTube has for a long time offered tools that allow creators to <a href="https://creatoracademy.youtube.com/page/lesson/livestream-planning-discovery#strategies-zippy-link-3">schedule</a> livestreams in advance in order to begin promotional efforts. And in 2018, it expanded its capabilities to allow creators to schedule the release of their pre-recorded videos <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/21/youtube-introduces-channel-memberships-merchandise-and-premieres/">through</a> a Premieres feature that offers similar functionality &#8212; like access to Super Chat, for example. Last year, it added a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/youtube-upgrades-premieres-with-trailers-themes-and-a-live-pre-show-option/">pre-show option,</a> as well.</p>
<p>Facebook Live has also offered tools to creators <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/10/18/facebook-live-unlocks-scheduling-and-pre-stream-lobby-first-for-verified-pages/">for many years,</a> including those for scheduling, marketing and pre-broadcast lobbies.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, TikTok just this year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/tiktok-expands-live-platform-with-new-features-for-creators-and-fans/">rolled out a set of creator tools</a> that included the ability to schedule TikTok LIVE videos, as it continues to more fully embrace the live format.</p>
<p>Instagram says its new Live Scheduling feature will be available to creators globally. After scheduling their upcoming Live video, they&#8217;ll then be able to share that scheduled content directly to their followers through both their Stories and Feed posts.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Followers can then use tools to set a reminder so they won&#8217;t miss the Live videos from their favorite creators.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2217720" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217720" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2217720 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/PracticeLaunchAsset-1.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217720" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Instagram</p></div></p>
<p>The launch arrives as the market for live content is heating up. In addition to enabling real-time e-commerce &#8212; an area where Instagram is deeply invested &#8212; Instagram&#8217;s biggest rival, TikTok, has also been working to make its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/tiktok-expands-live-platform-with-new-features-for-creators-and-fans/">live content a larger part</a> of the overall user experience. Not only do users randomly come across live videos as they scroll their TikTok feeds, it also recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/tiktok-expands-live-platform-with-new-features-for-creators-and-fans/">introduced</a> a new way to navigate through live videos by category using an &#8220;explore&#8221; button within the live section.</p>
<p>Instagram, on the other hand, has been revamping its video strategy in recent days. This month, it said <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/instagram-ditches-the-igtv-brand-combines-everything-but-reels-into-an-instagram-video-format/">it was giving up on the &#8220;IGTV&#8221; brand,</a> and instead would merge that long-form video with Feed video. As part of this effort, it rebranded the IGTV app, which will now be the home for all Instagram videos, including Lives, with the exception of Reels.</p>
<p>Reels, however, continues to have a central place in the main Instagram app, where it&#8217;s accessible from the center button, users&#8217; profiles, Explore, and &#8212;  just recently, we&#8217;ve confirmed &#8212; on hashtag pages.</p>
<p>Live Scheduling is available starting today to global users. Practice Mode will begin its rollout &#8220;soon,&#8221; the company says.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/instagram-adds-scheduling-and-practice-mode-features-for-live-creators/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217675</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok removed 81 million videos for violations in Q2, representing 1% of uploads</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/tiktok-removed-81-million-videos-for-violations-in-q2-representing-1-of-uploads/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/tiktok-removed-81-million-videos-for-violations-in-q2-representing-1-of-uploads/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 17:35:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content moderation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[misinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TikTok released a transparency update about content that was removed from the platform between April 1 and June 30, 2021. The platform says it removed 81,518,334 videos for violating its community guidelines or terms of service during that time period, which represents less than 1% of the total videos posted. This also means that during [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TikTok released a <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/safety/resources/tiktok-transparency-report-2021-q-2?lang=en">transparency update</a> about content that was removed from the platform between April 1 and June 30, 2021. The platform says it removed 81,518,334 videos for violating its community guidelines or terms of service during that time period, which represents less than 1% of the total videos posted. This also means that during that quarter, 8.1 billion+ videos were posted on TikTok, averaging out to about 90 million videos posted each day.</p>
<p>TikTok <a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/advancing-our-approach-to-user-safety">rolled out technology</a> in July that automatically removes content that violates its policies on minor safety, adult nudity and sexual activities, violent and graphic content, and illegal activities. The app uses automation for these kinds of content in particular, because it says these are the areas where its technology has the highest degree of accuracy. TikTok also has human content moderators on its safety team that reviews reported content.</p>
<p>When the automated technology was announced, TikTok said its false-positive rate for removals &#8212; when it removes content that actually doesn&#8217;t violate rules &#8212; is 5%. This number is reflected in the transparency report released today, as about 4.6 million of the 81 million removed videos were reinstated. The most common reason for content to be removed, encompassing 41.3% of removed videos, was for violation of minor safety guidelines. TikTok says that 94.1% of all removed content was identified and taken down before a user reported it.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217561" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Still, within that 5% of falsely removed content lies some troubling examples of failed content moderation, like when popular Black creator </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@ziggityler?lang=en">Ziggi Tyler</a> <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/tiktok-algorithm-prevents-user-declaring-support-black-lives-matter-n1273413">pointed out</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> that the app would flag his account bio as &#8220;inappropriate&#8221; when he included phrases like &#8220;Black Lives Matter&#8221; or &#8220;I am a black man.&#8221; Meanwhile, phrases like &#8220;supporting white supremacy&#8221; weren&#8217;t immediately censored.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pHc5h3rjd7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/tiktok-reached-1-billion-monthly-active-users/">TikTok reached 1 billion monthly active users</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok reached 1 billion monthly active users&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/tiktok-reached-1-billion-monthly-active-users/embed/#?secret=pHc5h3rjd7" data-secret="pHc5h3rjd7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As platforms like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/youtube-will-now-ban-content-with-vaccine-misinformation/">YouTube</a> and <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/feb/08/facebook-bans-vaccine-misinformation">Facebook</a> move to ban content with vaccine misinformation, other prominent social media companies like TikTok must decide how to tackle similar issues. TikTok&#8217;s community guidelines <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/safety/en/covid-19/">ban content</a> that&#8217;s false or misleading about COVID-19, vaccines and more broad anti-vaccine disinformation.</p>
<p>In Q2, TikTok removed 27,518 videos due to COVID-19 misinformation. TikTok says that 83% of these videos were removed before they were reported by users, 87.6% of these videos were removed within 24 hours of posting, and 69.7% of the videos had zero views. Meanwhile, TikTok&#8217;s COVID-19 information hub, developed with information from the WHO and CDC, was viewed over 921 million times globally.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Numbers-wise, it&#8217;s no secret that TikTok continues to grow, as the app crossed the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/tiktok-reached-1-billion-monthly-active-users/">1 billion monthly active user</a> landmark last month. The numbers in these transparency reports also reflect that growth &#8212; in the first half of 2020, TikTok removed 104 million videos, which represented 1% of all content posted. That 1% removal rate is consistent with the data published today, but today&#8217;s report accounts for 81 million videos posted in just one quarter, rather than two quarters.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/tiktok-removed-81-million-videos-for-violations-in-q2-representing-1-of-uploads/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217561</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: Marriage-based green card versus EB-1C green card?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/dear-sophie-marriage-based-green-card-versus-eb-1c-green-card/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/dear-sophie-marriage-based-green-card-versus-eb-1c-green-card/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 16:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Future of Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217044</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My company is sponsoring me for an EB-1C green card, but the process has been slow. I’m thinking about a green card through my spouse when we’re married. Is there anything I should keep in mind?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>Extra Crunch members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Dear Sophie,</strong></p>
<p><strong>My fiancé and I got engaged early this year. We’re planning a wedding for later in the year when my family can travel to the U.S. from Estonia, where I’m originally from. I’ve been living and working in the U.S. for almost two years on an L-1A visa. </strong></p>
<p><strong>My company is sponsoring me for an EB-1C green card, but the process has been slow. I’m thinking about getting a green card through my spouse when we’re married. </strong></p>
<p><strong>Is there anything in particular that I should keep in mind? Also, would it be a problem if I keep my maiden name after my fiancé and I get married?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Fantastic Fiancée</strong></p>
<p>Dear Fantastic,</p>
<p>Congratulations on your engagement!</p>
<p>My law partner, Anita Koumriqian, and I recently chatted about how our first clients as new immigration lawyers were in the process of obtaining <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/marriage-based-green-cards/">marriage-based green cards</a>, and the joy that supporting couples brings us! On our <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/092-marrying-a-u-s-citizen/">podcast</a>, we also talked about the <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/k-1-visa/">K-1 Fiancé(e) Visa</a>. Take a listen!</p>
<p>I can understand why you may be considering alternative green card options since one of the requirements of the <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/021-intracompany-transfers-l-1-visas-and-eb-1c-green-cards-for-multinational-managers-executives-and-people-with-specialized-knowledge/">EB-1C</a> green card for multinational transferee executives and managers is you must have been employed with your multinational company outside of the U.S. for at least one of the last three years and there’s no premium processing yet. Since this particular category is company-specific, it can make changing companies challenging.</p>
<p>As always, I recommend consulting an immigration attorney who can discuss your options based on your particular situation and goals, as well as help you through the marriage-based green card process and accompany you and your husband to the green card interview if you decide to take that route.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100312" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100312" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2100312" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg" alt="A composite image of immigration law attorney Sophie Alcorn in front of a background with a TechCrunch logo." width="1024" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=1536,1013 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Joanna Buniak / <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sophie Alcorn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<h2>Can I keep my maiden name?</h2>
<p>Yes, you can keep your maiden name! This should have no impact on your prospects for a green card through marriage. The key to a marriage-based green card is demonstrating that you married for love, not a green card — a “bona fide” marriage in legal terms. You will have to demonstrate that your marriage is in good faith and that you’re braiding your lives together.</p>
<p>The immigration officer evaluating your case will look for evidence such as photos from your wedding, a lease agreement or a mortgage loan signed by both of you, your 401(k) plans that list each other as the beneficiary, a joint bank account that’s frequently used to pay for household expenses, automobile or homeowners insurance policies listing both of your names, photographs and other possible evidence of your good faith marriage.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/dear-sophie-marriage-based-green-card-versus-eb-1c-green-card/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217044</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>T-minus 72 hours to save $100 on passes to TC Sessions: Space 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/t-minus-72-hours-to-save-100-on-passes-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/t-minus-72-hours-to-save-100-on-passes-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 16:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217518</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our countdown to early-bird savings is underway here at TechCrunch Central. You have just 72 hours left to save $100 on passes to TC Sessions: Space 2021, which takes place on December 14-15. Don’t miss this global gathering of the people who are literally pushing the boundaries of science and technology to envision, invent and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Our countdown to early-bird savings is underway here at TechCrunch Central. You have just 72 hours left to save $100 on passes to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021">TC Sessions: Space 2021</a>, which takes place on December 14-15. Don’t miss this global gathering of the people who are literally pushing the boundaries of science and technology to envision, invent and build a sustainable future in space.</p>
<p><strong>Savvy savings tip:</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?promo=launchpost#tickets">Buy your early-bird pass</a> before <strong>October 15 at 11:59 p.m. (PDT)</strong> and take advantage of full-event access at a discounted price.</p>
<p><strong>Other ways to save:</strong> Buy four or more passes, and you qualify for a group discount. Students and recent grads pay just $35.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217518" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Okay, now that you have your pass and that extra $100 safely tucked in your wallet, let’s talk about what this two-day conference has in store for you.</p>
<p>For starters, some of the most forward-thinking scientists, founders and investors will share insights, trends and tips. They’ll also engage with the audience and answer questions — as will promising early-stage startups and established space companies.</p>
<p>Here’s just one example. Accion Systems develops ion propulsion systems for satellites, and the company will join us on stage. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/learn-why-in-space-propulsion-systems-are-essential-for-a-sustainable-space-economy-at-tc-sessions-space-2021/">Learn more about why in-space propulsion systems are an essential part of building a sustainable space economy.</a></p>
<p>Speaking of promising startups, we’re limiting the number of exhibiting startups this year. We can’t wait to share more about them, but that will have to wait for a future post. Suffice it to say, you’ll definitely want to learn more about them and get a product demo. Who knows? Maybe you’ll meet a future unicorn, find a new customer or establish a creative collaboration.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>We’re building out our agenda and, although we have only a few spots left, our editorial team is still accepting speaker recommendations. <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/KUFW2e?typeform-source=techcrunch.com">Submit your recommendations here</a> <strong>by Friday, October 15</strong>, and we’ll notify you of your application status by October 31.</p>
<p>The official countdown to savings is on — you have just 72 hours left to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?promo=launchpost#tickets">buy an early-bird pass</a> to TC Sessions: Space 2021 and save $100. Take action before <strong>the sale expires on October 15 at 11:59 p.m. (PDT)</strong>.</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at TC Sessions: Space 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-054de807d08247a54a95307c1ca7ea3f"
			width="99%"
			height="1000"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/054de807d08247a54a95307c1ca7ea3f"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="bizzabo"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-054de807d08247a54a95307c1ca7ea3f')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-054de807d08247a54a95307c1ca7ea3f'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/t-minus-72-hours-to-save-100-on-passes-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217518</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Payments giant Stripe says its reentering the crypto market</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/payments-giant-stripe-says-its-re-entering-the-crypto-market/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/payments-giant-stripe-says-its-re-entering-the-crypto-market/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 16:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stripe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Payments company Stripe announced it&#8217;s building out a new crypto team to help build out the &#8220;future of Web3 payments,&#8221; according to public statements posted to Twitter on Tuesday. Stripe, which had once been among the first to support Bitcoin payments before leaving the market a few years ago, has been watching for the right [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Payments company <a href="https://stripe.com/">Stripe</a> announced it&#8217;s building out a new crypto team to help build out the &#8220;future of Web3 payments,&#8221; according to public statements posted to Twitter on Tuesday. Stripe, which had once been among the first to support Bitcoin payments before <a href="https://stripe.com/blog/ending-bitcoin-support">leaving</a> the market a few years ago, has been watching for the right time to get back in.  But how those plans will play out is still largely unknown.</p>
<p>Reached for comment, Stripe declined to share any additional insights or details about its strategy, pointing only to its new public statements and its <a href="https://stripe.com/blog/ending-bitcoin-support">earlier blog post</a>.</p>
<p>In January 2018, Stripe had <a href="https://stripe.com/blog/ending-bitcoin-support">announced</a> it was ending support for Bitcoin payments that April, saying that the cryptocurrency had become less useful for payments for a variety of reasons.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217522" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company noted then that transaction confirmation times had risen, leading to increased failure rates, and fees had also grown substantially. However, Stripe said then that it still remained &#8220;very optimistic&#8221; about cryptocurrencies overall and particularly projects like <a href="https://lightning.network/">Lightning</a> and others that could enable faster payments. It also referenced other developments like <a href="https://cdn.omise.co/omg/whitepaper.pdf">OmiseGO</a> and said there were a number of high-potential projects based on Ethereum in the works, as well.</p>
<p>Now, after sitting on the sidelines for years, Stripe is reentering the crypto space.</p>
<p>According to a post by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/edwinwee1/">Edwin Wee</a> on Stripe&#8217;s user relations team, Stripe is looking for Web3 engineers and designers to flesh out its new crypto team. While Stripe didn&#8217;t want to explain its vision, Wee&#8217;s post offers a bit more insight into how the company sees the market today.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">2/ That time has come! <a href="https://twitter.com/stripe?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Stripe</a> is starting a crypto team today, and I couldn&#39;t be more excited that <a href="https://twitter.com/gponcin?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@gponcin</a> is leading it. We&#39;re hiring for Web3 engineers and designers—I hope you&#39;ll join us: <a href="https://t.co/mT7QWbWgoL">https://t.co/mT7QWbWgoL</a>.<a href="https://t.co/vQenS0oMgx">https://t.co/vQenS0oMgx</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&mdash; edwin (@edwinwee) <a href="https://twitter.com/edwinwee/status/1447954119088492545?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 12, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>&#8220;Crypto holds the potential of faster and less expensive payments, particularly in underserved markets,&#8221; he wrote.</p>
<p>&#8220;In 2018, we said that Stripe would &#8216;look for opportunities to help our customers by adding support for crypto in the future.&#8217; That time has come,&#8221; Wee announced.</p>
<p>The team is being led by Stripe&#8217;s Head of Engineering, <a href="https://twitter.com/gponcin">Guillaume Poncin</a>, who also posted about the job openings. There are currently four roles listed for crypto engineers in New York, San Francisco, Seattle and in remote positions, but Stripe isn&#8217;t saying how many total employees it is looking to bring on out of the pool of job applicants.</p>
<p>While there&#8217;s no harm in a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/14/stripe-closes-600m-round-at-a-95b-valuation/">$95 billion company</a> dabbling in crypto once again, it&#8217;s unclear at this time how significant this announcement is in terms of Stripe&#8217;s broader corporate strategy.</p>
<p>That said, the market for crypto payments has heated up since Stripe&#8217;s exit in 2018. In addition to <a href="https://tracxn.com/d/trending-themes/Startups-in-Crypto-Payments">numerous</a> crypto payment startups entering the space and increased <a href="https://www.fool.com/the-ascent/cryptocurrency/articles/7-companies-where-you-can-pay-with-crypto/">acceptance</a> by larger brands and retailers, payments giant PayPal has also taken major steps to embrace crypto in recent months.</p>
<p>In November 2020, PayPal <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/paypal-says-all-users-in-u-s-can-now-buy-hold-and-sell-cryptocurrencies/">announced</a> it was now possible for all U.S. users to buy, hold and sell cryptocurrencies on its platform. It recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/paypal-expands-the-ability-to-buy-hold-and-sell-cryptocurrency-to-the-u-k/">expanded</a> that to international markets and to its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/venmo-adds-support-for-buying-holding-and-selling-cryptocurrencies/">payments</a> app Venmo. More importantly, it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/paypals-new-feature-allows-u-s-consumers-to-check-out-using-cryptocurrency/">launched a feature</a> that would allow U.S. consumers to check out using their cryptocurrency at any PayPal merchant, significantly broadening the potential for using crypto for online payments.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, cryptocurrency exchange Binance has <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2021/08/04/binance-pay-bringing-crypto-payments-to-shopify-others/">partnered</a> with e-commerce giant Shopify on crypto payments, while Coinbase has been making buying and spending crypto more accessible through integrations with <a href="https://blog.coinbase.com/a-new-way-to-buy-crypto-on-coinbase-using-paypal-e9162f735dcb">PayPal</a>, <a href="https://blog.coinbase.com/now-use-your-coinbase-card-with-apple-pay-and-google-pay-df951ad52c89">Apple Pay and Google Pay</a>, as consumer adoption grows.</p>
<p>Stripe, meanwhile, is not alone in thinking about crypto&#8217;s potential in &#8220;underserved&#8221; markets. <a href="https://squareup.com/us/en/press/equityinvestment">Square this summer announced</a> it was allocating the remaining $25 million of its $100 million investment in support of minority and underserved communities, with $5 million of that total going to the Square, Inc. Bitcoin Endowment.</p>
<p>&#8220;From those with no credit history who cannot open bank accounts, to people living in places with limited access to banks, to populations that have historically been discriminated against, Bitcoin can help level the playing field and build a more inclusive future,&#8221; Square had said. Perhaps Stripe now agrees.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/payments-giant-stripe-says-its-re-entering-the-crypto-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217522</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>reMarkable adds subscription service to access new features on its e-paper tablet</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/remarkable-adds-subscription-service-to-access-new-features-on-its-e-paper-tablet/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/remarkable-adds-subscription-service-to-access-new-features-on-its-e-paper-tablet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 16:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[E Ink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e paper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-readers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remarkable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tablets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216860</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a rather surprising move, the makers of the reMarkable line of e-paper tablets have added a subscription service to their latest device that enables several of its more advanced features. All current users are provided a lifetime subscription, and new users get about a year for free, so nothing will change for most, but [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In a rather surprising move, the makers of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/27/the-remarkable-2-improves-on-the-original-in-every-way-but-remains-firmly-in-its-niche/">reMarkable</a> line of e-paper tablets have <a href="https://remarkable.com/blog/introducing-connect-a-new-chapter-for-remarkable/">added a subscription service</a> to their latest device that enables several of its more advanced features. All current users are provided a lifetime subscription, and new users get about a year for free, so nothing will change for most, but it&#8217;s still a considerable pivot for the startup.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://remarkable.com/store/connect">reMarkable Connect</a> service comes in two tiers, a basic $5/month one that upgrades you to unlimited cloud storage for your documents, then an $8/month tier that adds access to Google Drive and Dropbox integration, handwriting conversion, screen sharing, send by mail and fast sync. With no subscription, devices will still sync but not for files left unopened for 50 days (so basically, you can&#8217;t use it as an archive). Anyone buying a reMarkable will get up to $150 off if they purchase a Connect subscription with it, which is pretty much break-even at a year or so.</p>
<p>On one hand, it&#8217;s an unexpected and somewhat dubious move: to charge for features that were essentially announced as simply part of the reMarkable suite of tools months back. And in fact those features were launched as ordinary free ones in recent weeks.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216860" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>On the other, it&#8217;s somewhat understandable in terms of revenue and just about the best way to implement this: every current user gets it free, and everyone else gets a free year, plus there&#8217;s a free option that doesn&#8217;t hurt much if you use your device pretty casually.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve asked the company for comment on the reasoning behind this decision and will update this post when I hear back.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="t6woybuotb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/27/the-remarkable-2-improves-on-the-original-in-every-way-but-remains-firmly-in-its-niche/">The reMarkable 2 improves on the original in every way, but remains firmly in its niche</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The reMarkable 2 improves on the original in every way, but remains firmly in its niche&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/27/the-remarkable-2-improves-on-the-original-in-every-way-but-remains-firmly-in-its-niche/embed/#?secret=t6woybuotb" data-secret="t6woybuotb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/27/the-remarkable-2-improves-on-the-original-in-every-way-but-remains-firmly-in-its-niche/">When I reviewed the reMarkable 2 last year</a>, I was impressed by the hardware, the responsiveness of the screen, and the simplicity of the interface. But as I noted then, despite its strengths the tablet really is still very much a niche device. Having spoken with the creators several times I&#8217;m convinced of their dedication to the vision of a sort of future paper that has an emphasis on focus and zero distraction. I get that, and I&#8217;m definitely into it — but the digital economy basically runs on distraction and overload, so it must be hard to carve a piece of that pie.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company has shipped well over 100,000 units and raised capital as well, but dedicated hardware startups are few and far between. It&#8217;s not too surprising that the company would be looking for ways to bolster its income as hardware sales approached saturation.</p>
<p>Who knows, but it might be a play for a broader &#8220;focused productivity&#8221; suite, something I would definitely use. My criticisms of the device and service were that while what it did, it did well, but it didn&#8217;t do enough. A Chrome extension added article saving, but as a Pocket user I wish I could just connect that. Same for other content that would simply feel better to experience on the reMarkable. While I appreciate the minimalist philosophy, it felt arbitrarily limited, and now that there&#8217;s screen sharing and Drive/Dropbox integration, they can hardly argue against inclusion of other services.</p>
<p>By all means no email, no chat, no social functions, nothing like that — let me focus! — but let me focus on anything, not just stuff that fits through the bottleneck of reMarkable services. Everyone could use a little more focus in their lives, but it helps to reduce the friction to achieve that focus as well.</p>
<p>Oh, and a front light would be nice too, while I&#8217;m making feature requests. Look, my eyes aren&#8217;t what they used to be. Help me out.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/remarkable-adds-subscription-service-to-access-new-features-on-its-e-paper-tablet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216860</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ScienceIO leaves stealth with millions to structure health data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/scienceio-leaves-stealth-with-millions-to-structure-health-data/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/scienceio-leaves-stealth-with-millions-to-structure-health-data/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 16:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scienceio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sea Lane Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[section 32]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216917</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Years before he co-launched a stealthy business to fix the messy world of health data, Gaurav Kaushik was slowly connecting the dots on how better visualization could impact health outcomes. In 2018, the budding entrepreneur was working with a Boston-based cancer research company and FlatIron Health to see how cancer patients, mutations in their cancer [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Years before he co-launched a stealthy business to fix the messy world of health data, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gauravkaushikphd">Gaurav Kaushik</a> was slowly connecting the dots on how better visualization could impact health outcomes. In 2018, the budding entrepreneur was working with a Boston-based cancer research company and FlatIron Health to see how cancer patients, mutations in their cancer and health outcomes were all related.</p>
<p>Eventually, his team did an analysis that suggested that patients with triple-negative breast cancer, a harsh form of cancer that particularly affects women of color, respond well to immunotherapies.</p>
<p>Understanding the impact of connecting unorganized patient data with treatment plans, Kaushik seeded the impetus for<a href="https://www.science.io/"> ScienceIO</a>, a new startup he co-founded with CEO <a href="https://twitter.com/WillManidis">Will Manidis</a>, a former Thiel fellow and managing partner of Dorm Room Fund. The startup is using natural language processing and data analytics to create a massive database of patient data that can help stakeholders better understand, and treat, people holistically.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216917" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“You can’t navigate without a map, and there is no map for healthcare. If we want to understand basic things — like which patients have dire, unmet needs and need special attention or new solutions, or finding novel treatments for rare diseases — that takes thousands of hours of labor and years to uncover,” Manidis said.</p>
<p>Now, ScienceIO is not the first startup to try to fix healthcare data. And it likely won’t be the last. The startup’s differentiator, though, is that it has spent years building up a database of what it claims is the most representative data out there.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’ve spent the past two years building the first healthcare AI platform of its kind. We’re taking a data-first approach to artificial intelligence, building the technology necessary to turn disparate healthcare data into high-quality, computable data,&#8221; said Kaushik. &#8220;There’s tremendous opportunity to build data-powered solutions in healthcare, and we’re excited to see an ecosystem of companies emerge and benefit from our platform and the broader [natural language processing] renaissance.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wYYVjHMFBL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/28/can-api-vendors-solve-healthcares-data-woes/">Can API vendors solve healthcare&#8217;s data woes?</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Can API vendors solve healthcare&#8217;s data woes?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/28/can-api-vendors-solve-healthcares-data-woes/embed/#?secret=wYYVjHMFBL" data-secret="wYYVjHMFBL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Natural language processing (NLP) is an advancing technology that makes it easier for computers to understand human speech. The company explained how NLP can be used for sentiment analysis, in which the technology looks at a social media post and predicts how the human behind it is feeling. ScienceIO’s application of NLP combines machine learning to find variables that impact patient health, using over 9 million medical conditions, drugs, device and genes as potential clues.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2216921" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216921" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2216921 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/ScienceIO-Annotate-Oct-7-2021.png" alt="" width="1024" height="802" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/ScienceIO-Annotate-Oct-7-2021.png 1440w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/ScienceIO-Annotate-Oct-7-2021.png?resize=150,118 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/ScienceIO-Annotate-Oct-7-2021.png?resize=300,235 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/ScienceIO-Annotate-Oct-7-2021.png?resize=768,602 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/ScienceIO-Annotate-Oct-7-2021.png?resize=680,533 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/ScienceIO-Annotate-Oct-7-2021.png?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2216921" class="wp-caption-text">ScienceIO in action. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> ScienceIO</p></div></p>
<p>The broadness means that the product is applicable to a number of different potential customers. Broadly, for example, Kaushik thinks that clinicians would be able to build a fuller picture of patients based on their backgrounds.</p>
<p>“The patients you deal with have a litany of healthcare issues, and it’s not enough to say we understand your cancer really well, or we independently understand socio-economic conditions,” Kaushik said. “It’s about incredible depth across every subject area, and the totality of the patient without minimizing them.”</p>
<p>He added: “The reason we spent three years not talking to the world and building this data set was to ensure we represent the patients that capture what a physician should see, rather than reduce them to their biorisks.”</p>
<p>Manidis gave an example that includes insurance providers, who get thousands of medical plans &#8212; and data points such as bill codes, costs, conditions &#8212; everyday.</p>
<p>“You are trying to figure out how to prioritize [claims], either to send it to adjudication or look for things like fraud detection,” Manidis said. “You can use ScienceIO to structure the data and then understand claims, and reimburse patients faster [and] more accurately.”</p>
<p>Notably, ScienceIO doesn’t track, it just makes data more searchable and produces analytics that can be turned into usable insights. ScienceIO said that it is currently in pilot programs with several customers, but declined to give specific names. The results of these pilots, per Kaushik, will help them decide a realistic timeline for general availability.</p>
<p>The progress so far has helped the once-stealthy business raise an $8 million seed round. Investors in the round include institutional investors such as Section 32 and Sea Lane Ventures, as well as entrepreneurs including Lachy Groom and Josh Buckley.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fclCWxymyD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/healthcare-is-the-next-wave-of-data-liberation/">Healthcare is the next wave of data liberation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Healthcare is the next wave of data liberation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/healthcare-is-the-next-wave-of-data-liberation/embed/#?secret=fclCWxymyD" data-secret="fclCWxymyD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/scienceio-leaves-stealth-with-millions-to-structure-health-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216917</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mindbody acquires ClassPass in all-stock deal and secures $500 million investment</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/mindbody-acquires-classpass-in-all-stock-deal-and-secures-500-million-investment/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/mindbody-acquires-classpass-in-all-stock-deal-and-secures-500-million-investment/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 16:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[classpass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mindbody]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sixth street]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217452</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ClassPass, the subscription-based fitness marketplace most recently valued at $1 billion, is today announcing that it has been acquired by Mindbody. Mindbody is a bit like the OpenTable of the fitness world. Its booking software is used by studios, gyms and other experience-based service providers — the company recently signed a global agreement with Blo [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/classpass/">ClassPass</a>, the subscription-based fitness marketplace most recently valued at $1 billion, is today announcing that it has been acquired by Mindbody.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.mindbodyonline.com/">Mindbody</a> is a bit like the OpenTable of the fitness world. Its booking software is used by studios, gyms and other experience-based service providers — the company recently signed a global agreement with Blo blowdry bar, for example — for customers and organizations to book their appointments, classes, etc.</p>
<p>ClassPass helps fill classes, while Mindbody provides the software that helps fitness centers run their business.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217452" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The terms of the deal were not disclosed, but Mindbody&#8217;s CEO Josh McCarter said that it was an all-stock deal. Alongside the acquisition, Mindbody is also announcing that it has secured a $500 million investment for the merged entity, led by Sixth Street.</p>
<p>ClassPass launched back in 2012 with a model not unlike Mindbody&#8217;s current model. Founder and then-CEO Payal Kadakia envisioned a site that would let you book classes à la carte from a variety of studios and gyms. Turns out, people weren&#8217;t as motivated as she expected.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="msyePizoZk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/08/classpass-finally-a-unicorn-raises-285-million-in-new-funding/">ClassPass, finally a unicorn, raises $285 million in new funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;ClassPass, finally a unicorn, raises $285 million in new funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/08/classpass-finally-a-unicorn-raises-285-million-in-new-funding/embed/#?secret=msyePizoZk" data-secret="msyePizoZk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Through a series of iterations, <a href="https://classpass.com/">ClassPass</a> moved to a subscription model, allowing users to pay for a monthly subscription that would let them access a specific number of classes across a spectrum of fitness genres.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Over time, high-usage customers were being subsidized by the lower-usage customers. Meanwhile, studios and gyms with their various classes and instructors were all being treated equally, regardless of whether a class was with a popular instructor or during peak hours.</p>
<p>This led ClassPass to introduce <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/20/classpass-begins-testing-variable-pricing-as-it-expands-beyond-studio-fitness/">virtual currency and variable pricing</a>. This allowed studios to price their classes based on a handful of factors, and ensured that customers were paying for exactly what they were using.</p>
<p>Once the company found that footing, it was off to the races in terms of growth. A huge international expansion commenced alongside a massive funding round led by Temasek. The biggest obstacle since then has been the pandemic, which hit gyms and fitness studios particularly hard.</p>
<p>But McCarter and ClassPass CEO Fritz Lanman told TechCrunch that all their data points to immense pent-up demand for in-person fitness classes and experiences.</p>
<p>By combining forces, the Mindbody/ClassPass entity has the opportunity for huge growth. ClassPass studios that are not using a booking software — Lanman says it&#8217;s about one-third of the studios on ClassPass — will now have the chance to sign up with Mindbody.</p>
<p>Mindbody&#8217;s consumer-facing business will have the chance to double-down on their experience by signing up for a ClassPass subscription and get access to those studios. And, of course, gyms and studios that use Mindbody for à la carte bookings could be upsold to ClassPass, as well.</p>
<p>Lanman and McCarter stressed that gyms and studios on the ClassPass network will not be required to use Mindbody, and vice versa.</p>
<p>&#8220;That&#8217;s because we think it&#8217;s critical that ClassPass maintains its advantage of having as much inventory available in a particular marketplace,&#8221; said McCarter. &#8220;That means they need to work with businesses that are potentially on some of our competitors&#8217; software.&#8221;</p>
<p>In other words, there will be no forced migration for any business from one software platform to the other, and the same goes on the consumer-facing sides of the business.</p>
<p>ClassPass will maintain its brand, and Lanman told TechCrunch that there are no redundancies or layoffs planned.</p>
<p>Lanman likened the deal to the Facebook/Instagram merger from way back when.</p>
<p>&#8220;Look at Instagram and Facebook,&#8221; said Lanman. &#8220;Instagram was only a small company when Facebook bought it, and Facebook really turbocharged it using its superior scale and services breath.&#8221;</p>
<p>The key, according to both Lanman and McCarter, is navigating their way through the end of the pandemic with as many studios, gyms and service providers in tact.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re lucky in that most of our customers are vaccinated,&#8221; said Lanman. &#8220;But, certainly people don&#8217;t want to work out in face masks, and there&#8217;s still massive mandates in some places. And so, the top complexity of risk to the business and execution is just how many of these small businesses can we keep in business. And how long can they hold on? But we&#8217;re seeing really encouraging signs of resilience in the industry so far.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/mindbody-acquires-classpass-in-all-stock-deal-and-secures-500-million-investment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217452</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Astropad&#8217;s Luna Display (finally) ships with Windows support</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/luna-display-ships-windows-support/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/luna-display-ships-windows-support/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 16:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Astropad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Luna Display]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sidecar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Touchscreens]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217077</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Luna Display from Astropad is a clever product enabling you to use your iPad as a second display. It was originally launched for Mac only, but Apple launched a competing product, putting the company in jeopardy for a couple of years. Today, it&#8217;s available for Windows machines as well, completing Astropad&#8217;s pivot to a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The <a href="https://astropad.com/product/lunadisplay/">Luna Display from Astropad</a> is a clever product enabling you to use your iPad as a second display. It was originally launched for Mac only, but Apple launched a competing product, putting the company in jeopardy for a couple of years. Today, it&#8217;s available for Windows machines as well, completing Astropad&#8217;s pivot to a multiplatform product.</p>
<p>To say that the company has had a hard time with bringing its products to market would be the understatement of the century. We&#8217;ve been following the company and its product for its long and arduous route. The company originally launched its product about five years ago, then <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/10/the-luna-wireless-portable-ipad-display-adapter-is-now-available-for-80/">added a wireless module</a> back in 2018 to get rid of the pesky wires. Its rapid rise to stardom was torpedoed when <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/28/apples-sidecar-just-really-gets-me-you-know/">Apple launched Sidecar back in 2019</a>, effectively making Luna&#8217;s product moot, and sending the company into crisis mode.</p>
<p>To its credit, the company and its founders have been good at staying transparent with its offering throughout. Once Apple beat it at its own game, <a href="https://astropad.com/blessing-in-disguise/">the founders kept the lights on</a> and announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/following-apples-sidecar-launch-astropad-announces-luna-display-for-windows/">a year ago that it pivoted to working on a Windows product instead</a>, fueling its product development with <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/767721702/luna-display-for-windows/description">a $400,000 Kickstarter project</a>.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217077" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2217110" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217110" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217110" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LunaWorkspace.jpg" alt="Luna Display" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LunaWorkspace.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LunaWorkspace.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LunaWorkspace.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LunaWorkspace.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LunaWorkspace.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LunaWorkspace.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LunaWorkspace.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217110" class="wp-caption-text">The red dongle on the left of the computer is the Luna Display. Here, it&#8217;s wirelessly throwing to an iPad operating as a secondary display. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Astropad</p></div></p>
<p>As part of the Kickstarter project, Astropad originally promised a May 2021 launch, but as things go in the world of product development, the company and its 6,000 Kickstarter backers were treated to a number of delays along the way. It&#8217;s been a long time coming, but that Windows product is finally here, along with version 5.0 of Luna Display. On paper, at least, the product looks promising; the Luna dongle plugs in and communicates with Mac or Windows operating systems, unlocking iPad support for gestures, Apple Pencil and the use of external keyboards. The company claims a latency of only 16ms. Not as good as Apple&#8217;s claimed 9ms latency for its Sidecar product, but it&#8217;s quick enough for most use cases that don&#8217;t require real-time input. Don&#8217;t expect to be doing heavy-duty design work or gaming on the display, in other words, but showing a Chrome tab or a Word document will work perfectly fine.</p>
<p>The company claims that its customers have been clamoring for Windows support, with a total of 8,000 preorders. No doubt, its patient and loyal followers will be delighted that they can finally get their mitts on the product they&#8217;ve been waiting for.</p>
<p>The solution supports a few different modes of operation &#8212; you can use an iPad as a secondary display, you can use<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/17/luna-display-now-supports-older-macs-as-a-secondary-screen/"> another Mac (including older equipment) as a secondary display</a>, or you can run the product in &#8220;headless mode.&#8221; In this configuration, you can use your Mac or PC as the primary display for your desktop Mac &#8212; such as a Mac Mini or a Mac Pro.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>To build out the software stack powering the solution, Astropad relied on the Rust programming language. For fans of such things, <a href="https://astropad.com/why-rust/">the company&#8217;s CEO Matt Ronge did an interesting deep-dive into the pros and cons</a> of using a relatively new language to build a low-latency solution.</p>
<p>&#8220;With Rust, we’ll have a high-performance and portable platform that we can easily run on Mac, iOS, Linux, Android, and Windows,&#8221; says Ronge. &#8220;Not only will this drastically expand our potential market size, but we also see many interesting new uses for our LIQUID technology that we’ll be able to pursue with our Rust based platform.&#8221;</p>
<p>Luna Display costs $129, and is <a href="https://shop.astropad.com/collections/luna-display-mac-and-pc/products/luna-display">available directly from Astropad starting today</a>, for both Mac and Windows, using USB-C, Mini DisplayPort or HDMI connectivity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/luna-display-ships-windows-support/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217077</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Security takes center stage at TC Sessions: SaaS this month</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/security-takes-center-stage-at-tc-sessions-saas-this-month/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/security-takes-center-stage-at-tc-sessions-saas-this-month/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 15:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business models]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Casey Aylward]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Javier Soltero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kobie Fuller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software as a service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wendy Nather]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2217278</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft, Cisco and Amplitude talk security at TC Sessions: SaaS this month. Enterprises face a constant stream of threats, from nation-state hackers and cybercriminals to corporate insiders. But the pandemic upended the world of work that saw millions of people shift from their downtown city offices to their spare room at home practically overnight. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Microsoft, Cisco and Amplitude talk security at TC Sessions: SaaS this month.</p>
<p class="c-mrkdwn__pre" data-stringify-type="pre">Enterprises face a constant stream of threats, from nation-state hackers and cybercriminals to corporate insiders. But the pandemic upended the world of work that saw millions of people shift from their downtown city offices to their spare room at home practically overnight.</p>
<p class="c-mrkdwn__pre" data-stringify-type="pre">The cloud held its own and reigned supreme, no longer as something we took for granted, but as a critical tool for keeping companies afloat during the lockdowns of 2020.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2217278" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p class="c-mrkdwn__pre" data-stringify-type="pre">With change also comes adjustment. Just as companies and their employees became accustomed to the new way of working, so have the bad actors. The cloud can store near-infinite amounts of data and deliver apps as a service, beaming directly into the homes of employees around the world, or wherever they work.</p>
<p class="c-mrkdwn__pre" data-stringify-type="pre">But with it comes a new set of challenges and risks, and bad actors are taking notes. Just as we adjust to this adapted way of working, startups and corporations alike can&#8217;t afford to stay off the security pulse.</p>
<p class="c-mrkdwn__pre" data-stringify-type="pre">That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re thrilled to have three leading cybersecurity veterans at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=saassecuritypost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=saassecuritypost&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TechCrunch Sessions: SaaS on October 27</a> to talk all things SaaS security.</p>
<p class="c-mrkdwn__pre" data-stringify-type="pre">TechCrunch will be joined by Edna Conway, vice president and chief security &amp; risk officer for Azure at Microsoft; Wendy Nather, head of advisory CISOs at Cisco; and Olivia Rose, vice president of IT and security at Amplitude for a live discussion to talk about the state of the SaaS security union, and what startups need to know about SaaS security now and in the future.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In addition to our discussion on security, the conference will also include Google’s Javier Soltero, as well as investors Kobie Fuller and Casey Aylward, among others. We hope you’ll join us. It’s going to be a thought-provoking lineup.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=saassecuritypost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=saassecuritypost&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Buy your pass now</a> to save before prices go up at the door. We can’t wait to see you!</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-76ca0a4b7b9ba6c90dbe352156de8454"
			width="99%"
			height="1000"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/76ca0a4b7b9ba6c90dbe352156de8454"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="bizzabo"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-76ca0a4b7b9ba6c90dbe352156de8454')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-76ca0a4b7b9ba6c90dbe352156de8454'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/security-takes-center-stage-at-tc-sessions-saas-this-month/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2217278</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
