<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 14:06:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>EBay and Adevinta to sell UK sites Gumtree, Motors.co.uk and Shpock to get their $9.2B deal past regulators</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/ebay-and-adevinta-to-sell-uk-sites-gumtree-motors-co-uk-and-shpock-to-get-their-9-2b-deal-past-regulators/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/ebay-and-adevinta-to-sell-uk-sites-gumtree-motors-co-uk-and-shpock-to-get-their-9-2b-deal-past-regulators/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 14:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adevinta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eBay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gumtree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motors.co.uk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[schibsted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shpock]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119562</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After inking a $9.2 billion deal to merge their classifieds businesses last year, eBay and Norway&#8217;s Adevinta have announced a deal to sell off three popular web properties in the UK to get the deal cleared by local regulators, the Competition Markets Authority. The companies plan to sell off Adevina-owned Shpock, and eBay-owned Gumtree and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/21/adevinta-acquires-ebays-classifieds-business-unit-in-9-2b-deal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">inking a $9.2 billion deal</a> to merge their classifieds businesses last year, eBay and Norway&#8217;s Adevinta have <a href="https://investors.ebayinc.com/investor-news/press-release-details/2021/eBay-Issues-Update-on-Proposed-Transaction-of-eBay-Classifieds-Group/default.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced a deal to sell off three popular web properties in the UK</a> to get the deal cleared by local regulators, the Competition Markets Authority. The companies plan to sell off Adevina-owned <a href="https://www.shpock.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shpock</a>, and eBay-owned <a href="https://www.gumtree.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gumtree</a> and <a href="https://www.motors.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Motors.co.uk</a> &#8212; three UK sites that let individuals sell used goods and find/offer services &#8212; with the transactions expected to be completed in time for eBay and Adevinta to complete their bigger deal in Q2 2021, pending final regulatory approvals.</p>
<p>&#8220;EBay and Adevinta remain excited about the proposed combination of Adevinta and eBay Classifieds Group and now target closing the transaction in Q2 2021, subject to final ratification of the remedies execution plan by the CMA and receipt of outstanding regulatory approval in Austria,&#8221; the companies said in a joint statement.</p>
<p>The companies have not yet said whether they plan to sell them in a single package or to independent buyers, but a spokesperson for Adevinta said that it&#8217;s likely that there will be another update in 4-6 weeks. She declined to give a price range for the properties.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>But in the statement from the companies, eBay said that Gumtree and Motors, which form its UK classifieds business, account for less than 10% of its consolidated revenues (<a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/EBAY/financials?p=EBAY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$10.3 billion</a> last year); and Adevinta said that Shpock revenues make up less than 1% of its consolidated revenues (which were <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/ADE.OL/financials?p=ADE.OL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">about $80 million</a> in the last 12 months). Adevinta is the majority owner of Norwegian publisher Schibsted, among other businesses.</p>
<p>The CMA provisionally has said that it would support the deal if the sale of the three properties gets completed.</p>
<p>&#8220;The CMA considers that there are reasonable grounds for believing that the undertakings offered by Adevinta and eBay, or a modified version of them, might be accepted by the CMA under the Enterprise Act 2002,&#8221; it noted in a <a href="https://www.gov.uk/cma-cases/adevinta-ebay-merger-inquiry#history" target="_blank" rel="noopener">brief update</a> (which was dated 2 March, 2020, although I think that was a typo).</p>
<p>The divestment decision comes as a result of the CMA last month <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/adevinta-s-merger-purchase-of-gumtree-raises-competition-concerns" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announcing</a> that the deal raised competition concerns as is.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is important that people have choice when it comes to selling items they no longer require or searching for a bargain online, and that they can enjoy competitive fees and services,&#8221; said CMA&#8217;s Joel Bamford, Senior Director of Mergers, in a statement. &#8220;There is a realistic chance that without this deal Gumtree and Shpock would have been direct competitors to eBay, which is by far the biggest player in this market. This is the latest in a series of merger probes by the CMA involving large digital companies, where we are thoroughly examining deals to ensure that competition is not restricted, and consumers’ interests are protected.&#8221;</p>
<p>Interestingly, one of those other deals also involves eBay, indirectly. Another asset that eBay sold off as part of its wider divestment efforts aiming to streamline its business was selling secondary ticket market company Stubhub to Viagogo in a $4 billion deal. That acquisition closed last year, but then the merger was investigated by the CMA, which last month <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/cma-requires-viagogo-to-sell-stubhub-s-international-business" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ordered Viagogo to divest the company&#8217;s business outside of North America</a>. It&#8217;s a crushing blow when you consider that events have fallen off a virtual cliff (literally and figuratively).</p>
<p>Turning back to Gumtree, Shpock and Motors.co.uk, even if those sites are a relatively small part of eBay and Adevinta&#8217;s wider business revenue-wise, collectively they form a very popular option for people looking to buy or sell used goods or hire people for service jobs in the UK. I&#8217;ve been a regular user of both in my time, to sell and buy items, and to advertise for/discover several excellent au pairs. Coincidentally, people also use them to resell tickets.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s notable that the CMA didn&#8217;t consider Facebook, or any others, big enough yet to be seen as viable competitors in that market. It will be worth watching to see how and if that changes though. With deals like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/spains-wallapop-raises-191m-at-an-840m-valuation-for-its-classifieds-marketplace/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">last week&#8217;s $191 million fundraise for Wallapop</a>, and Facebook&#8217;s persistent Marketplace efforts, it is clear that there is still business to be found in classified listings, both as a standalone enterprise, or as something that creates stickiness for users to hang around for other services and advertising alongside them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/ebay-and-adevinta-to-sell-uk-sites-gumtree-motors-co-uk-and-shpock-to-get-their-9-2b-deal-past-regulators/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119562</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft&#8217;s Power Automate Desktop is now free for all Windows 10 users</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsofts-power-automate-desktop-is-now-free-for-all-windows-10-users/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsofts-power-automate-desktop-is-now-free-for-all-windows-10-users/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 14:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Ignite 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softomotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 10]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119194</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft today announced that it is making Power Automate Desktop, its enterprise-level tool for creating automated desktop-centric workflows, available to all Windows 10 users for free. Power Automate Desktop is what Microsoft calls its &#8220;attended Robotic Process Automation&#8221; solution, but you can think of it as a macro recorder on steroids. It comes with 370 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Microsoft today announced that it is making <a href="https://flow.microsoft.com/en-us/desktop/">Power Automate Desktop</a>, its enterprise-level tool for creating automated desktop-centric workflows, available to all Windows 10 users for free. Power Automate Desktop is what Microsoft calls its &#8220;attended Robotic Process Automation&#8221; solution, but you can think of it as a macro recorder on steroids. It comes with 370 prebuilt actions that help you build flows across different applications, but its real power is in letting you build your own scripts to automate repetitive and time-consuming tasks.</p>
<p>Power Automate Desktop originally launched <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/22/microsoft-brings-new-robotic-process-automation-features-to-its-power-platform/">last September</a>. It&#8217;s based on Microsoft&#8217;s acquisition of Softomotive in early 2020, but Microsoft has since extended Softomotive&#8217;s technology and integrated it deeper into its own stack.</p>
<p>Users who want to give Power Automate Desktop a try can now download it from Microsoft, but in the coming weeks, it&#8217;ll become part of Microsoft&#8217;s Insider Builds for Windows 10 and then eventually become a built-in part of Windows 10, all the way down to the standard Windows Home version. Until now, a per-user license for Power Automate Desktop would set you back at least $15 per month.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve had this mission of wanting to go democratize development for everybody with the Power Platform,&#8221; Charles Lamanna, the CVP of Power Platform engineering at Microsoft, told me. &#8220;And that means, of course, making products which are accessible to anybody &#8212; and that&#8217;s what no-code/low-code is all about, whether it&#8217;s building applications with Power Apps or automating with Power Automate. But another big part of that is just, how do you also expand the imagination of a typical PC user to make them believe they can be a developer?&#8221;</p>
<p>This move, Lamanna believes, reduces the licensing friction and sends a message to Windows users that they can build bots and automate tasks, too. &#8220;The way we&#8217;ve designed it &#8212; and the experience we have, particularly around the recording abilities like a macro recorder &#8212; makes it so you don&#8217;t have to think about for loops or what is this app I&#8217;m clicking on or this text box &#8212; you can just record it and run it,&#8221; he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wdBoB9vPRQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/microsoft-acquires-robotic-process-automation-platform-softomotive/">Microsoft acquires robotic process automation platform Softomotive</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Microsoft acquires robotic process automation platform Softomotive&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/microsoft-acquires-robotic-process-automation-platform-softomotive/embed/#?secret=wdBoB9vPRQ" data-secret="wdBoB9vPRQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/microsoft-ignite-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/microsoft-ignite-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsofts-power-automate-desktop-is-now-free-for-all-windows-10-users/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119194</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft brings tighter integration to Dynamics 365 and Teams</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsoft-brings-tighter-integration-to-dynamics-365-and-teams/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsoft-brings-tighter-integration-to-dynamics-365-and-teams/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[collaboration tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dynamics 365]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Ignite 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Teams]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119510</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the pandemic drags on and we learn about the requirements of working from home with distributed teams, users could be craving more integration across their tools to help reduce the clicks required to complete a set of tasks. Today at the Ignite Conference, Microsoft announced tighter integration between its business suite Dynamics 365 and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As the pandemic drags on and we learn about the requirements of working from home with distributed teams, users could be craving more integration across their tools to help reduce the clicks required to complete a set of tasks. Today at the <a href="https://news.microsoft.com/march-2021-ignite/">Ignite Conference</a>, <a href="http://microsoft.com">Microsoft</a> announced tighter integration between its business suite Dynamics 365 and its collaboration tool Teams to help with that issue.</p>
<p>Alysa Taylor, corporate VP for business applications and global industry at Microsoft, pointed out that one of the advantages of this native integration approach is that it helps reduce context switching across different applications. &#8220;We are committed to really bringing together the collaboration platform and the business process layer to enable salespeople, service representatives, operations managers [and other similar roles] to really have a unified platform in which they both collaborate and have their everyday business functions,&#8221; Taylor explained.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mEmXDGrqgt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/08/microsoft-makes-teams-video-meetings-less-tiring-with-its-new-together-mode/">Microsoft makes Teams video meetings less tiring with its new Together mode</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Microsoft makes Teams video meetings less tiring with its new Together mode&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/08/microsoft-makes-teams-video-meetings-less-tiring-with-its-new-together-mode/embed/#?secret=mEmXDGrqgt" data-secret="mEmXDGrqgt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This could manifest itself in a number of different ways across marketing, sales and service. For instance, a marketer can create a webinar, which they set up and track in Dynamics 365 Marketing tools and run in Teams as a streaming event with the Teams streaming setup integrated directly into the Dynamics 365 console.</p>
<p>In a sales example Taylor says, &#8220;We&#8217;re enabling sellers to be able to track the career movements of their contacts using the LinkedIn Sales Navigator, as well as connect very specific sales records within Microsoft Teams without ever having to leave Dynamics 365 Sales. So you can be in the Sales application and you have the ability to deeply understand a contact and any contact changes that occur in Teams, and that&#8217;s automatically updated in Sales.&#8221;</p>
<p>If your company is not an all-Microsoft shop and wants to use different tools as part of these workflows, Taylor says that you can use Microsoft cross-cloud connectors to connect to another service, and this is true regardless of the tasks involved (so long as the connector to the desired application is available).</p>
<p>Salesforce, a primary rival of Microsoft in the business software space, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/">spent over $27 billion to buy Slack</a> at the end of last year to bring this kind of integration to its platform. Taylor sees the acquisition as a reaction to the integration Microsoft already has and continues to build.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think that Salesforce had to acquire Slack to be able to have that collaboration [we have], so we are years ahead of what they&#8217;re going to be able to provide because they will not have these native integrations. So I actually see the Salesforce acquisition as a response to what we&#8217;re doing with Dynamics 365 and Teams,&#8221; Taylor told me.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth pointing out that Salesforce is far ahead of Microsoft when it comes market share in the CRM space with over 19% versus under 3% for Microsoft, according to <a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2019-06-17-gartner-says-worldwide-customer-experience-and-relati">Gartner numbers from 2019</a>. While it&#8217;s possible these numbers have shifted some since then, probably not significantly.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0oeztonz64"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/">Salesforce buys Slack in a $27.7B megadeal</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Salesforce buys Slack in a $27.7B megadeal&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/embed/#?secret=0oeztonz64" data-secret="0oeztonz64" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/microsoft-ignite-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/microsoft-ignite-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsoft-brings-tighter-integration-to-dynamics-365-and-teams/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119510</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Piano acquires analytics company AT Internet</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/piano-acquires-analytics-company-at-internet/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/piano-acquires-analytics-company-at-internet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 14:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[piano]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119545</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Piano is expanding its platform for digital publishers with the acquisition of AT Internet, a 25-year-old analytics company based in France. Even if you don’t recognize Piano as a company, TechCrunch readers will probably be familiar with the product, since we use it to manage the reader experience of our Extra Crunch membership program. Other [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://piano.io">Piano</a> is expanding its platform for digital publishers with the acquisition of <a href="https://www.atinternet.com/en/">AT Internet</a>, a 25-year-old analytics company based in France.</p>
<p>Even if you don’t recognize Piano as a company, TechCrunch readers will probably be familiar with the product, since we use it to manage the reader experience of our Extra Crunch membership program.</p>
<p>Other customers include CNBC, The Wall Street Journal and the Associated Press, and Piano describes itself more broadly as a “digital business platform” with products around personalization, advertising and analytics, as well as subscriptions.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Fundamentally, our job is to help big websites make more money,” said CEO Trevor Kaufman. “We view that not as a billing problem, but as a marketing problem.”</p>
<p>Kaufman described a “pretty siloed system” used by most publishers and other digital businesses, where data around ad revenue, subscriptions, content engagement and customer profiles is all stored separately. By integrating with AT Internet’s “user-centric, event-based data store,&#8221; he said Piano can provide a more comprehensive picture of “the full customer journey,” allowing businesses to personalize their marketing and messaging accordingly.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="phCdDBzaT6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/20/piano-truex/">Piano teams up with True[x] to combine advertising and paywalls</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Piano teams up with True[x] to combine advertising and paywalls&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/20/piano-truex/embed/#?secret=phCdDBzaT6" data-secret="phCdDBzaT6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>He also praised AT Internet for its focus on “data quality and privacy,” with the company helping clients comply with GDPR and CCPA regulations.</p>
<p>New York-based Piano says AT Internet’s chief executive Mathieu Llorens will continue in that role while becoming a “significant shareholder” in the combined organization. The acquisition price was not disclosed, but the transaction involves both cash and equity and was funded by Updata Partners, Rittenhouse Ventures and Sixth Street Partners.</p>
<p>“The merger of our two organizations is an exciting chapter in our company’s history and prominence in the web analytics industry,” Llorens said in a statement. “This next chapter with Piano will enable AT Internet to invest more resources in and drive expansion of our current products, as well as help more organizations leverage analytics values and segments to deliver personalized customer experiences.”</p>
<p>Kaufman added that Piano and AT Internet will both work to integrate their platforms while continuing offer standalone products, but “the line becomes blurrier and blurrier as we use the backend of AT Internet to power more and more stuff for Piano.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RFhSiSnhlA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/9-vcs-say-interactivity-regulation-and-independent-creators-will-reshape-digital-media-in-2021/">10 VCs say interactivity, regulation and independent creators will reshape digital media in 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;10 VCs say interactivity, regulation and independent creators will reshape digital media in 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/9-vcs-say-interactivity-regulation-and-independent-creators-will-reshape-digital-media-in-2021/embed/#?secret=RFhSiSnhlA" data-secret="RFhSiSnhlA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/piano-acquires-analytics-company-at-internet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119545</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DJI launches an all-in-one FPV drone system</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/dji-launches-an-all-in-one-fpv-drone-system/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/dji-launches-an-all-in-one-fpv-drone-system/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 14:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DJI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drones]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DJI has flirted with FPV goggles before, of course. The company got on the burgeoning FPV movement with the launch of its DJI Goggles back in 2016. It was a logical extension for the company that controls around 70% of the drone market, at last count, and a push toward a more mainstream experience for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">DJI has flirted with FPV goggles before, of course. The company got on the burgeoning FPV movement with the launch of its DJI Goggles back in 2016. It was a logical extension for the company that controls around 70% of the drone market, at last count, and a push toward a more mainstream experience for what has largely been the realm of hobbyists.</p>
<p>Today, it takes another important step toward conquering that market with the launch of DJI FPV. The simply named new drone model is aimed at offering a similar off-the-shelf solution for those looking to add a head-mounted display to their flying experience.</p>
<p>The DJI FPV occupies a strange space, both in the DJI ecosystem and the overall drone market. While FPV drones have largely been the realm of more advanced hobbyists and racers, the new model is aimed at beginning and intermediate drone users. In that, it essentially works out of the box. Though unlike racing models, this device isn’t particularly modular or customizable, so you can’t really tweak it for speed.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2118665" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2118665" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2118665" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8862-1.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8862-1.jpeg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8862-1.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8862-1.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8862-1.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8862-1.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8862-1.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8862-1.jpeg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8862-1.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2118665" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>There are beginner modes and a new optional motion controller to help ease the learning curve. The drone builds on several generations of DJI consumer hardware and software, both in terms of imaging and controller. There’s even a flight simulator baked in to the app, to help get you acquainted with flying the device virtually before accidently slamming the pricey hardware into a tree.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="35DXYhnrLx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/27/dji-goggles/">DJI intros a pair of goggles to go along with its new drone</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;DJI intros a pair of goggles to go along with its new drone&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/27/dji-goggles/embed/#?secret=35DXYhnrLx" data-secret="35DXYhnrLx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That’s the other thing that warrants mention up top: This is a $1,299 system. That price gets you the drone, the second-gen FPV goggles, a controller and a battery. The motion controller runs another $199 and additional batteries can be purchased with the Fly More bundle. Of course, drone pricing is a pretty wide spectrum, and racing models tend to be be fairly expensive. The price puts it between the $799 Mavic Air 2 and the $1,599 Mavic 2 Pro, which sports a Hasselblad camera. Given that the FPV goggles retail for $570 on their own, the asking price certainly isn’t outlandish.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2118659" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2118659" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2118659" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8871.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8871.jpeg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8871.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8871.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8871.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8871.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8871.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8871.jpeg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8871.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2118659" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>Here’s how DJI’s European Creative Director describes the new system in a release:</p>
<blockquote><p>Right out of the box, DJI FPV combines the best available technology for a hybrid drone like no other. It can fly like a racer, hover like a traditional drone, accelerate like a homebuilt project and stop faster than any of them. DJI FPV lets the world experience the absolute thrill of immersive drone flight without being intimidated by the technology or spending hours building a system from scratch.</p></blockquote>
<p>That’s a pretty good assessment of the category here. It’s a way to dip one’s toes into this growing category, but backed with the peace of mind that comes with purchasing a more off-the-shelf solution from a company that knows how to build a good and fairly reliable drone (you’re not going to buy a product in this category that doesn’t give you some problems from time to time).</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2118661" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2118661" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2118661" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8875.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8875.jpeg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8875.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8875.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8875.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8875.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8875.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8875.jpeg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CMC_8875.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2118661" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>It’s not a racing drone, really, but it’s designed to offer a closer version of that experience than the company’s popular Mavic line. In fact, in one mode, it’s capable of speeds up to 87 MPH, with a 0-62 MPH acceleration in two seconds. Obviously, less experienced fliers are going to want to work up to that and familiarize themselves with the intricacies of the first-person view footage. When you flip over from Normal to Manual mode, you lose the hovering and obstacle sensors in the process, making it a lot easier to do some serious damage to the $1,300 drone.</p>
<p>The goggles themselves feature three different modes. Low-latency HD does 1440 x 810p at 60 fps or an increased field of view at 50 fps. Smooth mode increases the frame rate to up to 120 fps. Audience mode connects up to eight additional googles to the single view. The footage is shot with the on-board 4K/60fps 120 Mbps single-axis, image stabilized camera. Footage can be shot in up to 4x slow motion, as well.</p>
<p>[gallery ids="2118665,2118664,2118663,2118662,2118661,2118660,2118659,2118658,2118657,2118656"]</p>
<p>The DJI FPV is available to purchase starting today.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ILB0IDjE5z"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/04/djis-pint-sized-mavic-mini-gets-camera-and-connection-upgrades/">DJI’s pint-sized Mavic Mini gets camera and connection upgrades</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;DJI’s pint-sized Mavic Mini gets camera and connection upgrades&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/04/djis-pint-sized-mavic-mini-gets-camera-and-connection-upgrades/embed/#?secret=ILB0IDjE5z" data-secret="ILB0IDjE5z" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/dji-launches-an-all-in-one-fpv-drone-system/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119049</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft launches Azure Percept, its new hardware and software platform to bring AI to the edge</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsoft-launches-azure-percept-its-new-hardware-and-software-platform-to-bring-ai-to-the-edge/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsoft-launches-azure-percept-its-new-hardware-and-software-platform-to-bring-ai-to-the-edge/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 14:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Ignite 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft-azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perception]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product manager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software platform]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118796</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft today announced Azure Percept, its new hardware and software platform for bringing more of its Azure AI services to the edge. Percept combines Microsoft&#8217;s Azure cloud tools for managing devices and creating AI models with hardware from Microsoft&#8217;s device partners. The general idea here is to make it far easier for all kinds of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Microsoft today <a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/ai/?p=82484">announced</a> Azure Percept, its new hardware and software platform for bringing more of its Azure AI services to the edge. Percept combines Microsoft&#8217;s Azure cloud tools for managing devices and creating AI models with hardware from Microsoft&#8217;s device partners. The general idea here is to make it far easier for all kinds of businesses to build and implement AI for things like object detection, anomaly detections, shelf analytics and keyword spotting at the edge by providing them with an end-to-end solution that takes them from building AI models to deploying them on compatible hardware.</p>
<p>To kickstart this, Microsoft also today launches a hardware development kit with an intelligent camera for vision use cases (dubbed Azure Percept Vision). The kit features hardware-enabled AI modules for running models at the edge, but it can also be connected to the cloud. Users will also be able to trial their proofs-of-concept in the real world because the development kit conforms to the widely used <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/T-slot_structural_framing">80/20 T-slot framing architecture</a>.</p>
<p>In addition to Percept Vision, Microsoft is also launching Azure Percept Audio for audio-centric use cases.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2118799" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/azure_percept_2.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2118799" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2118799" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/azure_percept_2.jpg" alt="Azure Percept devices, including Trust Platform Module, Azure Percept Vision and Azure Percept Audio" width="1024" height="575" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/azure_percept_2.jpg 4785w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/azure_percept_2.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/azure_percept_2.jpg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/azure_percept_2.jpg?resize=768,431 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/azure_percept_2.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/azure_percept_2.jpg?resize=1536,862 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/azure_percept_2.jpg?resize=2048,1150 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/azure_percept_2.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2118799" class="wp-caption-text">Azure Percept devices, including Trust Platform Module, Azure Percept Vision and Azure Percept Audio</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;We’ve started with the two most common AI workloads, vision and voice, sight and sound, and we’ve given out that blueprint so that manufacturers can take the basics of what we’ve started,” said Roanne Sones, the corporate vice president of Microsoft’s edge and platform group, said. “But they can envision it in any kind of responsible form factor to cover a pattern of the world.”</p>
<p>Percept customers will have access to Azure&#8217;s cognitive service and machine learning models and Percept devices will automatically connect to Azure&#8217;s IoT hub.</p>
<p>Microsoft says it is working with silicon and equipment manufacturers to build an ecosystem of &#8220;intelligent edge devices that are certified to run on the Azure Percept platform.&#8221; Over the course of the next few months, Microsoft plans to certify third-party devices for inclusion in this program, which will ideally allow its customers to take their proofs-of-concept and easily deploy them to any certified devices.</p>
<p>&#8220;Anybody who builds a prototype using one of our development kits, if they buy a certified device, they don’t have to do any additional work,&#8221; said Christa St. Pierre, a product manager in Microsoft’s Azure edge and platform group.</p>
<p>St. Pierre also noted that all of the components of the platform will have to conform to Microsoft&#8217;s <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/ai/responsible-ai">responsible AI principles</a> &#8212; and go through extensive security testing.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/microsoft-ignite-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/microsoft-ignite-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsoft-launches-azure-percept-its-new-hardware-and-software-platform-to-bring-ai-to-the-edge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118796</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft&#8217;s Azure Arc multi-cloud platform now supports machine learning workloads</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsofts-azure-arc-multi-cloud-platform-now-supports-machine-learning-workloads/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsofts-azure-arc-multi-cloud-platform-now-supports-machine-learning-workloads/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 14:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud native computing foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fujitsu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hpe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lenovo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Ignite 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft-azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ML]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nutanix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red hat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RedHat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118773</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With Azure Arc, Microsoft offers a service that allows its customers to run Azure in any Kubernetes environment, no matter where that container cluster is hosted. From Day One, Arc supported a wide range of use cases, but one feature that was sorely missing when it first launched was support for machine learning (ML). But [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/azure-arc/">Azure Arc,</a> Microsoft offers a service that allows its customers to run Azure in any Kubernetes environment, no matter where that container cluster is hosted. From Day One, Arc supported a wide range of use cases, but one feature that was sorely missing when it first launched was support for machine learning (ML). But one of the advantages of a tool like Arc is that it allows enterprises to run their workloads close to their data and today, that often means using that data to train ML models.</p>
<p>At its Ignite conference, Microsoft today announced that it bringing exactly this capability to Azure Arc with the addition of Azure Machine Learning to the set of Arc-enabled data services.</p>
<p>&#8220;By extending machine learning capabilities to hybrid and multicloud environments, customers can run training models where the data lives while leveraging existing infrastructure investments. This reduces data movement and network latency, while meeting security and compliance requirements,&#8221; Azure GM Arpan Shah writes in today&#8217;s announcement.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This new capability is now available to Arc customers.</p>
<p>In addition to bringing this new machine learning capability to Arc, Microsoft also today announced that Azure Arc enabled Kubernetes, which allows users to deploy standard Kubernetes configurations to their clusters anywhere, is now generally available.</p>
<p>Also new in this world of hybrid Azure services is support for Azure Kubernetes Service on Azure Stack HCI. That&#8217;s a mouthful, but <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/azure-stack/hci/">Azure Stack HCI</a> is Microsoft&#8217;s platform for running Azure on a set of standardized, hyperconverged hardware inside a customer&#8217;s datacenter. The idea pre-dates Azure Arc, but it remains a plausible alternative for enterprises who want to run Azure in their own data center and has continued support from vendors like Dell, Lenovo, HPE, Fujitsu and DataOn.</p>
<p>On the open-source side of Arc, Microsoft also today stressed that Arc is built to work with any Kubernetes distribution that is conformant to the standard of the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF) and that it has worked with RedHat, Canonical, Rancher and now Nutanix to test and validate their Kubernetes implementations on Azure Arc.</p>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/microsoft-ignite-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/microsoft-ignite-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsofts-azure-arc-multi-cloud-platform-now-supports-machine-learning-workloads/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118773</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft Azure expands its NoSQL portfolio with Managed Instances for Apache Cassandra</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsoft-azure-expands-its-nosql-portfolio-with-managed-instances-for-apache-cassandra/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsoft-azure-expands-its-nosql-portfolio-with-managed-instances-for-apache-cassandra/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 14:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apache cassandra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[datastax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Ignite 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft-azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MongoDB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nosql]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SQL]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118760</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At its Ignite conference today, Microsoft announced the launch of Azure Managed Instance for Apache Cassandra, its latest NoSQL database offering and a competitor to Cassandra-centric companies like Datastax. Microsoft describes the new service as a &#8216;semi-managed offering that will help companies bring more of their Cassandra-based workloads into its cloud. &#8220;Customers can easily take [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At its Ignite conference today, Microsoft announced the launch of Azure Managed Instance for Apache Cassandra, its latest NoSQL database offering and a competitor to Cassandra-centric companies like Datastax. Microsoft describes the new service as a &#8216;semi-managed offering that will help companies bring more of their Cassandra-based workloads into its cloud.</p>
<p>&#8220;Customers can easily take on-prem Cassandra workloads and add limitless cloud scale while maintaining full compatibility with the latest version of Apache Cassandra,&#8221; Microsoft explains in its press materials. &#8220;Their deployments gain improved performance and availability, while benefiting from Azure’s security and compliance capabilities.&#8221;</p>
<p>Like its counterpart, Azure SQL Manages Instance, the idea here is to give users access to a scalable, cloud-based database service. To use Cassandra in Azure before, businesses had to either move to <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/cosmos-db/">Cosmos DB</a>, its highly scalable database service which supports the Cassandra, MongoDB, SQL and Gremlin APIs, or manage their <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/architecture/best-practices/cassandra">own fleet of virtual machines</a> or on-premises infrastructure.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Cassandra was originally developed at Facebook and then open-sourced in 2008. A year later, it joined the Apache Foundation and today it&#8217;s used widely across the industry, with companies like Apple and Netflix betting on it for some of their core services, for example. AWS launched a managed Cassandra-compatible service at its re:Invent conference in 2019 (it&#8217;s called <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/keyspaces/">Amazon Keyspaces</a> today), Microsoft only launched the Cassandra API for Cosmos DB last November. With today&#8217;s announcement, though, the company can now offer a full range of Cassandra-based servicer for enterprises that want to move these workloads to its cloud.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/microsoft-ignite-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/microsoft-ignite-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsoft-azure-expands-its-nosql-portfolio-with-managed-instances-for-apache-cassandra/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118760</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft launches Power Fx, a new open source low-code language</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsoft-launches-power-fx-a-new-open-source-low-code-language-for-its-power-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsoft-launches-power-fx-a-new-open-source-low-code-language-for-its-power-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 14:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitHub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft excel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Ignite 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[office suites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118414</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft today announced Power Fx, a new low-code language that takes its cues from Excel formulas. Power Fx will become the standard for writing logic customization across Microsoft&#8217;s own low-code Power Platform, but since the company is open-sourcing the language, Microsoft also hopes that others will implement it as well and that it will become [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Microsoft today announced Power Fx, a new low-code language that takes its cues from Excel formulas. Power Fx will become the standard for writing logic customization across Microsoft&#8217;s own low-code Power Platform, but since the company is <a href="https://github.com/microsoft/power-fx">open-sourcing the language</a>, Microsoft also hopes that others will implement it as well and that it will become the de facto standard for these kinds of use cases.</p>
<p>Since Power Platform itself targets business users more so than professional developers, it feels like a smart move to leverage their existing knowledge of Excel and their familiarity with Excel formulas to get started.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have this long history of programming languages and something really interesting happened over the last 15 years, which is programming languages became free, they became open source and they became community-driven,&#8221; Charles Lamanna, the CVP of Power Platform engineering at Microsoft, told me. He noted that even internal languages like C#, TypeScript or Google&#8217;s Go are good examples for this.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;That&#8217;s been an ongoing trend. And what&#8217;s interesting is: that&#8217;s all for pro devs and coders. If we go back and look at the low-code/no-code space, there actually are programming languages, like the Excel programming language, or in every low-code/no-code platform has its own programming language. But those aren&#8217;t open, those aren&#8217;t portable, and those are community-driven,&#8221; Lamanna explained.</p>
<p>Microsoft says the language was developed by a team led by Vijay Mital, Robin Abraham, Shon Katzenberger and Darryl Rubin. Beyond Excel, the team also took inspiration from tools and languages like Pascal, Mathematica and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miranda_(programming_language)">Miranda</a>, a functional programming language developed in the 1980s.</p>
<p>Microsoft plans to bring Power Fx to all of its low-code platforms, but given the focus on community, it&#8217;ll start making appearances in Power Automate, Power Virtual Agents and elsewhere soon.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/powerfx_language.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2119137" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/powerfx_language.png" alt="" width="1024" height="641" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/powerfx_language.png 1468w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/powerfx_language.png?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/powerfx_language.png?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/powerfx_language.png?resize=768,481 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/powerfx_language.png?resize=680,426 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/powerfx_language.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>But the team clearly hopes that others will adopt it as well. Low-code developers will see it pop up in the formula bars of products like Power Apps Studio, but more sophisticated users will also be able to use it to go to Visual Studio Code and build more complex applications with it.</p>
<p>As the team noted, it focused on not just making the language Excel-like but also having it behave like Excel &#8212; or like a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Read%E2%80%93eval%E2%80%93print_loop">REPL</a>, for you high-code programmers out there. That means formulas are declarative and instantly recalculate as developers update their code.</p>
<p>Most low-code/no-code tools these days offer an escape hatch to allow users to either extend their apps with more sophisticated code or have their tool export the entire code base. Because at the end of the day, you can only take these tools so far. By default, they are built to support a wide range of scenarios, but since every company has its own way of doing things, they can&#8217;t cover every use case.</p>
<p>&#8220;We imagine that probably the majority of developers &#8212; and I say &#8216;developers&#8217; as business users to coders that use Power Platform &#8212; will ultimately drop into writing these formulas in some form. The idea is that on that first day that you get started with Power Platform, we&#8217;re not going to write any formulas, right? [&#8230;] It&#8217;s a macro recorder, it&#8217;s templates. Same thing for Power Apps: it&#8217;s pure visual, drag and drop, you don&#8217;t write a single formula. But what&#8217;s great about Power Platform, in week number two, when you&#8217;re using this thing, you learn a little bit more sophistication. You start to use a little bit more of the advanced capabilities. And before you know it, you actually have professionals who are Power Platform or low-code developers because they&#8217;re able to go down that spectrum of capability.&#8221;</p>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/microsoft-ignite-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/microsoft-ignite-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsoft-launches-power-fx-a-new-open-source-low-code-language-for-its-power-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118414</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft updates Teams with new presentation features</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsoft-updates-teams-with-new-presentation-features/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsoft-updates-teams-with-new-presentation-features/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 14:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Ignite 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft powerpoint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Teams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft-Office]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[presentation software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reporter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Speaker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web conferencing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2118503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s (virtual) Microsoft Ignite this week, Microsoft&#8217;s annual IT-centric conference and its largest, with more than 26,000 people attending the last in-person event in 2019. Given its focus, it&#8217;s no surprise that Microsoft Teams is taking center stage in the announcements this year. Teams, after all, is now core to Microsoft&#8217;s productivity suite. Today&#8217;s announcements [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s (virtual) Microsoft Ignite this week, Microsoft&#8217;s annual IT-centric conference and its largest, with more than 26,000 people attending the last in-person event in 2019. Given its focus, it&#8217;s no surprise that Microsoft Teams is taking center stage in the announcements this year. Teams, after all, is now core to Microsoft&#8217;s productivity suite. Today&#8217;s announcements span the gamut from new meeting features to conference room hardware.</p>
<p>At the core of Teams &#8212; or its competitors like Slack for that matter &#8212; is the ability to collaborate across teams, but increasingly, that also includes collaboration with others outside of your organization. Today, Microsoft is announcing the preview Teams Connect to allow users to share channels with anyone, internal or external. These channels will appear alongside other teams and channel and allow for all of the standard Teams use cases. Admins will keep full control over these channels to ensure that external users only get access to the data they need, for example. This feature will roll out widely later this year.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s maybe more important to individual users, though, is that Teams will get a new PowerPoint Live feature that will allow presenters to present as usual &#8212; but with the added benefit of seeing all their notes, slides and meeting chats in a single view. And for those suffering through yet another PowerPoint presentation while trying to look engaged, PowerPoint Live lets them scroll through the presentation at will &#8212; or use a screen reader to make the content more accessible. This new feature is now available in Teams.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Open-chat-in-Presenter-mode_Under-embargo-until-March-2-at-6am-PT-1.gif"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2118530" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Open-chat-in-Presenter-mode_Under-embargo-until-March-2-at-6am-PT-1.gif" alt="" width="1024" height="573" /></a></p>
<p>Also new on the presentation side is a set of presentation modes that use some visual wizardry to make presentations more engaging. &#8216;Standout mode&#8217; shows the speakers video feed in front of the content, for example, while &#8216;Reporter mode; shows the content above the speaker&#8217;s shoulder, just like in your local news show. And side-by-side view &#8212; well, you can guess it. This feature will launch in March, but it will only feature the Standout mode first. Reporter mode and side-by-side will launch &#8220;soon.&#8221;</p>
<p>Another new view meant to visually spice up your meetings is the &#8216;Dynamic view.&#8217; With this, Teams will try to arrange all of the elements of a meeting &#8220;for an optimal viewing experience,&#8221; personalized for each viewer. &#8220;As people join, turn on video, start to speak, or begin to present in a meeting, Teams automatically adjusts and personalizes your layout,&#8221; Microsoft says. What&#8217;s maybe more useful, though, is that Teams will put a gallery of participants at the top of the screen to help you maintain a natural eye gaze (without any <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2019/10/03/microsofts-ai-powered-eye-gaze-tech-is-exclusive-to-the-surface-pro-x/">AI trickery</a>).</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/content-1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2118534" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/content-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="693" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/content-1.png 2560w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/content-1.png?resize=150,102 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/content-1.png?resize=300,203 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/content-1.png?resize=768,520 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/content-1.png?resize=680,460 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/content-1.png?resize=1536,1040 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/content-1.png?resize=2048,1386 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/content-1.png?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>As for large-scale meetings, Teams users can now hold interactive webinars with up to 1,000 people inside and outside of their organization. And for all of those occasions where your CEO just has to give a presentation to everybody, Teams supports broadcast-only meetings with up to 20,000 viewers. That&#8217;ll go down to 10,000 attendees after June 30, 2021, based on the idea that the pandemic will be mostly over then and the heightened demand for visual events will subside around that time. Good luck to us all.</p>
<p>For that time when we&#8217;ll go back to an office, Microsoft is building intelligent speakers for conference rooms that are able to differentiate between the voices of up to 10 speakers to provide more accurate transcripts. It&#8217;s also teaming up with Dell and others to launch new conference room monitors and speaker bars.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/microsoft-ignite-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/microsoft-ignite-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsoft-updates-teams-with-new-presentation-features/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2118503</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beam raises $80M as the dental insurer looks to keep up rapid historical growth</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/beam-raises-80m-as-the-dental-insurer-looks-to-keep-up-rapid-historical-growth/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/beam-raises-80m-as-the-dental-insurer-looks-to-keep-up-rapid-historical-growth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 13:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MetroMile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ROOT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119535</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning Beam, an insurtech startup that provides dental coverage to corporate employees, announced that it has closed an $80 million Series E. Mercato-affiliated Traverse led the investment, with Nationwide insurance joining the deal. Both are new investors in Beam. Prior investors Drive Capital and Georgian Partners also put capital into the funding event. The investment [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a href="https://beam.dental/">Beam</a>, an insurtech startup that provides dental coverage to corporate employees, announced that it has closed an $80 million Series E. Mercato-affiliated Traverse led the investment, with Nationwide insurance joining the deal. Both are new investors in Beam. Prior investors Drive Capital and Georgian Partners also put capital into the funding event.</p>
<p>The investment comes after rapid growth at the company, a common theme amongst neo-insurance providers. The startup cohort often leans on digital information collection to better information on consumer behavior. The information allows companies like Beam, and auto-insurers incent behaviors that lower costs like brushing, or safe driving, while having more information to inform their risk underwriting activities.</p>
<p>Once the neo-insurers have enough data to prove their underwriting models, they can rapidly scale their businesses, something investors covet.</p>
<p>Beam CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexfrommeyer/">Alex Frommeyer</a> said in an interview that the dental insurance business, which lacks the occasional catastrophic impact of a home insurer having to cover the cost of a house, for example, is an attractive slice of the coverage market. Per Frommeyer, his company has &#8220;sub-70s&#8221; loss ratios, meaning that it spends less than $0.70 per dollar of premium it receives on paying claims.</p>
<p>We lack specifics on its combined loss ratio and loss adjustment expenses, but the loss ratio itself points to enough margin in Beam&#8217;s core insurance product to possible create an attractive business; some neo-insurnace providers that have been well received by investors are struggling to get their numbers to even similar levels of performance. Add in Beam&#8217;s self declared revenue growth of 600% in the last three years, and &#8220;net revenue retention rate of 100%,&#8221; and it&#8217;s not hard to see why investors wanted to put more capital to work in the company.</p>
<p>Beam&#8217;s business is interesting for more reasons than merely its economics. It is also a consumer hardware player, manufacturing its own toothbrush to track, and encourage via promotions, its covered members to brush as frequently correctly. And the company&#8217;s software for enrollment, claims, and the like has become popular enough that Beam offers other insurance products via its platform to some customers, in addition to its own dental coverage.</p>
<p>Regarding its new investment, Frommeyer said that thanks to dental insurance&#8217;s lack of mega-claims, it doesn&#8217;t require as large a capital reserve as some insurance types. That means its new funding is largely earmarked for growth. The cash is likely welcome. After doubling its member base in both 2019 and 2020, the company has an upward climb ahead of if it wants to match the result again in 2021.</p>
<p>While the insurtech market has proven attractive for public investors in some cases &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/02/high-flying-ipos-for-lemonade-and-accolade-may-encourage-other-unicorns-to-go-public/">Lemonade&#8217;s post-IPO performance</a>, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/28/3-lessons-from-roots-ipo-pricing/">Root&#8217;s IPO pricing</a>, say &#8212; there have been bumps. Root&#8217;s share price has taken a beating in recent months, and MetroMile, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/how-will-investors-value-metromile-and-oscar-health/">which went public via a SPAC</a>, has lost ground in recent trading sessions.</p>
<p>Still, the market for insurance is huge, and with startups trying to apply tech solutions and modern digital software to the market, there&#8217;s plenty for investors to favor. Let&#8217;s see how far Beam can get with another huge check.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/beam-raises-80m-as-the-dental-insurer-looks-to-keep-up-rapid-historical-growth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119535</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is EV charging the next gig for the gig economy? SparkCharge thinks so</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/is-ev-charging-the-next-gig-for-the-gig-economy-sparkcharge-thinks-so/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/is-ev-charging-the-next-gig-for-the-gig-economy-sparkcharge-thinks-so/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 13:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Allstate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chevrolet Volt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechStars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Techstars boston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119506</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last week the mobile charging battery company SparkCharge announced a partnership agreement with AllState that expands the company&#8217;s reach into vehicle services, driving the company further down the road toward its goal of making electric vehicle charging the next gig economy job. The company, which has developed, designed and is commercializing a mobile vehicle charger [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last week the mobile charging battery company <a href="https://www.sparkcharge.io/">SparkCharge</a> announced<a href="https://www.sparkcharge.io/post/sparkcharge-partners-with-allstate-spiffy-mark-cuban-and-others-to-launch-boostev"> a partnership agreement with AllState</a> that expands the company&#8217;s reach into vehicle services, driving the company further down the road toward its goal of making electric vehicle charging the next gig economy job.</p>
<p>The company, which has developed, designed and is commercializing a mobile vehicle charger is also in the process of closing a $5 million round led by Shark Tank investor Mark Cuban and others as it brings its new mobile charging device, called the Roadie, to market.</p>
<p>SparkCharge&#8217;s 120 kilowatt fast charger can be delivered on-demand through a network of partners that now includes AllState and the Durham, N.C. vehicle services startup, <a href="https://www.getspiffy.com/">Spiffy</a>. Customers can choose to top up with between 50 miles and 100 miles of charge using the Roadie, which is the lynchpin in a broader charging network that SparkCharge&#8217;s founder, Joshua Aviv, envisions.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;You can say I want a charge at this point in time at this location and this much range,&#8221; Aviv said. &#8220;You pay and have the charge delivered all on one app.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>So far, the agreement between AllState and SparkCharge covers four cities: Chicago, Los Angeles, San Francisco, and San Diego, Calif., and the insurance and roadside assistance provider has ordered roughly twenty portable chargers.</p>
<p>Working through companies like Spiffy and AllState is one way to get to market, but SparkCharge&#8217;s chief executive thinks that independent workers could start up their own businesses offering on-demand charging to customers.</p>
<p>On-demand charges cost roughly 50 cents per mile and a customer can get a significant enough charge for as little as $10, according to Aviv.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We’re basically creating a whole new [charging] network,&#8221; said Aviv. &#8220;This isn’t a network meant to be a stopgap. It’s a network that’s always on, always available and better and faster than [traditional chargers]… we don’t need permits, we don’t need construction. With our unit, you take it out fo the box you plug it into the car you push a button and begin charging. With us, every parking spot, every location &#8212; that’s now a charging station. That’s a much better network than the legacy.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Folks who wanted to offer the charging services would pay roughly $450 per month for the equipment and that would give them the battery and the equipment they would need to start their own on-demand EV charging business.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;It’s a business designed to allow people to service EV owners,&#8221; said Aviv. </span></p>
<p>The Somerville, Mass.-based company was born from Aviv&#8217;s own fascination and frustration with the current state of electric vehicle charging infrastructure.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/whats-missing-in-the-electric-vehicle-revolution-enough-places-to-plug-in-except-tesla-11614380406">As the Wall Street Journal noted</a>, the lack of charging infrastructure is one of the major obstacles that electric vehicles have to overcome for them to achieve mass adoption.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://pluginamerica.org/about-us/electric-vehicle-survey/">a survey of 3,500 electric vehicle drivers</a>, cited by the Journal, which was conducted in September and October of last year by the advocacy group <a href="https://pluginamerica.org/">Plug In America</a>, over half of respondents reported having problems with public charging. Those problems are worse for drivers who don&#8217;t own Teslas.</p>
<p>Whatever else may be true about the EV that Elon built (along with thousands of workers and a slew of additional innovators and company founders), Tesla&#8217;s emphasis on having mostly adequate charging infrastructure to support its customers has paid huge dividends. And other carmakers, retailers, and standalone charging service providers are only beginning to catch up.</p>
<p>Companies ranging from oil majors like Shell to automakers like Volkswagen, who spent $2 billion to build out an electric vehicle charging network <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/05/10/vws-2-billion-penalty-for-diesel-scam-builds-ev-charging-network-across-us.html">as part of the settlement from its diesel emissions chicanery</a>, have networks built out or in the pipeline.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DhQUN77gCc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/planning-500000-charging-points-for-evs-by-2025-shell-becomes-the-latest-company-swept-up-in-ev-charging-boom/">Planning 500,000 charging points for EVs by 2025, Shell becomes the latest company swept up in EV charging boom</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Planning 500,000 charging points for EVs by 2025, Shell becomes the latest company swept up in EV charging boom&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/planning-500000-charging-points-for-evs-by-2025-shell-becomes-the-latest-company-swept-up-in-ev-charging-boom/embed/#?secret=DhQUN77gCc" data-secret="DhQUN77gCc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>For Aviv, who has owned an electric vehicle since 2013 when he bought a Chevrolet Volt, the problem was clear. He began working on the company in 2014 while still a student at Syracuse University. A professor and advisor at the university had previously served on the board of the Environmental Protection Agency and was a huge proponent of electric vehicles.</p>
<p>After college Aviv continued to work on the business developing a portable charging station and then creating a platform for distribution and sales and a network of service providers on top of it. That&#8217;s how SparkCharge was built.</p>
<p>In the early days, the company received assistance from groups like the Los Angeles Clean Technology Incubator and investors like Techstars Boston, Techstars, Steve Case&#8217;s Rise of the Rest fund and his Revolution investment firm, PEAK6 Investments, and the Buffalo, NY-based accelerator 46North, along with investors like Cuban.</p>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">I saw that the current [charging] infrastructure that we have has a lot of flaws,&#8221; Aviv said. They include the downtime between charging infrastructure upkeep, the time it takes to grow the charging network and the lack of maintenance and support for chargers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;There’s a huge push to move these chargers,&#8221; he said.&#8221;You don&#8217;t want these EV drivers to drive around a city with no guarantee of infrastructure. It’s an interesting tug of war that’s going on that we’re going to see unfold and consumers might be more persuaded to drive an EV [with SparkCharge] because not only can you deliver range but you can request it on demand.&#8221;</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/is-ev-charging-the-next-gig-for-the-gig-economy-sparkcharge-thinks-so/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119506</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flink, the Berlin-based grocery delivery startup that operates its own &#8216;dark stores&#8217;, raises $52M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/flink/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/flink/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 13:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119498</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The on-demand grocery delivery industry in Europe (and beyond) continues to heat up amidst the pandemic, including a plethora of startups taking a vertical approach by operating their own delivery only &#8212; or &#8220;dark&#8221; &#8212; stores. The latest to show its hand is Berlin-based Flink, which today is announcing that it has raised a hefty [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The on-demand grocery delivery industry in Europe (and beyond) continues to heat up amidst the pandemic, including a plethora of startups taking a vertical approach by operating their own delivery only &#8212; or &#8220;dark&#8221; &#8212; stores. The latest to show its hand is Berlin-based <a href="https://www.goflink.com/">Flink</a>, which today is announcing that it has raised a hefty $52 million in seed financing.</p>
<p>The round is led by Target Global and existing investors Northzone, Cherry Ventures, and Silicon Valley-based debt provider TriplePoint Capital. Cristina Stenbeck from Kinnevik also joins the round in a personal capacity.</p>
<p>TriplePoint&#8217;s inclusion is notable, since debt financing makes sense for these types of capital intensive businesses, including those that need to build out actual stores, albeit dark ones, and other deep logistics infrastructure.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>To that end, the injection of capital &#8212; which brings total funding to date to $64 million &#8212; coincides with Flink’s expansion into the Netherlands and France, and follows the opening of ten dark stores in a number of German cities. They include Berlin, Hamburg, Munich, Nuremberg, Dusseldorf, and Cologne, with more planned.</p>
<p>Officially launched just six weeks ago, Flink, which means “quick” in German, claims to deliver groceries from its own network of fulfilment centres in under 10 minutes. That puts it up against dark store competitors including Berlin’s much-hyped <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/gorillas/">Gorillas</a> and London’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/dija/">Dija</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/london-based-weezy-raises-seed/">Weezy</a>, and France’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/cajoo-promises-grocery-deliveries-in-15-minutes/">Cajoo</a>, all of which also claim to focus on fresh food and groceries.</p>
<p>There’s also the likes of <a href="https://tryzapp.com/">Zapp</a>, which is still in stealth and more focused on a potentially higher-margin convenience store offering similar to U.S. unicorn goPuff. (Related: goPuff itself is also looking to expand into Europe and is currently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/go-fancy/">in talks to acquire or invest in the U.K.&#8217;s Fancy</a>, which some have dubbed a mini goPuff).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7w2oZJbzW9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/go-fancy/">Delivery company goPuff is in talks to acquire the UK&#8217;s Fancy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Delivery company goPuff is in talks to acquire the UK&#8217;s Fancy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/go-fancy/embed/#?secret=7w2oZJbzW9" data-secret="7w2oZJbzW9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>However, based on today&#8217;s funding round and an extremely experienced founding team, Flink is certainly one to watch. The rather stealthy company was founded in late 2020 by Oliver Merkel (former Bain &amp; Company partner who led the firm’s retail practice in Germany), Christoph Cordes (former co-CEO of home24 which IPO’d in 2018), and Julian Dames (former co-founder of Foodora, CMO at foodpanda and VP at Delivery Hero, and most recently at Softbank). Founder-market-fit? Check.</p>
<p>As noted, Flink is pitching itself very much as a grocery solution, similar to Dija and Gorillas, for example, meaning that the real competition &#8212; in the short to mid-term, at least &#8212; is traditional supermarkets that do scheduled delivery but aren&#8217;t typically on-demand. However, delivering just-in-time fresh food poses many logistical challenges, such as the supply chain and ensuring you actually stock the products customers want when they want them. That&#8217;s a slightly different challenge to focusing on convenience store items such as beer, chocolate and snacks, or cigarettes etc., which is closer to the original goPuff model.</p>
<p>In a brief call last night with Christian Meermann, founding partner at Cherry Ventures, he told me that he believes truly on-demand groceries can be made to work, including the unit economics, but concedes it is a huge challenge logistically. But he also pointed out that the prize is potentially much bigger for whichever team can figure it out, since grocery shopping can easily happen multiple times per week and basket sizes can soon add up. Meermann isn&#8217;t convinced the same can be said of a pure convenience store offering, but of course there is overlap between the two.</p>
<p>Jessica Schultz, general partner at Northzone and previously a co-founder of HelloFresh, agrees. She says that instant shopping delivery will become &#8220;the new standard&#8221; in shopping more generally, and that groceries is the perfect category to start in, due to the nature of the products and frequency of consumption (e.g. perishables, waste, snacking, three meals per day etc.).</p>
<p>&#8220;Getting all your groceries, and not only convenience items but also your fresh herbs, your fruits, your bread&#8230; in less than 10 minutes is truly a wow experience,&#8221; she tells me. &#8220;I&#8217;m incredibly impressed with what the Flink team has achieved to date in this very fast-moving industry. I’m not sure I’ve seen such a rapid growth, or clean and strategic approach before. Their deep understanding of the core market dynamics is what will make them succeed&#8221;.</p>
<p>Schultz also argues that existing supermarket infrastructure can’t deliver on express grocery shopping and that large incumbents don&#8217;t have the skillset or agility to build on-demand grocery. &#8220;Instant delivery requires the build out of new infrastructure (micro-warehouses, hub &amp; spoke) as well as a fully vertically integrated approach,&#8221; she adds.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the new financing will be used to expand further within Germany and into additional European markets this year. &#8220;In Q2 2021, Flink will roll out its first stores in the Netherlands and France, beginning in cities like Amsterdam and Paris,&#8221; says the 120-person company.</p>
<p>Comments Flink founder Oliver Merkel: “Consumers absolutely love to get their grocery shopping done in 10 minutes,” says founder Oliver Merkel. “We’ve received fantastic NPS feedback and see people using Flink multiple times a week. With the additional funding, we can roll out Flink even faster in Europe.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4lcZxWTEF0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/gorillas/">Gorillas, the on-demand grocery delivery startup taking Berlin by storm, has raised $44M Series A</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gorillas, the on-demand grocery delivery startup taking Berlin by storm, has raised $44M Series A&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/gorillas/embed/#?secret=4lcZxWTEF0" data-secret="4lcZxWTEF0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/flink/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119498</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nigerian founders-turn-investors are now running syndicate funds</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/nigerian-founders-turn-investors-are-now-running-syndicate-funds/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/nigerian-founders-turn-investors-are-now-running-syndicate-funds/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 12:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Secondaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bosun Tijani]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iyinoluwa Aboyeji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jason Njoku]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Syndicates]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119192</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Future Africa Fund kicked off in 2015 when Iyinoluwa Aboyeji and Nadayar Enegesi, co-founders of US-based and African-focused talent company Andela, wrote checks to African startups as angel investors. This continued even as Aboyeji joined and left Flutterwave, the fintech company he co-founded. In January 2020, the pair made the fund official, with Aboyeji [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The<a href="https://www.future.africa/"> Future Africa Fund</a> kicked off in 2015 when <a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/eaboyeji">Iyinoluwa Aboyeji</a> and <a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/nadayar">Nadayar Enegesi</a>, co-founders of US-based and African-focused talent company Andela, wrote checks to African startups as angel investors</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">This continued even as Aboyeji joined and left Flutterwave, the fintech company he co-founded</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In January 2020, the pair made the fund official, with Aboyeji as general partner and Enegesi as limited partner</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Simultaneously</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, they announced that the fund had invested $1.5 million across 19 African companies</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The idea for a syndicate fund would come in the following months as the pandemic disrupted investment activities worldwide</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In the past year, syndicates have been emerging as a key force for investing &#8212; and for startups seeking capital to get going &#8212; on the continent. This is because most of the capital in Africa for promising startups is typically distributed among many investors. Syndicates are now emerging as one way of bringing the long tail together for more equity firepower.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During the onset of the pandemic, Aboyeji, <a href="https://www.future.africa/home/2021-ceo-letter">via his blog post</a>, said Future Africa Fund was looking to raise institutional investment</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the whole process proved difficult and the fund wasn&#8217;t able to because he was stuck in Nigeria and could not visit London, New York and Washington DC, &#8220;where institutional and development finance capital sits</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But in April, the fund <a href="https://www.future.africa/home/fund-the-future">decided to improvise</a> by launching a syndicate arm called the <a href="https://www.future.africa/collective">Future Africa Collective</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;There&#8217;s a massive early-stage funding gap for African startups. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">All the data we were looking at pointed to the fact that work needed to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be done</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to bridge that gap,&#8221; Aboyeji told TechCrunch</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">simply</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> couldn&#8217;t go on the journey alone to fix the gap and decided to build Future Africa Collective to democratize access to African startups</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We think</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of ourselves as pioneers in this field.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here, Future</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Africa acts as the syndicate lead sourcing investments, conducting due diligence, and securing allocations for investors called backers</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p>It&#8217;s a similar model employed by <a href="https://angellist.com/">AngelList</a>, the company founded by <span style="font-weight: 400;">Indian-American entrepreneur Naval Ravikant and Babak Nivi as a fundraising platform for startups to raise money from angel investors</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the years, the angel network has based its infrastructure on syndicates &#8212;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> investment vehicles that allow investors, referred to as backers, to co-invest with prominent investors &#8212; known as leaders</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Syndicate leads are often experienced angel investors or successful startup founders. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">They have a wealth of knowledge from playing different roles in the building of a startup ecosystem</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. On</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the other hand</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, backers don&#8217;t have much experience investing in startups most times, and for some that do, they will rather allow syndicate leads choose startups to invest in and manage their investments</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On AngelList</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, there are over 200 active syndicate leads listed with a typical check size ranging from $200,000 to $350,000</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Collectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, they have invested more than $2 billion in startups globally.</span></p>
<h2>Adopting syndicate funds for African startups</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like Aboyeji, two other Nigerian tech entrepreneurs &#8212; <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bosun-tijani-1b027b">Bosun Tijani</a> and <a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/jasonnj">Jason Njoku</a> &#8212; have also launched syndicate funds within the past year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tijani is the co-founder and CEO of Co-Creation Hub (CcHub), a pan-African innovation hub with offices in Lagos and Nairobi</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">He is also an angel investor, and via CcHub&#8217;s accelerator programme and a partner fund called <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/growth-capital">Growth Capital Fund</a>, Tijani has invested in more than 40 startups</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So why launch a syndicate given the success of the other funds? </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Tijani, the syndicate hopes to</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> solve the challenges that exist with </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">traditionally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> structured investment vehicles</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Here&#8217;s what he means.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2019, Nigeria accounted for more than 53% of the diaspora remittances to the African continent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Primarily</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, these remittances </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are channelled</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for domestic consumption. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tijani wants the <a href="https://cchubnigeria.com/syndicate/index.html">CcHub Syndicate</a> to be an avenue where a percentage of these remittances can come in to deepen the quality of capital available to local entrepreneurs</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">He believes the syndicate will help Africans in the diaspora who are passionate about nation-building but do not have the capacity to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be limited</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> partners in a typical fund structure, to co-invest alongside CcHUB in high growth tech companies across Africa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We see the syndicate as a complementary vehicle to our VC fund as it deploys bridge financing to companies with proven traction seeking to raise funds to meet critical milestones ahead of their next funding cycles,&#8221; he said</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mO6h6dFk40"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/30/bosun-tijani-talks-strategy-as-ceo-of-africas-new-largest-tech-hub/">Bosun Tijani talks strategy as CEO of Africa’s new largest tech hub</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bosun Tijani talks strategy as CEO of Africa’s new largest tech hub&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/30/bosun-tijani-talks-strategy-as-ceo-of-africas-new-largest-tech-hub/embed/#?secret=mO6h6dFk40" data-secret="mO6h6dFk40" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But before CcHub launched its $500,000 accelerator programme and Aboyeji founded Andela in 2014, <a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/jasonnj">Jason Njoku</a> of iROKO had already begun to invest in startups</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Two years after launching the African entertainment company in 2011, Njoku and his co-founder Bastian Gotter launched <a href="https://spark.ng/team.html">SPARK</a>, a self-described company builder and a $2 million fund</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fund whose LPs were HNIs investing between $100,000 to $500,000 has gone through several iterations to stay alive</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fund is currently in harvest mode but that hasn&#8217;t stopped Njoku from investing personally. His personal portfolio and Spark&#8217;s successful exit in Paystack has earned him a reputation that allows him to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">run some online communities where he charges people for his insights as an angel investor.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He tells me that <a href="https://investzilla.co/">Investzilla</a> came into play whe</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">n a couple of investors wanted to access his deal flow</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> after Paystack&#8217;s acquisition</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;I have been advising and referring investors into companies </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">informally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for the last few years, so this </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> formalizes it,&#8221; he said</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Investzilla investors wouldn&#8217;t consider themselves HNIs but have the ambition to invest $3-10k in </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">several</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> early-stage companies </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">annually</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Investzilla </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is focused</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on unlocking that opportunity for them.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a nutshell, the Future Africa Collective, CcHub Syndicate, and Investzilla want to improve access to financing for African founders</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The plan is to reduce venture flight which has become prevalent in the ecosystem in recent times. But how do they work, and what progress have they made so far?</span></p>
<h2>The nitty-gritty details</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Typically</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, leads allow backers to join the syndicate via an application. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">After vetting and then approving these backers, they gain access to the syndicate&#8217;s deal flow and can pick investments on a deal-by-deal basis</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Also, they </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are mandated</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to pay a one-time fee to join.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Investzilla, backers pay a membership fee of $500. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thereafter, investors can put between $5,000 to $15,000 checks in more than 10 early-stage companies </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">annually</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">While there has been no public announcement yet on its launch, Njoku says the syndicate soft-launched with 20 investors in January, and deals are waiting to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be completed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the pipeline</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CcHub Syndicate, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">on the other hand</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, launched in December 2020. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tijani doesn&#8217;t state how much the syndicate&#8217;s administration fee costs but says the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">minimum</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> backers can invest is $5,000</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So far, the syndicate has signed up more than 400 individuals, investing groups and institutional investors</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Out of that number, a little above 30 investors have undertaken the syndicate&#8217;s KYC (Know Your Customer) process</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last month, it announced that a total of $267,500 had been raised </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">to support three Nigerian startups&#8217; bridge financing rounds</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, the Future Africa Collective charges a membership due of $1000 a year and four times a year; it selects </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">some</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> backers to the syndicate</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Each quarter, backers </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are presented with</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> five startups they can invest in with a </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">minimum</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of $5,000. In less than a year, Future Africa Collective has grown to over 160 members. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Collectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, they have invested over $1 million in 14 startups across Africa.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2119225" style="width: 1888px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2119225" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2119225 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/3-up.jpg" alt="" width="1878" height="819" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/3-up.jpg 1878w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/3-up.jpg?resize=150,65 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/3-up.jpg?resize=300,131 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/3-up.jpg?resize=768,335 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/3-up.jpg?resize=680,297 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/3-up.jpg?resize=1536,670 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/3-up.jpg?resize=50,22 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1878px) 100vw, 1878px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2119225" class="wp-caption-text">L-R: Jason Njoku (Investzilla), Iyinoluwa Aboyeji (Future Africa Collective), and Bosun Tijani (CcHub Syndicate)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One important thing to note is that a transaction fee prorated by their check size </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is charged</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for every deal a backer makes across all three syndicates</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The three syndicates also charge carry, which is a cut of positive returns generated by the investment</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. For instance, Future Africa has a 20% carry. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">If a backer invests $5,000 in the syndicate and the investment returns $20,000, the syndicate would earn $3,000 in carry, leaving the backer with $12,000 profit</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Like Future Africa, Investzilla charges a 20% carry, but CcHub Syndicate does 15%.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As to when the return on investments is scheduled to be</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> made</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Aboyeji says the Future Africa Collective </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is designed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to return upon secondaries</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We hold the right to decide when to exit, but if there are any opportunities, we discuss them with the syndicate. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Returns </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are disbursed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to the syndicate members who invested in specific startups should there be an exit,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8221; he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And the timeline for this across the syndicates </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is designated</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> around 5 to 10 years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That said, with Africa&#8217;s seed-stage funding gap not closed enough yet, the founders believe that there will </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be increased</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> participation from more players with varied syndication models</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Njoku, who </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is enthused</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> about more capital </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">being pumped</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> into Africa&#8217;s tech ecosystem, says if these syndicates can get more than 200 angels to commit between $3,000 to $10,000 in at least five startups in a year, the continent might start to see more high net worth individuals </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">participate</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in tech investments</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;If we can unlock that, then it would be $2 million to $10 million in early-stage funding </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">annually,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> which may or may have </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">been attracted</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the first place</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like Iyin and Bosun, founders who have created a lot of wealth with African tech feel comfortable and breed confidence</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. That&#8217;s an attractive asset class for executives or HNIs.&#8221;</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/nigerian-founders-turn-investors-are-now-running-syndicate-funds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119192</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok calls in outside help with content moderation in Europe</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/tiktok-calls-in-outside-help-with-content-moderation-in-europe/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/tiktok-calls-in-outside-help-with-content-moderation-in-europe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 10:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content moderation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[platform regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119477</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TikTok is bringing in external experts in Europe in fields such as child safety, young people&#8217;s mental health and extremism to form a Safety Advisory Council to help it with content moderation in the region. The move, announced today, follows an emergency intervention by Italy&#8217;s data protection authority in January &#8212; which ordered TikTok to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TikTok is bringing in external experts in Europe in fields such as child safety, young people&#8217;s mental health and extremism to form a Safety Advisory Council to help it with content moderation in the region.</p>
<p>The move, <a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-be/meet-tiktoks-european-safety-advisory-council">announced today</a>, follows an emergency intervention by Italy&#8217;s data protection authority in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/tiktok-has-until-friday-to-respond-to-italys-order-to-block-users-it-cant-age-verify-after-girls-death/">January</a> &#8212; which ordered TikTok to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-will-recheck-the-age-of-every-user-in-italy-after-dpa-order/">block users it cannot age verify</a> after the death of a girl who was reported by local media to have died of asphyxiation as a result of participating in a black out challenge on the video sharing platform.</p>
<p>The social media platform has also been targeted by a series of coordinated complaints by EU consumer protection agencies, which put out <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/tiktok-hit-with-consumer-child-safety-and-privacy-complaints-in-europe/">two reports last month</a> detailing a number of alleged breaches of the bloc&#8217;s consumer protection and privacy rules &#8212; including child safety-specific concerns.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1QgqaZdXqh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-will-recheck-the-age-of-every-user-in-italy-after-dpa-order/">TikTok will recheck the age of every user in Italy after DPA order</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok will recheck the age of every user in Italy after DPA order&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-will-recheck-the-age-of-every-user-in-italy-after-dpa-order/embed/#?secret=1QgqaZdXqh" data-secret="1QgqaZdXqh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LPpkxP1PTd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/tiktok-hit-with-consumer-child-safety-and-privacy-complaints-in-europe/">TikTok hit with consumer, child safety and privacy complaints in Europe</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok hit with consumer, child safety and privacy complaints in Europe&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/tiktok-hit-with-consumer-child-safety-and-privacy-complaints-in-europe/embed/#?secret=LPpkxP1PTd" data-secret="LPpkxP1PTd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;We are always reviewing our existing features and policies, and innovating to take bold new measures to prioritise safety,&#8221; TikTok writes today, putting a positive spin on needing to improve safety on its platform in the region.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Council will bring together leaders from academia and civil society from all around Europe. Each member brings a different, fresh perspective on the challenges we face and members will provide subject matter expertise as they advise on our content moderation policies and practices. Not only will they support us in developing forward-looking policies that address the challenges we face today, they will also help us to identify emerging issues that affect TikTok and our community in the future.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not the first such advisory body TikTok has launched. A year ago it announced a <a href="https://www.voanews.com/usa/tiktok-reveals-1st-members-new-us-content-moderation-committee">US Safety Advisory Council</a>, after coming under <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/10/09/rubio-asks-us-to-investigate-china-based-tiktok-for-censorship.html">scrutiny from US lawmakers</a> concerned about the spread of election disinformation and wider data security issues, including accusations the Chinese-owned app was engaging in censorship at the behest of the Chinese government.</p>
<p>But the initial appointees to TikTok&#8217;s European content moderation advisory body suggest its regional focus is more firmly on child safety/young people&#8217;s mental health and extremism and hate speech, reflecting some of the main areas where it&#8217;s come under the most scrutiny from European lawmakers, regulators and civil society so far.</p>
<p>TikTok has appointed nine individuals to its European Council (<a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-be/meet-tiktoks-european-safety-advisory-council">listed here</a>) &#8212; initially bringing in external expertise in anti-bullying, youth mental health and digital parenting; online child sexual exploitation/abuse; extremism and deradicalization; anti-bias/discrimination and hate crimes &#8212; a cohort it says it will expand as it adds more members to the body (&#8220;from more countries and different areas of expertise to support us in the future&#8221;).</p>
<p>TikTok is also likely to have an eye on new pan-EU regulation that&#8217;s coming down the pipe for platforms operating in the region.</p>
<p>EU lawmakers recently put forward a legislative proposal that aims to dial up accountability for digital service providers over the content they push and monetize. The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">Digital Services Act</a>, which is currently in draft, going through the bloc&#8217;s co-legislative process, will regulate how a wide range of platforms must act to remove explicitly illegal content (such as hate speech and child sexual exploitation).</p>
<p>The Commission&#8217;s DSA proposal avoided setting specific rules for platforms to tackle a broader array of harms &#8212; such as issues like youth mental health &#8212; which, by contrast, the UK is proposing to address in its plan to regulate social media (aka the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/uk-online-harms-bill-coming-next-year-will-propose-fines-of-up-to-10-of-annual-turnover-for-breaching-duty-of-care-rules/">Online Safety bill</a>). However the planned legislation is intended to drive accountability around digital services in a variety of ways.</p>
<p>For example, it contains provisions that would require larger platforms &#8212; a category TikTok would most likely fall into &#8212; to provide data to external researchers so they can study the societal impacts of services. It&#8217;s not hard to imagine that provision leading to some head-turning (independent) research into the mental health impacts of attention-grabbing services. So the prospect is platforms&#8217; own data could end up translating into negative PR for their services &#8212; i.e. if they&#8217;re shown to be failing to create a safe environment for users.</p>
<p>Ahead of that oversight regime coming in, platforms have increased incentive to up their outreach to civil society in Europe so they&#8217;re in a better position to skate to where the puck is headed.</p>
<p><strong>Update:</strong> Reached for comment on TikTok&#8217;s advisory council, BEUC, the European consumer association that has coordinated recent consumer and data protection complaints against TikTok, sent us this statement, attributed to its deputy DG, Ursula Pachl: “We can only encourage TikTok to get advice from experts about how to better protect its users, especially children. TikTok&#8217;s foremost concern should however be to ensure that it takes all measures to comply with EU and national laws.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iz9l0kPbwg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/tiktok-joins-europes-code-on-tackling-hate-speech/">TikTok joins Europe&#8217;s code on tackling hate speech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok joins Europe&#8217;s code on tackling hate speech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/tiktok-joins-europes-code-on-tackling-hate-speech/embed/#?secret=iz9l0kPbwg" data-secret="iz9l0kPbwg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CVmjSAKGvH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/embed/#?secret=CVmjSAKGvH" data-secret="CVmjSAKGvH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/tiktok-calls-in-outside-help-with-content-moderation-in-europe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119477</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Humaans raises $5M seed to make it easier for companies to on-board and manage staff</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/humaans/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/humaans/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 09:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontline ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humaans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resources]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lachy Groom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moonfire Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2115837</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Humaans, a London-based HR startup, has raised $5 million in seed funding to accelerate the development of its employee on-boarding and management platform. Backing the round is Y Combinator, Mattias Ljungman’s Moonfire, Frontline Ventures and former head of Stripe Issuing, Lachy Groom. A number of other investors, made up of seasoned entrepreneurs and startup operators, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://humaans.io/">Humaans</a>, a London-based HR startup, has raised $5 million in seed funding to accelerate the development of its employee on-boarding and management platform. Backing the round is Y Combinator, Mattias Ljungman’s Moonfire, Frontline Ventures and former head of Stripe Issuing, Lachy Groom.</p>
<p>A number of other investors, made up of seasoned entrepreneurs and startup operators, also participated. They include LinkedIn CEO Jeff Weiner (via Next Play Ventures), Stripe COO Claire Johnson, Figma CEO Dylan Field, Intercom co-founder Des Traynor, former Workday CTO David Clarke, former Benchmark GP Scott Belsky, Notion COO Akshay Kothari, Qubit co-founder Emre Baran, Evervault CEO Shane Curren and Stripe head of security Gerardo Di Giacomo.</p>
<p>Founded by former Qubit employees Giovanni Luperti and Karolis Narkevicius, Humaans came into existence formerly in April 2020 after the pair quit the product agency they had founded together. With a soft launch the previous year while bootstrapping, and with validation from early users, Luperti and Narkevicius decided they had found enough product-market fit to focus on the startup full-time.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“We bootstrapped Humaans by reinvesting capital from the previous businesses we co-founded,” explains CEO Luperti. “After gaining initial commercial traction, we decided to raise capital and brought a number of investors and operators onboard, and joined Y Combinator”.</p>
<p>Pitching itself as a central hub for employee on-boarding and management &#8212; or a single source of truth for staffing &#8212; Humaans aims to play nicely by integrating with other existing SaaS used across the “HR stack”. This is because scaling companies are increasingly rejecting all-encompassing HR software and using the best modern SaaS offerings for various different functions.</p>
<p>“Companies are frustrated with poorly integrated HR stacks, making processes slow while exposing them to compliance risks,” says Luperti. “This is why the adoption of point solutions is increasing dramatically. Companies are adopting what&#8217;s best based on their needs and stage of growth to address their people needs”.</p>
<p>For example, a company may choose an applicant tracking system, a performance management system, contract management software and an employee engagement platform, and so on. “This makes the ‘all-in-one’ model antiquated, creating the opportunity for a solution like Humaans to emerge. We’re building a layer of infrastructure for all employee data”.</p>
<p>This is seeing Humaans attempt to bring together the full HR stack and automate processes like on-boarding, off-boarding and compensation management with fast workflows that can be set up not dissimilar to an IFTTT or Zapier-style type of interaction model.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2118890" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2118890" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2118890" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/humaans-screenshot.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="425" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/humaans-screenshot.png 1440w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/humaans-screenshot.png?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/humaans-screenshot.png?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/humaans-screenshot.png?resize=768,480 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/humaans-screenshot.png?resize=680,425 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/humaans-screenshot.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2118890" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Humaans</p></div></p>
<p>“If you ask around, most employees dislike their HR software,” says Luperti. “HR tools have historically been clunky, slow and not good at providing a good user experience. Existing players focused more on sales and acquisition than retention through product. But HR buyers today are more sophisticated than ever and have an appetite for best in class. We&#8217;re building the Slack of HR… an employee management platform that’s both delightful and very powerful”.</p>
<p>To that end, Humaans says it grew 3x in the past few months and is popular amongst distributed companies, such as Pleo, ChartMogul, Bombinate, HeySummit and Pento.</p>
<p>Adds the Humaans CEO: “There are two segments of existing players: those targeting SMEs, and those working with corporations. Serving the companies in the middle is the opportunity we’re going after”.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/humaans/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2115837</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amsterdam&#8217;s Crisp, an online-only supermarket, raises €30M Series B led by Target Global</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/amsterdams-crisp-an-online-only-supermarket-raises-e30m-series-b-led-by-target-global/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/amsterdams-crisp-an-online-only-supermarket-raises-e30m-series-b-led-by-target-global/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 08:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adyen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amsterdam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grocery store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netherlands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supermarkets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Takeaway.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Target Global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119461</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Crisp, an Amsterdam-based, online-only supermarket focused on fresh produce, has raised €30 million in a Series B financing led by leading Target Global and joined by Keen Venture Partners and the co-founders of Adyen and Takeaway.com. Crisp has now raised a total of €42.5 million to date. It plans to use the money to expand [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.crisp.nl/">Crisp</a>, an Amsterdam-based, online-only supermarket focused on fresh produce, has raised €30 million in a Series B financing led by leading Target Global and joined by Keen Venture Partners and the co-founders of Adyen and Takeaway.com. Crisp has now raised a total of €42.5 million to date. It plans to use the money to expand in the Netherlands, and eventually across Europe.</p>
<p>Crisp says its USP is seasonal products sourced directly from 600+ small and high-quality producers at an affordable price in the Netherlands. Customers order through a smartphone app and deliveries are the next day within a 1-hour time slot. It also uses a 100% electric fleet serving big cities and suburbs, and its model is to have zero food waste.</p>
<p>The European grocery market is currently worth €2 trillion, but access to customers for high-quality, smaller producers is still tricky and blocked by incumbents. Crisp is taking advantage of consumers moving online, and wanting fresher food.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Tom Peeters, CEO and co-founder of Crisp, told my via online interview that “the differentiation on our model is that we offer quality and convenience. So, fish is super fresh fruits and produce is super fresh, etc. We basically stay away from the standard supermarket proposition that everything is always there, and you manage long shelf life. We&#8217;d rather build a very short chain sourcing directly at the source and bringing it in a very convenient way to you.”</p>
<p>He said it’s not a 15 minute delivery but the next day in order to ensure freshness. “The typical customer is a young family. An average order is 45 products and rather than offering all the brands, we on-boarded the long-tail of food producers in our digital marketplace, so we sourced from over 600 sources of food.”</p>
<p>He said: “Food in Holland is 40 billion euros, in Germany it is 200 billion. I think Europe combined it&#8217;s over two or 3 trillion. So that means basically we don&#8217;t need to spread thin over many countries in order to build a healthy business, not just healthy products, so we make money on every customer order.”</p>
<p>Founded in 2018, by serial entrepreneurs Tom Peeters, Michiel Roodenburg and Eric Klaassen Crisp claims to be now one of the fastest-growing supermarkets in the Netherlands, with a seven-fold in sales in 2020 and more than 85% of sales coming from repeat customers, it says.</p>
<p>Bao-Y van Cong, Investment Director at Target Global, headquartered in Berlin, said: “Crisp is building a world-class technology platform that is of value to both consumers and producers. The way we buy our food has not changed a lot since the 1950’s, creating inefficiencies in quality, affordability, and convenience. Crisp reflects the changing relationship that consumers today have with food: The European market for grocery shopping is starting to move online fast, super-accelerated by the pandemic. At the same time, we see a massive surge in demand for fresh and transparently sourced food.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/amsterdams-crisp-an-online-only-supermarket-raises-e30m-series-b-led-by-target-global/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119461</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Czech on-demand grocery delivery startup Rohlik bags $230M to expand across Europe</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/czech-on-demand-grocery-delivery-startup-rohlik-bags-230m-to-expand-across-europe/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/czech-on-demand-grocery-delivery-startup-rohlik-bags-230m-to-expand-across-europe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 08:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grocery delivery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119111</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Food delivery &#8212; whether it&#8217;s ready-made orders from restaurants, meal kits or groceries &#8212; has been one of the most-used services in this last year of living under the cloud of a global health pandemic, and today one of the companies with ambitions to build a pan-European empire in the third of these categories is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Food delivery &#8212; whether it&#8217;s ready-made orders from restaurants, meal kits or groceries &#8212; has been one of the most-used services in this last year of living under the cloud of a global health pandemic, and today one of the companies with ambitions to build a pan-European empire in the third of these categories is announcing a major round of funding to help it get there.</p>
<p><a href="https://rohlik.cz/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rohlik</a>, a Czech startup that has built an online grocery ordering and delivery business combining your usual grocery fare &#8212; which it procures itself wholesale, or offers in concert with established businesses like Marks &amp; Spencer &#8212; with items sourced from local small businesses, has picked up €190 million ($230 million at today&#8217;s rates).</p>
<p>It plans to use the funding to expand its footprint across metropolitan areas in its existing three markets &#8212; the Czech Republic, Hungary and Austria &#8212; as well as to break into Germany, Poland, Romania and other countries in the near future.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company &#8212; which has some 17 thousand items in its online store &#8212; saw revenues rise 101% in FY 2020 to €300 million on 750,000 customers, and it is profitable. This round will give it significantly more fuel to grow than its balance sheet would, Tomáš Čupr, Rohlik CEO and founder, told TechCrunch in an interview.</p>
<p>In a market now full of companies offering online grocery delivery, from online arms of established brick and mortar sellers through to &#8220;digital native&#8221; brands, one of Rohlik&#8217;s unique selling points has been to tap into the specific shopping habits of average European urban consumers, who regularly combine shopping at smaller businesses alongside supermarkets.</p>
<p>&#8220;We found the sweet spot of great service, which is two-hour delivery turnaround ordered in windows of 15 minutes, and an amazing assortment. Traditionally you find supermarket assortments in online grocers, but what is the point of waiting for that? We have a supermarket, too, but we married it with local butchers, fishmongers, bakers, fruit and veg sellers, things you can’t buy in mass retail,&#8221; said Čupr. &#8220;We are saving people 5-7 shopping trips, not just the one to the supermarket, and that’s why we managed to scale.&#8221;</p>
<p>The round was led by Partech with significant participation also from Index Ventures. The <a href="https://www.ebrd.com/home" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EBRD</a>, Quadrille Capital, J&amp;T Bank, R2G, and Enern (a current investor) were also in the round.</p>
<p>The valuation is not being disclosed but <a href="https://forbes.cz/tomas-cupr-je-kral-rohlik-i-s-miliardovou-investici-prekracuje-svuj-stin-a-jde-dobyt-zapad/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Forbes&#8217; Czech edition</a>, when reporting on the round being in the works in January, said it was over €600 million ($723 million). We understand from sources it is around $600 million.</p>
<p>Founded in 2014, Rohlik&#8217;s funding comes at an interesting and key moment in the online grocery business, in Europe and beyond.</p>
<p>First, we as consumers have proven out the immediate and lasting demand for these services in the last year.</p>
<p>Shelter-in-place orders, and a general move from large parts of the consumer population to socially distance to help keep down community spread of the Covid-19 pandemic, have led to huge surges of consumers using online food ordering for their grocery needs.</p>
<p>That caused, in many cases, for those systems to get overloaded. For example, Ocado here in the UK, where I am a customer, saw its system fall over with the demand, leading it to implementing strict online queuing systems; many companies were unable to keep up with stock demands and requests for delivery slots; etc.)</p>
<p>Even with some (very much not all) countries in Europe relaxing parts of their orders, grocery has remained a very-much used online category in markets where it is available. That is to say, whatever growing trends there were before a year ago, that adoption has accelerated and stuck.</p>
<p>Second, online grocery delivery has become a key area of interest for investors, concentrating specifically on startups, who see an opportunity to innovate even as some of the very biggest players, such as Amazon, <a href="https://www.bnnbloomberg.ca/amazon-shutters-prime-pantry-an-early-online-grocery-initiative-1.1545336" target="_blank" rel="noopener">beat partial retreats</a>.</p>
<p>Last year, we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/dija/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> that Dija &#8212; a new startup from former Deliveroo employees in London &#8212; was raising a round; Gorillas in Berlin <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/gorillas/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised $44 million</a> in December; Ocado in the UK (which is listed here but is run like a startup) <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/566f8bc5-6419-4d57-aeb0-587d9d61a945" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised over $1 billion</a>.</p>
<p>Last month, Wolt in Finland &#8212; which started with restaurants but has since expanded into other areas, including grocery &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/wolt-closes-530m-round-to-continue-expanding-beyond-restaurant-delivery/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised $530 million</a>; Glovo in Spain <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/spains-glovo-inks-real-estate-tie-up-to-add-more-dark-stores-for-speedy-urban-delivery/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">picked up $120 million</a>; and Weezy in the UK <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/uk-on-demand-supermarket-weezy-raises-20m-series-a-led-by-nycs-left-lane-capital/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised $20 million</a>.</p>
<p>And just today, yet another online-only grocery delivery startup, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/amsterdams-crisp-an-online-only-supermarket-raises-e30m-series-b-led-by-target-global/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Crisp in the Netherlands</a>, raised $36 million (€30 million) led by Target Global. (And this is not a comprehensive list.)</p>
<p>Depending on the country, the target market (urban-only or everyone, families or single people), and the choice of food that&#8217;s getting delivered (eg, those who want things that are slightly more prepared versus farm-fresh produce for bigger cooking efforts, etc.), and sourcing relationships (directly with brick-and-mortar retailers, small or big, direct from producers), different startups are taking their own approaches around what kind of models they are building to manage sourcing, logistics and fulfillment.</p>
<p>Some are taking on &#8220;dark&#8221; convenience stores in cities, as is the case with Gorillas; others are using large fulfillment centers well outside of urban centers, such as Ocado. Some are building their supply chains from the ground up, while others are working with existing retailers, big and small.</p>
<p>The attraction in part with Rohlik is how it has used logistics technology combined with a close understanding of the market (one of Čupr&#8217;s previous startups was a restaurant delivery business, <a href="https://www.deliveryhero.com/delivery-hero-expands-business-in-europe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired by Delivery Hero</a>) to build its platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re making a substantial bet and we’re not looking for any business that provides a substitute to existing services,&#8221; said Index partner Jan Hammer, in an interview. &#8220;We&#8217;ve invested in different models around the globe and we have good experiences with Good Eggs. As a tech investment firm, we look at commerce payments, warehouse software and related models that can be synergistic. The macro trend is universal offline to online migration through a better business model. That is the direction of travel. As a VC we would also say that it&#8217;s also down to the individuals involved.&#8221;</p>
<p>Rohlik, Čupr said, uses large fulfillment venues that are not as big as out-of-town centers but located much closer to where their customers are based. (This could also potentially give the company an opportunity for expansion into new cities: as large supermarkets become less profitable, they can present themselves as a real estate opportunity for online delivery companies like Rohlik.)</p>
<p>Interestingly, a company probably most similar to Rohlik, and thus one of its potentially closest competitors, Picnic from The Netherlands, last raised money in 2019, <a href="https://www.dutchnews.nl/news/2019/11/picnic-raises-e250m-for-a-massive-automated-distribution-centre/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$300 million</a>, to build an automated distribution center to serve its home country and Germany. Perhaps it will be next in line for a big round of money. (I&#8217;ll also note that both Index and Accel were reportedly interested in Gorillas but neither invested in the end. With Index now putting its bets on Rohlik, you have to wonder what Accel might do next, if anything.)</p>
<p>A lot of companies in this space up to now have been focused on national markets &#8212; Instacart has not expanded outside of North America, Ocado is only in the UK, and so on. The opportunity for a company like Rohlik is to export its model to more countries that have similar market dynamics to those it already serves.</p>
<p>“Rohlik is the most exciting player in the European online grocery industry,&#8221; said Omri Benayoun, General Partner at Partech, in a statement. &#8220;We are honored to partner with Rohlik’s founder Tomáš Čupr, whose passion for service, sustainability and vision for the grocery sector we share. Rohlik’s execution expertise has earned it the trust of both local merchants and global FMCG companies; allowing Rohlik to outperform on quality and price compared to the grocery giants.”</p>
<p><em>Updated with more updated numbers from Rohlik on its full-year figures, and some changes to investor names in this round: Kaiser Permanente Ventures is not involved.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/czech-on-demand-grocery-delivery-startup-rohlik-bags-230m-to-expand-across-europe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119111</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coupang may raise up to $3.6 billion in its IPO, at a potential valuation of $51 billion</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/coupang-may-raise-up-to-3-6-billion-in-its-ipo-at-a-potential-valuation-of-51-billion/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/coupang-may-raise-up-to-3-6-billion-in-its-ipo-at-a-potential-valuation-of-51-billion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 05:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coupang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119451</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[According to an amended S-1 filing, South Korean e-commerce leader Coupang expects to price its initial public offering between $27 to $30 per share, potentially raising up to $3.6 billion. After the IPO, Coupang will have a total of 1.7 billion shares outstanding, including Class A and Class B. This means the means the pricing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">According to an <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1834584/000162828021003511/coupang-sx1a1.htm?source=content_type%3Areact%7Cfirst_level_url%3Anews%7Csection%3Amain_content%7Cbutton%3Abody_link">amended S-1 filing</a>, South Korean e-commerce leader <a href="https://www.coupang.com/">Coupang</a> expects to price its initial public offering between $27 to $30 per share, potentially raising up to $3.6 billion. After the IPO, Coupang will have a total of 1.7 billion shares outstanding, including Class A and Class B. This means the means the pricing would give Coupang a potential market capitalization between $46 billion to $51 billion, a huge increase over the $9 billion valuation it reached after its last funding round in 2018, led by SoftBank Vision Fund.</p>
<p>Coupang and some of its existing shareholders will offer a total of 120 million shares during the IPO.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Sn0ZvUO47w"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/20/coupang-raises-2-billion-from-softbanks-vision-fund/">Korean e-commerce firm Coupang raises $2 billion from SoftBank&#8217;s Vision Fund</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Korean e-commerce firm Coupang raises $2 billion from SoftBank&#8217;s Vision Fund&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/20/coupang-raises-2-billion-from-softbanks-vision-fund/embed/#?secret=Sn0ZvUO47w" data-secret="Sn0ZvUO47w" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>If Coupang’s IPO is successful, it would be a huge win for SoftBank Vision Fund, which will own 36.8% of its Class A shares after the listing.</p>
<p>Founded in 2010 by Bom Kim, Coupang is known for its ultra-speedy deliveries and is now the largest e-commerce company in South Korea, according to Euromonitor. According to the filing, Kim will hold 76.7% of voting power after the listing, while SoftBank Vision Fund will hold about 8.6%. Other investors that currently own 5% or more of Coupang’s shares include Greenoaks Capital Partners, Maverick Holdings, Rose Park Advisors, BlackRock and Ridd Investments.</p>
<p>Coupang filed to go public on the New York Stock Exchange last month, under the symbol CPNG. Based on <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-01/south-korea-s-coupang-seeks-up-to-3-6-billion-in-new-york-ipo">Bloomberg</a> data, Coupang’s listing will be the fourth-biggest by an Asian company on a U.S. exchange, and the largest since Alibaba’s $25 billion IPO in 2014.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Js3WtPJMZM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/coupang-files-for-mega-us-ipo/">Coupang files for mega US IPO</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Coupang files for mega US IPO&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/coupang-files-for-mega-us-ipo/embed/#?secret=Js3WtPJMZM" data-secret="Js3WtPJMZM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/coupang-may-raise-up-to-3-6-billion-in-its-ipo-at-a-potential-valuation-of-51-billion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119451</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Compass files S-1, reveals $3.7B in revenue on net loss of $270M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/compass-files-for-ipo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/compass-files-for-ipo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 02:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canadian Pension Plan Investment Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qatar Investment Authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Group]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2119431</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Compass, the real-estate brokerage startup backed by roughly $1.6 billion in venture funding, filed its S-1 Monday. The move comes just under one year after the New York-based company laid off 15% of its staff as a result of the shifting economic fortunes created by the global response to the novel coronavirus pandemic. Prior to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.compass.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Compass</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the real-estate brokerage startup backed by </span><a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/compassinc"><span style="font-weight: 400;">roughly $1.6 billion in venture funding</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, filed its <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001563190/000119312521063859/d36119ds1.htm">S-1</a> Monday.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The move comes just under one year after the New York-based company</span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/23/with-the-real-estate-industry-facing-headwinds-softbank-backed-compass-lays-off-15-of-staff-after/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> laid off 15% of its staff</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as a result of the shifting economic fortunes created by the global response to the novel coronavirus pandemic.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Prior to the IPO, SoftBank’s Vision Fund holds slightly more than a one-third stake in the company. Other investors include the Canadian Pension Plan Investment Board, Fidelity, Wellington Management, and the Qatar Investment Authority, according to Crunchbase.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company’s last fundraise was in July 2019, when Compass — a company that has built a three-sided marketplace for the real estate industry, along with a wide set of algorithms to help make it work — raised a $370 million round of funding. That financing valued Compass at $6.4 billion.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the greatest things about companies going public is that we get insight into their financials. Compass is not profitable but it did see a massive surge in revenue over the past few years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company’s revenues have increased from $186.8 million in 2016 to a whopping $3.7 billion last year, with much of the top-line revenue growth coming in the last two years, according to its S-1. Given the startup’s agency model, most of that revenue is paid out directly to the firm’s agents, who netted about $3 billion in commissions in 2020. Compass posted a net loss of $270 million in 2020, a net loss roughly in line with what it has experienced in the past two years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Total transactions on the platform grew from about 27,000 in 2018 to 145,000 in 2020, while total transaction volume (the value of the properties the company brokers) went up by about five-fold, from $34 billion to $152 billion last year. Since commissions on real estate are determined as fixed percentage of the value of the property, more transaction volume directly translates into more revenue for Compass. The company had 19,385 agents on its platform as of Dec. 31, 2020. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Compass had its share of trouble before the pandemic. In September 2019, the Wall Street Journal reported that the company had </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">lost a number of senior level individuals over the previous eighteen months including its chief financial officer, chief marketing officer and chief technology officer.</span></p>
<p><em>The story was updated post-publication to more accurately reflect the number of agents Compass has on its platform</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/compass-files-for-ipo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2119431</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
