<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 16:01:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Gay dating site Manhunt hacked, thousands of accounts stolen</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/gay-dating-site-manhunt-hacked/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/gay-dating-site-manhunt-hacked/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 16:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[@jack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ashley madison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Password]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[securedrop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security breaches]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138412</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Manhunt, a gay dating app that claims to have 6 million male members, has confirmed it was hit by a data breach in February after a hacker gained access to the company&#8217;s accounts database. In a notice filed with the Washington attorney general&#8217;s office, Manhunt said the hacker &#8220;gained access to a database that stored [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Manhunt, a gay dating app that claims to have 6 million male members, has confirmed it was hit by a data breach in February after a hacker gained access to the company&#8217;s accounts database.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/20615089-mhnextllc2021-04-01">a notice</a> filed with the Washington attorney general&#8217;s office, Manhunt said the hacker &#8220;gained access to a database that stored account credentials for Manhunt users,&#8221; and &#8220;downloaded the usernames, email addresses and passwords for a subset of our users in early February 2021.</p>
<p>The notice did not say how the passwords were scrambled, if at all, to prevent them from being read by humans. Passwords scrambled using weak algorithms can sometimes be decoded into plain text, allowing malicious hackers to break into their accounts.</p>
<p>Following the breach, Manhunt force-reset account passwords began alerting users in mid-March. Manhunt did not say what percentage of its users had their data stolen or how the data breach happened, but said that more than 7,700 Washington state residents were affected.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s attorneys did not reply to an email requesting comment.</p>
<p>But questions remain about how Manhunt handled the breach. In March, the company <a href="https://twitter.com/Manhunt/status/1370012193056493568 ">tweeted</a> that, &#8220;At this time, all Manhunt users are required to update their password to ensure it meets the updated password requirements.&#8221; The tweet did not say that user accounts had been stolen.</p>
<p>Manhunt was launched in 2001 by Online-Buddies Inc., which also offered gay dating app Jack&#8217;d before it <a href="https://www.bizjournals.com/newyork/news/2019/07/10/perry-street-owner-of-scruff-buys-jackd.html">was sold</a> to Perry Street in 2019 for an undisclosed sum. Just months before the sale, Jack&#8217;d had <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/02/indecent-disclosure-gay-dating-app-left-private-exposed-to-web/">a security lapse</a> that exposed users&#8217; private photos and location data.</p>
<p>Dating sites store some of the most sensitive information on their users, and are frequently a target of malicious hackers. In 2015, Ashley Madison, a dating site that encouraged users to have an affair, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/03/have-i-been-pwned/">was hacked</a>, exposing names, and postal and email addresses. Several people <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/08/24/ashley-madison-offering-500000-reward-for-info-on-hack-now-linked-to-two-suicides/">died by suicide</a> after the stolen data was posted online. A year later, dating site AdultFriendFinder was hacked, exposing <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/adultfriendfinder-network-hack-exposes-secrets-of-412-million-users/">more than 400 million user accounts</a>.</p>
<p>In 2018, same-sex dating app Grindr <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/azeenghorayshi/grindr-hiv-status-privacy">made headlines</a> for sharing users&#8217; HIV status with data analytics firms.</p>
<p>In other cases, poor security — in some cases none at all — led to data spills involving some of the most sensitive data. In 2019, Rela, a popular dating app for gay and queer women in China, left a server unsecured with no password, allowing anyone to access sensitive data — including sexual orientation and geolocation — on more than 5 million app users. Months later, Jewish dating app JCrush <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/04/jcrush-exposed-data-messages/">exposed</a> around 200,000 user records.</p>
<p><strong>Read more: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/27/rela-data-exposed/">Rela, a Chinese lesbian dating app, exposed 5 million user profiles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/04/jcrush-exposed-data-messages/">Jewish dating app JCrush exposed user data and private messages</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/28/security-flaw-in-grindr-exposed-locations-to-third-party-service/">Security flaw in Grindr exposed locations to third-party service</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/02/grindr-account-hijack-flaw/">A security flaw in Grindr let anyone easily hijack user accounts</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/grindr-on-the-hook-for-e10m-over-gdpr-consent-violations/">Grindr on the hook for €10M over GDPR consent violations</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p><em>Know something, say something. Send tips securely over Signal and WhatsApp to +1 646-755-8849. You can also send files or documents using our SecureDrop. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/techcrunch-launches-securedrop/">Learn more</a>. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/gay-dating-site-manhunt-hacked/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138412</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon&#8217;s latest Echo Buds are a shameless Apple knock-off</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amazons-latest-echo-buds-are-a-shameless-apple-knock-off/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amazons-latest-echo-buds-are-a-shameless-apple-knock-off/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AirPod pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[echo buds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is Amazon&#8217;s latest hardware product: The redesigned Alexa earbuds. TechCrunch covered the announcement here, where the specs and capabilities are listed. I&#8217;m sure they work fine, too, but the case design is a blatant rip-off of Apple&#8217;s AirPod Pros. This is just lazy. Amazon has a long history of selling and promoting lookalikes, copycats, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This is Amazon&#8217;s latest hardware product: The redesigned Alexa earbuds. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amazons-alexa-earbuds-return-with-a-smaller-design-and-wireless-charging/">TechCrunch covered the announcement here</a>, where the specs and capabilities are listed. I&#8217;m sure they work fine, too, but the case design is a blatant rip-off of Apple&#8217;s AirPod Pros.</p>
<p>This is just lazy.</p>
<p>Amazon has a long history of selling and promoting lookalikes, copycats, and clones of other products. Likewise, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/18/amazon-and-valentino-team-up-in-joint-lawsuit-against-new-york-counterfeiter-over-rockstud-knock-offs/">the retailer sued</a> third-party sellers for doing the same thing. Amazon also has been accused of investing in companies and later producing clones of the products. In 2020 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/29/bezos-cant-guarantee-no-anti-competitive-activity-as-congress-catches-him-flat-footed/">CEO Jeff Bezos testified on this subject</a> in front of a congressional hearing where he couldn&#8217;t guarantee the company would end this process. Often the products Amazon copies come from small startups without the resources to fight a giant like Amazon.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Last month California-based <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HbxWGjQ2szQ">Peak Design took to YouTube to protest Amazon&#8217;s unabashed copy of one of Peak&#8217;s top products</a>. As Peak points out, Amazon&#8217;s take is a cheap knockoff made from lower quality materials and without Peak Design&#8217;s ethical manufacturing. The video quickly went viral, amassing over 4.5 million hits and highlighting Amazon&#8217;s shady practices.</p>
<p>For the latest Echo Buds, Amazon copied a market leader instead of a small startup. To recap, Amazon, a company worth over a trillion dollars, just released a product that looks essentially identical to a top-selling product from Apple, a company worth 2 trillion dollars.</p>
<p>The Echo Buds are much less expensive than Apple&#8217;s $250 AirPod Pros, too. The standard Echo Buds costs $100, and the version with wireless charging runs $120. It&#8217;s important to note the wireless buds themselves do not look like AirPods. Amazon only copied the ubiquitous AirPod Pro case.</p>
<p>The consumer is the loser here. With more resources than many countries, Amazon can produce world-class products, yet it decided to copy a rival&#8217;s market-leading product. In the end, it&#8217;s easier (and cheaper) to follow trends than become a trendsetter.</p>
<hr />
<h2>Peak Design takes on Amazon</h2>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/HbxWGjQ2szQ?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amazons-latest-echo-buds-are-a-shameless-apple-knock-off/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138361</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I can&#8217;t believe it&#8217;s not meat! Mycelium meat replacement company aims for summer launch of first products</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/i-cant-believe-its-not-meat/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/i-cant-believe-its-not-meat/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acre venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barack Obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beef]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Congruent Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecovative Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jerky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michelle obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mycelium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MycoWorks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prelude ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silicon valley bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White House]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Meati, a company turning mycelium (the structural fibers of fungi) into healthier meat replacements for consumers, is prepping for a big summer rollout. Co-founder Tyler Huggins expects to have the first samples of its whole-cut steak and chicken products in select restaurants around the country &#8212; along with their first commercial product, a jerky strip. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://meati.com/">Meati</a>, a company turning mycelium (the structural fibers of fungi) into healthier meat replacements for consumers, is prepping for a big summer rollout.</p>
<p>Co-founder Tyler Huggins expects to have the first samples of its whole-cut steak and chicken products in select restaurants around the country &#8212; along with their first commercial product, a jerky strip.</p>
<p>For Huggins, the product launch is another step on a long road toward broad commercial adoption of functional fungi foods as a better-for-you alternative to traditional meats.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Use this as a conversation starter. About 2 ounces of this gives you 50% of your protein; 50% of your fiber; and half of your daily zinc. There really is nothing that can compare to this product in terms of nutritionals,&#8221; Huggins said. </span></p>
<p>And moving from meat to mushrooms is a better option for the planet.</p>
<p>Meati expects to turn on its pilot plant this summer and is joining a movement among mushroom fans that includes milk replacements, from <a href="https://perfectdayfoods.com/">Perfect Day</a>, more meat replacements from <a href="https://www.atlastfood.co/">Atlast</a>, and leather substitutes from <a href="https://ecovativedesign.com/mycoflex">Ecovative</a> and <a href="https://www.mycoworks.com/">MycoWorks</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DfZODAruTl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/ecovative-sees-a-fungal-future-for-fashion-food-and-foam-packaging-and-has-a-fresh-60m-to-make-it/">Ecovative sees a fungal future for fashion, food and foam packaging and has a fresh $60M to make it</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ecovative sees a fungal future for fashion, food and foam packaging and has a fresh $60M to make it&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/ecovative-sees-a-fungal-future-for-fashion-food-and-foam-packaging-and-has-a-fresh-60m-to-make-it/embed/#?secret=DfZODAruTl" data-secret="DfZODAruTl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re definitely all in this together,&#8221; said Huggins of the other mob of mycelium-based tech companies bringing products to market.</p>
<p>However, not all mycelium is created equally, Huggins said. Meati has what Huggins said was a unique way of growing its funguses (not a real word) that &#8220;keep it in its most happy state.&#8221; That means peak nutritional content and peak growth efficiency, according to the company.</p>
<p>For Huggins, whose parents own a bison ranch and who grew up in cattle country, the goal is not to replace a t-bone or a ribeye, but the cuts of meat and chicken that find their ways into a burrito supreme or other quick serve meat cuts.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2138406" style="width: 426px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2138406" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2138406" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg" alt="" width="416" height="624" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg 3689w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg?resize=768,1152 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg?resize=453,680 453w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg?resize=1024,1536 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg?resize=1365,2048 1365w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 416px) 100vw, 416px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2138406" class="wp-caption-text">Rendering of Meati mushroom meats in a Banh Mi. Image Credit: Meati</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Head to head with that kind of cut, we win,&#8221; Huggins said. &#8220;I&#8217;d rather pick a fight there now and buy ourselves some time. I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re going to go super high-end to start.&#8221;</p>
<p>That said, the company&#8217;s cap table of investors already includes some pretty heady culinary company. <a href="http://acre.vc/#company-info-full">Acre Venture Partners</a> (which counts Sam Kass &#8212; President Barack Obama&#8217;s Senior Policy Advisor for Nutrition Policy, Executive Director for First Lady Michelle Obama&#8217;s Let&#8217;s Move! campaign, and an Assistant Chef in the White House &#8212; among its partnership) is an investor. So is Chicago&#8217;s fine dining temple, Alinea.</p>
<p>But Huggins wants Meati to be an everyday type of meat replacement product. &#8220;I want to make sure that people think this is an every day protein,&#8221; Huggins said.</p>
<p>Meati thinks its future meat replacements will be cost competitive with conventional beef and chicken, but to whet consumers&#8217; appetites, the company is starting with jerky.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;Meati’s delicious jerky,&#8221; said Huggins. &#8220;It provides this blank canvas. We’ll start with these beef jerky like flavors. But I want to come out of the gate and say that we’re mycelium jerky.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>The company currently has 30 people on staff led by Huggins and fo-founder Justin Whiteley. The two men initially started working on Meati as a battery replacement. Based on their research (Huggins with mycelium and Whiteley with advanced batteries) the two men received a grant for a mycelium-based electrode for lithium ion batteries.</p>
<p>&#8220;We were trying to tweak the chemical composition of the mycelium to make a better battery. What we found was that we were making something nutritious and edible,&#8221; said Huggins.</p>
<p>Also&#8230; the battery companies didn&#8217;t want it.</p>
<p>Now, backed by $28 million from Acre, Prelude Ventures, Congruent Ventures and Tao Capital, Meati is ready to go to market. The company also has access to debt capital to build out its vast network of mycelium growing facilities. It&#8217;s just raised a $18 million debt round from Trinity and Silicon Valley Bank.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Two years ago … most companies in this space … there wasn’t this ability to take on debt to put steel in the ground,&#8221; said Huggins. &#8220;It’s an exciting time to be in food tech given that you can raise VC funding and there’s this ready available market for debt financing. You’ll start seeing faster and more rapid development because of it.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2138413" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2138413" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2138413" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg 5203w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg?resize=2048,1367 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2138413" class="wp-caption-text">Meati co-founders Tyler Huggins and Justin Whiteley. Image Credit: Meati</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/i-cant-believe-its-not-meat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138294</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inside the US’ epic first-quarter venture capital results</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/inside-the-us-epic-first-quarter-venture-capital-results/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/inside-the-us-epic-first-quarter-venture-capital-results/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC News Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pitchbook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We're diving into the data with help from Sarah Kunst of Cleo Capital, Jenny Lefcourt of Freestyle Capital, Iris Choi of Floodgate and Laela Sturdy of CapitalG.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/is-substack-really-worth-650m/">no surprise</a> that the venture capital market was incredibly active in the United States during the first quarter of 2021, but precisely how strong has only recently become clear. This morning, we’re digging into the data.</p>
<p>According to a<a href="https://pitchbook.com/news/reports/q1-2021-pitchbook-nvca-venture-monitor"> report from PitchBook</a>, venture capitalists unleashed a wave of capital in the first three months of the year. So much, in fact, that funding in the United States nearly doubled compared to the same quarter of 2020.</p>
<p>We’ll dig into specific numbers and trends regarding aggregate venture capital results in a moment, but what stood out the most while digesting the Q1 dataset was how strong VC results appeared across different states; a solo late-stage boom the quarter was not.</p>
<p>Seed deal volume appeared strong and early-stage venture capital activity could reach new highs in 2021, but late-stage venture capital activity in the United States is already setting records in both deal count and invested dollars.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>We&#8217;ll parse the headline numbers and then dive into seed and super late-stage data with the help of Sarah Kunst of Cleo Capital, Jenny Lefcourt of Freestyle Capital, Iris Choi of Floodgate and Laela Sturdy of CapitalG.</p>
<p>With their help, we’ll contextualize the numbers and weave anecdotal observations into what the charts and graphs tell us. Especially in the case of seed data, which is famously laggy, added context is crucial. Let’s go!</p>
<h2>A Q1 overview</h2>
<p>According to PitchBook’s report, some 3,987 venture capital rounds were closed in the United States during Q1 2021. Those deals were worth $69 billion, a figure up nearly 93% from 2020’s first-quarter results.</p>
<p>In broad strokes, the United States had a crushing venture capital start to the new year, pandemic be damned. That is especially true when we consider 2020’s full-year figures. Last year, venture capitalists deployed some $166 billion into U.S.-based startups across 12,546 rounds. In contrast, if the first quarter’s pace was maintained during the rest of 2021, the United States would see around 16,000 rounds worth around $280 billion.</p>
<p>Of course, we cannot see the future, so those projections are merely shared to underscore how active the first quarter proved to be; we’ll have to wait for at least another quarter’s data to confidently predict full-year records for 2021.</p>
<p>Powering the rapid start to the venture capital year was a holistic boom: Seed deal volume is forecasted to have set a multi-year high, perhaps matching the historically strong Q2 2018 period. Early-stage venture capital during Q1 2021 was also robust, with $14.5 billion deployed across 1,170 rounds. Both numbers set a pace for fresh records in 2021.</p>
<p>And then there was late-stage dealmaking, which soared in the first quarter. In 2020, late-stage venture capital deals were worth $111.4 billion raised from 3,504 rounds. In the first quarter of 2021, some $51.9 billion was invested into late-stage startups across 1,291 deals.</p>
<p>Valuations and round sizes continued to rise across the board. If there was a better time to raise a big whack of venture capital as a U.S.-based startup, we cannot recall it. And the data seems to scream that the good times are now as good, or gooder, than ever.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/inside-the-us-epic-first-quarter-venture-capital-results/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138308</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Astranis raises $250M at a $1.4B valuation for smaller, cheaper geostationary communications satellites</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/astranis-raises-250m-at-a-1-4b-valuation-for-smaller-cheaper-geostationary-communications-satellites/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/astranis-raises-250m-at-a-1-4b-valuation-for-smaller-cheaper-geostationary-communications-satellites/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:03:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Astranis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlackRock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite constellation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite constellations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venrock]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138366</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Space startup Astranis has raised a $250 million Series C round to provide it with a capital injection to help scale manufacturing of its unique MicroGEO satellites — geostationary communications satellites that are much smaller than the typical massive, expensive spacecraft used in that orbital band to provide communications and connectivity to specific points on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Space startup Astranis has raised a $250 million Series C round to provide it with a capital injection to help scale manufacturing of its unique MicroGEO satellites — geostationary communications satellites that are much smaller than the typical massive, expensive spacecraft used in that orbital band to provide communications and connectivity to specific points on Earth.</p>
<p>The Astranis Series C was led by BlackRock-managed funds, and includes participation from a host of new investors including Baillie Gifford, Fidelity, Koch Strategic Platforms and more. Existing investors including Andreessen Horowitz, Venrock, and more also chipped in, with the raise valuing the company at $1.4 billion post-money.</p>
<p>This brings the total funding raised by Astranis to over $350 million, including both equity and debt financing. Astranis got started only in 2016, and was part of the YC Winter 2016 cohort. While a lot of other companies are looking to build satellite constellations in low-Earth orbit to provide low-cost broadband on Earth, Astranis, led by co-founder and CEO John Gedmark, is focused on the GEO band, where the large legacy communications satellites currently operate, orbiting the Earth at a fixed position and providing connectivity to a set area on Earth.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4yz8fFod38"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/17/astranis-reaches-key-milestone-with-microgeo-communication-satellite-aims-for-service-to-begin-next-summer/">Astranis reaches key milestone with MicroGEO communication satellite, aims for service to begin next summer</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Astranis reaches key milestone with MicroGEO communication satellite, aims for service to begin next summer&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/17/astranis-reaches-key-milestone-with-microgeo-communication-satellite-aims-for-service-to-begin-next-summer/embed/#?secret=4yz8fFod38" data-secret="4yz8fFod38" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Gedmark has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/17/astranis-reaches-key-milestone-with-microgeo-communication-satellite-aims-for-service-to-begin-next-summer/">told me previously</a> that the company&#8217;s offering is very different from the LEO constellations being put up and operated by companies including SpaceX, because they&#8217;re essentially a much more targeted, nimble solution that works with existing ground infrastructure. Customers who have a specific regional need for connectivity can get Astranis to put one one up at a greatly reduced cost compared to a traditional GEO communications satellite, and do so to replace or upgrade aging existing satellite network infrastructure, for example.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that BlackRock, which led this round, has also been a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/rocket-startup-astra-is-going-public-vis-spac/">key participant in the PIPE components of high-profile space startup SPACs like launcher company Astra&#8217;s</a>. Not saying that&#8217;s the exit plan this round is setting up, but definitely something to think about.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TDI5qhiQNx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/11/9-top-space-tech-vcs-on-the-markets-opportunities-and-challenges/">9 top space tech VCs on the market&#8217;s opportunities and challenges</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;9 top space tech VCs on the market&#8217;s opportunities and challenges&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/11/9-top-space-tech-vcs-on-the-markets-opportunities-and-challenges/embed/#?secret=TDI5qhiQNx" data-secret="TDI5qhiQNx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/astranis-raises-250m-at-a-1-4b-valuation-for-smaller-cheaper-geostationary-communications-satellites/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138366</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Creatively raises $5M to help creative professionals showcase and find work</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/creatively-seed-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/creatively-seed-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creatively]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Link Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138340</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Creatively — a startup that helps designers, photographers, illustrators and other creative professionals showcase their work and find their next job — is announcing that it has raised in $5 million. Founded by Stacey Bendet (founder and CEO of fashion company Alicia + Olivia) and Joe Indriolo (who also serves as Creatively&#8217;s chief product officer), [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://creatively.life">Creatively</a> — a startup that helps designers, photographers, illustrators and other creative professionals showcase their work and find their next job — is announcing that it has raised in $5 million.</p>
<p>Founded by Stacey Bendet (founder and CEO of fashion company Alicia + Olivia) and Joe Indriolo (who also serves as Creatively&#8217;s chief product officer), the startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/05/creatively-launch/">launched last May</a>.</p>
<p>At the time, CEO Greg Gittrich emphasized the customizability of its creative portfolios, allowing each user to showcase their work in different ways. Potential employers, meanwhile, post creative jobs, and after a job has been completed on the platform, it can become the next piece in the artist&#8217;s portfolio.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup says there are now more than 125,000 creatives on the platform, while 650 companies (including HBO, Tom Ford, SKIMS, Nickelodeon, Ro, CNN and The Gap) have used it to recruit.</p>
<p>Gittrich told me via email that he&#8217;s been surprised by &#8220;the breadth of talent and variety of disciplines&#8221; on the platform, which includes &#8220;photographers like <a href="https://creatively.life/emmanuelsmonsalve" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/emmanuelsmonsalve&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGYdMf7LSQJ-okBznGKixQDUobAsA">Emmanuel Sanchez Monsalve</a> and <a href="https://creatively.life/derrickoboateng" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/derrickoboateng&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFjekL87LIpWrsjQd1p6q3o1rAbGA">Derrick Ofosu Boateng</a>, creative directors like <a href="https://creatively.life/Kameron_DePaul" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/Kameron_DePaul&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGKfonp4SevhSUjMfR4-Mauk2BkcA">Kameron Mack</a> and <a href="https://creatively.life/ericfranklin" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/ericfranklin&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEm9GMb7Gw9Ww7CpW3G5LlJfriJmg">Eric Alexander Franklin</a>, illustrators and animators like <a href="https://creatively.life/tarajacoby" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/tarajacoby&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGoVg7csd0h8S6VbHyPmrbCNlkp3w">Tara Jacoby</a> and <a href="https://creatively.life/mulanfu" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/mulanfu&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE8U01pYXu3dEJnwux3Ru2kA7bkzg">Mulan Fu</a>, visual artists like <a href="https://creatively.life/kingkesia" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/kingkesia&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG2y8DRUaRyN1N5YOOlzeMz9PCdZA">King Kesia</a> and <a href="https://creatively.life/bbroadie04" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/bbroadie04&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEj6G0uDJ977R2HUtAXA2N26oW4bQ">Bryane Broadie</a>, and designers like <a href="https://creatively.life/kidsuper" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/kidsuper&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHba200tWE27jRmKj1Yi0axFB4Vow">KidSuper</a> and <a href="https://creatively.life/azizaabdullahnicole" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/azizaabdullahnicole&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEmrij7kdFHFG5BBqmzyGTKafqxbQ">Aziza-Abdullah Nicole</a>.&#8221; He also pointed to the popularity of the free <a href="https://creatively.life/classes">Creatively Classes</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hxMp9cuwqq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/05/creatively-launch/">Creatively helps designers and other creative talent showcase their work</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Creatively helps designers and other creative talent showcase their work&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/05/creatively-launch/embed/#?secret=hxMp9cuwqq" data-secret="hxMp9cuwqq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;We originally envisioned Classes as a one-time virtual event for October,&#8221; Gittrich said. &#8220;But the number of sign-ups and the engagement for the first slate of instructors was so overwhelming that we made Classes into a monthly series. All the classes are taught by experienced creatives in our community and they’re designed to give our community the skills, mentorship and inspiration they need to succeed.”</p>
<p>The seed round was led by Link Ventures. (Previous investors include Michael Eisner’s Tornante Company and Shari Redstone’s Advancit Capital.) This investment also connects Creatively to the firm&#8217;s incubator Cogo Labs, which will help the startup grow revenue and lower customer acquisition costs.</p>
<p>In a statement, Link Ventures Managing Director Lisa Dolan described Creatively as &#8220;LinkedIn for the creative world.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Today’s job market needs Creatively,&#8221; she continued. &#8220;Businesses are looking to recruit creatives directly, but lack the network and resources to find qualified, diverse talent. Creatively changes that. Their growth in less than a year is very impressive, and we’re excited to be a part of the team.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IvxMHu7kqI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/05/design-may-be-the-next-entrepreneurial-gold-rush/">Design may be the next entrepreneurial gold rush</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Design may be the next entrepreneurial gold rush&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/05/design-may-be-the-next-entrepreneurial-gold-rush/embed/#?secret=IvxMHu7kqI" data-secret="IvxMHu7kqI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/creatively-seed-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138340</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PlexTrac raises $10M Series A round for its collaboration-centric security platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/plextrac-raises-10m-series-a-round-for-its-collaboration-centric-security-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/plextrac-raises-10m-series-a-round-for-its-collaboration-centric-security-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[madrona venture group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mayo Clinic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Noro-Moseley Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[qualys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red team]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ServiceNow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138039</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PlexTrac, a Boise, ID-based security service that aims to provide a unified workflow automation platform for red and blue teams, today announced that it has raised a $10 million Series A funding round led by Noro-Moseley Partners and Madrona Venture Group. StageDot0 ventures also participated in this round, which the company plans to use to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://plextrac.com/">PlexTrac</a>, a Boise, ID-based security service that aims to provide a unified workflow automation platform for red and blue teams, today announced that it has raised a $10 million Series A funding round led by <a href="https://noromoseley.com/">Noro-Moseley Partners</a> and <a href="https://www.madrona.com/">Madrona Venture Group</a>. <a href="https://www.stagedoto.com/">StageDot0</a> ventures also participated in this round, which the company plans to use to build out its team and grow its platform.</p>
<p>With this new round, the company, which was founded in 2018, has now raised a total of $11 million, with StageDot0 leading its 2019 seed round.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2138058" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2138058" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-2138058" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg?w=300" alt="PlexTrac CEO and President Dan DeCloss" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg 400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2138058" class="wp-caption-text">PlexTrac CEO and President Dan DeCloss</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;I have been on both sides of the fence, the specialist who comes in and does the assessment, produces that 300-page report and then comes back a year later to find that some of the critical issues had not been addressed at all.  And not because the organization didn’t want to but because it was lost in that report,&#8221; PlexTrac CEO and President Dan DeCloss said. &#8220;These are some of the most critical findings for an entity from a risk perspective. By making it collaborative, both red and blue teams are united on the same goal we all share, to protect the network and assets.&#8221;</p>
<p>With an extensive <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ddecloss/">career</a> in security that included time as a penetration tester for Veracode and the Mayo Clinic, as well as senior information security advisor for Anthem, among other roles, DeCloss has quite a bit of first-hand experience that led him to found PlexTrac. Specifically, he believes that it&#8217;s important to break down the wall between offense-focused red teams and defense-centric blue teams.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2138045" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2138045" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2138045" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png" alt="" width="1024" height="658" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png 2560w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png?resize=300,193 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png?resize=768,494 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png?resize=680,437 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png?resize=1536,988 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png?resize=2048,1317 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2138045" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> PlexTrac</p></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&#8220;Historically there has been more of the cloak and dagger relationship but those walls are breaking down&#8211; and rightfully so, there isn’t that much of that mentality today&#8211; people recognize they are on the same mission whether they are internal security team or an external team,&#8221; he said. &#8220;With the PlexTrac platform the red and blue teams have a better view into the other teams’ tactics and techniques &#8211; and it makes the whole process into an educational exercise for everyone.&#8221;</p>
<p>At its core, PlexTrac makes it easier for security teams to produce their reports &#8212; and hence free them up to actually focus on &#8216;real&#8217; security work. To do so, the service integrates with most of the popular scanners like Qualys, and Veracode, but also tools like ServiceNow and Jira in order to help teams coordinate their workflows. All the data flows into real-time reports that then help teams monitor their security posture. The service also features a dedicated tool, WriteupsDB, for managing reusable write-ups to help teams deliver consistent reports for a variety of audiences.</p>
<p>&#8220;Current tools for planning, executing, and reporting on security testing workflows are either nonexistent (manual reporting, spreadsheets, documents, etc…) or exist as largely incomplete features of legacy platforms,&#8221; Madrona&#8217;s S. Somasegar and Chris Picardo write in today&#8217;s announcement. &#8220;The pain point for security teams is real and PlexTrac is able to streamline their workflows, save time, and greatly improve output quality. These teams are on the leading edge of attempting to find and exploit vulnerabilities (red teams) and defend and/or eliminate threats (blue teams).&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-end-end-radius: initial; border-end-start-radius: initial; border-inline: initial; border-start-end-radius: initial; border-start-start-radius: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/plextrac-raises-10m-series-a-round-for-its-collaboration-centric-security-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138039</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Instagram&#8217;s new test lets you choose if you want to hide &#8216;Likes,&#8217; Facebook test to follow</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/instagrams-new-test-lets-you-choose-if-you-want-to-hide-likes-facebook-test-to-follow/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/instagrams-new-test-lets-you-choose-if-you-want-to-hide-likes-facebook-test-to-follow/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influencers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[like button]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[likes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Instagram today will begin a new test around hiding Like counts on users&#8217; posts, following its experiments in this area which first began in 2019. This time, however, Instagram is not enabling or disabling the feature for more users. Instead, it will begin to explore a new option where users get to decide what works [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Instagram today will begin a new test around hiding Like counts on users&#8217; posts, following its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/14/instagram-private-like-counts/">experiments</a> in this area which first began in 2019. This time, however, Instagram is not enabling or disabling the feature for more users. Instead, it will begin to explore a new option where users get to decide what works best for them &#8212; either choosing to see the Like counts on others&#8217; posts, or not. Users will also be able to turn off Like counts on their own posts, if they choose. Facebook additionally confirmed it will begin to test a similar experience on its own social network.</p>
<p>Instagram says tests involving Like counts were deprioritized after Covid-19 hit, as the company focused on other efforts needed to support its community. (Except for that <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-likes-hidden-024925910.html">brief period this March</a> where Instagram accidentally hid Likes for more users due to a bug.)</p>
<p>The company says it&#8217;s now revisiting the feedback it collected from users during the tests and found a wide range of opinions. Originally, the idea with hiding Like counts was about reducing the anxiety and embarrassment that surrounds posting content on the social network. That is, people would stress over whether their post would receive enough Likes to be deemed &#8220;popular.&#8221; This problem was particularly difficult for Instagram&#8217;s younger users, who care much more about what their peers think &#8212; so much so that they would <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/teens-curate-their-instagram-accounts-2016-5">take down posts that didn&#8217;t receive &#8220;enough&#8221; Likes</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In addition, the removal of Likes helped reduce the sort of herd mentality that drives people to like things that are already popular, as opposed to judging the content for themselves.</p>
<p>But during tests, not everyone agreed the removal of Likes was a change for the better. Some people said they still wanted to see Like counts so they could track what was trending and popular. The argument for keeping Likes was more prevalent among the <a href="https://www.refinery29.com/en-gb/2019/05/232006/instagram-hidden-like-count-influencers-creators">influencer community</a>, where creators <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/08/instagram-hide-likes-us/">used the metric</a> in order to communicate their value to partners, like brands and advertisers. Here, lower engagement rates on posts could directly translate to lower earnings for these creators.</p>
<p>Both arguments for and against Likes have merit, which is why Instagram&#8217;s latest test will put the choice back into users&#8217; own hands.</p>
<p>This new test will be enabled for a small percentage of users globally on Instagram, the company says.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve been opted in, you&#8217;ll find a new option to hide the Likes from within the app&#8217;s Settings. This will prevent you from seeing Likes on other people&#8217;s posts as you scroll through your Instagram Feed. As a creator, you&#8217;ll be able to hide Likes on a per-post basis via the three-dot &#8220;&#8230;&#8221; menu at the top. Even if Likes are disabled publicly, creators are still able to view Like counts and other engagements through analytics, just as they did before.</p>
<p>The tests on Facebook, which has also been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/02/facebook-hidden-likes/">testing Like count removals</a> for some time, have not yet begun. Facebook tells TechCrunch those will roll out in the weeks ahead.</p>
<p>Making Like counts an choice may initially seem like it could help to address everyone&#8217;s needs. But in reality, if the wider influencer community chooses to continue to use Likes as a currency that translates to popularity and job opportunities, then other users will continue to do the same.</p>
<p>Ultimately, communities themselves have to decide what sort of tone they want to set, preferably from the outset &#8212; before you&#8217;ve attracted millions of users who will be angry when you later try to change course.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s also a question as to whether social media users are really hungry for an &#8220;Like-free&#8221; safer space. For years we&#8217;ve seen startups focused on building an &#8220;anti-Instagram&#8221; of sorts, where they drop one or more Instagram features, like algorithmic feeds, Likes and other engagement mechanisms, such as <a href="https://www.minutiae-app.org/">Minutiae</a>, <a href="https://vero.co/">Vero</a>, <a href="https://www.dayflashapp.com/">Dayflash</a>, <a href="http://hipstamatic.com/oggl/">Oggl</a>, and now, newcomers like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/21/spark-capital-decides-to-sever-all-ties-with-david-dobriks-dispo-app-weeks-after-leading-investment/">troubled Dispo</a>, or under-the-radar <a href="https://www.instagram.com/herd.app/?hl=en">Herd</a>. But Instagram has yet to fail because of an anti-Instagram rival. If anything is a threat, it&#8217;s a new type of social network entirely, like TikTok &#8211;where it should be noted getting Likes and engagements is still very important for creator success.</p>
<p>Instagram didn&#8217;t say how long the new tests would last or if and when the features would roll out more broadly.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re testing this on Instagram to start, but we&#8217;re also exploring a similar experience for Facebook. We will learn from this new small test and have more to share soon,&#8221; a Facebook company spokesperson said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/instagrams-new-test-lets-you-choose-if-you-want-to-hide-likes-facebook-test-to-follow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138307</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Large-scale CO2 removal startup Carbo Culture raises $6.2M Seed led by True Ventures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/large-scale-co2-removal-startup-carbo-culture-raises-6-2m-seed-led-by-true-ventures/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/large-scale-co2-removal-startup-carbo-culture-raises-6-2m-seed-led-by-true-ventures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 14:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138354</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Carbo Culture — a startup that has scaled an industrial process to create large-scale CO2 removal using woody waste from agriculture and forests — has raised $6.2 million in seed a financing round led by Silicon Valley VC True Ventures. The round was co-led by European early-stage venture firm Cherry Ventures. Swiss climate investor Übermorgen Ventures [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://carboculture.com">Carbo Culture</a> — a startup that has scaled an industrial process to create large-scale CO2 removal using woody waste from agriculture and forests — has raised $6.2 million in seed a financing round led by Silicon Valley VC True Ventures. The round was co-led by European early-stage venture firm Cherry Ventures. Swiss climate investor Übermorgen Ventures also participated. The new funding will be used to grow the team, product development, and build one of Europe&#8217;s largest carbon removal facilities. </p>
<p>Energy from the sun creates photosynthesis in plants and turning CO2 into plant matter that eventually decomposes and re-enters the atmosphere. Carbo Culture mimics this existing process, it just makes it much, much faster.</p>
<p>Carbo Culture describes its process as an “ultra-rapid conversion” where woody residues are turned into functional biocarbons at an extremely high temperature. The process then “locks” the carbon into a sort of charcoal that won’t degrade for 1,000 years.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carbo-culture2547.jpg" alt="" width="819" height="546" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2138365" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carbo-culture2547.jpg 819w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carbo-culture2547.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carbo-culture2547.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carbo-culture2547.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carbo-culture2547.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carbo-culture2547.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 819px) 100vw, 819px" /></p>
<p>As well as removing CO2 from the wood, the whole process of generating this biocarbon from the wood waste generates renewable heat which can literally be used to heat homes or drive turbines to make electricity. The left-over biocarbon product can be used in biomaterials or environmental engineering, and could replace other polluting materials or be used in gasifiers, reducing greenhouse-gas emissions or perhaps in agriculture to improve soil health.</p>
<p>Thus, the startup sells two things as its main products: carbon removal credits and the biocarbon itself.</p>
<p>CEO and co-founder Henrietta Moon said in a statement: “We have this race against time to sequester billions of tons of carbon, and we’re not fully even utilizing one of the largest drawdown mechanisms in the world, the natural carbon cycle. At Carbo Culture, we’re tapping into it with a breakthrough technology that uses the already drawn down carbon in biomass and converts it for storing away for millennia.”</p>
<p>Toni Schneider, partner at True Ventures said: &#8220;We believe venture capital should play a greater role in creating a sustainable planet, and Carbo Culture has so many of the right ingredients for solving one of earth’s most pressing problems. Demand for carbon capture is rising, and meeting this demand will require some reimagining. Henrietta and her team have the experience, technology, passion, and palpable vision to turn this big idea into a truly impactful one.”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carboncycle.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="478" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2138367" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carboncycle.jpg 1093w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carboncycle.jpg?resize=150,70 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carboncycle.jpg?resize=300,140 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carboncycle.jpg?resize=768,358 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carboncycle.jpg?resize=680,317 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carboncycle.jpg?resize=50,23 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>Sophia Bendz, partner at Cherry Ventures said: &#8220;Carbo Culture has created one of the most effective negative emissions technologies through their patented technology and I can&#8217;t wait for them to scale up and remove significant amounts of carbon from the atmosphere. Henrietta, Chris, and their entire team have the inventiveness, technological know-how, and grit required to both scale and, most importantly, succeed in tackling the larger climate issues affecting us all. We are beyond excited to partner with this brilliant team and support them on their mission to remove CO2.”</p>
<p>Carbo Culture&#8217;s competitors include Climeworks (raised $145m) Carbon Engineering, CarbFix, Charm Industrial and CarboFex.</p>
<p>CTO and co-founder Christopher Carstens said: “We’ve managed to scale up production capacity 8x in volume, develop the system further, and begin testing with private labs, customers and universities. We’re now running our shipping container scale pilot plant in California’s Central Valley, where we can process over 200lbs of biomass per hour.&#8221;</p>
<p>The co-founders met at Singularity University’s 3-month program in 2013 at the Nasa Ames Research Center.</p>
<p>The underlying technology has been licensed from the Univerity of Hawaii, but, say the founders, it has been independently verified by <a href="http://Puro.earth">Puro.earth</a>, a carbon-negative marketplace</p>
<p>The startup recently announced its first large-scale (pre) purchase of <a href="https://www.southpole.com/news/could-humble-biochar-be-the-next-big-carbon-removal-solution-to-fight-climate-change">carbon removal credits by South Pole</a>.</p>
<p>Moon added: “Our cost to remove carbon is currently at above $600 per CO2 ton, and we’re aiming to drive the cost to $400 by the end of next year, and looking to achieve $200 by 2024. We&#8217;re building a scaled-up facility in the next 18 months, and it will become one of Europe’s largest carbon removal facilities.”</p>
<p>Carbo Culture’s additional investors include Albert Wenger, Gold&amp;Green Foods Founder Maija Itkonen, VP at Geltor Alex Patist,  alongside existing investors such as David Helgason, Moaffak Ahmed, Lifeline Ventures, and Paul and Dan Bragiel.</p>
<p>The vast majority of scientists believe the planet must curb CO2 emissions and remove carbon from the atmosphere at the same time, reaching net-zero emissions by 2050m for global warming to stay below 2C and void catastrophic climate effects.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/large-scale-co2-removal-startup-carbo-culture-raises-6-2m-seed-led-by-true-ventures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138354</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ireland opens GDPR investigation into Facebook leak</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/ireland-opens-gdpr-investigation-into-facebook-leak/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/ireland-opens-gdpr-investigation-into-facebook-leak/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 14:17:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2136465</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook&#8217;s lead data supervisor in the European Union has opened an investigation into whether the tech giant violated data protection rules vis-a-vis the leak of data reported earlier this month. Here&#8217;s the Irish Data Protection Commission&#8217;s statement: “The Data Protection Commission (DPC) today launched an own-volition inquiry pursuant to section 110 of the Data Protection [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook&#8217;s lead data supervisor in the European Union has opened an investigation into whether the tech giant violated data protection rules vis-a-vis the leak of data reported <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/answers-being-sought-from-facebook-over-latest-data-breach/">earlier this month</a>.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the Irish Data Protection Commission&#8217;s statement:</p>
<blockquote><p>“The Data Protection Commission (DPC) today launched an own-volition inquiry pursuant to section 110 of the Data Protection Act 2018 in relation to multiple international media reports, which highlighted that a collated dataset of Facebook user personal data had been made available on the internet. This dataset was reported to contain personal data relating to approximately 533 million Facebook users worldwide. The DPC engaged with Facebook Ireland in relation to this reported issue, raising queries in relation to GDPR compliance to which Facebook Ireland furnished a number of responses.</p>
<p>The DPC, having considered the information provided by Facebook Ireland regarding this matter to date, is of the opinion that one or more provisions of the GDPR and/or the Data Protection Act 2018 may have been, and/or are being, infringed in relation to Facebook Users’ personal data.</p>
<p>Accordingly, the Commission considers it appropriate to determine whether Facebook Ireland has complied with its obligations, as data controller, in connection with the processing of personal data of its users by means of the Facebook Search, Facebook Messenger Contact Importer and Instagram Contact Importer features of its service, or whether any provision(s) of the GDPR and/or the Data Protection Act 2018 have been, and/or are being, infringed by Facebook in this respect.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Facebook has been contacted for comment.<strong> Update</strong>: The company did not provide a statement but confirmed it&#8217;s in contact with regulators to answer their questions.</p>
<p>The move comes after the European Commission intervened to apply pressure on Ireland&#8217;s data protection commissioner. Justice commissioner, Didier Reynders, <a href="https://twitter.com/dreynders/status/1381663631981617163">tweeted</a> Monday that he had spoken with Helen Dixon about the Facebook data leak.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Commission continues to follow this case closely and is committed to supporting national authorities,&#8221; he added, going on to urge Facebook to &#8220;cooperate actively and swiftly to shed light on the identified issues&#8221;.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Today I spoke with Helen Dixon <a href="https://twitter.com/DPCIreland?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@DPCIreland</a> about the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FacebookLeak?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FacebookLeak</a>. The Commission continues to follow this case closely and is committed to supporting national authorities. We also call on <a href="https://twitter.com/Facebook?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Facebook</a> to cooperate actively and swiftly to shed light on the identified issues.</p>
<p>&mdash; Didier Reynders (@dreynders) <a href="https://twitter.com/dreynders/status/1381663631981617163?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 12, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>A spokeswoman for the Commission confirmed the virtual meeting between Reynders and Dixon, saying: &#8220;Dixon informed the Commissioner about the issues at stake and the different tracks of work to clarify the situation.</p>
<p>&#8220;They both urge Facebook to cooperate swiftly and to share the necessary information. It is crucial to shed light on this leak that has affected millions of European citizens.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;It is up to the Irish data protection authority to assess this case. The Commission remains available if support is needed. The situation will also have to be further analyzed for the future. Lessons should be learned,&#8221; she added.</p>
<p>The revelation that a vulnerability in Facebook&#8217;s platform enabled unidentified &#8216;malicious actors&#8217; to extract the personal data (including email addresses, mobile phone numbers and more) of more than 500 million Facebook accounts up until September 2019 &#8212; when Facebook claims it fixed the issue &#8212; only emerged in the wake of the data <a href="https://twitter.com/UnderTheBreach/status/1378314424239460352">being found</a> for free download on a hacker forum earlier this month.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">All 533,000,000 Facebook records were just leaked for free.</p>
<p>This means that if you have a Facebook account, it is extremely likely the phone number used for the account was leaked.</p>
<p>I have yet to see Facebook acknowledging this absolute negligence of your data. <a href="https://t.co/ysGCPZm5U3">https://t.co/ysGCPZm5U3</a> <a href="https://t.co/nM0Fu4GDY8">pic.twitter.com/nM0Fu4GDY8</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Alon Gal (Under the Breach) (@UnderTheBreach) <a href="https://twitter.com/UnderTheBreach/status/1378314424239460352?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 3, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Despite the European Union&#8217;s data protection framework (the GDPR) baking in a regime of data breach notifications &#8212; with the risk of hefty fines for compliance failure &#8212; Facebook did not inform its lead EU data supervisory when it found and fixed the issue. Ireland&#8217;s Data Protection Commission (DPC) was left to find out in the press, like everyone else.</p>
<p>Nor has Facebook individually informed the 533M+ users that their information was taken without their knowledge or consent, saying last week it has no plans to do so &#8212; despite the heightened risk for affected users of spam and phishing attacks.</p>
<p>Privacy experts have, meanwhile, been swift to point out that the company has still not faced any regulatory sanction under the GDPR &#8212; with a number of investigations ongoing into various Facebook businesses and practices and no decisions yet issued in those cases by Ireland&#8217;s DPC. (It has so far only issued one cross-border decision, fining<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/twitter-fined-550k-over-a-data-breach-in-irelands-first-major-gdpr-decision/"> Twitter</a> around $550k in December over a breach it disclosed back in 2019.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VFNN7Oh6QO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/facebooks-tardy-disclosure-of-breach-timing-raises-gdpr-compliance-questions/">Facebook&#8217;s tardy disclosure of breach timing raises GDPR compliance questions</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook&#8217;s tardy disclosure of breach timing raises GDPR compliance questions&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/facebooks-tardy-disclosure-of-breach-timing-raises-gdpr-compliance-questions/embed/#?secret=VFNN7Oh6QO" data-secret="VFNN7Oh6QO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Last month the European Parliament adopted a <a href="https://www.europarl.europa.eu/doceo/document/TA-9-2021-0111_EN.html">resolution</a> on the implementation of the GDPR which expressed &#8220;great concern&#8221; over the functioning of the mechanism &#8212; raising particular concern over the Irish data protection authority by writing that it &#8220;generally closes most cases with a settlement instead of a sanction and that cases referred to Ireland in 2018 have not even reached the stage of a draft decision pursuant to Article 60(3) of the GDPR&#8221;.</p>
<p>The latest Facebook data scandal further amps up the pressure on the DPC &#8212; providing further succour to critics of the GDPR who argue the regulation is unworkable under the current foot-dragging enforcement structure, given the major bottlenecks in Ireland (and Luxembourg) where many tech giants choose to locate regional HQ.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">After the <a href="https://twitter.com/EP_Justice?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@EP_Justice</a> and other EU DPAs raised concerns, the Irish Parliament is now also planning to look into the work of <a href="https://twitter.com/DPCIreland?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@DPCIreland</a> in a hearing on April 27th. </p>
<p>Glad to see pro-active steps to debate how <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GDPR?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GDPR</a> can be effectively enforced in all EU member states! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f601.png" alt="😁" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f44d.png" alt="👍" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/2mDaFOwEiR">https://t.co/2mDaFOwEiR</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Max Schrems <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f1ea-1f1fa.png" alt="🇪🇺" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@maxschrems) <a href="https://twitter.com/maxschrems/status/1380794291988148230?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 10, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>On Thursday Reynders made his concern over Ireland&#8217;s response to the Facebook data leak public, <a href="https://twitter.com/dreynders/status/1380182173739847681">tweeting</a> to say the Commission had been in contact with the DPC.</p>
<p>He does have reason to be personally concerned. Earlier last week <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/eu-leaders-facebook-data-leak-cybersecurity-didier-reynders/">Politico</a> reported that Reynders&#8217; own digits had been among the cache of leaked data, along with those of the Luxembourg prime minister Xavier Bettel &#8212; and &#8220;dozens of EU officials&#8221;. However the problem of weak GDPR enforcement affects everyone across the bloc &#8212; some 446M people whose rights are not being uniformly and vigorously upheld.</p>
<p>&#8220;A strong enforcement of GDPR is of key importance,&#8221; Reynders also remarked on Twitter, urging Facebook to &#8220;fully cooperate with Irish authorities&#8221;.</p>
<p>Last week <a href="https://www.gpdp.it/web/guest/home/docweb/-/docweb-display/docweb/9572143">Italy&#8217;s data protection commission</a> also called on Facebook to immediately offer a service for Italian users to check whether they had been affected by the breach. But Facebook made no public acknowledgment or response to the call. Under the GDPR&#8217;s one-stop-shop mechanism the tech giant can limit its regulatory exposure by direct dealing only with its lead EU data supervisor in Ireland.</p>
<p>A two-year Commission review of how the data protection regime is functioning, which reported <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/">last summer</a>, already drew attention to problems with patchy enforcement. A lack of progress on unblocking GDPR bottlenecks is thus a growing problem for the Commission &#8212; which is in the midst of proposing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">a package</a> of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/europe-sets-out-the-rules-of-the-road-for-its-data-reuse-plan/">additional</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/europe-sets-out-plan-to-boost-data-reuse-and-regulate-high-risk-ais/">digital regulations</a>. That makes the enforcement point a very pressing one as EU lawmakers are being asked how <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/eu-plan-for-risk-based-ai-rules-to-set-fines-as-high-as-4-of-global-turnover-per-leaked-draft/">new digital rules</a> will be upheld if existing ones keep being trampled on?</p>
<p>It&#8217;s certainly notable that the EU&#8217;s executive has proposed a different, centralized enforcement structure for<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/"> incoming pan-EU legislation</a> targeted at digital services and tech giants. Albeit, getting agreement from all the EU&#8217;s institutions and elected representatives on how to reshape platform oversight looks challenging.</p>
<p>And in the meanwhile the data leaks continue: <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/qj8dj5/facebook-phone-number-data-breach-telegram-bot">Motherboard</a> reported Friday on another alarming leak of Facebook data it found being made accessible via a bot on the Telegram messaging platform that gives out the names and phone numbers of users who have liked a Facebook page (in exchange for a fee unless the page has had less than 100 likes).</p>
<p>The publication said this data appears to be separate to the 533M+ scraped dataset &#8212; after it ran checks against the larger dataset via the breach advice site, <a href="https://haveibeenpwned.com">haveibeenpwned</a>. It also asked Alon Gal, the person who discovered the aforementioned leaked Facebook dataset being offered for free download online, to compare data obtained via the bot and he did not find any matches.</p>
<p>We contacted Facebook about the source of this leaked data and will update this report with any response.</p>
<p>In his <a href="https://twitter.com/dreynders/status/1380182173739847681">tweet</a> about the 500M+ Facebook data leak last week, Reynders made reference to the Europe Data Protection Board (EDPB), a steering body comprised of representatives from Member State data protection agencies which works to ensure a consistent application of the GDPR.</p>
<p>However the body does not lead on GDPR enforcement &#8212; so it&#8217;s not clear why he would invoke it. Optics is one possibility, if he was trying to encourage a perception that the EU has vigorous and uniform enforcement structures where people&#8217;s data is concerned.</p>
<p>&#8220;Under the GDPR, enforcement and the investigation of potential violations lies with the national supervisory authorities. The EDPB does not have investigative powers per se and is not involved in investigations at the national level. As such, the EDPB cannot comment on the processing activities of specific companies,&#8221; an EDPB spokeswoman told us when we enquired about Reynders&#8217; remarks.</p>
<p>But she also noted the Commission attends plenary meetings of the EDPB &#8212; adding it&#8217;s possible there will be an exchange of views among members about the Facebook leak case in the future, as attending supervisory authorities &#8220;regularly exchange information on cases at the national level&#8221;.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EWVMCgFXv4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/answers-being-sought-from-facebook-over-latest-data-breach/">Answers being sought from Facebook over latest data breach</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Answers being sought from Facebook over latest data breach&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/answers-being-sought-from-facebook-over-latest-data-breach/embed/#?secret=EWVMCgFXv4" data-secret="EWVMCgFXv4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MPBRuNV5Yo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/europe-sets-out-plan-to-boost-data-reuse-and-regulate-high-risk-ais/">Europe sets out plan to boost data reuse and regulate &#8216;high risk&#8217; AIs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe sets out plan to boost data reuse and regulate &#8216;high risk&#8217; AIs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/europe-sets-out-plan-to-boost-data-reuse-and-regulate-high-risk-ais/embed/#?secret=MPBRuNV5Yo" data-secret="MPBRuNV5Yo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/ireland-opens-gdpr-investigation-into-facebook-leak/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2136465</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sunday raises $24 million seed round to build a fast restaurant checkout flow</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/sunday-raises-24-million-seed-round-to-build-a-fast-restaurant-checkout-flow/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/sunday-raises-24-million-seed-round-to-build-a-fast-restaurant-checkout-flow/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 14:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[checkout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sunday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138329</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Meet Sunday, a new startup that is going to attract some headlines as it has raised a $24 million seed round at a $140 million post-money valuation. That’s a lot of money for a company that started just a few months ago but that’s because Sunday wants to move quickly. Sunday is getting noticed because [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Meet <a href="http://sundayapp.com">Sunday</a>, a new startup that is going to attract some headlines as it has raised a $24 million seed round at a $140 million post-money valuation. That’s a lot of money for a company that started just a few months ago but that’s because Sunday wants to move quickly.</p>
<p>Sunday is getting noticed because it is founded by Victor Lugger, Tigrane Seydoux and Christine de Wendel —&nbsp;Lugger and Tigrane have been working together for several years as they’re the founders of <a href="https://www.bigmammagroup.com">Big Mamma</a>. Christine de Wendel headed <a href="https://www.zalando.fr">Zalando</a> in France before joining <a href="https://www.manomano.fr">ManoMano</a> as COO.</p>
<p>If you’re not familiar with Big Mamma, they’ve launched a dozen Italian restaurants in France. They also manage La Felicità, the food court at <a href="https://stationf.co">Station F</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Some people love those restaurants because the food is good and it’s relatively affordable. Some people hate it because Big Mamma is also particularly well known for its long queues and the fact that you always feel like you have to eat quickly for the next group. But it’s clear that it’s been working well for the past few years.</p>
<p>Managing Big Mamma during a pandemic led to Sunday, a spin-off company incorporated in the U.S. The restaurant company wanted to offer a way to check the menu and pay without touching anything. Like many restaurants, they put QR codes on the tables to that customers can scan them with their phones and load a website.</p>
<p>But Sunday didn’t stop at the menu as it also connects directly to the cash register system. Sunday supports Oracle Micros, Brinks, Tiller, Zelty, Revo, CashPad, etc. This way, clients can also scan the QR code, check their tab and pay directly from their phone. When they’re done eating, they can pay by themselves, stand up and leave.</p>
<p>After trying Sunday in Big Mamma restaurants, the company saw some encouraging results. 80% of customers chose to pay using the QR code, which means that restaurants saved 15 minutes in wait time on average leading to a better table turnover rate.</p>
<p>And this is key to understanding Sunday. It’s easy to sell a new payment system to a restaurant if it leads to more revenue. Popular restaurants that feel like they’re always looking for empty tables could greatly benefit from Sunday.</p>
<p>It also opens up some new possibilities. For instance, guests can split the bill directly at the table —&nbsp;everyone loads up Sunday and pay. Sunday is based on QR codes right now, but the company isn’t attached to QR codes specifically. You could imagine loading your bill using RFID chips, a tablet, etc.</p>
<p>The vision is clear —&nbsp;Sunday wants to build the <a href="https://www.fast.co">Fast Checkout</a> of restaurants. The startup thinks online checkout is going to merge with offline, brick-and-mortar checkout.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lPOmIpmY1E"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/fast-raises-102m-as-the-online-checkout-wars-continue-to-attract-huge-investment/">Fast raises $102M as the online checkout wars continue to attract huge investment</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fast raises $102M as the online checkout wars continue to attract huge investment&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/fast-raises-102m-as-the-online-checkout-wars-continue-to-attract-huge-investment/embed/#?secret=lPOmIpmY1E" data-secret="lPOmIpmY1E" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Sunday customers don’t pay any monthly subscription fee or setup fee. You only pay processing fees based on usage. And those fees tend to be lower than the card machine you’re currently using.</p>
<p>The startup’s seed round was led by Coatue with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/new-wave/">New Wave</a> participating. New Wave is a new European seed fund led by Pia d’Iribarne and backed by Xavier Niel. Multiple hospitality and tech investors are also participating.</p>
<p>The idea is to raise a lot of money, sign up a lot of restaurants and take over the market right now while there’s an opportunity during the pandemic. They have hired 40 people already and they’re signing deals with restaurants even though most of them are still closed in Europe.</p>
<p>Sunday isn’t a tech achievement <em>per se</em> — it’s an execution play. The company that can roll out this kind of checkout experience faster than the others is going to take over the market.</p>
<p>When restaurants are going to be open again, you may notice Sunday QR codes in France at Eataly, PNY, Paris Society, Eric Frechon, Groupe Bertrand’s restaurants (Burger King France, Hippopotamus, Groupe Flo…). Similarly, in the U.K., Sunday is partnering with JKS Group (Hoppers, Brigadiers, Gymkhana…), Corbin &amp; King and others. Sunday is also talking with companies in the U.S. and Spain.</p>
<p>Overall, there are more than a thousand restaurants currently adopting Sunday.</p>
<p>“We follow the same model as the one we used when launching restaurants with Big Mamma. Seven years ago, we invested three times more than the others to compress fixed costs and deliver a better product,” Sunday co-founder and CEO Victor Lugger told me.</p>
<p>The startup already has an ambitious product roadmap. Eventually, you could imagine having your own Sunday account that remembers your past bills, tracks your allergies, saves your favorite payment method, etc. Once again, it’ll come down to execution.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/sunday-raises-24-million-seed-round-to-build-a-fast-restaurant-checkout-flow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138329</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why expensive workout gear is actually cheap</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/why-expensive-workout-gear-is-actually-cheap/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/why-expensive-workout-gear-is-actually-cheap/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 14:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ec-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tonal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2137925</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. For this week&#8217;s deep dive Natasha and Alex wanted to dig into the Tonal EC-1, a huge document spread across a number of posts. Our goals were pretty simple: To better understand Tonal&#8217;s journey, and also to get into the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/e1f4a3f0-993b-4ead-9d02-67bc029cbd38?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/equity/id1215439780">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>For this week&#8217;s deep dive <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> and<a href="https://twitter.com/alex"> Alex</a> wanted to dig into the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1/">Tonal EC-1</a>, a huge document spread across a number of posts. Our goals were pretty simple: To better understand Tonal&#8217;s journey, and also to get into the mind of its author.</p>
<p>So we corralled <a href="https://twitter.com/JPManga">JP Mangalindan</a> into firing up his computer, microphone, and recording software for a chat. Here&#8217;s what we covered:</p>
<ul>
<li>What is Tonal, why is it interesting, and why did JP spend so much time learning about the company?</li>
<li>What did he have to leave out of the final report?</li>
<li>His views on fitness gear, and the Peloton effect more broadly</li>
<li>What was it like to write something so gosh darn long?</li>
</ul>
<p>The Tonal EC-1 comprises four main articles representing about 10,600 words and a reading time of about 43 minutes:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1-origin/">How a homegrown experiment became one of the fastest-growing companies in fitness tech </a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1-launch/">Millions of dollars and 3.5 years, and it all came down to this</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1-community/">Building online communities for fun, profit and product</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1-future/">Can Tonal become the luxury fitness market champion?</a></li>
</ul>
<p>As Natasha is currently &#8212; shh, it&#8217;s a secret &#8212; working on an EC-1 of her own, we had more than a usual amount of interest in the project. Use code Equity for a super sweet discount to access this story and all of our premium content.</p>
<p><em>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday morning at 7:00 a.m. PST, so subscribe to us on <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity">Overcast</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ">Spotify</a> and all the casts.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/why-expensive-workout-gear-is-actually-cheap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2137925</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ZeroAvia&#8217;s hydrogen fuel cell plane ambitions clouded by technical challenges</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/zeroavias-hydrogen-fuel-cell-plane-ambitions-clouded-by-technical-challenges/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/zeroavias-hydrogen-fuel-cell-plane-ambitions-clouded-by-technical-challenges/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 14:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hydrogen fuel cell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ZeroAvia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2137224</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When ZeroAvia’s six-seater aircraft completed an eight-minute flight from Cranfield Airfield in the U.K. last September, the company claimed a “major breakthrough” with the first-ever hydrogen fuel cell flight of a commercial-size aircraft. The modified Piper Malibu propeller plane was now the largest hydrogen-powered aircraft in the world, wrote the company. “While some experimental aircraft [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When ZeroAvia’s six-seater aircraft completed an eight-minute flight from Cranfield Airfield in the U.K. last September, the company claimed a “major breakthrough” with the first-ever hydrogen fuel cell flight of a commercial-size aircraft.</p>
<p>The modified Piper Malibu propeller plane was now the largest hydrogen-powered aircraft in the world, wrote the company. “While some experimental aircraft have flown using hydrogen fuel cells, the size of this aircraft shows that paying passengers could be boarding a truly zero-emission flight very soon,” added Val Miftakhov, ZeroAvia’s CEO.</p>
<p>But just how hydrogen-powered was it, and how close is ZeroAvia to flying passengers?</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“[In] this particular setup, not all the energy is coming from hydrogen,” said Miftakhov at a press conference directly afterwards. “There is a combination of the battery and hydrogen. But the way the battery and hydrogen fuel cells combine is such that we are able to fly purely on hydrogen.”</p>
<p>Miftakhov’s comments don’t quite tell the whole story. TechCrunch has learned that batteries provided the majority of the power required for the landmark flight, and will continue to feature heavily in ZeroAvia’s longer flights and new aircraft. And while the Malibu is technically still a passenger aircraft, ZeroAvia has had to replace four of the Malibu’s five passenger seats to accommodate bulky hydrogen tanks and other equipment.</p>
<p>In less than four years, ZeroAvia has gone from testing aircraft parts in pickup trucks to gaining the support of the U.K. government, and attracting investment from the likes of Jeff Bezos, Bill Gates and &#8212; just last week &#8212; British Airways. Now the question is whether it can continue on its claimed trajectory and truly transform aviation.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AKEDurp56z"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/zeroavias-hydrogen-powered-vision-for-aviation-nets-21-4-million-from-amazon-shell-and-bill-gates-backed-fund/">ZeroAvia&#8217;s hydrogen-powered vision for aviation nets $21.4 million from Amazon, Shell and Bill Gates-backed fund</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;ZeroAvia&#8217;s hydrogen-powered vision for aviation nets $21.4 million from Amazon, Shell and Bill Gates-backed fund&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/zeroavias-hydrogen-powered-vision-for-aviation-nets-21-4-million-from-amazon-shell-and-bill-gates-backed-fund/embed/#?secret=AKEDurp56z" data-secret="AKEDurp56z" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Take off</h2>
<p>Aviation currently accounts for 2.5% of humanity’s carbon emissions, and could grow to a quarter of the planet’s carbon budget by 2050. Biofuels can displace trees or food crops, while batteries are too heavy for anything more than short hops. Hydrogen, by contrast, can be generated using solar or wind power, and packs quite an energetic punch.</p>
<p>Fuel cells combine hydrogen with oxygen from the air in an efficient reaction that produces only electricity, heat and water. But that doesn’t mean you can simply drop a fuel cell into an existing aircraft. Fuel cells are heavy and complex, hydrogen requires bulky storage and there are many technical problems for startups to solve.</p>
<p>Russian-born Miftakhov arrived in America in 1997 to study for a physics doctorate. In 2012, after starting several companies and a stint at Google, he founded eMotorWerks (aka EMW) to produce electric conversion kits for the BMW 3-series.</p>
<p>But in 2013, BMW accused EMW of infringing its trademarks. Miftakhov agreed to change its logo and marketing materials, and to refrain from suggesting it was affiliated with the carmaker. He also found demand from BMW owners to be sluggish.</p>
<p>EMW then pivoted to providing chargers and a smart energy management platform. The new direction succeeded, and in 2017 Italian energy company Enel acquired EMW for a reported $150 million. But Miftakhov faced legal difficulties here, too.</p>
<p>George Betak, an EMW vice president, filed two civil lawsuits against Miftakhov alleging, among other things, that Miftakhov had left his name off patents, withheld money and even faked a document to make it seem as though Betak had assigned his intellectual property rights to EMW. Betak later withdrew some claims. The cases were quietly settled in the summer of 2020.</p>
<p>Weeks after selling EMW in 2017, Miftakhov incorporated ZeroAvia in San Carlos, California with the stated aim of “zero emissions aviation.” He was counting on the aviation industry being more interested in electrifying existing aircraft than BMW drivers had been.</p>
<h2>First step: batteries</h2>
<p>The first public outing for ZeroAvia was in October 2018 at Hollister Airport, 50 miles southwest of San Jose. Miftakhov mounted a propeller, an electric motor and batteries in the bed of a 1969 El Camino and took it up to 75 knots (85mph) on electric power.</p>
<p>In December, ZeroAvia bought a Piper PA-46 Matrix, a six-seater propeller plane very similar to the one it would later use in the U.K. Miftakhov’s team installed the motor and about 75kWh of lithium ion batteries &#8212; about the same as in an entry-level Tesla Model Y.</p>
<p>In February 2019, two days after the FAA granted it an experimental airworthiness certificate, the all-electric Piper took to the air. By mid-April, the Matrix was flying at its top speed and maximum power. It was ready to upgrade to hydrogen.</p>
<p>Import records show that ZeroAvia took delivery of a carbon fiber hydrogen tank from Germany in March. One company photo exists of the Matrix with a tank on its left wing, but ZeroAvia never released a video of it flying. Something had gone wrong.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="g3SJltAtsg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/corporate-sustainability-initiatives-may-open-doors-for-carbon-offset-startups/">Corporate sustainability initiatives may open doors for carbon offset startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Corporate sustainability initiatives may open doors for carbon offset startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/corporate-sustainability-initiatives-may-open-doors-for-carbon-offset-startups/embed/#?secret=g3SJltAtsg" data-secret="g3SJltAtsg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In July, ZeroAvia’s R&amp;D director posted a message on a forum for Piper owners: “We have damaged a wing of our Matrix, which we loved and pampered so much. The damage is so bad that it has to be replaced. Is anyone aware of [a suitable aircraft] that is going to be sold for parts any time soon?”</p>
<p>Miftakhov confirmed that the damage, not previously reported, occurred while ZeroAvia was reconfiguring the aircraft. That aircraft has not flown since, and ZeroAvia’s time as a Silicon Valley startup was coming to an end.</p>
<h2>Moving to the UK</h2>
<p>With ZeroAvia’s U.S. flight tests on hold, Miftakhov turned his attention to Britain, where Prime Minister Boris Johnson is banking on ”a new green industrial revolution.”</p>
<p>In September 2019, Aerospace Technology Institute (ATI), a U.K. government-supported company, funded a ZeroAvia-led project called HyFlyer, with £2.68 million ($3.3 million). Miftakhov committed to deliver a hydrogen fuel cell Piper that could fly more than 280 miles, within a year. Sharing the money would be Intelligent Energy, a fuel cell maker, and the European Marine Energy Centre (EMEC), which would provide hydrogen fueling tech.</p>
<p>“ZeroAvia had proved the concept of retrofitting an electric power train into an aircraft and instead of powering it by batteries, they wanted to power it with hydrogen,” said Richard Ainsworth, EMEC’s hydrogen manager at the time. “That was the whole purpose of the HyFlyer project.”</p>
<p>Gary Elliott, CEO of ATI, told TechCrunch that it was “really important” to ATI that ZeroAvia was using fuel cells rather than a battery system: “You need to spread your investment profile, so that you&#8217;ve got as much likelihood of success as you can.”</p>
<p>ZeroAvia set up in Cranfield and in February 2020, bought a six-seater Piper Malibu, similar to the damaged Matrix. Although the company fitted and flew it with batteries by June, the government still needed reassuring. “I&#8217;d be happy to catch up and think about what we can do to address the concerns that are nagging away at the ATI,” wrote an official, according to an email obtained by TechCrunch under a freedom of information request.</p>
<p>Intelligent Energy CTO Chris Dudfield told TechCrunch that the HyFlyer program went smoothly, but that his company is still years away from flying a larger fuel cell and that he never even saw ZeroAvia’s plane.</p>
<p>ZeroAvia’s partnership with Intelligent Energy might have helped it secure U.K. government funding but it wasn’t going to help power the Malibu. ZeroAvia needed to find a fuel cell supplier &#8212; fast.</p>
<h2>Second step: Fuel cell power</h2>
<p>In August, ZeroAvia wrote to government officials that “we are now gearing up for our first hydrogen-powered flight,” and invited the Secretary of State to attend.</p>
<p>Miftakhov said that ZeroAvia’s demonstration flight used a 250 kilowatt hydrogen fuel cell powertrain &#8212; the largest ever in an aircraft. This is comparable in power to the internal combustion engine that Pipers typically use, giving a healthy margin of safety for the most demanding phase of flight: take off.</p>
<p>ZeroAvia never identified its fuel cell supplier, nor detailed how much of the 250kW came from the fuel cell.</p>
<p>However, the day after the demonstration flight, a Swedish company called PowerCell issued a press release stating that one PowerCell MS-100 fuel cell was “an integral part of the powertrain.”</p>
<p>The MS-100 generates a maximum power of just 100kW, leaving 150kW unaccounted for. This means the majority of the power needed for take-off could only have come from the Piper’s batteries.</p>
<p>In an interview with TechCrunch, Miftakhov acknowledged that the Piper could not have taken off on fuel cell power alone in the September flight. He said the plane’s batteries were probably operational for the entire demonstration flight, and provided “some additional safety margin for the aircraft.”</p>
<p>Many fuel cell vehicles use batteries, either to smooth out fluctuations or to boost power briefly, although some manufacturers have been more transparent about their sources of power. One problem with relying on batteries for take off is that the plane then has to carry them for the whole flight.</p>
<p>“The fundamental challenge for hydrogen fuel cell aircraft is weight,” said Paul Eremenko, CEO of Universal Hydrogen, which is collaborating on a 2000kW fuel cell powertrain for another aircraft. &#8220;One of the ways we save weight is having a much smaller battery that is only used when a pilot guns the throttle.&#8221;</p>
<p>In February, ZeroAvia’s vice president, Sergey Kiselev, said that the company’s goal was to do without batteries altogether. “Batteries may be used to provide an extra oomph during take off,” he told the Royal Aeronautical Society. “But if you use different types of propulsion or energy storage on the aircraft, the certification effort will be significantly harder.”</p>
<p>Relying heavily on batteries allowed ZeroAvia to pull off its high-profile demonstration flight for investors and the U.K. government, but could ultimately delay its first flights with paying passengers.</p>
<h2>The problem of heat</h2>
<p>Without an exhaust to expel waste heat, fuel cells usually need a complex air or liquid cooling system to avoid overheating</p>
<p>“This is really the key intellectual property, and why it isn&#8217;t just a matter of buying a fuel cell, buying a motor and plugging them together,” says Eremenko.</p>
<p>The German Aerospace Center in Cologne has been flying hydrogen fuel cell aircraft since 2012. Its current aircraft, the custom-designed HY4, can carry four passengers up to 450 miles. Its 65kW fuel cell has a liquid cooling system that uses a large, aerodynamically optimized channel for the cooling air flow (see picture).</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2138430" style="width: 2666px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/HY4-65kw-system.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2138430" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2138430 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/HY4-65kw-system.jpg" alt="HY4 65kw system - zeroavia story" width="2656" height="1642" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/HY4-65kw-system.jpg 2656w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/HY4-65kw-system.jpg?resize=150,93 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/HY4-65kw-system.jpg?resize=300,185 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/HY4-65kw-system.jpg?resize=768,475 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/HY4-65kw-system.jpg?resize=680,420 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/HY4-65kw-system.jpg?resize=1536,950 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/HY4-65kw-system.jpg?resize=2048,1266 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/HY4-65kw-system.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2656px) 100vw, 2656px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2138430" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Credit: DLR</p></div></p>
<p>A similar 100kW system would generally need a cooling intake longer and a third bigger than the HY4’s. ZeroAvia’s Piper Malibu has no additional cooling intakes at all.</p>
<p>“The openings look way too small for the air speed at take off, and even for cruise speed,” said an aviation fuel cell engineer who asked not to be named because they deal with some of the same companies as ZeroAvia.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="15ggQf2HSN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/with-a-rumored-deal-for-joby-aviation-and-archers-spac-making-electric-aircraft-is-now-a-10-billion-business/">With a reported deal in the wings for Joby Aviation, electric aircraft soars to $10B business</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;With a reported deal in the wings for Joby Aviation, electric aircraft soars to $10B business&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/with-a-rumored-deal-for-joby-aviation-and-archers-spac-making-electric-aircraft-is-now-a-10-billion-business/embed/#?secret=15ggQf2HSN" data-secret="15ggQf2HSN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“We had to experiment with the location and configuration of the heat exchangers… but we did not have to redesign the shape of the aircraft to handle the heat,” countered Miftakhov. He claims the fuel cell was operating at between 85 and 100kW during the flight.</p>
<p>Following TechCrunch’s interview with ZeroAvia, the company released a video that appears to show the Piper’s fuel cell operating at up to 70kW during a ground test, which could equate to a higher power level when airborne.</p>
<p>Although this still needs to be demonstrated with long-distance flights, ZeroAvia may have solved the heat problem that has dogged other engineers for years.</p>
<h2>The next plane: bigger and better?</h2>
<p>In September, aviation minister Robert Courts was at Cranfield to watch the demonstration flight. “It&#8217;s one of the most historic moments in aviation for decades, and it is a huge triumph for ZeroAvia,” he said after the flight. Time magazine named ZeroAvia’s technology as one of the best inventions of 2020.</p>
<p>Even with the HyFlyer extended flight still to come, in December the U.K. government announced HyFlyer 2 &#8212; a £12.3 million ($16.3 million) project for ZeroAvia to deliver a 600kW hydrogen-electric powertrain for a larger aircraft. ZeroAvia agreed to have a 19-seat plane ready for commercialization in 2023. (It now says 2024.)</p>
<p>On the same day, ZeroAvia announced its $21.3 million Series A investor lineup, including Bill Gates’ Breakthrough Ventures Fund, Jeff Bezos’ Amazon Climate Pledge Fund, Ecosystem Integrity Fund, Horizon Ventures, Shell Ventures and Summa Equity. It announced another $23.4 million raise from these investors, without Amazon but with British Airways, in late March.</p>
<p>Miftakhov said the Malibu has now completed about a dozen test flights, with the long-distance U.K. flight pushed to later this year, due to COVID delays. And as for HyFlyer 2, Miftakhov now says that this will initially use half batteries and half fuel cells, although “the final certifiable flight configuration will get its full 600kW from the fuel cells.”</p>
<p>There is no doubt that ZeroAvia is facing a steep climb to deliver its promised aircraft, starting with the 19-seater, then a 50-seater plane in 2026, and a 100-seater by 2030.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ulGb44W83w"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/14/sec-to-investigate-short-sellers-claims-against-nikola-report-says/">SEC to investigate short-seller&#8217;s claims against Nikola, report says</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SEC to investigate short-seller&#8217;s claims against Nikola, report says&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/14/sec-to-investigate-short-sellers-claims-against-nikola-report-says/embed/#?secret=ulGb44W83w" data-secret="ulGb44W83w" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Hydrogen fuel cells still have a whiff of snake oil about them, thanks to Nikola, a startup that exaggerated a public demonstration of a hydrogen fuel cell truck, triggering a collapse in its share price and investigation by the SEC. The best option for ambitious start-ups like ZeroAvia is to be more transparent about their current technology and the challenges that lie ahead, even if that means tempering the expectations of investors and a public excited by the prospect of sustainable air travel.</p>
<p>“I desperately want ZeroAvia to be successful,” says Paul Eremenko. “I think we have very complementary business models and together we help complete the value chain to make hydrogen aviation happen.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/zeroavias-hydrogen-fuel-cell-plane-ambitions-clouded-by-technical-challenges/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2137224</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A quick peek inside Fontinalis, one of Detroit&#8217;s best-known young venture firms</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/a-quick-peek-inside-fontinalis-one-of-detroits-best-known-young-venture-firms/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/a-quick-peek-inside-fontinalis-one-of-detroits-best-known-young-venture-firms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 13:27:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[additive manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bill Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dan Ratliff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[detroit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fontinalis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2123988</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fontinalis, the 12-year-old, Detroit-based early stage venture firm, is known for being among the very first investing outfits to focus squarely on mobility as an overarching theme. It wasn&#8217;t a surprising mandate, given that the outfit&#8217;s cofounders include Bill Ford, the great grandson of Henry Ford and the executive chairman of Ford Motor Company. Nevertheless, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://fontinalis.com/">Fontinalis</a>, the 12-year-old, Detroit-based early stage venture firm, is known for being among the very first investing outfits to focus squarely on mobility as an overarching theme. It wasn&#8217;t a surprising mandate, given that the outfit&#8217;s cofounders include Bill Ford, the great grandson of Henry Ford and the executive chairman of Ford Motor Company.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the firm has used its ties to the traditional automotive industry to effectively compete against, and invest alongside, many Silicon Valley venture firms in the intervening years, creating an interesting portfolio along the way. It had stakes in Postmates, acquired in an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/uber-officially-completes-postmates-acquisition/">all-stock deal</a> by Uber, and in Lyft, for example. It also backed the self-driving startup nuTonomy, which sold to auto supplier Delphi Automotive in 2017 for $450 million. Some of its newer bets include <a href="https://gatik.ai/">Gatik</a>, a startup developing an autonomous vehicle stack for B2B short-haul logistics; <a href="https://www.robust.ai/">Robust.AI</a>, a startup at work on an industrial-grade cognitive platform for robots; and <a href="https://www.helm.ai/">Helm.ai</a>, a maker of driverless car AI.</p>
<p>To get a better sense of what make a deal attractive to Fontinalis, as well as to understand how a venture firm in Detroit ensures that it&#8217;s top of mind for the founders it most wants to work with, we talked recently with Dan Ratliff, an investor with Fontinalis who joined the firm nearly seven years ago. Our chat has been edited lightly for length.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/tag/detroit"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2136381" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="141" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg?resize=150,21 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg?resize=300,41 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg?resize=768,106 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg?resize=680,94 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg?resize=1536,211 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg?resize=2048,282 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg?resize=50,7 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p><strong>TC: Are you a native of Detroit?</strong></p>
<p>DR: I am a native Michigander. I grew up in the metro region; I went to Michigan State. I&#8217;ve been here my entire life, except for a year spent in Nashville for grad school, and when I graduated, I moved straight downtown [in Detroit].</p>
<p><strong>TC: From where does the name Fontinalis come?</strong></p>
<p>DR: It&#8217;s a Latin name and the name of an outside nature preserve club where Bill [Ford] cultivated a lot of his thoughts on conservation and spent a lot of his youth fly fishing. He also joked that there was no way this name was taken.</p>
<p><strong>TC: How much of the firm&#8217;s funding is from Ford Motor Co.?</strong></p>
<p>DR: Fontinalis is very much separate by design. We wanted to be independent and not a strategic VC or Bill&#8217;s family office, so from day one, we went to outside LPs and we pulled in 20 to 30 LPs in our first fund, including high-net worth [individuals], family offices, and some institutions. Ford wasn&#8217;t even an LP. The company has since come on, but not in a majority position. We also now have a handful of corporate investors, including an OEM that hasn&#8217;t been announced yet, and insurance companies. And we have family offices with ties to mobility and the transportation industry and which have a keen interest in how mobility evolves and impacts their businesses. We&#8217;ve raised $260 million to date across our funds.</p>
<p><strong>TC: That&#8217;s a surprisingly conservative amount in the current market. On the coasts, obviously, we&#8217;re seeing a money grab like no other.</strong></p>
<p>DR: We see this as multi-decade opportunity, but there is a bit of a chicken-and-egg problem in the Midwest. There&#8217;s not as [ample] a base of angel investors. There are a handful of venture funds but not like on the coasts, where you have a lot of founders or people who&#8217;ve been part of companies where they&#8217;ve made a lot of money and understand the risk-reward profile. Here, [people are] more conservative; they might have made their wealth in more traditional, versus high-growth startup-type, industries.</p>
<p>I do think with Duo Security selling to Cisco [for $2.35 billion in 2018] and StockX&#8217;s awesome rise, we&#8217;re developing the right tailwinds to set up an ecosystem, but it requires a lot of different things, including people who are used to being at high-growth companies and are willing to take risks [in the form of equity grants and less] salary.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Fontinalis has a wide range of bets, including on a cognitive platform for robots. What&#8217;s the through-line?</strong></p>
<p>DR: The mission of the firm at a high level is to invest in companies and tech that impact the efficient movement of people and goods. Automotive is a component, but so are supply chains and logistics and AI and big data and their impact. So we&#8217;ll invest in all modes of transportation &#8212; road, rail, bike, air. We also invest in vertical technologies like cybersecurity and additive manufacturing.</p>
<p><strong>TC: These are mostly seed and Series A checks?</strong></p>
<p>DR: We invest in the A and B range, as well as in seed-stage startups and later-stage investments. We view ourselves as bringing the same value that a strategic investor might bring without necessarily the strings that might be attached because we work with a lot of the other corporate VCs and mobility-focused VCs, and we try to see if we can help on the [business development] side to get the startup in front of the right person at the right companies.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Is there any special emphasis on trying to fund startups in Detroit and the broader Midwest?</strong></p>
<p>DR: Our mandate is not geographic specific. We have investments on both coasts, in Northeast Boston, in Tennessee [where Fontinalis&#8217;s portfolio company, FreightWaves, the market forecasting and analytics platform is based]. We have deals in Switzerland and Israel. We do look globally; we&#8217;re more concerned with making sure we can add value.</p>
<p><strong>TC: One of Fontinalis&#8217;s other founding partners, Chris Cheever, is in Boston. Has the firm ever considered relocating outside of Detroit?</strong></p>
<p>DR: No, two of our founding partners are based here. A lot of companies we&#8217;ve funded are coming, too, because of the infrastructure here on the manufacturing side and things like the Michigan Mobility Center and we can both facilitate a lot of those introductions as well as be a permanent &#8216;man on the ground&#8217; for companies that aren&#8217;t based here.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Does Detroit have the professional services businesses in place to accommodate startups?</strong></p>
<p>DR: In the last five years, we&#8217;ve seen a number of law firms [that work with startups] plant flags in Ann Arbor, and it&#8217;s encouraging to see.</p>
<p>Also, from a business standpoint, you have the University of Michigan&#8217;s Research Corridor and the automotive industry and OEM suppliers and access to mechanical and electrical engineers whose skill sets are as strong and competitive as anywhere in the country. Over the past five years, too, there has been a huge emphasis, including by city and state policymakers, [to strengthen Michigan&#8217;s positioning] including through the Office of Future Mobility and Electrification and Detroit&#8217;s economic development arm, which is bringing startups into the city. There are a lot of resources going in on the back of what you&#8217;ve seen on the real estate side and all that [billionaire investor] Dan Gilbert has done [for the city], including buying up skyscrapers and making them Class A office space and putting them back on the market.</p>
<p><strong>TC: I had the opportunity to talk with Dan about the quality of life there and he&#8217;s obviously a big proponent. </strong></p>
<p>DR: Michigan and Detroit are super unique. The suburbs feature really strong school systems, and living in Detroit proper is awesome. It feels like a startup of its own, with new restaurants opening up and new construction and people everywhere on patios, even while Detroit maintains its historic feel, with many buildings that are 100 years old. You also have the Great Lakes and skiing and the outdoors. You can draw comparisons to other startup hotbeds, but there are definite diamond-in-the-rough aspects to being in Michigan.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Anecdotally, does it feel like people who grew up there are staying, rather than heading off in other directions?</strong></p>
<p>DR: When I was an undergrad, 75% of people said, &#8216;I&#8217;m going to Chicago or New York.&#8217; That has changed. Now people are moving to downtown Detroit. There&#8217;s high-end real estate, a walkability aspect, and if you&#8217;re a sports or music fan, the access you have to things like that is unrivaled. You don&#8217;t have to plan anything because there are 10 different things to choose from on a Friday night, from theaters to stadiums to art galleries. There are a lot of things pulling in different types of people.</p>
<p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/tag/detroit"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2136381" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="141" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg?resize=150,21 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg?resize=300,41 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg?resize=768,106 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg?resize=680,94 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg?resize=1536,211 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg?resize=2048,282 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/detroit-footer-banner-2.jpg?resize=50,7 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/a-quick-peek-inside-fontinalis-one-of-detroits-best-known-young-venture-firms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2123988</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>EU plan for risk-based AI rules to set fines as high as 4% of global turnover, per leaked draft</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/eu-plan-for-risk-based-ai-rules-to-set-fines-as-high-as-4-of-global-turnover-per-leaked-draft/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/eu-plan-for-risk-based-ai-rules-to-set-fines-as-high-as-4-of-global-turnover-per-leaked-draft/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 13:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[behavioral advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Data Protection Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facial recognition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138236</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[European Union lawmakers who are drawing up rules for applying artificial intelligence are considering fines of up to 4% of global annual turnover (or €20M, if greater) for a set of prohibited use-cases, according to a leaked draft of the AI regulation &#8212; reported earlier by Politico &#8212; that&#8217;s expected to be officially unveiled next [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">European Union lawmakers who are drawing up rules for applying artificial intelligence are considering fines of up to 4% of global annual turnover (or €20M, if greater) for a set of prohibited use-cases, according to a <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ZaBPsfor_aHKNeeyXxk9uJfTru747EOn/view">leaked draft</a> of the AI regulation &#8212; reported earlier by <a href="https://pro.politico.eu/news/134201">Politico</a> &#8212; that&#8217;s expected to be officially unveiled next week.</p>
<p>The plan to regulate AI has been on the cards for a while. Back in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/europe-sets-out-plan-to-boost-data-reuse-and-regulate-high-risk-ais/">February 2020</a> the European Commission published a white paper, sketching plans for regulating so-called &#8220;high risk&#8221; applications of artificial intelligence.</p>
<p>At the time EU lawmakers were toying with a sectoral focus &#8212; envisaging certain sectors like energy and recruitment as vectors for risk. However that approach appears to have been rethought, per the leaked draft &#8212; which does not limit discussion of AI risk to particular industries or sectors.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Instead, the focus is on compliance requirements for high risk AI applications, wherever they may occur (weapons/military uses are specifically excluded, however, as such use-cases fall outside the EU treaties). Although it&#8217;s not abundantly clear from this draft exactly how &#8216;high risk&#8217; will be defined.</p>
<p>The overarching goal for the Commission here is to boost public trust in AI, via a system of compliance checks and balances steeped in &#8220;EU values&#8221; in order to encourage uptake of so-called &#8220;trustworthy&#8221; and &#8220;human-centric&#8221; AI. So even makers of AI applications not considered to be &#8216;high risk&#8217; will still be encouraged to adopt codes of conduct &#8212; &#8220;to foster the voluntary application of the mandatory requirements applicable to high-risk AI systems&#8221;, as the Commission puts it.</p>
<p>Another chunk of the regulation deals with measures to support AI development in the bloc &#8212; pushing Member States to establish regulatory sandboxing schemes in which startups and SMEs can be proritized for support to develop and test AI systems before bringing them to market.</p>
<p>Competent authorities &#8220;shall be empowered to exercise their discretionary powers and levers of proportionality in relation to artificial intelligence projects of entities participating the sandbox, while fully preserving authorities’ supervisory and corrective powers,&#8221; the draft notes.</p>
<h2>What&#8217;s high risk AI?</h2>
<p>Under the planned rules, those intending to apply artificial intelligence will need to determine whether a particular use-case is &#8216;high risk&#8217; and thus whether they need to conduct a mandatory, pre-market compliance assessment or not.</p>
<p>&#8220;The classification of an AI system as high-risk should be based on its intended purpose &#8212; which should refer to the use for which an AI system is intended, including the specific context and conditions of use and &#8212; and be determined in two steps by considering whether it may cause certain harms and, if so, the severity of the possible harm and the probability of occurrence,&#8221; runs one recital in the draft.</p>
<p>&#8220;A classification of an AI system as high-risk for the purpose of this Regulation may not necessarily mean that the system as such or the product as a whole would necessarily be considered as ‘high-risk’ under the criteria of the sectoral legislation,&#8221; the text also specifies.</p>
<p>Examples of &#8220;harms&#8221; associated with high-risk AI systems are listed in the draft as including: &#8220;the injury or death of a person, damage of property, systemic adverse impacts for society at large, significant disruptions to the provision of essential services for the ordinary conduct of critical economic and societal activities, adverse impact on financial, educational or professional opportunities of persons, adverse impact on the access to public services and any form of public assistance, and adverse impact on [European] fundamental rights.&#8221;</p>
<p>Several examples of high risk applications are also discussed &#8212; including recruitment systems; systems that provide access to educational or vocational training institutions; emergency service dispatch systems; creditworthiness assessment; systems involved in determining taxpayer-funded benefits allocation; decision-making systems applied around the prevention, detection and prosecution of crime; and decision-making systems used to assist judges.</p>
<p>So long as compliance requirements &#8212; such as establishing a risk management system and carrying out post-market surveillance, including via a quality management system &#8212; are met such systems would not be barred from the EU market under the legislative plan.</p>
<p>Other requirements include in the area of security and that the AI achieves consistency of accuracy in performance &#8212; with a stipulation to report to &#8220;any serious incidents or any malfunctioning of the AI system which constitutes a breach of obligations&#8221; to an oversight authority no later than 15 days after becoming aware of it.</p>
<p>&#8220;High-risk AI systems may be placed on the Union market or otherwise put into service subject to compliance with mandatory requirements,&#8221; the text notes.</p>
<p>&#8220;Mandatory requirements concerning high-risk AI systems placed or otherwise put into service on the Union market should be complied with taking into account the intended purpose of the AI system and according to the risk management system to be established by the provider.</p>
<p>&#8220;Among other things, risk control management measures identified by the provider should be based on due consideration of the effects and possible interactions resulting from the combined application of the mandatory requirements and take into account the generally acknowledged state of the art, also including as reflected in relevant harmonised standards or common specifications.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hX8dRFmbtU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/europe-sets-out-plan-to-boost-data-reuse-and-regulate-high-risk-ais/">Europe sets out plan to boost data reuse and regulate &#8216;high risk&#8217; AIs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe sets out plan to boost data reuse and regulate &#8216;high risk&#8217; AIs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/europe-sets-out-plan-to-boost-data-reuse-and-regulate-high-risk-ais/embed/#?secret=hX8dRFmbtU" data-secret="hX8dRFmbtU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Prohibited practices and biometrics</h2>
<p>Certain AI &#8220;practices&#8221; are listed as prohibited under Article 4 of the planned law, per this leaked draft &#8212; including (commercial) applications of mass surveillance systems and general purpose social scoring systems which could lead to discrimination.</p>
<p>AI systems that are designed to manipulate human behavior, decisions or opinions to a detrimental end (such as via dark pattern design UIs), are also listed as prohibited under Article 4; as are systems that use personal data to generate predictions in order to (detrimentally) target the vulnerabilities of persons or groups of people.</p>
<p>A casual reader might assume the regulation is proposing to ban, at a stroke, practices like behavioral advertising based on people tracking &#8212; aka the business models of companies like Facebook and Google. However that assumes adtech giants will accept that their tools have a detrimental impact on users.</p>
<p>On the contrary, their regulatory circumvention strategy is based on claiming the polar opposite; hence Facebook&#8217;s talk of &#8220;relevant&#8221; ads. So the text (as written) looks like it will be a recipe for (yet) more long-drawn out legal battles to try to make EU law stick vs the self-interested interpretations of tech giants.</p>
<p>The rational for the prohibited practices is summed up in an earlier recital of the draft &#8212; which states: &#8220;It should be acknowledged that artificial intelligence can enable new manipulative, addictive, social control and indiscriminate surveillance practices that are particularly harmful and should be prohibited as contravening the Union values of respect for human dignity, freedom, democracy, the rule of law and respect for human rights.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s notable that the Commission has avoided proposing a ban on the use of facial recognition in public places &#8212; as it had apparently been considering, per a leaked draft <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/17/eu-lawmakers-are-eyeing-risk-based-rules-for-ai-per-leaked-white-paper/">early last year</a>, before last year&#8217;s White Paper steered away from a ban.</p>
<p>In the leaked draft &#8220;remote biometric identification&#8221; in public places is singled out for &#8220;stricter conformity assessment procedures through the involvement of a notified body&#8221; &#8212; aka an &#8220;authorisation procedure that addresses the specific risks implied by the use of the technology&#8221; and includes a mandatory data protection impact assessment &#8212; vs most other applications of high risk AIs (which are allowed to meet requirements via self-assessment).</p>
<p>&#8220;Furthermore the authorising authority should consider in its assessment the likelihood and severity of harm caused by inaccuracies of a system used for a given purpose, in particular with regard to age, ethnicity, sex or disabilities,&#8221; runs the draft. &#8220;It should further consider the societal impact, considering in particular democratic and civic participation, as well as the methodology, necessity and proportionality for the inclusion of persons in the reference database.&#8221;</p>
<p>AI systems &#8220;that may primarily lead to adverse implications for personal safety&#8221; are also required to undergo this higher bar of regulatory involvement as part of the compliance process.</p>
<p>The envisaged system of conformity assessments for all high risk AIs is ongoing, with the draft noting: &#8220;It is appropriate that an AI system undergoes a new conformity assessment whenever a change occurs which may affect the compliance of the system with this Regulation or when the intended purpose of the system changes.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;For AI systems which continue to ‘learn’ after being placed on the market or put into service (i.e. they automatically adapt how functions are carried out) changes to the algorithm and performance which have not been pre-determined and assessed at the moment of the conformity assessment shall result in a new conformity<br />
assessment of the AI system,&#8221; it adds.</p>
<p>The carrot for compliant businesses is to get to display a &#8216;CE&#8217; mark to help them win the trust of users and friction-free access across the bloc&#8217;s single market.</p>
<p>&#8220;High-risk AI systems should bear the CE marking to indicate their conformity with this Regulation so that they can move freely within the Union,&#8221; the text notes, adding that: &#8220;Member States should not create obstacles to the placing on the market or putting into service of AI systems that comply with the requirements laid down in this Regulation.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1HMCJtLL53"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/17/eu-lawmakers-are-eyeing-risk-based-rules-for-ai-per-leaked-white-paper/">EU lawmakers are eyeing risk-based rules for AI, per leaked white paper</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;EU lawmakers are eyeing risk-based rules for AI, per leaked white paper&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/17/eu-lawmakers-are-eyeing-risk-based-rules-for-ai-per-leaked-white-paper/embed/#?secret=1HMCJtLL53" data-secret="1HMCJtLL53" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Transparency for bots and deepfakes</h2>
<p>As well as seeking to outlaw some practices and establish a system of pan-EU rules for bringing &#8216;high risk&#8217; AI systems to market safely &#8212; with providers expected to make (mostly self) assessments and fulfil compliance obligations (such as around the quality of the data-sets used to train the model; record-keeping/documentation; human oversight; transparency; accuracy) prior to launching such a product into the market and conduct ongoing post-market surveillance &#8212; the proposed regulation seeks shrink the risk of AI being used to trick people.</p>
<p>It does this by suggesting &#8220;harmonised transparency rules&#8221; for AI systems intended to interact with natural persons (aka voice AIs/chat bots etc); and for AI systems used to generate or manipulate image, audio or video content (aka deepfakes).</p>
<p>&#8220;Certain AI systems intended to interact with natural persons or to generate content may pose specific risks of impersonation or deception irrespective of whether they qualify as high-risk or not. In certain circumstances, the use of these systems should therefore be subject to specific transparency obligations without prejudice to the requirements and obligations for high-risk AI systems,&#8221; runs the text.</p>
<p>&#8220;In particular, natural persons should be notified that they are interacting with an AI system, unless this is obvious from the circumstances and the context of use. Moreover, users, who use an AI system to generate or manipulate image, audio or video content that appreciably resembles existing persons, places or events and would falsely appear to a reasonable person to be authentic, should disclose that the content has been artificially created or manipulated by labelling the artificial intelligence output accordingly and disclosing its artificial origin.</p>
<p>&#8220;This labelling obligation should not apply where the use of such content is necessary for the purposes of safeguarding public security or for the exercise of a legitimate right or freedom of a person such as for satire, parody or freedom of arts and sciences and subject to appropriate safeguards for the rights and freedoms of third parties.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9mvQw7R5E8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/10/eu-lawmakers-say-its-time-to-go-further-on-tackling-disinformation/">EU lawmakers say it&#8217;s time to go further on tackling disinformation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;EU lawmakers say it&#8217;s time to go further on tackling disinformation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/10/eu-lawmakers-say-its-time-to-go-further-on-tackling-disinformation/embed/#?secret=9mvQw7R5E8" data-secret="9mvQw7R5E8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>What about enforcement?</h2>
<p>While the proposed AI regime hasn&#8217;t yet been officially unveiled by the Commission &#8212; so details could still change before next week &#8212; a major question mark looms over how a whole new layer of compliance around specific applications of (often complex) artificial intelligence can be effectively oversee and any violations enforced, especially given ongoing weaknesses in the enforcement of the EU&#8217;s data protection regime (which begun being applied back in 2018).</p>
<p>So while providers of high risk AIs are required to take responsibility for putting their system/s on the market (and therefore for compliance with all the various stipulations, which also include registering high risk AI systems in an EU database the Commission intends to maintain), the proposal leaves enforcement in the hands of Member States &#8212; who will be responsible for designating one or more national competent authorities to supervise application of the oversight regime.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve seen how this story plays out with the General Data Protection Regulation. The Commission itself has conceded <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/">GDPR enforcement is not consistently or vigorously applied</a> across the bloc &#8212; so a major question is how these fledgling AI rules will avoid the same <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/lack-of-big-tech-gdpr-decisions-looms-large-in-eu-watchdogs-annual-report/">forum-shopping fate</a>?</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iz0LhBXHTC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/">GDPR&#8217;s two-year review flags lack of &#8216;vigorous&#8217; enforcement</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GDPR&#8217;s two-year review flags lack of &#8216;vigorous&#8217; enforcement&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/embed/#?secret=iz0LhBXHTC" data-secret="iz0LhBXHTC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;Member States should take all necessary measures to ensure that the provisions of this Regulation are implemented, including by laying down effective, proportionate and dissuasive penalties for their infringement. For certain specific infringements, Member States should take into account the margins and criteria set out in this Regulation,&#8221; runs the draft.</p>
<p>The Commission does add a caveat &#8212; about potentially stepping in in the event that Member State enforcement doesn&#8217;t deliver. But there&#8217;s no near term prospect of a different approach to enforcement, suggesting the same old pitfalls will likely appear.</p>
<p>&#8220;Since the objective of this Regulation, namely creating the conditions for an ecosystem of trust regarding the placing on the market, putting into service and use of artificial intelligence in the Union, cannot be sufficiently achieved by the Member States and can rather, by reason of the scale or effects of the action, be better achieved at Union level, the Union may adopt measures, in accordance with the principle of subsidiarity as set out in Article 5 of the Treaty on European Union,&#8221; is the Commission&#8217;s back-stop for future enforcement failure.</p>
<p>The oversight plan for AI includes setting up a mirror entity akin to the GDPR&#8217;s European Data Protection Board &#8212; to be called the European Artificial Intelligence Board &#8212; which will similarly support application of the regulation by issuing relevant recommendations and opinions for EU lawmakers, such as around the list of prohibited AI practices and high-risk systems.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Rwe2lkFado"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/embed/#?secret=Rwe2lkFado" data-secret="Rwe2lkFado" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FCtcq1a402"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/europe-sets-out-the-rules-of-the-road-for-its-data-reuse-plan/">Europe sets out the rules of the road for its data reuse plan</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe sets out the rules of the road for its data reuse plan&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/europe-sets-out-the-rules-of-the-road-for-its-data-reuse-plan/embed/#?secret=FCtcq1a402" data-secret="FCtcq1a402" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/eu-plan-for-risk-based-ai-rules-to-set-fines-as-high-as-4-of-global-turnover-per-leaked-draft/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138236</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon’s Alexa earbuds return with a smaller design and wireless charging</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amazons-alexa-earbuds-return-with-a-smaller-design-and-wireless-charging/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amazons-alexa-earbuds-return-with-a-smaller-design-and-wireless-charging/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 13:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[echo buds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wireless earbuds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138085</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s been about a year and a half since Amazon released the first Echo Buds. I reviewed them when they arrived, and they were, I don’t know, fine, I guess. They were a bit on the cheap side, facing some stiff competition in the category and, honestly, the idea of wearing Alexa on my head [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It’s been about a year and a half since Amazon released the first Echo Buds. I reviewed them when they arrived, and they were, I don’t know, fine, I guess. They were a bit on the cheap side, facing some stiff competition in the category and, honestly, the idea of wearing Alexa on my head still isn’t super exciting to me.</p>
<p>But for a first attempt at the space, they weren’t bad. And now the company’s giving it a second go, with some tweaks to the original formula. Top of the list is a redesign that shrinks them 20% and makes them a bit lighter weight. The nozzle is smaller, which should make them more comfortable for longer periods, coupled with four ear tip sizes. The headphones are rated IPX4 for sweat and weather resistance.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2138091" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2138091" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2138091 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-Glacier-White-Case.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="1024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-Glacier-White-Case.jpg 5000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-Glacier-White-Case.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-Glacier-White-Case.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-Glacier-White-Case.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-Glacier-White-Case.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-Glacier-White-Case.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-Glacier-White-Case.jpg?resize=2048,2048 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-Glacier-White-Case.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-Glacier-White-Case.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-Glacier-White-Case.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-Glacier-White-Case.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-Glacier-White-Case.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2138091" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Amazon</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Amazon has moved on from the predecessor’s Bose noise canceling to its own proprietary tech, which it says can effectively double V1. There’s also an optional case that supports wireless charging via Qi, à la AirPods. The white case, in particular, looks&#8230;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/29/apples-airpods-pro-set-a-pricey-new-standard-for-earbuds/">rather familiar</a>.</p>
<p>That case runs an extra $20 over the $120 asking price for the USB-C case. Though Amazon’s running a limited-time deal to get the standard for $100 and the wireless charging version for $120. They’re also throwing in six months of Amazon Music Unlimited and Audible Plus. The new buds are also available in white. They’re up for preorder today and start shipping in May.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2138093" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2138093" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2138093" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-X-Ray.png" alt="" width="1024" height="1024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-X-Ray.png 5000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-X-Ray.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-X-Ray.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-X-Ray.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-X-Ray.png?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-X-Ray.png?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-X-Ray.png?resize=2048,2048 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-X-Ray.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-X-Ray.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-X-Ray.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-X-Ray.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Echo-Buds-X-Ray.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2138093" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits: </strong>Amazon</p></div></p>
<p>Future software updates will bring a new VIP Filter to the headphones. Introduced on the Echo Frames, the feature lets users filter notifications from select senders. In addition to Alexa, the buds can also be set to access Siri or Google Assistant.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eAF2a6qBTL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/29/amazon-echo-buds-review/">Amazon Echo Buds review</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon Echo Buds review&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/29/amazon-echo-buds-review/embed/#?secret=eAF2a6qBTL" data-secret="eAF2a6qBTL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amazons-alexa-earbuds-return-with-a-smaller-design-and-wireless-charging/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138085</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Plex raises $50M growth round to fuel ad-supported streaming, expansions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/plex-raises-50m-growth-round-to-fuel-ad-supported-streaming-expansions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/plex-raises-50m-growth-round-to-fuel-ad-supported-streaming-expansions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 13:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[avod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intercap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Streaming Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VOD]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2137923</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Streaming media software maker Plex announced today it has raised a $50 million growth equity round from existing investor Intercap ahead of its planned business expansion into rentals, purchases and subscription content. This is the first financing Plex has taken on since 2014 and is being partly used to purchase shares and options from Plex&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Streaming media software maker <a href="https://www.plex.tv/">Plex</a> announced today it has raised a $50 million growth equity round from existing investor Intercap ahead of its planned business expansion into rentals, purchases and subscription content. This is the first financing Plex has taken on since 2014 and is being partly used to purchase shares and options from Plex&#8217;s early seed investors and shareholders from prior acquisitions, and to give the company&#8217;s earliest employees a bit of liquidity. Of the $50 million raised, $15 million will be put to work as new growth capital.</p>
<p>The company declined to disclose its valuation as a result of the funding &#8212; technically Plex&#8217;s Series C &#8212; but says it resulted in a relatively low dilution for its existing investors who have stayed in, including Kleiner Perkins and Nexstar, for example. Meanwhile, some of its earliest investors were able to get a 10x return or greater on their shares.</p>
<p>As part of the round, Intercap chairman and CEO Jason Chapnik joined the board of directors as chairman, and Intercap president James Merkur also joined the board. Including this financing, Plex has raised more than $60 million.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>To date, Plex has been cautious about fundraising because, as Plex CEO Keith Valory says, &#8220;we really hadn&#8217;t had to.&#8221; That is, the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/29/plex-is-launching-its-own-ad-supported-video-service-starting-with-content-from-warner-bros-tv/">has been profitable</a> on its own.</p>
<p>But things have been changing at Plex in recent years. Though it has always catered to the home media enthusiast with its software for organizing movies, TV, music and photos on users&#8217; home networks, Plex more seriously began to go after the larger market of cord cutters with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/01/plex-becomes-a-low-cost-diy-streaming-tv-service/">its 2017 launch of a low-cost, DIY streaming TV service</a>. In the years since, it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/04/plex-launches-a-free-ad-supported-streaming-service-in-over-200-countries/">expanded into free, ad-supported streaming</a> and last year took on rivals like ViacomCBS-owned Pluto TV with its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/plex-launches-a-live-tv-service-with-over-80-free-channels-most-available-worldwide/">own launch of a live TV service</a>, also supported by ads.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wzrLGKbOe2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/07/plexs-secret-weapon-cross-media-integrations/">Plex&#8217;s secret weapon: cross-media integrations</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Plex&#8217;s secret weapon: cross-media integrations&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/07/plexs-secret-weapon-cross-media-integrations/embed/#?secret=wzrLGKbOe2" data-secret="wzrLGKbOe2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Today, Plex now offers more than 20,000 free on-demand movies and shows and over 150 free live TV channels in 193 countries, alongside access to other content, including personal media libraries, streaming music and podcasts.</p>
<p>As it expanded the types of services it offers, it also lowered the barriers to entry for Plex newcomers. Users now no longer have to sign up for an account to access the ad-supported video or <a href="https://www.plex.tv/watch-free-tv/">live linear streaming</a> service, which impacts Plex&#8217;s business model.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2137984" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2137984" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2137984" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-13-at-3.49.12-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="342" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-13-at-3.49.12-PM.jpg 3336w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-13-at-3.49.12-PM.jpg?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-13-at-3.49.12-PM.jpg?resize=300,151 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-13-at-3.49.12-PM.jpg?resize=768,386 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-13-at-3.49.12-PM.jpg?resize=680,342 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-13-at-3.49.12-PM.jpg?resize=1536,772 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-13-at-3.49.12-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1029 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-13-at-3.49.12-PM.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2137984" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Plex</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;That is much more tailored towards paid marketing &#8212; like getting integrated into the search capabilities for devices like Roku, Fire TV or Vizio, etc. But then, also, using [search engine marketing] and Facebook and other, even on-device paid marketing programs to get people to get in and start watching something,&#8221; says Valory. &#8220;We found that the kind of paid marketing and customer acquisition costs for that business is really efficient. We&#8217;ve been able to get profitable on that marketing investment really, really quickly,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p>That model is what prompted Plex to consider raising capital to grow this aspect of its business and expand in new areas, as well.</p>
<p>That included managing subscription content and offering rentals and purchases &#8212; something<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/07/media-streamer-plex-to-add-subscription-channels-rentals-and-more/"> Plex began to talk about last year</a> as part of its roadmap, saying they could potentially arrive in 2020. But then COVID hit, and though streaming itself grew &#8212; particularly ad-supported video in April through June or July &#8212; some Plex employees were hit harder than others by the pandemic. And Plex also needed more time to ready the infrastructure involved.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s now preparing to launch these efforts this year, perhaps initially with a video rental marketplace or a subscription aggregator. (Plex says it&#8217;s not sure which will get out of the gate first because both are being built simultaneously.)</p>
<p>With the subscription play, Plex isn&#8217;t looking just at selling subscriptions the way that say, Amazon or Apple do through Prime Video Channels or Apple TV Channels. It&#8217;s also considering deep linking technology to get users to their favorite streaming apps, including those from the big-name brands that otherwise wouldn&#8217;t want to be a part of someone else&#8217;s service. This could position Plex as a competitor to services like <a href="https://reelgood.com/">Reelgood</a>, which today allows users to track what they&#8217;re watching and get recommendations across all their streaming apps, not just within each individual app.</p>
<p>Plex&#8217;s video rental (and maybe purchases) marketplace, meanwhile, will be much like any other, offering users a chance to pay for content they couldn&#8217;t find a way to stream.</p>
<p>Both ideas fit in with Plex&#8217;s larger goal to become a one-stop shop for all your media needs.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve always had a fairly audacious mission. You shouldn&#8217;t have to go to 20 different apps to get the content you care about. You should be able to go to one place and we should be able to do all that for you,&#8221; notes Valory.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1920030" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1920030" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-1920030" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/plex-movies-and-tv-home.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/plex-movies-and-tv-home.jpg 5120w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/plex-movies-and-tv-home.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/plex-movies-and-tv-home.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/plex-movies-and-tv-home.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/plex-movies-and-tv-home.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/plex-movies-and-tv-home.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/plex-movies-and-tv-home.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/plex-movies-and-tv-home.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1920030" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Plex</p></div></p>
<p>To fuel its growth on both this front and for its ad-supported businesses, Plex plans to use the funds to expand its now 100-person team with investments in marketing and monetization teams, as well as on the development side.</p>
<p>&#8220;Certainly, there&#8217;s still way more work to do in terms of amplifying the efforts on our performance and growth marketing and engagement,&#8221; Valory says. &#8220;I mean, the business is growing super fast, so we&#8217;ve done a pretty good job, to date, of building out the muscles to get new users in the pipeline for the AVOD business. There&#8217;s still a ton of work to do there, but a lot of the muscles that we&#8217;re building there will help in terms of the top-of-funnel and increasing engagement for the whole product,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3lns6274zT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/plex-launches-a-live-tv-service-with-over-80-free-channels-most-available-worldwide/">Plex launches a live TV service with over 80 free channels, most available worldwide</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Plex launches a live TV service with over 80 free channels, most available worldwide&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/plex-launches-a-live-tv-service-with-over-80-free-channels-most-available-worldwide/embed/#?secret=3lns6274zT" data-secret="3lns6274zT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Intercap, which led Plex&#8217;s round, is in it for the long haul &#8212; citing in particular how the fragmentation happening now in the streaming landscape could ultimately be good for Plex&#8217;s own growth.</p>
<p>&#8220;Content providers, creators and consumers are all paying the price for the explosion of so many streaming media services and the industry needs a trusted way for the experience to be as enjoyable as possible,&#8221; says Chapnik. &#8220;Plex has always been at the forefront of solving new media challenges and we believe they are primed to solve this problem &#8212; they are the cable company of the future.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/plex-raises-50m-growth-round-to-fuel-ad-supported-streaming-expansions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2137923</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Upstack raises $50M for its platform and advisory to help businesses plan and buy for digital transformation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/upstack-raises-50m-for-its-platform-and-advisory-to-help-businesses-plan-and-buy-for-digital-transformation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/upstack-raises-50m-for-its-platform-and-advisory-to-help-businesses-plan-and-buy-for-digital-transformation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital transformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upstack]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138255</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Digital transformation has been one of the biggest catchphrases of the past year, with many an organization forced to reckon with aging IT, a lack of digital strategy, or simply the challenges of growth after being faced with newly-remote workforces, customers doing everything online and other tech demands. Now, a startup called Upstack that has [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Digital transformation has been one of the biggest catchphrases of the past year, with many an organization forced to reckon with aging IT, a lack of digital strategy, or simply the challenges of growth after being faced with newly-remote workforces, customers doing everything online and other tech demands.</p>
<p>Now, a startup called <a href="https://upstack.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Upstack</a> that has built a platform to help those businesses evaluate how to grapple with those next steps &#8212; including planning and costing out different options and scenarios, and then ultimately buying solutions &#8212; is announcing financing to do some growth of its own.</p>
<p>The New York startup has picked up funding of $50 million, money that it will be using to continue building out its platform and expanding its services business.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The funding is coming from <a href="https://www.berkshirepartners.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Berkshire Partners</a>, and it&#8217;s being described as an &#8220;initial investment&#8221;. The firm, which makes private equity and late-stage growth investments, typically puts between $100 million and $1 billion in its portfolio companies so this could end up as a bigger number, especially when you consider the size of the market that Upstack is tackling: the cloud and internet infrastructure brokerage industry generates annual revenues &#8220;in excess of $70 billion,&#8221; the company estimates.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re asking about the valuation, but PitchBook notes that the median valuation in its deals is around $211 million. Upstack had previously raised around $35 million.</p>
<p>Upstack today already provides tools to large enterprises, government organizations, and smaller businesses to compare offerings and plan out pricing for different scenarios covering a range of IT areas, including <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">private, p</span><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">ublic and hybrid cloud deployments; data center investments; network connectivity; business continuity and mobile services, and the plan is to bring in more categories to the mix, including unified communications and security.</span></p>
<p>Notably, Upstack itself is profitable and names a lot of customers that themselves are tech companies &#8212; they include Cisco, Accenture, cloud storage company Backblaze, Riverbed and Lumen &#8212; a mark of how digital transformation and planning for it are not necessarily a core competency even of digital businesses, but especially those that are not technology companies. It says it has helped complete over 3,700 IT projects across 1,000 engagements to date.</p>
<p>&#8220;Upstack was founded to bring enterprise-grade advisory services to businesses of all sizes,&#8221; said Christopher Trapp, founder and CEO, in a statement. &#8220;Berkshire&#8217;s expertise in the data center, connectivity and managed services sectors aligns well with our commitment to enabling and empowering a world-class ecosystem of technology solutions advisors with a platform that delivers higher value to their customers.&#8221;</p>
<p>The core of the Upstack&#8217;s proposition is a platform that system integrators, or advisors, plus end users themselves, can use to design and compare pricing for different services and solutions. This is an unsung but critical aspect of the ecosystem: We love to hear and write about all the interesting enterprise technology that is being developed, but the truth of the matter is that buying and using that tech is never just a simple click on a &#8220;buy&#8221; button.</p>
<p>Even for smaller organizations, buying tech can be a hugely time-consuming task. It involves evaluating different companies and what they have to offer &#8212; which can differ widely in the same category, and gets more complex when you start to compare different technological approaches to the same problem.</p>
<p>It also includes the task of designing solutions to fit one&#8217;s particular network. And finally, there are the calculations that need to be made to determine the real cost of services once implemented in an organization. It also gives users the ability to present their work, which also forms a critical part of the evaluating and decision-making process. When you think about all of this, it&#8217;s no wonder that so many organizations have opted to follow the &#8220;if it ain&#8217;t broke, don&#8217;t fix it&#8221; school of digital strategy.</p>
<p>As technology has evolved, the concept of digital transformation itself has become more complicated, making tools like Upstack&#8217;s more in demand both by companies and the people they hire to do this work for them. Upstack also employs a group of about 15 advisors &#8212; consultants &#8212; who also provide insight and guidance in the procurement process, and it seems some of the funding will also be used to invest in expanding that team.</p>
<p>(Incidentally, the model of balancing technology with human experts is one used by other enterprise startups that are built around the premise of helping businesses procure technology: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/30/enterprise-cybersecurity-startup-bluevoyant-raises-82-5m-at-a-430m-valuation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BlueVoyant</a>, a security startup that has built a platform to help businesses manage and use different security services, also retains advisors who are experts in that field.)</p>
<p>The advisors are part of the business model: Upstack&#8217;s customers can either pay Upstack a consulting fee to work with its advisors, or Upstack receives a commission from suppliers that a company ends up using, having evaluated and selected them via the Upstack platform.</p>
<p>The company competes with traditional systems integrators and consultants, but it seems that the fact that it has built a tech platform that some of its competitors also use is one reason why it&#8217;s caught the eye of investors, and also seen strong growth.</p>
<p>Indeed, when you consider the breadth of services that a company might use within their infrastructure &#8212; whether it&#8217;s software to run sales or marketing, or AI to run a recommendation for products on a site, or business intelligence or RPA &#8212; it will be interesting to see how and if Upstack considers deeper moves into these areas.</p>
<p>&#8220;Upstack has quickly become a leader in a large, rapidly growing and highly fragmented market,&#8221; said Josh Johnson, principal at Berkshire Partners, in a statement. “Our experience has reinforced the importance of the agent channel to enterprises designing and procuring digital infrastructure. Upstack&#8217;s platform accelerates this digital transformation by helping its advisors better serve their enterprise customers. We look forward to supporting Upstack&#8217;s continued growth through M&amp;A and further investment in the platform.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/upstack-raises-50m-for-its-platform-and-advisory-to-help-businesses-plan-and-buy-for-digital-transformation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138255</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Outschool is the newest edtech unicorn</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/outschool-series-c-unicorn/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/outschool-series-c-unicorn/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 13:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amir nathoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[early stage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundraising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Outschool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pandemic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[series C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unicorn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Outschool, a marketplace providing small-group, virtual after-school activities for children has raised a $75 million Series C led by Coatue and Tiger Global Management. TechCrunch first learned of the round from sources familiar with the transaction; the company confirmed the deal to TechCrunch later today. The new funding values Outschool’s at $1.3 billion, around 4 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://outschool.com/#abkn97lfgv">Outschool</a>, a marketplace providing small-group, virtual after-school activities for children has raised a $75 million Series C led by Coatue and Tiger Global Management. TechCrunch first learned of the round from sources familiar with the transaction; the company confirmed the deal to TechCrunch later today.</p>
<p>The new funding values Outschool’s at $1.3 billion, around 4 times higher than its roughly $320 million valuation <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/18/outschool-newly-profitable-raises-a-45m-series-b-for-virtual-small-group-classes/">set less than a year ago.</a></p>
<p>To date, Outschool has raised $130 million in venture capital to date, inclusive of its new round.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company’s valuation growth curve is steep for any startup, let alone an edtech concern that saw the majority of its growth during the pandemic. But while CEO and co-founder Amir Nathoo says his company’s new valuation is partially a reflection of today’s fundraising frenzy, he thinks revenue sustainability is a key factor in his company&#8217;s recent fundraise.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wZrfGDde1B"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/how-is-edtech-spending-its-extra-capital/">How is edtech spending its extra capital?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How is edtech spending its extra capital?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/how-is-edtech-spending-its-extra-capital/embed/#?secret=wZrfGDde1B" data-secret="wZrfGDde1B" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The new unicorn’s core product is after school classes for entertainment or supplemental studies, on an ongoing or one-off basis. As the company has grown, ongoing classes have grown from 10% of its business to 50% of its business, implying that the startup is generating more reliable revenue over time.</p>
<p>The change from one-off classes to enduring engagements could be good for the company and its students. On the former, recurring revenue is music to investor ears. On the latter, students need repetition to develop close relationships with a course and a group. Ongoing classes about debate or a weekly zombie dance class makes for a stickier experience.</p>
<p>Nathoo says everyone always asks what the most popular classes are, but said it continues to change since its main clientele &#8211; kids &#8211; have evolving favorites. One week it might be math, the other it might be minecraft and architecture.</p>
<p>Its changing revenue profile helped Outschool generate more than $100 million in bookings in 2020, compared to $6 million in 2019 and just $500,000 in 2017. Nathoo declined to share the company’s expectations for 2021 beyond “projecting to grow aggressively.”</p>
<p>Outschool reached brief positive cash flow last year as a result of massive growth in bookings, but Nathoo shared that that has since changed.</p>
<p>“My goal is to always stay within touching distance of profit,” he said. “But given the fast change in the market, it makes sense to invest aggressively into opportunities that will make sense in the long-term.”</p>
<h2>What’s next</h2>
<p>Nathoo expects to grow Outschool’s staff from 110 people to 200 by the end of the year, with a specific focus on international growth. In 2020, Outschool launched in Canada, New Zealand, Australia and the UK, so hiring will continue there and elsewhere.</p>
<p>On the flip side, Outschool isn&#8217;t  teachers at the same clip it was at the height of the pandemic in the United States. When the pandemic started, Outschool had 1,000 teachers on its platform. Within months, Outschool grew to host 10,000 teachers, a screening process that the founder explained was resource-heavy but vital. Outschool makes more money if teachers join the platform full-time: teachers pocket 70% of the price they set for classes, while Outschool gets the other 30% of income. But, Nathoo views the platform as more of a supplement to traditional education. Instead of scaling revenue by convincing teachers to come on full-time, the CEO is growing by adding more part-time teachers to the platform.</p>
<p>Similar to how Airbnb created a <a href="https://news.airbnb.com/update-on-the-airbnb-host-endowment-and-our-commitment-to-communities/">host endowment fund</a> to share its returns with the people who made its platform work, Outschool has dedicated 2% of its fundraise to creating a similar program to reward teachers on its platform in the event of liquidity.</p>
<p>One of Outschool&#8217;s most ambitious goals is, ironically, to go in school. While some startups have found success selling to schools amid the pandemic, district sales cycles and tight budgets continue to be a difficult challenge for scaling purposes. Still, the startup wants to make its way into students’ lives through contracts with schools and employers, which could help low income families access the platform. Nathoo says enterprise sales is a small part of its business, but the strategy began just last year as part of COVID-19 response. It is currently piloting its B2B offering with a number of schools.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LE0dqSlett"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/30/teachers-are-leaving-schools-will-they-come-to-startups-next/">Teachers are leaving schools. Will they come to startups next?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Teachers are leaving schools. Will they come to startups next?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/30/teachers-are-leaving-schools-will-they-come-to-startups-next/embed/#?secret=LE0dqSlett" data-secret="LE0dqSlett" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Outschool will also consider acquiring early-stage startups focused on direct-to-consumer learning in international markets. While no acquisitions have been made by the startup to date, consolidation in the edtech sector broadly is heating up.</p>
<p>Nathoo stressed that Outschool’s continued growth, even as schools reopen, has de-risked the company from post-pandemic worries.</p>
<p>“There’s going to be a big spike of in-person activities because everyone is going to want to do that at once,” he said. “But then we’re going to settle at some more even distribution because the future of education is hybrid.”</p>
<p>He added that Outschool’s ethos around online learning hasn’t changed since conception. The company has never seen opportunity in the for-credit, subject-matter digital education sector, and instead has focused more on supplemental ways to support students after school.</p>
<p>“That’s the piece of the education system that is underserved and that was missing,” he said. “The advantages of online learning will remain in the convenience, the cost, and the variety of what you can get that isn’t always available locally.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/outschool-series-c-unicorn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138183</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pale Blue Dot aims to be Europe&#8217;s premier early-stage climate investor and has $100 million to prove it</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/pale-blue-dot-aims-to-be-europes-premier-early-stage-climate-investor-and-has-100-million-to-prove-it/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/pale-blue-dot-aims-to-be-europes-premier-early-stage-climate-investor-and-has-100-million-to-prove-it/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 12:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[albert wenger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amsterdam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlueYard Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daniel ek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hampus Jakobsson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heidi Lindvall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joel Larsson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managing partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pale Blue Dot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supercell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TransferWise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Union Square Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zendesk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138261</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When Hampus Jakobsson, Heidi Lindvall, and Joel Larsson, all well-known players in the European venture ecosystem, began talking about their new firm Pale Blue Dot, they began by looking at the problems with venture capital. For the three entrepreneurs and investors, whose resumes included co-founding companies and accelerators like The Astonishing Tribe (Jakobsson) and Fast [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When Hampus Jakobsson, Heidi Lindvall, and Joel Larsson, all well-known players in the European venture ecosystem, began talking about their new firm <a href="https://www.paleblue.vc/#section-0">Pale Blue Dot</a>, they began by looking at the problems with venture capital.</p>
<p>For the three entrepreneurs and investors, whose resumes included co-founding companies and accelerators like The Astonishing Tribe (Jakobsson) and Fast Track Malmö (Lindvall and Larsson) and working as a venture partner at BlueYard Capital (Jakobsson again), the problems were clear.</p>
<p>Their first thesis was that all investment funds should be impact funds, and be taking into account ways to effect positive change; their second thesis was that since all funds should be impact funds, what would be their point of differentiation &#8212; that is, where could they provide the most impact.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The three young investors hit on climate change as the core mission and ran with it.</p>
<p>As it was closing on €53 million ($63.3 million) last year, the firm also made its first investments in <a href="https://www.phytoformlabs.com/">Phytoform</a>, a London headquartered company creating new crops using computational biology and synbio; <a href="https://www.usepatch.com/">Patch</a>, a San Francisco-based carbon-offsetting platform that finances both traditional and frontier “carbon sequestration” methods; and <a href="http://www.20tree.ai/">20tree.ai</a>, an Amsterdam-based startup, using machine learning and satellite data to understand trees to lower the risk of forest fires and power outages.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XlsrsctA8e"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/16/pale-blue-dot/">Pale Blue Dot is a new early-stage fund backing &#8216;climate-focused&#8217; startups in Europe</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pale Blue Dot is a new early-stage fund backing &#8216;climate-focused&#8217; startups in Europe&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/16/pale-blue-dot/embed/#?secret=XlsrsctA8e" data-secret="XlsrsctA8e" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now they&#8217;ve raised another €34 million and seven more investments on their path to doing between 30 and 35 deals. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These investments primarily focus on Europe and include <a href="https://www.veat.se/">Veat</a>, a European vegetarian prepared meal company; <a href="https://madefrom.io/">Madefrom</a>, a still-in-stealth company angling to make everyday products more sustainable; <a href="https://www.hackyourcloset.com/">HackYourCloset</a>, a clothing rental company leveraging fast fashion to avoid landfilling clothes; <a href="https://hier.in/">Hier</a>, a fresh food delivery service; <a href="https://www.cirplus.com/en">Cirplus</a>, a marketplace for recycled plastics trading; and <a href="https://www.overstory.ai/">Overstory</a>, which aims to prevent wildfires by giving utilities a view into vegetation around their assets. </span></p>
<p>The team expects to be primarily focused on Europe, with a few opportunistic investments in the U.S., and intends to invest in companies that are looking to change systems rather than directly affect consumer behavior. For instance, a Pale Blue Dot investment likely wouldn&#8217;t include e-commerce filters for more sustainable shopping, but potentially could include investments in sustainable consumer products companies.</p>
<p>The size of the firm&#8217;s commitments will range up to €1 million and will look to commit to a lot of investments. That&#8217;s by design, said Jakobsson. &#8220;Climate is so many different fields that we didn&#8217;t want to do 50% of the fund in food or 50% of the fund in materials,&#8221; he said. Also, the founders know their skillsets, which are primarily helping early stage entrepreneurs scale and making the right connections to other investors that can add value.</p>
<p>&#8220;In every deal we&#8217;ve gotten in co-investors that add particular, amazing, value while we still try to be the shepherds and managers and sherpas,&#8221; Jakobsson said. &#8220;We&#8217;re the ones that are going to protect the founder from the hell-rain of investor opinions.&#8221;</p>
<p>Another point of differentiation for the firm are its limited partners. Jakobsson said they rejected capital from oil companies in favor of founders and investors from the tech community that could add value. These include <a href="https://primamateria.com/">Prima Materia</a>, the investment vehicle for Spotify founder Daniel Ek; the founders of Supercell, Zendesk, TransferWise and DeliveryHero are also backing the firm. So too, is Albert Wenger, a managing partner at <a href="https://www.usv.com/people/albert-wenger/">Union Square Ventures</a>.</p>
<p>The goal, simply, is to be the best early stage climate fund in Europe.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We want to be <em>the</em> European climate fund,&#8221; Lindvall said. &#8220;This is where we can make most of the difference.&#8221; </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xgEdPse032"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/16/european-vc-firm-pale-blue-dot-plans-to-fund-40-planet-positive-startups/">European VC firm Pale Blue Dot plans to fund 40 &#8216;planet-positive&#8217; startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;European VC firm Pale Blue Dot plans to fund 40 &#8216;planet-positive&#8217; startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/16/european-vc-firm-pale-blue-dot-plans-to-fund-40-planet-positive-startups/embed/#?secret=xgEdPse032" data-secret="xgEdPse032" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/pale-blue-dot-aims-to-be-europes-premier-early-stage-climate-investor-and-has-100-million-to-prove-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138261</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
