<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 17:06:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>TikTok parent ByteDance joins patent troll protection group LOT Network</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/tiktok-parent-bytedance-joins-patent-troll-protection-group-lot-network/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/tiktok-parent-bytedance-joins-patent-troll-protection-group-lot-network/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 17:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbnb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IBM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instacart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intellectual property law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LOT Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monopoly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Patent Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patent troll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Triller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vw]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[LOT Network, the non-profit that helps businesses of all sizes and across industries defend themselves against patent trolls by creating a shared pool of patents to immunize themselves against them, today announced that TikTik parent ByteDance is joining its group. ByteDance has acquired its fair share of patents in recent years and is itself embroiled [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://lotnet.com/">LOT Network</a>, the non-profit that helps businesses of all sizes and across industries defend themselves against patent trolls by creating a shared pool of patents to immunize themselves against them, today announced that TikTik parent ByteDance is joining its group.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.bytedance.com/en/">ByteDance</a> has <a href="https://medium.com/@jacknwellis/bytedance-the-75b-social-media-unicorn-from-china-is-now-in-the-market-for-patents-909f25ef8182">acquired</a> its fair share of patents in recent years and is itself embroiled in a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/30/triller-sues-tiktok-over-patent-infringement/">patent fight</a> with its rival Triller. That&#8217;s not what joining the LOT Network is about, though. ByteDance is joining a group of companies here that includes the likes of IBM, the Coca-Cola Company, Cisco, Lyft, Microsoft, Oracle, Target, Tencent, Tesla, VW, Ford, Waymo, Xiaomi and Zelle. In total, the group now has over 1,300 members.</p>
<p>As LOT CEO Ken Seddon told me, the six-year-old group had a record year in 2020, with 574 companies joining it and bringing its set of immunized patents to over 3 million, including 14% of all patents issued in the U.S.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Among the core features of LOT, which only charges members who make more than $25 million in annual revenue, is that its members aren&#8217;t losing control over the patents they add to the pool. They can still buy and trade them as before, but if they decide to sell to what the industry calls a &#8216;patent assertion entity,&#8217; (PAE) that is, a patent troll, they automatically provide a free licence to that patent to every other member of the group. This essentially turns LOT into what Seddon calls a &#8216;flu shot &#8216; against patent trolls (and one that&#8217;s free for startups).</p>
<p>&#8220;The conclusion that people are waking up to is, is that we&#8217;re basically like a herd, we&#8217;re herd immunization, effectively,&#8221; Seddon said. &#8220;And every time a company joins, people realize that the community of non-members shrinks by one. It&#8217;s like those that don&#8217;t have the vaccination shrinks &#8212; and they are, &#8216;wait a minute, that makes me a higher risk of getting sued. I&#8217;m a bigger target.&#8217; And they&#8217;re like, &#8216;wait a minute, I don&#8217;t want to be the target.'&#8221;</p>
<p>ByteDance, he argues, is a good example for a company that can profit from membership in LOT. While you may think of patents as purely a sign of a company&#8217;s innovativeness, for corporate lawyers, they are also highly effective defense tools (that can be used aggressively as well, if needed). But it can take a small company years to build up a patent portfolio. But a fast-growing, successful company also becomes an obvious target for patent trolls.</p>
<p>&#8220;When you are a successful company, you naturally become a target,&#8221; Seddon said. &#8220;People become jealous and they become threatened by you. And they covet your money and your revenue and your success. One of the ways that companies can defend themselves and protect their innovation is through patents. Some companies grow so fast, they become so successful, that their revenue grows faster than they can grow their patent portfolio organically.&#8221; He cited Instacart, which <a href="https://newsroom.ibm.com/2021-02-09-Instacart-Acquires-Over-250-Patents-From-IBM">acquired 250 patents from IBM</a> earlier this month, and Airbnb, which was <a href="https://lawstreetmedia.com/tech/airbnb-sued-for-patent-infringement-by-ibm/">sued by IBM over patent infringement</a> in early 2020 (the companies <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/ibm-and-airbnb-announce-settlement-in-patent-litigation-301198325.html">settled in December</a>), as examples.</p>
<p>ByteDance, thanks to the success of TikTok, now finds itself in a situation where it, too, is likely to become a target of patent trolls. The company has started acquiring patents itself to grow its portfolio faster and now it is joining LOT to strengthen its protection there.</p>
<p>&#8220;[ByteDance] is being a visionary and trying to get ahead of the wave,&#8221; Seddon noted. &#8220;They are a successful global company that needs to develop a global IP strategy. Historically, PAEs were just a US problem, but now ByteDance has to worry about PAEs being an issue in China and Europe as well.  By joining <span class="il">LOT,</span> they protect themselves and their investments from over 3 million patents should they ever fall into the hands of a PAE.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lynn-wu-2b587b3a/?originalSubdomain=cn">Lynn Wu</a>, Director and Chief IP Counsel, Global IP and Digital Licensing Strategy at ByteDance, agrees. &#8220;Innovation is core to the culture at ByteDance, and we believe it’s important to protect our diverse technical and creative community,&#8221; she said in today&#8217;s announcement. &#8220;As champions for the fair use of IP, we encourage other companies to help us make the industry safer by joining <span class="il">LOT</span> Network. If we work together, we can protect the industry from exploitation and continue advancing innovation, which is key to the growth and success of the entire community.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PastedGraphic-4-1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2114811" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PastedGraphic-4-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="486" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PastedGraphic-4-1.png 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PastedGraphic-4-1.png?resize=150,71 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PastedGraphic-4-1.png?resize=300,143 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PastedGraphic-4-1.png?resize=768,365 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PastedGraphic-4-1.png?resize=680,323 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PastedGraphic-4-1.png?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>There&#8217;s another reason companies are so eager to join the group now, though, and that&#8217;s because these patent assertion entities, which had faded into the background a bit in the mid- to late-2010s, may be making a comeback. The core assumption here is a bit gloomy: many companies seem to assume we&#8217;re in for an economic downturn. If we hit a recession, a lot of patent holders will start looking at their patent portfolios and start selling off some their more valuable patents in order to stay afloat. Since beggars can&#8217;t be choosers, that often means they&#8217;ll sell to a patent troll if that troll is the highest bidder. Last year, a patent troll sued Uber <a href="https://www.law360.com/articles/1246739/alleged-troll-sues-uber-using-newly-offloaded-ibm-patents">using a patent sold by IBM</a>, for example (and IBM gets a bit of a bad rap for this, but, hey, it&#8217;s business).</p>
<p>That&#8217;s what happened after the last recession &#8212; though it typically takes a few years for the effect to be felt. Nothing in the patent world moves quickly.</p>
<p>Now, when LOT members sell to a troll, that troll can&#8217;t sue other LOT members over it. Take IBM, for example, which joined LOT last year.</p>
<p>&#8220;People give IBM a lot of grief and criticism for selling to PAEs, but at least IBM is giving everybody a chance to get a free license,&#8221; Seddon told me. &#8220;IBM joined LOT last year and what IBM is effectively doing is saying to everybody, &#8216;look, I joined LOT.&#8217; And they put all of their entire patent portfolio into LOT. And they&#8217;re saying to everybody, &#8216;look, I have the right to sell my patents to anybody I want, and I&#8217;m going to sell it to the highest bidder. And if I sell it to a patent troll and you don&#8217;t join LOT &#8212; and if you get sued by a troll, is that my fault or your fault? Because if you join LOT, you could have gotten a free license.'&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PfaGD7I1xP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/05/cloudflare-beat-a-patent-troll-what-now/">Cloudflare beat a patent troll. What now?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cloudflare beat a patent troll. What now?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/05/cloudflare-beat-a-patent-troll-what-now/embed/#?secret=PfaGD7I1xP" data-secret="PfaGD7I1xP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NQ8Qnowkz2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/04/microsoft-joins-the-lot-network-to-help-fight-patent-trolls/">Microsoft joins the LOT Network to help fight patent trolls</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Microsoft joins the LOT Network to help fight patent trolls&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/04/microsoft-joins-the-lot-network-to-help-fight-patent-trolls/embed/#?secret=NQ8Qnowkz2" data-secret="NQ8Qnowkz2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/tiktok-parent-bytedance-joins-patent-troll-protection-group-lot-network/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114795</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paying $115B for Stripe or $77B for Coinbase might be quite rational</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/paying-115b-for-stripe-or-77b-for-coinbase-might-be-quite-rational/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/paying-115b-for-stripe-or-77b-for-coinbase-might-be-quite-rational/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 16:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stripe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114116</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It's hard to overvalue a startup when the public market is willing to double its valuation the moment it starts to trade.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.coindesk.com/coinbase-valuation-nasdaq-private-market">CoinDesk reported</a> yesterday that crypto trading startup Coinbase is being valued at $77 billion on private exchanges. And <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jeffkauflin/2021/02/17/investors-are-now-valuing-stripe-at-115-billion/?sh=7b6c95824786">Forbes reported</a> that Stripe is being valued at $115 billion on secondary markets, where private shares can be bought and sold, albeit in a limited fashion.</p>
<p>I instantly wanted to write a piece headlined &#8220;Beware those super hot secondary market valuations,<em>&#8220;</em> but after a little digging, I cannot. It turns out that the public markets are so hot, there is historical precedent for seemingly aggressive secondary market transactions being conservative compared to later IPO valuations. And there is further precedent for private market transactions that are more conservative in price terms than venture-determined valuations also working out.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a>, or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>The hot equities market is making stock pickers out of many startup investors, regardless of whether they are leading priced rounds of buying shares on modern secondary markets.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995212 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>It&#8217;s hard to overvalue a startup when the public market is willing to double its valuation the moment it starts to trade.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s explore the new prices for Coinbase and Stripe by starting with a look at their dated private valuations, their new, reported secondary prices and where some companies that went public with notable secondary prices wound up trading today.</p>
<p>This will be fun! I promise!</p>
<h2>Overprice me, I dare you</h2>
<p>Coinbase was last valued by private-market money at <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/funding_round/coinbase-series-e--25f6f746">around $8 billion, per Crunchbase data</a> back in October of 2018. More recently we&#8217;ve seen secondary transactions that value the firm <a href="https://twitter.com/fintechfrank/status/1354562917744713734">at $50 billion</a>, other notes concerning <a href="https://fortune.com/2021/01/14/coinbase-valuation-75-billion-bitcoin-value-cryptocurrency/">a $75 billion possible valuation</a>, and even some enthusiastic chat from a former employee <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jeffkauflin/2021/01/29/coinbase-investors-say-it-could-hit-100-billion-valuation-when-it-goes-public/?sh=b05f8fa5b50f">that the company could be worth $100 billion</a>.</p>
<p>Its new $77 billion price tag might seem somewhat pedestrian in that mix, but recall that we&#8217;re largely discussing the valuations associated with Coinbase set by buyers not in the know; retail secondary buyers of shares in the cryptocurrency exchange are probably not its board members.</p>
<p>So, the <em>public</em> is, to some degree, repricing Coinbase. The question is whether those prices make any sense. Hold your answer, we have more work to do.</p>
<p>Stripe at $115 billion on secondary exchanges is perhaps bonkers, or perhaps nothing more than rationality. In its last round, a $600 million Series G that came in mid-2020, Stripe was valued at around $36 billion. And, it is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/28/what-to-make-of-stripes-possible-100-billion-valuation/">rumored to be raising capital at a $100 billion valuation</a>.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/paying-115b-for-stripe-or-77b-for-coinbase-might-be-quite-rational/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114116</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Census raises $16M Series A to help companies put their data warehouses to work</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/census-raises-16m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/census-raises-16m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 16:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clearbit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CTO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data warehouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dylan Field]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Figma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fivetran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitHub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[information]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LogDNA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Looker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NetSuite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Notion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parker conrad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warehouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zendesk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114464</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Census, a startup that helps businesses sync their customer data from their data warehouses to their various business tools like Salesforce and Marketo, today announced that it has raised a $16 million Series A round led by Sequoia Capital. Other participants in this round include Andreessen Horowitz, which led the company&#8217;s $4.3 million seed round [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.getcensus.com/">Census</a>, a startup that helps businesses sync their customer data from their data warehouses to their various business tools like Salesforce and Marketo, today announced that it has raised a $16 million Series A round led by Sequoia Capital. Other participants in this round include <span style="font-weight: 400;">Andreessen Horowitz, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/27/census-announces-4-3m-seed-to-put-product-info-in-cloud-data-warehouses-to-work/">led the company&#8217;s $4.3 million seed round last year</a>, as well as several notable angles, including Figma CEO Dylan Field, GitHub CTO Jason Warner, Notion COO Akshay Kothari and Rippling CEO Parker Conrad.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IXekrbZ1Dt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/27/census-announces-4-3m-seed-to-put-product-info-in-cloud-data-warehouses-to-work/">Census raises $4.3M seed to put product info in cloud data warehouses to work</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Census raises $4.3M seed to put product info in cloud data warehouses to work&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/27/census-announces-4-3m-seed-to-put-product-info-in-cloud-data-warehouses-to-work/embed/#?secret=IXekrbZ1Dt" data-secret="IXekrbZ1Dt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The company is part of a new crop of startups that are building on top of data warehouses. The general idea behind Census is to help businesses operationalize the data in their data warehouses, which was traditionally only used for analytics and reporting use cases. But as businesses realized that all the data they needed was already available in their data warehouses and that they could use that as a single source of truth without having to build additional integrations, an ecosystem of companies that operationalize this data started to form.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company argues that the modern data stack, with data warehouses like Amazon Redshift, Google BigQuery and Snowflake at its core, offers all of the tools a business needs to extract and transform data (like Fivetran, dbt) and then visualize it (think Looker).</p>
<p>Tools like Census then essentially function as a new layer that sits between the data warehouse and the business tools that can help companies extract value from this data. With that, users can easily sync their product data into a marketing tool like Marketo or a CRM service like Salesforce, for example.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2114481" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sync_configuration_app.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2114481" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2114481" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sync_configuration_app.png" alt="" width="800" height="600" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sync_configuration_app.png 800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sync_configuration_app.png?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sync_configuration_app.png?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sync_configuration_app.png?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sync_configuration_app.png?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sync_configuration_app.png?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2114481" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Census</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">Three years ago, we were the first to ask, &#8216;Why are we relying on a clumsy tangle of wires connecting every app when everything we need is already in the warehouse? What if you could leverage your data team to drive operations?&#8217; </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">When the data warehouse is connected to the rest of the business, the possibilities are limitless.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8221; Census explains in today&#8217;s announcement. &#8220;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">When we launched, our focus was enabling product-led companies like Figma, Canva, and Notion to drive better marketing, sales, and customer success. Along the way, our customers have pulled Census into more and more scenarios, like auto-prioritizing support tickets in Zendesk, automating invoices in Netsuite, or even integrating with HR systems.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;</span></p>
<p>Census already integrates with dozens of different services and data tools and its customers include the likes of Clearbit, Figma, Fivetran, LogDNA, Loom and Notion.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, Census plans to use the new funding to launch new features like deeper data validation and a visual query experience. In addition, it also plans to launch code-based orchestration to make Census workflows versionable and make it easier to integrate them into enterprise orchestration system.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jAnBLQ254N"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/iteratively-raises-5-4m-to-help-companies-build-data-pipelines-they-can-trust/">Iteratively raises $5.4M to help companies build data pipelines they can trust</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Iteratively raises $5.4M to help companies build data pipelines they can trust&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/iteratively-raises-5-4m-to-help-companies-build-data-pipelines-they-can-trust/embed/#?secret=jAnBLQ254N" data-secret="jAnBLQ254N" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1PRVN4OQrG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/hightouch-raises-2-1m-to-help-businesses-get-more-value-from-their-data-warehouses/">Hightouch raises $2.1M to help businesses get more value from their data warehouses</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hightouch raises $2.1M to help businesses get more value from their data warehouses&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/hightouch-raises-2-1m-to-help-businesses-get-more-value-from-their-data-warehouses/embed/#?secret=1PRVN4OQrG" data-secret="1PRVN4OQrG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/census-raises-16m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114464</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Logging startups are suddenly hot as CrowdStrike nabs Humio for $400M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/logging-startups-are-suddenly-hot-as-crowdstrike-nabs-humio-for-400m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/logging-startups-are-suddenly-hot-as-crowdstrike-nabs-humio-for-400m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 15:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crowdstrike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data lakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[logging tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114725</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A couple of weeks ago SentinelOne announced it was acquiring high-speed logging platform Scalyr for $155 million. Just this morning CrowdStrike struck next, announcing it was buying unlimited logging tool Humio for $400 million. In Humio, CrowdStrike gets a company that will provide it with the ability to collect unlimited logging information. Most companies have [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A couple of weeks ago SentinelOne announced it was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/sentinelone-acquires-high-speed-logging-startup-scalyr-for-155m/">acquiring high-speed logging platform Scalyr</a> for $155 million. Just this morning <a href="http://crowdstrike.com">CrowdStrike</a> struck next, announcing it was buying unlimited logging tool <a href="https://www.humio.com/">Humio</a> for $400 million.</p>
<p>In Humio, CrowdStrike gets a company that will provide it with the ability to collect unlimited logging information. Most companies have to pick and choose what to log and how long to keep it, but with Humio, they don&#8217;t have to make these choices with customers processing multiple terabytes of data every single day.</p>
<p>Humio CEO Geeta Schmidt writing in <a href="https://www.humio.com/humio-crowdstrike">a company blog post announcing the deal</a> described her company in similar terms to Scalyr, a data lake for log information:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Humio had become the data lake for these enterprises enabling searches for longer periods of time and from more data sources allowing them to understand their entire environment, prepare for the unknown, proactively prevent issues, recover quickly from incidents, and get to the root cause,&#8221; she wrote.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LRa5LW16G1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/14/crowdstrike-a-cybersecurity-unicorn-files-to-go-public/">CrowdStrike, a cybersecurity unicorn, files to go public</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;CrowdStrike, a cybersecurity unicorn, files to go public&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/14/crowdstrike-a-cybersecurity-unicorn-files-to-go-public/embed/#?secret=LRa5LW16G1" data-secret="LRa5LW16G1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That means with Humio in the fold, CrowdStrike can use this massive amount of data to help deal with threats and attacks in real time as they are happening, rather than reacting to them and trying to figure out what happened later, a point by the way that SentinelOne also made when it purchased Scalyr.</p>
<p>&#8220;The combination of real-time analytics and smart filtering built into CrowdStrike’s proprietary Threat Graph and Humio’s blazing-fast log management and index-free data ingestion dramatically accelerates our [eXtended Detection and Response (XDR)] capabilities beyond anything the market has seen to date,&#8221; CrowdStrike CEO and co-founder George Kurtz said in a statement.</p>
<p>While two acquisitions don&#8217;t necessarily make a trend, it&#8217;s clear that security platform players are suddenly seeing the value of being able to process the large amounts of information found in logs, and they are willing to put up some cash to get that capability. It will be interesting to see if any other security companies react with a similar move in the coming months.</p>
<p>Humio was founded in 2016 and raised just over $31 million, according to Pitchbook Data. Its most recent funding round came in March 2020,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/25/humio-announces-20m-series-b-to-advance-unlimited-logging-tool/"> a $20 million Series B</a> led by Dell Technologies Capital. It would appear to be a decent exit for the startup.</p>
<p>CrowdStrike was founded in 2011 and raised over $480 million along the way <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/14/crowdstrike-a-cybersecurity-unicorn-files-to-go-public/">before going public in 2019</a>. The deal is expected to close in the first quarter, and is subject to typical regulatory oversight.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="I0BQSDiN11"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/25/humio-announces-20m-series-b-to-advance-unlimited-logging-tool/">Humio announces $20M Series B to advance unlimited logging tool</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Humio announces $20M Series B to advance unlimited logging tool&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/25/humio-announces-20m-series-b-to-advance-unlimited-logging-tool/embed/#?secret=I0BQSDiN11" data-secret="I0BQSDiN11" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/logging-startups-are-suddenly-hot-as-crowdstrike-nabs-humio-for-400m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114725</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>California DMV warns of data breach after a contractor was hit by ransomware</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/california-motor-vehicles-afts-ransomware/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/california-motor-vehicles-afts-ransomware/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 15:21:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Contractor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[driver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seattle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114774</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[California&#8217;s Department of Motor Vehicles is warning of a potential data breach after a contractor was hit by ransomware. The Seattle-based Automatic Funds Transfer Services (AFTS), which the DMV said it has used for verifying changes of address with the national database since 2019, was hit by an unspecified strain of ransomware earlier this month. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">California&#8217;s Department of Motor Vehicles is warning of a potential data breach after a contractor was hit by ransomware.</p>
<p>The Seattle-based Automatic Funds Transfer Services (AFTS), which the DMV said it has used for verifying changes of address with the national database since 2019, was hit by an unspecified strain of ransomware earlier this month.</p>
<p>In a statement sent by email, the DMV said that the attack may have compromised &#8220;the last 20 months of California vehicle registration records that contain names, addresses, license plate numbers and vehicle identification numbers.&#8221; But the DMV said AFTS does not have access to customers&#8217; Social Security numbers, dates of birth, voter registration, immigration status or driver&#8217;s license information, and was not compromised.</p>
<p>The DMV said it has since stopped all data transfers to AFTS and has since initiated an emergency contract to prevent any downtime.</p>
<p>AFTS is used across the United States to process payments, invoices and verify addresses. Several <a href="https://www.skagitpud.org/news/pud-aware-of-potential-data-security-issue/">municipalities</a> have <a href="https://awwd.com/impact/emergency-information/afts-inc-security-issue/">already</a> confirmed that they are affected by the <a href="https://www.kirklandwa.gov/Government/Departments/Finance-and-Administration/Customer-Accounts/Utility-Billing/AFTS-FAQ">data breach</a>, suggesting it may not be limited to California&#8217;s DMV. But it&#8217;s not known what kind of ransomware hit AFTS. Ransomware typically encrypts a company&#8217;s files and will unlock them in exchange for a ransom. But since many <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/08/as-ransomware-gets-craftier-companies-must-start-thinking-creatively/">companies have backups</a>, some ransomware groups threaten to publish the stolen files online unless the ransom is paid.</p>
<p>AFTS could not be immediately reached for comment. Its website is offline, with a short message: &#8220;The website for AFTS and all related payment processing website <em>[sic] </em>are unavailable due to technical issues. We are working on restoring them as quickly as possible.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We are looking at additional measures to implement to bolster security to protect information held by the DMV and companies that we contract with,&#8221; said Steve Gordon, the director of the state&#8217;s DMV.</p>
<p>Last year <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/evjekz/the-california-dmv-is-making-dollar50m-a-year-selling-drivers-personal-information">it was reported</a> that California&#8217;s DMV makes more than $50 million a year by selling drivers&#8217; personal information, including <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/dyzeza/california-dmv-data-private-investigators">to bondsmen and private investigators</a>.</p>
<p>California has more than 35 million registered vehicles.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="86Imt2BXDS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/08/as-ransomware-gets-craftier-companies-must-start-thinking-creatively/">As ransomware gets craftier, companies must start thinking creatively</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As ransomware gets craftier, companies must start thinking creatively&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/08/as-ransomware-gets-craftier-companies-must-start-thinking-creatively/embed/#?secret=86Imt2BXDS" data-secret="86Imt2BXDS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/california-motor-vehicles-afts-ransomware/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114774</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tired of &#8216;Zoom University&#8217;? So is edtech</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/edtech-zoom-university/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/edtech-zoom-university/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 15:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[class]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ClassDojo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engageli]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top hat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114285</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The rise of &#8220;Zoom University&#8221; was only possible because edtech wasn’t ready to address the biggest opportunity of the past year: remote learning at scale. Of course, the term encapsulates more than just Zoom, it’s a nod to how schools had to rapidly adopt enterprise video conferencing software to keep school in session in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The rise of &#8220;Zoom University&#8221; was only possible because edtech wasn’t ready to address the biggest opportunity of the past year: remote learning at scale. Of course, the term encapsulates more than just Zoom, it’s a nod to how schools had to rapidly adopt enterprise video conferencing software to keep school in session in the wake of closures brought on by the virus’ rapid spread.</p>
<p>Now, nearly a year since students were first sent home because of the coronavirus, a cohort of edtech companies is emerging, emboldened with millions in venture capital, ready to take back the market.</p>
<p>The new wave of startups are slicing and dicing the same market of students and teachers who are fatigued by Zoom University, which &#8212; at best &#8212; often looks like a gallery view with a chat bar. Four of the companies that are gaining traction include <a href="https://www.class.com/">Class</a>, <a href="https://www.engageli.com/">Engageli</a>, <a href="https://tophat.com/">Top Hat</a> and <a href="https://inspace.chat/">InSpace</a>. It signals a shift from startups playing in the supplemental education space and searching to win a spot in the largest chunk of a students day: the classroom.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While each startup has its own unique strategy and product, the founders behind them all need to answer the same question: Can they make digital learning a preferred mode of pedagogy and comprehension &#8212; and not merely a backup &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/to-win-post-pandemic-edtech-needs-to-start-thinking-big/">after the pandemic is over</a>?</p>
<p>Answering that question begins with deciding whether videoconferencing is what online, live learning should look like.</p>
<h2>Ground up</h2>
<p>“This is completely grounds up; there is no Zoom, Google Meets or Microsoft Teams anywhere in the vicinity,” said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dan-avida/">Dan Avida</a>, co-founder of Engageli, just a few minutes into the demo of his product.</p>
<p>Engageli, a new startup founded by Avida, Daphne Koeller and Serge Plotkin, <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2020/10/14/engageli-launches-with-14-5-million-to-bring-digital-learning-to-universities/">raised $14.5 million</a> in October to bring digital learning to college universities. The startup wants to make big lecture-style classes feel more intimate, and thinks digitizing everything from the professor monologues to side conversations between students is the way to go.</p>
<p>Engageli is a videoconferencing platform in that it connects students and professors over live video, but the real product feature that differentiates it, according to Avida, is in how it views the virtual classroom.</p>
<p>Upon joining the platform, each student is placed at a virtual table with another small group of students. Within those pods, students can chat, trade notes, screenshot the lecture and collaborate, all while hearing a professor lecture simultaneously.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-2114420" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Engageli_Groups.png" alt="" width="683" height="381" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Engageli_Groups.png 1448w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Engageli_Groups.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Engageli_Groups.png?resize=300,167 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Engageli_Groups.png?resize=768,428 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Engageli_Groups.png?resize=680,379 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Engageli_Groups.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /></p>
<p>“The FaceTime session going on with friends or any other communication platform is going to happen,” Avida said. “So it might as well run it through our platform.”</p>
<p>The tables can easily be scrambled to promote different conversation or debates, and teachers can pop in and out without leaving their main screen. It’s a riff on Zoom’s breakout rooms, which let participants jump into separate calls within a bigger call.</p>
<p>There’s also a notetaking feature that allows students to screenshot slides and live annotate them within the Engageli platform. Each screenshot comes with a hyperlink that will take the student back to the live recording of that note, which could help with studying.</p>
<p>“We don’t want to be better than Zoom, we want to be different than Zoom,” Avida said. Engageli can run on a variety of products of differing bandwidth, from Chromebooks to iPads and PCs.</p>
<p>Engageli is feature-rich to the point that it has to onboard teachers, its main customer, in two phases, a process that can take over an hour. While Avida says that it only takes five minutes to figure out how to use the platform to hold a class, it does take longer to figure out how to fully take advantage of all the different modules. Teachers and students need to have some sort of digital savviness to be able to use the platform, which is both a barrier to entry for adoption but also a reason why Engageli can tout that it&#8217;s better than a simple call. Complexity, as Avida sees it, requires well-worth-it time.</p>
<p>The startup’s ambition doesn’t block it from dealing with contract issues. Other video conferencing platforms can afford to be free or already have been budgeted into. Engageli currently charges $9.99 or less per student seat for its platform. Avida says that with Zoom, “it’s effectively free because people have already paid for it, so we have to demonstrate why we’re much better than those products.”</p>
<p>Engageli’s biggest hurdle is another startup’s biggest advantage.</p>
<h2>Built on top of Zoom</h2>
<p>Class, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/23/class-for-zoom-earliest-investors-are-betting-millions/">launched less than a year ago</a> by Blackboard co-founder <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/chasen">Michael Chasen</a>, integrates exclusively with Zoom to offer a more customized classroom for students and teachers alike. The product, currently in private paid beta, helps teachers launch live assignments, track attendance and understand student engagement levels in real time.</p>
<p>While positioning an entire business on Zoom could lead to platform risk, Chasen sees it as a competitive advantage that will help the startup stay relevant after the pandemic.</p>
<p>“We’re not really pitching it as pandemic-related,” Chasen said. “No school has only said that we’re going to plan to use this for a month, and very few K-12 schools say we’re only looking at this in case a pandemic comes again.” Chasen says that most beta customers say online learning will be part of their instructional strategy going forward.</p>
<p>Investors clearly see the opportunity in the company’s strategy, from distribution to execution. Earlier this month, Class announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/class-series-a-zoom/">it had raised $30 million in Series A financing</a>, just 10 weeks after raising a $16 million seed round. Raising that much pre-launch gives the startup key wiggle room, but it also gives validation: a number of Zoom’s earliest investors, including Emergence Capital and Bill Tai, who wrote the first check into Zoom, have put money into Class.</p>
<p>“At Blackboard, we had a six to nine month sales cycle; we’d have to explain that e-learning is a thing,” Chasen said, who was at the LMS business for 15 years. “[With Class] we don’t even have to pitch. It wraps up in a month, and our sales cycle is just showing people the product.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YwVKyJICdk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/class-series-a-zoom/">Class adds $30 million to its balance sheet for a Zoom-friendly edtech solution</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Class adds $30 million to its balance sheet for a Zoom-friendly edtech solution&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/class-series-a-zoom/embed/#?secret=YwVKyJICdk" data-secret="YwVKyJICdk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Unlike Engageli, Class is selling to both K-12 institutions and higher-education institutions, which means its product is more focused on access and ease of use instead of specialized features. The startup has over 6,000 institutions, from high schools to higher education institutions, on the waitlist to join.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2108367" style="width: 660px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2108367" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2108367" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Class-for-Zoom-Attendance-.png" alt="" width="650" height="447" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Class-for-Zoom-Attendance-.png 1004w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Class-for-Zoom-Attendance-.png?resize=150,103 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Class-for-Zoom-Attendance-.png?resize=300,206 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Class-for-Zoom-Attendance-.png?resize=768,529 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Class-for-Zoom-Attendance-.png?resize=680,468 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Class-for-Zoom-Attendance-.png?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2108367" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Class</p></div></p>
<p>Right now, Class software is only usable on Macs, but its beta will be available on iPhone, Windows and Android in the near future. The public launch is at the end of the quarter.</p>
<p>“K-12 is in a bigger bind,” he said, but higher-ed institutions are fully committed to using synchronous online learning for the “long haul.”</p>
<p>“Higher-ed has already been taking this step towards online learning, and they&#8217;re now taking the next step,” he said. “Whereas with a lot of K-12, I&#8217;m actually seeing that this is the first step that they&#8217;re taking.”</p>
<p>The big hurdle for Class, and any startup selling e-learning solutions to institutions, is post-pandemic utility. While institutions have traditionally been slow to adopt software due to red tape, Chasen says that both of Class’ customers, higher ed and K-12, are actively allocating budget for these tools. The price for Class ranges between $10,000 to $65,000 annually, depending on the number of students in the classes.</p>
<p>“We have not run into a budgeting problem in a single school,” he said. “Higher ed has already been taking this step towards online learning, and they’re now taking the next step, whereas K-12, this is the first step they’re taking.”</p>
<h2>Asynchronously, silly</h2>
<p>Engageli and Class are both trying to innovate on the live learning experience, but Top Hat, which raised $130 million in a Series E round<a href="https://www.finsmes.com/2021/02/top-hat-raises-130m-in-series-e-funding.html#"> this past week</a>, thinks that the future is pre-recorded video.</p>
<p>Top Hat digitizes textbooks, but instead of putting a PDF on a screen, the startup fits features such as polls and interactive graphics in the text. The platform has attracted millions of students on this premise.</p>
<p>“We’re seeing a lot of companies putting emphasis on creating a virtual classroom,” he said. “But replicating the same thing in a different medium is never a good idea…nobody wants to stare at a screen and then have the restraint of having to show up at a previous pre-prescribed time.”</p>
<p><a href="https://tophat.com/press-releases/top-hat-launches-community/#:~:text=TORONTO%20%E2%80%94%20July%2030%2C%202020%20%E2%80%94,communicate%2C%20collaborate%2C%20and%20build%20connections">In July</a>, Top Hat launched <a href="https://tophat.com/features/community/">Community</a> to give teachers a way to make class more than just a YouTube video. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/classdojos-second-act-comes-with-first-profits/">Similar to ClassDojo,</a> Community provides a space for teachers and students to converse and stay up to date on shared materials. The interface also allows students to create private channels to discuss assignments and work on projects, as well as direct message their teachers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="987ODe3Rz9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/will-edtech-empower-or-erase-the-need-for-higher-education/">Will edtech empower or erase the need for higher education?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Will edtech empower or erase the need for higher education?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/will-edtech-empower-or-erase-the-need-for-higher-education/embed/#?secret=987ODe3Rz9" data-secret="987ODe3Rz9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>CEO Mike Silagadze says that Top Hat tried a virtual classroom tool early on, and “very quickly learned that it was fundamentally just the wrong strategy.” His mindset contrasts with the demand that Class and Engageli have proven so far, to which Silagadze says might not be as long-term as they think.</p>
<p>“There&#8217;s definitely a lot of interest that&#8217;s generated in people signing up to beta lists and like wanting to try it out. But when people really get into it, everyone pretty much drops off and focuses more on asynchronous, small and in-person groups.”</p>
<p>Instead, the founder thinks that “schools are going to double down on the really valuable in-person aspects of higher education that they couldn&#8217;t provide before” and deliver other content, like large lecture-style classes or meetings, through asynchronous content delivery.</p>
<p>This is similar to what Jeff Maggioncalda, the CEO of Coursera, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/will-edtech-empower-or-erase-the-need-for-higher-education/">told TechCrunch in November:</a> Colleges are going to re-invest in their in-person and residential experiences, and begin offering credentials and content online to fill in the gaps.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="i4NXP2URAA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/classdojos-second-act-comes-with-first-profits/">ClassDojo&#8217;s second act comes with first profits</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;ClassDojo&#8217;s second act comes with first profits&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/classdojos-second-act-comes-with-first-profits/embed/#?secret=i4NXP2URAA" data-secret="i4NXP2URAA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“We&#8217;ve been on the journey to create a more and more complete platform that our customers can use since almost day one,” Silagadze said. “What the pandemic has brought is much more comprehensive testing functionality that Top Hat has rolled out and better communication tooling so basically better chat and communication tooling for professors.”</p>
<p>Community costs $30 per semester, per student. Currently Top Hat has most of its paying customers coming in through its content offering, the digital textbooks, instead of this learning platform.</p>
<h2>College spin-out</h2>
<p><a href="https://inspace.chat/">InSpace</a>, a startup spinning out of Champlain college, is similarly focused on making the communication between professors and students more natural. <a href="https://www.champlain.edu/academics/our-faculty/hall-narine">Dr. Narine Hall</a>, the founder of the startup, is a professor herself who just wanted class to “feel more natural&#8221; when it was being conducted.</p>
<p>InSpace is similar to some of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/virtual-hqs-race-to-win-over-a-remote-work-fatigued-market/">virtual HQ platforms</a> that have popped up over the past few months. The platforms, which my colleague Devin Coldewey aptly dubbed Sims for Enterprise, are trying to create the feel of an office or classroom online but without a traditional gallery view or conference call vibe. The potential success of inSpace and others could signal how the future of work will blend gaming and socialization for distributed teams.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/RvhJbVm3t54?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>InSpace is using spatial gaming infrastructure to create spontaneity. The technology allows users to only hear people within their nearby proximity, and get quieter as they walk, or click, away. When applied to a virtual world, spatial technology can give the feeling of a hallway bump-in.</p>
<p>Similar to Engageli, inSpace is rethinking how an actual class is conducted. In inSpace, students don&#8217;t have to leave the main call to have a conversation during inSpace, which they do in Zoom. Students can just toggle over to their own areas and a professor can see teamwork being done in real time. When a student has a question, their bubble becomes bigger, which is easier to track than the hand-raise feature, says Hall.</p>
<p>InSpace has a different monetization strategy than other startups. It charges $15 a month per-educator or “host” versus per-student, which Hall says was so educators could close contracts “as fast as possible.” Hall agrees with other founders that schools have a high demand for the product, but she says that the decision-making process around buying new tooling continues to be difficult in schools with tight budgets, even amid a pandemic. There are currently 100 customers on the platform.</p>
<p>So far, Hall sees inSpace working best with classes that include 25 people, with a max of 50 people.</p>
<p>The company was born out of her own frustrations as a teacher. In grad school, Hall worked on research that combined proximity-based interactions with humans. When August rolled around and she needed a better solution than WebEx or Zoom, she turned to that same research and began building code atop of her teachings. It led to inSpace, which recently announced that it has landed $2.5 million in financing led by Boston Seed Capital.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yT9bTtbfPY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/virtual-hqs-race-to-win-over-a-remote-work-fatigued-market/">Virtual HQs race to win over a remote-work-fatigued market</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Virtual HQs race to win over a remote-work-fatigued market&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/virtual-hqs-race-to-win-over-a-remote-work-fatigued-market/embed/#?secret=yT9bTtbfPY" data-secret="yT9bTtbfPY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The differences between each startup, from strategy to monetization to its view of the competition, are music to Zoom’s ears. Anne Keough Keehn, who was hired as Zoom’s Global Education Lead just nine months ago, says that the platform has a “very open attitude and policy about looking at how we best integrate&#8230;and sometimes that’s going to be a co-opetition.”</p>
<p>“In the past there has been too much consolidation and therefore it limits choices,” Keehn said. “And we know everybody in education likes to have choices.” Zoom will be used differently in a career office versus a class, and in a happy hour versus a wedding; the platform sees opportunity in it all beyond the “monolithic definition” that video-conferencing has had for so long.</p>
<p>And, despite the fact that this type of response is expected by a well-trained executive at a big company in the spotlight, maybe Keehn is onto something here: Maybe the biggest opportunity in edtech right now is that there is opportunity and money in the first place, for remote learning, for better video-conferencing and for more communication.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/edtech-zoom-university/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114285</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pipe17 closes $8M to connect a range of e-commerce tools without any code required</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/pipe17-closes-8m-to-connect-a-range-of-e-commerce-tools-without-any-code-required/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/pipe17-closes-8m-to-connect-a-range-of-e-commerce-tools-without-any-code-required/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 15:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alloy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bigcommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114694</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning Pipe17, a software startup focused on the e-commerce market, announced that it has closed $8 million in funding. Pipe17&#8217;s service helps smaller e-commerce merchants connect their digital tools, without the need to code. With the startup&#8217;s service, e-commerce operations that may lack an in-house IT function can quickly connect their selling platform to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a href="https://pipe17.com/">Pipe17</a>, a software startup focused on the e-commerce market, announced that it has closed $8 million in funding.</p>
<p>Pipe17&#8217;s service helps smaller e-commerce merchants connect their digital tools, without the need to code. With the startup&#8217;s service, e-commerce operations that may lack an in-house IT function can quickly connect their selling platform to shipping, or point-of-sale data to their ERP.</p>
<p>The venture arm of a large logistics investor GLP, <a href="https://glpcp.com/">GLP Capital Partners</a> led the round.</p>
<p>Pipe17 co-founders <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohamadafshar/">Mo Afshar</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/middleworks/">Dave Shaffer</a> told TechCrunch in an interview that the idea for their startup came from examining the e-commerce market, noting the energy to be found concerning selling platforms, and the comparative dearth of software to help get e-commerce tools to work together; Shopify and BigCommerce and Shippo are just fine, but if you can&#8217;t code you might wind up schlepping data from one platform to the next to keep your e-commerce operation humming.</p>
<p>So they built Pipe17 to fill in the gap.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wSoWxlpkKk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/why-e-commerce-startups-arent-raising-more-funding-during-this-historic-boom/">Why e-commerce startups aren&#8217;t raising more funding during this historic boom</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why e-commerce startups aren&#8217;t raising more funding during this historic boom&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/why-e-commerce-startups-arent-raising-more-funding-during-this-historic-boom/embed/#?secret=wSoWxlpkKk" data-secret="wSoWxlpkKk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>According to Afshar, Pipe17 wants to simplify operations for e-commerce merchants through the lens of connection; the pair of co-founders believe that easy cross-compatibility is the key missing ingredient in the modern-day e-commerce software stack, likening the current e-commerce maket to the IT and datacenter worlds before the advent of Splunk and Datadog.</p>
<p>The prevailing view in the e-commerce industry, the co-founders explained, is that to fix a problem e-commerce players should purchase another application. Pipe17 thinks that most ecommerce companies probably have enough tooling, and that they instead need to get their existing tooling to communicate.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s neat about the startup is that it&#8217;s building something that we might call no-code-no-code, or no-code to a higher degree. Instead of offering a interface for non-developers to visually map out connections between different software services, it has pre-built what might need to be mapped. Just pick the two e-commerce services you want to link, and Pipe17 will connect them for you in an intelligent manner. For folks who find <em>any</em> sort of coding hard (which probably describes a lot of indie online store operators), the method could be an attractive pitch.</p>
<p>The startup&#8217;s customer target are sellers doing single-digit millions to nine-figures in year sales.</p>
<p>Why did Pipe17 raise capital now? The co-founders said that there are only so many chances to simplify a large market, akin to what Plaid and Twilio did for their own niches, so taking on funds now made sense. In Afshar&#8217;s view, e-commerce operations is going to be simply massive. Given <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/24/covid-19-pandemic-accelerated-shift-to-e-commerce-by-5-years-new-report-says/">the growth in digital selling that we saw last year</a>, it&#8217;s a perspective that is hard to dispute.</p>
<p>The niche that Pipe17 wants to fill has more than one player. While the startups themselves might quibble about just how much competitive space they share, Y Combinator-backed <a href="https://runalloy.com/">Alloy</a> recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/alloy-raises-4m-to-build-out-its-e-commerce-automation-service/">raised $4 million</a> to build a no-code e-commerce automation service. Which is related to what Pipe17 does. It will be interesting to see if they wind up in competition, and, if so, who comes out on top.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WPSevjMur0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/24/covid-19-pandemic-accelerated-shift-to-e-commerce-by-5-years-new-report-says/">COVID-19 pandemic accelerated shift to e-commerce by 5 years, new report says</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;COVID-19 pandemic accelerated shift to e-commerce by 5 years, new report says&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/24/covid-19-pandemic-accelerated-shift-to-e-commerce-by-5-years-new-report-says/embed/#?secret=WPSevjMur0" data-secret="WPSevjMur0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/pipe17-closes-8m-to-connect-a-range-of-e-commerce-tools-without-any-code-required/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114694</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook applies overly broad content block in flex against Australia&#8217;s planned news reuse law</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/facebook-applies-overly-broad-content-block-in-flex-against-australias-planned-news-reuse-law/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/facebook-applies-overly-broad-content-block-in-flex-against-australias-planned-news-reuse-law/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 15:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[censorship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[platform regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114673</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Outrage fast-followed Facebook&#8217;s announcement yesterday that it was making good on its threat to block Australian users&#8217; ability to share news on its platform. The tech giant&#8217;s intentionally broad-brush &#8212; call it antisocial &#8212; implementation of content restrictions took down a swathe of non-news publishers&#8217; Facebook pages, as well as silencing news outlets&#8217;, illustrating its planned [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Outrage fast-followed Facebook&#8217;s announcement <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/facebook-restricts-users-in-australia-from-sharing-or-viewing-news-links-in-response-to-proposed-legislation/">yesterday</a> that it was making good on its<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/01/facebook-threatens-to-block-news-sharing-in-australia-as-it-lobbies-against-revenue-share-law/"> threat</a> to block Australian users&#8217; ability to share news on its platform.</p>
<p>The tech giant&#8217;s intentionally broad-brush &#8212; call it antisocial &#8212; implementation of content restrictions took down a swathe of non-news publishers&#8217; Facebook pages, as well as silencing news outlets&#8217;, illustrating its planned dodge of the (future) law.</p>
<p>Facebook took the step to censor a bunch of pages as parliamentarians in Australia are debating a legislative proposal to force Facebook (and Google) to pay publishers for linking to their news content. In recent years the media industry in the country has successfully lobbied for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/31/australia-now-has-a-template-for-forcing-facebook-and-google-to-pay-for-news/">a law to extract payment from the tech giants</a> for monetizing news content when it&#8217;s reshared on their platforms &#8212; though the legislation is still being drafted.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5DrCfzkt22"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/31/australia-now-has-a-template-for-forcing-facebook-and-google-to-pay-for-news/">Australia now has a template for forcing Facebook and Google to pay for news</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Australia now has a template for forcing Facebook and Google to pay for news&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/31/australia-now-has-a-template-for-forcing-facebook-and-google-to-pay-for-news/embed/#?secret=5DrCfzkt22" data-secret="5DrCfzkt22" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/22/google-threatens-to-close-its-search-engine-in-australia-as-it-lobbies-against-digital-news-code/">Last month</a> Google also threatened to close its search engine in Australia if the law isn&#8217;t amended. But it&#8217;s Facebook that screwed its courage to the sticking place and flipped the chaos switch first.</p>
<p>Last night Internet users in Australia took to Twitter to report local scores of Facebook pages being wiped clean of content &#8212; including hospitals, universities, unions, government departments and the bureau of meteorology, to name a few.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Facebook&#39;s news ban hammer having a lot of collateral damage. <a href="https://t.co/mP4pfd3nL5">pic.twitter.com/mP4pfd3nL5</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Josh Taylor (@joshgnosis) <a href="https://twitter.com/joshgnosis/status/1362158667760496642?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 17, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Me to Facebook: Is the Bureau of Meteorology considered an Australian news publisher or was it mistakenly blocked? <br />Facebook spox: It is not – we are working to reverse this. <a href="https://t.co/S8aSSIprdi">pic.twitter.com/S8aSSIprdi</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Queenie Wong (@QWongSJ) <a href="https://twitter.com/QWongSJ/status/1362174532123959297?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 17, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In the wake of Facebook&#8217;s unilateral censorship of all sorts of Facebook pages, parliamentarians in the country accused the tech giant of &#8220;an assault on a sovereign nation&#8221;.</p>
<p>The prime minister of Australia also said today that his government &#8220;would not be intimidated&#8221;.</p>
<p>Reached for comment, Facebook confirmed it has applied an intentionally broad definition of news to restrict &#8212; saying it has done so to reflect the lack of clear guidance in the law &#8220;as drafted&#8221;.</p>
<p>So it looks like the collateral damage of Facebook silencing scores of public information pages is at least partly a PR tactic to illustrate potential &#8216;consequences&#8217; of lawmakers forcing it to pay to display certain types of content &#8212; i.e. to &#8216;encourage&#8217; a rethink while there&#8217;s still time.</p>
<p>The tech giant did also say it would reverse pages that are &#8220;inadvertently impacted&#8221;.</p>
<p>But it did not indicate whether it would be doing the leg work of checking its own homework there, or whether silenced pages must (somehow) petition it to be reinstated.</p>
<p>“The actions we&#8217;re taking are focused on restricting publishers and people in Australia from sharing or viewing Australian and international news content. As the law does not provide clear guidance on the definition of news content, we have taken a broad definition in order to respect the law as drafted. However, we will reverse any Pages that are inadvertently impacted,” a Facebook company spokesperson said in the statement.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also not clear how many non-news pages have been affected by Facebook&#8217;s self-imposed content restrictions.</p>
<p>If the tech giant was hoping to kick off a wider debate about the merits of Australia&#8217;s (controversial) plan to make tech pay for news (including in its current guise, for <em>links</em> to news &#8212; not just snippets of content, as under the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/26/european-parliament-votes-for-controversial-copyright-reform/">EU&#8217;s recent copyright reform expansion of neighbouring rights for news</a>) &#8212; Facebook has certainly succeeded in grabbing global eyeballs by blocking regional access to vast swathes of useful, factual information.</p>
<p>However Facebook&#8217;s blunt action has also attracted criticism that it&#8217;s putting business interests before human rights &#8212; given it&#8217;s shuttering users&#8217; ability to find what might be vital information, such as from hospitals and government departments, in the middle of a pandemic. (Albeit, being accused of ignoring human rights is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/13/un-says-facebook-is-accelerating-ethnic-violence-in-myanmar/">hardly a new look for Facebook</a>.)</p>
<p>The Harvard professor Shoshana Zuboff&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/europe-urged-to-block-google-fitbit-ahead-of-major-digital-policy-overhaul/">academic critique of surveillance capitalism</a> &#8212; including that it engages in propagating &#8220;epistemic chaos&#8221; for profit &#8212; has perhaps never felt quite so on the nose. (&#8220;We turned to Facebook in search of information. Instead we found lethal strategies of epistemic chaos for profit,&#8221; she <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/29/opinion/sunday/facebook-surveillance-society-technology.html">wrote only last month</a>.)</p>
<p>Facebook&#8217;s intentional over-flex has also underscored the vast power of its social monopoly &#8212; which will likely only strengthen calls for policymakers and antitrust regulators everywhere to grasp the nettle and rein in big tech. So its local lobbying effort may backfire on the global stage if it further sours public opinion against the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/10/a-brief-history-of-facebooks-privacy-hostility-ahead-of-zuckerbergs-testimony/">scandal-hit company</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">With Facebook deplatforming all news en masse, this is a good time to scrutinise the way platforms can and do take advantage of their monopoly position as ubiquitous / essential intermediaries in people&#39;s lives to throw their weight around. As Culpepper and Thelen (2019) put it: <a href="https://t.co/cPvrdjEWpx">pic.twitter.com/cPvrdjEWpx</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Jathan Sadowski (@jathansadowski) <a href="https://twitter.com/jathansadowski/status/1362168704499257346?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 17, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Facebook&#8217;s rush to censor may even encourage a proportion of its users to remember/discover that there&#8217;s a whole open Internet outside its walled garden &#8212; where they can freely access public information without having to log into Facebook&#8217;s ad-targeting platform (and be stripped of their privacy) first.</p>
<p>As <a href="https://twitter.com/robinberjon/status/1362132589688090626">others have noted</a>, it&#8217;s also interesting to note how quickly Facebook can pull the content moderation trigger when it believes its bottom line is threatened. And a law to extract payment for sharing news content presents a clear threat.</p>
<p>Compare and contrast Facebook&#8217;s rush to silence information pages in Australia with its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/12/facebook-in-a-reversal-will-now-ban-holocaust-denial-content-under-its-hate-speech-policy/">laid back approach</a> to tackling outrage-inducing hate speech or violent conspiracy nonsense and it&#8217;s hard not to conclude that content moderation on (and by) Facebook is always viewed through the prism of Facebook&#8217;s global revenue growth goals. (Much like how the tech giant can here be seen in a court filing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/facebook-knew-for-years-ad-reach-estimates-were-based-on-wrong-data-but-blocked-fixes-over-revenue-impact-per-court-filing/">chainlinking revenue to its self-reported ad metric tools</a>.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TDADbcp11f"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/facebook-restricts-users-in-australia-from-sharing-or-viewing-news-links-in-response-to-proposed-legislation/">Facebook restricts users in Australia from sharing or viewing news links</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook restricts users in Australia from sharing or viewing news links&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/facebook-restricts-users-in-australia-from-sharing-or-viewing-news-links-in-response-to-proposed-legislation/embed/#?secret=TDADbcp11f" data-secret="TDADbcp11f" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dp71AQS5kr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/20/google-and-facebook-must-pay-media-for-content-reuse-says-australia/">Google and Facebook must pay media for content reuse, says Australia</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google and Facebook must pay media for content reuse, says Australia&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/20/google-and-facebook-must-pay-media-for-content-reuse-says-australia/embed/#?secret=dp71AQS5kr" data-secret="dp71AQS5kr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/facebook-applies-overly-broad-content-block-in-flex-against-australias-planned-news-reuse-law/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114673</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wholesale marketplace Abound raises $22.9M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/abound-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/abound-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 15:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Left Lane Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114708</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Abound, an online marketplace that helps independent retailers stock their shelves with new products from up-and-coming brands, is announcing that it has raised $22.9 million in its first institutional round of funding. CEO Bill Shope founded the company with Niklas de la Motte and Drew Sfugaras. He told me that small retailers are constantly on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://helloabound.com">Abound</a>, an online marketplace that helps independent retailers stock their shelves with new products from up-and-coming brands, is announcing that it has raised $22.9 million in its first institutional round of funding.</p>
<p>CEO Bill Shope founded the company with Niklas de la Motte and Drew Sfugaras. He told me that small retailers are constantly on the hunt for new products, which means attending trade shows several times a year. Abound, on the other hand, allows them to find those products through an online shopping experience, with wholesale prices (a.k.a. discounts of up to 50 percent), free returns and, in some cases, Net 60 sale terms (meaning retailers don&#8217;t have to pay until 60 days after the invoice).</p>
<p>The startup actually began as a community connecting manufacturer&#8217;s representatives and retailers, but Shope said the team &#8220;kept seeing the limits of that model,&#8221; while some retailers were asking to buy from the brands directly. So the team decided to support that experience, starting out by recruiting 50 brands with an offer of free consulting — as long as they were willing to be one of the brands on the marketplace when it launched in October 2019.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Of course, the retail environment changed dramatically in the following months, as the pandemic forced stores to close and/or adopt social distancing measures. Shope said the startup saw a dramatic, short-term decline in sales — but things quickly bounced back and kept growing as &#8220;all the trade shows got canceled.&#8221;</p>
<p>Partly, that&#8217;s because Abound also supports e-commerce retailers, but Shope noted that &#8220;the brick and mortars that were succeeding had a very powerful hybrid model,&#8221; where they continued to operate a physical store while also quickly launching websites and adding features like curbside pickup.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2114762" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2114762" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2114762" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ABOUND-homepage-screenshot.jpg?w=680" alt="Abound screenshot" width="680" height="618" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ABOUND-homepage-screenshot.jpg 1268w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ABOUND-homepage-screenshot.jpg?resize=150,136 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ABOUND-homepage-screenshot.jpg?resize=300,273 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ABOUND-homepage-screenshot.jpg?resize=768,698 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ABOUND-homepage-screenshot.jpg?resize=680,618 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ABOUND-homepage-screenshot.jpg?resize=50,45 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2114762" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Abound</p></div></p>
<p>Abound says that since the beginning of 2020, it has added 180,000 new products in categories like baby and kid products, beauty, food and drink, home and living, jewelry and more. And monthly sales volume has increased 20-fold.</p>
<p>&#8220;From a retail perspective, I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s any going back [to pre-COVID buying models,]&#8221; Shope said. After all, even before the pandemic, independent retailers had to compete with giants like Amazon and Walmart. &#8220;You’re not going to beat them on convenience products. The store that&#8217;s helping consumers discover new brands, or donating 10 percent of profits to charities — those are types of stories and products you need to have to draw consumers into your store.&#8221;</p>
<p>The funding was led by Left Lane Capital, with participation from RiverPark Ventures, All Iron Ventures and branding firm Red Antler. This will allow Abound to grow the team, expand internationally and continue developing the product.</p>
<p>In a statement, Left Lane Managing Partner Harley Miller said:</p>
<blockquote><p>My family has been in independent retail for the last 20 years. Growing up, I attended many industry events, so I have long understood how under-optimized the wholesale buying and selling experience is. With the cancellation of most major trade shows in 2020 and 2021, emerging brands and independent retailers have been seeking new distribution channels to support their business ambitions. Abound offers an exciting and unique alternative to the legacy wholesale model at a time when small businesses need it most.</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3E8i2c5UOZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/olive-launch/">Jet co-founder Nate Faust is building a more sustainable e-commerce experience with Olive</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Jet co-founder Nate Faust is building a more sustainable e-commerce experience with Olive&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/olive-launch/embed/#?secret=3E8i2c5UOZ" data-secret="3E8i2c5UOZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/abound-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114708</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Varo Bank raises another $63M, led by NBA star Russell Westbrook</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/varo-bank-raises-another-63m-led-by-nba-star-russell-westbrook/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/varo-bank-raises-another-63m-led-by-nba-star-russell-westbrook/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 15:04:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114707</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Varo Bank, which last year became the first U.S. neobank to be granted a national bank charter, announced this morning it&#8217;s raised another $63 million in new funding. The round was led by NBA star Russell Westbrook, who will also join the startup as an advisor focused on the direction of Varo Bank&#8217;s programs aimed [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.varomoney.com/">Varo Bank</a>, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/03/mobile-banking-startup-varo-is-becoming-a-real-bank/">last year became</a> the first U.S. neobank to be granted a national bank charter, announced this morning it&#8217;s raised another $63 million in new funding. The round was led by NBA star Russell Westbrook, who will also join the startup as an advisor focused on the direction of Varo Bank&#8217;s programs aimed at underserved communities, including communities of color.</p>
<p>Westbrook&#8217;s investment came through <a href="https://westbrookenterprises.com/#digital">Russell Westbrook Enterprises</a>, which previously <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/darrenheitner/2017/06/14/russell-westbrook-invests-in-social-media-news-startup/?sh=343f28cfd69f">backed</a> social avatar startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/genies-updates-its-software-development-kit-and-partners-with-gucci-giphy/">Genies</a>.</p>
<p>Existing Varo Bank investors also joined the round, including Warburg Pincus, The Rise Fund, Gallatin Point Capital, HarbourVest Partners, and funds managed by BlackRock. Varo Bank last year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/03/challenger-bank-varo-soon-to-become-a-real-bank-raises-241m-series-d/">raised $241 million in Series D funding. </a>With the additional funds, Varo Bank&#8217;s total raise to date is now $482.4 million.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Founded in 2017, Varo Bank competes with a growing number of all-digital banks operating in the U.S., including Chime, Current, N26, Level, Step, Moven, Empower Finance, Dave, GoBank, Aspiration, Stash, Zero, and <a href="https://neobanks.app/neobanks/united-states">others</a>.</p>
<p>Like most neobanks, Varo Bank offers an easily accessible bank account with no monthly fees or minimum balance requirements, and a modern mobile app experience. It also includes high-interest savings and provides customers with access to a network of 55,000 fee-free Allpoint ATMs. But Varo Bank doesn&#8217;t have any physical bank branches.</p>
<p>Varo <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/03/mobile-banking-startup-varo-is-becoming-a-real-bank/">announced</a> last year it had been granted a national bank charter from the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency (OCC) and secured regulatory approvals from the FDIC and Federal Reserve to open Varo Bank, N.A. &#8212; effectively becoming a &#8220;real&#8221; bank.</p>
<p>Today, Varo Bank has over 3 million bank accounts, and says it&#8217;s deposits are up by over 900% year-over-year. Spend on the Varo platform is also up by over 300%, year-over-year.</p>
<p>Westbrook&#8217;s interest in working with Varo Bank has to do with its focus on making an impact on financial inequality through its banking services. Specifically, the company is committed to bringing up to two-day early payroll deposits, savings accounts that pay higher rates than the national average, and a short-term cash advance line of credit, <a href="https://www.varomoney.com/cash-advance/">Varo Advance</a>, that gives qualifying customers access to up to $100 as needed in the Varo Bank app. The credit line was launched in Dec. 2020, and remains fee-free through March 2021 due to the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>The new funds will be used to expand Varo Bank&#8217;s services, as well as work with Westbrook to co-create a community impact program that focuses on building financial literacy in underserved communities, the company told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>&#8220;The banking system has ignored or underserved a large portion of the American population &#8211; particularly communities of color. I’m passionate about making lasting social change and creating a stronger and more inclusive system,&#8221; said Mr. Westbrook, in a statement about his investment. &#8220;I am excited and ready to work with Varo to be a part of an economic revitalization for those who never had the access they deserved,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p><div style="width: 568px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-2114707-1" width="568" height="320" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/RW-Varo-SOT-Video-2.mp4?_=1" /><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/RW-Varo-SOT-Video-2.mp4">https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/RW-Varo-SOT-Video-2.mp4</a></video></div></p>
<p>Russell Westbrook Enterprises, who was exclusively advised by <a href="https://www.jefferies.com/">Jefferies LLC</a> in this transaction, the company noted.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/varo-bank-raises-another-63m-led-by-nba-star-russell-westbrook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114707</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Torii announces $10M Series A to automate SaaS management</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/torii-announces-10m-series-a-to-automate-saas-management-with-workflows/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/torii-announces-10m-series-a-to-automate-saas-management-with-workflows/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 15:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS management tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wing venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114676</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, that software is offered as a cloud service should be pretty much considered a given. Certainly any modern tooling is going to be SaaS, and as companies and employees add services, it becomes a management nightmare. Enter Torii, an early stage startup that wants to make it easier to manage SaaS bloat. Today, the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today, that software is offered as a cloud service should be pretty much considered a given. Certainly any modern tooling is going to be SaaS, and as companies and employees add services, it becomes a management nightmare. Enter <a href="https://toriihq.com/">Torii</a>, an early stage startup that wants to make it easier to manage SaaS bloat.</p>
<p>Today, the company announced a $10 million Series A investment led by Wing Venture Capital with participation from prior investors Entree Capital, Global Founders Capital, Scopus Ventures and Uncork Capital. The investment brings the total raised to $15 million, according to the company. Under the terms of the deal, Wing partner Jake Flomenberg is joining the board.</p>
<p>Uri Haramati, co-founder and CEO, is a serial entrepreneur who helped launch Houseparty and Meerkat. As a serial founder, he says that he and his co-founders saw first-hand how difficult it was to manage their companies&#8217; SaaS applications and the idea for Torii developed from that.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We all felt the changes around SaaS and managing the tools that we were using. We were all early adopters of SaaS. We all [took advantage of SaaS] to scale our companies and we felt the same thing: The fact is that you just can&#8217;t add more people who manage more software, it just doesn&#8217;t scale,&#8221; Haramati told me.</p>
<p>He said they started Torii with the idea of using software to control the SaaS sprawl they were experiencing. At the heart of the idea was an automation engine to discover and manage all of the SaaS tools inside an organization. Once you know what you have, there is a no-code workflow engine to create workflows around those tools for key activities like onboarding or offboarding employees.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2114680" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2114680" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2114680" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-17-at-21.59.03.png?w=680" alt="Torii no code workflow engine." width="680" height="396" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-17-at-21.59.03.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-17-at-21.59.03.png?resize=150,87 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-17-at-21.59.03.png?resize=300,175 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-17-at-21.59.03.png?resize=768,448 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-17-at-21.59.03.png?resize=680,396 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-17-at-21.59.03.png?resize=1536,895 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-17-at-21.59.03.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2114680" class="wp-caption-text">Torii Workflow Engine. Image Credits<strong>:</strong> Torii</p></div></p>
<p>The approach seems to be working. As the pandemic struck in 2020, more companies than ever needed to control and understand the SaaS tooling they had, and revenue grew 400% YoY last year. Customers include Delivery Hero, Chewy, Monday.com and Palo Alto Networks.</p>
<p>The company also doubled its employees from a dozen they started last year with with plans to get to 60 people by the end of this year. As they do that, as experienced entrepreneurs Haramati told me they already understood the value of developing a diverse and inclusive workforce, certainly around gender. Today, the team is 25 people with 10 being women and they are working to improve those ratios as they continue to add new people.</p>
<p>Flomenberg invested in Torii because he was particularly impressed with the automation aspect of the company and how it took a holistic approach to the SaaS management problem, rather than attempting to solve one part of it. &#8220;When I met Uri, he described this vision. It was really to become the operating system for SaaS. It all starts with the right data. You can trust data that is gathered from [multiple] sources to really build the right picture and pull it together. And then they took all those signals and they built a platform that is built on automation,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Haramati admits that it&#8217;s challenging to scale in the midst of a pandemic, but the company is growing and is already working to expand the platform to include product recommendations and help with compliance and cost control.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0xaqprxLc2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/20/bettercloud-scores-75m-series-f-as-saas-management-needs-grow/">BetterCloud scores $75M Series F as SaaS management needs grow</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BetterCloud scores $75M Series F as SaaS management needs grow&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/20/bettercloud-scores-75m-series-f-as-saas-management-needs-grow/embed/#?secret=0xaqprxLc2" data-secret="0xaqprxLc2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/torii-announces-10m-series-a-to-automate-saas-management-with-workflows/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114676</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sennheiser partners with Formlabs for customized headphones</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/sennheiser-partners-with-formlabs-for-customized-headphones/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/sennheiser-partners-with-formlabs-for-customized-headphones/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 14:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3d printing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[formlabs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[headphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sennheiser]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2112779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[3D printing has come a long way over the course of the last decade, but questions about mainstream adoption still linger around the technology. Medical devices have been a pretty compelling use case &#8212; they’re not really mass produced and require a high level of personalization. Clear orthodontics are a great example of something that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">3D printing has come a long way over the course of the last decade, but questions about mainstream adoption still linger around the technology. Medical devices have been a pretty compelling use case &#8212; they’re not really mass produced and require a high level of personalization. Clear orthodontics are a great example of something that falls in that sweet spot &#8212; in fact, dental in general has been a big application.</p>
<p>Audio, too, holds a lot of potential. Imagine, for example, a set of headphones custom designed for your ears. The technology has been available on high-end models for a while, courtesy of molding, but 3D printing could unlock a more easily scalable version of that kind of luxury.</p>
<p>This week, Sennheiser announced a partnership that will utilize Formlabs technology to print custom earphones. Specifically, the headphone maker will be using the Form 3B, a printer design for use with biocompatible material that has largely been utilized for dental applications. Product specifics haven’t been revealed, but the audio company’s Ambeo division will be using the tech to create custom headphone eartips. Users would be able to scan their ears with a smartphone and send that to the company to get a tip printed.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2114663" style="width: 406px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2114663" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2114663" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-04-at-9.40.19-AM-1.png" alt="" width="396" height="500" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-04-at-9.40.19-AM-1.png 396w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-04-at-9.40.19-AM-1.png?resize=119,150 119w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-04-at-9.40.19-AM-1.png?resize=238,300 238w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-04-at-9.40.19-AM-1.png?resize=40,50 40w" sizes="(max-width: 396px) 100vw, 396px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2114663" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sennheiser</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Our technology collaboration with Sennheiser seeks to change the way customers interact with the brands they love by enabling a more customized, user-centric approach to product development,” Formlabs audio head Iain McLeod said in a release.. “Formlabs’ deep industry knowledge and broad expertise in developing scalable solutions enable us to deliver tangible innovations to our customers. In this case, we are working with Sennheiser’s Ambeo team to deliver a uniquely accessible, custom fit experience.”</p>
<p>The product is still very much in the prototype phase. And while such a partnership seems like a no-brainer for headphone makers going forward, there are some big questions here, including pricing and scalability. Clearly such a product would come at a premium over standard headphones, but not at so high a cost that supersedes such novelty.</p>
<p>The release calls it “an affordable and simple solution is now available to mass 3D print custom-fit earphones.” What, precisely, it means by affordable remains to be seen.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SaghQzSTds"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/best-noise-canceling-headphones-over-ear-wireless/">Noise-canceling headphones that pair big sound with sweet silence</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Noise-canceling headphones that pair big sound with sweet silence&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/best-noise-canceling-headphones-over-ear-wireless/embed/#?secret=SaghQzSTds" data-secret="SaghQzSTds" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/sennheiser-partners-with-formlabs-for-customized-headphones/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2112779</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Proptech startup Knock secures $20M to grow SaaS platform for property managers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/proptech-startup-knock-raises-20m-to-grow-saas-platform-for-property-managers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/proptech-startup-knock-raises-20m-to-grow-saas-platform-for-property-managers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 14:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cushman & Wakefield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer relationship management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fifth Wall Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[knock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lead Edge Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[madrona venture group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pew Research Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[property management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proptech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seattle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[second avenue partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114151</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In recent years, the U.S. has seen more renters than at any point since at least 1965, according to a Pew Research Center analysis of Census Bureau housing data.  Competition for renters is fierce and property managers are turning to technology to get a leg up. To meet that demand, Seattle-based Knock – one startup [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In recent years, the U.S. has seen more renters than at any point since at least 1965, according </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">to a Pew Research Center analysis of </span><a href="https://www.census.gov/topics/housing.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Census Bureau housing data</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Competition for renters is fierce and property managers are turning to technology to get a leg up.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To meet that demand, Seattle-based <a href="https://www.knockcrm.com/">Knock </a>– one startup that has developed tools to give property management companies a competitive edge – has raised $20 million in a growth funding round led by Fifth Wall Ventures.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Existing backers Madrona Venture Group, Lead Edge Capital, Second Avenue Partners and Seven Peaks Ventures also participated in the financing, which brings the company’s total capital raised to $47 million.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Demetri Themelis and Tom Petry co-founded Knock in 2014 after renting “in super competitive markets” such as New York City, San Francisco and Seattle. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“After meeting with property management companies, it was eye-opening to learn about the total gap across their tech stacks,” Themelis recalled.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Knock’s goal is to provide CRM tools to modernize front office operations for these companies so they can do things like offer virtual tours and communicate with renters via text, email or social media from “a single conversation screen.” For renters, it offers an easier way to communicate and engage with landlords. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Apartment buildings, like almost every customer-driven business, compete with each other by attracting, converting and retaining customers,” Themelis said. “For property management companies, these customers are renters.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup &#8212; which operates as a SaaS business &#8212; has seen an uptick in growth, quadrupling its revenue over the past two years. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Its software is used by hundreds of the</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> largest property management companies across the United States and Canada and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">has more than 1.5 million apartment units using the platform. Starwood Capital Group, ZRS, FPI and Cushman &amp; Wakefield (formerly Pinnacle) are among its users.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As Petry explains it, Knock serves as the sales inbox (chat, SMS, phone, email), sales calendar and CRM systems, all in one. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We also automate certain sales tasks like outreach and appointment scheduling, while also surfacing which sales opportunities need the most attention at any given time, for both new leases as well as renewals,” he said.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2114161" style="width: 4096px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2114161" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2114161 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/device-horizontal-large.png" alt="" width="4086" height="2860" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/device-horizontal-large.png 4086w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/device-horizontal-large.png?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/device-horizontal-large.png?resize=300,210 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/device-horizontal-large.png?resize=768,538 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/device-horizontal-large.png?resize=680,476 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/device-horizontal-large.png?resize=1536,1075 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/device-horizontal-large.png?resize=2048,1433 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/device-horizontal-large.png?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 4086px) 100vw, 4086px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2114161" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credit: Knock</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company, Themelis said, was well-prepared for the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our software supports property management companies, which operate high-density apartment buildings that people live and work in,” he told TechCrunch. “You can’t just ‘shut them down,’ which has made multifamily resilient and even grow in comparison to retail and industrial real estate.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example, when lockdowns went into effect, in-person property tours declined by an estimated 80% in a matter of weeks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Knock did things like help property managers transition to a centralized and remote leasing model so remote agents could work across a large portfolio of properties rather than in a single on-site leasing office, noted Petry.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It also helped them adopt self-guided, virtual and live video-based leasing tools, so prospective renters could tour properties in person on their own or virtually.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This transformation and modernization became a huge tailwind for our business in 2020,” Petry said. “Not only did we have a record year in terms of new customers, revenue growth and revenue retention, but our customers outperformed market averages for occupancy and rent growth as well.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looking ahead, the company says it </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">will be using its new capital to (naturally!) hire across product, engineering, sales, marketing, customer success, finance and human resources divisions. It expects to grow headcount by 40% to 50% before year-end. It also plans to expand its product portfolio to include AI communications, fraud prevention, applicant screening and leasing, and intelligent forecasting. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fifth Wall partner Vik Chawla, who is joining Knock’s board of directors, pointed out that the macroeconomic environment is driving institutional capital into multifamily real estate at an accelerated pace. This makes Knock&#8217;s offering even more timely in its importance, in the firm&#8217;s view.</span></p>
<p>The startup, he believes, outshines its competitors in terms of quality of product, technical prowess and functionality.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;The Knock team has accomplished so much in just a short period of time by attracting very high quality product design and engineering talent to ameliorate a nuanced pain point in the tenant acquisition process,&#8221; Chawla told TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p>In terms of fitting with its investment thesis, Chawla said companies like Knock can both benefit from Fifth Wall&#8217;s global corporate strategic partners &#8220;and simultaneously serve as a key offering which we can share with real estate industry leaders in different countries as a potential solution for their local markets.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/proptech-startup-knock-raises-20m-to-grow-saas-platform-for-property-managers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114151</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Magical raises $3.3M to modernize calendars</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/magical-raises-3-3m-to-modernize-calendars/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/magical-raises-3-3m-to-modernize-calendars/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 14:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calendar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Workspace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Louisiana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outlook.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resolute ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tel Aviv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114494</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Calendars. They are at the core of how we organize our workdays and meetings, but despite regular attempts to modernize the overall calendar experience, the calendar experience you see today in Outlook or G Suite Google Workspace hasn&#8217;t really changed at its core. And for the most part, the area that startups like Calendly or [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Calendars. They are at the core of how we organize our workdays and meetings, but despite regular attempts to modernize the overall calendar experience, the calendar experience you see today in Outlook or <del>G Suite</del> Google Workspace hasn&#8217;t really changed at its core. And for the most part, the area that startups like Calendly or ReclaimAI have focused on in recent years is scheduling.</p>
<p><a href="https://magicalhq.com/">Magical</a> is a Tel Aviv-based startup that wants to reinvent the calendar experience from the ground up and turn it into more of a team collaboration tool than simply a personal time-management service. The company today announced that it has raised a $3.3 million seed round led by Resolute Ventures, with additional backing from Ibex Investors, Aviv Growth Partners, ORR Partners, Homeward Ventures and Fusion LA, as well as several angel investors in the productivity space.</p>
<p>The idea for the service came from discussions on <a href="https://www.supertools.ai/">Supertools</a>, a large workplace-productivity community, which was also founded by Magical founder and CEO Tommy Barav.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2114524" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Magical_Calendar_v2.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2114524" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2114524" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Magical_Calendar_v2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="511" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Magical_Calendar_v2.png 2891w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Magical_Calendar_v2.png?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Magical_Calendar_v2.png?resize=300,150 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Magical_Calendar_v2.png?resize=768,383 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Magical_Calendar_v2.png?resize=680,339 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Magical_Calendar_v2.png?resize=1536,766 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Magical_Calendar_v2.png?resize=2048,1022 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Magical_Calendar_v2.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2114524" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Magical</p></div></p>
<p>Based on the feedback from the community &#8212; and his own consulting work with large Fortune 500 multinationals &#8212; Barav realized that time management remains an unsolved business problem. &#8220;The time management space is so highly fragmented,&#8221; he told me. &#8220;There are so many micro tools and frameworks to manage time, but they&#8217;re not built inside of your calendar, which is the main workflow.&#8221;</p>
<p>Traditional calendars are add-ons to bigger product bundles and find themselves trapped under those, he argues. &#8220;The calendar in Outlook is an email sidekick, but it&#8217;s actually the center of your day. So there is an unmet need to use the calendar as a time management hub,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Magical, which is still in private beta, aims to integrate many of the features we&#8217;re seeing from current scheduling and calendaring startups, including AI-scheduling and automation tools. But Magical&#8217;s ambition is larger than that.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2114527" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CleanShot_2021-02-11_at_00.47.08.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2114527" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2114527" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CleanShot_2021-02-11_at_00.47.08.png" alt="" width="1024" height="728" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CleanShot_2021-02-11_at_00.47.08.png 1439w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CleanShot_2021-02-11_at_00.47.08.png?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CleanShot_2021-02-11_at_00.47.08.png?resize=300,213 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CleanShot_2021-02-11_at_00.47.08.png?resize=768,546 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CleanShot_2021-02-11_at_00.47.08.png?resize=680,483 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CleanShot_2021-02-11_at_00.47.08.png?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2114527" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Magical</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;We want to redefine how you use a calendar in the first place,&#8221; Barav said. &#8220;Many of the innovations that we&#8217;ve seen are associated with scheduling: how you schedule your time, letting you streamline the way you schedule meetings, how you see your calendar. [&#8230;] But we&#8217;re talking about redefining time management by giving you a better calendar, by bringing these workflows &#8212; scheduling, coordinating and utilizing &#8212; into your calendar. We&#8217;re redefining the use of the calendar in the modern workspace.&#8221;</p>
<p>Since Magical is still in its early days, the team is still working out some of the details, but the general idea is to, for example, turn the calendar into the central repository for meeting notes &#8212; and Magical will feature tools to collaborate on these notes and share them. Team members will also be able to follow those meeting notes without having to participate in the actual meeting (or get copied on the emails about that meeting).</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ll help teams reduce pointless meetings,&#8221; Barav noted. To do this, the team is also integrating other service into the calendar experience, including the usual suspects like Zoom and Slack, but also Salesforce and Notion, for example.</p>
<p>&#8220;It’s rare that you find an entrepreneur who has so clearly validated its market opportunity,&#8221; said Mike Hirshland, a founding partner of <span class="il">Magical</span> investor Resolute Ventures. &#8220;Tommy and his team have been talking to thousands of users for three years, they’ve validated the opportunity, and they’ve designed a product from the ground-up that meets the needs of the market. Now it&#8217;s &#8216;go time&#8217; and I&#8217;m thrilled to be part of the journey ahead.&#8221;</p>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/magical-raises-3-3m-to-modernize-calendars/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114494</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fintech Marqeta expands into credit card space days after filing for an IPO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/fintech-marqeta-expands-into-credit-card-space/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/fintech-marqeta-expands-into-credit-card-space/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 14:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kalpesh Kapadia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marqeta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[risk management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114384</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Marqeta is expanding into the consumer credit card space to help other brands launch credit card programs.  The move comes just days after the payment card issuing company reportedly filed confidentially for an initial public offering, making it the latest fintech to make a move to the public markets. The value of the IPO is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Marqeta is expanding into the consumer credit card space to help other brands launch credit card programs. </span></p>
<p>The move comes just days after the payment card issuing company reportedly filed confidentially for an initial public offering, making it the latest fintech to make a move to the public markets.</p>
<p>The value of the IPO is expected to be around $10 billion, according to<a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-marqeta-ipo/u-s-payments-startup-marqeta-files-with-regulators-for-ipo-source-idUSKBN2AG2JQ"> Reuters.</a> Marqeta &#8212; which is working with Goldman Sachs and JPMorgan Chase on the offering &#8212; is reportedly hoping to complete the IPO by April.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Oakland, California-based <a href="https://www.marqeta.com/">Marqeta</a> raised $150 million last May at a $4.2 billion valuation, TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/providing-card-services-to-fintech-companies-around-the-world-gives-marqeta-a-4-3-billion-valuation/">previously reported</a>. Then in October, Mastercard put <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-mastercard-marqeta/mastercard-backs-card-issuing-start-up-marqeta-idUSKBN26T1WN">an undisclosed amount of money</a> in Marqeta.</p>
<p>The company, which provides the tools for financial services platforms of all stripes to provide cards, wallets and other payment mechanisms, counts Cash App, Affirm, DoorDash, and Instacart among its customers. At the end of 2020, Marqeta says it had issued 270 million cards through its platform, up from 140 million at the end of 2019. The company, which has over 550 employees, is live in 35 countries.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ff8fJpugTN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/providing-card-services-to-fintech-companies-around-the-world-gives-marqeta-a-4-3-billion-valuation/">Providing card services to fintech companies around the world gives Marqeta a $4.3 billion valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Providing card services to fintech companies around the world gives Marqeta a $4.3 billion valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/providing-card-services-to-fintech-companies-around-the-world-gives-marqeta-a-4-3-billion-valuation/embed/#?secret=ff8fJpugTN" data-secret="ff8fJpugTN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, Marqeta is partnering with another startup, Deserve, on its new credit card initiative.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Deserve CEO Kalpesh Kapadia explains it, his company’s technology and open API platform will power Marqeta’s program management services, including origination</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, underwriting, bank and bureau Integration, customer service, compliance and risk management. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Marqeta founder and CEO Jason Gardner described Marqeta’s expansion into building new credit products as a “major milestone” for the company in building out a &#8220;</span>truly comprehensive card issuing platform, able to support any card type.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;This technology is complex, and we saw that this barrier to market had created an opportunity for us to take what we’ve learned helping customers innovate in the prepaid and debit space and adapt that to credit,&#8221; he told TechCrunch.</p>
<div>Marqeta is banking on the notion that any business currently issuing a card is looking, or currently working, on a credit card.</div>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;These innovators want to launch modern card products but having to rely on legacy technology, which allows much less options for flexibility and personalization, has slowed down innovation,&#8221; Gardner added.</p>
<div>It&#8217;s also betting that consumers want more from credit cards than just paying for a purchase.</div>
<p><div id="attachment_2114525" style="width: 347px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2114525" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2114525 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/credit-section-1-image-e1613612706794.png?w=337" alt="" width="337" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/credit-section-1-image-e1613612706794.png 745w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/credit-section-1-image-e1613612706794.png?resize=74,150 74w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/credit-section-1-image-e1613612706794.png?resize=149,300 149w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/credit-section-1-image-e1613612706794.png?resize=337,680 337w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/credit-section-1-image-e1613612706794.png?resize=25,50 25w" sizes="(max-width: 337px) 100vw, 337px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2114525" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Marqeta</p></div></p>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;They want seamless digital experiences, rewards that match their lifestyle, and personalized apps that track financial health, but there’s been little innovation that speaks to this,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>With the COVID-19 pandemic accelerating touchless payments &#8212; as more people avoided in-person interaction and shopping &#8212; the demand for more digital financial offerings has exploded.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With its new initiative, Marqeta aims to be able to help its customers launch new customized credit card products “in a fraction of the time, with more flexible controls and features.”</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example, they will have what Marqeta describes as a modern credit system of record that can adjust account parameters, such as rewards, APR and credit lines, in real time based on custom rules. Customers will have the ability to instantly activate cardholders upon approval and provision cards directly into digital wallets.</span></p>
<p>Gardner called <span style="font-weight: 400;">Menlo Park-based Deserve &#8220;an ideal first strategic partner&#8221; in its expansion into the credit card market. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We plan to offer program management services for customers using our credit card issuing platform through an ecosystem of partners,&#8221; he said. &#8220;They are a good DNA fit for what we’re trying to accomplish &#8211; with a strong belief in the power of open APIs to increase speed to market, and also targeting innovators looking to build truly modern card products. They’re experienced in the credit card space, which has a unique set of requirements, and have a unique approach to underwriting.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For its part, Deserve says its B2B business has been growing in recent years, with it currently adding one prospect every week and one new partner to its business every month. More than 1.5 million consumers have applied and interacted with its platform over the past three years and the company is currently serving hundreds of thousands of customers (directly and indirectly), with tens of millions of dollars transacting every month on its platform, according to Kapadia.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Deserves also manages the entire</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">credit card infrastructure for companies like Sallie Mae in the cloud, whereby consumers applying for and using Sallie Mae credit cards are engaging with Deserve behind the scene. It also provides origination services to companies such as BankMobile. Other fintechs such as Opploans, BlockFi and Earnest use its entire credit card infrastructure to launch their credit products. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">The credit market is dominated by legacy technologies, high cost of operations and lack of customization and speed,” Kapadia told TechCrunch. “Marqeta’s leading card-issuing platform paired with Deserve’s digital card expertise will enable further innovation in the credit industry and provide consumers with superior card experiences.”</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/fintech-marqeta-expands-into-credit-card-space/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114384</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>App monitoring platform Sentry gets $60 million Series D at $1 billion valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/app-monitoring-platform-sentry-gets-60-million-series-d-at-1-billion-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/app-monitoring-platform-sentry-gets-60-million-series-d-at-1-billion-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 13:04:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[application monitoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[application performance monitoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sentry]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114666</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Application performance monitoring startup Sentry announced today that it has reached unicorn status, raising a $60 million Series D with a post-funding valuation of $1 billion. The round was led by Accel and New Enterprise Associates, both returning investors, and Bond. Accel led Sentry&#8217;s seed funding in 2015, and has invested in each of its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Application performance monitoring startup <a href="https://sentry.io/">Sentry</a> announced today that it has reached unicorn status, raising a $60 million Series D with a post-funding valuation of $1 billion. The round was led by Accel and New Enterprise Associates, both returning investors, and Bond.</p>
<p>Accel led Sentry&#8217;s seed funding in 2015, and has invested in each of its rounds since then. The startup, which serves 68,000 organizations, has now raised a total of $127 million. Its clients include Disney, Cloudflare, Peloton, Slack, Eventbrite, Supercell and Rockstar Games.</p>
<p>Sentry&#8217;s software monitors apps for potential issues, helping developers catch bugs before they result in outages, downtime and frustrated users. Its Series D will be used on product development, like adding support for more languages and frameworks, and hiring for its offices in San Francisco, Toronto and Vienna.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While Sentry&#8217;s products are used by a wide range of sectors, it is seeing continued growth in gaming and streaming media, and new demand in industries that are digitizing more of their infrastructure and services, including finance, commerce and healthcare.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JiPoS8sOdF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/14/sentry-launches-new-performance-monitoring-software-for-python-and-javascript/">Sentry launches new performance monitoring software for Python and Javascript</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Sentry launches new performance monitoring software for Python and Javascript&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/14/sentry-launches-new-performance-monitoring-software-for-python-and-javascript/embed/#?secret=JiPoS8sOdF" data-secret="JiPoS8sOdF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In July, Sentry announced the launch of frontend monitoring software for Python and Javascript. At the time, Sentry&#8217;s chief executive officer Milin Desai told TechCrunch that its customers in all verticals were relying more heavily on the platform as the COVID-19 pandemic increased the usage of work, education and e-commerce apps.</p>
<p>In a press statement, Accel partner Dan Levine said, &#8220;With nearly all companies moving to digital-first ways of working and engaging with customers, application health has become a business-critical initiative, and as a result, Sentry is poised for explosive growth.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DO1WB5468n"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/22/customer-experience-and-digital-transformation-concepts-are-merging-during-the-pandemic/">Customer experience and digital transformation concepts are merging during the pandemic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Customer experience and digital transformation concepts are merging during the pandemic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/22/customer-experience-and-digital-transformation-concepts-are-merging-during-the-pandemic/embed/#?secret=DO1WB5468n" data-secret="DO1WB5468n" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/app-monitoring-platform-sentry-gets-60-million-series-d-at-1-billion-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114666</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook knew for years ad reach estimates were based on &#8216;wrong data&#8217; but blocked fixes over revenue impact, per court filing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/facebook-knew-for-years-ad-reach-estimates-were-based-on-wrong-data-but-blocked-fixes-over-revenue-impact-per-court-filing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/facebook-knew-for-years-ad-reach-estimates-were-based-on-wrong-data-but-blocked-fixes-over-revenue-impact-per-court-filing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 12:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ad tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sheryl Sandberg]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114586</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Some more internal emails Facebook really doesn&#8217;t want you to see: Turns out in 2017 COO Sheryl Sandberg had already known for years there were problems with a free ad planning tool the company offers to marketeers to display estimates of how many people campaigns running on its platform may reach, per newly unsealed court [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Some more internal emails <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/23/facebook-really-doesnt-want-you-to-read-these-emails/">Facebook really doesn&#8217;t want you to see</a>: Turns out in 2017 COO Sheryl Sandberg had already known for years there were problems with a free ad planning tool the company offers to marketeers to display estimates of how many people campaigns running on its platform may reach, per newly unsealed court documents.</p>
<p>The filing also reveals that a Facebook product manager for the &#8216;potential reach&#8217; tool warned the company was making revenue it &#8220;should never have&#8221; off of &#8220;wrong data&#8221;.</p>
<p>The unsealed documents pertain to a US class action lawsuit, filed in 2018, which alleges that Facebook deceived advertisers by knowingly including fake and duplicate accounts in &#8216;potential reach&#8217; metric.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Facebook denies the claim but has acknowledged accuracy issues with the &#8216;potential reach&#8217; metric as far back as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/12/09/facebook-corrects-more-metrics-affecting-ad-reach-streaming-reactions-plus-like-share-counts/">2016</a> &#8212; and also changed how it worked in 2019.</p>
<p>While the litigants have continued to accuse Facebook of continuing to misrepresent the ad reach estimate in updates to their 2018 complaint.</p>
<p>Redacted documents from the lawsuit, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-accused-in-amended-lawsuit-of-knowing-ad-audiences-were-inflated-11584745492">reported by the WSJ</a> last year, included the awkward detail that a Facebook employee had asked &#8220;how long can we get away with the reach overestimation?&#8221;</p>
<p>But sections of the filing pertaining to Sandberg and other Facebook executives were redacted.</p>
<p>Newly unsealed documents from the suit &#8212; which we&#8217;ve reviewed &#8212; now reveal that in fall 2017 Sandberg &#8220;acknowledged in an internal email she had known about problems with Potential Reach for years&#8221;.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Tv90EZOzs6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/22/facebook-miscalculation-significantly-inflated-average-video-view-times-for-years/">Facebook miscalculation significantly inflated average video view times for years</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook miscalculation significantly inflated average video view times for years&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/22/facebook-miscalculation-significantly-inflated-average-video-view-times-for-years/embed/#?secret=Tv90EZOzs6" data-secret="Tv90EZOzs6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>They also show Facebook repeatedly rejected internal proposals to fix the issue of fake and duplicate accounts inflating the estimates its platform showed to advertisers of the number of people who could see their ads &#8212; citing impact on revenue as a reason not to act.</p>
<p>In early 2018 Facebook estimated that removing duplicate accounts would cause a 10% drop in potential reach, per the unsealed filing. While Facebook management rejected an employee&#8217;s suggestion to change the language the tool showed to advertisers, declining to swap out the words &#8220;people&#8221; and &#8220;reach&#8221; for the (more accurate) term &#8220;accounts&#8221; &#8212; on the grounds that &#8220;people-based marketing was core to Facebook&#8217;s value proposition&#8221;.</p>
<p>The filing also reveals that a product manager for &#8216;potential reach&#8217;, Yaron Fidler, proposed a fix for the tool that would have decreased its numbers. His proposal was rejected by Facebook&#8217;s metrics leadership on the grounds that it would have a &#8220;significant&#8221; impact on the company&#8217;s revenue &#8212; to which Fidler responded: &#8220;It&#8217;s revenue we should have never made given the fact it&#8217;s based on wrong data.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Always interesting to go back and see what Facebook worked for years to keep sealed. &quot;trade secrets&quot;&#8230;.lol 2/4 <a href="https://t.co/vISCzezjKH">pic.twitter.com/vISCzezjKH</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Jason Kint (@jason_kint) <a href="https://twitter.com/jason_kint/status/1362278582932934656?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 18, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>In <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/12/09/facebook-corrects-more-metrics-affecting-ad-reach-streaming-reactions-plus-like-share-counts/">2016</a>, when Facebook published an <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2016/11/an-update-on-metrics-and-reporting/">update on metrics</a> &#8212; a few weeks after publicly disclosing it had been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/22/facebook-miscalculation-significantly-inflated-average-video-view-times-for-years/?_ga=2.140390259.118496112.1613376463-1757155993.1533833482">over-inflating average video view times</a>, as it sought to regain advertiser trust in its reporting tools &#8212; the tech giant also announced a new channel for &#8220;regular information on metrics enhancements&#8221;, called <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/category/measurement-fyi/">Metrics FYI</a>.</p>
<p>This is where it made the aforementioned fuzzy disclosure of accuracy issues with &#8216;potential reach&#8217; &#8212; writing then that it was &#8220;improving our methodology for sampling and extrapolating potential audience sizes&#8221; to &#8220;help to provide a more accurate estimate for a given target audience and to better account for audiences across multiple platforms (Facebook, Instagram and Audience Network)&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;In most cases, advertisers should expect to see less than a 10% change (increase or decrease) in the audience sizes shown in the tool,&#8221; it added at the time.</p>
<p>However the December 2016 <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2016/12/metrics-fyi-estimated-reach-streaming-reactions-and-graph-api/">blog post</a> did not go into any detail about the nature of the accuracy problems Facebook thought needed improving &#8212; reading more like another classic slice of <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/14/technology/facebook-data-russia-election-racism.html">Facebook crisis PR</a>.</p>
<p>The class action suit, meanwhile, alleges that rather than accepting internal proposals to fix the accuracy problems of &#8216;potential reach&#8217;, Facebook instead &#8220;developed talking points to deflect from the truth&#8221;.</p>
<p>The tech giant did announce some changes to the ad tool in <a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/help/567031670465069">March 2019</a> &#8212; when it said an advertiser&#8217;s campaign&#8217;s estimated potential reach &#8220;is now based on how many people have been shown an ad on a Facebook Product in the past 30 days who match your desired audience and placement criteria&#8221; (vs the estimates being previously based on &#8220;people who were active users in the past 30 days&#8221;).</p>
<p>But the litigants argue that the changes to the tool which displays an estimate to advertisers as they are beginning to create a campaign &#8212; and therefore when they&#8217;re deciding/considering whether/how much money to spend with Facebook &#8212; do not fully fix the issue of the metric not corresponding to the potential audience of people who could see the ad on Facebook.</p>
<p>An analyst report back in <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebooks-claimed-reach-in-the-u-s-is-larger-than-census-figures-analyst-finds-1504711935">2017</a> showed that Facebook&#8217;s ad platform claimed to reach millions more users among specific age groups in the U.S. than official census data indicated reside in the country.</p>
<p>At the time the company said the audience reach estimates &#8220;are based on a number of factors, including Facebook user behaviors, user demographics, location data from devices, and other factors&#8221;, per the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebooks-claimed-reach-in-the-u-s-is-larger-than-census-figures-analyst-finds-1504711935">WSJ</a>, and claimed they are &#8220;not designed to match population or census estimates&#8221;. Facebook added then that it is &#8220;always working to improve our estimates&#8221;.</p>
<p>Asked about the latest batch of unsealed court documents pertaining to the lawsuit &#8212; including the revelation that Facebook&#8217;s COO had told staff she knew about &#8220;problems&#8221; with the ad tool &#8220;for years&#8221; as far back as fall 2017 &#8212; Facebook sent us this statement, attributed to a spokesperson: “These allegations are without merit and we will defend ourselves vigorously.”</p>
<p>Problems with self-reporting ad metrics have been a recurring theme for Facebook.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/facebooks-latest-ad-tool-fail-puts-another-dent-in-its-reputation/">Last year</a> the tech giant disclosed yet another issue on this front &#8212; saying its &#8216;conversion lift&#8217; ad tool had a code error that meant it had miscalculated the number of sales derived from ad impressions for a number of advertisers.</p>
<p>That &#8216;technical problem&#8217; with Facebook&#8217;s internal calculation of the efficacy of third parties&#8217; ad campaigns meant advertisers saw skewed data which they may have used to determine how much to spend on its platform.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NIhFzI2hOk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/12/09/facebook-corrects-more-metrics-affecting-ad-reach-streaming-reactions-plus-like-share-counts/">Facebook corrects more metrics affecting ad reach, streaming reactions, plus Like &amp; Share counts</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook corrects more metrics affecting ad reach, streaming reactions, plus Like &amp; Share counts&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2016/12/09/facebook-corrects-more-metrics-affecting-ad-reach-streaming-reactions-plus-like-share-counts/embed/#?secret=NIhFzI2hOk" data-secret="NIhFzI2hOk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rzfjYQXwid"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/facebooks-latest-ad-tool-fail-puts-another-dent-in-its-reputation/">Facebook&#8217;s latest ad tool fail puts another dent in its reputation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook&#8217;s latest ad tool fail puts another dent in its reputation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/facebooks-latest-ad-tool-fail-puts-another-dent-in-its-reputation/embed/#?secret=rzfjYQXwid" data-secret="rzfjYQXwid" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/facebook-knew-for-years-ad-reach-estimates-were-based-on-wrong-data-but-blocked-fixes-over-revenue-impact-per-court-filing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114586</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yext brings more answers to its site search by processing unstructured data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/yext-answers-orion/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/yext-answers-orion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yext]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114451</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yext Answers allows businesses to provide a better search experience on their own websites — but as the name implies, the goal is really to make sure consumers get the answers they&#8217;re looking for. &#8220;If we deliver a link [in response to a search query], we consider it a failure on our side,&#8221; Chief Strategy [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.yext.com/products/answers">Yext Answers</a> allows businesses to provide a better search experience on their own websites — but as the name implies, the goal is really to make sure consumers get the answers they&#8217;re looking for.</p>
<p>&#8220;If we deliver a link [in response to a search query], we consider it a failure on our side,&#8221; Chief Strategy Officer Marc Ferrentino told me.</p>
<p>Ferrentino said the company will be able to do an even better job of that starting on March 17, with the launch of the &#8220;Orion&#8221; update to its search algorithm.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Yext will then be able to pull answers directly from unstructured pages on a business&#8217; website. The key, he said, is that Yext can &#8220;extract structured information&#8221; from an unstructured document — whether that&#8217;s a webpage, a blog post or a help document — rather than just searching for keywords. So instead of simply presenting a link or a &#8220;blob of text,&#8221; it will offer a &#8220;rich snippet&#8221; that actually answers your question.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2114459" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2114459" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2114459" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PressImages-EQA-1560x878-1.jpg?w=680" alt="Yext Answers" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PressImages-EQA-1560x878-1.jpg 3250w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PressImages-EQA-1560x878-1.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PressImages-EQA-1560x878-1.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PressImages-EQA-1560x878-1.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PressImages-EQA-1560x878-1.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PressImages-EQA-1560x878-1.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PressImages-EQA-1560x878-1.jpg?resize=2048,1153 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/PressImages-EQA-1560x878-1.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2114459" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Yext</p></div></p>
<p>There&#8217;s a good chance that you&#8217;re familiar with something similar from Google&#8217;s consumer search experience, where the results often include a widget with questions and answers. Ferrentino welcomed the comparison, saying this will allow Yext customers to close the &#8220;experience gap&#8221; between Google&#8217;s search experience and their own.</p>
<p>To demonstrate the technology, Ferrentino showed me how Yext Answers could crawl pages about presidential history and then return the correct answer when asked, &#8220;Who was the only U.S. president to be impeached twice?&#8221;</p>
<p>Or for a more commercial (albeit slightly meta) example, he showed me how it could answer questions about Yext&#8217;s technology. As another example, Yext says it could search a bank&#8217;s website to answer a question about the difference between a 401(k) and Roth IRA.</p>
<p>Also worth noting: This change won&#8217;t just improve things for business and their customers, but also Yext&#8217;s non-profit clients, including the World Health Organization, which is <a href="https://www.yext.com/about/news-media/2020-05-world-health-organization-and-yext-collaborate-to-answer-covid-19-questions-online/">using Yext to provide pandemic-related answers online</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lAEFRa4lji"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/21/how-yext-reinvented-itself-on-its-way-to-going-public/">How Yext reinvented itself on its way to going public</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How Yext reinvented itself on its way to going public&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/21/how-yext-reinvented-itself-on-its-way-to-going-public/embed/#?secret=lAEFRa4lji" data-secret="lAEFRa4lji" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/yext-answers-orion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114451</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Leverage Edu raises $6.5 million to help Indian students land in top colleges abroad</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/indias-college-admission-platform-leverage-edu-raises-6-5-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/indias-college-admission-platform-leverage-edu-raises-6-5-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 11:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114603</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Each year, millions of students in India rush to get an admission in universities abroad. Often they don’t know which program they should focus on, or the college that is right for their skillset and ambition. Scores of legacy and newfound firms are attempting to offer counselling to these students. But despite India contributing more [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Each year, millions of students in India rush to get an admission in universities abroad. Often they don’t know which program they should focus on, or the college that is right for their skillset and ambition.</p>
<p>Scores of legacy and newfound firms are attempting to offer counselling to these students. But despite India contributing more international students than any other country, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/04/edtechs-newest-unicorn-applyboard-lands-1-4b-valuation-with-fresh-funding/">most firms</a> aiming to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/22/crimson-education-a-platform-to-help-students-get-into-top-universities-nabs-5m-at-a-245m-valuation/">address this challenge</a> are not focused on India, and struggle to understand some unique problems students in the world’s second most populous country face.</p>
<p>An Indian startup that is bridging this gap on Thursday said it has raised $6.5 million in a new financing round as it looks to scale its platform in the world’s second largest internet market.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://leverageedu.com">Leverage Edu</a> said Tomorrow Capital led the Delhi-headquartered startup’s Series A financing round. Existing investors Blume Ventures and DSG Consumer Partners also participated in the round.</p>
<p>Akshay Chaturvedi, founder and chief executive of Leverage Edu, told TechCrunch in an interview that he believes that eventually the firm that is going to serve the students best and emerge most successful will be the one that is physically closer to them, and not to the universities.</p>
<p>Chaturvedi, 30, began exploring this idea for this startup in 2015 and spent a little more than a year experimenting with different models. One of the earliest iterations of Leverage Edu offered mentorship to students and rewarded counselors with points.</p>
<p>Today, the startup offers a broad range of services in addition to offering personalized mentorship. Through its workshops, it helps students find the right college, guides them with complex applications and grade conversions, as well as assists with education loan, VISA, and accommodation. &#8220;It&#8217;s one digital dashboard. You get everything from flight tickets to local phone numbers, to education loan in one place,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>“We believe it is inevitable that the next stellar brand in the global cross-border education space will be a home-grown one. We have a great belief in Akshay as a founder &#8211; he has a fantastic roadmap for scaling the business and the passion to build a truly global Indian edtech brand &#8211; and are excited about working with the Leverage Edu team on this journey,” said Rohini Prakash, chief executive of Tomorrow Capital, in a statement.</p>
<p>Leverage Edu helps students land admission in the most prestigious colleges, but also works with those that didn’t score the most marks.</p>
<p>“Students going to the top colleges is just 10% of the potential audience,” explained Chaturvedi, who spent his teen years attending talks from startup founders and also made money by bringing more people to those talks.  “There are many universities that don’t have the best branding. To connect them with students, we have our SaaS offering <a href="https://univalley.com">Univalley.com</a>,” he said.</p>
<p>The startup plans to deploy the fresh capital to help students find colleges in more geographies including the UK and Australia, he said.</p>
<p>&#8220;We want to focus on a few things and do them really really well. There is also this myth around foreign education being expensive that we&#8217;ve been busting for last four years. 18 months from now, we want to be among the top study abroad companies in India, both by number of students and a roof-hitting NPS &#8211; because a happy student is why we are all really motivated everyday to do this!”, he added.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/indias-college-admission-platform-leverage-edu-raises-6-5-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114603</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Event networking app Grip raises $13M, as pandemic forces events to stay virtual</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/event-networking-app-grip-raises-13m-as-pandemic-forces-events-to-stay-virtual/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/event-networking-app-grip-raises-13m-as-pandemic-forces-events-to-stay-virtual/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 09:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2114308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With offline events now firmly moved to online for the foreseeable future, startups in the networking space had to pivot fast in the face of the pandemic. One of those was Grip, previously better known as a networking app for physical conferences (including TechCrunch Disrupt, at one point). Since last year, Grip moved into an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With offline events now firmly moved to online for the foreseeable future, startups in the networking space had to pivot fast in the face of the pandemic. One of those was <a href="https://grip.events/">Grip</a>, previously better known as a networking app for physical conferences (including TechCrunch Disrupt, at one point). Since last year, Grip moved into an ‘omnichannel’ experience, combining various event types across virtual, hybrid, and live. That strategy appears to have paid off as it has now raised a $13 million Series A funding round, taking its total amount raised to $14.5 million.</p>
<p>The round was led by London-based growth equity fund Kennet Partners. The raise is reflective of the boom in online events, which saw London-based startup Hopin raise a $40m Series A last year. Founded in 2016, Grip counts some large event organizers as clients including  Reed Exhibitions and Messe Frankfurt.</p>
<p>In a statement Tim Groot, CEO and founder of Grip, said: “Our mission is to empower organizers to bring professionals together to advance industries. This funding round is going to enable us to take the experience to a new level, leveraging our extensive  industry-leading platform, offering unique value for Virtual, Hybrid and In-Person events.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He said they would now be investing heavily in the product and looking to global expansion.</p>
<p>Other competitors to Grip have, in the past, included <a href="https://www.brella.io/">Brella</a> which raised $1.5m, and <a href="https://www.swapcard.com/">Swapcard</a> which raised $6m to date.</p>
<p>So why is it that Grip seems to have pulled away from pack in this way?</p>
<p>Groot told me: “We took a slightly different approach in that we managed to work in a plug-and-play method alongside other platforms. So grip gets used as a standalone virtual event platform by lots of these organizers. So they might use Hopin for the conference but Grip for the networking. So maybe we managed to get more traction that way, over the course of 2020.&#8221;</p>
<p>In 2020, following the pivot to virtual events, Grip hosted over 100 events a month and was used by 1.5m people. As a result, the company says revenue grew almost 4x in 2020, and this year it expects to do over 10,000 events on its platform with over 5 million participants.</p>
<p>Grips AI-powered algorithms mean attendees get more personalized matchmaking recommendations based on their interests, including pre-event meeting scheduling. For exhibitors, the software captures business leads and provides post-event analytics.</p>
<p>People can be added to meetings to have group conversations and the startup is also working on a topic-based “speed networking” functionality to hold instant 3 minute conversations.</p>
<p>Grip integrates with various streaming platforms such as Vimeo, Youtube, Zoom, BlueJeans and others, unlike “full-service” platforms such as Hopin or Bizzabo.</p>
<p>Hillel Zidel, Partner at Kennet and Grip board member, added: “Grip’s ability to organize virtual events with a key focus on networking has meant that the company has seen tremendous growth over the last year. Event organizers and their clients have been able to remain connected with their customers despite the constraints on in-person events. As live events resume in the future, Grip is extremely well-positioned to continue to assist event organizers through the provision of software solutions supporting live, virtual and hybrid events.”</p>
<p>Brent Hoberman, co-founder of Founders Factory and a previous investor, said: “Grip was born out of a need we saw in running events at Founders Forum &#8211; how do you use smart technology to catalyze the most relevant and valuable connections between your guests?”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/event-networking-app-grip-raises-13m-as-pandemic-forces-events-to-stay-virtual/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2114308</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
