<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 10:26:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Twitter fined ~$550k over a data breach in Ireland&#8217;s first major GDPR decision</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/twitter-fined-550k-over-a-data-breach-in-irelands-first-major-gdpr-decision/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/twitter-fined-550k-over-a-data-breach-in-irelands-first-major-gdpr-decision/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 10:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086888</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ireland&#8217;s Data Protection Commission (DPC) has issued Twitter with a fine of €450,000 (~$547k) for failing to promptly declare and properly document a data breach under Europe&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). The decision is noteworthy as it&#8217;s the first such cross-border GDPR decision by the Irish watchdog, which is the lead EU privacy supervisor [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Ireland&#8217;s Data Protection Commission (DPC) has issued <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/twitter" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="twitter">Twitter <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> with a fine of €450,000 (~$547k) for failing to promptly declare and properly document a data breach under Europe&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).</p>
<p>The decision is noteworthy as it&#8217;s the first such cross-border <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/gdpr" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="gdpr">GDPR <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> decision by the Irish watchdog, which is the lead EU privacy supervisor for a number of tech giants &#8212; having a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/lack-of-big-tech-gdpr-decisions-looms-large-in-eu-watchdogs-annual-report/">backlog</a> of some 20+ ongoing cases at this point, including active probes of Facebook, WhatsApp, Google, Apple and LinkedIn, to name a few.</p>
<p>&#8220;The DPC’s investigation commenced in January, 2019 following receipt of a breach notification from Twitter and the DPC has found that Twitter infringed Article 33(1) and 33(5) of the GDPR in terms of a failure to notify the breach on time to the DPC and a failure to adequately document the breach. The DPC has imposed an administrative fine of €450,000 on Twitter as an effective, proportionate and dissuasive measure,&#8221; the regulator writes in a press release.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The GDPR requires most breaches of personal data to be notified to the relevant supervisory authority within 72 hours of the controller becoming aware of the breach.</p>
<p>The regulation also requires they document what data was involved and how they&#8217;ve responded to the security incident &#8212; in order that the relevant data supervisor can check against compliance.</p>
<p>In this case Twitter was found to have failed on both counts.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve reached out to the social media company for comment, including asking whether it plans to accept the decision and pay up &#8212; or if it&#8217;s considering its legal options.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hyeaJ1igmf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/gdpr-enforcement-must-level-up-to-catch-big-tech-report-warns/">GDPR enforcement must level up to catch big tech, report warns</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GDPR enforcement must level up to catch big tech, report warns&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/gdpr-enforcement-must-level-up-to-catch-big-tech-report-warns/embed/#?secret=hyeaJ1igmf" data-secret="hyeaJ1igmf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The DPC&#8217;s decision relates to a breach that Twitter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/17/twitter-bug-revealed-some-android-users-private-tweets/">publicly disclosed in January 2019</a> &#8212; when it said a bug in its ‘Protect your tweets’ feature could have meant some Android users who’d applied the setting to make their tweets non-public may have had their data exposed to the public Internet since as far back as 2014. (Though GPDR would only apply to data the bug exposed since May 2018.)</p>
<p>Since fessing up to the &#8216;Protect your tweets&#8217; bug, Twitter has had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/23/twitter-says-some-business-users-had-their-pivate-data-exposed/">plenty more egg on its face</a> where security is concerned &#8212; including suffering a high profile account hijacking episode <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/15/twitter-accounts-hacked-crypto-scam/">earlier this year</a>, after crypto-scam-spreading hackers gained network access credentials using a social engineering technique.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CT6FkIDzyQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/15/twitter-accounts-hacked-crypto-scam/">Apple, Biden, Musk and other high-profile Twitter accounts hacked in crypto scam</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple, Biden, Musk and other high-profile Twitter accounts hacked in crypto scam&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/15/twitter-accounts-hacked-crypto-scam/embed/#?secret=CT6FkIDzyQ" data-secret="CT6FkIDzyQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Ireland&#8217;s DPC, meanwhile, continues to face criticism for the length of time it&#8217;s taking to reach decisions on major cross-border GDPR cases where impacts on individual rights can scale to hundreds of millions of European Internet users.</p>
<p>Last year commissioner Helen Dixon said its first major GDPR decisions would come &#8220;early&#8221; in 2020.</p>
<p>In the event the first cross-border decision has crossed the line days before the end of the year &#8212; underlining the challenges for the bloc in effectively enforcing its digital rulebook against tech giants. (GDPR technically begun being applied in May 2018, although platform giants have faced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/19/french-court-slaps-down-googles-appeal-against-57m-gdpr-fine/">precious little enforcement to date</a>.)</p>
<p>In this specific case, some half a year extra was added to the decision timeline after a draft outcome Ireland submitted to other EU DPAs for review, back in May, was not accepted by all of them &#8212; triggering a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/twitter-could-face-its-first-gdpr-penalty-within-days/">majority vote mechanism</a> in the GDPR for settling disagreement between the bloc&#8217;s data supervisors.</p>
<p>The European Data Protection Board has published the Article 65 decision and the full final decision <a href="https://edpb.europa.eu/our-work-tools/consistency-findings/binding-decisions_en">on its website here</a>.</p>
<p>The (now) final outcome on the Twitter case comes at a key time &#8212; with EU lawmakers due to set out their next major pieces of digital policy later today, as part of an ambitious push to accelerate regional digitization by rolling out a reassuring promise of European guardrails wrapping around all this tech.</p>
<p>Yet with GDPR enforcement proving such a tedious, friction-filled process that threatens to take the shine off the nascent Digital Services Act and Digital Markets Act many months (or even years) before they can become EU law &#8212; raising questions about how the whole strategy can be expected to function in the absence of effective (i.e. fair but fast) enforcement.</p>
<p>The wider risk here is European citizens losing faith in the rights-based framework they&#8217;re told they enjoy, under EU law and the bloc&#8217;s patchwork of regulatory frameworks, if the animal turns out to be such a plodding house-cat when people do try to obtain relief.</p>
<p>So the Commission&#8217;s strategy of claiming expanded digital rules will act as a public trust booster risks falling into a trough of disillusionment at the legislative proposal stage.</p>
<p>Simple put: You can&#8217;t allow your regulators to move so slowly and expect your rulebook to touch tech giants whose playbook is to move fast in order to disrupt the rule of law in their own business&#8217; interests.</p>
<p>The DPC&#8217;s decision in the Twitter case is thus a measure of how sizeable a gap sits between the rhetoric EU policymakers ply around the bloc&#8217;s &#8216;powerful&#8217; digital rules &#8212; and the messier and more faltering reality: Nearly two years since Twitter disclosed the breach and waiting for a hammer to drop in what should be a relatively straightforward case.</p>
<p>A data breach is not an investigation into the lawfulness of Facebook&#8217;s business model vs GDPR, after all, nor does it delve into the intricacies of Google&#8217;s adtech &#8212; both of which are still open case files on the DPC&#8217;s desk.</p>
<p>The penalty itself is also a fraction (~0.1%) of Twitter&#8217;s full-year 2019 revenue; a far cry from the up to 4% of global annual turnover maximum allowed for under the GDPR (or up to 2% for the specific infringements involved in the breach case). So this first cross-border GDPR decision looks more millstone than milestone for the Commission, at the fag end of 2020.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s not a lot for commissioners to celebrate here, even though they <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/">suggested in the summer</a> that the best answer to GDPR enforcement concerns would be for Ireland to get a decision out. The problem now is the black marks against the bloc&#8217;s record on digital enforcement look stubbornly set in &#8212; just as the Commission is laying out a plan to go <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/30/big-techs-blackbox-algorithms-face-regulatory-oversight-under-eu-plan/">all in on platform regulation</a>.</p>
<p>The questions over enforcement are going to keep coming.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7arL3nJ3K4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/">GDPR&#8217;s two-year review flags lack of &#8216;vigorous&#8217; enforcement</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GDPR&#8217;s two-year review flags lack of &#8216;vigorous&#8217; enforcement&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/embed/#?secret=7arL3nJ3K4" data-secret="7arL3nJ3K4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/twitter-fined-550k-over-a-data-breach-in-irelands-first-major-gdpr-decision/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086888</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Extra Crunch membership now available to readers in Norway, Sweden, Finland, and Denmark</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/extra-crunch-arrives-in-nordics/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/extra-crunch-arrives-in-nordics/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Travis Bernard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 09:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscriptions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086755</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We’re excited to announce that Extra Crunch memberships are now available in several Nordic countries: Norway, Sweden, Finland, and Denmark. For a full list of supported countries, head here. Sign up for Extra Crunch membership here to join our growing community of founders, startup teams, and investors. Use the code NORDICCRUNCH during checkout for an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’re excited to announce that Extra Crunch memberships are now available in several Nordic countries: Norway, Sweden, Finland, and Denmark. For a full list of supported countries, head </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/extra-crunch-supported-countries/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sign up for Extra Crunch membership </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=nordiclaunch"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to join our growing community of founders, startup teams, and investors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use the code </span><b>NORDICCRUNCH</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> during checkout for an additional 25% off an annual or 2-year plan. The discount code expires on January 15, 2021, and it will only work for readers in Europe. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thanks to everyone who voted on where to expand. If you’d like to see Extra Crunch memberships available in your country, <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSefwP6pePyrmSQatUlra2ih3Re3S9APo_CMhFy9c6BaahXM3w/viewform">let us know</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Join Extra Crunch by heading </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=nordiclaunch"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><b>What is Extra Crunch?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Extra Crunch is a membership program from TechCrunch that helps you spot technology trends and opportunities, build better startups, and stay connected. It features thousands of articles, including weekly investor surveys, daily private market analysis, and expert interviews on fundraising, growth, monetization, and other work topics.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’d love to have you join our growing community of founders, investors, and startup teams.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Committing to an annual and two-year plan will save you a few bucks on the membership price and unlock access to TechCrunch event discounts and</span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/extra-crunch-partner-perks/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Partner Perks</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Extra Crunch annual membership gets you 20% off tickets to all TechCrunch 2021 </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/announcing-techcrunchs-2021-event-calendar/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">virtual events</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/15/extra-crunch-members-save-money-with-partner-perks-and-event-discounts/?tpcc=auslaunch"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Partner Perks</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> program features discounts and savings on services from DocSend, Crunchbase, AWS and more.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can sign up or learn more about Extra Crunch </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=nordiclaunch"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/extra-crunch-arrives-in-nordics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086755</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data privacy startup eXate raises £2.3M Seed led by Outward VC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/data-privacy-startup-exate-raises-2-3m-seed-led-by-outward-vc/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/data-privacy-startup-exate-raises-2-3m-seed-led-by-outward-vc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 09:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terms of service]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086889</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Accessing and sharing data is a complicated issue for large businesses, and doing this in a secure, compliant way is a problem for many. eXate, a London-based data software firm is attacking this problem and has now raised a £2.3 million seed round led by Outward VC, with additional backing from ING Ventures and Triple [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Accessing and sharing data is a complicated issue for large businesses, and doing this in a secure, compliant way is a problem for many. <a href="http://www.exate.com">eXate</a>, a London-based data software firm is attacking this problem and has now raised a £2.3 million seed round led by Outward VC, with additional backing from ING Ventures and Triple Point Ventures.</p>
<p>eXate is competing with those that tend to do more specific types of data privacy such as  Hazy, Privitar, and Very Good Security. By contrast, eXate says it aggregates multiple types of privacy into one solution, and provides central governance and control.</p>
<p>eXate was founded by Peter Lancos and Sonal Rattan, former digital business leaders at HSBC. Its clients include ING, its new investor.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Peter Lancos, CEO, eXate, said in a statement: “Organisations that store and process large volumes of data experience many challenges when it comes to data sharing. We see the biggest obstacles arise from the lack of joined-up thinking.  The use of expensive multiple single-point solutions, coupled with monitoring complicated country-by-country policies adds time and budget to data initiatives.”</p>
<p>The funding will enable eXate to capitalize on DataSecOps demand by growing its team, accelerating platform development and expanding into new geographies and verticals.</p>
<p>Andi Kazeroonian, Investor at Outward VC, commented on the investment: “Ensuring the protection of sensitive data is a mission-critical challenge for companies that wish to utilise data to deliver value to its stakeholders. eXate’s unique platform provides companies with the tools it requires to ensure data privacy and protection by design.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/data-privacy-startup-exate-raises-2-3m-seed-led-by-outward-vc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086889</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taxdoo, the tax compliance platform for cross-border e-commerce, raises $21M Series A</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/taxdoo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/taxdoo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 08:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taxdoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086528</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Taxdoo, a startup that has built what it calls an &#8220;automated platform for financial compliance&#8221; aimed at cross-border e-commerce companies, has raised $21 million in new funding. Leading the Series A round is venture capital firm Accel, with participation from Visionaries Club, 20VC and existing investor HTGF. The funding will be invested in Taxdoo’s growth [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.taxdoo.com/">Taxdoo</a>, a startup that has built what it calls an &#8220;automated platform for financial compliance&#8221; aimed at cross-border e-commerce companies, has raised  $21 million in new funding.</p>
<p>Leading the Series A round is venture capital firm Accel, with participation from Visionaries Club, 20VC and existing investor HTGF. The funding will be invested in <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/taxdoo" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="taxdoo">Taxdoo’s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> growth &#8212; including international expansion&#8211; increased hiring, R&amp;D, sales, and customer support. Accel’s Harry Nelis has joined the Taxdoo board.</p>
<p>The inclusion of Harry Stebbings’ 20VC is noteworthy, as the podcaster-turned-VC <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/17/from-twenty-minute-vc-to-20vc-harry-stebbings-launched-a-micro-vc-off-the-back-of-his-popular-podcast/">originally said</a> his micro fund was targeting U.S. startups across various stages, and therefore there wasn’t any perceived conflict with his role as a partner at European VC Stride. Taxdoo is based out of Hamburg, Germany. “20VC essentially invests largely in the U.S. but can also invest where Stride does not, anywhere in Europe outside of the U.K. and Paris,” clarified Stebbings in a WhatsApp message.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Founded in May 2016, after its three founders &#8212; Christian Koenigsheim, Matthias Allmendinger, and Roger Gothmann &#8212; finished their PhDs in finance at the University of Hamburg, Taxdoo wants to use automation to meet the tax and compliance burden faced by cross-border e-commerce companies that sell on various marketplaces and platforms such as Amazon, eBay, and Shopify. This sees those businesses facing increasing complexity around VAT, accounting and other compliance requirements, with data siloed across multiple online systems.</p>
<p>Taxdoo brings that data into a single place and then uses its own tech to automate transaction-level data ingestion, tax calculation and filings across Europe. Customers can also collaborate with their tax advisors through the platform and reduce other compliance burdens, including Intrastat filings.</p>
<p>“While it has become easier and easier to sell products across borders in Europe from a marketing and logistics standpoint, the resulting compliance obligations – like accounting or VAT – are a nightmare for sellers,” Taxdoo’s Christian Koenigsheim tells me.</p>
<p>“Handling these issues manually using spreadsheets is a recipe for disaster. To solve this problem, we&#8217;ve used our in-house expertise to automate the entire process – from the collection of data to the filing of VAT returns in different countries and the integration of transactions into the seller&#8217;s accounting system”.</p>
<p>Koenigsheim says a typical Taxdoo customer sells products on different marketplaces and their own shop, with annual revenues of around €5-10 million. “Our largest customers are global consumer brands with annual revenues of €150 million and above,” he says.</p>
<p>Examples include D2C brands like air up and YFood or e-commerce companies OmniDeal and sellvin. “Among others, we partner with tax professionals, ERP systems, and e-commerce agencies to help them handle these complex issues for their clients,” adds Koenigsheim.</p>
<p>“Our secret sauce is that we automate the entire workflow from end-to-end. This starts with the aggregation of data from different channels like marketplaces, shops, and ERP systems using our automated connectors. Our system [then] analyses data under all applicable regulations and prepares the required returns across the EU, which are filed by an international network of tax partners using a convenient software solution created by us”.</p>
<p>Taxdoo data can also be exported to a seller’s accounting system, enabling them to more easily collaborate with local tax advisors.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the addressable market is growing fast, in part helped by accelerated digitisation during the pandemic and the growth of e-commerce. Taxdoo cites data showing that cross-border transactions now represents approximately 25% of total e-commerce transactions in Western Europe and Scandinavia, and is rising.</p>
<p>Cue statement from Accel’s Harry Nelis: “With a booming e-commerce landscape and companies of all sizes looking to sell their products and services internationally, we see an acute need for integrated financial and tax compliance. Taxdoo’s founders bring together unique experience at the intersection of tax, finance and software and we are excited to work with them to build Taxdoo into a category defining company”.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/taxdoo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086528</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lux Capital&#8217;s Deena Shakir sees space and frontier tech going mainstream right now</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/lux-capitals-deena-shakir-sees-space-and-frontier-tech-going-mainstream-right-now/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/lux-capitals-deena-shakir-sees-space-and-frontier-tech-going-mainstream-right-now/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 07:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deena Shakir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lux capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2087161</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Deena Shakir joined Lux Capital as a partner last year after spending seven years with Google, the last of them with GV, Google&#8217;s venture unit. While Shakir seems to fit right in with the firm &#8212; known for its wealth of PhDs and moonshot investments &#8212; venture wasn&#8217;t something she was focused on as a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/deena-shakir" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="deena-shakir">Deena Shakir <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> joined <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/lux-capital" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="lux-capital">Lux Capital <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> as a partner last year after spending seven years with Google, the last of them with GV, Google&#8217;s venture unit.</p>
<p>While Shakir seems to fit right in with the firm &#8212; known for its wealth of PhDs and moonshot investments &#8212; venture wasn&#8217;t something she was focused on as a career, as she told us during a lengthy interview last week. An Iraqi-American who grew up in Silicon Valley after her parents immigrated to the region, Shakir put herself through both Harvard, then Georgetown&#8217;s School of Foreign Service through a mix of merit scholarships and work and thought she might become a doctor or nab a PhD in anthropology.</p>
<p>Instead, an internship with the BBC saw her cover an historic White House speech, which led her to spend more than two years at the State Department, working for then Secretary Clinton. When she later headed home to be with her family, she was aware that she wanted to make an impact; she didn&#8217;t foresee making it through her investments, yet that&#8217;s what&#8217;s now happening.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>If you don&#8217;t know Shakir, it&#8217;s worth listening to our conversation <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/lux-capitals-deena-shakir-frontier-tech-is-going-mainstream/id1498270180?i=1000502187169">here </a>at some point; in the meantime, here are some lightly edited excerpts that shine a light on where she is placing her bets and why.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Lux is known for investing in rocket companies and satellites, though its website actually lists 21 different industries in its portfolio. Did the firm&#8217;s deals arise from these industries that interest the firm or because of teams that interest the firm and that happen to operate in these industries? </strong></p>
<p>DS: I actually find some of this industry categorization as problematic because if you look through the portfolio, you&#8217;ll see we love healthcare, meats, robotics, AI, food production, industrial IoT, and data meets FinTech. It really is intersectional in terms of how we approach industries; that&#8217;s the nature of how we think about investing. But in terms of how we think about where we want to make investments, we certainly have areas where historically we&#8217;ve spent a lot of time that have given us insights into where there are white spaces [such as having worked on] autonomous vehicles and having insights through that experience into the types of software platforms that could power the next generation of autonomy. So there&#8217;s definitely a lot of generational and evolutionary investing.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Last week, Lux participated in the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/space-manufacturing-startup-varda-incubated-at-founders-fund-emerges-with-9-million-in-funding/">seed round</a> a startup called Varda that is centered around manufacturing in space. What is it trying to make in space and why?</strong></p>
<p>DS: There are few companies that I think would be perceived as more of a Lux fit than Varda. We pride ourselves on companies that turns science fiction into fact [including in the] space space. We were in Relativity Space; we&#8217;re in a number of satellite companies &#8212; Orbital Insight and Planet and several others.</p>
<p>But this is not only a space that we&#8217;re interested in, but also the founding team is one that we&#8217;ve had the chance to get to know over time and felt very strongly about. It is not an intuitive company, which is probably part of the reason why you might be asking about it, like: what exactly do they do, right? At the end of the day, it&#8217;s quite early, but they&#8217;re working on two things that we really love &#8212; manufacturing and space &#8212; abd there are some really interesting innovations that we&#8217;re just at the very beginning of understanding their application in space [including around] physical processes and the supply chain. And this team is at the forefront of taking those on.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Is it going to be manufacturing carbon nanotubes in space to take to the ISS? What&#8217;s the need it&#8217;s addressing?</strong></p>
<p>DK: At the end of the day, the need is around cost and supply chain. It&#8217;s still extremely expensive to launch anything into orbit &#8212; we&#8217;re talking tens of millions of dollars if not more. That&#8217;s the key problem that they want to solve. Manufacturing in space is the hypothesis here. And they have some fascinating and confidential, at this point, hypotheses as to how they will be able to do that.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Is there enough later-stage funding for companies that will need a lot of capital? Lux is now managing $2.5 billion in assets, after raising $1 billion last year. But some space investors say there is not [enough to go around] partly because there haven&#8217;t yet been enough liquidity events.</strong></p>
<p>DK: That&#8217;s interesting, because we got excited about what we now call frontier tech before that was really a category &#8212; certainly before it had any venture-return profile. Now, it&#8217;s becoming increasingly clear that frontier tech is no longer at the frontier. It&#8217;s becoming a key part of many large enterprises. And we&#8217;re seeing huge companies producing rockets en masse. We&#8217;re seeing private companies launch rockets into space and collaborate with NASA. We&#8217;re also seeing venture-funded companies that previously sounded like science fiction that are approaching just phenomenal valuations. So it does seem like we&#8217;re at a turning point here. If you take a look at the cap tables [of] these types of companies, you&#8217;ll see players that may not necessarily have taken those types of bets earlier on.</p>
<p><strong>TC: One of your bets is <a href="https://www.shiru.com/">Shiru</a>, which is leveraging computational design to create enhanced proteins to help feed the world. What does it say about your interests and process?</strong></p>
<p>DS: I spent a lot of time, especially at GV, with some of the alternative protein companies in our portfolio. And a big part of what I&#8217;ve done since my days in government, and certainly throughout my time at Google, has been talking to commercial partners, Fortune 500 companies, and understanding what their needs are. A big part of my role at GV was helping to plug in these large, behemoth companies with up-and-coming tech companies and help them to meet the innovation demands that they have, and that&#8217;s a large part of where my thesis came from.</p>
<p>I genuinely believe that there is a huge opportunity in food that enables these Fortune 500 food companies to meet the increasing demands from consumers, environmental demands, and cost demands [related to] animal-based ingredients. Shiru&#8217;s approach is an interesting one because they are taking a business model that has worked quite well in pharma . . .in enabling the production of novel IP. In this case, [it&#8217;s] novel plant-based proteins, using machine learning and computational biology and actually licensing it to these food companies so they can go on to produce their own versions of the Impossible Burger or Beyond Meat or simply replace a costly animal-based ingredient in one of their products.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Another of your deals is <a href="https://www.allstripes.com/">AllStripes</a>, which aggregates and analyzes medical records, then sells the de identified data to pharma companies to help them develop medicines. So the common thread is machine learning?</strong></p>
<p>DS: Yes, so for me, it&#8217;s about machine learning AI that&#8217;s streamlining a really analog industry, whether it&#8217;s education, whether it&#8217;s finance, whether it&#8217;s food, and certainly healthcare, where I spend the majority of my time.</p>
<p><strong>TC: What are some of the areas you&#8217;re digging into?</strong></p>
<p>DK: Within healthcare, specifically, I am spending a lot of time looking at women&#8217;s health and within women&#8217;s health. I am looking a lot at fertility tech, and I&#8217;ve seen everything from robotic cryo storage to embryo selection to consumerized clinics for IVF. And it&#8217;s definitely an interesting market and one that&#8217;s growing, especially if you look more broadly at demographic trends in terms of women having children later in life, as well as what we&#8217;re seeing in terms of IVF rates and other countries as well.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m a mother of two young kids and had some pretty scary medical experiences myself with with both of their births, and that definitely inspired a look into that space as a patient, but also one where I think there&#8217;s really been underinvestment. I get really frustrated when I hear anyone talk about women&#8217;s health as niche, there is nothing niche about it. From the pure numbers perspective, [women] represents obviously half the population. But women also account for over 80% of dollars spent in healthcare and so companies that are focused on women in the healthcare space are also excellent wedges into other areas.</p>
<p>So outside of those areas in women&#8217;s health, I&#8217;m looking at menopause and at aging in place for anyone across the gender spectrum. Mental health is a huge one, too. I come from a family of physicians. My father is a psychiatrist. In fact, that&#8217;s the reason I grew up in the Bay Area. He came to Stanford in the &#8217;70s for his residency in psychiatry and I&#8217;ve had a lifelong fascination with mental health. In fact, like many children of immigrants, for a hot minute I thought I was going to be a doctor myself and and even interned with VA&#8217;s psychiatry department right before going to college.</p>
<p>Part of why I get excited about it is because it is one of the fields in medicine that&#8217;s still so untouched by tech &#8212; certainly on the data side in terms of being slow to adopt EHRs. On the diagnostic and therapeutic side, there have been some really interesting non-pharmacological interventions for mental health, like TMS (transcranial magnetic stimulation), but it has been elusive to attack and, of course, it&#8217;s top of mind for many folks right now with the mental health burden on everyone at the pandemic. So we&#8217;re seeing a lot of really interesting novel approaches emerge, as well as tailwinds propelling some companies that have been around for a while in a space.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Lux actually formed a $345 million <a href="https://medium.com/lux-capital/announcing-lux-health-tech-acquisition-corp-2f02fa4b39ba">health-care focused SPAC, or special purpose acquisition company, in October.</a> Is that one of many to come and also, is the idea to perhaps back a company that Lux has funded earlier in time or an outfit it has no association with whatsoever?</strong></p>
<p>DS: We believe that SPACs are really powerful for companies that have an exciting big story to tell and whose value isn&#8217;t necessarily best evaluated by looking in the rearview mirror. And given the changing nature of health care, particularly given everything the pandemic has done, it&#8217;s a particularly salient and interesting opportunity for health care.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve have gotten some <em>really</em> interesting inbound from some of the top companies in the healthcare space. As you can imagine, it&#8217;s just a very, very interesting time for healthcare. We&#8217;re not looking at our own portfolio companies. But a number of our companies are going down that path, and we&#8217;re encouraging them to [pursue it].</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/lux-capitals-deena-shakir-sees-space-and-frontier-tech-going-mainstream-right-now/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2087161</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zenoti becomes a unicorn with $160 million funding round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/zenoti-becomes-a-unicorn-with-160-million-funding-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/zenoti-becomes-a-unicorn-with-160-million-funding-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 07:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advent International]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zenoti]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2087176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Zenoti, a 10-year-old startup that develops services for the spa and salon industry, is the latest entrant to the coveted unicorn list. The Bellevue, Washington-headquartered SaaS startup has raised $160 million in its Series D financing round that valued it at “well past $1 billion,” said Sudheer Koneru, founder and chief executive of Zenoti, in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/zenoti" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="zenoti">Zenoti, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> a 10-year-old startup that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/11/zenoti-raises-15-million-for-spa-bookings/">develops services for the spa and salon industry</a>, is the latest entrant to the coveted unicorn list.</p>
<p>The Bellevue, Washington-headquartered SaaS startup has raised $160 million in its Series D financing round that valued it at “well past $1 billion,” said Sudheer Koneru, founder and chief executive of Zenoti, in an interview with TechCrunch earlier this week. The round was led by <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/advent-international" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="advent-international">Advent International <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> with participation from Tiger Global and Steadview Partners. The startup has raised about $251 million to date.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.zenoti.com/">Zenoti</a>, which started its journey in India, has built a cloud management solution for health and wellness industries. The startup’s platform allows customers to pay directly from a mobile app after their appointment. It also checks them in when they walk into the store and notifies the providers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For their clients, Zenoti allows them to accept bookings, accept digital payments, handle payroll, manage backend inventory, and transfer the tip from customers to directly a staff’s bank account. The startup was founded in 2010, but it wasn’t until 2012 when it had built this complete stack and went to the market.</p>
<p>Zenoti’s platform combines both the ERP and CRM tools. And that’s what this industry, which had surprisingly been underserved prior to Zenoti’s entry, needed, explained Shekhar Kirani, partner at <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/accel" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="accel">Accel, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> in an interview with TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Accel was the first investor to back Zenoti. Unlike offerings from companies such as Microsoft and Notion, for instance, that have built “horizontal” services that people across the industries use, the spa and salon industry needed a “vertical” player that just looked at solving the issues that they were facing, he explained. Zenoti did just that.</p>
<p>It became very clear early on that Zenoti could pursue customers beyond India. That early bet has proven right for the startup, for which the U.S. now accounts for 60% of the revenue, followed by the UK. Over 12,000 businesses including Hand &amp; Stone and Gene Juarez in more than 50 countries today use Zenoti&#8217;s offering. The startup works with higher-end businesses.</p>
<p>Kirani described the success of Zenoti as a growing SaaS movement in India, which has produced scores of startups such as Freshworks, Zoho, MindTickle, and Crazybee that started in the world’s second largest internet market but now have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/chargebee-raises-55-million-to-help-businesses-move-to-subscriptions/">most of their customers outside of the country</a>.</p>
<p>Zenoti&#8217;s offerings have proven even more useful in recent months as the pandemic prompted firms to move several aspects of their businesses digital. An increasingly growing number of spa and salon chains that previously did not adopt digital offerings are now embracing mobile apps and ways to cut reliance on paper bills.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are seeing businesses embrace Zenoti’s technology to help pivot and strengthen their offering, and we are impressed by the company’s growth over the last year, particularly among some of the most established brands in the industry,” said Eric Wei, Managing Director of Advent International, in a statement.</p>
<p>Despite the pandemic, the startup has grown by 100% this year, its best to date, and has a large backlog of businesses who want to become customers, said Koneru, who is hopeful to maintain this growth momentum next year. (Zenoti employees also donated $250,000 to help the workers in the industry they serve.)</p>
<p>Zenoti, which employs about 550 people, does not make money from end-customers and instead charges a subscription fee to businesses. Koneru, who previously worked at Microsoft and invested in offline spa businesses, said that while the startup is currently not turning a profit, its margin has improved and the revenue growth has accelerated. He declined to share figures.</p>
<p>The startup plans to deploy the fresh capital to expand to some additional categories such as grooming. In recent months, it has started to serve gyms and other fitness centres. Zenoti is also open to exploring M&amp;A opportunities, Koneru said, adding that these acquisitions would ideally fuel the startup&#8217;s customer growth instead of broadening the technology stack.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/zenoti-becomes-a-unicorn-with-160-million-funding-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2087176</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tencent invests in DJI-backed agritech startup FJ Dynamics</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/tencent-invests-in-dji-backed-agritech-startup-fj-dynamics/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/tencent-invests-in-dji-backed-agritech-startup-fj-dynamics/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 07:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2087168</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Back in 2018, Tencent pledged to put more focus on enterprises as traditional industries in China increasingly tapped technology to boost productivity. The firm&#8217;s industrial projects range from using AI to screen medical images to building customer management tools for retailers on its WeChat messenger. Most recently, Tencent invested in FJ Dynamics, a Chinese startup [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Back in 2018, Tencent <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/02/tencent-reorg-enterprise/">pledged</a> to put more focus on enterprises as traditional industries in China increasingly tapped technology to boost productivity. The firm&#8217;s industrial projects range from using AI to screen medical images to building customer management tools for retailers on its WeChat messenger.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Most recently, Tencent invested in FJ Dynamics, a Chinese startup selling <a href="https://www.fjdynamics.com/en/aboutus">agricultural automation solutions</a> such as smart tractors and rice transplanters as well as unmanned vehicles for ports and factories to clients around the world. The funding from Tencent and other undisclosed investors amounted</span><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> to &#8220;hundreds of millions of yuan&#8221; ($1= 6.55 yuan), Tencent said in an announcement <a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/jA0GHrTCb9cUrQP12QnUzg">on Tuesday</a>. </span></p>
<p>Founded 2017, FJ Dynamics has links to several big-name corporations in China. Among its shareholders are drone maker DJI and Dongfeng Asset Management, a Chinese state-owned automaker, according to the firm&#8217;s <a href="https://www.tianyancha.com/company/3300185708">business registration filing</a>. There are clues in its name, too: FJ is short for &#8220;Feng&#8221; and &#8220;Jiang&#8221; in Chinese, which are taken from the Chinese spelling of Dongfeng and DJI respectively. Its founder and chief executive officer Wu Di also hailed from DJI, where he worked as<a href="https://www.sohu.com/a/376881361_649045"> the chief scientist</a> and led research and development in chips.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">FJD Affordable and Mass-produced Agri-robots. It is not an expensive demo. They support sustainable business for farmers on earth. The series of FJD smart agri-machines includes tractor, transplanter, harvester,etc.. Learn more: <a href="https://t.co/XvMZpBFI7G">https://t.co/XvMZpBFI7G</a>  <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AgriRobot?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#AgriRobot</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Smartfarm?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Smartfarm</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FJD?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FJD</a></p>
<p>&mdash; FJ Dynamics (@FJDynamics) <a href="https://twitter.com/FJDynamics/status/1232579277658324992?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 26, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Interestingly, DJI has also been making a strong push into <a href="https://ag.dji.com/">agricultural drones</a> itself in recent times.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our society is turning to improve productivity, which ushers in growth opportunities for enterprise services,&#8221; <a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s?__biz=MzU2MTM3NjE5Mg==&amp;mid=2247484282&amp;idx=1&amp;sn=5dc135fd3f1eec3c97e3a1bf07638659&amp;chksm=fc78fdd5cb0f74c3f7e2f725b6f2ff00e039830a4c3ab8fe33a376c0a93b54281ad756c56388&amp;scene=21#wechat_redirect">said</a> Jeffrey Li, managing partner of Tencent&#8217;s investment unit, at a speech in April. &#8220;In the U.S., a considerable amount of venture capital and private equity fundings go towards enterprise-focused companies; but in China, enterprised-focused businesses take up only a small share of deals compared to consumer-facing companies. The pivot to industries takes time.&#8221;</p>
<p>Registered in China, FJ Dynamics <a href="https://www.fjdynamics.com/en/aboutus">claims</a> to have R&amp;D centers in China, Sweden, and the Netherlands.</p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/tencent-invests-in-dji-backed-agritech-startup-fj-dynamics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2087168</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dott to expand beyond e-scooters with bike-sharing service</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/dott-to-expand-beyond-e-scooters-with-bike-sharing-service/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/dott-to-expand-beyond-e-scooters-with-bike-sharing-service/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 06:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bike sharing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-bike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric bike]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086083</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dott is better known for its electric scooter service that is available in a few cities across Europe. But the company is working on electric bikes and wants to launch a bike-sharing service in London and Paris in March 2021. Dott currently doesn’t operate in London. So it looks like it’ll be the company’s 16th [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://ridedott.com">Dott</a> is better known for its electric scooter service that is available in a few cities across Europe. But the company is working on electric bikes and wants to launch a bike-sharing service in London and Paris in March 2021.</p>
<p>Dott currently doesn’t operate in London. So it looks like it’ll be the company’s 16th city with this launch.</p>
<p>As for the bike, it has been designed by Dott and it is going to be assembled in Portugal. It is built around a colorful frame made from a single piece of aluminum — there’s no welding. The company also opted for puncture-resistant tyres thanks to foam tyre inserts.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As you can see on the photo, there’s no visible chain as it’s integrated in the frame. The battery can be swapped by Dott without having to bring the entire bike to the charging station. There’s also an integrated geolocation system.</p>
<p>“This European-made bike has been designed inline with our mission: to make mobility accessible to all. Our multimodal (e-bike and e-scooter) service will include the same level of operational excellence: removable batteries, secure charging, operations performed by experienced professionals, systematic repairs and recycling,” co-founder and COO Maxim Romain said in the release.</p>
<p>Dott will compete with Lime, which acquired Jump back in May as part of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/07/uber-leads-170-million-lime-investment-offloads-jump-to-lime/">a deal with Uber</a>. Bolt has also been operating bike-sharing services in some cities.</p>
<p>And, of course, Dott will compete with pay-as-you-go docked bike rental schemes, such as Santander Cycles in London and Vélib’ in Paris. In Paris alone, Vélib’ now has 400,000 subscribers. As it is a subsidized service, it’s going to be hard to compete on price.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/j_VZ53mJ-Ro?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IQz0n1pLAf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/how-four-european-cities-are-embracing-micromobility-to-drive-out-cars/">How four European cities are embracing micromobility to drive out cars</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How four European cities are embracing micromobility to drive out cars&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/how-four-european-cities-are-embracing-micromobility-to-drive-out-cars/embed/#?secret=IQz0n1pLAf" data-secret="IQz0n1pLAf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/dott-to-expand-beyond-e-scooters-with-bike-sharing-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086083</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arya raises $21M to provide farmers in India finance and post-harvest services</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/arya-raises-21-million-for-its-agritech-and-finance-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/arya-raises-21-million-for-its-agritech-and-finance-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quona Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2087138</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Only about a third of the yields Indian farmers produce reaches the big markets. Those whose produce makes it there today are able to leverage post-harvest services. Everyone else is missing out. A Noida-based startup is working with all the stakeholders &#8212; farmers, food processors, traders and financial institutions &#8212; to bridge this post-harvest services [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Only about a third of the yields Indian farmers produce reaches the big markets. Those whose produce makes it there today are able to leverage post-harvest services. Everyone else is missing out.</p>
<p>A Noida-based startup is working with all the stakeholders &#8212; farmers, food processors, traders and financial institutions &#8212; to bridge this post-harvest services gap &#8212; and it just secured new funds to continue its journey.</p>
<p>Seven-year-old <a href="https://www.aryacma.co.in/">Arya</a> said on Tuesday it has raised $21 million in its Series B financing round. The round was led by <a href="https://quona.com/">Quona Capital</a>, a venture firm that focuses on fintech in emerging markets. Existing investors LGT Lightstone Aspada and Omnivore also participated in the round, while multiple unnamed lenders are providing additional debt financing to the startup, Arya said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Nearly all post-harvest interventions that exist in India today are focused largely toward major agriculture centres such as Kota in the northern Indian state of Rajasthan and Azadpur Mandi in capital New Delhi, explained Prasanna Rao, co-founder and chief executive of Arya, in an interview with TechCrunch.</p>
<p>This uneven concentration has deprived millions of farmers in the country of reasonable options to efficiently store and sell their produce and of financing options to maintain their cash flow, he said.</p>
<p>“Our belief is that we should cater to the two-thirds of the market that are currently underserved. The Kota mandi (market), for instance, has 35 bank branches in a kilometre of radius. But if you travel 70 to 80 kilometres away from Kota, this really declines,” said Rao, who previously worked at a bank.</p>
<p>Arya is solving all the aforementioned challenges: It operates a network of more than 1,500 warehouses in 20 Indian states where it stores over $1 billion worth of commodities. This network allows farmers to store their produce at a centre that is much nearer to their farms, avoiding any spillage and exorbitant real estate costs of the big markets. On the credit side, Arya has disbursed over $36.5 million to farmers and its banking partners have disbursed more than $95 million.</p>
<p>“Arya is addressing a vastly underserved market of farmers in India, half of whom previously had little access to post-harvest finance,” said Ganesh Rengaswamy, co-founder and partner at <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/quona-capital-management" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="quona-capital-management">Quona Capital, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> in a statement. “We believe Arya’s unique approach, providing a full-service digital platform with embedded finance and differentiated efficiencies for small farmholders, will drive the future of farming in India.”</p>
<p>The startup’s offerings have proven even more useful during the coronavirus pandemic, which saw New Delhi <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/04/amazon-flipkart-ola-and-uber-begin-to-resume-their-services-in-india/">enforce one of the world’s strictest lockdowns</a> earlier this year. The lockdown broke the supply chain network, and prices of agricultural commodities dropped by over 20%.</p>
<p>To navigate this, Arya connected farmer produce organizers, or FPOs, with buyers through its own digital marketplace <a href="https://www.a2zgodaam.com/">a2zgodaam.com</a>. “The need for immediate liquidity saw demand increase for credit against these warehouse receipts. Arya’s credit portfolio saw a 3x jump year-on-year,” <a href="https://www.seedtoscale.com/blog/post-covid-agritech-landscape-in-india">wrote</a> Prashanth Prakash, a founding partner at Accel in India, and Mark Kahn, managing partner at Omnivore in an industry report last week.</p>
<p>Rao said Arya will deploy the fresh capital to scale its fintech platform in a “big way” as the startup broadens its network of warehouses across the country. Additionally, the startup plans to fuel the growth of a2zgodaam.com, which also aggregates unorganized warehouses, and supercharge them with their own set of financiers and insurers and ways to allow farmers to sell directly through these warehouses if they need.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="25jzWZfpY4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/04/amazon-flipkart-ola-and-uber-begin-to-resume-their-services-in-india/">Amazon, Flipkart, Ola and Uber begin to resume their services in India</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon, Flipkart, Ola and Uber begin to resume their services in India&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/04/amazon-flipkart-ola-and-uber-begin-to-resume-their-services-in-india/embed/#?secret=25jzWZfpY4" data-secret="25jzWZfpY4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/arya-raises-21-million-for-its-agritech-and-finance-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2087138</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK Online Harms Bill, coming next year, will propose fines of up to 10% of annual turnover for breaching duty of care rules</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/uk-online-harms-bill-coming-next-year-will-propose-fines-of-up-to-10-of-annual-turnover-for-breaching-duty-of-care-rules/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/uk-online-harms-bill-coming-next-year-will-propose-fines-of-up-to-10-of-annual-turnover-for-breaching-duty-of-care-rules/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illegal content]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ofcom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK Online Harms Bill]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2087013</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.K. is moving ahead with a populist but controversial plan to regulate a wide range of illegal and/or harmful content almost anywhere online such stuff might pose a risk to children. The government has set out its final response to the consultation it kicked off back in April 2019 &#8212; committing to introduce an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The U.K. is moving ahead with a populist but controversial plan to regulate a wide range of illegal and/or harmful content almost anywhere online such stuff might pose a risk to children. The government has set out its final response to the consultation it kicked off back in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/08/uk-sets-out-safety-focused-plan-to-regulate-internet-firms/">April 2019</a> &#8212; committing to introduce an Online Safety Bill next year.</p>
<p>&#8220;Tech platforms will need to do far more to protect children from being exposed to harmful content or activity such as grooming, bullying and pornography. This will help make sure future generations enjoy the full benefits of the internet with better protections in place to reduce the risk of <span class="il">harm</span>,&#8221; it said today.</p>
<p>In an earlier partial response to the consultation on its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/08/uk-sets-out-safety-focused-plan-to-regulate-internet-firms/">Online Harms white paper</a> ministers confirmed the U.K.&#8217;s media regulator, Ofcom, as its pick for enforcing the forthcoming rules.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rhWxyBu3xF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/08/uk-sets-out-safety-focused-plan-to-regulate-internet-firms/">UK sets out safety-focused plan to regulate internet firms</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;UK sets out safety-focused plan to regulate internet firms&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/08/uk-sets-out-safety-focused-plan-to-regulate-internet-firms/embed/#?secret=rhWxyBu3xF" data-secret="rhWxyBu3xF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Under the plans announced today, the government said <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/ofcom" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="ofcom">Ofcom <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> will be able to levy fines of up to 10% of a company&#8217;s annual global turnover (or £18 million, whichever is higher) on those that are deemed to have failed in their duty of care to protect impression eyeballs from being exposed to illegal material &#8212; such as child sexual abuse, terrorist material or suicide-promoting content.</p>
<p>Ofcom will also have the power to block non-compliant services from being accessed in the U.K. &#8212; although it&#8217;s not clear how exactly that will be achieved (or whether the legislation will seek to prevent VPNs being used by Brits to access blocked internet services).</p>
<p>The regulator&#8217;s running costs will be paid by companies that fall under the scope of the law, above a threshold based on global annual revenue, per the government, although it&#8217;s not yet clear where that pay-bar will kick in (nor how much tech giants and others will have to stump up for the cost of the oversight).</p>
<p>The online safety &#8220;duty of care&#8221; rules are intended to cover not just social media giants like Facebook but a wide range of internet services &#8212; from dating apps and search engines to online marketplaces, video sharing platforms and instant messaging tools, as well as consumer cloud storage and even video games that allow relevant user interaction.</p>
<p>P2P services, online forums and pornography websites will also fall under the scope of the laws, as will quasi-private messaging services, according to a government press release.</p>
<p>That raises troubling questions about whether the legal requirements could put pressure on companies not to use end-to-end encryption (i.e. if they face being penalized for not being able to monitor robustly encrypted content for illegal material).</p>
<p>&#8220;The new regulations will apply to any company in the world hosting user-generated content <span class="il">online</span> accessible by people in the UK or enabling them to privately or publicly interact with others <span class="il">online</span>,&#8221; the government writes in a press release.</p>
<p>The rules will include different categories of responsibility for content and activity &#8212; with a top tier (category 1) only applying to companies with &#8220;the largest <span class="il">online</span> presences and high-risk features,&#8221; which the government said is likely to include Facebook, TikTok, Instagram and Twitter.</p>
<p>&#8220;These companies will need to assess the risk of legal content or activity on their services with &#8216;a reasonably foreseeable risk of causing significant physical or psychological <span class="il">harm</span> to adults&#8217;. They will then need to make clear what type of &#8216;legal but harmful&#8217; content is acceptable on their platforms in their terms and conditions and enforce this transparently and consistently,&#8221; it said.</p>
<p>Category 1 companies will also have a legal requirement to publish transparency reports about the steps they are taking to tackle <span class="il">online</span> <span class="il">harms</span>, per the government&#8217;s PR.</p>
<p>While all companies that fall under the scope of the law will be required to have mechanisms so people can easily report harmful content or activity while also being able to appeal the takedown of content, it added.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The government believes that less than 3% of U.K. businesses will fall within the scope of the legislation &#8212; adding that &#8220;the vast majority&#8221; will be Category 2 services.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Protections for free speech are also slated as being baked in &#8212; with the government saying the laws will <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">not affect articles and comments sections on news websites, for example. </span></p>
<p dir="ltr">The legislation will contain provisions to impose criminal sanctions on senior managers (introduced by parliament via secondary legislation). On this the government added that it will not hesitate to use the power if companies fail to take the new rules seriously (such as by not responding &#8220;fully, accurately and in a timely manner&#8221; to information requests from Ofcom).</p>
<p dir="ltr">Commenting on the plans in a statement, digital secretary Oliver Dowden said: &#8220;I’m unashamedly pro tech but that can’t mean a tech free for all. Today Britain is setting the global standard for safety <span class="il">online</span> with the most comprehensive approach yet to <span class="il">online</span> regulation. We are entering a new age of accountability for tech to protect children and vulnerable users, to restore trust in this industry, and to enshrine in law safeguards for free speech.</p>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;This proportionate new framework will ensure we don’t put unnecessary burdens on small businesses but give large digital businesses robust rules of the road to follow so we can seize the brilliance of modern technology to improve our lives.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">In another supporting statement, home secretary Priti Patel added: &#8220;Tech companies must put public safety first or face the consequences.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">Also commenting, Ofcom CEO Dame Melanie Dawes welcomed its new broader oversight remit, adding in a statement that: &#8220;Being <span class="il">online</span> brings huge benefits, but four in five people have concerns about it. That shows the need for sensible, balanced rules that protect users from serious <span class="il">harm</span>, but also recognise the great things about <span class="il">online</span>, including free expression. We’re gearing up for the task by acquiring new technology and data skills, and we’ll work with Parliament as it finalises the plans.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">The government has said it will publish Interim Codes of Practice today to provide guidance for companies on tackling terrorist activity and <span class="il">online</span> child sexual exploitation prior to the introduction of legislation &#8212; which is unlikely to make it into law before late 2021 at the earliest to allow adequate time for parliamentary debate and scrutiny.</p>
<p dir="ltr">And while a noisy political push to &#8220;protect kids&#8221; online can expect to enjoy plenty of tabloid-level support, the wide-ranging application of the duty of care rules the government is envisaging &#8212; with large swathes of the U.K.&#8217;s tech sector set to be impacted &#8212; means ministers can expect to attract plenty of homegrown criticism too, from business groups, entrepreneurs and investors and legal and policy experts, including over specific concerns about knock-on impacts on privacy and security.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Its plan to push ahead with an Online Safety Bill that will impact scores of smaller digital businesses, instead of zeroing in on the handful of platform giants that are responsible for generating high volumes of harms, has already attracted criticism from the tech sector.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Coadec, a digital policy group that advocates for startups and the U.K. tech sector, branded the plan &#8220;a confusing minefield&#8221; for entrepreneurs &#8212; arguing it will do the opposite of fostering digital competition, counteracting other measures <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/27/uk-to-set-up-pro-competition-regulator-to-put-limits-on-big-tech/">recently announced</a> by the government in response to concerns about market concentration in the digital advertising sphere.</p>
<p>“Last week the Government announced a new unit within the CMA [Competition and Markets Authority] to promote greater competition within digital markets. Days later they have announced regulatory measures that risk having the opposite effect,&#8221; said Dom Hallas, Coadec&#8217;s executive director in a statement. &#8220;86% of UK investors say that regulation aiming to tackle big tech could lead to poor outcomes that damage tech startups and limit competition &#8212; these plans risk being a confusing minefield that will have a disproportionate impact on competitors and benefit big companies with the resources to comply.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;British startups want a safer internet. But it’s not clear how these proposals, which still cover a huge range of services that are nowhere near social media from ecommerce to the sharing economy, are better targeted than the last time government published proposals nearly a year and a half ago,&#8221; he added. &#8220;Until the Government starts to work collaboratively instead of consistently threatening startup founders with jail time it’s not clear how we’re going to deliver proposals that work.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QveMcVxPmq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/27/uk-to-set-up-pro-competition-regulator-to-put-limits-on-big-tech/">UK to set up &#8216;pro-competition&#8217; regulator to put limits on big tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;UK to set up &#8216;pro-competition&#8217; regulator to put limits on big tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/27/uk-to-set-up-pro-competition-regulator-to-put-limits-on-big-tech/embed/#?secret=QveMcVxPmq" data-secret="QveMcVxPmq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>One gap in the government&#8217;s proposal is financial harms &#8212; with issues such as fraud and the sale of unsafe goods explicitly excluded from the framework (as it says it wants the regulations to be &#8220;clear and manageable&#8221; for businesses and to avoid the risk of duplicating existing rules).</p>
<p>Some &#8220;lower-risk&#8221; services may also be exempt from the duty of care requirement, per the government, to avoid the law being overly burdensome.</p>
<p>Email services will also not be in scope, it confirmed.</p>
<p>And while it says some types of advertising will be in scope (such as influencer ads posted on social media) ads placed on an in-scope service via a direct contract between an advertiser and an advertising service (such as Facebook or Google Ads) will be exempt because &#8220;this is covered by existing regulation&#8221; &#8212; which looks set to let the adtech duopoly off the harmful ads hook without good clear reason.</p>
<p>After all, existing U.K. regulations do not seem to have done much to stem the tide of crypto scam ads running on Facebook (or served via Google&#8217;s ad tools) in recent years &#8212; which led to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/23/facebook-agrees-to-do-more-to-tackle-scam-ads-after-celebrity-defamation-lawsuit/">a campaign by a consumer advice personality</a> to get Facebook and other companies to clean up their act, for example.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8QL387BPWg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/23/facebook-agrees-to-do-more-to-tackle-scam-ads-after-celebrity-defamation-lawsuit/">Facebook agrees to do more to tackle scam ads after celebrity defamation lawsuit</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook agrees to do more to tackle scam ads after celebrity defamation lawsuit&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/23/facebook-agrees-to-do-more-to-tackle-scam-ads-after-celebrity-defamation-lawsuit/embed/#?secret=8QL387BPWg" data-secret="8QL387BPWg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Consumer group <em>Which?</em> has criticized the lack of government attention to financial scams in the Online Safety Bill. In a response statement, Rocio Concha, its director of policy and advocacy, said: “It’s positive that the government is recognising the responsibility of online platforms to protect users, but it would be a big missed opportunity if online scams were not dealt with through the upcoming bill. Our research has shown the financial and emotional toll of scams and that social media firms such as Facebook and search engines like Google need to do much more to protect users.</p>
<p>&#8220;We look forward to the detail and hope to see a clear plan to give online platforms greater responsibility for fraudulent content on their sites, including having in place better controls to prevent fake adverts from appearing, so that all users can be confident that they will truly be safe online.&#8221;</p>
<p>European Union lawmakers are due to unveil their own pan-EU policy package to regulate illegal and harmful content later today &#8212; but the Digital Services Act will tackle the sale of illegal goods online as well as proposing to harmonize rules for reporting troublesome content on online services.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bLQfdxft5D"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/europe-to-limit-how-big-tech-can-push-its-own-services-and-use-third-party-data/">Europe to limit how big tech can push its own services and use third-party data</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe to limit how big tech can push its own services and use third-party data&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/europe-to-limit-how-big-tech-can-push-its-own-services-and-use-third-party-data/embed/#?secret=bLQfdxft5D" data-secret="bLQfdxft5D" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/uk-online-harms-bill-coming-next-year-will-propose-fines-of-up-to-10-of-annual-turnover-for-breaching-duty-of-care-rules/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2087013</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Apple launches Fitness+</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/daily-crunch-apple-launches-fitness/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/daily-crunch-apple-launches-fitness/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 23:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2087066</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We review Apple Fitness+, Gmail goes down and Pornhub cracks down on unverified content. This is your Daily Crunch for December 14, 2020. The big story: Apple launches Fitness+ Brian Heater tried out Apple&#8217;s new $10-per-month subscription service for guided workouts, prompting some broader reflections on exercise during this terrible year — and on how [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We review <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/apple" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="apple">Apple <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Fitness+, Gmail goes down and Pornhub cracks down on unverified content. This is your Daily Crunch for December 14, 2020.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: Apple launches Fitness+</strong></p>
<p>Brian Heater tried out <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/fitness-wont-replace-the-gym-but-it-will-help-you-break-a-sweat/">Apple&#8217;s new $10-per-month subscription service for guided workouts</a>, prompting some broader reflections on exercise during this terrible year — and on how Fitness+ might fit in.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The service requires an Apple Watch to sign up, which is a hurdle if (like me) you don&#8217;t already own the device, but Brian writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>Honestly, the Apple Watch integration is probably the best-executed aspect of the entire undertaking — down to the way the wearable doubles as a start and stop button for the workout. It also ensures a more complete rundown of your workouts at the end of the day.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/gmail-youtube-google-docs-and-other-services-go-down-simultaneously-in-multiple-countries/">Gmail, YouTube, Google Docs and other services go down in multiple countries</a> — A huge range of Google services went down for about an hour today.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/reddit-acquires-dubsmash/">Reddit acquires Dubsmash</a> — Dubsmash will retain its own platform and brand, while Reddit will integrate its video creation tools.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/apple-launches-its-new-app-privacy-labels-across-all-its-app-stores/">Apple launches its new app privacy labels across all its App Stores</a> — The new labels aim to give Apple customers an easier way to understand what sort of information an app collects across three categories.</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/tonic-synthetic-data/">Tonic is betting that synthetic data is the new big data to solve scalability and security</a> — Tonic transforms raw data into more manageable and private data sets usable by software engineers and business analysts.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/german-bionic-raises-20m-led-by-samsung-for-exoskeleton-tech-to-supercharge-human-labor/">German Bionic raises $20M led by Samsung for exoskeleton tech to supercharge human labor</a> — The company describes its Cray X robot as “the world’s first connected exoskeleton for industrial use.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/mombox-is-a-curated-kit-of-postnatal-products-that-puts-new-moms-first/">Mombox is a curated kit of postnatal products that puts new moms first</a> — The standard Mombox includes organic overnight pads, a peri bottle, perineal ice pack, post-pregnancy panties and other care products.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/hype-machine-sinan-aral/">MIT professor wants to overhaul ‘The Hype Machine’ that powers social media</a> — Sinan Aral has spent years analyzing the social media market.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/5-questions-every-it-team-should-to-be-able-to-answer/">Five questions every IT team should be able to answer</a> — When the CEO comes calling, are you prepared?</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/ipo-delays-are-bumming-me-out/">IPO delays are bumming me out</a> — Roblox is on ice and Affirm could slip.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which aims to democratize information about startups. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/fda-grants-emergency-use-authorization-for-pfizers-covid-19-vaccine-distribution-to-begin-within-days/">FDA grants emergency use authorization for Pfizer’s COVID-19 vaccine, distribution to begin within days</a> — And vaccinations started today!</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/pornhub-removes-all-unverified-content-following-reports-of-exploitation/">Pornhub removes all unverified content, following reports of exploitation</a> — Pornhub announced last week that it would be limiting uploads to only verified users.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/original-content-mank/">Original Content podcast: David Fincher presents a compelling character study in ‘Mank’</a> — Gary Oldman delivers a mesmerizing performance as the co-writer of &#8220;Citizen Kane.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/daily-crunch-apple-launches-fitness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2087066</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FTC orders ByteDance, Facebook, Snap and others to explain what they do with user data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/ftc-tiktok-amazon-facebook-social-media-study/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/ftc-tiktok-amazon-facebook-social-media-study/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 22:15:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. government]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086946</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The FTC is ordering the companies behind many of the largest social and video platforms to explain how they use the treasure troves of data they harvest from users. Amazon, TikTok owner ByteDance, Facebook, WhatsApp, Discord, Reddit, Snap, Twitter and YouTube were all sent the order, with a deadline set 45 days from now. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/federal-trade-commission" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="federal-trade-commission">FTC <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is ordering the companies behind many of the largest social and video platforms to explain how they use the treasure troves of data they harvest from users. Amazon, TikTok owner ByteDance, Facebook, WhatsApp, Discord, Reddit, Snap, Twitter and YouTube <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2020/12/ftc-issues-orders-nine-social-media-video-streaming-services">were all sent the order</a>, with a deadline set 45 days from now.</p>
<p>The FTC&#8217;s focus is on how these companies &#8220;collect, use, and present personal information, their advertising and user engagement practices, and how their practices affect children and teens.&#8221; Four of the FTC&#8217;s commissioners voted in favor of the order, with Commissioner Noah Joshua Phillips dissenting.</p>
<p>&#8220;Despite their central role in our daily lives, the decisions that prominent online platforms make regarding consumers and consumer data remain shrouded in secrecy,&#8221; Commissioners Rohit Chopra, Rebecca Kelly Slaughter and Christine S. Wilson said in a joint statement.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;&#8230; Policymakers and the public are in the dark about what social media and video streaming services do to capture and sell users’ data and attention. It is alarming that we still know so little about companies that know so much about us.&#8221;</p>
<p>The FTC&#8217;s new fact-finding mission is the latest federal action to put tech in its crosshairs, following last week&#8217;s news that the agency would <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/ftc-seeks-to-break-up-facebook-alleging-illegal-monopoly/">sue Facebook over antitrust violations</a>. The new order was issued under Section 6(b) of the FTC Act as a study of tech industry practices. It isn&#8217;t coupled with any law enforcement action, but that doesn&#8217;t preclude the agency from pursuing enforcement options with what it finds.</p>
<p>Last year the FTC signaled a deeper interest in tech, particularly on antitrust issues. The agency launched a purpose-built tech task force to monitor acquisitions and other potential competition-crushing behavior that raises red flags. In early 2020, the FTC launched an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/11/ftc-to-examine-every-acquisition-by-alphabet-amazon-apple-facebook-and-microsoft-in-2010-2019-over-antitrust-issues/">extensive separate study</a> examining nearly a decade&#8217;s worth of acquisitions made by Alphabet, Amazon, Apple, Facebook and Microsoft.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="afmafTnWDu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/ftc-seeks-to-break-up-facebook-alleging-illegal-monopoly/">FTC seeks to break up Facebook, alleging illegal monopoly</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;FTC seeks to break up Facebook, alleging illegal monopoly&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/ftc-seeks-to-break-up-facebook-alleging-illegal-monopoly/embed/#?secret=afmafTnWDu" data-secret="afmafTnWDu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/ftc-tiktok-amazon-facebook-social-media-study/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086946</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pinterest settles gender discrimination lawsuit with former COO for $22.5 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/pinterest-settles-gender-discrimination-lawsuit-with-former-coo-for-22-5-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/pinterest-settles-gender-discrimination-lawsuit-with-former-coo-for-22-5-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Megan Rose Dickey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 22:03:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pinterest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Include]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086996</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pinterest today announced it has settled the gender discrimination lawsuit brought forth by former COO Francoise Brougher. In August, Brougher sued Pinterest, alleging gender discrimination, retaliation and wrongful termination. As part of the settlement, Pinterest will pay $20 million to Brougher and her attorneys, and both Pinterest and Brougher will commit $2.5 million toward &#8220;Advancing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/pinterest" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="pinterest">Pinterest <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a href="https://d18rn0p25nwr6d.cloudfront.net/CIK-0001506293/3fef4e2e-328e-449a-8971-469b1f68011a.pdf">today announced</a> it has settled the gender discrimination lawsuit brought forth by former COO Francoise Brougher. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/former-coo-sues-pinterest-accusing-it-of-gender-discrimination-retaliation-and-wrongful-termination/">In August</a>, Brougher sued Pinterest, alleging gender discrimination, retaliation and wrongful termination.</p>
<p>As part of the settlement, Pinterest will pay $20 million to Brougher and her attorneys, and both Pinterest and Brougher will commit $2.5 million toward &#8220;Advancing women and underrepresented communities&#8221; in the tech industry, <a href="https://d18rn0p25nwr6d.cloudfront.net/CIK-0001506293/3fef4e2e-328e-449a-8971-469b1f68011a.pdf">the company wrote in a filing</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;Pinterest recognizes the importance of fostering a workplace environment that is diverse, equitable and inclusive and will continue its actions to improve its culture,&#8221; Pinterest and Brougher said in a joint statement detailing the settlement. &#8220;Francoise welcomes the meaningful steps Pinterest has taken to improve its workplace environment and is encouraged that Pinterest is committed to building a culture that allows all employees to feel included and supported.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Shortly after Brougher went public with her claims, Pinterest employees staged a walkout in response to her accusations as well as in response to the claims of two former Black Pinterest employees. Prior to Brougher&#8217;s claims, <a href="https://twitter.com/erikashimizu/status/1272547227177713664">Aerica Shimizu Banks</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/ifeomaozoma/status/1272546213322080258">Ifeoma Ozoma</a> accused Pinterest of racial discrimination.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ezm5NWksfb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/former-coo-sues-pinterest-accusing-it-of-gender-discrimination-retaliation-and-wrongful-termination/">Former COO sues Pinterest, accusing it of gender discrimination, retaliation and wrongful termination</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Former COO sues Pinterest, accusing it of gender discrimination, retaliation and wrongful termination&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/former-coo-sues-pinterest-accusing-it-of-gender-discrimination-retaliation-and-wrongful-termination/embed/#?secret=Ezm5NWksfb" data-secret="Ezm5NWksfb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In addition to the walkout, <a href="https://www.coworker.org/petitions/put-an-end-to-all-forms-of-discrimination-and-retaliation-at-pinterest-1">a petition circulated throughout the company demanding systemic change</a>. The change they sought entailed full transparency about promotion levels and retention, total compensation package transparency and for the people within two layers of reporting to the CEO to be at least 25% women and 8% underrepresented employees.</p>
<p>Since then, Pinterest has notably made some changes at the board level. A couple of days after the walkout, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/17/pinterest-announces-first-black-board-member/">Pinterest announced Andrea Wishom as the company&#8217;s first-ever Black board member</a>. In October, Pinterest added its second Black board member, Salaam Coleman Smith.</p>
<p>Pinterest says it has also enhanced its hiring and interview processes to try to improve diversity at senior levels, updated its inclusion training and launched an internal wiki detailing how Pinterest makes compensation decisions.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FIdVbKSXvc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/17/pinterest-announces-first-black-board-member/">Pinterest announces first Black board member</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pinterest announces first Black board member&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/17/pinterest-announces-first-black-board-member/embed/#?secret=FIdVbKSXvc" data-secret="FIdVbKSXvc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/pinterest-settles-gender-discrimination-lawsuit-with-former-coo-for-22-5-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086996</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gift Guide: Fun photography gear to brighten up the holidays</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/gift-guide-photography-2020-best-photography-gifts-ideas-for-photographers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/gift-guide-photography-2020-best-photography-gifts-ideas-for-photographers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 20:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gift Guide 2020]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086245</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It's a difficult time to be a photographer. Getting creative feels impossible when every day is the same and the most exotic locale you visit is the living room. Travel is out this year, vacations are pushed back and everybody is cooped up inside trying not to lose it.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome to TechCrunch’s 2020 Holiday Gift Guide! Need help with gift ideas? We’re here to help! We’ll be rolling out gift guides from now through the end of December. You can find <a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2020/">our other guides right here</a>.</em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s a difficult time to be a photographer. Getting creative feels impossible when every day is the same and the most exotic locale you visit is the living room. Travel is out this year, vacations are pushed back and everybody is cooped up inside trying not to lose it. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Everything is hard in like 12 different ways right now, but encouraging your friends and fam to immerse themselves in new hobbies and plan future adventures is a great distraction. For photographers at a loss for what to shoot this year, it&#8217;s the perfect time to mix things up, switch up your gear entirely and try to see the world with fresh eyes.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">This article contains links to affiliate partners where available. When you buy through these links, TechCrunch may earn an affiliate commission.</span></i></p>
<h2><strong>Fujifilm Instax Square SQ6 Instant Film Camera</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2086307" style="width: 800px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2086307" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2086307 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-4.37.23-PM.png" alt="" width="790" height="447" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-4.37.23-PM.png 790w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-4.37.23-PM.png?resize=150,85 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-4.37.23-PM.png?resize=300,170 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-4.37.23-PM.png?resize=768,435 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-4.37.23-PM.png?resize=680,385 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-4.37.23-PM.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 790px) 100vw, 790px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2086307" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits: </strong>Fujifilm</p></div></p>
<h3></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It might not seem like it, but it’s actually the perfect time to get into instant photography. As a photographer myself, I haven’t picked up my main camera in months. Nothing feels inspiring. But I started carrying a cheap instant camera on walks around my neighborhood, rain permitting, and it’s been a meditative way to appreciate the beauty of small things that otherwise just blend into my routine. This Fujifilm Instax shoots larger, square photos and they look great popping up in an Instagram feed too if you&#8217;re in it for the &#8216;gram.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another good option: The Fujifilm Instax Mini 11 Camera </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">creates smaller, rectangular photos and it’s playful design makes it perfect for anyone.</span></p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>Fujifilm Instax, <a href="https://www.adorama.com/fjim16581458.html?CategoryID=240274">$80 from Adorama</a> | Fujifilm Instax Mini, <a href="https://www.target.com/p/fujifilm-mini-11-cloud-green-camera/-/A-79785394">$70 from Target</a></p>
<h2><strong>GoPro Hero8 Black</strong></h2>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/Mh-x8kbJT5k?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<h3></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a year when we can’t do a lot of the things we’d normally enjoy, many of the safest, most enjoyable things are outdoors. If your giftee is an adrenaline junkie (climbing, snowboarding, surfing, etc.) the latest GoPro is a no-brainer for in-the-moment action stills or video that you could never capture otherwise. But like an instant camera, a GoPro can also be a really fun way to switch things up for nonadventure photography. I brought one along on my honeymoon and ended up shooting stills with it half the time even when I wasn’t in the water — having a teeny indestructible pocket camera just feels really fun and different.</span></p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$280<a href="https://www.rei.com/product/170238/gopro-hero8-black-camera?"> from REI</a></p>
<h2><strong>SanDisk 64GB Extreme PRO SDXC</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2086300" style="width: 456px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2086300" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2086300 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/sd-extreme-pro-e1607735323940.jpg?w=446" alt="" width="446" height="360" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/sd-extreme-pro-e1607735323940.jpg 446w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/sd-extreme-pro-e1607735323940.jpg?resize=150,121 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/sd-extreme-pro-e1607735323940.jpg?resize=300,242 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/sd-extreme-pro-e1607735323940.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 446px) 100vw, 446px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2086300" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SanDisk</p></div></p>
<h3></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’ve met a photographer who has enough memory cards, I’d like to know their secret. These SD cards are fast, reliable and widely compatible. Much like socks, SD cards have a way of vanishing and you never have enough of them even though it feels like you buy them all the time. Good stocking material! </span></p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$20 and up <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07H9J1YXN/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B07H9J1YXN&amp;linkId=de2b61e1ca0d6072f4df953ae67b8f3a">from Amazon</a>, depending on capacity</p>
<h3></h3>
<h2><strong>Sony RX100 VII</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1881979" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1881979" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1881979 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sony-RX100-VII-1.jpg?w=680" alt="Sony RX100 VII 1" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sony-RX100-VII-1.jpg 2400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sony-RX100-VII-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sony-RX100-VII-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sony-RX100-VII-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sony-RX100-VII-1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sony-RX100-VII-1.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sony-RX100-VII-1.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Sony-RX100-VII-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1881979" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sony</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Know someone who (a) wants a super compact travel camera, (b) wants to get into photography but doesn’t care about interchangeable lenses or (c) needs a small camera for anything, really? Sony’s been killing it in compact photography for years now and the RX100 series is a testament to everything it does right. The RX100 VII is an incredible camera in a really small package, capable of taking everything from beginner night sky photos and professional-looking portraits to casual photos and everything in between. Since it’s got full manual settings, new photographers can go as deep as they’d like and anyone who wants to keep it simple can stay in full auto and snap away. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Pro tip:</strong> Since Sony is in the 6th generation of the RX100, you can find old versions for screaming good deals and you won’t even know what you’re missing. Just stick with the RX100 III on up for the included viewfinder.</span></p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$1,298<a href="https://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/1503857-REG/sony_cyber_shot_dsc_rx100_vii_digital.html/"> from B&amp;H</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VDKUcihcQQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/17/the-sony-rx100-vii-is-the-best-compact-camera-you-can-buy/">The Sony RX100 VII is the best compact camera you can buy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Sony RX100 VII is the best compact camera you can buy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/17/the-sony-rx100-vii-is-the-best-compact-camera-you-can-buy/embed/#?secret=VDKUcihcQQ" data-secret="VDKUcihcQQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2><strong>B&amp;H Gift Card</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Know a photographer who always needs stuff, but you’re not totally sure what that stuff is? Or someone who wants to start shooting but likes the process of researching and picking things out themselves? A gift card to New York-based photography supercenter B&amp;H is a solid choice. They’ve got a robust online shop where you can buy anything and everything.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Bushnell Core DS 30MP Low-Glow Trail Camera</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2086315" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2086315" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2086315" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bushnell-trail-cam.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="451" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bushnell-trail-cam.png 1020w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bushnell-trail-cam.png?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bushnell-trail-cam.png?resize=300,199 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bushnell-trail-cam.png?resize=768,509 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bushnell-trail-cam.png?resize=680,451 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bushnell-trail-cam.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2086315" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bushnell/Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is a weird year and we’ve all learned weird new stuff about ourselves. In my case, I have learned the weird new fact that coyotes are frequently roaming around my fairly urban backyard eating people’s pets. (Sad but also interesting!) With entertainment options slim and monotony all but guaranteed, a lot of people are paying more attention to backyard and neighborhood wildlife lately. Even if you live in a major city, there are tons of wild creatures around. Go full Nat Geo with a trail cam </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">and finally find out what happens when animals stop being polite and start getting real.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also cool: We haven’t tried this one out, but the Canon PowerShot Zoom (</span><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08KTQBZHF/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B08KTQBZHF&amp;linkId=26ec3280aaf833810a44ed5d8fd1ec5f"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$299</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">) looks like a handy present for anyone who’s started bird or wildlife watching lately and is interested in nabbing quick super-zoomed-in shots.</span></p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$199<a href="https://www.bushnell.com/trail-cameras/core/core-ds-low-glow-trail-camera/PB-119975C.html"> from Bushnell</a></p>
<h2><strong>Sony a7 III Mirrorless Digital Camera</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2086301" style="width: 510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2086301" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2086301 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/sony-a7iii-e1607734179998.jpg?w=500" alt="" width="500" height="423" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/sony-a7iii-e1607734179998.jpg 500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/sony-a7iii-e1607734179998.jpg?resize=150,127 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/sony-a7iii-e1607734179998.jpg?resize=300,254 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/sony-a7iii-e1607734179998.jpg?resize=50,42 50w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2086301" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sony</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A lot of photographers, myself included, have switched over from DSLRs to full-frame mirrorless cameras in recent years, and for good reason. Mirrorless cameras are smaller and lighter, but that used to mean compromising on image quality in the name of portability. Those days are long over. New mirrorless cameras have image quality on par with their larger, more traditional counterparts and their light weight and smaller size makes them easier to cart around for stuff like travel, street or outdoor photography. You really can’t go very wrong with most of the full-frame mirrorless options out there, but Sony’s a7 III is perfect for anyone getting serious about photography. The brand new Sony a7C is another mirrorless full-frame also worth a look if you want an even </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">more</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> compact option on the cutting edge of what small cameras can do.</span></p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$1,698 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07B43WPVK/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B07B43WPVK&amp;linkId=0d23178fd406fd0d53876058c62d6595">from Amazon</a></p>
<h2><strong>Fujifilm&#8217;s X100V</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2086305" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2086305" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2086305" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-4.28.56-PM.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="435" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-4.28.56-PM.png 1239w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-4.28.56-PM.png?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-4.28.56-PM.png?resize=300,192 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-4.28.56-PM.png?resize=768,491 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-4.28.56-PM.png?resize=680,435 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-11-at-4.28.56-PM.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2086305" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Fujifilm</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Is your loved one one of those pretentious film photography people who talks about how digital ruined the art and nothing feels as good as a film camera? Well for one they’re kind of right. But you might be able to delight them nonetheless with the latest from Fujifilm&#8217;s’s extremely well-loved X100 series. It’s about as close as you can get to the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">je ne sais quoi</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of shooting with film, offering lots of little touches (classic design! an ISO dial!) that capture some of the magic of film photography. This is another option where you can save significant $$$ by finding a new last-generation version on the cheap. </span></p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$1,399 <a href="https://www.adorama.com/ifjx100vb.html">from Adorama</a></p>
<h2><strong>Nikon D3500 and Canon EOS Rebel T7 </strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-2086302 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nikon-d3500-e1607735821735.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="499" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nikon-d3500-e1607735821735.png 700w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nikon-d3500-e1607735821735.png?resize=150,110 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nikon-d3500-e1607735821735.png?resize=300,220 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nikon-d3500-e1607735821735.png?resize=680,499 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nikon-d3500-e1607735821735.png?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nikon</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Compact mirrorless cameras are having an extended moment right now, but sometimes a regular DSLR is a better choice. For anyone learning the basics of photography for the first time, a “cropped sensor” DSLR (versus a pro-level full-frame DSLR) is really a better starting place in some ways. These camera bodies and their lenses are larger, but they’re generally more tactile in a way that will help new photographers build up a good foundation of knowledge. These bodies usually come with a “kit lens” (18-55mm) that’s not terribly impressive, but if you also pick up a cheap 50mm f/1.8 your budding photog will have plenty to play around with. Whether you go Nikon or Canon, it really doesn’t matter — just pick a horse and ride it. Did we mention these are great, affordable choices for a teen who’s just getting into photography? They are!</span></p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>Nikon D3500, $499 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07GWKDLGT/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B07GWKDLGT&amp;linkId=25d42905ed27b6e5ff66ce5838fb0c65">from Amazon</a> | Canon EOS Rebel T7, $449 <a href="https://shop.usa.canon.com/shop/en/catalog/eos-rebel-t7-ef-s-18-55mm-f35-56-is-ii">from Canon</a></p>
<h2><strong>Peak Design Field Pouch and Tech Pouch</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2086314" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2086314" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2086314 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/peak-design-tech-pouch-e1607733957271.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="511" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/peak-design-tech-pouch-e1607733957271.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/peak-design-tech-pouch-e1607733957271.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/peak-design-tech-pouch-e1607733957271.jpg?resize=300,226 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/peak-design-tech-pouch-e1607733957271.jpg?resize=768,578 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/peak-design-tech-pouch-e1607733957271.jpg?resize=680,511 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/peak-design-tech-pouch-e1607733957271.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2086314" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Peak Design</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Peak Design is best known for their camera bags and those are cool too and very worth a look. Bag preferences can be a pretty personal thing but even the most well-geared photographer can appreciate one of these handy little pouches for stashing SD cards (so they don’t vanish!) and all the random little odds and ends you need to cart around in a camera bag. You can’t go wrong with any of Peak Design’s organizational stuff — it’s all thoughtful and handsomely designed. </span></p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>Field Pouch, $40<a href="https://www.peakdesign.com/products/field-pouch/"> from Peak Design</a> | Tech Pouch, $60<a href="https://www.peakdesign.com/products/tech-pouch/"> from Peak Design </a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2020/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/gift-guide-2020-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/gift-guide-photography-2020-best-photography-gifts-ideas-for-photographers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086245</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 questions every IT team should be able to answer</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/5-questions-every-it-team-should-to-be-able-to-answer/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/5-questions-every-it-team-should-to-be-able-to-answer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 20:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Extra Crunch Daily]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[endpoint security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile device management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telecommuting]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085066</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It's more important than ever to know if your IT team has made sound investments and has the agility needed to operate successfully in the face of continued uncertainty.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Christy Wyatt</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/christywyatt">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/christywyatt/">Christy Wyatt</a> is Chief Executive Officer and a member of the board of directors at <a />Absolute</a>, a leader in endpoint resilience solutions and the industry’s only undeletable defense platform embedded in over a half-billion devices.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Now more than ever, IT teams play a vital role in keeping their businesses running smoothly and securely. With all of the assets and data that are now broadly distributed, a CEO depends on their IT team to ensure employees remain connected and productive and that sensitive data remains protected.</p>
<p>CEOs often visualize and measure things in terms of dollars and cents, and in the face of continuing uncertainty, IT &#8212; along with most other parts of the business &#8212; is facing intense scrutiny and tightening of budgets. So, it is more important than ever to be able to demonstrate that they’ve made sound technology investments and have the agility needed to operate successfully in the face of continued uncertainty.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			For a CEO to properly understand risk exposure and make the right investments, IT departments have to be able to confidently communicate what types of data are on any given device at any given time.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Here are five questions that IT teams should be ready to answer when their CEO comes calling:</p>
<h2>What have we spent our money on?</h2>
<p>Or, more specifically, exactly how many assets do we have? And, do we know where they are? While these seem like basic questions, they can be shockingly difficult to answer … much more difficult than people realize. The last several months in the wake of the COVID-19 outbreak have been the proof point.</p>
<p>With the mass exodus of machines leaving the building and disconnecting from the corporate network, many IT leaders found themselves guessing just how many devices had been released into the wild and gone home with employees.</p>
<p>One CIO we spoke to estimated they had “somewhere between 30,000 and 50,000 devices” that went home with employees, meaning there could have been up to 20,000 that were completely unaccounted for. The complexity was further compounded as old devices were pulled out of desk drawers and storage closets to get something into the hands of employees who were not equipped to work remotely. Companies had endpoints connecting to corporate network and systems that they hadn’t seen for years — meaning they were out-of-date from a security perspective as well.</p>
<p>This level of uncertainty is obviously unsustainable and introduces a tremendous amount of security risk. Every endpoint that goes unaccounted for not only means wasted spend but also increased vulnerability, greater potential for breach or compliance violation, and more. In order to mitigate these risks, there needs to be a permanent connection to every device that can tell you exactly how many assets you have deployed at any given time — whether they are in the building or out in the wild.</p>
<h2>Are our devices and data protected?</h2>
<p>Device and data security go hand in hand; without the ability to see every device that is deployed across an organization, it becomes next to impossible to know what data is living on those devices. When employees know they are leaving the building and going to be off network, they tend to engage in “data hoarding.”<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/5-questions-every-it-team-should-to-be-able-to-answer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085066</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roblox buys digital avatar startup Loom.ai</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/roblox-buys-digital-avatar-startup-loom-ai/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/roblox-buys-digital-avatar-startup-loom-ai/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 19:10:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avatar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitmoji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitstrips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[films]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Loom.ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roblox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snap inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zach coelius]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086838</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roblox announced today that it&#8217;s buying a digital avatar startup called Loom.ai. Purchasing a company that has focused singularly on creating more realistic human avatars is an interesting play for a gaming platform that has made such an impact by building experiences that tend to cast realism to the wayside. We covered the company&#8217;s $1.35 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/roblox" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="roblox">Roblox <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> announced today that it&#8217;s buying a digital avatar startup called <a href="https://loomai.com/product">Loom.ai</a>. Purchasing a company that has focused singularly on creating more realistic human avatars is an interesting play for a gaming platform that has made such an impact by building experiences that tend to cast realism to the wayside.</p>
<p>We <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/12/13/loom-ai-is-building-an-avatar-that-can-capture-your-personality/">covered the company&#8217;s $1.35 million seed round</a> back in 2016. Since then, it has brought in additional seed funding, scoring $5.9 million in total capital raised. The startup&#8217;s investors include Y Combinator, Samsung Ventures, Anorak Ventures and Zach Coelius.</p>
<p>Terms of the deal weren&#8217;t disclosed.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/loomai" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="loomai">Loom.ai <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> was one in a long list of avatar companies to launch during the mid 2010&#8217;s that capitalized on computer vision advancements and aimed to build out a cross-game/cross-platform network of users that relied on their tech to create in-app avatars. This field of companies aimed to capitalize on opportunities in 3D that expanded beyond what companies like Snapchat had identified following its Bitmoji acquisition.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2086876" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2086876" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2086876 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-14-at-12.52.56-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="487" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-14-at-12.52.56-PM.jpg 1702w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-14-at-12.52.56-PM.jpg?resize=150,108 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-14-at-12.52.56-PM.jpg?resize=300,215 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-14-at-12.52.56-PM.jpg?resize=768,551 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-14-at-12.52.56-PM.jpg?resize=680,487 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-14-at-12.52.56-PM.jpg?resize=1536,1101 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-14-at-12.52.56-PM.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2086876" class="wp-caption-text">Image via Loom.ai</p></div></p>
<p>Over the years, Loom.ai shifted its effort from photorealism to creating more Memoji-like representations that allowed users to upload a 2D photo and automatically create a realistic 3D avatar. In recent years, Loom.ai focused heavily on enterprise opportunities. The company&#8217;s products also included a suite of integrations to build out personalized avatar stickers that could be used on messaging platforms like Slack or WhatsApp as well as live avatars that could be used during video calls.</p>
<p>Though Roblox has some of the more simplistic avatars on the market, this acquisition may suggest that the company is open to building out a system that places more of a premium on realism and more life-like facial animations. In a press release announcing the deal, Roblox shared that this acquisition &#8220;will accelerate the development of next-generation avatars.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qgATwooyDa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/12/13/loom-ai-is-building-an-avatar-that-can-capture-your-personality/">Loom.ai is building an avatar that can capture your personality</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Loom.ai is building an avatar that can capture your personality&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2016/12/13/loom-ai-is-building-an-avatar-that-can-capture-your-personality/embed/#?secret=qgATwooyDa" data-secret="qgATwooyDa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/roblox-buys-digital-avatar-startup-loom-ai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086838</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Atlanta-based gaming controller peripheral seller KontrolFreek has been bought by SteelSeries</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/atlanta-based-gaming-controller-peripheral-seller-kontrolfreek-has-been-bought-by-steelseries/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/atlanta-based-gaming-controller-peripheral-seller-kontrolfreek-has-been-bought-by-steelseries/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 19:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlanta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blh venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[components]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[controller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gamer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kontrolfreek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SteelSeries]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086831</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After nearly a decade selling gaming and console peripherals to gamers looking to spice up their systems, Atlanta-based KontrolFreek has been acquired by the international peripherals retailer SteelSeries. Terms of the acquisition were undisclosed, but KontrolFreek has shipped more than 2 million units of its flagship product, which is available in over 9,000 retailers in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After nearly a decade selling gaming and console peripherals to gamers looking to spice up their systems, Atlanta-based <a href="https://www.kontrolfreek.com/">KontrolFreek</a> has been acquired by the international peripherals retailer <a href="https://steelseries.com/">SteelSeries.</a></p>
<p>Terms of the acquisition were undisclosed, but <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/kontrolfreek" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="kontrolfreek">KontrolFreek <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has shipped more than 2 million units of its flagship product, which is available in over 9,000 retailers in 60 countries and can be found in over 16 online marketplaces.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s not bad for a company that was founded 11 years ago with a $50,000 check from <a href="https://www.blhventures.com/team/">BLH Venture Partners</a>, the Atlanta-based investment firm co-founded by Billy L. Harbert and Ashish Mistry. Mistry, a co-founder of Virtex Networks and later an early team member at Air Defense.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Neither Harbert nor Mistry were much for gaming, but they did see the opportunity in selling peripherals to the folks who were, Mistry said in a direct message.</p>
<p>&#8220;Huge markets have large niches,&#8221; Mistry wrote.</p>
<p>By acquiring KontrolFreek, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/steelseries" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="steelseries">SteelSeries <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is further consolidating its position in the console gaming market by folding one of the leading sellers of high-performance controller accessories into its portfolio of products. Earlier this year, SteelSeries nabbed A-volute, which provides three dimensional sound systems for games.</p>
<p>SteelSeries also gets a vibrant user-generated media property in KontrolFreek&#8217;s <a href="https://www.kontrolfreek.com/pages/freeknation">FreekNation</a> community, which boasts 4 million community members.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“With the next-generation consoles at the forefront of the gaming industry’s mind, there’s never been a better time to maximize our ability to provide the best gaming experiences and products to console gamers,” said Ehtisham Rabbani, CEO of SteelSeries. “With KontrolFreek’s expertise and global popularity, we know they’ll open new opportunities to entertain, delight, and assist new gamers across the world.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/atlanta-based-gaming-controller-peripheral-seller-kontrolfreek-has-been-bought-by-steelseries/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086831</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>MIT professor wants to overhaul &#8216;The Hype Machine&#8217; that powers social media</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/hype-machine-sinan-aral/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/hype-machine-sinan-aral/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 18:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data portability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media literacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[misinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085959</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["I think that having objective sources of fact checking are important. We know that fact-checking does reduce the belief in and sharing of fake information."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">More than 3.6 billion people use social media, and its runaway success has left the industry at a crossroads. There are now heated debates in Washington and Brussels over the future of antitrust regulation for this market, whether platform operators should filter certain content (and if so, which types), and how to open the market to new innovators.</p>
<p>To find my way through this thicket of interesting questions, I spoke with <a href="https://mitsloan.mit.edu/faculty/directory/sinan-kayhan-aral">Sinan Aral</a>, a professor of management at the MIT Sloan School of Management who also co-leads MIT’s Initiative on the Digital Economy. He has spent years analyzing the social media market, directly participating in its development as chief scientist of SocialAmp and Humin and as a founding partner of Manifest Capital.</p>
<p>This fall, he published his latest book, <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/570128/the-hype-machine-by-sinan-aral/">&#8220;The Hype Machine,&#8221;</a> which explores what’s next for social media giants. In our discussion, we talked about the landscape of the market today, what responsibilities companies and users have to each other and what come next as the industry evolves.</p>
<p><i>This interview has been edited and condensed for clarity.</i></p>
<p><strong>TechCrunch: Why don’t we start with how the book came together and how you got interested in this topic of digital media and how it affects our decision-making?</strong></p>
<p><b>Sinan Aral</b>: I started researching social media four years before Mark Zuckerberg founded Facebook. I have worked with all of the major social media platforms for the last 20 years: Facebook, Twitter, Snapchat, WeChat, Yahoo and the rest. I’ve published a number of very large-scale studies, and I’m also an entrepreneur. So, I’ve got a vantage point as a practitioner, but also as a long-time academic leader in this area.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			We really have a full-blown social media crisis on our hands, as is obvious if you turn on the TV on any given day.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>The reason why I wrote &#8220;The Hype Machine&#8221; is because essentially, we’ve seen this coming to a head for many years now. We really have a full-blown social media crisis on our hands, as is obvious if you turn on the TV on any given day.</p>
<p>My book takes off from where &#8220;The Social Dilemma&#8221; documentary and Shoshana Zuboff’s &#8220;The Age of Surveillance Capitalism&#8221; leave off, which is to ask, what can we concretely do to solve the social media crisis that we find ourselves in? The book argues that in order to do that, we have to stop armchair theorizing about how social media works, and we have to stop debating whether or not social media is good or evil. The answer is yes.</p>
<p>The book goes through the fundamentals of how social media works. So, there’s a chapter on neuroscience and social media, and economics and social media, and that eventually informs the solutions in the book, which cover everything from antitrust and competition to federal privacy legislation. How do we secure our elections and our democracy? What do we do about Section 230 of the Communications Decency Act? How do we balance free speech and hate speech? How do we deal with misinformation and fake news?</p>
<p><strong>I think for a lot of us in tech, we’re a bit stuck. On one hand, these technologies have produced jarring amounts of wealth in the tech industry, but they have also caused a large number of harms. What do we do next?</strong></p>
<p>Let me start by saying that the general framework of the solution is about what I call the four levers: money, code, norms and laws.</p>
<p>Money is the business models, which create the incentives for how the advertisers on the platforms and the users behave. Code is how we design the platforms and the algorithms underlying the platforms, which I go into in great detail. Norms are how we adopt, appropriate and use the technology. And obviously, laws are regulation.</p>
<p>In terms of solutions, I think the entry ticket for solving the social media crisis is creating competition in the social media economy. Platforms that lack competition don’t have any incentive to change away from the attention economy and their engagement-driven business models, nor do they have any real incentive to clean up their negative externalities in our information ecosystem, whether it’s hate speech or misinformation or manipulation.</p>
<p>Now, when I say competition, the first thing on everyone’s mind is always, “Oh, you mean break up Facebook.” But the point I make in the book — and I take a very clear stance on this — is that breaking up Facebook in this economy doesn’t solve the problem. This economy runs on network effects. The value of these platforms is a function of the number of users on the platform. Economies that run on network effects tend toward concentration and monopoly.</p>
<p>So, if you break up Facebook, it’s just going to tip the next Facebook-like company into market dominance. What we really need is structural reform of the social media economy, and that involves social network portability, data portability and interoperability legislation.</p>
<p><strong>Let me push back on this a bit though. Terms like “data portability” always sound nice as a solution, but have we ever effectively used this tool to open a market?</strong></p>
<p>This isn’t the first time that we’ve done this. During the AOL-Time Warner merger, we forced AOL’s AIM product to become interoperable with Yahoo Messenger and MSN Messenger. And it went from a 65% market share to a 59% market share one year later, down to like 50%, then it ceded the entire market to new entrants three years later.</p>
<p>Another good analogy is number portability in the cell phone market. It used to be that you couldn’t take your cell phone number with you when you switched from one cell phone provider to another, and then we legislated that they had to let you take your number with you. That was akin to a social network at the time, because all of your friends knew to call you at that number.</p>
<p>Research has shown that number portability created about $880 million of consumer surplus every quarter for years and years after it was instituted in Europe, and it created a lot of competition. We should have something very similar in social networks, around social network portability and data portability, so that we could create competition.</p>
<p>Now, if you break up Facebook after these kinds of structural reforms to the market, that’s a different question, but breaking up Facebook without structural reforms to the market economy is like putting a Band-Aid on a tumor. It’s not going to solve the underlying lack of competition that the social media economy has.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Hype Machine&#8221; details how we might do that and suggests that there could be a stack of commodity messaging formats that would be required to be interoperable. Then, you could have unique messaging formats for every platform on top of that. But things like texts, short-form videos, stories that either persist or disappear, that kind of stuff should have a level of interoperability that’s legislated. The entry ticket to solving the social media crisis is creating competition.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/hype-machine-sinan-aral/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085959</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indiegogo expands its Global Fast Track Program to Japan</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/indiegogo-global-fast-track-japan/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/indiegogo-global-fast-track-japan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 18:36:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crowdfunding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity crowdfunding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indiegogo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086820</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Indiegogo plans to help more Japanese entrepreneurs run successful crowdfunding campaigns through a new expansion of its Global Fast Track Program. Indiegogo first launched the program several years ago in China. The idea behind Global Fast Track is to provide an extra level of support to entrepreneurs in specific markets, guiding them through the process [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/indie-gogo" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="indie-gogo">Indiegogo <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> plans to help more Japanese entrepreneurs run successful crowdfunding campaigns through <a href="https://go.indiegogo.com/blog/2020/12/now-in-japan-the-indiegogo-global-fast-track-program.html">a new expansion of its Global Fast Track Program</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/05/indiegogo-china-global-fast-track/"> Indiegogo first launched the program several years ago in China</a>. The idea behind Global Fast Track is to provide an extra level of support to entrepreneurs in specific markets, guiding them through the process of creating campaigns for global consumers, particularly those in the U.S. and Europe.</p>
<p>In fact, Lu Li, the general manager for Indiegogo&#8217;s global strategy, told me that the program has already supported more than 670 entrepreneurs launching campaigns, with 40 of those campaigns raising $1 million or more. To support this, Indiegogo has a team in China &#8220;doing sales and marketing and really focusing on bringing on the most high-quality campaigns,&#8221; Li said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>And although there have already been <a href="https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/atmoph-window-2-smart-display-with-1-000-views#/">successful campaigns launched from Japan</a>, it sounds like Indiegogo will be expanding its presence in a similar way in Japan. In this case, it&#8217;s also partnering with the <a href="https://www.jetro.go.jp">Japanese External Trade Organization</a> (JETRO).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PkweizkRqN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/05/indiegogo-china-global-fast-track/">Indiegogo expands its efforts to help Chinese startups reach global consumers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Indiegogo expands its efforts to help Chinese startups reach global consumers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/05/indiegogo-china-global-fast-track/embed/#?secret=PkweizkRqN" data-secret="PkweizkRqN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;We are very excited to announce JETRO’s partnership with Indiegogo,&#8221; said Noriya Tarutani, executive director of JETRO San Francisco, in a statement. &#8220;Thanks to more than 40% annual growth of crowdfunding in Japan in recent years, we have been receiving a lot of inquiries from Japanese startups about how they can leverage crowdfunding as a way to bring their amazing products to the global market. We are confident that our collaboration will be mutually beneficial to Indiegogo as they enter Japan, as well as Japanese startups expanding overseas.”</p>
<p>In addition, Indiegogo says it will start supporting campaigns using Japanese yen, and it will also showcase campaigns from the country through a &#8220;Made in Japan&#8221; collection.</p>
<p>Indiegogo CEO Andy Yang said that this is the right time to expand into Japan because of a &#8220;vibrant startup ecosystem&#8221; that has emerged in recent years to challenge the dominance of traditional giants.</p>
<p>Yang added that the company has become cashflow positive, and that it has continued to see growth during the pandemic.</p>
<p>&#8220;There was a crowdfunding peak or heyday in 2016, and then the industry overall went through an awkward period where entrepreneurs were still learning and backers are still trying to understand what to expect,&#8221; he said. &#8220;That’s a continually evolving process &#8230; but we&#8217;re seeing lot of great tailwinds, specifically from entrepreneurs with a lot of appetite to find new sales channels.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hhl4DpiGZA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/20/all-roads-lead-to-shenzhen/">&#8216;All roads do lead back to Shenzhen,&#8217; according to Indiegogo&#8217;s Sandy Diao</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;&#8216;All roads do lead back to Shenzhen,&#8217; according to Indiegogo&#8217;s Sandy Diao&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/20/all-roads-lead-to-shenzhen/embed/#?secret=hhl4DpiGZA" data-secret="hhl4DpiGZA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/indiegogo-global-fast-track-japan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086820</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Troy Carter and Suzy Ryoo&#8217;s music tech startup Q&#038;A launches software group, Venice Innovation Labs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/troy-carter-and-suzy-ryoos-music-tech-startup-qa-launches-software-group-venice-innovation-labs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/troy-carter-and-suzy-ryoos-music-tech-startup-qa-launches-software-group-venice-innovation-labs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 18:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lady Gaga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Q&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[record label]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[troy carter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2086552</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Q&#38;A, a startup developing tech for the music industry co-founded by industry insiders Troy Carter (Lady Gaga&#8217;s first manager) and Suzy Ryoo (Carter&#8217;s longtime collaborator), has launched a new suite of software products through a division called Venice Innovation Labs. The new tools are designed to help record labels beta test songs, manage artists and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.qanda.la/">Q&amp;A</a>, a startup developing tech for the music industry co-founded by industry insiders Troy Carter (Lady Gaga&#8217;s first manager) and Suzy Ryoo (Carter&#8217;s longtime collaborator), has launched a new suite of software products through a division called<a href="https://www.venice.tech/"> Venice Innovation Labs</a>.</p>
<p>The new tools are designed to help record labels beta test songs, manage artists and distribute music easily and efficiently, the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>The first releases from the new division are StreamRate, which provides sentiment analysis of new songs before they&#8217;re released; and Venice For Labels, which tracks splits and payments among different artists, manages and monitors music distribution, and helps labels keep track of their rosters.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company is also providing a human touch through a strategic marketing and advisory &#8220;Premium Services&#8221; team led by <span style="font-weight: 400;">Ray Kurzeka in North America and Matt Ott in the U.K.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Technology is rapidly changing the way music is consumed, yet our industry&#8217;s</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">infrastructure remains underserved. We&#8217;ve been quietly building beautiful and intuitive</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">tools that labels will love, as well as services that move the needle. Our vision is to</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">create an authentic community to empower brilliant artists and the labels that support</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">them daily,&#8221; said Suzy Ryoo, president of Q&amp;A.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/troy-carter-and-suzy-ryoos-music-tech-startup-qa-launches-software-group-venice-innovation-labs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2086552</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
