<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:18:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>The venture firm SOSV has hired former TechCrunch COO Ned Desmond to help grow its startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/the-venture-firm-sosv-has-hired-former-techcrunch-coo-ned-desmond-to-help-grow-its-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/the-venture-firm-sosv-has-hired-former-techcrunch-coo-ned-desmond-to-help-grow-its-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[formlabs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getaround]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jump bikes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memphis meats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ned Desmond]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sean O'Sullivan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sosv]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088932</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ned Desmond, a longtime publishing executive who spent more than half a dozen years at Time Inc. before becoming the chief operating officer of both TechCrunch and Engadget for more than eight years, has joined the investment firm SOSV as a senior operating partner. It&#8217;s seemingly a good fit for both sides. SOSV &#8212; which [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/ned-desmond" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="ned-desmond">Ned Desmond, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> a longtime publishing executive who spent more than half a dozen years at Time Inc. before becoming the chief operating officer of both TechCrunch and Engadget for more than eight years, has joined the investment firm <a href="https://sosv.com/">SOSV</a> as a senior operating partner.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s seemingly a good fit for both sides.</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/sosv" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="sosv">SOSV <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> &#8212; which is currently managing a $277 million flagship fund alongside some smaller vehicles &#8212; has become known for its popular accelerator programs, including <a href="https://hax.co/">Hax</a>, a program focused around nascent hardware startups, and <a href="https://indiebio.co/">IndieBio</a>, SOSV&#8217;s life-sciences-focused accelerator.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In fact, the outfit, founded by serial entrepreneur Sean O&#8217;Sullivan in 1995, has now funded so many startups &#8212;  roughly 1,000 of them  &#8212;  that it recently sought out Desmond to work with them, connect them, shine a light on their work and help them raise follow-on funding.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s work that has become intuitive for Desmond, who among other things, was heavily involved in organizing TechCrunch&#8217;s multiple events around the world each year, along with its signature Battlefield competitions, which collectively feature dozens of nascent startups annually.</p>
<p>Indeed, soon after Desmond <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/20/so-long-techcrunch/">resigned</a> from TechCrunch last summer in search of a new challenge (and some needed downtime), O&#8217;Sullivan reached out to him, asking if he might join SOSV to help with its marketing and sales efforts, as well as to provide coaching and connections to its startups.</p>
<p>By O&#8217;Sullivan&#8217;s telling, SOSV could use the help more than ever.</p>
<p>The outfit has had its share of successes. It was the lead investor in the electric bike company Jump Bikes, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/09/uber-acquires-bike-share-startup-jump/">acquired</a> by Uber in 2018 for an undisclosed amount. It&#8217;s an early investor in the 3D printing company FormLabs (valued at <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/amyfeldman/2018/08/01/3-d-printing-startup-formlabs-venture-capital-unicorn-1-billion-valuation-financing-jeff-immelt-forbes-30-under-30-alumni-max-lobovsky/#69e047fc7471">more than $1 billion</a> during its last round in 2018). It also wrote an early check to the peer-to-peer car-sharing company <a href="https://www.getaround.com/">GetAround</a>, which was hard hit by the pandemic but whose business has since reportedly rebounded such that it was able to raise $140 million in Series E funding in October. (It has raised $600 million altogether.)</p>
<p>Not last, SOSV is an investor in the lab-grown meat producer <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/memphis-meats" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="memphis-meats">Memphis Meats, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> which raised <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-memphis-meats-funding/lab-grown-meat-producer-memphis-meats-raises-161-million-in-funding-led-by-softbank-idUSKBN1ZL2OO">$161 million</a> in new funding at the start up of the year led by SoftBank.</p>
<p>Still, SOSV is in the same boat as many seed-stage investment firms. It&#8217;s working with a lot of very new teams for whom the pandemic has been rough. <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/q3-2020-global-venture-report/">According to Crunchbase</a>, seed funding in the third quarter was down 32% percent year over year and down 11% quarter over quarter.</p>
<p>While the buzzier, more established companies have had no problems in fundraising &#8212; many are having to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/07/technology/this-is-insanity-start-ups-end-year-in-a-deal-frenzy.html">bat back overeager investors</a> &#8212; newer, unproven teams without established connections have found it harder to land seed-stage and Series A checks.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s a super tough market,&#8221; says O&#8217;Sullivan. &#8220;Angels have completely dropped out. Seed investing is down massively.&#8221; Except in life sciences, especially in the U.S., says O&#8217;Sullivan, &#8220;it&#8217;s tougher for every company because you can&#8217;t move quite as fast.&#8221;</p>
<p>What of Zoom and related talk by VCs of the <a href="https://www.gsb.stanford.edu/insights/vcs-covid-19-were-doing-fine-thanks">extra time they now have to meet with new startups</a>? O&#8217;Sullivan suggests with a laugh that there&#8217;s no shortage of posturing in the industry. &#8220;Everyone&#8217;s always doing &#8216;great,'&#8221; he notes. &#8220;But I&#8217;m a Catholic guy. I have to be honest&#8221; and there&#8217;s &#8220;nothing quite like going to meet with a company and working with them across the table. When you&#8217;re working with them remotely, it&#8217;s just a slower process.&#8221;</p>
<p>With Desmond&#8217;s work ethic, his connections and his experience, O&#8217; Sullivan thinks he can speed it up. He&#8217;s also fairly clear-eyed about the coming months. &#8220;The stock market is doing great, but the economy is not doing well, so there&#8217;s tremendous uncertainty about what happens next.&#8221;</p>
<p>While he&#8217;s &#8220;cautiously optimistic,&#8221; he adds, but like a growing number other investors, he also can&#8217;t help but wonder: &#8220;How long can the party continue?&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/the-venture-firm-sosv-has-hired-former-techcrunch-coo-ned-desmond-to-help-grow-its-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088932</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Googling for &#8216;Baby Yoda&#8217; will beam him into your living room via augmented reality</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/googling-for-baby-yoda-will-beam-him-into-your-living-room-via-augmented-reality/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/googling-for-baby-yoda-will-beam-him-into-your-living-room-via-augmented-reality/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 23:26:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Augmented Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baby Yoda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[star wars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Mandalorian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088952</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google has been all about the fun little augmented reality Easter Eggs lately, with a bevy of search terms triggering Halloween-themed AR experiences back in October. Ghosts! Jack-o-lanterns! Dancing skeletons! Now they&#8217;ve got another one. Rolled out just in time for tomorrow&#8217;s Season 2 finale of The Mandalorian, this one brings The Child (or, as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/google" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="google">Google <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has been all about the fun little augmented reality Easter Eggs lately, with a bevy of search terms triggering Halloween-themed AR experiences <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/google-brings-halloween-to-life-using-augmented-reality/">back in October</a>. Ghosts! Jack-o-lanterns! Dancing skeletons!</p>
<p>Now they&#8217;ve got another one. Rolled out just in time for tomorrow&#8217;s Season 2 finale of The Mandalorian, this one brings The Child (or, as the world has taken to calling him, &#8220;Baby Yoda&#8221;) into your living room.</p>
<p>Want to check it out yourself? You just need to search for the right thing. <strong>This is the way:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Open Google.com in the browser of an iOS or Android device</li>
<li>Search for &#8220;The Child,&#8221; &#8220;Baby Yoda&#8221; or [The Child&#8217;s actual name here which I&#8217;ll omit because spoilers].</li>
<li>Scroll down until the &#8220;View in 3D&#8221; button appears. Tap it. (Depending on your device, you might need the Google search app installed. It worked by default on a Pixel.)</li>
<li>Wait until the camera view pops up, then wave your camera around a bit. Once the camera figures out where the floor is, he should appear. Be sure to bump your volume up.</li>
</ol>
<p>I just tested it myself and it worked well, albeit better on some devices than others. It was fast and flawless on a Pixel, but the lighting was bugging out hard on my iPhone.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s a camera button that&#8217;ll let you snap photos and videos, and you can drag/pinch to move him around the room or rotate him in place for better shots. Have fun!</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2b1zzvwHVF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/google-brings-halloween-to-life-using-augmented-reality/">Google brings Halloween to life using augmented reality</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google brings Halloween to life using augmented reality&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/google-brings-halloween-to-life-using-augmented-reality/embed/#?secret=2b1zzvwHVF" data-secret="2b1zzvwHVF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/googling-for-baby-yoda-will-beam-him-into-your-living-room-via-augmented-reality/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088952</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mental wellness platform Lyra Health is raising up to $175M at a $2.25B valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/mental-wellness-platform-lyra-health-is-raising-up-to-175m-at-a-2-25b-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/mental-wellness-platform-lyra-health-is-raising-up-to-175m-at-a-2-25b-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 23:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lyra health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088903</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The coronavirus pandemic has underscored, and often exacerbated, the mental health crisis that exists across the world. Even the spread of remote work is part of the problem: As everyone stays at home, the lack of interaction and watercooler chat has left employees without in-person interaction. The need for a solution has helped tech-powered mental [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The coronavirus pandemic has underscored, and often exacerbated, the mental health crisis that exists across the world. Even the spread of remote work is part of the problem: As everyone stays at home, the lack of interaction and watercooler chat has left employees without in-person interaction.</p>
<p>The need for a solution has helped tech-powered mental health solutions raise funding to meet increased demand. In the latest development, it emerged that <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/lyra-health" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="lyra-health">Lyra Health, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> a platform that focuses on providing workforces with mental health care, has filed paperwork to raise a $175 million Series E at a $2.25 billion valuation.</p>
<p>The paperwork was uncovered by <a href="https://primeunicornindex.com/lyra-health-secures-175m-series-e-round/">Prime Unicorn Index</a>. While it is not clear whether the company has closed the round, filings in Delaware usually appear after part or all of the funding has been secured. Prime Unicorn Index notes that the terms surrounding this Series E round include a “pari passu liquidation preference with all other preferred, and conventional convertible, meaning they will not participate with common stock if there are remaining proceeds.” It also noted that Lyra Health&#8217;s most recent price per share is $27.47, an up round from the Series D, which priced shares at $14.21.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>We are reaching out to the company and investors for a response to the filing. One investor noted that the round has not closed yet.</p>
<p>Past backers of the company include Adams Street Partners, Tenaya Capital, Meritech Capital Partners, IVP and Greylock.</p>
<p>We seem to be in a period of rapid growth rounds getting raised in quick succession for the most promising startups. As with Discord &#8212; which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/filing-discord-is-raising-up-to-140m-at-a-valuation-of-up-to-7b/">confirmed a $100 million round</a> just six months after raising $100 million &#8212; Lyra Health also recently raised funding &#8212; specifically <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/lyra-health-gains-unicorn-status-after-110m-series-d/">a $110 million Series D</a> that catapulted it above a $1 billion valuation.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="95qBJQ2NHy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/filing-discord-is-raising-up-to-140m-at-a-valuation-of-up-to-7b/">Update: Discord confirms raising $100M, sources say at a valuation of up to $7B</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Update: Discord confirms raising $100M, sources say at a valuation of up to $7B&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/filing-discord-is-raising-up-to-140m-at-a-valuation-of-up-to-7b/embed/#?secret=95qBJQ2NHy" data-secret="95qBJQ2NHy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That effectively means the startup doubled its valuation in a handful of months, suggesting rapid growth or key validation. As reported by <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/katiejennings/2020/08/25/lyra-health-hits-11-billion-valuation-as-coronavirus-boosts-need-for-teletherapy/?sh=1b581bf66938">Forbes</a>, Lyra Health was set to bring in around $100 million in revenue by the end of the year at the time of its prior fundraise.</p>
<p>There have been a number of categories of technology that have seen a bump of usage and interest during this coronavirus pandemic, and sadly &#8212; or perhaps usefully, depending on how you look at it &#8212; mental health and wellness startups, aimed at helping our well-being in this trying time, have been one of them. Just last week, the meditation app Calm raised $75 million at a $2 billion valuation.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UDKc2TWNau"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/calm-raises-75m-more-at-2b-valuation/">Calm raises $75M more at $2B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Calm raises $75M more at $2B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/calm-raises-75m-more-at-2b-valuation/embed/#?secret=UDKc2TWNau" data-secret="UDKc2TWNau" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Burlingame, California-based Lyra Health wants to live in offices everywhere. The company helps employers give their employees a suite of safe and confidential tools to support their mental health needs. This is a tricky space to play in, considering that mental health can still feel taboo in workplaces and employees might feel uncomfortable turning to their employers for support. Still, in a world where in-office perks are no longer available, mental health might be a key investment to help startup retention.</p>
<p>Once an employee joins Lyra, the company creates a set of recommendations for the now-patient based on a survey. Lyra Health then can connect patients to its network of thousands of therapists for appointments, consultations and check-ins. The flywheel continues.</p>
<p>During the pandemic, Lyra Health has brought on 80,000 new users, to a total of 1.5 million users last reported.</p>
<p>Tech-enabled mental health care has found tailwinds as the coronavirus pandemic leads to a <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/69/wr/mm6943a3.htm">surge of telehealth</a>, as in-person doctor’s appointments could leave patients at risk. Indeed, Lyra Health started Lyra Blended Care, which pairs video therapy with online lessons and exercises rooted in cognitive behavioral therapy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/mental-wellness-platform-lyra-health-is-raising-up-to-175m-at-a-2-25b-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088903</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lockheed Martin&#8217;s Lisa Callahan on building a lunar lander collaboratively (and during COVID)</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/lockheed-martins-lisa-callahan-on-building-a-lunar-lander-collaboratively-and-during-covid/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/lockheed-martins-lisa-callahan-on-building-a-lunar-lander-collaboratively-and-during-covid/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 23:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artemis program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lisa callahan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088906</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NASA&#8217;s Artemis mission is just starting to get underway, and among the commercial partnerships vying for the privilege of building the lunar landing system is one between Lockheed Martin and Blue Origin, which is leading the effort. Lockheed VP and GM of Commercial Civil Space Lisa Callahan says that the collaboration has been surprisingly smooth [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/nasa" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="nasa">NASA&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Artemis mission is just starting to get underway, and among the commercial partnerships vying for the privilege of building the lunar landing system is one between <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/lockheed-martin" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="lockheed-martin">Lockheed Martin <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Blue Origin, which is leading the effort. Lockheed VP and GM of Commercial Civil Space Lisa Callahan says that the collaboration has been surprisingly smooth and fruitful.</p>
<p>Speaking at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2020/">TC Sessions: Space</a>, Callahan expressed her excitement for being able to take part in such an endeavor to begin with: &#8220;Who wouldn&#8217;t want to do that? That&#8217;s pretty awesome,&#8221; she said. &#8220;A lot of our workforce wasn&#8217;t around in the Apollo days, so they&#8217;re really excited to be a part of this next generation and bringing astronauts back to the moon — and for me personally, the fact that we&#8217;re going to bring the first woman to the moon is just amazing.&#8221;</p>
<p>She explained that Lockheed is working on the ascent module, while Northrup Grumman and Draper are working on other components, and Blue Origin, the prime contractor, is making the descent module.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s a really fun combination of the entrepreneurial, from the Blue Origin perspective, with some of the heritage companies that Lockheed and Northrop Grumman and Draper provide going back to the Apollo days, to bring a kind of national time together for this national priority,&#8221; she said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RV6XRQHJcN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/30/heres-how-blue-origins-human-lander-system-will-carry-astronauts-to-the-lunar-surface/">Here&#8217;s how Blue Origin&#8217;s human lander system will carry astronauts to the lunar surface</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Here&#8217;s how Blue Origin&#8217;s human lander system will carry astronauts to the lunar surface&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/30/heres-how-blue-origins-human-lander-system-will-carry-astronauts-to-the-lunar-surface/embed/#?secret=RV6XRQHJcN" data-secret="RV6XRQHJcN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>One might fairly expect a bit of friction between the old rivals and the newcomer, but according to Callahan it&#8217;s been extremely constructive.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s a merging of different cultures, and I think everyone on the team is growing because of it,&#8221; she said. &#8220;Blue Origin has been a great prime, they&#8217;ve really welcomed everybody in a sort of&#8230; what I&#8217;ll call a badge-less environment. I don&#8217;t think if you were sitting in one of the technical interchange meetings that we have, you would even know who works for who. Because we just bring the best of breed and who has the right experiences to do the job we&#8217;ve got to the table. So it&#8217;s really been quite seamless, and we&#8217;ve had a lot of fun with it.&#8221;</p>
<p>
		<div class="embed breakout" id="vidible_div_0" data-pid="56faf851e4b0d3dcac2e081a" data-bcid="564f313b67b6231408bc51ee" data-video="5fda4c5bb748e12cbbf1cacf"></div>
		<span><script type="text/javascript" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/themes/techcrunch-2017/features/shortcodes/vidible-callback-js.php?id=0"></script></span>
		</p>
<p>All despite the pandemic, which has caused nearly every company to change the way it operates. Callahan said that this has really put existing efforts to modernize operations into focus rather than upend their plans.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve been investing for probably the last five years or more in what we&#8217;re calling digital transformation — so, digital collaboration tools, building digital twins of our spacecraft, so multiple people can work on the design at the same time,&#8221; she explained. &#8220;The silver lining, if you want to think about it that way is&#8230; COVID has just helped to accelerate those. It&#8217;s teaching us that we can really collaborate in this kind of virtual environment in ways that maybe we&#8217;d never thought of.&#8221;</p>
<p>Lockheed&#8217;s next big milestone is the delivery of its Orion spacecraft to Kennedy Space Station in Cape Canaveral.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re really excited. We&#8217;ll be delivering that system over the VAB [NASA&#8217;s Vehicle Assembly Building], and it&#8217;ll go through its launch prep for a launch that will happen in 2021. And that will be the first time Orion will have launched off of the Space Launch System,&#8221; Callahan said.</p>
<p>Missed the event? Extra Crunch subscribers get access to full videos from our stage, including TC Sessions: Space, Disrupt, and all the rest. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/extracrunch/">You can sign up here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/lockheed-martins-lisa-callahan-on-building-a-lunar-lander-collaboratively-and-during-covid/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088906</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Discord raises $100M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/daily-crunch-discord-raises-100m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/daily-crunch-discord-raises-100m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 23:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discord]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088953</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Discord announces a big funding round, Google gets European approval to acquire Fitbit and Twitter launches a new voice-based feature. This is your Daily Crunch for December 17, 2020. Discord raises $100M The popular gaming chat platform confirmed today that it has raised $100 million and also announced that it has 140 million monthly active [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/discord" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="discord">Discord <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> announces a big funding round, Google gets European approval to acquire Fitbit and Twitter launches a new voice-based feature. This is your Daily Crunch for December 17, 2020.</p>
<p><strong>Discord raises $100M</strong></p>
<p>The popular gaming chat platform confirmed today that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/filing-discord-is-raising-up-to-140m-at-a-valuation-of-up-to-7b/">it has raised $100 million</a> and also announced that it has 140 million monthly active users, twice as many as a year ago.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“We are humbled and honored by the growth we’ve seen among so many incredible and diverse communities that have made Discord their place to hang out,” said CEO Jason Citron in a statement. “As we look to 2021, we are excited about what we have in store and plan to use this funding to help make Discord even better &#8212; both for our free service and our Nitro subscribers.”</p>
<p>The confirmation comes after TechCrunch reported that the company was raising up to $140 million at a valuation that could be as high as $7 billion.</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/europe-clears-google-fitbit-with-a-ten-year-ban-on-using-health-data-for-ads/">Europe clears Google-Fitbit with a ten-year ban on using health data for ads</a> — Under the terms of the EU’s clearance for the deal, Google has committed to not use Fitbit user data in the European Economic Area for ad targeting purposes for a 10-year period.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/twitter-launches-its-voice-based-spaces-social-networking-feature-into-beta-testing/">Twitter launches its voice-based ‘Spaces’ social networking feature into beta testing</a> — During this initial testing period, the product will be limited to select individuals, largely from underrepresented backgrounds, Twitter says.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/google-antitrust-lawsuit-new-york-colorado-35-states-search/">Google slammed for ‘monopoly power’ in new antitrust lawsuit from 35 states</a> — Compared to the Texas-led suit against Google announced yesterday, the second lawsuit represents a broader coalition of 35 states.</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/coinbase-files-to-go-public-confidentially-and-were-hyped/">Coinbase files to go public confidentially and we’re hyped</a> — To be clear, I don&#8217;t consider myself part of the &#8220;we&#8221; that&#8217;s hyped, but Alex Wilhelm definitely is.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/spryker-raises-130m-at-a-500m-valuation-to-provide-b2bs-with-agile-e-commerce-tools/">Spryker raises $130M at a $500M+ valuation to provide B2Bs with agile e-commerce tools</a> — Spryker offers a platform to bring a company’s inventory online, as well as tools to analyze and measure how that inventory is selling and where.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/health-insurer-oscar-adds-another-140-million-in-whats-likely-a-pre-ipo-round/">Health insurer Oscar adds another $140M in what’s likely a pre-IPO round</a> — The new capital means that Oscar has raised what would be the equivalent of $1 million a day for the entirety of 2020.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/virgin-orbit-relativity-space-and-astra-dish-on-the-economics-and-efficiencies-of-space-launches/">Virgin Orbit, Relativity Space and Astra dish on the economics and efficiencies of space launches</a> — Relativity Space CEO Tim Ellis, Astra CEO Chris Kemp and Virgin Orbit&#8217;s VOX Space President Mandy Vaughn all joined us at TC Sessions: Space to discuss their approaches to the small spacecraft launch market.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/fireeye-breach-solarwinds-federal-agencies/">Just how bad is that hack that hit US government agencies?</a> — Spoiler: It&#8217;s a nightmare scenario.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/the-top-10-enterprise-ma-deals-in-2020-totaled-a-staggering-165b/">2020’s top 10 enterprise M&amp;A deals totaled a staggering $165B</a> — It was a blockbuster year for enterprise M&amp;A.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which aims to democratize information about startups. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/hbo-max-will-finally-land-on-roku-devices-tomorrow/">HBO Max finally lands on Roku devices</a> — &#8220;Finally&#8221; gets overused in headlines, but it absolutely applies here.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/techcrunch-launches-securedrop/">You can now securely submit tips to TechCrunch using SecureDrop</a> — We’re making it easier and more secure for you to contact TechCrunch reporters and editors.</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/daily-crunch-discord-raises-100m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088953</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UiPath files confidential IPO paperwork with SEC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/uipath-files-confidential-ipo-paperwork-with-sec/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/uipath-files-confidential-ipo-paperwork-with-sec/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 22:51:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[initial public offering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotic process automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uipath]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[UiPath, the robotic process automation startup that has been growing like gangbusters, filed confidential paperwork with the SEC today ahead of a potential IPO. &#8220;UiPath, Inc. today announced that it has submitted a draft registration statement on a confidential basis to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (the “SEC”) for a proposed public offering of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://uipath.com">UiPath</a>, the robotic process automation startup that has been growing like gangbusters, filed confidential paperwork with the SEC today ahead of a potential IPO.</p>
<p>&#8220;<a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/uipath" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="uipath">UiPath, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Inc. today announced that it has submitted a draft registration statement on a confidential basis to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (the “SEC”) for a proposed public offering of its Class A common stock. The number of shares of Class A common stock to be sold and the price range for the proposed offering have not yet been determined. UiPath intends to commence the public offering following completion of the <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/sec-a9ff" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="sec-a9ff">SEC <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> review process, subject to market and other conditions,&#8221; the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>The company has raised more than $1.2 billion from investors like Accel, CapitalG, Sequoia and others. Its biggest raise was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/30/uipath-rpa-series-d/">$568 million led by Coatue</a> on an impressive $7 billion valuation in April 2019. It <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/13/uipath-reels-in-another-225m-as-valuation-soars-to-10-2b/">raised another $225 million</a> led by Alkeon Capital last July when its valuation soared to $10.2 billion.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XtaRJpvR6k"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/30/uipath-rpa-series-d/">UiPath nabs $568M at a $7B valuation to bring robotic process automation to the front office</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;UiPath nabs $568M at a $7B valuation to bring robotic process automation to the front office&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/30/uipath-rpa-series-d/embed/#?secret=XtaRJpvR6k" data-secret="XtaRJpvR6k" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>At the time of the July raise, CEO and co-founder Daniel Dines did not shy away from the idea of an IPO, telling me:</p>
<blockquote><p>We’re evaluating the market conditions and I wouldn’t say this to be vague, but we haven’t chosen a day that says on this day we’re going public. We’re really in the mindset that says we should be prepared when the market is ready, and I wouldn’t be surprised if that’s in the next 12-18 months.</p></blockquote>
<p>This definitely falls within that window. RPA helps companies take highly repetitive manual tasks and automate them. So for example, it could pull a number from an invoice, fill in a number in a spreadsheet and send an email to accounts payable, all without a human touching it.</p>
<p>It is a technology that has great appeal right now because it enables companies to take advantage of automation without ripping and replacing their legacy systems. While the company has raised a ton of money, and seen its valuation take off, it will be interesting to see if it will get the same positive reception as companies like Airbnb, C3.ai and Snowflake.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="H9KUjM9LYf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/13/uipath-reels-in-another-225m-as-valuation-soars-to-10-2b/">UiPath reels in another $225M as valuation soars to $10.2B</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;UiPath reels in another $225M as valuation soars to $10.2B&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/13/uipath-reels-in-another-225m-as-valuation-soars-to-10-2b/embed/#?secret=H9KUjM9LYf" data-secret="H9KUjM9LYf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/uipath-files-confidential-ipo-paperwork-with-sec/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088936</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Social gaming platform Rec Room scores $20 million Series C</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/social-gaming-platform-rec-room-scores-20-million-series-c/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/social-gaming-platform-rec-room-scores-20-million-series-c/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 21:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Against Gravity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[madrona venture group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rec Room]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social gaming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088699</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Social gaming platform Rec Room has scored some new funding as it aims to bring its once VR-centric world to every major gaming platform out there. The startup has closed a $20 million Series C led by Madrona Venture Group . Existing investors, including First Round Capital, Index, Sequoia and DAG, also participated in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Social gaming platform <a href="https://recroom.com/">Rec Room</a> has scored some new funding as it aims to bring its once VR-centric world to every major gaming platform out there.</p>
<p>The startup has closed a $20 million Series C led by <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/madrona-venture-group" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="madrona-venture-group">Madrona Venture Group <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>. Existing investors, including First Round Capital, Index, Sequoia and DAG, also participated in the round. They&#8217;ve raised just shy of $50 million to date.</p>
<p>The platform has been around for years serving as a social hub and gaming platform for virtual reality users. In recent years, the company has tried to scale its ambitions past being known as the &#8220;Roblox of VR&#8221; and scale its capabilities to meet its young user base. This year was big for the platform doing just that.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>CEO Nick Fajt estimates that the company has tripled its total audience since this time last year as the company has made a concerted drive on new platforms. <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">While a substantial portion of Rec Room&#8217;s audience still comes from its bread-and-butter VR audience, the platform&#8217;s base of console users has grown substantially in 2020 and, by the end of next year, Fajt expects that mobile will have grown to be Rec Room&#8217;s most common point of entry. Meanwhile, m</span>obile Android remains one of the last major gaming platforms on which <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/rec-room" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="rec-room">Rec Room <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> still doesn&#8217;t have a home.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="d7iKzr103C"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/12/against-gravity-is-building-a-vr-world-that-wont-stop-growing/">Against Gravity is building a VR world that won’t stop growing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Against Gravity is building a VR world that won’t stop growing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/12/against-gravity-is-building-a-vr-world-that-wont-stop-growing/embed/#?secret=d7iKzr103C" data-secret="d7iKzr103C" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>One of the company&#8217;s big aims heading into the new year is scaling their creation tools, which allow players to build their own experiences inside the game. More than 1 million of the platform&#8217;s 10 million registered users have engaged with creator tools, building 4 million distinct rooms on the platform. Next year, Fajt plans to scale up creator payments estimating that by the end of 2021 they&#8217;ll have paid out $1 million to their network.</p>
<p>Fajt says he wants creation tools on Rec Room to be more accessible to the general player base than other platforms, including Roblox, aiming to keep tools simple for now and push everyday users to invest time in the creation platform.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2088884" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2088884" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2088884 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ScreenShots_RecRoyale_Frontier.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ScreenShots_RecRoyale_Frontier.jpg 2560w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ScreenShots_RecRoyale_Frontier.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ScreenShots_RecRoyale_Frontier.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ScreenShots_RecRoyale_Frontier.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ScreenShots_RecRoyale_Frontier.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ScreenShots_RecRoyale_Frontier.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ScreenShots_RecRoyale_Frontier.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ScreenShots_RecRoyale_Frontier.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2088884" class="wp-caption-text">Image via Rec Room</p></div></p>
<p class="p1">&#8220;Roblox has an incredible business, that’s certainly no secret,&#8221; Fajt tells TechCrunch. &#8220;We want breadth of expression over depth of expression; we want anyone who comes into to Rec Room to be able to build.&#8221;</p>
<p>Despite the slow maturation of the VR market, Fajt says the company doesn&#8217;t plan on moving away from its VR roots anytime soon. The company has just updated its popular battle royale mode Rec Royale for the new Quest 2, as well as on iOS.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/social-gaming-platform-rec-room-scores-20-million-series-c/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088699</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Umba, a digital bank for emerging markets, raises $2M Seed funding to expand across Africa</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/umba-a-digital-bank-for-emerging-markets-raises-2m-seed-funding-to-expand-across-africa/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/umba-a-digital-bank-for-emerging-markets-raises-2m-seed-funding-to-expand-across-africa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 20:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brett deMarrais]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[east africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontline ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lachy Groom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ludlow Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paystack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stripe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Umba]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088787</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Umba, a digital bank for emerging markets and aiming first at Africa, has secured a $2 million seed funding round from new investors including Lachy Groom, ex-Head of Issuing at Stripe; Ludlow Ventures; Frontline Ventures and Act Venture. Currently operating in Kenya and Nigeria, Umba offers a digital financial service alternative to legacy African banks. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.umba.com/">Umba</a>, a digital bank for emerging markets and aiming first at Africa, has secured a $2 million seed funding round from new investors including Lachy Groom, ex-Head of Issuing at Stripe; Ludlow Ventures; Frontline Ventures and Act Venture.</p>
<p>Currently operating in <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/kenya" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="kenya">Kenya <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Nigeria, Umba offers a digital financial service alternative to legacy African banks. Its mobile app gives customers a free checking account, free instant peer-to-peer money transfers, lending, deposits, BillPay and cash back. This is in contrast to the generally high-cost barriers found among traditional banking institutions in African countries.</p>
<p>Right now it’s available in Kenya and Nigeria, which have a combined population of over a quarter of a billion people.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/umba" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="umba">Umba <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> competes with Kudao, Carbon, Eversend and &#8220;Chip or cash&#8221; methods.</p>
<p>Umba’s CEO Tiernan Kennedy said: “From the outset we built our platform to serve multiple markets, currencies and payment infrastructures. This flexibility is an extremely important consideration as it’s much harder to upgrade your systems at a later date. For example, bank and debit card penetration is high in Nigeria, so Umba is deeply integrated into those payment methods, while across Kenya and East Africa mobile money is dominant so our platform is tightly integrated with those services, too.&#8221;</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/ludlow-ventures-llc" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="ludlow-ventures-llc">Ludlow Ventures <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> partner Brett deMarrais said: “Umba is the first investment we’ve made in the African market and it’s one we were excited to participate in. The team at Umba have an excellent service that drives down the cost of banking for their customers and democratizes access. The move away from physical branch infrastructure was already underway and it has accelerated this year. It’s clear the African market is maturing and that we’re entering a very interesting phase.”</p>
<p>The news comes shortly after <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/stripe" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="stripe">Stripe’s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> $200 million acquisition of Nigerian payment service startup Paystack as well as the acquisition of DPO Group for $288 million and Sendwave for $500 million, showing a booming ecosystem breaking records in venture rounds and acquisitions.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nwrmHUPsZ0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/15/stripe-acquires-nigerias-paystack-for-200m-to-expand-into-the-african-continent/">Stripe acquires Nigeria&#8217;s Paystack for $200M+ to expand into the African continent</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Stripe acquires Nigeria&#8217;s Paystack for $200M+ to expand into the African continent&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/15/stripe-acquires-nigerias-paystack-for-200m-to-expand-into-the-african-continent/embed/#?secret=nwrmHUPsZ0" data-secret="nwrmHUPsZ0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/umba-a-digital-bank-for-emerging-markets-raises-2m-seed-funding-to-expand-across-africa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088787</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Venn diagram between crypto and OnlyFans</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/the-venn-diagram-between-crypto-and-onlyfans/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/the-venn-diagram-between-crypto-and-onlyfans/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 20:21:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture-capital-focused podcast (now on Twitter!), where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. For the first time in donkey&#8217;s years, we didn&#8217;t have our full crew this week. Instead, we had just Natasha and Chris and myself &#8212; we had to survive without Danny while he took the week [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/7b62fda4-6711-4978-a031-2108f993c4d6?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture-capital-focused podcast (<a href="https://twitter.com/equitypod">now on Twitter!</a>), where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>For the first time in donkey&#8217;s years, we didn&#8217;t have our full crew this week. Instead, we had just <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/cgates123">Chris</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">myself</a> &#8212; we had to survive without <a href="https://twitter.com/dannycrichton">Danny</a> while he took the week &#8220;off&#8221; to &#8220;relax.&#8221;</p>
<p>But our depleted ranks did not mean that news was waiting for us to reassemble. Indeed, there was a mass of stuff to get through:</p>
<ul>
<li>Atlanta-based Presso <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/dry-cleaning-robotics-startup-presso-raises-1-6m-as-it-shifts-focus-to-hollywood/">raised $1.6 million</a> for its in-unit dry cleaning tech, which we thought was neat.</li>
<li>OpenSensors <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/opensensors-secures-4m-for-air-monitoring-platform-which-allows-offices-to-be-more-covid-safe/">raised $4 million</a> for its air-monitoring tech after a history of bootstrapping.</li>
<li>Lantern, which helps folks plan for their death, is having a big year. It <a href="https://lantern.co/">raised $1.4 million</a>.</li>
<li>Public <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/social-stock-trading-services-public-raises-65m-series-c/">raised $65 million</a>, the same week that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/robinhood-pays-65m-to-settle-sec-charges-for-past-inferior-pricing-execution-misleading-customers/">Robinhood came under fire</a> by the Massachusetts securities group, and the SEC. Robinhood will pay $65 million to settle the SEC&#8217;s charges without admitting wrongdoing.</li>
<li>In the world of product, we chatted about <a href="https://blog.substack.com/p/new-reader-homepage">Substack&#8217;s new Reader service</a>, which we seem to like. (We also chatted about <a href="https://www.niemanlab.org/2020/12/journalists-will-learn-influencing-isnt-easy/">this</a> Taylor Lorenz piece.)</li>
<li>It was also prime season to chat a little about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/is-rising-usage-driving-cryptos-recent-price-boom/">what&#8217;s new in the Bitcoin world</a>, and take a peek at the stock market&#8217;s recent over-success. Roblox, see you in 2021.</li>
</ul>
<p>And for everyone who made it to the end, here are the pieces <a href="https://www.axios.com/creators-income-revenue-snapchat-cameo-substack-66457b1b-a9ab-4065-b0c6-58baa81edec4.html">from Axios</a> <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/onlyfans-is-not-only-popular-but-hugely-profitable">and The Information</a> that we mentioned.</p>
<p>Before we say goodbye, our very own Natasha is taking on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/startups-weekly/">Startups Weekly</a>, a long-time TechCrunch Newsletter.<a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters"> Subscribe</a> to it for her debut issue, and while you&#8217;re at it, check out Alex&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/the-exchange/">The Exchange,</a> which goes out the same day and means the Equity conversation can continue well into your weekends.</p>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST and Thursday afternoon as fast as we can get it out, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts.</i></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="container__access-control">
<div class="article__comments">
<div class="comments__spot-im--locked">
<div class="comments__spot-im__modal-wrapper"></div>
<div id="comments__spot-im__container" class="comments__spot-im__container" data-post-id="2078782" data-spot-id="sp_It0mQWOO">
<div data-spotim-default-areas="">
<div data-spot-im-module-default-area="multiplex" data-spot-id="sp_It0mQWOO" data-post-id="2078782"></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/the-venn-diagram-between-crypto-and-onlyfans/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088681</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coinbase files to go public confidentially and we&#8217;re hyped</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/coinbase-files-to-go-public-confidentially-and-were-hyped/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/coinbase-files-to-go-public-confidentially-and-were-hyped/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 20:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088810</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Coinbase, perhaps the best-known American crypto company, announced today that it has filed confidentially to go public. The company&#8217;s debut was expected, having been reported earlier in the year. As the well-funded unicorn has filed confidentially, its debut looks to be an early-2021 affair. What sort of flotation the company will pursue is not clear [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.coinbase.com/">Coinbase</a>, perhaps the best-known American crypto company, <a href="https://blog.coinbase.com/coinbase-announces-confidential-submission-of-draft-registration-statement-b140a9dfc9f5">announced</a> today that it has filed confidentially to go public. The company&#8217;s debut was expected, having been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/coinbase-reported-to-consider-late-2020-early-2021-public-debut/">reported earlier in the year</a>.</p>
<p>As the well-funded unicorn has filed confidentially, its debut looks to be an early-2021 affair. What sort of flotation the company will pursue is not clear at this stage. <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/coinbase" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="coinbase">Coinbase&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> announcement is anodyne, as releases of this sort tend to be. The text of the short blog post does not mention whether Coinbase will pursue a traditional IPO or direct listing, but Slack&#8217;s <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20190204005225/en/">similar message</a> from early 2019 was similarly devoid of information; Slack went public via a direct listing last year before agreeing recently to sell to Salesforce.</p>
<p>Coinbase raised extensive known capital while private, including a $300 million Series E in October of 2018. Its August, 2017 Series D was worth a hair over $100 million, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/coinbase">according to Crunchbase data</a>. Tiger Global, Andreessen Horowitz, DFJ Growth and IVP are among the investors that led rounds into the crypto-focused fintech company.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TeO6HCxgtp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/coinbase-reported-to-consider-late-2020-early-2021-public-debut/">Coinbase reported to consider late 2020, early 2021 public debut</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Coinbase reported to consider late 2020, early 2021 public debut&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/coinbase-reported-to-consider-late-2020-early-2021-public-debut/embed/#?secret=TeO6HCxgtp" data-secret="TeO6HCxgtp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>It is not clear how large Coinbase&#8217;s revenues have grown, or how profitable or not its operations have proven in recent years. While there has been some reporting about its historical growth, how the company has fared more recently is opaque. Therefore, how well Coinbase&#8217;s impending public valuation will compare to its <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/funding_round/coinbase-series-e--25f6f746">$8 billion private valuation</a> is hard to guess.</p>
<p>The company is going public amidst a surge of interest in cryptocurrencies, the prices of many having risen in recent months. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/is-rising-usage-driving-cryptos-recent-price-boom/">TechCrunch explored the trend earlier today.</a></p>
<p>Coinbase has also been in a number of controversial spots in 2020, including the loss of dozens of employees after its CEO declared that the company would not participate in any political matters that were not, in his view, directly tied to the company&#8217;s mission.<b> </b>The ensuing dialogue about the company&#8217;s decision <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/working-for-social-justice-isnt-a-distraction-for-mission-focused-companies/">was loud</a>.</p>
<p>Regardless, with Roblox and Affirm now taking an early-2021 tack for their own IPOs, we can add Coinbase to the list of companies we expect to float in January.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DOA4znAlhf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/working-for-social-justice-isnt-a-distraction-for-mission-focused-companies/">Working for social justice isn&#8217;t a &#8216;distraction&#8217; for mission-focused companies</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Working for social justice isn&#8217;t a &#8216;distraction&#8217; for mission-focused companies&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/working-for-social-justice-isnt-a-distraction-for-mission-focused-companies/embed/#?secret=DOA4znAlhf" data-secret="DOA4znAlhf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/coinbase-files-to-go-public-confidentially-and-were-hyped/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088810</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>We must end the era of adjunct surveillance</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/we-must-end-the-era-of-adjunct-surveillance/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/we-must-end-the-era-of-adjunct-surveillance/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 20:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088757</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To anyone paying attention, it has become painfully evident that the surveillance pendulum has swung too far.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Vijay Sundaram</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/vijaysundaram/">Vijay Sundaram</a> is the Chief Strategy Officer of Zoho Corporation, the parent company of ManageEngine. He leads or is involved in multiple functional areas from corporate strategy and execution to channel management, business development and enterprise sales.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">As consumers, most of us <a href="https://www.pwc.com/us/en/services/consulting/library/consumer-intelligence-series/cybersecurity-protect-me.html">don’t mind providing companies</a> like Google, Facebook and Twitter with our personal data, as long as we get access to the services and solutions we want to use. However, many people don’t realize that these companies function as data-collecting surveillance organizations, integrating data collection into their business models in clandestine ways.</p>
<p>Unbeknownst to users, many companies allow third parties to place embed codes on their websites, capturing user behavior to either harvest or sell to other parties. This practice of &#8220;adjunct surveillance,&#8221; as Zoho Chief Evangelist Raju Vegesna describes it, has become common practice given a lack of resistance from users, investors and other business leaders.</p>
<p>To anyone paying attention, it has become painfully evident that the surveillance pendulum has swung too far. Companies are collecting <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/cambridge-analytica-sought-to-use-facebook-data-to-predict-partisanship-for-voter-targeting-uk-investigation-confirms/">and sharing</a> user data with impunity. In fact, adjunct surveillance has become so egregious that a wave of data privacy laws has sprung up in recent years: the EU&#8217;s GDPR, California&#8217;s CCPA, New York&#8217;s SHIELD Act and Brazil&#8217;s LGPD, among others.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			It’s time for tech leaders to take a stand by formally, and visibly, taking a privacy pledge.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Due to increased government regulation and public awareness, business leaders are starting to see the writing on the wall. However, it&#8217;s not enough to rely on lawmakers and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/29/apple-ceo-tim-cook-questioned-over-app-stores-removal-of-rival-screen-time-apps-in-antitrust-hearing/">regulators&#8217; activity</a>. It is also not enough to be<em> legally</em> compliant, burying the notices in legalese or fine print. Such Machiavellian maneuvers may technically be legal, but they&#8217;re certainly not moral.</p>
<p>It’s time for tech leaders to take a stand by formally, and visibly, taking a privacy pledge.</p>
<h2>Don&#8217;t let advertising companies track your users without their knowledge</h2>
<p>Even if your business depends upon selling user data to third-party advertisers, it is vital that you inform your users about what you&#8217;re doing with their data. In some cases, it very well may be legal to withhold such information from users; however, that doesn&#8217;t make it right.</p>
<p>Since its inception in 1996, ManageEngine — then doing business as Zoho — has refused to allow any third-party advertisements on any of its websites or products. In an effort to block all adjunct surveillance, they don&#8217;t allow the embedding of any third-party tracking codes anywhere on their sites. Although social media share buttons may seem innocuous, they should be removed as well, as the buttons can essentially function as Trojan horses.</p>
<h2>Inform your customers about any third-party integrations that may track their data</h2>
<p>If your enterprise is financially reliant on such activity, it needs to be transparent about it. Take Google as an example: Many of us don&#8217;t have a problem using Gmail because we value the service enough to provide the search behemoth with our data. However, when Google leverages our user data to enter into partnerships with credit card and healthcare companies on the sly, that is a different story entirely.</p>
<p>Google partnered with Ascension hospitals back in 2018 on &#8220;Project Nightingale,&#8221; a data-sharing initiative that was not revealed to Ascension patients. Although subsequent investigations found that Google had not technically violated HIPAA, or any other laws for that matter, it is likely that the public wouldn&#8217;t even know about this initiative had it not been for this <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/google-s-secret-project-nightingale-gathers-personal-health-data-on-millions-of-americans-11573496790">scoop</a>. Also, it&#8217;s highly unlikely that this type of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/18/the-coming-fight-over-who-controls-digital-health-data/">surreptitious health data partnership</a> is an anomaly.</p>
<p>As another example, Google also secretly partnered with Mastercard in an effort to compete with Amazon and capture consumer retail spending data. After an exposé revealed the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/31/google-and-mastercard-reportedly-partner-to-track-offline-purchases/">clandestine partnership</a>, both companies claimed that they didn&#8217;t have any personally identifiable information for any customers. According to Google, they utilized double-blind encryption technology that protected all user data, which had been aggregated and anonymized. Despite this frequently made argument that all the users&#8217; personal data had been &#8220;de-identified,&#8221; at no point were Mastercard or Google users made privy of the deal. In all likelihood, this Mastercard partnership is not a one-off for Google. Through an <a href="https://blog.google/products/ads/">AdWords blog</a>, Google claims to have access to 70% of all credit and debit card users&#8217; activity.</p>
<p>The moral of the story? Don’t be like Google.</p>
<h2>Use encryption tools to protect customer data transmitted over public networks</h2>
<p>If your business sends user data over public networks, ensure all server connections use encryption with strong ciphers. Follow the hypertext transfer protocol secure (HTTPS) and the transport layer security (TLS) protocols to ensure there is always a secure connection between web browsers, your corporate server and all third-party servers. Not only does the TLS protocol allow both parties to be authenticated, but it also encrypts the data, ensuring that no third parties can eavesdrop or otherwise interfere with the data transfer process.</p>
<h2>Consider investing in internal data centers</h2>
<p>If economically feasible, companies should store customer data in self-owned data centers, or own the servers inside these data centers. By not relying on third-party data centers and public cloud offerings, not only will you bolster your data privacy initiatives, but you&#8217;ll also likely save money over time. Additionally, your company will benefit as more and more users begin to value companies that go out of their way to protect user data.</p>
<p>As a private company, ManageEngine has never been beholden to external shareholders, which has allowed executives to look at things through a philosophical lens as opposed to a financial lens. From the outset, they&#8217;ve always placed a premium on user privacy, which is why the current surveillance landscape has garnered such ire within their organization. To be sure, they&#8217;ve left some money on the table by taking such a hard line on privacy.</p>
<p>However, as Vegesna frequently asks, &#8220;What&#8217;s the point of being financially profitable if your business is morally bankrupt?&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FzqwG3nR3f"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/cambridge-analytica-sought-to-use-facebook-data-to-predict-partisanship-for-voter-targeting-uk-investigation-confirms/">Cambridge Analytica sought to use Facebook data to predict partisanship for voter targeting, UK investigation confirms</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cambridge Analytica sought to use Facebook data to predict partisanship for voter targeting, UK investigation confirms&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/cambridge-analytica-sought-to-use-facebook-data-to-predict-partisanship-for-voter-targeting-uk-investigation-confirms/embed/#?secret=FzqwG3nR3f" data-secret="FzqwG3nR3f" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/we-must-end-the-era-of-adjunct-surveillance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088757</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>You can now securely submit tips to TechCrunch using SecureDrop</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/techcrunch-launches-securedrop/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/techcrunch-launches-securedrop/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 20:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dark web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom of the press foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet traffic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[securedrop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whistleblowing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2068862</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Now we're making it easier and more secure for you to contact our reporters and editors.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">For the past few years, some of the biggest stories on TechCrunch have come from you.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve revealed <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/22/google-employees-demand-company-stop-selling-tech-to-police/">internal employee battles</a> at some of the world&#8217;s biggest tech companies, reported on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/16/t-mobile-layoffs-sprint/">unexpected layoffs</a> during <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/27/bird-lays-off-about-30-of-workforce-amid-covid-19-pandemic/">the pandemic</a>, uncovered safety violations, seen how Facebook <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/29/facebook-project-atlas/">paid teens to snoop</a> on their private data, revealed a major hack that a company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/03/stockx-hacked-millions-records/">tried to cover up</a>, and exposed workplace discrimination, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/07/nso-group-fleming-contact-tracing/">secretive startups</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/27/aclu-ice-stingray-documents/">government wrongdoing</a>.</p>
<p>We have been able to report on these important issues in large part because sources have reached out with information that companies and governments don&#8217;t want to come to light.</p>
<p>Now we&#8217;re making it easier and more secure for you to contact TechCrunch reporters and editors.</p>
<p>Today, we are launching our own SecureDrop, a tip submission system that allows you to securely and anonymously reach out with information, files and documents for us to investigate.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2068864" style="width: 2330px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2068864" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2068864 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/securedrop-hero.jpg" alt="" width="2320" height="1638" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/securedrop-hero.jpg 2320w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/securedrop-hero.jpg?resize=150,106 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/securedrop-hero.jpg?resize=300,212 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/securedrop-hero.jpg?resize=768,542 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/securedrop-hero.jpg?resize=680,480 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/securedrop-hero.jpg?resize=1536,1084 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/securedrop-hero.jpg?resize=2048,1446 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/securedrop-hero.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2320px) 100vw, 2320px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2068864" class="wp-caption-text">This is what TechCrunch&#8217;s SecureDrop looks like. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>SecureDrop is a system designed to allow us to communicate with you while protecting your identity from virtually all kinds of tracking. It works in part thanks to the Tor anonymity network, which bounces and encrypts your internet traffic through several servers on its way to its destination in order to make tracking almost impossible. Accessing Tor — and our SecureDrop — requires use of the free-to-use Tor Browser. That means we won&#8217;t know who you are, unless you tell us.</p>
<p>We know what sources risk in revealing information that the powerful want to keep secret.</p>
<p>Rest assured, our SecureDrop is physically controlled by TechCrunch, and anything you submit to SecureDrop is encrypted and can only be viewed by TechCrunch editors. The software itself, maintained by the nonprofit <a href="https://securedrop.org/directory/techcrunch">Freedom of the Press Foundation</a>, goes through regular security audits and will be kept up-to-date with the latest fixes.</p>
<p>You can access instructions on how to use our SecureDrop by going to: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/securedrop"><strong>techcrunch.com/securedrop</strong></a></p>
<p>We&#8217;re looking forward to hearing from you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/techcrunch-launches-securedrop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2068862</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Whatnot raises $4M as it gets into livestreamed auctions and Pokémon cards</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/whatnot-raises-4m-as-it-gets-into-livestreamed-auctions-and-pokemon-cards/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/whatnot-raises-4m-as-it-gets-into-livestreamed-auctions-and-pokemon-cards/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 19:36:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whatnot]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088785</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whatnot, a company I first wrote about back in February, has spent the months since growing rapidly — both in terms of feature set and user base. This morning the company is announcing it has raised a $4 million seed round. Originally focused on being a platform for safely reselling FunkoPop vinyl figurines, Whatnot has [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.whatnot.com">Whatnot</a>, a company I <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/whatnot-wants-to-be-the-goat-of-collectible-toys-starting-with-funko-pop-figurines/">first wrote about back in February</a>, has spent the months since growing rapidly — both in terms of feature set and user base. This morning the company is announcing it has raised a $4 million seed round.</p>
<p>Originally focused on being a platform for safely reselling FunkoPop vinyl figurines, Whatnot has since expanded into other types of collectables, including Pokémon cards, sports cards and FiGPiNs.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3fjS1ZzGgS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/whatnot-wants-to-be-the-goat-of-collectible-toys-starting-with-funko-pop-figurines/">Whatnot wants to be the GOAT of collectible toys, starting with Funko Pops</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Whatnot wants to be the GOAT of collectible toys, starting with Funko Pops&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/whatnot-wants-to-be-the-goat-of-collectible-toys-starting-with-funko-pop-figurines/embed/#?secret=3fjS1ZzGgS" data-secret="3fjS1ZzGgS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The company has also expanded beyond simple buying/selling mechanics, embracing a trend that was already proving popular before the pandemic struck and has only grown since: livestreamed video sales and auctions.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve never fallen down the rabbit hole that is collecting, perhaps you haven&#8217;t seen this kind of sale — but once you&#8217;ve tuned in, it&#8217;s hard to stop. Popular amongst groups like Disney pin traders, live video auctions are … well, they&#8217;re exactly what they sound like. The host fires up a livestream, a notification going out to their fanbase of fellow collectors that it&#8217;s time for a sale. Their phone camera pointed at the item up for grabs (often spinning in place on a turntable to give a full view of its condition), the host&#8217;s job is part auctioneer, part hype man. They&#8217;ve got to know the ins and outs of the item in question, interact with folks in chat, and generally just keep the energy high so that viewers stick around.</p>
<p>A lot of these auctions happen on platforms like Instagram, which … aren&#8217;t really built for this. Selling an item there means manually connecting with buyers after the fact, figuring out payments and hoping no one backs out. Whatnot wants to specialize in it and has spent the last few months building out livestreaming tools accordingly. Streams are handled directly through their mobile app, as is all the payment and processing on the seller&#8217;s end. I popped into a few random streams last night, and they each had dozens to hundreds of people watching and bidding on items like Mumm-Ra Funko Pops, with users trying to guess what might show up in the stream next.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2088789" style="width: 1459px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2088789" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2088789 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/whatnot-auction.jpg" alt="" width="1449" height="902" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/whatnot-auction.jpg 1449w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/whatnot-auction.jpg?resize=150,93 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/whatnot-auction.jpg?resize=300,187 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/whatnot-auction.jpg?resize=768,478 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/whatnot-auction.jpg?resize=680,423 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/whatnot-auction.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1449px) 100vw, 1449px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2088789" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Whatnot</p></div></p>
<p>Another increasingly popular livestreaming concept for Whatnot is that of the &#8220;card break.&#8221; Users pool their money to buy an entire box of trading card packs — often boxes that are no longer being produced and can cost thousands of dollars to obtain. Each user gets a number, each number tied to a pack (or packs) within the box. Each pack is opened on the livestream, its contents sent to the (hopefully?) lucky owner tied to that pack&#8217;s number.</p>
<p>Whatnot co-founder Logan Head calls the company&#8217;s growth in recent months &#8220;explosive,&#8221; telling me that additions like livestreaming have helped them grow &#8220;at least 100% month-over-month&#8221; as of late. The Whatnot team has grown as well. It&#8217;s currently sitting at 12 employees and is actively looking for more engineers — thus the need to raise. The company tells me that this $4 million seed round was backed by Scribble Ventures, Operator Partners, Wonder Ventures, Y Combinator and a number of angel investors.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/whatnot-raises-4m-as-it-gets-into-livestreamed-auctions-and-pokemon-cards/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088785</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Virgin Orbit, Relativity Space and Astra dish on the economics and efficiencies of space launches</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/virgin-orbit-relativity-space-and-astra-dish-on-the-economics-and-efficiencies-of-space-launches/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/virgin-orbit-relativity-space-and-astra-dish-on-the-economics-and-efficiencies-of-space-launches/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 19:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Astra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chris kemp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relativity Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions Space 2020]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tim ellis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Orbit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088745</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Relativity Space CEO Tim Ellis, Astra CEO Chris Kemp and VOX Space (Virgin Orbit&#8217;s national-security-focused subsidiary) President Mandy Vaughn all joined us at TC Sessions: Space to jointly discuss their varied approaches to the small spacecraft launch market. Each has a very different type of space launch system, but each is targeting roughly the same [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/relativity-space" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="relativity-space">Relativity Space <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> CEO <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/tim-ellis-3" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="tim-ellis-3">Tim Ellis, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Astra CEO Chris Kemp and VOX Space (Virgin Orbit&#8217;s national-security-focused subsidiary) President Mandy Vaughn all joined us at TC Sessions: Space to jointly discuss their varied approaches to the small spacecraft launch market. Each has a very different type of space launch system, but each is targeting roughly the same group of customers.</p>
<p>There are plenty of those customers to go around, they all agree, but they each have very different takes on the best way to serve this growing need in the space industry. Check out the full panel below to learn more about that in detail.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/virgin-orbit-relativity-space-and-astra-dish-on-the-economics-and-efficiencies-of-space-launches/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088745</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NASA&#8217;s Kathy Lueders discusses the Artemis moon landing 2024 target and team selection</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/nasas-kathy-lueders-discusses-the-artemis-moon-landing-2024-target-and-team-selection/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/nasas-kathy-lueders-discusses-the-artemis-moon-landing-2024-target-and-team-selection/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 19:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artemis program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[astronaut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial crew program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emily Calandrelli]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jim bridenstine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kathy Lueders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions Space 2020]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088671</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NASA&#8217;s head of human spaceflight Kathy Lueders joined us on stage at TechCrunch Sessions: Space, where she spoke to scientist and Netflix host Emily Calandrelli about her work at the agency — including NASA&#8217;s progress on the Artemis program and the return of American astronauts to the surface of the moon. The 2024 target for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/nasa" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="nasa">NASA&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> head of human spaceflight Kathy Lueders joined us on stage at TechCrunch Sessions: Space, where she spoke to <a href="http://www.thespacegal.com">scientist and Netflix host Emily Calandrelli</a> about her work at the agency — including NASA&#8217;s progress on the Artemis program and the return of American astronauts to the surface of the moon.</p>
<p>The 2024 target for NASA&#8217;s first Artemis moon landing has been oft-repeated by the agency, and by current NASA administrator Jim Bridenstine, who has confirmed that his tenure is ending in January once the Biden administration takes over the U.S. presidency. But it&#8217;s also a timeline that has raised many an eyebrow among outside observers, and seems particularly challenging given setbacks resulting from stay-at-home orders and remote-work measures implemented by NASA in response to the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we had Commercial Crew, my goal was 2017,&#8221; Lueders said. &#8220;We did not fly in 2017, even though we were working super, super hard to get to 2017. Having that 2017 goal didn&#8217;t mean that I made stupid decisions just to get to 2017 — I still carefully went through and made the decisions. And then we ended up flying in 2020 — in fact we ended up flying [the mission] in 2019, which originally would have been our 2017 goal. People get very fixated on 2024, because it is an important goal for us. But I also know that we&#8217;ll work through this carefully, and we will inform people of our progress along the way, just like we&#8217;ve done for every single other program out there. And we will fly when we&#8217;re ready to fly with the mission capability that we need to fly in a safe and effective manner.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Lueders also addressed a question about diversity, and racial diversity in the agency, and its importance to the agency. Lueders is the first woman to ever occupy the role of the associate administrator of the Human Exploration and Operations Mission Directorate, who leads all human spaceflight activities across the agency.</p>
<p>&#8220;I want people to see themselves in what we&#8217;re doing, because the point of this is it&#8217;s not about NASA doing this anymore,&#8221; she said. &#8220;This is about you doing it, and about you being able to do it. I think one of the most striking things that I got was a letter from a nine-year-old girl in India right after I got announced. And she said, &#8216;Because you have your job, I think I can be NASA administrator someday.&#8217; And you saw the diversity in that Artemis crew, and we want people to see themselves out there.&#8221;</p>
<p>Lueders also talked about the<a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-names-artemis-team-of-astronauts-eligible-for-early-moon-missions"> diversity present in the NASA Artemis astronaut class</a>, which it just announced, and about the potential for who from that pool will be selected to actually crew the first lunar landing for Artemis.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of my favorite things is, I&#8217;m still not sure it can&#8217;t be two women,&#8221; she said. &#8220;We need to pick the right people.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/nasas-kathy-lueders-discusses-the-artemis-moon-landing-2024-target-and-team-selection/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088671</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8216;Gas stations in space&#8217; startup Orbit Fab extends seed round to $6M with strategic investor Munich Re Ventures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/gas-stations-in-space-startup-orbit-fab-extends-seed-round-to-6m-with-strategic-investor-munich-re/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/gas-stations-in-space-startup-orbit-fab-extends-seed-round-to-6m-with-strategic-investor-munich-re/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 18:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daniel faber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Science Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orbit Fab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spacecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions Space 2020]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2087895</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Orbit Fab CDO Jeremy Schiel shows off the company&#8217;s satellite coupling system on stage at TC Disrupt 2019. On-orbit servicing startup Orbit Fab, which bills itself as the company focused on creating &#8220;gas stations in space,&#8221; has added an additional investor to its seed funding round. The add-on investment comes from Munich Re Ventures (the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>Orbit Fab CDO Jeremy Schiel shows off the company&#8217;s satellite coupling system on stage at TC Disrupt 2019.</h6>
<p id="speakable-summary">On-orbit servicing startup <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/orbit-fab" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="orbit-fab">Orbit Fab, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> which bills itself as the company focused on creating &#8220;gas stations in space,&#8221; has added an additional investor to its seed funding round. The add-on investment comes from Munich Re Ventures (the corporate VC arm of Munich Re Group, one of the largest insurance companies in the world). Munich Re Group is a key provider of insurance for satellite operators in particular, offering policies that cover pre-launch, launch and on-orbit operations.</p>
<p>Orbit Fab, which was a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/03/orbit-fab-gas-stations-in-space-seed-funding/">finalist in our TechCrunch Disrupt Battlefield</a> in 2019, has designed a system that consists of what are essentially in-space tugs that can guide spacecraft on-orbit to refueling depots, to which they connect with the company&#8217;s custom fueling interface. It&#8217;s designed to be relatively easy to incorporate into new satellite designs, providing a way to easily refuel in space without requiring any special robotic systems for capture and docking.</p>
<p>The goal of the startup is to help create a more sustainable orbital commercial operating environment, extending the life of spacecraft, reducing debris and saving companies money. Bringing on Munich Re Ventures should provide it with significant advantages in terms of being able to build more sustainable, long-lived operational spacecraft into launch and operation risk models for satellite operators.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;When we look at standing up a propellant supply chain, so much of it is the financial model,&#8221; Orbit Fab co-founder and CEO <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/daniel-faber" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="daniel-faber">Daniel Faber <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> told me in an interview. &#8220;How do we use this to move our customers&#8217; risk, to make sure that we&#8217;re moving capital expenditure to operational expenditure, and yet not introducing additional risk?&#8221;</p>
<p>Faber went on to explain that Munich Re Ventures Timur Davis began to show up at more and more space conferences, and Faber began to chat with him at these events. It turned out that the venture firm was putting together an investment thesis around in-space servicing and infrastructure, and Orbit Fab eventually became the first investment on the back of that new thesis.</p>
<p>The new investment brings Orbit Fab&#8217;s total seed raise to $6 million, including between $2 to $3 million in government funding on top of VC funds. The company has also now conceived and researched a &#8220;self-driving satellite&#8221; kit for docking that it has received <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/national-science-foundation" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="national-science-foundation">National Science Foundation <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> funding to do preliminary requirements development, and it&#8217;s now at the point where it can begin designing and building that out. 2021 looks to be a big year for many new companies in the space industry, and Orbit Fab with its new approach to sustainable, scalable satellites operations is definitely among them.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hK0ovjoQ0f"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/03/orbit-fab-gas-stations-in-space-seed-funding/">Orbit Fab raises $3M to make orbital refueling easier, cheaper and more accessible</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Orbit Fab raises $3M to make orbital refueling easier, cheaper and more accessible&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/03/orbit-fab-gas-stations-in-space-seed-funding/embed/#?secret=hK0ovjoQ0f" data-secret="hK0ovjoQ0f" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/gas-stations-in-space-startup-orbit-fab-extends-seed-round-to-6m-with-strategic-investor-munich-re/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2087895</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google slammed for &#8216;monopoly power&#8217; in new antitrust lawsuit from 35 states</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/google-antitrust-lawsuit-new-york-colorado-35-states-search/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/google-antitrust-lawsuit-new-york-colorado-35-states-search/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 18:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antitrust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The battle over big tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088697</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Another day, another major antitrust effort seeking to dismantle the unprecedented power of the world&#8217;s biggest tech companies. On Thursday, a group of 38 attorneys general announced a bipartisan lawsuit against Google, alleging the company has engaged in &#8220;illegal, anti-competitive conduct&#8221; to create a monopoly in search and search advertising. &#8220;Google’s anti-competitive actions have protected [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Another day, another <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/google-state-antitrust-lawsuit-texas-paxton/">major antitrust effort</a> seeking to dismantle the unprecedented power of the world&#8217;s biggest tech companies.</p>
<p>On Thursday, a group of 38 attorneys general announced a bipartisan lawsuit against <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/google" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="google">Google, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> alleging the company has engaged in &#8220;illegal, anti-competitive conduct&#8221; to create a monopoly in search and search advertising.</p>
<p>&#8220;Google’s anti-competitive actions have protected its general search monopolies and excluded rivals, depriving consumers of the benefits of competitive choices, forestalling innovation, and undermining new entry or expansion,&#8221; Colorado Attorney General Phil Weiser said. “This lawsuit seeks to restore competition.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The state of Colorado is co-leading the lawsuit with Arizona, Iowa, Nebraska, New York, North Carolina, Tennessee and Utah. New York Attorney General Letitia James called Google the &#8220;gatekeeper of the internet&#8221; and slammed the company for leveraging the personal data it collects to solidify its market dominance.</p>
<p>Compared to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/google-state-antitrust-lawsuit-texas-paxton/">Texas-led suit against Google</a> announced yesterday, the second lawsuit represents a broader coalition of 35 states, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico and Guam. The new lawsuit, embedded below, will run in parallel with the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/justice-department-will-reportedly-file-its-antitrust-lawsuit-against-google-today/">Justice Department&#8217;s own federal suit</a>, which also alleges that the company has abused its power to create and maintain a monopoly.</p>
<p>In the new lawsuit, the group of states accuses Google of entering into exclusionary agreements, disadvantaging specialized search sites like Expedia and Yelp and favoring its own business with its search engine marketing tools. They describe Google&#8217;s power as self-reinforcing, blaming the company for limiting consumers&#8217; options and in turn feeding it more valuable data on their behavior.</p>
<p>Citing violations of Section 2 of the Sherman Act, the federal antitrust law meant to protect competition, the group of states asks the court to rebalance the advantages that Google enjoys and suggests &#8220;structural divestitures&#8221; as one course of action.</p>
<p>Unlike the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/facebook-antitrust-state-attorneys-general/">46-state suit against Facebook</a> we saw last week, U.S. state efforts to challenge Google were split in two. Why are there <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/google-state-antitrust-lawsuit-texas-paxton/">two separate antitrust lawsuits</a> going after Google over similar complaints? Likely because many state leaders weren&#8217;t eager to sign on to an effort led by Texas Attorney General Ken Paxton, who not only led the doomed long-shot effort to overturn election results in four states but is also <a href="https://apnews.com/article/ken-paxton-austin-texas-crime-f8413d14842d848e69cf81bb4d2e87e2">currently being investigated by the FBI</a> for bribery.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/public-policy/redesigning-search-would-harm-consumers-and-american-businesses/">blog post</a>, Google responded to the allegations presented in the new suit, emphasizing the company&#8217;s positive impact on consumers and small businesses.&#8221;&#8230;This lawsuit seeks to redesign Search in ways that would deprive Americans of helpful information and hurt businesses’ ability to connect directly with customers,&#8221; Adam Cohen, Google&#8217;s Director of Economic Policy, wrote. &#8220;We look forward to making that case in court, while remaining focused on delivering a high-quality search experience for our users.&#8221;</p>
<p><iframe class="scribd_iframe_embed" src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/488521765/content?start_page=1&view_mode&access_key=key-1TC9ol9dGPRmpFoeXjx9"  data-auto-height="true" scrolling="no" id="scribd_488521765" width="100%" height="500" frameborder="0"></iframe>
		<div style="font-size:10px;text-align:center;width:100%"><a href="https://www.scribd.com/doc/488521765" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">View this document on Scribd</a></div></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Yp9W312jnG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/facebook-antitrust-state-attorneys-general/">Facebook hit with massive antitrust lawsuit from 46 states</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook hit with massive antitrust lawsuit from 46 states&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/facebook-antitrust-state-attorneys-general/embed/#?secret=Yp9W312jnG" data-secret="Yp9W312jnG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/google-antitrust-lawsuit-new-york-colorado-35-states-search/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088697</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Update: Discord confirms raising $100M, sources say at a valuation of up to $7B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/filing-discord-is-raising-up-to-140m-at-a-valuation-of-up-to-7b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/filing-discord-is-raising-up-to-140m-at-a-valuation-of-up-to-7b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 18:45:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088638</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The world of virtual communications continues to hold a central place in our socially-distanced lives, and today it looks like one of the companies reaping some of the spoils is also reaping some funding out of it. Discord, the chat and communications platform wildly popular with gamers and, increasingly, many others, has confirmed to us [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The world of virtual communications continues to hold a central place in our socially-distanced lives, and today it looks like one of the companies reaping some of the spoils is also reaping some funding out of it. <a href="http://discord.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a>, the chat and communications platform wildly popular with gamers and, increasingly, many others, has confirmed to us today that it has raised $100 million more in funding as it hits 140 million monthly active users, double the number it had a year ago.</p>
<p>“We are humbled and honored by the growth we’ve seen among so many incredible and diverse communities that have made Discord their place to hang out,&#8221; said co-founder and CEO Jason Citron in a statement. &#8220;As we look to 2021, we are excited about what we have in store and plan to use this funding to help make Discord even better &#8211; both for our free service and our <a href="https://discord.com/nitro" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://discord.com/nitro&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1608323767203000&amp;usg=AFQjCNH8y28UNMK7cpgOyRnj5JgeY58wrg">Nitro</a> subscribers.”</p>
<p>Greenoaks Capital is leading this round, and we&#8217;ve confirmed with sources that Index Ventures is also participating.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Discord is the best place to gather with your communities, whether to play video games, swap recipes, or collaborate on a project,&#8221; said Neil Mehta, founder and managing partner at Greenoaks Capital, in a statement. &#8220;We believe Discord will evolve and grow alongside the endless innovation in the ways people interact, ultimately connecting billions of people around the world. We are lucky to continue our long-term partnership with Jason, Stan and the entire Discord team.&#8221;</p>
<p>Earlier today, we reported that the company was in the process of raising up to $140 million in a Series H round, at a valuation that could be as high as $7 billion, according to paperwork filed by the company and unearthed by <a href="https://primeunicornindex.com/discord-secures-140m-doubles-valuation-to-7b/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Prime Unicorn Index</a>.</p>
<p>We have attached the documentation at the end of this article. Given the discrepancy between how much it&#8217;s announcing today, and how much it&#8217;s filed to raise, we have asked to see if the round is still open.</p>
<p>The analysts&#8217; report appears to confirm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/discord-is-close-to-closing-a-round-that-would-value-the-company-at-up-to-7b/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">our own reporting</a> from some weeks ago. At the end of November, sources had confirmed to us that the company was raising at a valuation of up to $7 billion.</p>
<p>We also are trying to confirm if that is indeed the valuation with this round.</p>
<p>This latest fundraising had been rumored for a while, and some have described it as a &#8220;<a href="https://twitter.com/genuinfo/status/1328856563205828608?s=20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pre-IPO round</a>&#8221; for the privately-backed startup. Prime Unicorn notes that Discord&#8217;s most recent price per share in the documentation is $280.2487, with the Series G priced at $144.1809.</p>
<p>Previous investors in the company have included Greylock, IVP, Spark Capital, Tencent and Benchmark, among others. With an extra $140 million, the total amount raised by the startup would stand at $420 million.</p>
<p>The fundraise, and the size of it, is a testament not just to how virtual communications tools continue to be an important part of our lives these days; but to the growth of Discord itself.</p>
<p>Discord made its name originally as a communications channel that could exist in an easy way alongside popular online games &#8212; a byproduct, perhaps, of how it first came into existence. Discord was started by Jason Citron and Stanislav Vishnevskiy as part of their Hammer &amp; Chisel gaming studio as a way for them and their teams to communicate tactics and other details to each other while playing games (their own games, other people&#8217;s games, all games).</p>
<p>It proceeded to get lots of traction on Twitch and with e-sports players, environments where it might be especially interesting for both players and spectators to have a place to provide running commentary on what is going on.</p>
<p>But just as the biggest games and gameplay has mass-market, even casual, appeal, so can the platforms that gamers use to communicate. Discord&#8217;s growth has exploded in recent years, with m<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">onthly active users doubling to 140 million this year with 800,000 downloads a day. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">That&#8217;s in part down to Discord&#8217;s use alongside newly, virally popular games like </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/10/14/style/among-us.html">Among Us</a>; but also because it&#8217;s being used for more than just games.</p>
<p>The company had already raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/30/discord-now-has-a-3-5b-valuation-and-100m-for-a-sales-pitch-lighter-on-the-gaming/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$100 million on a $3.5 billion valuation</a> earlier this year, and at the time Citron and Vishnevskiy noted that the platform had already outgrown &#8212; or at least made room for much more than &#8212; its gaming roots:</p>
<p data-selectable-paragraph="">“It turns out that, for a lot of you, it wasn’t just about video games anymore,” they<a href="https://blog.discord.com/your-place-to-talk-a7ffa19b901b"> noted</a>, describing Discord as “a place designed to hang out and talk in the comfort of your own communities and friends&#8230; a place to have genuine conversations and spend quality time with people, whether catching up, learning something or sharing ideas.”</p>
<p data-selectable-paragraph="">That growth among &#8220;communities&#8221; hasn&#8217;t been without its teething pains. Discord has had a high profile, ongoing battle with unsavory elements like white supremacism on its platform. The company claims that this is on the wane, and that the platform is also a home for Black Lives Matter organizers, less politicised social media influencers, and more. Some are not so convinced, so perhaps it&#8217;s a problem that not a finished story and will continue to need to be tackled, much as it is on any social platform.</p>
<p data-selectable-paragraph="">“Discord is always on and always present among these groups on the far-right,” Joan Donovan, the lead researcher on media manipulation at the Data &amp; Society Research Institute, told <a href="https://slate.com/technology/2018/10/discord-safe-space-white-supremacists.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Slate</a> some years ago. “It’s the place where they do most of the organizing of doxing and harassment campaigns.”</p>
<p>It&#8217;s interesting that this latest $140 million of funding &#8212; that is if it closes &#8212; is coming so swiftly on the heels of the last round, just six months later. The company and its investors have some clear ambitions to build out not just more, better and efficient  tools for gamers, but for people online at large, and that&#8217;s not cheap.</p>
<p>Some of that is happening already: witness yesterday&#8217;s news of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/discord-will-be-able-to-screen-share-from-ios-and-android-devices-starting-today/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord&#8217;s screen share functionality getting extended finally beyond desktop to iOS and Android</a> (an interesting area, considering <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/twitter-acquires-screen-sharing-social-app-squad/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter&#8217;s recent acquisition of Squad</a>).</p>
<p>“Rather than throwing raw content at you, like Facebook, [Discord] provides a shared experience for you and your friends,&#8221; said Danny Rimer of Index Ventures, which led the $100 million round earlier this year. &#8220;We’ll come to appreciate that Discord does for social conversation what Slack has done for professional conversation.”</p>
<p>Prime Unicorn note that the terms in the Series H include &#8220;a pari passu liquidation preference with all other preferred, and conventional convertible meaning they will not participate with common stock if there are remaining proceeds.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/PrimeUnicornIndex_Discord_COI_12112020.pdf">PrimeUnicornIndex_Discord_COI_12112020</a></p>
<p><em>Updated with confirmation from Discord</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/filing-discord-is-raising-up-to-140m-at-a-valuation-of-up-to-7b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088638</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Poland&#8217;s GeneMe secures €5.2M seed funding for its rapid COVID-19 test</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/polands-geneme-secures-e5-2m-seed-funding-for-its-rapid-covid-19-test/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/polands-geneme-secures-e5-2m-seed-funding-for-its-rapid-covid-19-test/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 18:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biotechnology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Atlantic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yoti]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088703</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[GeneMe, Poland-based biotechnology company with a COVID-19 test, has secured a €5.2 million round of seed funding led by Robin Tombs, co-founder of Yoti and previously of Gamesys, and other angel investors. The startup has developed and patented a universal protein (polymerase) for RT-LAMP testing, which allows the production of highly accurate, rapid, molecular genetic [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://geneme.eu/">GeneMe</a>, Poland-based biotechnology company with a COVID-19 test, has secured a €5.2 million round of seed funding led by <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/robin-tombs">Robin Tombs</a>, co-founder of <a href="https://www.yoti.com/">Yoti</a> and previously of Gamesys, and other angel investors.</p>
<p>The startup has developed and patented a universal protein (polymerase) for RT-LAMP testing, which allows the production of highly accurate, rapid, molecular genetic COVID tests. It has three molecular NAAT COVID-19 tests: FRANKD, SAVD and ICED. FRANKD is CE IVD-approved and FDA EUA-applied, and its solution is already utilized in over twenty countries. FRANKD has been identified, through official research made by the Scottish government, as the most accurate, rapid COVID-19 test on the market. The FRANKD solution has already been used by Heathrow Airport, Virgin Atlantic and TV show &#8220;Britain’s Got Talent.&#8221;</p>
<p>Dawid Nidzworski, CEO of GeneMe said: “We’re interested not only in health issues, but also in genetic predispositions, such as talents, sports abilities, learning problems, or caffeine metabolism. In the future, everyone will be able to conduct genetic analysis at home.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Robin Tombs, co-founder of <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/yoti" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="yoti">Yoti <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> said: “GeneMe’s innovative approach will be highly disruptive over coming years, enabling more regular testing at point of care at much lower cost.”</p>
<p>GeneMe is a spin-out from The Institute of <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/biotechnology-4c46" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="biotechnology-4c46">Biotechnology <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Molecular Medicine (IBMM), an independent biomedical research institution.</p>
<p>Recently, the company announced a partnership with U.S.-based BIOLYPH, the world leader in lyophilization services, to scale up FRANKD and SAVD significantly.</p>
<p>GeneMe’s patented technology simplifies the entire testing procedure compared to standard laboratory-based RT-PCR tests. RT-LAMP tests are more effective, which means results can be trusted. GeneMe’s testing technology can also be assembled at point of care, which makes it possible to integrate highly accurate testing stations at places of work and in locations with high throughput, such as international borders.</p>
<p>The global COVID-19 diagnostics market size is estimated at $84.4 billion in 2020 and is expected to expand at a compound annual growth rate (CAGR) of 3.1% from 2021 to 2027 (Grand View Research).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="o9hgqiKvI4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/opensensors-secures-4m-for-air-monitoring-platform-which-allows-offices-to-be-more-covid-safe/">OpenSensors secures $4M for air-monitoring platform which allows offices to be more COVID-safe</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;OpenSensors secures $4M for air-monitoring platform which allows offices to be more COVID-safe&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/opensensors-secures-4m-for-air-monitoring-platform-which-allows-offices-to-be-more-covid-safe/embed/#?secret=o9hgqiKvI4" data-secret="o9hgqiKvI4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/polands-geneme-secures-e5-2m-seed-funding-for-its-rapid-covid-19-test/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088703</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter launches its voice-based &#8216;Spaces&#8217; social networking feature into beta testing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/twitter-launches-its-voice-based-spaces-social-networking-feature-into-beta-testing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/twitter-launches-its-voice-based-spaces-social-networking-feature-into-beta-testing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 18:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2088696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last month, Twitter announced it would soon begin testing a new social experience on its platforms involving audio-only chat rooms, similar to the sometimes controversial startup Clubhouse. Today, Twitter Spaces, as the product is now being called, is launching into private beta testing. During this time, the product will be limited to select individuals, largely [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last month, Twitter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/twitter-rolls-out-stories-aka-fleets-to-all-users-will-also-test-a-clubhouse-rival/">announced</a> it would soon begin testing a new social experience on its platforms involving audio-only chat rooms, similar to the sometimes <a href="https://www.joinclubhouse.com/on-community-moderation">controversial</a> startup Clubhouse. Today, Twitter Spaces, as the product is now being called, is launching into private beta testing. During this time, the product will be limited to select individuals, largely from underrepresented backgrounds, Twitter says.</p>
<p>As the company had explained in November, it would be critical to getting safety right in order for people to feel comfortable in these sorts of spaces. That&#8217;s a difficult challenge to overcome &#8212; particularly for a company like Twitter, which some have argued has overly favored free speech to limit cries of censorship, even when such speech made some afraid to speak up on the platform&#8217;s potential for abuse, bullying and cancel culture.</p>
<p>Though audio-based social networking is still a relatively new concept, in its current iteration of private mobile-social &#8220;spaces,&#8221; it&#8217;s already been proven difficult to moderate.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Clubhouse, though still in invite-only testing phase, has seen several high-profile incidents of moderation failure, including <a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2020/7/8/21316172/clubhouse-content-moderation-taylor-lorenz-harassment-abuse?scrolla=5eb6d68b7fedc32c19ef33b4">the harassment of a New York Times reporter,</a> and another conversation that <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/30/21495419/clubhouse-conversation-antisemitism-content-moderation">delved into anti-Semitism</a>. And it hasn&#8217;t publicly launched.</p>
<p>Twitter&#8217;s test hopes to discover where issues impacting user safety and comfort can be addressed.</p>
<p>The test will run on iOS during the beta, offering the opportunity for users to participate in host-moderated audio conversations between two or more people.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2079726" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2079726" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2079726" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-1.00.14-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="474" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-1.00.14-PM.jpg 1832w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-1.00.14-PM.jpg?resize=150,104 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-1.00.14-PM.jpg?resize=300,209 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-1.00.14-PM.jpg?resize=768,535 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-1.00.14-PM.jpg?resize=680,474 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-1.00.14-PM.jpg?resize=1536,1070 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-30-at-1.00.14-PM.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2079726" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twitter</p></div></p>
<p>There are two ways to create a Space, Twitter says. You can either press and hold the compose button in the lower right corner of the screen, or you can create a Space through the Fleet creation screen by swiping right.</p>
<p>Hosts on Spaces will also be able to invite people to join a Space through DMs, by tweeting links, or by sharing a link elsewhere. As the test rolls out, everyone can see and join Spaces when they&#8217;re invited to do so, but hosts will control who&#8217;s speaking. Soon, hosts will also have more options to control conversations.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">aye we’re live! what up y’all, we&#39;re the team behind Spaces––a small experiment focused on the intimacy of the human voice<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f9f5.png" alt="🧵" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>&mdash; Spaces (@TwitterSpaces) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSpaces/status/1339639767089238019?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 17, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The test additionally adds new reaction emojis — the 100, raised hand, fist, peace sign and wave &#8212; along with reporting and blocking tools, a &#8220;very early version&#8221; of automatic transcriptions, and the ability to share tweets into a Space. Many of these features <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/twitters-audio-spaces-test-includes-transcriptions-speaker-controls-and-reporting-features/">were already spotted last month</a> by eagle-eyed reverse engineer <a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane">Jane Manchun Wong.</a> But today, Twitter is confirming they will be part of the beta test at launch.</p>
<p>The company will also tweet about Spaces from a dedicated Twitter account, <a href="https://twitter.com/twitterspaces">@TwitterSpaces</a>.</p>
<p>Twitter says the beta test will involved around a couple hundred people and will roll out over the course of the coming weeks on iOS.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rk3yWsKWr3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/twitters-audio-spaces-test-includes-transcriptions-speaker-controls-and-reporting-features/">Twitter&#8217;s Audio Spaces test includes transcriptions, speaker controls and reporting features</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter&#8217;s Audio Spaces test includes transcriptions, speaker controls and reporting features&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/twitters-audio-spaces-test-includes-transcriptions-speaker-controls-and-reporting-features/embed/#?secret=rk3yWsKWr3" data-secret="rk3yWsKWr3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/twitter-launches-its-voice-based-spaces-social-networking-feature-into-beta-testing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2088696</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
