<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 18:08:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>TC Sessions: Space 2021 offers unmatched visibility for space startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/tc-sessions-space-2021-offers-unmatched-visibility-for-space-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/tc-sessions-space-2021-offers-unmatched-visibility-for-space-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marquise Foster]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 18:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions Space 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212631</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you’re building a startup to the stars, you’ll find an un-earthly amount of opportunity waiting for you at TC Sessions: Space 2021 on December 14-15. This virtual two-day conference focuses on all aspects of a sector — both public and private — that’s thrilling, complex and expanding at an incredible pace. You won’t find [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If you’re building a startup to the stars, you’ll find an un-earthly amount of opportunity waiting for you at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021">TC Sessions: Space 2021</a> on December 14-15. This virtual two-day conference focuses on all aspects of a sector — both public and private — that’s thrilling, complex and expanding at an incredible pace.</p>
<p>You won’t find a better or more targeted platform to showcase your space technology. Global in its reach, TC Sessions: Space 2021 is expected to increase attendance by 30 percent over last year’s inaugural event. We’re talking the top CEOs, founders, scientists, engineers and investors determined to expand humanity’s reach into and far beyond our orbit.</p>
<p>Only a very limited number of space startups will be allowed to exhibit this year, which means you’ll receive more access to investors, aerospace primes and government entities that can cut through mountains of red tape.</p>
<p><strong>Don’t space out:</strong> We still have two months before this event launches, but we have only 12 exhibitor spots left. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?promo=launchpost#tickets">Buy a Space Startup Exhibitor Package</a> ($345) and get your space startup in front of the industry’s leading movers, shakers and unicorn makers. That’s right, forget <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0sIT0u7akdc">pigs in space</a> — we’re talking unicorns.</p>
<p>Bring your team and get busy connecting with opportunities; the exhibitor package includes full event access for four people, virtual booth space, lead generation capabilities, breakout sessions, networking and video on demand.</p>
<p>Exhibitors will also take part in a pitch feedback session with TC staff, and we’re holding a Startup Crawl over both days. Not familiar with the crawl? TC editors will choose select exhibitors and interview them live from the main stage. Lots of exposure, lots of opportunities.</p>
<p>There’s a lot more to space than blasting billionaires into it and, when you’re not networking, you’ll hear major players on the TC Sessions stage talking about commercial launches, constellations of data-gathering satellites and human space flight missions. You’ll also hear from space-happy VCs like Tess Hatch, a partner at Bessemer Venture Partners.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>She knows her stuff when it comes to frontier tech — from space commercialization, drones and autonomous vehicles to the future of agriculture and food technology. You don’t want to miss her insights.</p>
<p>We’re accepting speaker applications until October 15, so if you’d like to toss your space helmet into the ring or have a recommendation, <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/KUFW2e?typeform-source=techcrunch.com">fill out this submission form</a>. We’ll notify applicants by October 31.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021">TC Sessions: Space 2021</a> takes place on December 14-15, and it’s a huge opportunity for space startups to receive invaluable visibility in front of a highly targeted audience. Don’t wait — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?promo=launchpost#tickets">buy a Space Startup Exhibitor Package</a> and make it your mission to accelerate your startup into hyperspace.</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at TC Sessions: Space 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p><!-- Embed not found --></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/tc-sessions-space-2021-offers-unmatched-visibility-for-space-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212631</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why generic marketing approaches don&#8217;t work on software developers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/why-generic-marketing-approaches-dont-work-on-software-developers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/why-generic-marketing-approaches-dont-work-on-software-developers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 17:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer relations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Experts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212513</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Developer marketer Adam DuVander explains why education should be the focus for companies that market directly to developers. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">&#8220;Most of the technical content published misses the mark with developers. I think we can all do a better job,&#8221; author and developer marketing expert <a href="https://www.adamd.org/">Adam DuVander</a> says.</p>
<p>That was the very realization that led DuVander to share what he had learned about marketing to developers in two ways: He recently launched a book, <a href="https://everydeveloper.com/developer-marketing/book/">&#8220;Developer Marketing Does Not Exist,&#8221;</a> and also works through his consultancy, <a href="https://everydeveloper.com/">EveryDeveloper</a>, which helps its clients, including Algolia, HelloSign and Stoplight, with technical content strategy and production.</p>
<p>DuVander was recommended to us by Karl Hughes, the CEO of Draft.dev, which specializes in content production for developer-focused companies. When we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/draft-dev-ceo-karl-hughes-on-the-importance-of-using-experts-in-developer-marketing/">interviewed him last July</a>, Hughes explained that he would refer leads to EveryDeveloper when they needed to sort out their content strategy.</p>
<p>Hughes was therefore happy to recommend DuVander via our experts survey. (You can share your own recommendations <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">here</a>!) &#8220;Adam draws from deep experience as a developer and developer advocate to make sure his clients set a winning strategy in motion,&#8221; he wrote.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This made us curious, so we got ourselves a copy of DuVander&#8217;s book and reached out to him for additional insights. The main takeaway? If you are reaching out to developers, you&#8217;ll absolutely want to avoid coming across as too promotional or too generic.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s more:</p>
<p><em>Editor&#8217;s note: This interview has been edited lightly for length and clarity.</em></p>
<p><b>Why did you write a book titled “Developer Marketing Does Not Exist”?</b></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2212518" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2212518" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-2212518" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/adamd-sign-500x500-1.jpg?w=300" alt="Adam DuVander" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/adamd-sign-500x500-1.jpg 500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/adamd-sign-500x500-1.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/adamd-sign-500x500-1.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/adamd-sign-500x500-1.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/adamd-sign-500x500-1.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/adamd-sign-500x500-1.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/adamd-sign-500x500-1.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/adamd-sign-500x500-1.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2212518" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Adam DuVander</p></div></p>
<p>Developer marketers certainly exist, because I work with them every day. The book title is a call to these marketers to treat their technical audience differently. To reach more developers requires more education and less promotion. Your “marketing” should not feel like marketing.</p>
<p>The idea for this book dates back to my time at <a href="https://www.programmableweb.com/">ProgrammableWeb</a> (2009-2014). Every press release looked the same. A company has a new API, but they haven’t bothered to explain why developers should care.</p>
<p>After ProgrammableWeb, I spent five years on the provider side in developer marketing roles. The book is a compilation of the philosophy I learned and created along the way. I hope the book helps anyone who wants to reach developers directly in an authentic way.</p>
<p><b>You mentioned reaching &#8220;the right developers.&#8221; What does that mean?</b></p>
<p>Every developer (the origin of our name) has a few basic needs, like clear documentation, help getting started and use cases to spark creativity.</p>
<p>The educational and inspirational content you use to attract developers will depend on who is the best fit for your product. If you provide a mobile SDK, the right developer is building iOS and Android apps. If your customers are data engineers, it probably won’t make sense to discuss front-end web technologies.</p>
<p>If the most common developer marketer mistake is being too promotional, the second is being too generic. Be specific with the best developer match for your product.</p>
<p><b>What are some arguments in favor of getting external help for developer marketing?</b></p>
<p>It’s tough for companies to see their own products the way someone outside that company does. Also, they may not have the development background within their marketing team to fully understand the audience.</p>
<p>In addition, hiring a full-time, experienced developer marketer can be difficult and expensive. An outside partner can provide better results, often for less than a full-time salary.</p>
<p><b>And what should startups keep in mind when picking these partners?</b></p>
<p>Look for that magical combination of technical skill and communications. The &#8220;education, not promotion&#8221; ethos should be obvious in the work they do.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Have you worked with a talented individual or agency who helped you find and keep more users?</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03"><i>Respond to our survey</i></a><i> and help other startups find top growth marketers they can work with!</i></em></p>
<hr />
<p><b>This brings us to EveryDeveloper — can you tell us more about it?</b></p>
<p>EveryDeveloper helps attract the right developers to our clients’ technical products. Our content strategy plans remove the guesswork and enable companies to produce content developers want to read.</p>
<p>There are about a dozen of us, split between content strategy and production. Most of the team can write code but prefer to write words about code.</p>
<p>Once we have jointly created a developer content strategy with a client, we’ll typically deliver two to four pieces a month.</p>
<p><b>What type of clients are best suited for the help you provide?</b></p>
<p>Anyone can benefit from fresh eyes on their developer experience and an objective plan to attract developers.</p>
<p>Those with a full staff of developer advocates or experienced developer marketers are best set up to execute on the plan we deliver. We sometimes work with unlaunched products, but usually there’s some initial success they are looking to amplify and improve. We also advise clients on how to build internal expertise.</p>
<p>All in all, we’ve helped companies from seed stage to Fortune 50 create better developer content strategies. The difference is whether it’s a product or an entire company that needs to reach more developers.</p>
<p><b>Do you have some recommendations for content and activities that you encourage companies to come up with?</b></p>
<p>EveryDeveloper focuses on content, which I believe is the most scalable way to reach developers. Blog articles are certainly core, but you want to make sure you’re covering the right topics in the right way. Don’t just publish to check a box. Make sure what you write has a strategic purpose and is something a developer wants to read. I think most developer-focused companies publishing multiple times per week would be better off with fewer, deeper pieces.</p>
<p>Other types of content include deep subject matter guides that barely mention the product (see the <a href="https://www.heavybit.com/library/blog/the-developer-content-mind-trick-for-signature-content/">Developer Content Mind Trick</a>) and all sorts of documentation.</p>
<p>Outside content, there’s events (in-person and virtual), advertising, sponsorships, open source and tools. I cover all of these in the book and the philosophy is the same: You’re more likely to attract developers when you aim to educate and inspire first.</p>
<p><b>What are some good targets for developer-oriented startups to sponsor? What should they keep in mind when it comes to sponsorship?</b></p>
<p>You want to use the same &#8220;education over promotion&#8221; philosophy even when you’re paying for the message. Developers are always skeptical, but especially with advertising.</p>
<p>Look for where your developers are already learning and getting their development news. If your sponsorship can feel as naturally helpful as other content from that source, you’ll be doing well.</p>
<p>I encourage developer marketers to think broadly about the sites, podcasts, events and tools they sponsor. Your best partner may not do any sponsorship yet.</p>
<p><b>In your book, you mention Netlify as an example others might want to follow when it comes to using tools as developer marketing. Could you sum that up? And why are acquisitions a good option in this context?</b></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2212519" style="width: 205px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2212519" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2212519 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/developer-marketing-does-not-exist-cover.png?w=195" alt="Book cover - Developer Marketing Does Not Exist - Adam DuVander" width="195" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/developer-marketing-does-not-exist-cover.png 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/developer-marketing-does-not-exist-cover.png?resize=97,150 97w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/developer-marketing-does-not-exist-cover.png?resize=195,300 195w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/developer-marketing-does-not-exist-cover.png?resize=768,1183 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/developer-marketing-does-not-exist-cover.png?resize=442,680 442w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/developer-marketing-does-not-exist-cover.png?resize=32,50 32w" sizes="(max-width: 195px) 100vw, 195px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2212519" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Adam DuVander</p></div></p>
<p>There are dozens of technology choices for content management and static site generation. That leads to hundreds of potential combinations and can be overwhelming for a developer that wants to build something new. Netlify recognized that problem and built filtered galleries to help developers choose the right tools.</p>
<p>It goes to show that developer-focused companies can recognize a problem their audience wants solved and build a tool to address it.</p>
<p>Better yet, look for existing tools that already have traction. Sponsor or even acquire them. I write about &#8220;the Runscope playbook&#8221; in the book, because they executed this strategy fabulously.</p>
<p><b>Do you have any final piece of advice to share with developer-focused companies?</b></p>
<p>Developer experience is foundational for developer-focused companies. They should continually look to improve the experience — both initial and ongoing. It takes a lot of effort and resources to reach the right developers, and too many companies send them directly into a poor experience.</p>
<p>You want to make it clear you have a product for developers, show what’s possible and get them started quickly.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/why-generic-marketing-approaches-dont-work-on-software-developers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212513</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>RoboTire raises $7.5M to automate tire replacement</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/robotire-raises-7-5m-to-automate-tire-replacement/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/robotire-raises-7-5m-to-automate-tire-replacement/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 17:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Reinalt-Thomas Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2214639</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[RoboTire crossed our radar in February of last year, just before much of the world was brought to a complete standstill courtesy of the pandemic. Things were still fairly early stages for the Detroit-based startup, which was founded by former Spark Robotics CEO Victor Darolfi. The company has clearly picked up some good, strategic interest [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">RoboTire <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/24/your-next-tire-change-could-be-performed-by-a-robot/">crossed our radar in February of last year</a>, just before much of the world was brought to a complete standstill courtesy of the pandemic. Things were still fairly early stages for the Detroit-based startup, which was founded by former Spark Robotics CEO Victor Darolfi.</p>
<p>The company has clearly picked up some good, strategic interest in the intervening year and a half, as more and more industries are looking to embrace the benefits of automation. Today it announced that it has raised a $7.5 million Series A round, led by The Reinalt-Thomas Corporation, the major tire retail brand behind Discount Tire and America’s Tire. The latter, funnily enough, got a bit of a mixed shout-out when we spoke to Darolfi last year.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2214611" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2214611" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2214611" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RoboTire-Image-2.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RoboTire-Image-2.jpeg 4032w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RoboTire-Image-2.jpeg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RoboTire-Image-2.jpeg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RoboTire-Image-2.jpeg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RoboTire-Image-2.jpeg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RoboTire-Image-2.jpeg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RoboTire-Image-2.jpeg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/RoboTire-Image-2.jpeg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2214611" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> RoboTire</p></div></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2214611" alt="" /></p>
<p>“I sat at America’s Tires for three hours and thought, hey, we use robots to put tires on at the factory,” he told us. “Why don’t we bring robots into the service industry?” Clearly Reinalt-Thomas was listening. The company was joined by Automotive Ventures, Detroit Venture Partners and 640 Oxford Ventures in the round. RoboTire says the funding will go toward expanding its operations in Detroit.</p>
<p>The underlying technology is capable of changing a set of tires in less than 15 minutes, by the company’s count. From the sound of things, Discount Tire will be among the first to adopt the automated tech.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>We&#8217;re launching a robotics newsletter! Please sign up <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">to get Actuator in your inbox</a> as soon as the first issue hits! For free!</em></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<hr />
<p>“Discount Tire is excited to support RoboTire in the development of new and innovative technologies that drive a better customer experience,” Discount Tire Chief Experience Officer Tom Williams said in a release. “As customer expectations around the ‘buy and book online’ experience and our ability to deliver reduced wait times continue to grow, we will continue to pursue automation and enhancements that ensure an inviting, easy and safe experience for all our customers.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/robotire-raises-7-5m-to-automate-tire-replacement/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2214639</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>It&#8217;s time to end the war at home for troops with traumatic brain injuries</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/its-time-to-end-the-war-at-home-for-troops-with-traumatic-brain-injuries/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/its-time-to-end-the-war-at-home-for-troops-with-traumatic-brain-injuries/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 17:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brain training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concussion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[department of defense]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neuroscience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2214032</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We need a concerted effort from the Department of Defense and the Veterans Affairs Administration to move proven science out of the lab and into the world to help people in need.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Henry Mahncke</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/socialprimate">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Henry Mahncke has a Ph.D. in neuroscience from UCSF and is the CEO of Posit Science, developers of the <a href="https://www.brainhq.com/">BrainHQ</a> brain training program.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The war is over now. Our troops have come home, many after years of service across multiple tours of duty. And as they return, their next phase of service begins — to their families, where they are parents to children and caregivers to parents, and to their communities, where they will return to school or launch new careers.</p>
<p>But for far too many, the battle continues. Traumatic brain injuries (TBIs) — considered to be the signature injury of the Iraq and Afghanistan wars — were sustained by more than <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/traumaticbraininjury/military/index.html">430,000 U.S. service members</a>. The most common type of TBI is the somewhat misleadingly named “mild” TBI (mTBI, or concussion), <a href="https://www.brainline.org/article/how-many-service-members-have-sustained-tbi">affecting more than 82% of service members diagnosed with TBIs</a>.</p>
<p>Many were able to recover from those injuries, but thousands are plagued by persistent cognitive issues affecting speed, attention and memory — years after their injury — that make it challenging to return to work, school and family roles. People with a history of TBI are also at higher risk for complications from other conditions, notably pre-dementia and dementia.</p>
<p>That’s a burden on those service members and their families &#8212; and it’s also a burden on our nation because the talents and experience of these citizens aren’t being used to their fullest potential.</p>
<p>The Department of Defense recognized this problem more than 10 years ago and called for academic and industry researchers to find new kinds of treatments for this new kind of war injury. A number of research groups answered the call. At Posit Science, where I am a scientist and the CEO, we responded with a team including leading clinicians from military hospitals and VA medical centers from around the country with a proposal to put a new kind of computerized brain training to the test.</p>
<p>We recognized we had to solve two problems to help service members with TBI.</p>
<p>First, the brain training program needed to work. Fortunately, we built a brain training program, <a href="http://www.brainhq.com/">BrainHQ</a>, shown to improve cognitive function in older adults through multiple studies funded by the National Institutes of Health — we just needed to adapt it for use by younger service members. The brain training exercises in BrainHQ work differently than traditional cognitive training because they are designed to improve the fundamentals of information processing in the brain using brain plasticity — the ability of the brain to rewire itself through learning and experience.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Second, the brain training program needed to reach people where they were. Many active duty service members and veterans don’t have the ability to come into a clinic several times a week for several months for in-person treatments — they’re about to be deployed, or they’re going back to school or work, or they’re located in areas outside of big cities with top clinics. Computerized brain training can be helpful here: Because it’s delivered over the internet, it can reach people in their own homes on their own schedules — wherever they are and whenever they have time.</p>
<p>In the <a href="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/144/7/1994/6328669">BRAVE Study, which was published this summer in the journal Brain</a>, five U.S. military and veterans hospitals enrolled 83 patients diagnosed with a history of cognitive impairment and mTBI in a double-blind randomized controlled trial. The average participant in the study had experienced persistent cognitive issues for more than seven years before this intervention.</p>
<p>The BRAVE study pitted the intervention of BrainHQ plasticity-based exercises against attention-demanding video games, used as an active control. The researchers found significant improvements in overall cognition among those who used BrainHQ compared to the video game control. While the intervention did not make each patient a genius, it did result in an average gain equal to about 24 percentile points (like moving from the 50<sup>th</sup> to the 74<sup>th</sup> percentile). This was the first scalable intervention of any kind to achieve a significant gain in a gold standard study of mTBI.</p>
<p>Those results were confirmed and extended in<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34420987/"> a second study from NYU, which was recently published in the journal NeuroRehabilitation</a>. That study was of 48 civilians with a mix of mild, moderate and severe TBIs. These researchers found a significant gain in an objective measure of overall cognition in patients using BrainHQ. They also used a self-rated assessment of cognitive function, which showed that the patients noticed a significant improvement in their own cognitive health.</p>
<p>We weren’t the only ones to show success. Several other academic and military research groups using cognitive compensation techniques delivered in person by a trained clinician (notably <a href="https://brainhealth.utdallas.edu/programs/smart-curriculum/">SMART</a> training, developed at the Center for Brain Health at UT Dallas, and <a href="http://www.cogsmart.com/">CogSMART</a> training, developed at UCSD and the VA San Diego Healthcare System, showed good results.</p>
<p>But right now, much of this science is sitting on the shelf. Congress and the Department of Defense have spent hundreds of millions of dollars on basic science and clinical trials for TBI — but when I visit military hospitals and VA medical centers, I find dedicated health care providers who are committed to helping people but lacking the staff, space, technology or other resources to put the results of research into practice. We need a concerted effort from the Department of Defense and the Veterans Affairs Administration to move this proven science out of the lab and into the world to help people in need.</p>
<p>As the wars abroad end, we cannot forget our obligation to ensure that our nation&#8217;s warriors benefit from the research that’s been done on their behalf. We need to unleash the discoveries of that research so that they — and our entire nation — can benefit from everything they have to offer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/its-time-to-end-the-war-at-home-for-troops-with-traumatic-brain-injuries/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2214032</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcome debuts a smarter city guide app on iOS, backed by $3.5M led by Accel</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/welcome-debuts-a-smarter-city-guide-app-on-ios-backed-by-3-5m-led-by-accel/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/welcome-debuts-a-smarter-city-guide-app-on-ios-backed-by-3-5m-led-by-accel/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 16:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[city guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lonely Planet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[matthew rosenberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parsing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persoanlization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recommendations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel guides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tripadvisor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vimeo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2214102</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When you&#8217;re exploring a city &#8212; whether one you&#8217;re visiting on your travels or your own &#8212; there are a number of tools that can help you find out where to go, what to see, and what to do, like Google Maps, Yelp, TripAdvisor and others. But a startup called Welcome thinks that today&#8217;s set [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When you&#8217;re exploring a city &#8212; whether one you&#8217;re visiting on your travels or your own &#8212; there are a number of tools that can help you find out where to go, what to see, and what to do, like Google Maps, Yelp, TripAdvisor and others. But a startup called <a href="https://welco.me/">Welcome</a> thinks that today&#8217;s set of tools could be smarter and more personalized to the individuals who use them. Its new app instead uses &#8220;real-time&#8221; technologies to make recommendations that take into account a user&#8217;s preferences as well as other details about their current context &#8212; like the weather, season, traffic, and the popularity of the place at the current time of day &#8212; in order to provide a better-curated set of recommendations.</p>
<p>The end result is meant to be a city guide that&#8217;s more like &#8220;a concierge in your pocket,&#8221; says Welcome co-founder Matthew Rosenberg.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2214225" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2214225" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2214225" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Artwork-2.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="415" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Artwork-2.png 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Artwork-2.png?resize=150,91 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Artwork-2.png?resize=300,183 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Artwork-2.png?resize=768,468 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Artwork-2.png?resize=680,415 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Artwork-2.png?resize=1536,937 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Artwork-2.png?resize=2048,1249 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Artwork-2.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2214225" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Welcome</p></div></p>
<p>Rosenberg says he was inspired to build Welcome after traveling, pre-pandemic, with his then-girlfriend, now-wife following the acquisition of his first company, a mobile video creation app called <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/06/17/cameo-vimeos-video-editing-platform-ditches-social-networking-functionality/">Cameo</a>,<a href="https://venturebeat.com/2014/03/18/vimeo-buys-cameo/"> by Vimeo</a>. During this time, the couple explored parts of Europe, Latin America, and the U.S., which was an amazing experience he says, and one that ultimately brought them closer together, as it turned out.</p>
<p>&#8220;But something I found myself doing in in those moments &#8212; we&#8217;re in all these beautiful places&#8230;we&#8217;re in an incredible museum or at a wonderful lunch &#8212; and I found myself hunched over my phone, trying to figure out where to go next,&#8221; Rosenberg explains. He was sifting through Google Maps, recommendations from friends, and trying to read reviews to make a decision about what was next on their journey.</p>
<p>This led him to wonder: &#8220;why isn&#8217;t there a tool that like can be smart and go beyond just place [recommendations] &#8212; that can really look at what&#8217;s going on in my life and in the world around me, and make smarter recommendations?&#8221; he recalls.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2214220" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2214220" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2214220" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-2.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="415" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-2.png 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-2.png?resize=150,91 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-2.png?resize=300,183 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-2.png?resize=768,468 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-2.png?resize=680,415 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-2.png?resize=1536,937 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-2.png?resize=2048,1249 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-2.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2214220" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Welcome</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This led to the development of what&#8217;s now become <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/welcome-smart-travel-companion/id1447252527">Wonder</a>, a city guide app that combines intelligence, recommendations, personalization, and even media, like photos and videos, to help users find things to do.</p>
<p>The startup is co-founded by fellow Vimeo employees Peter Gerard, Mark Armendariz, and Mark Essel, who together with Rosenberg launched an early version of Welcome back in 2019 as something of a market test. Their idea landed them some seed money from Accel, which gave them enough runway to build the version of the app they had in mind.</p>
<p>That version has <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/welcome-smart-travel-companion/id1447252527">now arrived on the App Store</a>.</p>
<p>Upon first launch, you&#8217;ll give Welcome some input about your interests and you&#8217;ll have the option to pick from a series of publishers to follow &#8212; like Condé Nast, Lonely Planet, Eater, Culture Trip, Food &amp; Wine, and others &#8212; whose content is used to help inform Welcome&#8217;s recommendations.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2214222" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2214222" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2214222" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-3.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="415" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-3.png 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-3.png?resize=150,91 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-3.png?resize=300,183 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-3.png?resize=768,468 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-3.png?resize=680,415 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-3.png?resize=1536,937 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-3.png?resize=2048,1249 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Welcome-Screenshots-3.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2214222" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Welcome</p></div></p>
<p>You can then scroll through the app&#8217;s home feed to see relevant articles for the city you&#8217;re currently researching or browse the map, where suggestions are marked with icons related to the place &#8212; like a cheeseburger for a restaurant, martini glass for a bar, tree for an outdoor place (like a farmers market), and so on.</p>
<p>As you tap into each place, you&#8217;ll be presented with photos and videos, and links to get directions, the website, the phone number, as well as a button to order an Uber or Lyft, and more. You can also leave your own tips for fellow Welcome users, mark the list as a favorite, and add tags.</p>
<p>As you browse the map, buttons at the top let you filter to see only a subset of places, like food, drinks, activities, arts, and more.</p>
<p>The app itself is well-designed in terms of the look of its user interface, but it&#8217;s perhaps not as simple to use as an app that&#8217;s more heavily focused on collecting user-generated content &#8212; like business ratings and reviews.</p>
<p>It was not immediately obvious, for example, how you could contribute your own photos and videos to a place, as some listings offered a prominently placed &#8220;Add&#8221; button for uploading your media, while it seemed others did not. In reality, the &#8220;Add&#8221; button wasn&#8217;t missing &#8212; you just had to scroll over to the right to see it. But it wasn&#8217;t clear that the row was scrollable. It looked like the Add button simply wasn&#8217;t there. (See below examples.)</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2214239" style="width: 519px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2214239" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2214239" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/row-in-welcome.jpeg?w=680" alt="" width="509" height="358" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/row-in-welcome.jpeg 1256w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/row-in-welcome.jpeg?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/row-in-welcome.jpeg?resize=300,211 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/row-in-welcome.jpeg?resize=768,540 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/row-in-welcome.jpeg?resize=680,478 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/row-in-welcome.jpeg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 509px) 100vw, 509px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2214239" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> screenshots from Welcome</p></div></p>
<p>Still, Welcome&#8217;s underlying data and parsing engines are interesting. The team developed custom tools that pick up keywords in the articles from publishers and turn them into tags. Eventually, it wants to expand this technology to any site &#8212; like local blogs, for instance &#8212; which users could click and save, perhaps via a web browser extension. The team is even thinking about offering a way to ingest the travel lists and tips people collect in less obvious places &#8212; like spreadsheets, notes, and emails.</p>
<p>In time, Welcome would also like to better integrate suggestions and guides from travel content creators to enhance its recommendations further. This could also later aid its business model, where premium travel guides from specific creators or publishers could be made available for a fee. The company also plans to add more ways to transact in-app, like booking tickets or other activities where a revenue share would be involved.</p>
<p>Before its public debut, Welcome grew to over 50,000 beta users across more than 350 cities worldwide and now has over 6.5 million places its database. It&#8217;s offering over 300,000 curated recommendations globally, at launch.</p>
<p>The startup is backed by a $3.5 million seed round led by Accel, with Lakestar Ventures participating. The round closed in 2020 but hadn&#8217;t yet been announced. Including pre-seed funding, Welcome has raised $4.2 million to date.</p>
<p>Welcome&#8217;s app, for the time being, is available <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/welcome-smart-travel-companion/id1447252527">on iOS only</a> as a free download.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/welcome-debuts-a-smarter-city-guide-app-on-ios-backed-by-3-5m-led-by-accel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2214102</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DOJ will sue federal contractors that hide cyberattacks and breaches</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/doj-will-sue-federal-contractors-that-hide-cyberattacks-and-breaches/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/doj-will-sue-federal-contractors-that-hide-cyberattacks-and-breaches/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 16:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberattack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyberwarfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monaco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SolarWinds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2214082</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Department of Justice has said it will launch civil legal action against federal contractors if they fail to report cyberattacks or data breaches. The Civil Cyber-Fraud Initiative, introduced by Deputy Attorney General Lisa O. Monaco this week, will leverage the existing False Claims Act (FCA) to “pursue cybersecurity-related fraud by government contractors and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The U.S. Department of Justice has said it will launch civil legal action against federal contractors if they fail to report cyberattacks or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/data-breach/">data breaches</a>.</p>
<p>The Civil Cyber-Fraud Initiative, introduced by Deputy Attorney General Lisa O. Monaco this week, will leverage the existing False Claims Act (FCA) to “pursue cybersecurity-related fraud by government contractors and grant recipients.”</p>
<p>The initiative will hold entities, such as federal contractors or individuals, accountable when they put U.S. cyber infrastructure at risk by knowingly providing flawed cybersecurity products or services, <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/deputy-attorney-general-lisa-o-monaco-announces-new-civil-cyber-fraud-initiative">according to a DOJ press release</a>. Similarly, government contractors now also face penalties for &#8220;violating obligations&#8221; to monitor and report cybersecurity incidents and breaches.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the latest response by the Biden administration following <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/solarwinds-hackers-targeted-nasa-federal-aviation-administration-networks/">a spate of hacks</a> targeting federal agencies, including the Treasury, the State Department, and Homeland Security. The DOJ later <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/fbi-nsa-says-hacks-on-us-federal-agencies-likely-russian-in-origin/">blamed</a> hackers working for Russia&#8217;s foreign intelligence service, the SVR, for the espionage campaign. The Russian hackers broke into SolarWinds’ network and planted a backdoor in its Orion software, which helps companies monitor their networks and fleets of devices, and pushed it directly to customer networks with a tainted software update.</p>
<p>The initiative will help it build “broad resiliency” against <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/cybersecurity/">cybersecurity</a> intrusions across the public sector and will help government efforts to identify, create and publicize patches for vulnerabilities in commonly-used products and services, according to the DOJ. It will also help the government and to reclaim losses from the companies if found to have failed to meet the government&#8217;s security standards.</p>
<p>“For too long, companies have chosen silence under the mistaken belief that it is less risky to hide a breach than to bring it forward and to report it,” said Monaco. “Well that changes today. We are announcing today that we will use our civil enforcement tools to pursue companies, those who are government contractors who receive federal funds, when they fail to follow required cybersecurity standards — because we know that puts all of us at risk. This is a tool that we have to ensure that taxpayer dollars are used appropriately and guard the public fisc and public trust.”</p>
<p>The timing of the unveiling of the initiative coincides with the creation of a National Cryptocurrency Enforcement Team, which has been set up to tackle complex investigations and criminal cases of cryptocurrency misuse.</p>
<p>Also this week Sen. Elizabeth Warren and Rep. Deborah Ross <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/a-new-us-bill-would-force-companies-to-disclose-ransomware-payments/">proposed a new bicameral bill, the Ransom Disclosure Act</a>, which would require ransomware victims to disclose details of any ransom amount paid within 48 hours.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pzitqxEFYX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/fireeye-breach-solarwinds-federal-agencies/">Just how bad is that hack that hit US government agencies?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Just how bad is that hack that hit US government agencies?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/fireeye-breach-solarwinds-federal-agencies/embed/#?secret=pzitqxEFYX" data-secret="pzitqxEFYX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/doj-will-sue-federal-contractors-that-hide-cyberattacks-and-breaches/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2214082</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8216;Fantasy startup investing&#8217; NFT platform Visionrare shuts down paid marketplace after a day in open beta</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/fantasy-startup-investing-nft-platform-visionrare-shuts-down-paid-marketplace-after-a-day-in-open-beta/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/fantasy-startup-investing-nft-platform-visionrare-shuts-down-paid-marketplace-after-a-day-in-open-beta/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 15:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business incubators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visionrare]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2214093</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just over 24 hours into its open beta, Visionrare, which launched an NFT marketplace for &#8220;fantasy startup investing,&#8221; is temporarily shutting down and refunding users who purchased shares, saying it will relaunch soon as a free-to-play game. The platform allowed users to bid on auctions of fake NFT shares of real startups, building up a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Just over 24 hours into its open beta, <a href="https://app.visionrare.com/dealflow">Visionrare</a>, which launched an NFT marketplace for &#8220;fantasy startup investing,&#8221; is temporarily shutting down and refunding users who purchased shares, saying it will relaunch soon as a free-to-play game.</p>
<p>The platform allowed users to bid on auctions of fake NFT shares of real startups, building up a quasi-portfolio that they could compete in a fantasy sports-styled league around who could build the most &#8220;profitable&#8221; portfolio. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/fantasy-equity-nft-game-wants-you-to-spend-real-money-buying-fake-shares-of-real-startups/">As we noted in our coverage of the startup&#8217;s launch yesterday</a>, they didn&#8217;t have the permission of most of the startups that they were selling synthetic shares in.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Well that might be the quickest pivot for a startup I&#39;ve written about, &quot;&#8230;we underestimated the legal complexities&#8230;&quot; <a href="https://t.co/amTyQTBX6k">https://t.co/amTyQTBX6k</a> <a href="https://t.co/yhP1Xd0h2D">https://t.co/yhP1Xd0h2D</a> <a href="https://t.co/C3mMUS8jEs">pic.twitter.com/C3mMUS8jEs</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Lucas Matney (@lucasmtny) <a href="https://twitter.com/lucasmtny/status/1446121592904294406?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 7, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>In a <a href="https://app.visionrare.com/dealflow">note</a> posted to the company&#8217;s auction marketplace this morning, the founders noted that they had &#8220;underestimated the legal complexities&#8221; with selling novelty NFT shares in real startups and were temporarily shutting down the marketplace and refunding users as they planned out a pivot. In a message on the company&#8217;s public Discord channel, the team noted it had already processed all of the credit card refunds to buyers, though some refunds may still be pending due to Stripe processing.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The platform and its founders had received some substantial pushback after Visionrare&#8217;s launch yesterday, with various tech entrepreneurs and investors questioning whether the platform was legal, whether it was a security, whether the NFT platform was taunting the SEC and/or whether this was finally the sign of the market&#8217;s &#8220;top&#8221;.</span></p>
<p>Visionrare&#8217;s founders say they aren&#8217;t done with the idea of &#8220;fantasy startup investing&#8221; quite yet, but that they are going to have to rethink how the platform is fundamentally structured.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">In the coming days, we will re-launch Visionrare as a completely free-to-play game. All players start with a fixed amount of credits that they can use to build their startup portfolio, and they can compete in leagues based on how well their portfolios perform in the real world. Down the line, we&#8217;ll figure out if and how we can add a financial element again,&#8221; the founders&#8217; blog post reads.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Okay so remember when I said NFTs aren’t securities? These NFTs MAY end up being securities <a href="https://t.co/wNkpAlH8Er">https://t.co/wNkpAlH8Er</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Bennett Tomlin (@BennettTomlin) <a href="https://twitter.com/BennettTomlin/status/1445921881194782723?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 7, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">So the SEC won’t allow non-accredited investor to buy shares in startups, but they can buy worthless NFT fake shares in them? </p>
<p>Got it!  <a href="https://t.co/O4AP5a6tgE">https://t.co/O4AP5a6tgE</a></p>
<p>&mdash; jason@calacanis.com (@Jason) <a href="https://twitter.com/Jason/status/1445932303675396097?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 7, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/fantasy-startup-investing-nft-platform-visionrare-shuts-down-paid-marketplace-after-a-day-in-open-beta/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2214093</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lyft now lets you pay for your Tinder date&#8217;s ride</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/lyft-now-lets-you-pay-for-your-tinder-dates-ride/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/lyft-now-lets-you-pay-for-your-tinder-dates-ride/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 15:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tinder]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2214178</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Now that in-person dating is making a comeback, Lyft and Tinder want to encourage more face-to-face encounters: Tinder app now includes an Explore hub that lets you buy a Lyft ride for your date.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jon Fingas</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jon Fingas is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/your-iphone-could-eventually-control-your-cars-climate-and-seats/">Your iPhone could eventually control your car&#8217;s climate and seats</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/jeeps-grand-cherokee-plug-in-hybrid-will-arrive-in-early-2022/">Jeep&#8217;s Grand Cherokee plug-in hybrid will arrive in early 2022</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Now that <a href="https://www.engadget.com/dating-apps-perks-covid-19-vaccine-white-house-151019253.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="22" data-v9y="1">in-person dating</a> is making a comeback, Lyft and Tinder want to encourage more of those face-to-face encounters. As teased in March, the Tinder app <a href="https://www.lyft.com/blog/posts/lyft-and-tinder-first-impression" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="23" data-v9y="1">now includes</a> an Explore hub that lets you buy a Lyft ride for your date. You don&#8217;t have to exchange addresses or locations — you just send a credit (with a set destination, if you prefer) and your date does the rest.</p>
<p>The credit is only useful for dropoffs within a half-mile of a set destination, and you&#8217;ll get a refund for any unused credit. You don&#8217;t have to worry that your would-be beau will travel to the other end of town, in other words.</p>
<p>The motivations are fairly obvious here. This gives Lyft drivers more business, and encourages Tinder users to do more than message each other and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tinder-video-profile-update-130041493.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="24" data-v9y="1">watch videos</a>. It might be difficult to complain about a free ride to the restaurant, mind you, and you might just land a relationship in the bargain.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/lyft-tinder-send-a-ride-to-date-150422959.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/lyft-now-lets-you-pay-for-your-tinder-dates-ride/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2214178</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cruise plans to have &#8216;tens of thousands&#8217; of Origin AVs on roads in coming years</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/cruise-plans-to-have-tens-of-thousands-of-origin-avs-on-roads-in-coming-years/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/cruise-plans-to-have-tens-of-thousands-of-origin-avs-on-roads-in-coming-years/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 15:45:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cruise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dan Ammann]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General-Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotaxi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213764</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cruise expects to leap from a limited commercial robotaxi and delivery service that will start in earnest in 2022 to a business of &#8220;tens of thousands&#8221; of its purpose-built Origin AVs on the road over the next few years. The eye-popping projections will be reached, according to CEO Dan Ammann, through a combination of regulatory [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="c-message_kit__gutter">
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter__right" role="presentation" data-qa="message_content">
<div class="c-message_kit__blocks c-message_kit__blocks--rich_text">
<div class="c-message__message_blocks c-message__message_blocks--rich_text">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer" data-qa="block-kit-renderer">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper--first">
<div class="p-rich_text_block" dir="auto">
<p id="speakable-summary">Cruise expects to leap from a limited commercial robotaxi and delivery service that will start in earnest in 2022 to a business of &#8220;tens of thousands&#8221; of its purpose-built Origin AVs on the road over the next few years.</p>
<p>The eye-popping projections will be reached, according to CEO Dan Ammann, through a combination of regulatory approvals, capital from investors and a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/cruise-secures-5b-credit-line-to-buy-electric-autonomous-cruise-origin-vehicles-from-gm/">$5 billion credit line from GM Financial</a> and technological breakthroughs, including a 90% reduction in compute costs over the next four years.</p>
<p>&#8220;Over the next 12 to 24 months, you will be able to push a button and get a ride with a very short ETA in a couple of major cities in the United States,&#8221; said Ammann. &#8220;If you look at the next three to four years, we will be deployed in multiple cities, multiple markets around the U.S.&#8221;</p>
<p>These are seriously bold claims, but the company appears to be laying down some of the groundwork to back them up. Just last week, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/cruise-waymo-get-ok-to-launch-robotaxi-service-in-san-francisco/">Cruise received its driverless deployment permit</a>, which allows the company to begin charging for autonomous services, from the California Department of Motor Vehicles. It just needs one more permit from the California Public Utilities Commission to operate a commercial robotaxi service in San Francisco. Cruise says that reality is only months away.</p>
<p>The $5 billion line of credit from GM Financial, which Cruise secured this summer, will be used to pay for the production of the Origin without having to give away more equity to investors. Separately, GM has invested a total of $6 billion in Cruise, including the initial acquisition cost, operating costs for 2015 to 2016, and further investments, according to the company.</p>
<p>The question is whether all this is enough to help Cruise scale up into the thousands of vehicles at a lower cost per mile than a human driver service over the next half a decade.</p>
</div>
<div class="p-rich_text_block" dir="auto">
<p>Cruise laid out its plan to go from a limited commercial AV service to tens of thousands of vehicles in a short span during GM&#8217;s Investor Event on Wednesday. Let&#8217;s dive into the claims.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>From product-market fit to rapid scaleup</h2>
<p>Ammann broke down Cruise&#8217;s path to market into three phases. The first was the R&amp;D phase, which took the company to the beginning of driverless testing at the end of last year and into this year. Phase two, which will begin next year, will be early commercialization via the retrofitted Chevy Bolt EV-based fleet of Cruise vehicles, which are currently on the roads in San Francisco and Phoenix, Arizona. During this time, Cruise wants to demonstrate product-market fit with a minimum viable product.</p>
<p>Phase three, the &#8220;rapid scaling phase,&#8221; begins in 2023, when production of the Cruise Origin will begin at GM&#8217;s Zero Assembly Plant, a factory dedicated to the production of electric vehicles.</p>
<p>&#8220;In that first year, we&#8217;ll be building what can be measured in thousands, and in 2024 we&#8217;ll be thinking about things measured in tens of thousands,&#8221; said Ammann.</p>
<p>Having GM as a backer for OEM-level production of vehicles will be a huge advantage for Cruise, said the CEO. The Origin will be built off the same Ultium platform that GM has built to support a wide range of products across its brands, which should enable faster production.</p>
<p>The company also invested in the technology and software tools needed to ramp up the rate of improvement of Origin&#8217;s autonomous system, which is ultimately a platform that allows AI and robotics to develop together in a closed-loop system.</p>
<p>Part of that investment went into Cruise&#8217;s simulation software, through which the Origin will largely be validated. It&#8217;s already begun virtual autonomous testing, even though it has not gone out onto public roads yet.</p>
<p>&#8220;The goal in the medium to longer term for everybody working on this is to get to low-cost generalized autonomy,&#8221; said Ammann. &#8220;We want fully autonomous driving, we want it to work everywhere and we want it to be really inexpensive.&#8221;</p>
<p>Throwing obvious shade at Tesla, Ammann said that while some companies are trying to solve the autonomy problem by working their way up from a low-cost Level 2 autonomous system, which translates to an advanced driver assistance system, Cruise&#8217;s approach is to solve the hardest problem first: getting the human out of the loop and doing so in one of the most complex driving environments – downtown San Francisco.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer" data-qa="block-kit-renderer">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper--first">
<div id="1633558740.036200" class="c-virtual_list__item" tabindex="-1" role="group" aria-roledescription="list item" data-qa="virtual-list-item">
<div class="c-message_kit__background p-message_pane_message__message c-message_kit__message" role="presentation" data-qa="message_container" data-qa-unprocessed="false" data-qa-placeholder="false">
<div class="c-message_kit__hover" role="document" aria-roledescription="message" data-qa-hover="true">
<div class="c-message_kit__actions c-message_kit__actions--above">
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter">
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter__right" role="presentation" data-qa="message_content">
<div class="c-message_kit__blocks c-message_kit__blocks--rich_text">
<div class="c-message__message_blocks c-message__message_blocks--rich_text">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer" data-qa="block-kit-renderer">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper--first">
<div class="p-rich_text_block" dir="auto">
<h2 class="p-rich_text_section">Driving costs down with technological advancements</h2>
<p class="p-rich_text_section">It might seem counterproductive, but Cruise says it has thrown a lot of money into the compute power of the Origin to get it to a place where it&#8217;ll be able to commercialize and scale profitably.</p>
<p>&#8220;Even though the technology carries a higher cost, we&#8217;re able to amortize that cost over a high-utilization fleet, high-mileage vehicle, and do that at a compelling cost point,&#8221; said Ammann. &#8220;The cost advantage of the Origin relative to a retrofitted vehicle, even including a Bolt AV, is about 60% to 70% lower cost per mile.&#8221;</p>
<p>That said, Cruise has plans to bring down the cost of that compute power over the next four generations by 90%. One way to do this is to start manufacturing custom silicon, which Cruise says will help it both scale compute use and cut costs. Ammann didn&#8217;t go into detail about what it will use the silicon for &#8212; a tidbit that will be touched upon further at the company&#8217;s &#8220;Under the Hood&#8221; recruitment event in November &#8212; but at the very least, the company is signaling a move toward vertical integration.</p>
<p>Considering the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/gm-extends-chevy-bolt-ev-production-shutdown-through-mid-october/">damage the semiconductor shortage has done to GM&#8217;s production lines</a> and the fact GM has just announced a supplier agreement with Wolfspeed to provide silicon carbide semiconductors for GM&#8217;s EV program, it&#8217;s probably safe to say Cruise has put chips on the menu. Others in the industry, like <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/why-tesla-designing-chips-train-self-driving-tech/">Tesla,</a> are also securing the supplies and production of their own silicon chips.</p>
<h2>Cheaper than a human by nature</h2>
<p>The Origin is purpose-built to provide excellent customer service at a low cost for both ride-hail and delivery, said Ammann. The vehicle itself is only as long as a Chevy Cruze, but the inside will be optimized to provide plenty of space to make for a pleasant ride-hail experience. It&#8217;ll also be able to convert from passenger mode to delivery mode, complete with a delivery unit that can slide in and out multiple times within a 24-hour operating cycle to make the most use of each vehicle.</p>
<p>Cruise thinks within just a few years, its Origin will be able to outstrip Uber and Lyft with cheaper prices and higher revenues. In some cities, <a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/08/07/1025534409/lyft-and-uber-prices-are-high-wait-times-are-long-and-drivers-are-scarce">Uber and Lyft prices are up almost 80%</a> from pre-pandemic prices, but the companies are still &#8220;not materially profitable today,&#8221; said Ammann. That&#8217;s due to their business model, he claimed. In San Francisco today, a rider is paying about $5 per mile, three-quarters of which probably goes to the driver and the rest gets spent on funding expenses and other costs, which results in companies just breaking even.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are two fundamental differences in our model, the first being that we don&#8217;t split the revenue &#8212; we get all the revenue,&#8221; said Ammann. &#8220;Because we have a lower cost structure, we&#8217;re able to charge less and make a profit. It&#8217;s as simple as that.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Can Cruise scale as rapidly as it hopes?</h2>
<p>Cruise didn&#8217;t share its revenue projections, but it did compare itself to other companies that have brought breakthrough products to very large markets and within a decade or so have gotten to &#8220;say $50 billion in revenue.&#8221; Ammann did say that Cruise conservatively expects to make about $100,000 in revenue per vehicle per year.</p>
<p>The company plans to own everything to do with its services, from the vehicles and autonomous software to the ride-hailing app and customer service. It hopes that by bringing more services in-house, it&#8217;ll be able to scale quickly and save money in the long run through constantly improving software that will allow it to begin to ditch sensors along the way.</p>
<p>Ammann even went so far as to say that it&#8217;ll be able to get its autonomous system&#8217;s cost curve so far down that it&#8217;ll be at a price point where it can be deployed into retail vehicles.</p>
<p>&#8220;You can go to your local dealer and buy a car that has Cruise L4 system capability inside of it, and with a partnership with GM, that obviously gives us a huge opportunity to turn that into a reality, and to do that at a really large scale,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>That reality is likely many, many years off, but Cruise isn&#8217;t shy about dreaming big.</p>
<p>&#8220;When you look out eight to 10 years from now, <span style="font-weight: 400;">I think we&#8217;ll look back and we&#8217;ll see that we&#8217;ve started to actually bend the curve on road safety in the United States and around the world,&#8221; he said. &#8220;C</span>ities will be given back to the humans &#8230; our cities will be cleaner and less congested. And people will have access to transportation that don&#8217;t have access to transportation today.&#8221;</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/cruise-plans-to-have-tens-of-thousands-of-origin-avs-on-roads-in-coming-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213764</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chronosphere raises $200M at a $1B+ valuation for cloud-native monitoring, adds granular, distributed tracing to its dashboard</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/chronosphere-raises-200m-at-a-1b-valuation-for-cloud-native-monitoring-adds-granular-distributed-tracing-to-its-dashboard/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/chronosphere-raises-200m-at-a-1b-valuation-for-cloud-native-monitoring-adds-granular-distributed-tracing-to-its-dashboard/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 15:32:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Addition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chronosphere]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CTO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Datadog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founders Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[general atlantic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Genius]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Georgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greylock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[infrastructure software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lee Fixel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lux capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[on-demand services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[performance management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real-time analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[series B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2214067</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Data observability &#8212; necessary to keep tabs on infrastructure performing as it should; to see if apps are returning errors; and to ensure that critical business data is getting to where it needs to go &#8212; is becoming an evermore complicated task as organizations&#8217; cloud-native data demands and data usage grow. Today a startup that&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Data observability &#8212; necessary to keep tabs on infrastructure performing as it should; to see if apps are returning errors; and to ensure that critical business data is getting to where it needs to go &#8212; is becoming an evermore complicated task as organizations&#8217; cloud-native data demands and data usage grow. Today a startup that&#8217;s built a scalable platform to manage that is announcing a big round of funding to continue its own scaling journey. <a href="https://chronosphere.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chronosphere</a> &#8212; a cloud-native monitoring platform co-founded by two former Uber engineers &#8212; has raised $200 million, a Series C that values the company at over $1 billion.</p>
<p>Alongside this, Chronosphere is also announcing a new set of tools specifically for distributed tracing, which will help make more granular observations and respond quicker to issues on the network as they arise.</p>
<p>General Atlantic led the round with Addition, Greylock, Lux Capital and new backer Founders Fund also participating. In yet one more example of how the most promising companies are fundraising with increasing frequency these days, General Atlantic, Addition&#8217;s Lee Fixel, Greylock and Lux Capital all backed Chronosphere in its Series B, which was only nine months ago, in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/chronosphere-nabs-43m-series-b-to-expand-cloud-native-monitoring-tool/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">January of this year</a>.</p>
<p>As with its previous round, this one was opportunistic, not because it was needed. &#8220;We are in the same spot as a year ago: more than 85% of our Series B b is still in our bank account and we didn’t need the cash,&#8221; said Martin Mao, Chronosphere&#8217;s co-founder and CEO. &#8220;But this was a response to our growth this year.&#8221; The company has been making regular updates to its tech and its revenues have grown tenfold in the last year, a reflection of what is also happening with data in the industry.</p>
<p>&#8220;Demand has risen 10X, too,&#8221; he said, adding that the size of the Chronosphere team has not, so it will be hiring. &#8220;This is indicative of the product providing value to customers and shows how quickly the market is adopting cloud. So we are trying to capture the market as quickly as possible.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company, which is 2.5 years old, has now raised $255 million to date.</p>
<p>Mao and co-founder Rob Skillington (CTO) founded Chronosphere on the back of early work that they started at Uber, where they built an observability platform very specific to Uber&#8217;s needs as a business.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The underlying large-scale metrics storage technology they built was <a href="https://eng.uber.com/m3/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">eventually open sourced as M3</a>. The two then left Uber to build Chronosphere to take their ideas and concepts for cloud-native monitoring technology to a wider market.</p>
<p>Specifically, they saw an opportunity to address a particular gap: Uber built its own observability platform from the ground up to handle its particular mix of microservices and containers because, as Mao described it, the Googles of the world had built their own, &#8220;so we followed the same path.&#8221;</p>
<p>But, he added, &#8220;there was nothing on the market designed for this type of architecture&#8221; that others could equally use, so they wanted to tackle the more general challenges of cloud-native complexity, by building that platform themselves.</p>
<p>Since being widely released in GA in January, Chronosphere has found early traction with companies that operate at the same &#8220;horsepower&#8221; (Mao&#8217;s word) as Uber &#8212; other on-demand businesses like DoorDash that may also deal in a similar architecture involving multiple cloud applications, on-demand services and real-time analytics.</p>
<p>Other customers include those whose business models are equally banked on moving and analyzing large amounts of data, such as cryptocurrency mining platform Cudo, sports data company Genius Sports, and Tecton, an enterprise-focused &#8220;store&#8221; for machine learning applications.</p>
<p>The distributed tracing tools also being announced today speak to how Chronosphere will be, going forward, looking for further applications of its monitoring tech. It will give users more detailed notifications around workflows, with root cause analysis, and it will also give engineers, whether or not they are data science specialists, more tools to run analytics on their datasets.</p>
<p>While the two co-founders continue to maintain M3, Mao points out that Chronosphere&#8217;s platform can work independent of it; it&#8217;s aimed at companies whose data needs have outgrown <a href="https://prometheus.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prometheus</a>, another monitoring and alerting solution that works well with M3. In terms of competitors, Mao describes Datadog as &#8220;the 800-pound gorilla in the room.&#8221;</p>
<p>(That is another reason to continue building fast and taking market share &#8212; and investment &#8212; where it can.)</p>
<p>“Chronosphere is purpose-built to address the needs of large modern cloud-native enterprises,&#8221; said Anton Levy, co-president, MD and head of technology investing at General Atlantic, in a statement. &#8220;Sitting at the intersection of the major trends transforming infrastructure software – the rise of open-source and the shift to containers – Chronosphere has quickly become a transformative player in observability. We’re excited by the team’s ambitious vision, with distributed tracing as yet another solution that differentiates Chronosphere as a next generation leader and paves the way for its continued growth.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/chronosphere-raises-200m-at-a-1b-valuation-for-cloud-native-monitoring-adds-granular-distributed-tracing-to-its-dashboard/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2214067</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tech giants&#8217; slowing progress on hate speech removals underscores need for law, says EC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/tech-giants-slowing-progress-on-hate-speech-removals-underscores-need-for-law-says-ec/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/tech-giants-slowing-progress-on-hate-speech-removals-underscores-need-for-law-says-ec/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 15:19:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[code of conduct on countering illegal hate speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital Services Act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freedom of speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hate speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vera Jourova]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2214081</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tech giants have gotten worse at removing illegal hate speech from their platforms under a voluntary arrangement in the European Union, according to the Commission&#8217;s latest assessment. The sixth evaluation report of the EU&#8217;s Code of Conduct on removing illegal hate speech found what the bloc&#8217;s executive calls a &#8220;mixed picture&#8221;, with platforms reviewing 81% [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tech giants have gotten worse at removing illegal hate speech from their platforms under a voluntary arrangement in the European Union, according to the Commission&#8217;s latest assessment.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/fs_21_5106">sixth evaluation report</a> of the EU&#8217;s Code of Conduct on removing illegal hate speech found what the bloc&#8217;s executive calls a &#8220;mixed picture&#8221;, with platforms reviewing 81% of the notifications within 24 hours and removing an average of 62.5% of flagged content.</p>
<p>These results are lower than the average recorded in both 2019 and 2020, the Commission notes.</p>
<p>The self-regulatory initiative kicked off <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/05/31/facebook-twitter-youtube-and-microsoft-agree-to-remove-hate-speech-across-the-eu/">back in 2016</a>, when Facebook, Microsoft, Twitter and YouTube agreed to remove in less than 24 hours hate speech that falls foul of their community guidelines.</p>
<p>Since then Instagram, Google+, Snapchat, Dailymotion, Jeuxvideo.com, TikTok and LinkedIn have also signed up to the code.</p>
<p>While the headline promises were bold, the reality of how platforms have performed has often fallen short of what was pledged. And while there had been a trend of improving performance, that&#8217;s now stopped or stalled per the Commission &#8212; with Facebook and YouTube among the platforms performing worse than in earlier monitoring rounds.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2214133" style="width: 2072px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2214133" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2214133 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screenshot-2021-10-07-at-16.04.03.png" alt="" width="2062" height="1226" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screenshot-2021-10-07-at-16.04.03.png 2062w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screenshot-2021-10-07-at-16.04.03.png?resize=150,89 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screenshot-2021-10-07-at-16.04.03.png?resize=300,178 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screenshot-2021-10-07-at-16.04.03.png?resize=768,457 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screenshot-2021-10-07-at-16.04.03.png?resize=680,404 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screenshot-2021-10-07-at-16.04.03.png?resize=1536,913 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screenshot-2021-10-07-at-16.04.03.png?resize=2048,1218 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screenshot-2021-10-07-at-16.04.03.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2062px) 100vw, 2062px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2214133" class="wp-caption-text">Screengrab of a chart showing varying rates of removals per company, from a European Commission fact-sheet on the hate speech removals code (<strong>Image Credit:</strong> European Commission)</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A key driver for the EU to establish the code five years ago was concern about the spread of terrorist content online, as lawmakers sought ways to quickly apply pressure to platforms to speed up the removal of hate-preaching content.</p>
<p>But the bloc now has a regulation for that: In <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/eu-adopts-rules-on-one-hour-takedowns-for-terrorist-content/">April</a> the EU adopted a law on terrorist content takedowns that set one hour as the default time for removals to be carried out.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MCuK3De8zs"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/eu-adopts-rules-on-one-hour-takedowns-for-terrorist-content/">EU adopts rules on one-hour takedowns for terrorist content</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;EU adopts rules on one-hour takedowns for terrorist content&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/eu-adopts-rules-on-one-hour-takedowns-for-terrorist-content/embed/#?secret=MCuK3De8zs" data-secret="MCuK3De8zs" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>EU lawmakers have also proposed a wide-ranging update to digital regulations that will expand requirements on platforms and digital services in a range of areas around their handling of illegal content and/or goods.</p>
<p>This <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/europe-lays-out-its-plan-to-reboot-digital-rules-and-tame-tech-giants/">Digital Services Act</a> (DSA) has not yet been passed, so the self-regulatory code is still operational &#8212; for now.</p>
<p>The Commission said today that it wants to discuss the code&#8217;s evolution with signatories, including in light of the &#8220;upcoming obligations and the collaborative framework in the proposal for a <a href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/policies/digital-services-act-package">Digital Services Act</a>&#8220;. So whether the code gets retired entirely &#8212; or beefed up as a supplement to the incoming legal framework &#8212; remains to be seen.</p>
<p>On disinformation, where the EU also operates a voluntary code to squeeze the tech industry to combat the spread of harmful non-truthful content, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/europe-to-press-the-adtech-industry-to-help-fight-online-disinformation/">Commission has said</a> it intends to keep obligations voluntary while simultaneously strengthening measures and linking compliance with it &#8212; at least for the largest platforms &#8212; to the legally binding DSA.</p>
<p>The stalled improvement in platforms&#8217; hate speech removals under the voluntary code suggests the approach may have run its course. Or that platforms are taking their foot off the gas while they wait to see what specific legal requirements they will have.</p>
<p>The Commission notes that while some companies&#8217; results &#8220;clearly worsened&#8221;, others &#8220;improved&#8221; over the monitored period. But such patchy results are perhaps a core limitation of a non-binding code.</p>
<p>EU lawmakers also flagged that &#8220;insufficient feedback&#8221; to users (via notifications) remains a &#8220;main weakness&#8221; of the code, as in previous monitoring rounds. So, again, legal force seems necessary &#8212; and the DSA proposes standardized rules for elements like reporting procedures.</p>
<p>Commenting on the latest report on the hate speech code in a statement, Věra Jourová, the Commission&#8217;s VP for values and transparency, looked ahead to the incoming regulation, saying: &#8220;Our unique Code has brought good results but the platforms cannot let the guard down and need to address the gaps. And gentlemen agreement alone will not suffice here. The Digital Services Act  will provide strong regulatory tools to fight against illegal hate speech online.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The results show that IT companies cannot be complacent: just because the results were very good in the last years, they cannot take their task less seriously,&#8221; added Didier Reynders, commissioner for Justice, in another supporting statement. &#8220;They have to address any downward trend without delay. It is matter of protecting a democratic space and fundamental rights of all users. I trust that a swift adoption of the Digital Services Act will also help solving some of the persisting gaps, such as the insufficient transparency and feedback to users.”</p>
<p>Other findings from the illegal hate speech takedowns monitoring exercise include that:</p>
<ul>
<li>Removal rates varied depending on the severity of hateful content; <strong>69%</strong> of content calling for murder or violence against specific groups was removed, while <strong>55%</strong> of the content using defamatory words or pictures aiming at certain groups was removed. Conversely, in 2020, the respective results were <strong>83.5%</strong> and <strong>57.8%</strong>.</li>
<li>IT companies gave feedback to <strong>60.3%</strong> of the notifications received, which is lower than during the previous monitoring exercise (<strong>67.1%)</strong>.</li>
<li>In this monitoring exercise, <strong>sexual orientation</strong> is the most commonly reported ground of hate speech (<strong>18.2%)</strong> followed by xenophobia (<strong>18%)</strong> and anti-Gypsyism (<strong>12.5%)</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<p>The Commission also said that for the first time signatories reported &#8220;detailed information&#8221; about measures taken to counter hate speech outside the monitoring exercise, including actions to automatically detect and remove content.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oRjzjsQPDX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/europe-lays-out-its-plan-to-reboot-digital-rules-and-tame-tech-giants/">Europe lays out its plan to reboot digital rules and tame tech giants</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe lays out its plan to reboot digital rules and tame tech giants&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/europe-lays-out-its-plan-to-reboot-digital-rules-and-tame-tech-giants/embed/#?secret=oRjzjsQPDX" data-secret="oRjzjsQPDX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/tech-giants-slowing-progress-on-hate-speech-removals-underscores-need-for-law-says-ec/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2214081</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter invests in avatar startup Facemoji</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/twitter-invests-in-avatar-startup-facemoji/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/twitter-invests-in-avatar-startup-facemoji/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 15:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avatar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Epic Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facemoji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[films]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jack dorsey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metaverse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Play Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roblox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual world]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213918</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Avatar startups have come and gone over the past few years, but the future that many of the entrepreneurs behind them originally imagined has proven more or less accurate. Apple is increasingly interested in avatar representations through Memoji, Mark Zuckerberg wants Facebook to be a metaverse company and platforms like Roblox, where users enter a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Avatar startups have come and gone over the past few years, but the future that many of the entrepreneurs behind them originally imagined has proven more or less accurate. Apple is increasingly interested in avatar representations through Memoji, Mark Zuckerberg wants Facebook to be a metaverse company and platforms like Roblox, where users enter a virtual world and buy accessories for their character, have never been more popular.</p>
<p><a href="https://facemoji.co/">Facemoji</a> is building a plug-and-play tech platform to help game and app developers put avatar systems into their apps with the startup&#8217;s SDK. Facemoji has raised a $3 million seed round led by Play Ventures, with participation from Twitter and Roosh Ventures, alongside some angel investors.</p>
<p>The startup&#8217;s lightweight solution leans on its own rendering pipeline, with the team noting that most other players in the space lean on Unity plugins that many developers don&#8217;t want to deal with. They also already have a full, diverse system of avatar art that developers can lean on out of the box if they so desire.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2214149" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2214149" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2214149" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-07-at-8.13.31-AM.png" alt="" width="1024" height="655" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-07-at-8.13.31-AM.png 1420w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-07-at-8.13.31-AM.png?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-07-at-8.13.31-AM.png?resize=300,192 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-07-at-8.13.31-AM.png?resize=768,491 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-07-at-8.13.31-AM.png?resize=680,435 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-07-at-8.13.31-AM.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2214149" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facemoji</p></div></p>
<p>Facemoji believes that more game-makers want to easily build their own avatar systems but don&#8217;t necessarily want to plug into other networks. The Achilles&#8217; heel of most early avatar platforms has often been the ambition to build a consistent cross-platform avatar system that functioned as its own metaverse. It makes sense for the startup building the product and users, but for game-makers, leaving that slice of the platform opportunity on the table was a waste.</p>
<p>Facemoji says they don&#8217;t anticipate Apple opening up Memoji to the developer community and that Snap is a more salient competitor. Facemoji&#8217;s startup competitors have been getting acquired at an increasingly rapid pace. In 2020, Roblox <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/roblox-buys-digital-avatar-startup-loom-ai/">bought</a> Loom.ai and Epic Games acquired HyperSense.</p>
<p>The startup&#8217;s founders are still heavily intrigued by the metaverse hype and the latest NFT craze and have been working on plug-and-play NFT storefronts that developers can integrate to let their users buy accessories for their avatars. Facemoji sees some of the early crypto Twitter profile pic usage as a sign that regular consumers are going to be excited about tricking out their avatars.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Ultimately, it boils down to ego,&#8221; Facemoji CEO Robin Raszka tells TechCrunch. &#8220;How you show off that you have a Birkin bag, avatars on Twitter is the prime real estate for this, people just want to show off.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a particularly interesting investment for Twitter, which is an infrequent corporate investor. Facemoji&#8217;s team said they had some conversations with the team at screen-sharing social app Squad about integrating their avatars before that startup was bought by Twitter. Twitter has also detailed a number of NFT projects in the works and CEO Jack Dorsey has been a major cheerleader for startups in the space.</p>
<p>In addition to gaming, Facemoji&#8217;s team hopes that soon people have the option of easily dialing into their next Zoom as an avatar or attending a class as one and that that live-action avatar overlays lose some of their silly reputation in favor of being treated as a healthy medium between having your camera on and off.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MdYj0xMO12"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/twitter-acquires-screen-sharing-social-app-squad/">Twitter acquires screen-sharing social app Squad</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter acquires screen-sharing social app Squad&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/twitter-acquires-screen-sharing-social-app-squad/embed/#?secret=MdYj0xMO12" data-secret="MdYj0xMO12" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/twitter-invests-in-avatar-startup-facemoji/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213918</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Robot response team</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/actuator-7/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/actuator-7/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 15:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abundant Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Actuator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diligent Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future acres]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jamba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moxi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wavemaker Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213843</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve been working on a big project the past several days (more on that soon), which means, unfortunately, I’ve been away from the daily breaking news. That means, in turn, that I really haven’t been on top of the big robotics news this week. So let’s use this column as an opportunity to play a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">I’ve been working on a big project the past several days (more on that soon), which means, unfortunately, I’ve been away from the daily breaking news. That means, in turn, that I really haven’t been on top of the big robotics news this week. So let’s use this column as an opportunity to play a little catch-up.</p>
<p>Before we get to that, however, I did have the opportunity to sit down with an interesting robotics company that had a unique pandemic experience.</p>
<p>It’s fair to say the world was a different place when <a href="https://www.diligentrobots.com/">Diligent Robotics</a> announced its Series A. March 2020 wasn’t all that long ago, of course, but the worlds of healthcare and hospitals have seen tremendous strain amid a pandemic whose scope and length few could have predicted. Demand for the company’s nurse assisting robot Moxi has spiked as hospital staffs have grown increasingly overworked and understaffed, accelerating trends that existed prior to COVID-19.</p>
<p>While last year’s $10 million cash infusion has no doubt helped Diligent grow, the company has faced the difficult task of accelerating production while dealing with the familiar challenges of moving to remote work.</p>
<p>Andrea Thomaz, the associate professor of Interactive Computing at Georgia Tech who co-founded Diligent in 2017 with Vivian Chu, joined us this week to discuss the unique challenges and opportunities the last year has held.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2191371" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2191371" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2191371" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2191371" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin/TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p><em>Don’t forget to sign up to get the upcoming <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">free newsletter version</a> of Actuator delivered to your inbox.</em></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>How profound an impact is the pandemic having on both robotics generally and Diligent specifically?</strong></p>
<p>It is really just a dramatic shift in labor markets across a lot of different industries. It seems to be related both to people kind of having a great resignation, where people are deciding that they want to do different things. And a lot of people shifting jobs. We’re seeing that all across tech work, a lot in our industry and healthcare. A lot of people are just deciding to do something else. There were already workforce challenges pre-pandemic, and now those are reaching crisis levels.</p>
<p><strong>This is kind of a perfect storm, in a sense, because you have fewer people wanting to do the job, and more people needed to do the job all at the same time.</strong></p>
<p>And that trend was starting before the pandemic. The pandemic just added fuel to the fire. But the trend kind of started with the Affordable Care Act. More people having access to healthcare means more people are going to hospitals and getting care. That together with an aging population, and you just have more care needing to happen with fewer and fewer people.</p>
<p><strong>Are you able to quantify that demand, in terms of how many hospitals you were in initially, and how that demand has spiked subsequently?</strong></p>
<p>We&#8217;re not really sharing that. I think towards the early half of next year, we&#8217;ll be sharing more specific announcements around scale numbers, but I can say that we&#8217;re, we&#8217;re doubling the number of robots that are deployed every quarter.</p>
<p><strong>What is that process like in terms getting one of these robots up and running?</strong></p>
<p>I think that’s what’s really interesting about hospital markets. It’s different than traditional warehouse or manufacturing automation. There’s people in the environment and they’re nurses and clinicians. The robot has to work within that environment and alongside the people. The first thing we do is workflow assessments. How does work currently happen in that environment?</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2213848" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2213848" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2213848" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Moxiteammatesinhallway.jpg" alt="" width="750" height="500" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Moxiteammatesinhallway.jpg 750w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Moxiteammatesinhallway.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Moxiteammatesinhallway.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Moxiteammatesinhallway.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Moxiteammatesinhallway.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2213848" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Diligent Robotics</p></div></p>
<p><strong>How has the pandemic impacted your own growth?</strong></p>
<p>Pre-pandemic, we were still proving out product market fit. We were keeping the R &amp; D team pretty small, making small tweaks to the product, but really, it was all about getting it out in front of customers and showing that they were really seeing value. And Now it&#8217;s all about execution and delivery, how do we make it as fast as possible to implement and as robust as possible. On the hardware side, in particular, it&#8217;s around design for manufacturing and reliability. Now that we&#8217;ve had robots out in the field for over a year, you&#8217;re starting to see some of the pieces and parts that we could get more reliability around, so we’re getting to that fun longtail of robotics.</p>
<p><strong>Are there any surprising features or demands that people had of the robots that are a result of the pandemic?</strong></p>
<p>I think that across all of our customer sites, the one request that we get, from every single nurse is, “is that robot gonna be able to bring me coffee?” They want Moxi to go to the Starbucks in the lobby and bring coffee for everyone. They try to justify that as a time savings, because then I wouldn&#8217;t have to go and stand in line at Starbucks. It&#8217;s not out of the question. But we&#8217;re not actively piloting that one.</p>
<p><strong>So, you’re not going to build an espresso machine into Moxi?</strong></p>
<p>Not in the next year.</p>
<p><strong>Do you anticipate seeking additional funding at some point in the near future?</strong></p>
<p>We are making plans for growth capital. They&#8217;re still working it out. But with the huge uptick in demand from customers, I think we&#8217;re ready to sort of accelerate some of our team and get more robots out.</p>
<p><strong>Are you focusing on the U.S. for the time being?</strong></p>
<p>For the time being. We are starting to consider what an international strategy would look like. I wouldn’t expect that we’ll have any international deployments next year, but we’ve started to have a lot of interest. We’re deciding what the right distribution partners would look like. We get several inquiries a month from international clients. At this point, we’re not actively in any project with them.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2121617" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2121617" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2121617" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Safeway-Tortoise.png" alt="Safeway Tortoise" width="1024" height="653" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Safeway-Tortoise.png 1060w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Safeway-Tortoise.png?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Safeway-Tortoise.png?resize=300,191 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Safeway-Tortoise.png?resize=768,490 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Safeway-Tortoise.png?resize=680,434 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Safeway-Tortoise.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2121617" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Tortoise/Albertsons</p></div></p>
<p>So, more on funding rounds and coffee deliveries at a later time. There are, however, a couple of delivery stories worth noting this week. First off, Tortoise (which we’ve covered a bunch in the past), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/tortoise-expands-remote-operated-robotic-delivery-to-convenience-stores-across-the-us/">is getting a big boost</a> for its team of remote-controlled delivery bots. A deal with Idaho-based King Retail Solutions will bring more than 500 of its robots to U.S. sidewalks for last-mile delivery.</p>
<p>“Everybody’s waking up to this new reality that same-day is the new normal, and it’s just not sustainable on every possible front to have that consumer expectation be met with people making $20 an hour doing those deliveries,” CEO Dmitry Shevelenko said of the deal. “The math just doesn’t work.”</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LsBABo5JkFo?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>Yesterday, <a href="https://wing-prod.blogspot.com/2021/10/check-out-worlds-first-rooftop-drone.html">Google’s Wing announced its own partnership</a>. Teaming with Australian retail property group Vicinity Centres lets the drone-based delivery program expand its footprint. Following the recent announcement of its 100,000<sup>th</sup> delivery, the Wing team says it’s already launched 2,500 deliveries from the roof of Logan, Australia’s Grand Plaza shopping center over the past month.</p>
<p>Residents can get bubble tea, juice, sushi and now health and beauty products. Says Wing, &#8220;Because almost every business has a roof, our new rooftop delivery model opens up the possibility for more businesses to offer drone delivery services with little additional cost or added infrastructure.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2213855" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2213855" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2213855" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/JambaBlendid_Stonewood1-2048x1537-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="769" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/JambaBlendid_Stonewood1-2048x1537-1.png 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/JambaBlendid_Stonewood1-2048x1537-1.png?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/JambaBlendid_Stonewood1-2048x1537-1.png?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/JambaBlendid_Stonewood1-2048x1537-1.png?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/JambaBlendid_Stonewood1-2048x1537-1.png?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/JambaBlendid_Stonewood1-2048x1537-1.png?resize=1536,1153 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/JambaBlendid_Stonewood1-2048x1537-1.png?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2213855" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Jamba/Blendid</p></div></p>
<p>Speaking of juice (not a segue I get to use very frequently in this roundup), Bay Area-based smoothie robot maker Blendid this week announced that it will be powering Jamba’s second mall kiosk. The location opened this week at a mall in Downey, California, a city in LA County that’s also home to the oldest operating McDonald’s (thanks, Wikipedia).</p>
<p>Wave of the future or gimmick? Yes and yes.</p>
<p>“After a successful launch of our first Jamba by Blendid kiosk, we’re excited to open a second test kiosk at the Stonewood Center, bringing freshly blended smoothies to mall shoppers,” Jamba president Geoff Henry, <a href="https://www.blendid.com/jamba-and-blendid-announce-the-opening-of-second-robotic-smoothie-kiosk-at-the-stonewood-center-in-downey-california/">said in a release</a>. “Jamba by Blendid provides an opportunity for our local franchisees to make smoothies more accessible to Jamba fans, while leveraging the latest in technology to deliver contactless food.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1802085" style="width: 2410px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1802085" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-1802085 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-02-1.jpg" alt="" width="2400" height="1599" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-02-1.jpg 2400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-02-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-02-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-02-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-02-1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-02-1.jpg?resize=1536,1023 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-02-1.jpg?resize=2048,1364 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-02-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2400px) 100vw, 2400px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1802085" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Abundant Robotics</p></div></p>
<p>On the orchard side of the fruit business, <a href="https://www.therobotreport.com/wavemaker-labs-acquires-ip-from-agtech-startup-abundant-robotics/">The Robot Report this week notes</a> that Wavemaker Labs has acquired the IP for Abundant Robotics, which shuffled off this mortal coil over the summer. Unfortunately, this likely doesn’t mean the return of Abundant’s apple-picking robots, but rather the integration of its technology into the robotic systems from Future Acres, a Wavemaker portfolio startup.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iqehzw_aLc0?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>And finally, a quick bit of robotic <a href="https://news.mit.edu/2021/robot-finds-items-camera-antenna-1005">search out of MIT</a> that uses an RF antenna and camera mounted to an arm to find lost objects. Per the school:</p>
<blockquote><p>Using machine learning, the robotic arm automatically zeroes-in on the object’s exact location, moves the items on top of it, grasps the object, and verifies that it picked up the right thing. The camera, antenna, robotic arm, and AI are fully integrated, so RFusion can work in any environment without requiring a special set up.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/actuator-7/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213843</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Snapchat is launching new tools to crack down on illicit drug sales on its platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/snapchat-is-launching-new-tools-to-crack-down-on-illicit-drug-sales-on-its-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/snapchat-is-launching-new-tools-to-crack-down-on-illicit-drug-sales-on-its-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 15:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drugs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teens]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2214103</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Snapchat is rolling out new tools and educational resources to prevent younger users from buying counterfeit pills and illicit drugs via the platform. The company said on Thursday that the goal of the new tools is to keep its users safe from “the devastating impacts of the fentanyl crisis.” “We are determined to remove illegal [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Snapchat is rolling out new tools and educational resources to prevent younger users from buying counterfeit pills and illicit drugs via the platform. The company said on Thursday that the goal of the new tools is to keep its users safe from “the devastating impacts of the fentanyl crisis.”</p>
<p>“We are determined to remove illegal drug sales from our platform, and we have been investing in proactive detection and collaboration with law enforcement to hold drug dealers accountable for the harm they are causing our community,” Snapchat’s parent company, Snap, said in a <a href="https://snap.com/en-US/safety-and-impact">blog post</a>. “While we still have work to do, across all types of law enforcement requests we receive, our response times have improved 85% year over year.”</p>
<p>The company says it has improved its proactive detection capabilities to remove drug dealers from its platform before they are able to engage with users and cause harm. Snapchat notes that its enforcement rates have increased by 112% during the first half of 2021, and that it has increased proactive detection rates by 260%. It also claims nearly two-thirds of drug-related content found on the platform is detected proactively by its artificial intelligence systems. It has also worked to improve its in-app reporting tools to make it easier for users to report drug-related content.</p>
<p>Further, when users search for drug-related keywords, they’ll now see a new in-app educational portal called “Heads Up.” The portal will show relevant educational content designed to prevent harm. Heads Up distributes content from reputable organizations such as Song for Charlie, Shatterproof and the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA). Additional resources from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention will be added in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>The launch of the new tools comes as a recent report from <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/specials/pills-bought-on-snapchat-deadly/index.html">NBC News</a> investigated the deaths of teens and young adults who allegedly used Snapchat to purchase pills that had turned out to be laced with fentanyl. The report alleged that drug dealers have been using the social media platform to find buyers and that Snapchat isn&#8217;t doing enough to prevent harm.</p>
<p>“We have heard devastating stories from families impacted by this crisis, including cases where fentanyl-laced counterfeit pills were purchased from drug dealers on Snapchat. We are determined to remove illegal drug sales from our platform,” the company said.</p>
<p>Social media platforms like Snapchat and TikTok, which are geared toward young users, are facing increased pressure to crack down on the sale and promotion of illicit drugs as overdose deaths continue to soar. Parent groups have argued that the digital giants aren’t doing enough to prevent harm to young users on these apps. Additionally, the U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration issued a warning last week about the increase of fake pills laced with fentanyl.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The administration released <a href="https://www.dea.gov/alert/sharp-increase-fake-prescription-pills-containing-fentanyl-and-meth">a public safety alert</a> “warning the American public about the increasing availability of fake pills that are more deadly than ever before, and that are easy to purchase, widely available, and often contain deadly doses of fentanyl.”</p>
<p>Snapchat has said it’s “heartbroken” that drugs have taken the lives of people in its user community and that it will work to do better and keep its users safe.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/snapchat-is-launching-new-tools-to-crack-down-on-illicit-drug-sales-on-its-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2214103</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mark Cuban-backed Otto raises $4.5M to turn car equity into credit</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/mark-cuban-backed-otto-raises-4-5m-to-turn-car-equity-into-credit/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/mark-cuban-backed-otto-raises-4-5m-to-turn-car-equity-into-credit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 15:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dallas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mark cuban]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[otto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tikhon bernstam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncommon Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213933</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Otto, a fintech startup which aims to allow people to tap into their vehicle’s equity for access to credit, has raised $4.5 million in a seed round of funding. The Dallas-based company is building a mobile platform that will essentially let people borrow against their vehicles at the same interest rate as standard credit cards. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://www.otto.xyz"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Otto</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a fintech startup which aims to allow people to tap into their vehicle’s equity for access to credit, has raised $4.5 million in a seed round of funding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Dallas-based company is building a mobile platform that will essentially let people borrow against their vehicles at the same interest rate as standard credit cards. But unlike other cards, Otto will not charge fees or overdraft charges, and will not require applicants to supply their FICO credit scores. Users will be able remotely verify and collateralize their cars through Otto’s mobile platform, which is set to launch in early 2022.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Uncommon Capital led the startup&#8217;s seed financing, which included participation from Pelion Venture Partners, 1930 Capital, Bloom VP and Spacecadet Ventures. Other investors include Mark Cuban, entrepreneur and Shark Tank investor; Leo Polovets, co-founder and general partner at Susa Ventures; Bill Clerico, co-founder and CEO of WePay; and Vivek Garipalli, co-founder and CEO of Clover Health.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Friends and former colleagues George Utkov, Jordan Miller and Daniel Ashy came up with the idea for the company after Utkov’s friend became the victim of a “predatory” title loan agreement. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Millions of people every year take out what are called title loans &#8212; and it&#8217;s when you own your car outright, and basically go pledge the title of your car as collateral against the loan,” said Miller. “These loans are 30 days long. They are 500%+ APR, and they absolutely crush people.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Utkov’s friend, who had lost a job during COVID, got a title loan against a truck that was worth between $15,000 and $20,000. When he couldn’t pay it back, he lost his car.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“That exposed us to this whole world of lending products for the underserved, for the non-banked,” Miller said.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The trio began work on Otto at the onset of the COVID-19 pandemic. After Utkov’s friend’s experience, they realized that people, for example, with unstable incomes or that are recent immigrants are extremely limited in options when needing money. As such they often have to resort to payday and title lenders, pawn shops or other non-bank credit lenders who often charge “exorbitant” fees.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With Otto, the friends/founders want to give people another option and one that won’t make their financial situation worse, but instead, better.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Otto chose the asset class since vehicles are often the most common and biggest asset owned by so many who are struggling financially and are underbanked.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Through the company’s mobile app, users will be able to apply and get pre-approved “within minutes” for standard interest credit cards, which are about 96% cheaper than the loans typically available to this user. The user is then guided through a step-by-step process of remotely validating their information and activating their new Otto credit card.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Consumers can use their credit cards to help pay for in-store and online purchases, build credit and earn rewards. Part of the goal is to help users build their credit so they can gain access to even more affordable credit products. When consumers use Otto, their repayment history will be reported to all three major credit bureaus.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like all major credit card issuers, Otto will make money in two ways &#8212; via interchange fees and interest.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We want to provide financial mobility to those that need it most, regardless of their credit history, and help them move forward in their lives by giving them credit options that they may not otherwise be able to access,” Utkov said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Besides helping people build credit, the Otto team also will track a user’s financial health and tell them things like what they’re spending their money on, and to be prepared for certain expenses based on their previous charging history.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Really what we’re creating is a system that is 95% cheaper than the lending products that these people use every day,” Miller said. “We feel like as we build this, and launch it, we have the power to fundamentally change millions of people&#8217;s lives.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Part of their plan to get their word out is tap into the resources of their investors. For example, Mark Cuban is already helping Otto forge local partnerships with businesses doing adjacent services such as advancing financial literacy and credit repair that are already doing outreach in communities, Utkov noted.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We believe that building trust from the ground up is very important, and that there’s a benefit to building on the community level,” Miller said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Via email, Cuban said</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> he invested in Otto simply because he liked “the idea of helping people use the equity in their cars.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I think Otto has a strong commitment to helping those who are underbanked and need financial support rather than extracting every dollar they can,” he added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tikhon Bernstam, managing partner at lead investor Uncommon Capital, said his firm was inspired by Otto&#8217;s vision of offering a new type of asset-backed loan for the underbanked.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“If you&#8217;re unbanked or underbanked you currently don&#8217;t have access to credit at the price that Otto is going to provide it at,” Bernstam wrote via email. “Your alternatives are traditional payday loans at predatory interest rates or traditional title loans at predatory interest rates. Otto is changing that.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/mark-cuban-backed-otto-raises-4-5m-to-turn-car-equity-into-credit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213933</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opal is helping companies ensure employees have access to the right apps</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/opal-is-helping-companies-ensure-employees-have-access-to-the-right-apps/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/opal-is-helping-companies-ensure-employees-have-access-to-the-right-apps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 15:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greylock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stephen Cobbe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213694</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The platform enables enterprises to design intelligent user access policies and automate reviews of current company access points.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Remember when a Twitter contractor <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/29/meet-the-man-who-deactivated-trumps-twitter-account/">deactivated Donald Trump’s personal account</a> for 11 minutes in 2017? <a href="https://opal.dev/">Opal</a> co-founder Stephen Cobbe says that is one example of an instance where certain employees were provided too much access to the inner-workings of the company.</p>
<p>His company, based in San Francisco and New York, is working with enterprises to design intelligent user access policies and automate reviews of current company access points. Cobbe explained that companies either grant access that is too broad or restrict it too much.</p>
<p>Cobbe and his founding team come from companies like Dropbox, Scale, Brex, MuleSoft and Palo Alto Networks. He personally saw at Dropbox some of the pain points of managing access at scale. What happens is that organizations have access policies around which roles do what, but in reality, life doesn’t fit perfectly into those access structures, he added.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2213697" style="width: 3594px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2213697" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2213697 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Opal_SS1.png" alt="Opal" width="3584" height="1842" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Opal_SS1.png 3584w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Opal_SS1.png?resize=150,77 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Opal_SS1.png?resize=300,154 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Opal_SS1.png?resize=768,395 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Opal_SS1.png?resize=680,349 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Opal_SS1.png?resize=1536,789 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Opal_SS1.png?resize=2048,1053 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Opal_SS1.png?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 3584px) 100vw, 3584px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2213697" class="wp-caption-text">Opal dashboard. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Opal</p></div></p>
<p>“Employees can have too much access, which is how the Twitter employee was able to go rogue,” Cobbe told TechCrunch. “When companies that we talked to tried to deal with the problem, they weren’t happy with existing solutions. We interviewed 100 companies and found that they all have versions of the same internal tool that they were individually updating each time.”</p>
<p>The tools are also typically based on SAML, or Security Assertion Markup Language, and not up to the task of managing the diverse systems companies have. Instead, Opal’s approach is to turn a once rigid model into a needs-based one through API integrations.</p>
<p>Companies can log in and see a list of engineering infrastructure, SaaS apps and internal tools. When access requests are made, they are routed to an owner for approval. On the flip side, when an employee leaves the company, an owner can go in and remove access with the push of a button.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>To continue developing its platform, Opal closed on a $1.8 million seed round led by Greylock. Angel investors participating in the deal include Expanse CEO Tim Junio, Abnormal Security CEO Evan Reiser and Signal Sciences CEO Andrew Peterson.</p>
<p>&#8220;Every enterprise knows that managing permissions at scale is challenging,” said Saam Motamedi, partner at Greylock, in a written statement. “More systems mean more attack vectors, places to audit, and overhead to ensure engineers have the access they need. Opal is tackling these problems with a strong team of security experts, and I look forward to partnering with them on their journey.&#8221;</p>
<p>Opal was founded in 2020, but came out of stealth mode a few months ago. It already touts a list of customers including Blend and Coffee Meets Bagel. The company used the new investment to hire on both the engineering and business side, Cobbe said.</p>
<p>He did not disclose growth metrics, but did say the company is poised to raise another round of funding in the future.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JmHVZw1oLv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/twitters-rinki-sethi-on-why-cisos-win-when-security-is-a-shared-responsibility/">Twitter&#8217;s Rinki Sethi on why CISOs win when security is a shared responsibility</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter&#8217;s Rinki Sethi on why CISOs win when security is a shared responsibility&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/twitters-rinki-sethi-on-why-cisos-win-when-security-is-a-shared-responsibility/embed/#?secret=JmHVZw1oLv" data-secret="JmHVZw1oLv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/opal-is-helping-companies-ensure-employees-have-access-to-the-right-apps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213694</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Instacart is acquiring catering software company FoodStorm</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/instacart-is-acquiring-catering-software-company-foodstorm/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/instacart-is-acquiring-catering-software-company-foodstorm/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 15:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acquisition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instacart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213497</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On-demand grocery delivery platform Instacart announced this morning that it’s acquiring FoodStorm, a SaaS order management system (OMS) that powers end-to-end order-ahead and catering for grocery retailers. The companies have not disclosed the financial details of the deal, but as part of the acquisition, Instacart will integrate FoodStorm’s technology into its suite of enterprise grocery [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">On-demand grocery delivery platform Instacart announced this morning that it’s acquiring FoodStorm, a SaaS order management system (OMS) that powers end-to-end order-ahead and catering for grocery retailers. The companies have not disclosed the financial details of the deal, but as part of the acquisition, Instacart will integrate FoodStorm’s technology into its suite of enterprise grocery e-commerce solutions.</p>
<p>FoodStorm has developed a SaaS offering that covers multi-channel ordering, order management, payment and fulfillment. Its technology also integrates with several third-party systems, including point-of-sale systems (POS). The technology also offers CRM capabilities that help grocers collect feedback and leverage promotional features.</p>
<p>“Our goal is to help our retail partners increase their sales and ensure more of their customers’ everyday meals come from the grocery store. That’s why we’re excited to welcome the talented FoodStorm team to Instacart and integrate their end-to-end, order-ahead and catering platform into Instacart’s leading enterprise offering,” said Instacart’s chief technology officer, Mark Schaaf, in a statement.</p>
<p>FoodStorm, which was founded 14 years ago, has formed partnerships with several of Instacart’s existing retail partners, including Bi-Rite Market, Mollie Stone’s Markets, Uncle Giuseppe’s and Roche Brothers. Instacart plans to make FoodStorm’s technology available to more retailers.</p>
<p>Instacart states that this new enterprise solution helps retailers bring even more of their inventory online and enhance their e-commerce capabilities while meeting the needs of customers. As for customers, Instacart says the technology unlocks a more affordable alternative to restaurant delivery.</p>
<p>“Grocery is an incredibly complex retail category, making the need for enterprise-grade solutions like FoodStorm and Instacart critical to the long-term success of the industry we all rely on to put food on our tables. We’re excited about this next chapter as we join the Instacart team and create new ways for retailers to serve the ever-changing needs of their businesses and customers,” said FoodStorm CEO Rob Hill in a statement.</p>
<p>Instacart notes that order-ahead technology solutions provide grocery retailers with a significant growth opportunity. For instance, Instacart customers who purchase prepared foods and catering items like hot and cold side dishes, cakes and sushi from the grocery store have significantly larger baskets and shop more frequently than customers who don’t. As for retailers, Instacart outlines that order-ahead items and prepared foods are also typically more profitable than traditional groceries like produce and package goods.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Earlier this year, Instacart <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/instacart-raises-265m-at-a-39b-valuation/">raised a $265 million funding</a> round from existing investors, including Andreessen Horowitz, Sequoia Capital, D1 Capital Partners and others. The funding pushed the company’s valuation to $39 billion. Instacart also recently debuted a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/instacart-speeds-up-grocery-orders-with-priority-delivery-option/">faster delivery service, &#8220;Priority Delivery,</a>&#8221; in select markets in the U.S. and Canada with the aim of attracting customers who would have otherwise quickly run to the store for their smaller orders or more urgent needs.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/instacart-is-acquiring-catering-software-company-foodstorm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213497</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Your iPhone could eventually control your car&#8217;s climate and seats</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/your-iphone-could-eventually-control-your-cars-climate-and-seats/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/your-iphone-could-eventually-control-your-cars-climate-and-seats/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 14:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CarPlay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[infotainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2214096</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new report claims Apple is developing a CarPlay upgrade codenamed "IronHeart" that would let you use your iPhone to control the climate system, radio, seats and even the instrument clusters.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jon Fingas</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jon Fingas is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/your-iphone-could-eventually-control-your-cars-climate-and-seats/">Your iPhone could eventually control your car&#8217;s climate and seats</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/jeeps-grand-cherokee-plug-in-hybrid-will-arrive-in-early-2022/">Jeep&#8217;s Grand Cherokee plug-in hybrid will arrive in early 2022</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Your iPhone could soon be useful for more in a car than <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-teams-hybrid-meetings-features-apple-carplay-intelligent-cameras-164625137.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="17" data-v9y="1">answering calls</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-07-02-spotify-stations-carplay-support.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="18" data-v9y="1">spicing up the music selection</a>. <em>Bloomberg</em> <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-07/apple-s-plan-for-cars-using-iphone-to-control-a-c-seats-radio?srnd=premium-europe" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1">sources</a> claim Apple is developing a technology codenamed &#8220;IronHeart&#8221; that would let you use your iPhone to control the climate system, radio, seats and even the instrument clusters. You wouldn&#8217;t have to switch between CarPlay and your car&#8217;s (likely clunky) infotainment software just to turn up the heat.</p>
<p>IronHeart is still early in development, according to the tipsters, and would require partnerships with car brands. Apple has declined to comment.</p>
<p>An initiative like this could extend Apple&#8217;s presence in cars far beyond limited technologies like CarPlay or its more recent <a href="https://www.engadget.com/carkey-apple-unlock-car-iphone-nfc-bmw-ios-14-13-175711038.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1">CarKey</a> feature. While it&#8217;s not necessarily part of the company&#8217;s long-rumored <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-car-hyundai-010548978.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1">electric car strategy</a>, it could give the company experience with more aspects of cars and help with any in-house vehicle development.</p>
<p>Whether or not automakers embrace the concept is another matter. Apple would effectively bypass a car&#8217;s native interface for many common tasks. It&#8217;s easy to see manufacturers balking after pouring extensive work into <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-30-fords-sync-4-add-wireless-carplay-android-auto.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="22" data-v9y="1">their own car interfaces</a> and companion apps, particularly if they have any services that compete with Apple offerings. If IronHeart ships, it may be limited to a handful of makes and models unless there&#8217;s an enthusiastic response from car buyers.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-ironheart-iphone-car-control-133752151.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/your-iphone-could-eventually-control-your-cars-climate-and-seats/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2214096</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BrightHire scores $20.5M Series B for Zoom-based job interview app</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/brighthire-scores-20-5m-series-b-for-zoom-based-job-interview-app/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/brighthire-scores-20-5m-series-b-for-zoom-based-job-interview-app/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 14:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[01 advisors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BrightHire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dick costolo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zoom Apps]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2214068</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BrightHire, a startup that wants to transform the way people are hired inside organizations, announced a $20.5 million Series B investment today led by 01 Advisors, with participation from Index Ventures and Zoom Apps Fund. The fact that Zoom Apps Fund is involved is not a coincidence, as the company is based on taking information [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://brighthire.com">BrightHire</a>, a startup that wants to transform the way people are hired inside organizations, announced a $20.5 million Series B investment today led by 01 Advisors, with participation from Index Ventures and Zoom Apps Fund.</p>
<p>The fact that Zoom Apps Fund is involved is not a coincidence, as the company is based on taking information from a Zoom-based interview and using the data to drive hiring decision-making. Company co-founder and CEO Ben Sesser says that while most business decisions are grounded in data, hiring decisions have been an obvious exception with a lot of emotion and gut feelings involved. He is hoping to change that.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our goal is to transform the way teams are built. In business, it&#8217;s kind of expected that any critical decision will be grounded in hard data and rigorous analysis. And yet in hiring, which is perhaps the most important thing a company does for its future, the decisions are made largely based on gut feel and memories and recollections,&#8221; Sesser told me.</p>
<p>He said that most companies are not terribly consistent about the way they hire and BrightHire brings some order to the hiring exercise, and in that way improves the experience for everyone involved.</p>
<p>The company records and transcribes each interview, which is conducted over Zoom, enabling the interviewer to concentrate solely on the candidate, and not on taking notes or other tasks. In addition, throughout the interview, the software will surface critical questions to ask the candidate, which helps ensure every interview is conducted in a consistent way.</p>
<p>After every interview, the software surfaces highlights and insights that help companies as they hire new employees and ultimately to continually improve hiring overall.</p>
<p>Dick Costolo, who is managing partner at lead investor 01A, says that one of the reasons he liked what BrightHire was doing was because he recognized that they were solving a fundamental hiring problem he had when he was running Twitter from 2009-2015 during a period of extreme growth.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;One of the things we noticed at Twitter was there was all this unconscious or unintentional bias in the interview process or even in the promotion process,&#8221; he said. This led them to try to seek a more data-driven way to make better decisions, something that&#8217;s much easier to do with a tool like BrightHire. &#8220;This would have solved so many issues we had around subjectivity and unconscious bias,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>During the pandemic when so much business was shifting online, the idea of interviewing over Zoom became much more normalized than perhaps it would have been when the company launched in 2019.</p>
<p>&#8220;Six months or seven months prior to the pandemic, just based on the problem, hiring was too important to not fix in really fundamental ways, but ultimately 2020 was a very interesting year due to the pandemic, and ultimately there have been a bunch of changes that have been big accelerants for our business,&#8221; Sesser said.</p>
<p>As the company grows, Sesser says he is using the product to drive diversity in hiring inside his own organization, but it&#8217;s just one tool in the arsenal. &#8220;We don&#8217;t solve diversity in hiring, but what our product does is create a more equitable process,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>He adds, &#8220;How can you have an equitable approval process if you&#8217;re assessing candidates inconsistently [&#8230;], and if we have no grounding or basis for our decisions that we can fall back on or hold ourselves accountable to. Otherwise, it&#8217;s literally our subjective memory and our feelings, which is a really really hard thing to do.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/brighthire-scores-20-5m-series-b-for-zoom-based-job-interview-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2214068</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Medley, the coaching platform for personal and professional development, gets $3.7M led by a16z</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/medley-the-coaching-platform-for-personal-and-professional-development-gets-3-7m-led-by-a16z/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/medley-the-coaching-platform-for-personal-and-professional-development-gets-3-7m-led-by-a16z/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 14:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edith cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jordan taylor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medley]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2214057</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Medley, the group coaching platform that focuses on both personal and professional development, announced the close of a $3.7 million seed round led by a16z today. Connie Chan and Anne Lee Skates of Andreessen Horowitz led the round, with participation from Aglaé Ventures, Foundation Capital, Ciara Wilson, Jen Rubio, Dara Treseder (Peloton) and Sanyin Siang [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.withmedley.com/">Medley</a>, the group coaching platform that focuses on both personal and professional development, announced the close of a $3.7 million seed round led by a16z today.</p>
<p>Connie Chan and Anne Lee Skates of Andreessen Horowitz led the round, with participation from Aglaé Ventures, Foundation Capital, Ciara Wilson, Jen Rubio, Dara Treseder (Peloton) and Sanyin Siang (Duke University), among others.</p>
<p>Medley was co-founded by Edith Cooper and Jordan Taylor, a mother-daughter duo who believe that the personal and professional development of people are inextricably linked. The platform <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/21/medley-a-life-and-career-coaching-community-for-everyone-launches-today/">launched back in July of 2020</a> with the goal of facilitating small group discussions led by a professional development coach. These groups were matched with the express intention of fostering diversity and inclusion, with different age groups, genders, ethnicities and backgrounds represented in each group.</p>
<p>With inclusivity top of mind, Medley welcomes everyone to join the membership, and even launched with an opportunity-based sliding scale for the annual membership fee.</p>
<p>Alongside the announcement of the funding, Medley is also introducing Medley Moments in the coming months. Moments are specifically designed courses that members can enroll in to focus on their particular goals. Taylor gave a few examples of the kinds of topics that Moments will cover, including becoming a new parent, learning about leadership, relocating, career pivots and more.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pxlpYDyjSf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/21/medley-a-life-and-career-coaching-community-for-everyone-launches-today/">Medley, a life and career coaching community for everyone, launches today</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Medley, a life and career coaching community for everyone, launches today&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/21/medley-a-life-and-career-coaching-community-for-everyone-launches-today/embed/#?secret=pxlpYDyjSf" data-secret="pxlpYDyjSf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;There was a heightened focus on the significance of gaining perspective on other people&#8217;s reality that was in people&#8217;s consciousness when we first launched, but now is critical to their center of gravity, in terms of what people are seeking when participating in groups,&#8221; said Edith Cooper. &#8220;There&#8217;s also an increasing expectation from people that their employers actually care about them and provide offerings that are not tactically oriented but for the benefit of them as people.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Given these insights, and a successful pilot program with LinkedIn, Medley is now looking at B2B options for the company, with the potential to sell the programs to larger organizations for the benefit of their employees.</p>
<p>Following the LinkedIn pilot, which saw a 99% NPS score, the professional social behemoth will be expanding that partnership in 2022.</p>
<p>The fresh funding means hiring is certainly on the table for Medley this year. Cooper, who sits on numerous boards, including those of Amazon and PepsiCo, says that the biggest challenge for Medley, or any organization for that matter, is attracting and retaining world-class talent, where both the passion and the vision are aligned.</p>
<p>&#8220;The best part of being an entrepreneur is getting to work with people who challenge me, who I learn from and who I can enjoy spending time with,&#8221; said Taylor. &#8220;It&#8217;s a great challenge but also something that I feel grateful for, is being able to, with Edith, build out a team of people who are always looking to learn.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/medley-the-coaching-platform-for-personal-and-professional-development-gets-3-7m-led-by-a16z/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2214057</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
