<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 13:37:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Formlabs raises $150M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/formlabs-raises-150m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/formlabs-raises-150m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 13:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3d printer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3d printing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[formlabs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Vision Fund 2]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154646</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A massive raise for the 3D printing industry this morning, as Massachusetts-based Formlabs has announced a $150 million Series E. The round, led by Softbank’s Vision Fund 2, effectively doubles the value of the unicorn to $2 billion dollars. The news comes during a kind of resurgence as the once-beleaguered industry is seeing a massive [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A massive raise for the 3D printing industry this morning, as Massachusetts-based Formlabs has announced a $150 million Series E. The round, led by Softbank’s Vision Fund 2, effectively doubles the value of the unicorn to $2 billion dollars.</p>
<p>The news comes during a kind of resurgence as the once-beleaguered industry is seeing a massive uptick in interest – and funding. Of note, Desktop Metal, Shapeways, Velo3D and Markforged have all announced places to go public via SPAC. The company notes <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2020/10/30/2117800/0/en/3D-Printing-Market-Worth-51-77-Billion-at-25-8-CAGR-Growing-Demand-for-Prototyping-Technology-from-Defense-Industry-to-Widen-Sales-Horizons-Fortune-Business-Insights.html">a recent study</a> that projects that the industry will hit more than $51 billion by 2026. The news arrives as technology is improving, materials are diversifying and companies are looking for ways to introduce additive manufacturing into mass production.</p>
<p>Founded in 2011 by MIT Media Lab students, Formlabs has been something of an anomaly in the world of 3D printing. The company adapted a formerly industrial method of additive manufacturing (stereolithography) to a desktop form factor. It was enough to keep the firm going amid a bubble burst for the industry.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Today, most 3D printing technology is still too expensive and difficult to use for widespread adoption,” CEO Max Lobovsky said in a press release tied to the round. “Our laser focus on improving the user experience and quality of these machines while bringing down the cost is central to our success and the growth of the industry. With this investment, we plan to expand our current portfolio of SLA and SLS technology and accelerate our product development to continue delivering on the expectations of the 3D printing industry.”</p>
<p>The large round will go toward increasing the company’s global headcount and helping Formlabs scale its technology toward mass production – a longstanding sticking point for most 3D printing tech.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="D00yYBLruO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/fortify-raises-a-20m-series-b-for-its-composite-manufacturing-3d-printer/">Fortify raises a $20M Series B for its composite manufacturing 3D printer</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fortify raises a $20M Series B for its composite manufacturing 3D printer&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/fortify-raises-a-20m-series-b-for-its-composite-manufacturing-3d-printer/embed/#?secret=D00yYBLruO" data-secret="D00yYBLruO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/formlabs-raises-150m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154646</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Super raises $50M to cover home repairs and maintenance via a subscription model</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/super-raises-50m-to-cover-home-repairs-and-maintenance-via-a-subscription-model/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/super-raises-50m-to-cover-home-repairs-and-maintenance-via-a-subscription-model/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 13:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Augmented Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Super]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The real estate sales market has been in an upswing this year, and today a startup that&#8217;s addressing one of homeowners&#8217; biggest needs &#8212; repair and maintenance services, and specifically the stress of sorting these out when things break down &#8212; is announcing some funding on the heels of strong growth. Super &#8212; which has [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The real estate sales market has been in an <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/petertaylor/2021/04/18/yes-americas-housing-market-is-officially-over-heating-everywhere-how-long-can-it-last/?sh=67f362964437" target="_blank" rel="noopener">upswing</a> this year, and today a startup that&#8217;s addressing one of homeowners&#8217; biggest needs &#8212; repair and maintenance services, and specifically the stress of sorting these out when things break down &#8212; is announcing some funding on the heels of strong growth.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.hellosuper.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Super</a> &#8212; which has built a business providing repair and maintenance for electrical and mechanical systems, appliances, and plumbing by way of a monthly subscription &#8212; has closed a growth round of $50 million.</p>
<p>The startup plans to use the funding to expand into new markets, to hire more people, and to continue adding more maintenance/repair services and partnerships into its wider home-warranty-by-subscription proposition.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>CEO Jorey Ramer, who co-founded the company with Ryan Donnelly (VP of engineering), also said that another part of the investment will be used to enhance the AI tech that underpins Super&#8217;s service and <a href="https://www.hellosuper.com/pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pricing plans</a>. More on that below.</p>
<p>The San Francisco-based company is currently active in some of the fastest-growing housing markets in the U.S.,  Austin, Chicago, Dallas, Houston, Phoenix, San Antonio, and Washington, D.C. (ironically not in SF itself), and it has grown revenue 7x since April 2019, when it previously raised money, a<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/17/super-raises-20m-to-fix-the-home-services-and-repairs-market-with-its-subscription-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> $20 million Series B</a>. It&#8217;s not disclosing actual revenue numbers, nor user numbers.</p>
<p>This is latest Series C has a number of strategic backers that speaks to the bigger ecosystem of financial and insurance services that interlink with each other, and which are used by the average person in the course of home ownership. (Indeed, Super these days seems to refer to itself as an &#8220;insuretech&#8221;.)</p>
<p>Led by Wells Fargo Strategic Capital, the venture arm of the banking giant, others in the round included home construction giant Asahi Kasei, AAA &#8211; Auto Club Group (which also sells insurance), Gaingels, and REACH. The last of these is a scale-up service from Second Century Ventures, which is the investment fund of the National Association of Realtors. Aquiline Technology Growth, Liberty Mutual Strategic Ventures, Moderne Ventures and the HSB Fund of Munich Re Ventures &#8212; which all invested in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/17/super-raises-20m-to-fix-the-home-services-and-repairs-market-with-its-subscription-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Super&#8217;s previous $20 million round</a> back in April 2019 &#8212; also participated.</p>
<p>The company has now raised $80 million in total, and it&#8217;s not disclosing its valuation.</p>
<p>As we have noted before, Ramer came up with the idea for Super when he himself moved to San Francisco after he sold his previous startup, Jumptap — an advertising network <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/08/13/millennial-acquires-jumptap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired by Millennial Media</a> (which is now part of Verizon by way of its acquisition of AOL, just like TechCrunch). He&#8217;d been an apartment renter for all of his adult life, but when he moved to the Bay Area, he found himself buying property, and it came with more than a little reluctance because of the headache of taking care of his new home.</p>
<p>“I liked being a renter,” he said in an interview. “You pay a fee, and you know what to expect.” (“Super” is a reference to the superintendents that handle maintenance and repair in an apartment building, and to what Super hopes customers will think about its service.)</p>
<p>The route that Ramer decided to take for how to approach filling that gap, interestingly, is not unlike the challenges that Jumptap faced in the world of ad tech: instead of trying to build a services business from the ground up, he opted to build an integrated network that tapped into a number of small services enterprises already working in the business of maintaining homes. (The correlation here is that, rather than building a first-party behemoth, the approach is to knit together a number of online properties so that people looking to advertise can do so across a wide range of places in a network).</p>
<p>Super has created a kind of marketplace: the services businesses and individuals that Super engages with to carry out maintenance and repairs are all licensed and use its platform for free, essentially, and Super handles remuneration based on call-outs. For users, the call-outs come as <a href="https://www.hellosuper.com/pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">part of their monthly plans</a>, and they include different options based on which level of service they pay for.</p>
<p>The funding it&#8217;s announcing today will be used in part to enhance how those monthly plans work.</p>
<p>Not only are there algorithms that Super has built to determine how to price its services based on location, size of home and other factors; but there are features in the app that subscribers can use to interact with Super to report issues, call out maintenance people, and provide more detail about problems to improve faster, and in some cases, automated adjudication on issues.</p>
<p>Better tech for more responsive home services has been an interesting area of the market, but one that&#8217;s largely been ignored up to now, but as they have matured, AR and other computer vision breakthroughs have definitely helped to advance that game. (And a number of others are also tapping into that, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/hover-secures-60m-for-a-3d-imaging-platform-used-to-assess-and-fix-properties/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hover</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/nana-nabs-6m-for-an-online-academy-and-marketplace-dedicated-to-appliance-repair/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nana</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/jobber-raises-60m-as-its-platform-for-home-service-professionals-hits-100k-users/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jobber</a> and more.)</p>
<p>The way that the service has been built to scale &#8212; working with contractors means adding in more kinds of coverage is easier than building from the ground up &#8212; also means that Super over time may well add more services into the mix.</p>
<p>&#8220;The things we would do are things your super would do,&#8221; Ramer said. &#8220;So that might include fixing plumbing, but might also potentially include cleaning carpets, which you could think of as maintenance. Painting is another interesting area. It seems like it might be a cosmetic thing, but if you do not paint, you risk dry rot. It&#8217;s also preventative care. So if we, say, cover 100% maintenance you could imagine that included, too.&#8221;</p>
<p>One area where it&#8217;s unlikely to move is general contract work, say rebuilding a bathroom or kitchen, or adding in a new room in your loft: the focus it seems will remain on the essentials of keeping your home working.</p>
<p>But aside of expanding the services directly on its own platform, there are also potentially opportunities for how Super might work with partners. AAA for example has a notable business not just in roadside assistance but also insurance coverage. Ramer describes Super as &#8220;roadside assistance for your home,&#8221; and he points out that it&#8217;s a natural partnership to sell those alongside each other.</p>
<p>Similarly, Wells Fargo, as a mortgage lender, is a natural complement, providing a route to its customers to help maintain the properties that they&#8217;re in the process of paying off to the bank. This in turn also becomes a kind of insurance policy to the bank itself, as it keeps the homes it is financing in better shape.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">“Wells Fargo embraces innovation, and we’re excited to support a tech-forward platform like Super which brings further advancement to the home services market,” said Matthew Raubacher, managing director for WFSC’s Principal Technology Investments Group, in a statement. “The challenges of ongoing repairs and maintenance resonates with every homeowner, and Super provides an experience that is convenient for the customer, while boosting job visibility for local contractors and businesses. We look forward to seeing them continue to widen their geographic footprint and expand their product offering.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/super-raises-50m-to-cover-home-repairs-and-maintenance-via-a-subscription-model/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154611</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sequoia&#8217;s Shaun Maguire and Vise&#8217;s Samir Vasavada will talk success in fintech on Extra Crunch Live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/sequoias-shaun-maguire-and-vises-samir-vasavada-will-talk-success-in-fintech-on-extra-crunch-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/sequoias-shaun-maguire-and-vises-samir-vasavada-will-talk-success-in-fintech-on-extra-crunch-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 13:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ECL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch live announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samir Vasavada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shaun Maguire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vise]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144992</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the past few weeks, we&#8217;ve heard Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand discuss the biggest opportunities in prop tech, heard why Scale AI&#8217;s Alex Wang and Accel&#8217;s Dan Levine think that unconventional VC deals can be the best option and taken a stroll through the Poshmark Series A deck with CEO Manish [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In the past few weeks, we&#8217;ve heard <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/fifth-walls-brendan-wallace-and-hippos-assaf-wand-discuss-proptechs-biggest-opportunities/">Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand discuss the biggest opportunities in prop tech</a>, heard why <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/09/scale-ceo-alex-wang-and-accels-dan-levine-explain-why-sometimes-unconventional-vc-deals-are-best/">Scale AI&#8217;s Alex Wang and Accel&#8217;s Dan Levine think that unconventional VC deals can be the best option</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/27/ceo-manish-chandra-and-investor-navin-chaddha-explain-why-poshmarks-series-a-deck-sings/">taken a stroll through the Poshmark Series A deck with CEO Manish Chandra and Mayfield&#8217;s Navin Chaddha</a>.</p>
<p>This is the particular flavor of content, rich in key insights and tactical advice for founders, that goes down on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">Extra Crunch Live</a>.</p>
<p>In an upcoming episode on Wednesday, May 19, we&#8217;ll sit down with Sequoia&#8217;s Shaun Maguire and Vise CEO and co-founder Samir Vasavada. <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-sequoia-and-vise">You can register here.</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Maguire focuses on enterprise, fintech and frontier technology for Sequoia. His portfolio companies include AMP Robotics, Knowde, Physna and Vise. He joined Sequoia in 2019, before which he was a partner at GV, where he led investments in Stripe, Opendoor, IonQ, SpinLaunch, Lambda School, Dandelion Energy, Clutter and Mode and sourced the firm&#8217;s investment in Segment.</p>
<p>Maguire has also been an entrepreneur in his own right, co-founding Expanse (a cybersecurity company), which was ultimately acquired by Palo Alto Networks for more than $800 million.</p>
<p>If that weren&#8217;t enough, Maguire also spent two years working at DARPA, and was deployed to Afghanistan, participating on a team that earned a Joint Meritorious Unit Award from the U.S. Secretary of Defense.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZnzQGTxh2Q"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/28/justworks-series-b-pitch-deck-may-be-the-most-wonderfully-simple-deck-ive-ever-seen/">Justworks&#8217; Series B pitch deck may be the most wonderfully simple deck I&#8217;ve ever seen</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Justworks&#8217; Series B pitch deck may be the most wonderfully simple deck I&#8217;ve ever seen&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/28/justworks-series-b-pitch-deck-may-be-the-most-wonderfully-simple-deck-ive-ever-seen/embed/#?secret=ZnzQGTxh2Q" data-secret="ZnzQGTxh2Q" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Samir Vasavada co-founded Vise in 2016. Vise is an AI-powered investment management platform that aims to give independent financial advisors access to technology and tools to build and manage personalized portfolios for their clients, ultimately giving those advisors more time and energy to spend on the relationships.</p>
<p>Vise has raised upwards of $60 million.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll talk to Maguire and Vasavada about what brought them together, key tips for fundraising and how to be successful in the fintech space, and ask about the next great opportunity in fintech.</p>
<p>On the second half of the episode, Maguire and Vasavada will put on their feedback hats and listen to live elevator pitches from the audience as part of the ECL Pitch-off. Folks attending the event will be able to raise their hand and pitch their startup to the VC/founder duo, and then answer their questions and get their feedback.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3zX1oc3ClX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/join-ecl-on-wednesday-to-pitch-your-startup-to-fifth-walls-brendan-wallace-and-hippos-assaf-wand/">Join ECL on Wednesday to pitch your startup to Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Join ECL on Wednesday to pitch your startup to Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/join-ecl-on-wednesday-to-pitch-your-startup-to-fifth-walls-brendan-wallace-and-hippos-assaf-wand/embed/#?secret=3zX1oc3ClX" data-secret="3zX1oc3ClX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But the only way you can pitch is to show up. This episode of Extra Crunch Live goes down on Wednesday, May 19 at 3pm ET/12pm PT. Anyone can attend as long as they register here, but on-demand access to the content is reserved strictly for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe">Extra Crunch members</a>, who also have access to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">complete library of Extra Crunch Live content, among many, many other awesome articles and perks. </a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/sequoias-shaun-maguire-and-vises-samir-vasavada-will-talk-success-in-fintech-on-extra-crunch-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144992</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unbounce snags Snazzy.ai to add automated copywriting to platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/unbounce-snags-snazzy-ai-to-add-automated-copywriting-to-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/unbounce-snags-snazzy-ai-to-add-automated-copywriting-to-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gpt-3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unbounce]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154612</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Unbounce, a Vancouver startup best known for helping marketers create automated landing pages, added a new wrinkle this morning when it announced it has acquired Snazzy.ai, an early stage automated copywriting startup. The two companies did not share the terms. Unbounce Chief Strategy Officer Tamara Grominsky says that her company focuses on helping customers convert [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://unbounce.com/">Unbounce</a>, a Vancouver startup best known for helping marketers create automated landing pages, added a new wrinkle this morning when it announced it has acquired <a href="http://snazzy.ai">Snazzy.ai</a>, an early stage automated copywriting startup. The two companies did not share the terms.</p>
<p>Unbounce Chief Strategy Officer Tamara Grominsky says that her company focuses on helping customers convert their customers into sales, and with Snazzy, it gets some pretty nifty technology based on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/4-ways-startups-will-drive-gpt-3-adoption-in-2021/">GPT-3 artificial intelligence</a> technology.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re focused right now on building conversion intelligence software that will allow marketers to work with machines to really unlock their true conversion potential, [&#8230;] and we saw a huge opportunity with Snazzy to focus particularly on the content creation and copy creation space to help us accelerate that strategy,&#8221; Grominsky explained.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>She points out that the product is really aimed at the marketing generalist charged with overseeing landing pages, and who is responsible for a range of tasks including writing copy. &#8220;The average Unbounce customer isn&#8217;t a specialized copywriter, so they don&#8217;t spend [their work] day writing copy. They&#8217;re what we would consider a marketing generalist or really someone who&#8217;s responsible for a wide range of marketing responsibilities,&#8221; she said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dnDYtL5I7O"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/4-ways-startups-will-drive-gpt-3-adoption-in-2021/">4 ways startups will drive GPT-3 adoption in 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;4 ways startups will drive GPT-3 adoption in 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/4-ways-startups-will-drive-gpt-3-adoption-in-2021/embed/#?secret=dnDYtL5I7O" data-secret="dnDYtL5I7O" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Snazzy co-founder Chris Frantz says the tech is really about getting people started, and then they can tweak the results as needed. &#8220;The hardest part has always been to get that first line, that first page, the first couple of words in &#8212; and we eliminate that entirely. That might not always result in amazing copy, but on the plus side you can always click the button again and give it another try,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Frantz says that with so much competition in the space, he and his co-founder felt they could build a market much faster as part of a larger and broader marketing platform solution like Unbounce.</p>
<p>&#8220;I love Tamara&#8217;s vision for the future of Unbounce. I think she has a very ambitious vision. She sold me on that very early on in the process. At the same time, there was a lot of competition in the space, and to have a key differentiator with a company like Unbounce, which has a decade of marketing experience and a lot of trust within this community, I think it&#8217;s a very powerful wedge that we can use to further grow our audience,&#8221; Frantz said.</p>
<p>The tool lets you write a range of copy from landing pages to Google ad copy. The company launched in alpha last October and already had 30,000 customers, which Grominsky says Unbounce hopes to convert into customers. The good news for those customers is that the company plans to leave Snazzy as a stand-alone product, while incorporating the tech into the platform in ways that make sense in the coming year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LkG8WqIE2P"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/17/unbounce-funding/">Unbounce raises $38.4M to build better landing pages with automation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Unbounce raises $38.4M to build better landing pages with automation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/17/unbounce-funding/embed/#?secret=LkG8WqIE2P" data-secret="LkG8WqIE2P" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/unbounce-snags-snazzy-ai-to-add-automated-copywriting-to-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154612</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>More funding flows into Pipe, as buzzy fintech raises $250M at a $2B valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/pipe-raises-250m-at-a-2b-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/pipe-raises-250m-at-a-2b-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 12:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alexis Ohanian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baltimore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chamath Palihapitiya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CreditEase Fintech Investment Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greenspring Associates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HubSpot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MaC Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marc Benioff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maryland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miami]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Okta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pipe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raptor Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sbi investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siemens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social + capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154196</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At the end of March, TechCrunch reported that buzzy startup Pipe &#8212; which aims to be the &#8220;Nasdaq for revenue&#8221; &#8212; had raised $150 million in a round of funding that values the fintech at $2 billion. Well, that deal has closed and in the end, Miami-based Pipe confirms that it has actually raised $250 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the end of March, TechCrunch reported that buzzy startup </span><a href="http://pipe.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pipe</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8212; which aims to be the &#8220;Nasdaq for revenue&#8221; &#8212; had </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/pipe-which-aims-to-be-the-nasdaq-for-revenue-raises-more-money-at-a-2b-valuation/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">raised $150 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in a round of funding that values the fintech at $2 billion.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, that deal has closed and in the end, Miami-based Pipe confirms that it has actually raised $250 million at a $2 billion valuation in a round that was “massively oversubscribed,” according to co-founder and co-CEO Harry Hurst.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We had originally allocated $150 million for the round, but capped it at $250 million although we could have raised significantly more,” he told TechCrunch.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As we previously reported, Baltimore, Maryland-based Greenspring Associates led the round, which included participation from new investors Morgan Stanley’s Counterpoint Global, CreditEase FinTech Investment Fund, Fin VC, 3L and Japan’s SBI Investment. Existing backers such as Next47, Marc Benioff, Alexis Ohanian’s Seven Seven Six, MaC </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ventures and Republic also put money in the latest financing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The investment comes about 2 ½ months after Pipe </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/this-pipe-ing-hot-startup-just-raised-50m-to-be-the-nasdaq-for-revenue/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">raised $50 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">“strategic equity funding” from a slew of high-profile investors such as Siemens’ Next47 and Jim Pallotta’s Raptor Group, Shopify, Slack, HubSpot, Okta and Social Capital’s Chamath Palihapitiya. With this latest round, Pipe has now raised about $316 million in total capital. The new funding was raised at &#8220;a significant step up in valuation&#8221; from the company&#8217;s last raise.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FbSU9SEqDA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/pipe-which-aims-to-be-the-nasdaq-for-revenue-raises-more-money-at-a-2b-valuation/">Pipe, which aims to be the &#8216;Nasdaq for revenue,&#8217; raises more money at a $2B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pipe, which aims to be the &#8216;Nasdaq for revenue,&#8217; raises more money at a $2B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/pipe-which-aims-to-be-the-nasdaq-for-revenue-raises-more-money-at-a-2b-valuation/embed/#?secret=FbSU9SEqDA" data-secret="FbSU9SEqDA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a journalist who first covered Pipe when they raised $6 million in seed funding back in late February 2020, it’s been fascinating to watch the company’s rise. In fact, Pipe claims that its ability to achieve a $2 billion valuation in just under a year since its public launch in June of last year makes it the fastest fintech to reach this valuation in history. While I can’t substantiate that claim, I can say that its growth has indeed been swift and impressive.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hurst, Josh Mangel and Zain Allarakhia founded Pipe in September 2019 </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">with the mission of giving SaaS companies a way to get their revenue upfront, by pairing them with investors on a marketplace that pays a discounted rate for the annual value of those contracts. (Pipe describes its buy-side participants as “a vetted group of financial institutions and banks.”)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The goal of the platform is to offer companies with recurring revenue streams access to capital so they don’t dilute their ownership by accepting external capital or get forced to take out loans.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">More than 4,000 companies have signed up on the Pipe trading platform since its public launch in June 2020, with just over 1,000 of those signing up since its March raise, according to Hurst. Tradable annual</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">recurring revenue (ARR) on the Pipe platform is in excess of $1 billion and trending toward $2 billion,</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">with tens of millions of dollars currently being traded </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">every month</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. When I last talked to the company in March, it had reported tens of millions of dollars traded in all of the first quarter.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Growth has been insane,” Hurst told TechCrunch. “This speaks to why we managed to raise at such a high valuation and attract so much investor interest.”</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2154315" style="width: 1450px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2154315" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2154315 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/PipePressKit_Trade.jpg" alt="" width="1440" height="900" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/PipePressKit_Trade.jpg 1440w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/PipePressKit_Trade.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/PipePressKit_Trade.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/PipePressKit_Trade.jpg?resize=768,480 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/PipePressKit_Trade.jpg?resize=680,425 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/PipePressKit_Trade.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1440px) 100vw, 1440px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2154315" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Pipe</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over time, Pipe’s platform has evolved to offer non-dilutive capital to non-SaaS companies as well. In fact, 25% of its customers are currently non-SaaS, according to Hurst &#8212; a number he expects to climb to over 50% by year’s end.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Examples of the types of businesses now using Pipe’s platform include property management companies, direct-to-consumer companies with subscription products, insurance brokerages, online pharmacies and even sports/entertainment-related organizations, Hurst said. Even VC firms are users.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Duud3LKqFu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/this-pipe-ing-hot-startup-just-raised-50m-to-be-the-nasdaq-for-revenue/">This Pipe-ing hot startup just raised $50M to be the &#8216;Nasdaq for revenue&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;This Pipe-ing hot startup just raised $50M to be the &#8216;Nasdaq for revenue&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/this-pipe-ing-hot-startup-just-raised-50m-to-be-the-nasdaq-for-revenue/embed/#?secret=Duud3LKqFu" data-secret="Duud3LKqFu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Any business with very predictable revenue streams is ripe for trading on our platform,” Hurst emphasizes. “We have unlocked the largest untapped asset class in the world.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He emphasizes that what Pipe is offering is not debt or a loan.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Other companies in this space are dealing in loans and they&#8217;re actually raising debt and giving companies money &#8212; like reselling debt,” Hurst said. “This is what differentiates us so massively.”</span></p>
<div>Pipe’s platform assesses a customer’s key metrics by integrating with its accounting, payment processing and banking systems. It then instantly rates the performance of the business and qualifies them for a trading limit. Trading limits currently range from $50,000 for smaller early-stage and bootstrapped companies to over $100 million for late-stage and publicly traded companies, although there is no cap on how large a trading limit can be.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Pipe has no cost of capital. Institutional investors compete against each other for deals on its platform. In return, Pipe charges both parties on each side of the transaction a fixed trading fee of up to 1%, depending on the volume.<span style="color: #888888;"><span style="color: #333333; font-family: Helvetica Neue, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif; font-size: medium;"><br clear="all" /></span></span></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup has been operating with a lean and mean strategy and has a current headcount of 34. Pipe plans to use its latest capital in part to double that number by year’s end.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We haven&#8217;t actually spent a penny of our prior financing,” Hurst told TechCrunch. “But we&#8217;re seeing huge demand for the product globally, and across so many different verticals, so we&#8217;re going to use this capital to not only secure the future of business obviously but to continue to invest into growing all of these different verticals and kick off our global expansion.”</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2154320" style="width: 527px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2154320" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2154320" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Harry-Hurst-Headshot-1.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="517" height="341" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Harry-Hurst-Headshot-1.jpg 1046w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Harry-Hurst-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Harry-Hurst-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Harry-Hurst-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=768,507 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Harry-Hurst-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=680,449 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Harry-Hurst-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 517px) 100vw, 517px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2154320" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Pipe co-founder and co-CEO Harry Hurst / Pipe</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ashton Newhall, managing general partner of Greenspring Associates, described Pipe as &#8220;one of the fastest-growing companies&#8221; his firm has seen.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup, he added, is &#8220;addressing a very large TAM (total addressable market) with the potential to fundamentally shift the financial services landscape.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>In particular, Greenspring was drawn to Pipe&#8217;s alternative financing model.</p>
<p>&#8220;While there are many companies that service specific niches with traditional lending products, Pipe isn’t a lender,&#8221; Newhall told TechCrunch. &#8220;Rather, it’s a trading platform and does not actually raise any money to give to customers. Instead, Pipe connects customers directly with institutional investors to get the best possible pricing to trade their actual contracts in lieu of taking a loan.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/pipe-raises-250m-at-a-2b-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154196</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Startup studio eFounders reaches portfolio valuation of $2 billion</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/startup-studio-efounders-reaches-portfolio-valuation-of-2-billion/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/startup-studio-efounders-reaches-portfolio-valuation-of-2-billion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 12:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eFounders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup Studio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154615</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[European startup studio eFounders has now been around for 10 years. And because a birthday sounds like a good opportunity to share some metrics, the portfolio companies have reached a valuation of $2 billion together —&#160;only 18 months after reaching $1 billion. eFounders says it is focused on building the future of work. In practical [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">European startup studio <a href="https://www.efounders.com">eFounders</a> has now been around for 10 years. And because a birthday sounds like a good opportunity to share some metrics, the <a href="https://www.efounders.com/companies">portfolio companies</a> have reached a valuation of $2 billion together —&nbsp;only 18 months after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/08/startup-studio-efounders-has-a-portfolio-valuation-of-1-billion/">reaching</a> $1 billion.</p>
<p>eFounders says it is focused on building the future of work. In practical terms, it means the company is building B2B SaaS startups with a focus on productivity and workflows. For instance, <a href="https://frontapp.com">Front</a>, <a href="https://aircall.io">Aircall</a> and <a href="https://www.spendesk.com">Spendesk</a> all started with eFounders.</p>
<p>There have been a few exits, such as TextMaster, Mention, Mailjet, Hivy and Briq. Those exits are included in the total valuation of eFounders companies —&nbsp; exit values are freezed as of date of exit. But Front, Aircall and Spendesk could represent even more massive successes down the road.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“When we started in 2011, there was an existing model that was Rocket Internet. We liked the entrepreneurship spirit but we didn’t like the philosophy,” co-founder and CEO Thibaud Elzière told me.</p>
<p>Instead of copying Rocket Internet altogether, they altered the business model quite drastically on three different aspects:</p>
<ul>
<li>They try to come up with original startup ideas, not copycats;</li>
<li>They want to work with entrepreneurs, not consultants-turned-entrepreneurs;</li>
<li>Their portfolio companies should be able to operate on their own after 12 to 18 months.</li>
</ul>
<p>When eFounders come up with a new project, they act as a sort of third co-founder. The startup studio tries to find a CEO and a CTO. In exchange for a third of equity, the eFounders core team helps take the project off the ground. When the startup raises a seed round, eFounders moves on from day-to-day activities and focuses on new projects.</p>
<p>And it’s been working well. With 30 portfolio companies, there are now 1,500 people working for an eFounders-backed company. Combined, they generate $131 million in annual recurring revenue.</p>
<p>As for the next 10 years, Elzière doesn’t think eFounders can simply increase the cadence and launch more and more projects. “It’s a model that isn’t scalable — it’s hand crafted,” he said.</p>
<p>There are two ways to expand. First, eFounders is going to focus on more verticals. That’s why the startup studio partnered with Camille Tyan so that he would be in charge of fintech projects. You can imagine another studio for blockchain startups, another one for AI startups, etc.</p>
<p>“We want to remain focused on software with a B2B angle — not enterprise but long-tail B2B. We don’t pretend to be a general-purpose studio, but we can acquire specific skills and knowledge on specific topics,” Elzière said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="p3aXp6TYCI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/saas-startup-studio-efounders-launches-a-fintech-startup-studio/">SaaS startup studio eFounders launches a fintech startup studio</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SaaS startup studio eFounders launches a fintech startup studio&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/saas-startup-studio-efounders-launches-a-fintech-startup-studio/embed/#?secret=p3aXp6TYCI" data-secret="p3aXp6TYCI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>If there are some liquidity events with some of the most successful eFounders companies, the startup studio is also going to use part of its cash to invest in other companies. This eFounders fund would focus on seed investments in SaaS companies with a hands-on approach.</p>
<p>But having more money isn’t necessarily a bad thing as SaaS products today don’t look like SaaS products from ten years ago.</p>
<p>“Creating a SaaS company today is a lot more complicated and more expensive,” Elzière said. “People who use Notion tell you that Notion is slow because it takes more than 100 milliseconds to load a page. People expect the same thing in consumer apps and in SaaS when it comes to performance, design and experience.”</p>
<p>“Companies raise more and more money because there’s a lot of money available, but also because it takes more and more time and skills in order to build a product,” he added.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/startup-studio-efounders-reaches-portfolio-valuation-of-2-billion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154615</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Proton, the privacy startup behind e2e encrypted ProtonMail, confirms passing 50M users</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/__trashed-13/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/__trashed-13/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 11:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[andy yen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e2e]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e2e encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Edward Snowden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[end-to-end encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet cables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law enforcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online Safety Bill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Proton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[protonmail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[switzerland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vpn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web browsing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[End-to-end encrypted email provider ProtonMail has officially confirmed it&#8217;s passed 50 million users globally as it turns seven years old. It’s a notable milestone for a services provider that intentionally does not have a data business — opting instead for a privacy pledge based on zero access architecture that means it has no way to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">End-to-end encrypted email provider ProtonMail has officially confirmed it&#8217;s passed 50 million users globally as it turns seven years old.</p>
<p>It’s a notable milestone for a services provider that intentionally does not have a data business — opting instead for a privacy pledge based on zero access architecture that means it has no way to decrypt the contents of ProtonMail users’ emails.</p>
<p>Although, to be clear, the 50M+ figure applies to total users of all its products (which includes a VPN offering), not just users of its e2e encrypted email. (It declined to break out email users vs other products when we asked.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Commenting in a statement, Andy Yen, founder and CEO, said: “The conversation about privacy has shifted surprisingly quickly in the past seven years. Privacy has gone from being an afterthought, to the main focus of a lot of discussions about the future of the Internet. In the process, Proton has gone from a crowdfunded idea of a better Internet, to being at the forefront of the global privacy wave. Proton is an alternative to the surveillance capitalism model advanced by Silicon Valley&#8217;s tech giants, that allows us to put the needs of users and society first.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="d5rrGBcug4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/e2e-encrypted-email-providers-also-see-sign-ups-surge-as-chat-app-users-flock-to-signal-and-telegram-in-search-of-privacy/">E2E encrypted email providers also see sign-ups surge as chat app users flock to Signal and Telegram in search of privacy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;E2E encrypted email providers also see sign-ups surge as chat app users flock to Signal and Telegram in search of privacy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/e2e-encrypted-email-providers-also-see-sign-ups-surge-as-chat-app-users-flock-to-signal-and-telegram-in-search-of-privacy/embed/#?secret=d5rrGBcug4" data-secret="d5rrGBcug4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>ProtonMail, which was founded in 2014, has diversified into offering a suite of products — including the aforementioned VPN and a calendar offering (<a href="https://protonmail.com/blog/protoncalendar-beta-announcement/">Proton Calendar</a>). A cloud storage service, <a href="https://protonmail.com/blog/proton-drive-early-access/">Proton Drive</a>, is also slated for public release later this year.</p>
<p>For all these products it claims take the same &#8216;zero access&#8217; hands off approach to user data. Albeit, it&#8217;s a bit of an apples and oranges comparison to compare e2e encrypted email with an encrypted VPN service &#8212; since the issue with VPN services is that they can see activity (i.e. where the encrypted or otherwise packets are going) and that metadata can sum to a log of your Internet activity (even with e2e encryption of the packets themselves).</p>
<p>Proton claims it doesn’t track or record its VPN users’ web browsing. And given its wider privacy-dependent reputation that&#8217;s at least a more credible claim vs the average VPN service. Nonetheless, you do still have to trust Proton not to do that (or be forced to do that by, for e.g., law enforcement). It&#8217;s not the same technical &#8216;zero access&#8217; guarantee as it can offer for its e2e encrypted email.</p>
<p>Proton does also offer a free VPN &#8212; which, as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/01/01/wtf-is-a-vpn/">we&#8217;ve said before</a>, can be a red flag for data logging risk &#8212; but the company specifies that users of the paid version subsidize free users. So, again, the <em>claim</em> is zero logging but you still need to make a judgement call on whether to trust that.</p>
<h2>From Snowden to 50M+</h2>
<p>Over ProtonMail&#8217;s seven year run privacy has certainly gained cache as a brand promise &#8212; which is why you can now see data-mining giants like Facebook making ludicrous claims about &#8216;pivoting&#8217; their people-profiling surveillance empires to &#8216;privacy&#8217;. So, as ever, PR that&#8217;s larded with claims of &#8216;respect for privacy&#8217; demands very close scrutiny.</p>
<p>And while it&#8217;s clearly absurd for an adtech giant like Facebook to try to cloak the fact that its business model relies on stripping away people&#8217;s privacy with claims to the contrary, in Proton&#8217;s case the privacy claim is very strong indeed &#8212; since the company was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/06/23/protonmail-is-a-swiss-secure-mail-provider-that-wont-give-you-up-to-the-nsa/">founded with the goal of being &#8220;immune to large scale spying&#8221;</a>. Spying such as that carried out by the NSA.</p>
<p>ProtonMail&#8217;s founding idea was to build a system &#8220;that does not require trusting us&#8221;.</p>
<p>While usage of e2e encryption has grown enormously since 2013 &#8212; when disclosures by NSA whistleblower, Edward Snowden, revealed the extent of data gathering by government mass surveillance programs, which were shown (il)liberally tapping into Internet cables and mainstream digital services to grab people’s data without their knowledge or consent &#8212; growth that&#8217;s certainly been helped by consumer friendly services like ProtonMail making robust encryption far more accessible &#8212; there are worrying moves by lawmakers in a number of jurisdictions that clash with the core idea and threaten access to e2e encryption.</p>
<p>In the wake of the Snowden disclosures, &#8216;Five Eyes&#8217; countries steadily <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/25/australia-wants-five-eyes-to-squeeze-tech-firms-on-encryption/">amped up international political pressure on e2e encryption</a>. Australia, for example, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/05/australia-rushes-its-dangerous-anti-encryption-bill-into-parliament/">passed an anti-encryption law in 2018</a> &#8212; which grants police powers to issue &#8216;technical notices&#8217; to force companies operating on its soil to help the government hack, implant malware, undermine encryption or insert backdoors at the behest of the government.</p>
<p>While, in 2016, the UK <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/11/29/yes-the-uk-now-has-a-law-to-log-web-users-browsing-behavior-hack-devices-and-limit-encryption/">reaffirmed its surveillance regime</a> &#8212; passing a law that gives the government powers to compel companies to remove or not implement e2e encryption. Under the Investigatory Powers Act, a statutory instrument called a <a href="https://beta.techcrunch.com/2017/05/05/uk-surveillance-law-still-fuzzy-on-decryption-rules-for-comms-providers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Technical Capability Notice</a> (TCN) can be served on comms services providers to compel decrypted access. (And as the <a href="https://www.openrightsgroup.org/blog/endgame-for-end-to-end-encryption/">ORG</a> noted in April, there&#8217;s no way to track usage as the law gags providers from reporting anything at all about a TCN application, including that it even exists.)</p>
<p>More recently, UK ministers have kept up public pressure on e2e encryption &#8212; <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-56795852">framing it as an existential threat to child protection</a>. Simultaneously they are legislating &#8212; via an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/uk-publishes-draft-online-safety-bill/">Online Safety Bill, out in draft earlier this month</a> &#8212; to put a legally binding obligation on service providers to &#8216;prevent bad things from happening on the Internet&#8217; (as the <a href="https://www.openrightsgroup.org/blog/online-harms-encryption-under-attack/">ORG</a> neatly sums it up). And while still at the draft stage, private messaging services are in scope of that bill &#8212; putting the law on a potential collision course with messaging services that use e2e encryption.</p>
<p>The U.S., meanwhile, has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/16/senate-fisa-section-702-cloture-vote-wyden-paul/">declined to reform warrantless surveillance</a>.</p>
<p>And if you think the EU is a safe space for e2e encryption, there are reasons to be concerned in continental Europe too.</p>
<p>EU lawmakers have recently made a push for what they describe as &#8220;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/on-encryption-and-counter-terrorism-eu-lawmakers-say-theyll-work-for-lawful-data-access/">lawful access</a>&#8221; to encrypted data — without specifying exactly how that might be achieved, i.e. without breaking and/or backdooring e2e encryption and therefore undoing the digital security they also say is vital.</p>
<p>In a further worrying development, EU lawmakers have proposed automated scanning of encrypted communications services — aka a provision called ‘chatcontrol’ that’s ostensibly targeted at prosecuting those who share child exploitation content — which raises further questions over how such laws might intersect with &#8216;zero access&#8217; services like ProtonMail.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://european-pirateparty.eu/the-end-of-the-privacy-of-digital-correspondence/">European Pirate Party</a> has been sounding the alarm &#8212; and dubs the &#8216;chatcontrol&#8217; <a href="https://www.europarl.europa.eu/RegData/docs_autres_institutions/commission_europeenne/com/2020/0568/COM_COM(2020)0568_EN.pdf">proposal</a> &#8220;the end of the privacy of digital correspondence&#8221; &#8212; <a href="https://www.patrick-breyer.de/en/posts/message-screening/">warning</a> that &#8220;securely encrypted communication is at risk&#8221;.</p>
<p>A plenary vote on the proposal is expected in the coming months &#8212; so where exactly the EU lands on that remains to be seen.</p>
<p>ProtonMail, meanwhile, is based in Switzerland which is not a member of the EU and has one of the stronger reputations for privacy laws globally. However the country also backed beefed-up surveillance powers<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/26/swiss-public-back-law-expanding-surveillance-powers/"> in 2016</a> &#8212; extending the digital snooping capabilities of its own intelligence agencies.</p>
<p>It does also adopt some EU regulations &#8212; so, again, it&#8217;s not clear whether or not any pan-EU automated scanning of message content could end up being applied to services based in the country.</p>
<p>The threats to e2e encryption are certainly growing, even as usage of such properly private services keeps scaling.</p>
<p>Asked whether it has concerns, ProtonMail pointed out that the EU&#8217;s current temporary chatcontrol proposal is voluntary &#8212; meaning it would be up to the company in question to decide its own policy. Although it accepts there is &#8220;some support&#8221; in the Commission for the chatcontrol proposals to be made mandatory.</p>
<p>&#8220;It’s not clear at this time whether these proposals could impact Proton specifically [i.e. if they were to become mandatory],&#8221; the spokesman also told us. &#8220;The extent to which a Swiss company like Proton might be impacted by such efforts would have to be assessed based on the specific legal proposal. To our knowledge, none has been made for now.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We completely agree that steps have to be taken to combat the spread of illegal explicit material. However, our concern is that the forced scanning of communications would be an ineffective approach and would instead have the unintended effect of undermining many of the basic freedoms that the EU was established to protect,&#8221; he added. &#8220;Any form of automated content scanning is incompatible with end-to-end encryption and by definition undermines the right to privacy.&#8221;</p>
<p>So while Proton is rightly celebrating that a steady commitment to zero access infrastructure over the past seven years has helped its business grow to 50M+ users, there are reasons for all privacy-minded folk to be watchful of what the next years of political developments might mean for the privacy and security of all our data.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="M6mvIagazU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/protonmail-threema-tresorit-and-tutanota-warn-eu-lawmakers-against-anti-encryption-push/">ProtonMail, Threema, Tresorit and Tutanota warn EU lawmakers over &#8216;anti-encryption&#8217; push</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;ProtonMail, Threema, Tresorit and Tutanota warn EU lawmakers over &#8216;anti-encryption&#8217; push&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/protonmail-threema-tresorit-and-tutanota-warn-eu-lawmakers-against-anti-encryption-push/embed/#?secret=M6mvIagazU" data-secret="M6mvIagazU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NUNGt3Y3jn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/whats-all-this-about-europe-wanting-crypto-backdoors/">What&#8217;s all this about Europe wanting crypto backdoors?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What&#8217;s all this about Europe wanting crypto backdoors?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/whats-all-this-about-europe-wanting-crypto-backdoors/embed/#?secret=NUNGt3Y3jn" data-secret="NUNGt3Y3jn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/__trashed-13/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154309</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>IFA Berlin 2021 is canceled, citing ‘uncertainties’ around vaccine rollouts</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/ifa-berlin-2021-is-canceled-citing-uncertainties-around-vaccine-rollouts/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/ifa-berlin-2021-is-canceled-citing-uncertainties-around-vaccine-rollouts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 11:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coronavirus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IFA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154602</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After IFA became one of an extremely small number of in-person trade shows in 2020, the gfu Consumer &#38; Home Electronics GmbH is pulling the plug on this year’s event. Initially planned for September 3-7 at the Messe in Berlin, the large-scale consumer electronics trade show is going on hiatus. Among other concerns, organizer are [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After IFA became one of an extremely <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/28/ifas-executive-director-discusses-why-the-tech-show-must-go-on/">small number of in-person trade shows</a> in 2020, the gfu Consumer &amp; Home Electronics GmbH <a href="https://b2b.ifa-berlin.com/en/press/press-releases/news_4033.html?referrer=/press/press-releases/#news-en-4033">is pulling the plug on this year’s event</a>. Initially planned for September 3-7 at the Messe in Berlin, the large-scale consumer electronics trade show is going on hiatus.</p>
<p>Among other concerns, organizer are citing the emergency of Covid-19 variants and concerns around the speed and consistency with which vaccines have been rolled out globally.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">We planned, hoped and tried to make the impossible possible – and yet had to cancel <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/IFA2021?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#IFA2021</a>. We&#39;re <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/heartbroken?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#heartbroken</a>, but full of confidence for <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/IFA2022?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#IFA2022</a>!<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/seeyouatIFA2022?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#seeyouatIFA2022</a><a href="https://t.co/VzBGNTCvFA">https://t.co/VzBGNTCvFA</a> <a href="https://t.co/ZvM2FCnLv1">pic.twitter.com/ZvM2FCnLv1</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&mdash; IFA Berlin (@IFA_Berlin) <a href="https://twitter.com/IFA_Berlin/status/1394962508369252357?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 19, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>“Ultimately, several key global health metrics did not move as fast in the right direction as had been hoped for &#8211; from the rapid emergence of new COVID-19 variants, for example in South Asia, to continued uncertainties about the speed of the rollout of vaccination programmes around the world,” the organization said in a press release. “This in turn is adding uncertainty for the companies that were committed or interested in coming to Berlin, as well as media and visitors – all of whom have to plan well ahead with regards to budgets, investments and travel – not just for IFA, but all similar events around the world.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="h2Y6NGSdlQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/qualcomm-wont-be-exhibiting-in-person-at-mwc/">Qualcomm won’t be exhibiting in-person at MWC</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Qualcomm won’t be exhibiting in-person at MWC&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/qualcomm-wont-be-exhibiting-in-person-at-mwc/embed/#?secret=h2Y6NGSdlQ" data-secret="h2Y6NGSdlQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Another key issue here is the Messe Berlin (convention center) has been – and continues to be – used as both an emergency medical facility and a vaccination center. The planned Berlin Photo Week at ARENA Berlin and SHIFT Mobility events will continue. IFA, meanwhile, is set to return on September 2, 2022.</p>
<p>The news comes as a number of high profile exhibitors have opted not to exhibit in-person at MWC late next month in Barcelona. The list, thus far, includes Qualcomm, Google, IBM, Nokia, Sony, Oracle, Ericsson, Samsung and Lenovo. As with IFA before it, MWC’s organizers are citing a number of safety precautious and likely – given travel restrictions, MIA exhibitors and a general sense of caution even among vaccinated people – a scaled back event.</p>
<p>MWC will be something of a hybrid event, with both online and in-person exhibits. IFA, meanwhile, appears to be canceled outright. The Berlin show is notably different than other consumer trade shows in that it is partially open to the public.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="30wLzALaKu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/can-the-tech-trade-show-return-in-2021/">Can the tech trade show return in 2021?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Can the tech trade show return in 2021?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/can-the-tech-trade-show-return-in-2021/embed/#?secret=30wLzALaKu" data-secret="30wLzALaKu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/ifa-berlin-2021-is-canceled-citing-uncertainties-around-vaccine-rollouts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154602</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spotify launches a virtual concert series with The Black Keys and more</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/spotify-launches-a-virtual-concert-series-with-the-black-keys-and-more/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/spotify-launches-a-virtual-concert-series-with-the-black-keys-and-more/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 11:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concerts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual concerts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154316</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The past year has been utterly devastating to the music industry generally, and live music in particular. Artists who make a living touring have been forced to find alternative ways to make ends meet, while those among us who once frequented live events have been looking for ways to plug the hole created by wide-scale [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The past year has been utterly devastating to the music industry generally, and live music in particular. Artists who make a living touring have been forced to find alternative ways to make ends meet, while those among us who once frequented live events have been looking for ways to plug the hole created by wide-scale shutdowns.</p>
<p>A number of music-related platforms have spent much of the pandemic looking to offer some semblance of the concert-going experience, ranging from live venues to services like Bandcamp. Today, Spotify is announcing<a href="https://www.spotify.live/"> the launch of a new feature</a> designed to provide a live-show experience remotely. Venues in many areas are beginning to reopen, but even fans may be cautious to return to packed, indoor events.</p>
<p>The streaming service is announcing a series of shows starting with dates this month and next, including names like The Black Keys, Rag&#8217;n&#8217;Bone Man, Bleachers’ Jack Antonoff, Leon Bridges and girl in red. Spotify is billing them as “prerecorded livestreams” &#8212; a bit of an oxymoron, that. I recognize that livestream has become kind of a catchall, but it loses some meaning when the thing isn’t, you know, live.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Rather than streaming straight from a venue, the service is taking the somewhat novel approach of letting the artist choose the spot for the pre-recorded show. That means live-show venues in the case of The Black Keys and something more creative for Antonoff, who shot his segment on a bus traveling from Brooklyn to Springsteen’s old stomping ground, Asbury Park, New Jersey (greetings).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tB3UM16rkm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/02/are-virtual-concerts-here-to-stay/">Are virtual concerts here to stay?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Are virtual concerts here to stay?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/02/are-virtual-concerts-here-to-stay/embed/#?secret=tB3UM16rkm" data-secret="tB3UM16rkm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“We have always been a band that loves to play live in venues of all shapes and sizes,” The Black Keys said in a release tied to the news. “The past year has been tough for musicians and fans alike, so we wanted to find a way to share this live performance of songs from our new project, <em>Delta Kream</em>, from a place we love, the Blue Front Café, the oldest active juke joint in America. We’re excited to be a part of this new initiative with Spotify that will give fans a great way to connect with their favorite artists.”</p>
<p>The shows run 40-75 minutes and run $15 a pop. The price seems a bit high to stream a pre-recorded concert, but fans of the groups will likely appreciate what’s being billed as an “intimate” look at one of their favorite artists &#8212; though intimacy is, in part, limited as the company will be selling unlimited tickets to the events. The service isn&#8217;t revealing how large of a cut artists will get, simply telling TechCrunch, &#8220;All artists will receive a guaranteed fee for their participation in the livestream.&#8221;</p>
<p>Streaming the shows requires a Spotify account &#8212; either premium or free.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LWBRSQcKmD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/musicians-get-the-bulk-of-ticket-sales-with-bandcamps-new-live-streaming-concert-feature/">Musicians get the bulk of ticket sales with Bandcamp’s new live-streaming concert feature</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Musicians get the bulk of ticket sales with Bandcamp’s new live-streaming concert feature&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/musicians-get-the-bulk-of-ticket-sales-with-bandcamps-new-live-streaming-concert-feature/embed/#?secret=LWBRSQcKmD" data-secret="LWBRSQcKmD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/spotify-launches-a-virtual-concert-series-with-the-black-keys-and-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154316</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Upstream, a Miami-based professional networking platform, raises a $2.75M seed round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/upstream-a-miami-based-professional-networking-platform-raises-a-2-75m-seed-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/upstream-a-miami-based-professional-networking-platform-raises-a-2-75m-seed-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marcella McCarthy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 11:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alex taub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cory booker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resource management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Human Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ibex Investors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miami]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Schonfeld]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nicole Priel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recruitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upstream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154136</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you’re reading this, there’s a pretty good chance you have a LinkedIn profile with your digital resume and hundreds &#8212; if not thousands &#8212; of professional connections. But how many of those people do you actually know well, and, more importantly, do you ever connect with them and meet others from their networks? “You [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re reading this, there’s a pretty good chance you have a LinkedIn profile with your digital resume and hundreds &#8212; if not thousands &#8212; of professional connections. But how many of those people do you actually know well, and, more importantly, do you ever connect with them and meet others from their networks?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“You don’t go to LinkedIn to meet people. You don’t hang out and spend meaningful time there,” said Alex Taub, co-founder and CEO of <a href="https://upstreamapp.com/">Upstream</a>, a new professional networking platform that just closed a $2.75 million seed round, bringing their total raised to $3.25 million. The round was led by Ibex Investors and managing partner Nicole Priel (who joins the board) and includes participation by 8-Bit Capital, Human Ventures, NYVP, Converge Venture Partners and a number of angel investors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Your LinkedIn network is not a good representation of who you actually know and how well you know them. We see these places that LinkedIn isn’t particularly focused [on] and believe there are opportunities for multiple big companies to better serve the needs of professionals,” Taub added.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unlike LinkedIn, Upstream focuses on generating meaningful connections between its members, and one way they go about it is by hosting digital events that start with a speaker, followed by breakout matched sessions that are five minutes each.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To get a sense of the product, Upstream invited me to be the speaker at last Friday’s “Upstream Social,” where I talked about my work as a journalist and then coincidently got matched with two founders &#8212; one in Brazil and the other in Boston. The week before, the guest speaker was U.S. Senator Cory Booker of New Jersey.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OyjW6G2tVS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/6-miami-based-investors-share-their-views-on-the-regions-startup-scene/">8 Miami-based investors share their views on the region&#8217;s startup scene</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;8 Miami-based investors share their views on the region&#8217;s startup scene&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/6-miami-based-investors-share-their-views-on-the-regions-startup-scene/embed/#?secret=OyjW6G2tVS" data-secret="OyjW6G2tVS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To me, the experience felt like LinkedIn meets Clubhouse meets Hoppin.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Upstream, which is pre-revenue and is Miami-based, is a company whose founder was attracted to the Sunshine State from NYC during the pandemic. Taub and his family signed a two-year lease here and plan to reevaluate their residence in the summer of 2022; they are one of the movers who are cautiously optimistic about the tech industry’s recent explosion in the Magic City.</span></p>
<h2>The origin story</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Taub and his co-founder, Michael Schonfeld, are both serial entrepreneurs, having built and sold Social Rank for an undisclosed amount before launching Upstream in October 2020. The impetus for the company came as a solution to a struggle Taub faced in his daily life.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Throughout my life, regardless of the job I’ve been in, I spend my time making introductions, connecting people and helping friends hire rock-star talent. Like many people, I get energy from helping others,” Taub said. “When COVID-19 hit and the job market took a dive last March, the number of requests for help I received increased 100X. I noticed quickly that my speed of responding to emails and brain capacity to connect the dots became the limiting factor in getting people help,” he added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So it’s no surprise that Upstream started as a product where people could ask for help, and others from the community pitched in. The company now has more than 200 communities (similar to LinkedIn groups), and about 75% of the people who attend an initial Upstream event return for a second one.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I joke that we are building a product that people need because I need it. We feel that we are the right team to solve this problem because we so desperately want it ourselves,” Taub said.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="e9Vk7LtFdn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/accessing-social-groups-through-referrals/">Accessing social groups through referrals</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Accessing social groups through referrals&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/accessing-social-groups-through-referrals/embed/#?secret=e9Vk7LtFdn" data-secret="e9Vk7LtFdn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/upstream-a-miami-based-professional-networking-platform-raises-a-2-75m-seed-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154136</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>API security startup 42Crunch raises $17M Series A led by Energy Impact Partners</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153972</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153972#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 11:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adara Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[APIs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy impact partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firewall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet traffic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulesoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[player]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[qualys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software engineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153972</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With security top of mind in many companies these days, especially given how many staff work at home, there is one area that remains chronically ignored: that of the world of APIs which power all of the platforms we all use every day. Now, a significant player in the cybersecurity of APIs is super-charging its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With security top of mind in many companies these days, especially given how many staff work at home, there is one area that remains chronically ignored: that of the world of APIs which power all of the platforms we all use every day.</p>
<p>Now, a significant player in the cybersecurity of APIs is super-charging its offering.  42Crunch, an API security startup, has raised $17 million in a Series A round led by Energy Impact Partners. Adara Ventures also participated.</p>
<p>42Crunch has a &#8216;micro firewall&#8217; for APIs which aims to protect against attacks listed in the <a href="https://owasp.org/www-project-api-security/">OWASP Top 10 for API Security</a>. It is used by companies such as Mulesoft, Ford Motors, and Qualys.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>CEO and Co-Founder of 42Crunch, Jacques Declas said: “What do the recent data breaches at Tesla, Facebook, and Clubhouse have in common? They all came about due to API vulnerabilities. 83% of internet traffic now comes from APIs but traditional firewall approaches are not adapted to cope with the specific threats that APIs create.”</p>
<p>The three French co-founders came up with the idea after being the number of APIs used by customers proliferate.</p>
<p>The normal approach to firewalls &#8211; relying on patterns and signatures to detect potential incursions &#8211; does not work when it comes to API traffic. 42Crunch claims its platform can individually protect each API, and prevent common cyber-attacks such as injections but also API-specific attacks.</p>
<p>Isabelle Mauny, Co-founder and CTO of 42Crunch, said: “Protecting APIs from threats at runtime is only part of the story. APIs will only be truly secured when security becomes part of the developer’s flow, rather than an afterthought.”</p>
<p>Nazo Moosa, Co-Managing Partner, Energy Impact Partners added: “42Crunch’s ‘shift-left approach’ to the creation of secure-by-design APIs fits strongly with EIP’s vision of protecting global critical infrastructure. The company’s six-digit customer wins last year were catalytic to our decision to lead the round.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153972/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153972</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India tells WhatsApp to withdraw its new policy terms</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/india-tells-whatsapp-to-withdraw-its-new-policy-terms/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/india-tells-whatsapp-to-withdraw-its-new-policy-terms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 10:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Indian government is not pleased with WhatsApp’s new privacy policy. The nation’s Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology (MeitY) has once again directed the Facebook-owned company to withdraw the planned update. In a letter to WhatsApp on Tuesday &#8212; which was read to TechCrunch &#8212; MeitY has given the popular instant messaging provider seven [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Indian government is not pleased with WhatsApp’s new privacy policy. The nation’s Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology (MeitY) has once again directed the Facebook-owned company to withdraw the planned update.</p>
<p>In a letter to WhatsApp on Tuesday &#8212; which was read to TechCrunch &#8212; MeitY has given the popular instant messaging provider seven days to offer a “satisfactory” response. Failure to do so, the ministry warned, will prompt lawful measures.</p>
<p>“In fulfilment of its sovereign responsibility to protect the rights and interests of Indian citizens, the government of India will consider various options available to it under laws in India,” the letter reads.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The letter comes at a time when the ministry is also pursuing a legal case on this matter in the Delhi High Court &#8212; and  the second largest internet market is also<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/india-antitrust-body-orders-investigation-into-whatsapp-privacy-policy-changes/"> conducting an antitrust probe on the subject</a>.</p>
<p>This is not the first time New Delhi has issued a notice to WhatsApp about the new privacy terms. Earlier this year, in a similar letter,&#8221; the Indian government had expressed &#8220;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/india-asks-whatsapp-to-withdraw-new-privacy-policy-expresses-grave-concerns/">grave concerns</a>&#8221; about the planned update.</p>
<p>Following backlash from several governments and users, WhatsApp earlier this year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/whatsapp-delays-new-data-sharing-policy-enforcement-to-may-15/">delayed enforcement of the privacy update</a> by three months &#8212; to May 15. Last week, it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/whatsapp-is-doing-fine-despite-months-long-backlash-over-policy-update/">somewhat relaxed the deadline</a>, though users need to still need to comply to access some basic features.</p>
<p>A spokesperson at the time told TechCrunch that the vast majority of users who had seen the new privacy terms on the app had accepted it.</p>
<p>With over 450 million users, India is WhatsApp’s biggest market by users.</p>
<p>The ministry in its notice this week has asked WhatsApp why it needs to enforce the new changes to its terms of service &#8212; the first major update in years &#8212; to users in India when those in the EU have been exempted from it.</p>
<p>The updated privacy terms grant WhatsApp the consent to share some personal information &#8212; such as their phone number and location &#8212; with parent firm Facebook. WhatsApp has clarified that communication between two individuals remains just as private as before.</p>
<p>“It is not just problematic, but also irresponsible, for WhatsApp to leverage this position to impose unfair terms and conditions on Indian users, particularly those that discriminate against Indian users vis-à-vis users in Europe,” the ministry wrote in the letter.</p>
<p>In response to a petition filed in the Delhi High Court earlier this month, WhatsApp argued that many Indian firms <a href="https://inc42.com/buzz/exclusive-whatsapp-says-zomato-ola-koo-bigbasket-among-others-collect-as-much-or-more-data/">maintain similar policies and share more data</a>. In the petition, WhatsApp had identified food delivery startup Zomato, ride-hailing giant Ola, online grocer BigBasket, as well as Swedish giant Truecaller, which counts India as its largest market by users, as some examples.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/india-tells-whatsapp-to-withdraw-its-new-policy-terms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154573</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PhonePe in talks to acquire Indian app store Indus OS</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/phonepe-in-talks-to-acquire-indian-app-store-indus-os/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/phonepe-in-talks-to-acquire-indian-app-store-indus-os/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 08:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indus os]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paytm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PhonePe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154554</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Walmart-backed Indian payments services firm PhonePe is in advanced stages of talks to acquire Samsung-backed Indus OS, a startup that operates an eponymous third-party Android app store, a source familiar with the matter told TechCrunch. The deal values Noida-headquartered Indus OS at $60 million, the source said, requesting anonymity as the matter is private. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Walmart-backed Indian payments services firm PhonePe is in advanced stages of talks to acquire <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/10/samsung-venture-india-indusos/">Samsung-backed Indus OS</a>, a startup that operates an eponymous third-party Android app store, a source familiar with the matter told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The deal values Noida-headquartered Indus OS at $60 million, the source said, requesting anonymity as the matter is private. The deal has yet to close. PhonePe and Indus OS didn&#8217;t immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>
<p>Indian news outlet Entrackr <a href="https://entrackr.com/2021/05/exclusive-phonepe-set-to-acquire-indus-os-for-60-mn/">first reported</a> about the development.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Indus OS powers several popular third-party Android stores including Samsung&#8217;s Galaxy Store and provides partners with localized content and apps.</p>
<p>Late last year, Indus OS said it offered its partners 400,000 apps in English and 12 Indian languages. The seven-year-old startup, which has raised about $21 million to date and monetizes through ads, has amassed over 100 million users.</p>
<p>The startup plans to launch an app store for individual users once Google begins accepting third-party app stores, another source familiar with the matter said.</p>
<p>It remains unclear why PhonePe is interested in Indus OS&#8217; offering. The Bangalore-based startup has long offered its own mini app store on its app. A handful of firms &#8212; including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/04/google-policy-cut-india-paytm-mini-app-store/">PhonePe rival Paytm</a> &#8212; have either launched or explored launching their own mini app stores in recent months.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/phonepe-in-talks-to-acquire-indian-app-store-indus-os/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154554</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Forecast nabs $19M for its AI-based approach to project management and resource planning</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/forecast-nabs-19m-for-its-ai-based-approach-to-project-management-and-resource-planning/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/forecast-nabs-19m-for-its-ai-based-approach-to-project-management-and-resource-planning/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 08:22:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[project management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154549</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Project management has long been a people-led aspect of the workplace, but that has slowly been changing. Trends in automation, big data, and AI have not only ushered in a new wave of project management applications, but they have led to a stronger culture of people willing to use them. Today, one of the startups [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Project management has long been a people-led aspect of the workplace, but that has slowly been changing. Trends in automation, big data, and AI have not only ushered in a new wave of project management applications, but they have led to a stronger culture of people willing to use them. Today, one of the startups building a platform for the next generation of project management is announcing some funding &#8212; a sign of the traction it&#8217;s getting in the market.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.forecast.app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Forecast</a>, a platform and startup of the same name that uses AI to help with project management and resource planning &#8212; put simply, it uses artificial intelligence to both &#8220;read&#8221; and integrate data from different enterprise applications in order to build a bigger picture of the project and potential outcomes &#8212; has raised $19 million to continue building out its business.</p>
<p>The company plans to use some of the funding to expand to the U.S., and some to continue building out its platform and business, headquartered in London with a development office also in Copenhagen.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This funding, a Series A, comes less than a year after the startup&#8217;s commercial launch, and it was led by Balderton Capital, with previous investors Crane Ventures Partners, SEED Capital and Heartcore also participating.</p>
<p>Forecast closed a seed round in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/01/forecast/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">November 2019</a> and then launched just as the pandemic was kicking off. It was a time when some projects were indeed put on ice, but others that went ahead did so with more caution on all sorts of fronts &#8212; financial, organizational, and technical. It turned out to be a &#8220;right place, right time&#8221; moment for Forecast, a tool that plays directly into providing a technical platform to manage all of that in a better way, and it tripled revenues during the year. Its customers include the likes of the NHS, the Red Cross, Etain and more. It says over 150,000 projects have been created and run through its platform to date.</p>
<p>Project management &#8212; the process of planning what you need to do, assigning resources to the task and tracking how well all of that actually goes to plan &#8212; has long been stuck between a rock and a hard place in the world of work.</p>
<p>It can be essential to getting things done, especially when there are multiple departments or stakeholders involved; yet it&#8217;s forever an inexact science that often does not reflect all the complexities of an actual project, and therefore may not be as useful as it could or should be.</p>
<p>This was a predicament that founder and CEO Dennis Kayser knew all too well, having been an engineer and technical lead on a number of big projects himself. His pedigree is an interesting one: one of his early jobs was as a developer at Varien, where he built the first version of Magento. (The company was <a href="https://inchoo.net/magento/varien-is-now-magento-inc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">eventually rebranded as Magento</a> and then <a href="https://www.ebayinc.com/stories/news/ebay-inc-completes-acquisition-magento/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired by eBay</a>, then <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20151102006822/en/eBay-Completes-Sale-eBay-Enterprise" target="_blank" rel="noopener">spun out</a>, then <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/21/adobe-to-acquire-magento-for-1-6-b/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired again, this time by Adobe</a> for nearly $1.7 billion, and now a huge player in the world of e-commerce tools.) He also spent years as a consultant at IBM, where among other things he helped build and formulate the first versions of ikea.com.</p>
<p>In those and other projects, he saw the pitfalls of project management <em>not</em> done right &#8212; not just in terms of having the right people on a project at the right time, but the resource planning needed, better calculations of financial outcomes in the event of a decision going one way or the other, and so on.</p>
<p>(He didn&#8217;t say this outright, but I&#8217;m sure one of the points of contention was the fact that the first ikea.com site didn&#8217;t actually have any e-commerce in it, just a virtual window display of sorts. That would have been because Ikea wanted to keep people shopping in its stores, away from the efficiency of just buying the one thing you actually need and not the 10 you do not. Yes, there are plenty of ways now of recirculating people to buy more when you select one item for a shopping cart &#8212; something the likes of Amazon has totally mastered &#8212; but this was years ago when there was still even more opportunities for innovation than there are now. All of this is to say that you might very reasonably argue that had there been better project managing and resource planning tools to give forecasts of potential outcomes of one or another route taken, people advocating for a different approach could have made their case better. And maybe Ikea would have jumped on board with digital commerce far sooner than it did.)</p>
<p>&#8220;Typically you get a lot of spreadsheets, people scattered across different tools that include accounting, CRM, Gitlab and more,&#8221; Kayser said.</p>
<p>That became the impetus for trying to build something that can take all of that into account and make a project management tool that &#8212; rather than just being a way of accounting to a higher-up, or reflecting only what someone can be bothered to update in the system &#8212; something that can help a team.</p>
<p>&#8220;Connecting everything into our engine, we leverage data to understand what they are working on and what is the right thing to be working on, what the finances are looking like,&#8221; he continued. &#8220;So if you work in product, you can plan out who is where, and what resourcing you need, what kind of people and skills you require.&#8221; This is a more dynamic progression of some of the other newer tools that are being used for project management today, targeting, in his words, &#8220;people who graduate from Monday and Asana who need something ore robust, either because they have too many people working on a project or because its too complicated, there is just too much stuff to handle.&#8221;</p>
<p>More legacy tools he said that are used include Oracle &#8220;to some degree&#8221; and Mavenlink, which he describes as possibly Forecast&#8217;s closest competitor, &#8220;but its platform is aging.&#8221;</p>
<p>Currently the Forecast platform has <a href="https://www.forecast.app/integrations" target="_blank" rel="noopener">some 26 integrations</a> of popular tools used for projects to produce its insights and intelligence, including Salesforce, Gitlab, Google Calendar, and, as it happens, Asana. But given how fragmented the market is, and the signals one might gain from any number of other resources and apps, I suspect that this list will grow as and when its customers need more supported, or Forecast works out what can be gleaned from different places to paint an even more accurate picture.</p>
<p>The result may not ever replace an actual human project manager, but certainly starts to then look like a &#8220;digital twin&#8221; (a phrase I have been hearing more and more these days) that will definitely help that person, and the rest of the team, work in a smarter way.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are really excited to be an early investor in Forecast,&#8221; said James Wise,  a partner at Balderton Capital, in a statement. “We share their belief that the next generation of SaaS products will be more than just collaboration tools, but use machine learning to actively solve problems for their users. The feedback we got from Forecast&#8217;s customers was quite incredible, both in their praise for the platform and in how much of a difference it had already made to their operations. We look forward to supporting the company to scale this impact going forward.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/forecast-nabs-19m-for-its-ai-based-approach-to-project-management-and-resource-planning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154549</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Payroll automation startup raises $15.6M Series A led by General Catalyst</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/payroll-automation-startup-raises-15-6m-series-a-led-by-general-catalyst/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/payroll-automation-startup-raises-15-6m-series-a-led-by-general-catalyst/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 08:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam Valkin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avid Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric Yuan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Catalyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gocardless]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hustle fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Localglobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matt Robinson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moonfire Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outsourcing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payroll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pento]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Point Nine Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SeedCamp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tom Blomfield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Payroll automation is not exactly the sexiest of startup areas but it’s a pretty decent business. The larger startup in the space is Payfit which has raised upwards of $208.4M to do something that lots of companies find quite painful. But Payfit does a lot of other things as well, potentially leaving it exposed. Now [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Payroll automation is not exactly the sexiest of startup areas but it’s a pretty decent business. The larger startup in the space is Payfit which has raised upwards of $208.4M to do something that lots of companies find quite painful. But Payfit does a lot of other things as well, potentially leaving it exposed. Now a startup aims to come along and hone in on the thorny issue of payroll automation, alone.</p>
<p>Founded by Jonas Bøgh Larsen and Emil Hagbarth Rasmussen, Danish firm <a href="https://www.pento.io/">Pento</a> has raised $15.6 million in a Series A funding led by General Catalyst. Also participating was Avid Ventures and the UK’s LocalGlobe. Existing investors Point Nine Capital, Moonfire Ventures, Hustle Fund, and Seedcamp also took part, alongside angels (see below). This latest funding takes the total raised by Pento to $18.4 million.</p>
<p>The startup claims 700 companies are using it including tech firms Pleo and Cuvva; large hospitality brands (Honest Burgers); and retail and e-commerce brands (Lacoste, Beauty Pie). Pento replaces spreadsheets etc and gives them cloud-based tools, real-time calculations, transparency, and online and telephone support.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Pento co-founder and CEO, Jonas Bøgh Larsen told me: “The biggest process we&#8217;re replacing is payroll outsourcing where companies are outsourcing payroll to an accountant, which the vast majority of companies do in Europe. We automate the entire process from reporting to tax calculations to payments. So, what most other platforms or payable products do is basically just helping you calculate the right taxes and National Insurance, and so on. We also take care of the reporting. We also do payments, and we integrate the product to other HR products.”</p>
<p>Adam Valkin, Managing Director at General Catalyst said: &#8220;Despite being so business-critical, payroll is one of the least digitally advanced services across the globe. It’s also one that has garnered a reputation for being too complex, too convoluted and too out of reach for those who aren’t payroll specialists, leading many to consider expensive outsourcing as the only route to go. Pento dispels this myth because it’s built purely with HR and finance teams in mind, by business leaders who truly understand the frustrations involved. It’s easy-to-use, transparent, flexible, secure and affordable. It’s what payroll should be in a modern company and it represents the future of employee compensation.”</p>
<p>Pento’s angel are from Stripe (Thairu and Diede van Lamoen), Monzo (Tom Blomfield), GoCardless (Matt Robinson), Zoom (Eric Yuan), Cuvva (Freddy Macnamara), Intercom (Des Traynor) and others.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/payroll-automation-startup-raises-15-6m-series-a-led-by-general-catalyst/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154143</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Otter.ai&#8217;s new assistant can automatically transcribe your Zoom meetings</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/otter-ais-new-assistant-can-automatically-transcribe-your-zoom-meetings/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/otter-ais-new-assistant-can-automatically-transcribe-your-zoom-meetings/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Assistant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hybrid office]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meeting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meetings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Office]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[otter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[otter.ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[productivity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Speaker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web conferencing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A.I.-powered voice transcription service Otter.ai wants to make it even easier for its business users to record their meetings. The company is today introducing a new feature, Otter Assistant, which can automatically join the Zoom meetings on your calendar, transcribe the conversations, and share the notes with other participants. Though Otter.ai is already integrated with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A.I.-powered voice transcription service <a href="https://otter.ai/">Otter.ai</a> wants to make it even easier for its business users to record their meetings. The company is today introducing a new feature, Otter Assistant, which can automatically join the Zoom meetings on your calendar, transcribe the conversations, and share the notes with other participants. Though Otter.ai is already integrated with Zoom, the assistant is designed to make using transcription something you don&#8217;t have to constantly remember to enable at the meeting&#8217;s start or stop at the end, while also serving as a place where participants can collaborate by asking questions, sharing photos and more, as the meeting is underway.</p>
<p>The feature also works around the earlier limitation with Zoom, where only the meeting host could use the Otter.ai integration directly.</p>
<p>The idea to automate meeting transcription makes sense for the remote work environment <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/boosted-by-the-pandemic-meeting-transcription-service-otter-ai-raises-50m/">created by the pandemic</a>, where people have been splitting their time between work, parenting, homeschooling and other duties. This can often lead to meetings where users are pulled away and miss things that had been said. That&#8217;s one area where Otter.ai can help. But it can also help with issues like overlapping meetings, or larger meetings were only a few topics are directly relevant to your work &#8212; but where you&#8217;d like to be able to review the rest of the meeting discussion later, instead of in real-time.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>To use the new Otter Assistant, users first synchronize their Google Calendar or Microsoft Calendar with Otter&#8217;s service. The assistant will then automatically join all Zoom meetings going forward, where it appears as an additional meeting participant, for transparency&#8217;s sake.</p>
<p>The assistant also posts a link to the transcription in the Zoom chat for everyone to access. In other words, this is not a feature to use to skip meetings without your boss knowing &#8212; it&#8217;s designed for those times when everyone has already agreed the meeting will be transcribed.</p>
<p>As the meeting continues, attendees can use Otter&#8217;s live transcript to highlight key parts, add photos, and make notes. They can also ask questions via the commenting feature, as opposed to speaking up &#8212; which may be helpful if you&#8217;re in a noisy place at the time of the meeting.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/jzbRLczOk1w?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Once the assistant is enabled, you don&#8217;t have to remember to turn on Otter.ai for each meeting, and you can even use your headphones to listen to the meeting in progress. The Otter Assistant will still be able to record both sides of the conversation.</p>
<p>However, you are able to turn Otter Assistant off on a per-meeting basis via the &#8220;My Agenda&#8221; section on the Otter website, which will include new toggles next to each meeting you have scheduled.</p>
<p>When meetings wrap, you can also have Otter.ai configured to automatically share the meeting notes with all the attendees.</p>
<p>The Otter Assistant is available to Otter.ai Business users, which are <a href="https://otter.ai/pricing">upgraded plans </a>that start at $20 per month, and include features like two-factor authentication, SOC2 compliance, advanced search, export, custom vocabulary, shared speaker identification, centralized data and billing, and more.</p>
<p>To date, Otter.ai says it has transcribed over 150 million meetings, up from 100 million <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/a-i-powered-transcription-service-otter-ai-can-now-record-from-google-meet/">in the beginning of 2021</a> . The company doesn&#8217;t provide details on its total subscriber base, but did note earlier it saw a sizable 8x increase in revenues in 2020, leading up to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/boosted-by-the-pandemic-meeting-transcription-service-otter-ai-raises-50m/">its $50 million Series B, announced in February.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/otter-ais-new-assistant-can-automatically-transcribe-your-zoom-meetings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153737</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gillmor Gang: Party Line</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/gillmor-gang-party-line/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/gillmor-gang-party-line/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 03:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brent Leary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denis Pombriant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frank radice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keith Teare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Markman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154527</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the early days of social media, all things seemed possible. Twitter was this weird reboot of blogs, with a social layer atop an RSS feed that gave authority to last in/first out musings by providing data not just about read or unread but shared by who. You could take that authority data and rank [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/BTHUNvsf3jM?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>In the early days of social media, all things seemed possible. Twitter was this weird reboot of blogs, with a social layer atop an RSS feed that gave authority to last in/first out musings by providing data not just about read or unread but shared by who. You could take that authority data and rank posts by who shared them and who followed those people and what they in turn recommended. Although this was mostly ignored at the time by vendors and writers looking for a viral eyeball payoff, for those looking to support new talent there was something more valuable than reach.</p>
<p>Something like that could happen with Clubhouse and newsletters. On this week&#8217;s edition of the Gillmor Gang, recorded just over a week ago, we talk about Clubhouse, the Facebook advisory board and its siderstep of the Trump deplatforming, and early stuff I can never quite remember because the show always takes a bit too long to fully get up to speed. I&#8217;d apologize for this, but the apology would take too long to reach sincerity sufficient to not make things worse. This by the way is why newsletters exist — to save time scouring the Web and cable news for a sufficient return on investment, as in &#8220;well there&#8217;s another [duration] I&#8217;ll never get back.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Temporal time displacement suffered a serious blow at the hands of HBO Max and its strategy of releasing theater-less blockbusters on the streaming network in 2021 but only intermittently moving forward. As the CDC noted in a confusing but welcome announcement this past Thursday, vaccines are making possible a safe return to theaters in the near future. Soon it will be possible to be confused about the movie Tenet on the big screen. It is not a spoiler to say that Tenet is all about moving through time in the normal forward but also the incomprehensible backward. Time travel stories are invariably brought to a complete standstill when how this works is explained. The only thing harder to do is find a way to end a Saturday Night Live sketch. The only rationale appears to be that the sketch is over, like a bad pun not even worthy of a groan.</p>
<p>Speaking as I was of Clubhouse, we tried it out last Wednesday with Keith Teare and a brief drive-by from Brent Leary. Somehow we were in Hallway mode, which actually captured the feel of the thing nicely. Being in experimental mood, I added anyone who showed up as a speaker whether they wanted to or not. The result felt like a remnant of my childhood in Woodstock, NY, where we were part of a party line with nearby neighbors. You&#8217;d be talking with someone and suddenly realize someone else was on the line, interrupting to basically say they needed to make a more important call. Awkward but oddly exhilarating, as you realized the potential of not only lurking but lurked. I&#8217;m not sure how this is useful or not, but remember that @mentions and retweets were invented not by Twitter but by users. And using Twitter like a party line turned out to be the true superpower of the social network. On Clubhouse, if no one had anything to say, they were quiet. It was very peaceful.</p>
<p>Another pleasant surprise was a listener/speaker from Manchester, England who professed to being a longtime listener to the Gang. He and Keith, also from Manchester, started talking about Manchester United, an important football team I know nothing about. An old friend from the conference circuit popped in and our producer/director Tina Chase Gillmor somehow started up a conversation about my alleged style as a writer. Talking about me is easily my least favorite thing to do, but having others do the job is high on my most list. It&#8217;s also acutely reminiscent of the tech conference hallway conversation stubbed out by the pandemic. I now started to understand why Hallway mode was so-called. It&#8217;s the grease of the wheel business rides on. Follow the Gillmor Gang club on Clubhouse and you&#8217;ll be notified about our next experiment.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><strong><em>from the <a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang/issues/gillmor-gang-newsletter-revue-7-560606"> Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center">__________________</p>
<p>The Gillmor Gang — Frank Radice, Michael Markman, Keith Teare, Denis Pombriant, Brent Leary and Steve Gillmor. Recorded live Friday, May 7, 2021.</p>
<p>Produced and directed by Tina Chase Gillmor @tinagillmor</p>
<p>@fradice, @mickeleh, @denispombriant, @kteare, @brentleary, @stevegillmor, @gillmorgang</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang">Subscribe to the new Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></strong> and join the backchannel <a href="https://t.me/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> on Telegram.</p>
<p><a href="http://facebook.com/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Gillmor Gang on Facebook</a> … and here’s our sister show <a href="http://facebook.com/g3show" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">G3 on Facebook</a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="169" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2012361" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/gillmor-gang-party-line/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154527</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kia&#8217;s fast-charging EV6 electric crossover is coming to the U.S. in early 2022</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/kias-fast-charging-ev6-electric-crossover-is-coming-to-the-u-s-in-early-2022/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/kias-fast-charging-ev6-electric-crossover-is-coming-to-the-u-s-in-early-2022/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 02:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EV6]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyundai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154500</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Kia EV6, an all-electric crossover that kicks off the automaker&#8217;s Plan S strategy to shift away from internal combustion engines and toward EVs, will come to the U.S. early next year, the company said Tuesday evening during a live streamed event in New York. The EV6 is the first dedicated battery-electric vehicle to built [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Kia EV6, an all-electric crossover that kicks off the automaker&#8217;s Plan S strategy to shift away from internal combustion engines and toward EVs, will come to the U.S. early next year, the company said Tuesday evening during a live streamed event in New York.</p>
<p>The EV6 is the first dedicated battery-electric vehicle to built on its new Electric-Global Modular Platform, a platform that is shared with Hyundai and Genesis as part of the Hyundai Motor Group. The EGM-platform is the underlying foundation of the new Hyundai Ioniq 5 compact crossover. And it&#8217;s one of 11 electric vehicles that Kia plans to deliver globally by 2026.</p>
<p>Kia said its new dedicated battery electric vehicles will all start with the &#8220;EV&#8221; prefix. A number will follow &#8220;EV&#8221; to indicate the vehicle&#8217;s position in the lineup. That puts the EV6 somewhere in the middle of its upcoming lineup.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While the global debut held earlier this year provided <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/kias-electric-vehicle-plans-take-shape-with-ev6-teaser-new-naming-strategy/">many of the details</a>, a few new nuggets of information were shared, including that customers can make reservations for 1,500 first edition versions of the EV6 beginning June 3. The automaker has not revealed pricing for any of the vehicle trims.</p>
<p>The EV6 First Edition will be similar to the base model with lots of techie add-ons, including an augmented reality head-up display, remote smart parking assist feature, 14-speaker Meridian audio system and a two-year subscription to SiriusXM. There will be notable mechanical and exterior differences as well, including a wide sunroof, 20-inch wheels, dual-motor AWD and a 77.4 kWh battery.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2154505" style="width: 1360px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/17379_2022_EV6.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2154505" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2154505 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/17379_2022_EV6.jpg" alt="" width="1350" height="900" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/17379_2022_EV6.jpg 1350w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/17379_2022_EV6.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/17379_2022_EV6.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/17379_2022_EV6.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/17379_2022_EV6.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/17379_2022_EV6.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1350px) 100vw, 1350px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2154505" class="wp-caption-text">2022 EV6 <strong>Image credit</strong>: Kia</p></div></p>
<h2>Nuts and bolts</h2>
<p>Kia designed the EV6 to look and perform like a roomy sports car. The four-door crossover has a low front end that moves up into a roofline, giving it coupe-like profile. The LED headlights have a segmented pattern and the traditional grille found on internal combustion engine vehicles is gone.</p>
<p>The EV6 has the same 114.2-inch wheelbase as the Kia Telluride, which gives some sense of its size.</p>
<p>The Kia EV6 will come with two Nickel-Cobalt-Manganese battery pack options — a 58 kWh or 77.4 kWh — with the larger one providing a targeted range of 300 miles. The vehicle is offered in both rear-wheel and AWD, which depending on the electric motor and battery configuration delivers between 167 and 313 horsepower. The EV6 GT, an AWD model that comes with the larger battery and powerful front and rear electric motors, delivers 567 horsepower. The GT model, which won&#8217;t be available until late 2022, can travel from 0 to 60 mph in less than 3.5 seconds.</p>
<p>Perhaps more importantly, is that the vehicle supports 400-volt and 800-volt DC charging. Kia claims that 800v DC fast charging from a 350-kW charger can add up to 210 miles to the battery in under 18 minutes.</p>
<p>Kia loaded up on various charging features. The EV6 has an onboard 11 kW charger for Level 2 charging that will power up the battery in about seven hours. There&#8217;s also what Kia calls vehicle-to-load functionality, which is jargony way of saying the EV6 can be a power source for appliances, tools and devices like a computer. It works by taking electricity from the battery to a charging control unit, which provides 1900 watts of power.</p>
<p>The user is able to plug into that power via a 100v outlet located in a socket on front of second row seat base. If the battery is fully charged, Kia says power  can be drawn from the vehicle for 36 or more consecutive hours. It can also be used to charge vehicle-to-vehicle, albeit at 1.1 kW, which is a glacial pace that is equivalent to a 110V charger.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2154518" style="width: 1360px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/17351_2022_EV6.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2154518" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2154518 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/17351_2022_EV6.jpg" alt="Kia EV6" width="1350" height="900" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/17351_2022_EV6.jpg 1350w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/17351_2022_EV6.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/17351_2022_EV6.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/17351_2022_EV6.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/17351_2022_EV6.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/17351_2022_EV6.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1350px) 100vw, 1350px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2154518" class="wp-caption-text">2022 Kia EV6 <strong>Image credit</strong>: Kia</p></div></p>
<p>There are numerous other driver assistance, safety and in-car tech features as well. Inside the vehicle, are two 12-inch screens that form a curved display and house the instrument cluster and infotainment center. There is Bluetooth functionality and wireless smartphone charging, which has become standard fare in modern vehicles.</p>
<p>For an extra fee, customers can add on a Wi-FI hotspot and the ability to update the maps and infotainment system software wirelessly. Other features include a in-car commerce feature called Kia Pay, a stolen vehicle recovery tracker, smartwatch accessibility that provides battery status, vehicle notifications and certain vehicle control through Apple and Android smartwatches and connected car functions for weather and routing.</p>
<p>Customers are also able to use Amazon Alexa or Google Assistant through a smart speaker integration to remotely control vehicle functions such as remote start.</p>
<p>Four cameras outside of the vehicle give a 360-degree view and help with to detect obstructions while parking along with several other safety features including a safe exit assist that alerts the driver or passengers opening the door to not exit if the system spots approaching traffic.</p>
<p>There is also 21 standard active advanced driver assistance systems including a feature that keeps a set distance from a car in front and centers the EV6 in the lane. A newer version of this feature will be able to assist with assist with lane changes and adjust the lateral position of the car within the lane, according to Kia.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WuBpC8yv7Z"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/automakers-suppliers-and-startups-see-growing-market-for-in-vehicle-ar-vr-applications/">Automakers, suppliers and startups see growing market for in-vehicle AR/VR applications</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Automakers, suppliers and startups see growing market for in-vehicle AR/VR applications&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/automakers-suppliers-and-startups-see-growing-market-for-in-vehicle-ar-vr-applications/embed/#?secret=WuBpC8yv7Z" data-secret="WuBpC8yv7Z" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/kias-fast-charging-ev6-electric-crossover-is-coming-to-the-u-s-in-early-2022/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154500</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UTEC, one of Asia&#8217;s largest deep-tech investment firms, launches new $275M fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/utec-one-of-asias-largest-deep-tech-investment-firms-launches-new-275m-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/utec-one-of-asias-largest-deep-tech-investment-firms-launches-new-275m-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deep tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The University of Tokyo Edge Capital Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UTEC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154452</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The University of Tokyo Edge Capital Partners (UTEC), a deep-tech investment firm, announced the first close of its fifth fund, which is expected to total 30 billion JPY (or about $275 million USD) by June 2021. UTEC currently has about $780 million in total assets under management, and says this makes it one of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.ut-ec.co.jp/english/">The University of Tokyo Edge Capital Partners (UTEC)</a>, a deep-tech investment firm, announced the first close of its fifth fund, which is expected to total 30 billion JPY (or about $275 million USD) by June 2021. UTEC currently has about $780 million in total assets under management, and says this makes it one of the largest venture capital funds focused on science and tech in Japan, and one of the largest deep-tech funds in Asia.</p>
<p>UTEC is an independent firm that works closely with universities. It is associated with The University of Tokyo (UTokyo), where it has a partnership with its Technology Licensing Office (TLO) to spin off and invest in companies that originated as research projects. It has also worked with researchers from Waseda University, Kyoto University, Stanford, UC Berkeley, Carnegie Mellon, Cambridge University, the National University of Singapore and the Indian Institute of Technology, among other institutions.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2154462" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/UTEC-Global-Portfolio.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2154462" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2154462" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/UTEC-Global-Portfolio.png" alt="A map showing UTEC's deep-tech investments around the world" width="1024" height="562" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/UTEC-Global-Portfolio.png 1362w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/UTEC-Global-Portfolio.png?resize=150,82 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/UTEC-Global-Portfolio.png?resize=300,165 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/UTEC-Global-Portfolio.png?resize=768,421 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/UTEC-Global-Portfolio.png?resize=680,373 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/UTEC-Global-Portfolio.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2154462" class="wp-caption-text">UTEC&#8217;s deep-tech investments around the world</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Broadly speaking, UTEC focuses on three areas: healthcare and life sciences, information technology and physical sciences and engineering. More specifically, it is looking for tech that addresses some of the most important issues in Japan, including an aging population, labor shortage and the digitization of legacy industries.</p>
<p>“UTEC 5 will allow us to provide more funds from seed/early to pre-IPO/M&amp;A stages in Japan and worldwide, on a wider scale and in a more consistent manner,” said managing partner and president Tomotaka Goji in a statement. “I believe this will further help our startups expand to address the global issues of humankind.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Uq3R7dxHKZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/11/what-do-we-mean-when-we-talk-about-deep-tech/">What do we mean when we talk about deep tech?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What do we mean when we talk about deep tech?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/11/what-do-we-mean-when-we-talk-about-deep-tech/embed/#?secret=Uq3R7dxHKZ" data-secret="Uq3R7dxHKZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The firm also partners with other funds, including Arch Venture Partners and Blume Ventures, to find investment opportunities around the world.</p>
<p>UTEC&#8217;s portfolio already includes more than 80 Japanese startups and 30 startups from other places, including the United States, India, Southeast Asia and Europe. So far, 25 of its investments have exited. Thirteen went public and now have an aggregated market cap of about $15 billion, and 12 were through mergers and acquisitions.</p>
<p>Some of its exits include 908 Devices, a mass spectrometry company that <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/research-device-developer-908-devices-raises-range-to-%2418-to-%2419-ahead-of-%24116-million-ipo">went public on Nasdaq last year</a>; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/18/fyusion-is-bringing-3d-vision-technologies-to-a-device-near-you/">Fyusion</a>, a computer vision startup <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/cox-automotive-acquires-fyusion-301200890.html">acquired by Cox Automotive</a>; and Phyzios, which was <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/acquisition/google-acquires-phyzios--1e577118">acquired by Google in 2013</a>.</p>
<p>About half of UTEC&#8217;s portfolio are university spin-offs. For companies that originated in academic research, UTEC supports their commercialization by helping hire crucial talent, including executive positions, business development and go-to-market strategies. The firm’s first check size is about $500,000 to $5 million, and it also usually provides follow-on capital.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Pti4ELdTYS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/commercializing-deep-tech-startups-a-practical-guide-for-founders-and-investors/">Commercializing deep tech startups: A practical guide for founders and investors</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Commercializing deep tech startups: A practical guide for founders and investors&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/commercializing-deep-tech-startups-a-practical-guide-for-founders-and-investors/embed/#?secret=Pti4ELdTYS" data-secret="Pti4ELdTYS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“We typically double-down on our investment in subsequent funding rounds of the company and can invest up to about $23 million per company over its lifecycle,” UTEC principal Kiran Mysore, who leads their global AI investments, told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>UTEC’s other investments include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/video/bionicm-powered-prosthetics/">personal mobility robotics</a> company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/german-bionic-raises-20m-led-by-samsung-for-exoskeleton-tech-to-supercharge-human-labor/">BionicM</a>, which started at UTokyo and spatial intelligence solution developer Locix, spun-off from UC Berkeley. The firm also helps startups collaborate with academic institutions. For example, Indian biotech <a href="https://bugworksresearch.com/">Bugworks</a> collaborates with the Tokyo Institute of Technology and Japanese industrial robotics startup <a href="https://www.mujin.co.jp/en/">Mujin</a> now works with Carnegie Mellon.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4r6lCPYVDx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/founded-by-australias-national-science-agency-main-sequence-launches-250m-aud-deep-tech-fund/">Founded by Australia&#8217;s national science agency, Main Sequence launches $250M AUD deep tech fund</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Founded by Australia&#8217;s national science agency, Main Sequence launches $250M AUD deep tech fund&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/founded-by-australias-national-science-agency-main-sequence-launches-250m-aud-deep-tech-fund/embed/#?secret=4r6lCPYVDx" data-secret="4r6lCPYVDx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/utec-one-of-asias-largest-deep-tech-investment-firms-launches-new-275m-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154452</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Financing for students startup StudentFinance raises $5.3M seed from Giant and Armilar</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/financing-for-students-startup-studentfinance-raises-5-3m-seed-from-giant-and-armilar/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/financing-for-students-startup-studentfinance-raises-5-3m-seed-from-giant-and-armilar/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 23:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Armilar Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bolt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ed Vaizey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Giant Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Income Share Agreements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sabadell Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SeedCamp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[StudentFinance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uniplaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154236</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fintech startup StudentFinance &#8212; which allows educational institutions to offer success-based financing for students &#8212; has raised a $5.3 million (€4.5 million) seed round co-led by Giant Ventures and Armilar Venture Partners. It’s now raised $6.6 million total, to date. StudentFinance launched in Spain first, followed by Germany and Finland, with the U.K. planned this [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Fintech startup <a href="https://www.studentfinance.com/">StudentFinance</a> &#8212; which allows educational institutions to offer success-based financing for students &#8212; has raised a $5.3 million (€4.5 million) seed round co-led by Giant Ventures and Armilar Venture Partners. It’s now raised $6.6 million total, to date.</p>
<p>StudentFinance launched in Spain first, followed by Germany and Finland, with the U.K. planned this year. Existing investors Mustard Seed Maze and Seedcamp, along with Sabadell Venture Capital, also participated.</p>
<p>The startup, which launched at the beginning of 2020, provides the tech back end for institutions to offer flexible payment plans in the form of ISAs (income-share agreements). It also provides data intelligence on the employment market to predict job demand.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It now has 35 education providers signed up, managing over €5 million worth of ISAs. It also works with upskilling platforms including Ironhack and Le Wagon. StudentFinance’s competitors include (in the USA) Blair, Leif, Vemo Education, Chancen (Germany-based) and EdAid (U.K.-based).</p>
<p>As for why StudentFinance stands out from those companies, Mariano Kostelec, co-founder and CEO of StudentFinance, said: “StudentFinance is the only platform in this space providing the full end-to-end, cross-border infrastructure to deliver ISAs for students whilst helping to plug the growing skills gap. Not only do we provide the infrastructure to support the ISA financing model, but we also provide data intelligence on the employment market and a career-as-a-service platform that focuses on placing students in the right job. We are creating an equilibrium between supply and demand.”</p>
<p>With an ISA, students only start paying back tuition once they are employed and earning above a minimum income threshold, with payments structured as a percentage of their earnings. This makes it a &#8220;success-based model&#8221;, says StudentFinance, which shifts the risk away from the students. They are likely to be popular as workers need to reskill with the onset of digitization and the pandemic’s effects.</p>
<p>The startup was founded in 2019 by Kostelec, Marta Palmeiro, Sergio Pereira and Miguel Santo Amaro. Kostelec and Santo Amaro previously built Uniplaces, which raised $30 million as a student housing platform in Europe.</p>
<p>Cameron Mclain, managing partner of Giant Ventures, commented: “What StudentFinance has built empowers any educational institution to offer ISAs as an alternative to upfront tuition or student loans, broadening access to education and opportunity.”</p>
<p>Duarte Mineiro, partner at Armilar Venture Partners, commented: “StudentFinance is a great opportunity to invest in because aside from its very compelling core purpose, this is a sound business where its economics are backed by a solid proprietary software technology.”</p>
<p>Sia Houchangnia, partner at Seedcamp, commented: “The need for reskilling the workforce has never been as acute as it is today and we believe StudentFinance has an important role to play in tackling this societal challenge.”</p>
<p>Angel backers include investors, which includes: Victoria van Lennep (founder of Lendable); Martin Villig (founder of Bolt); Ed Vaizey (the U.K.’s longest-serving Culture &amp; Digital Economy Minister); Firestartr (U.K.-based early-stage VC); Serge Chiaramonte (U.K. fintech investor); and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/financing-for-students-startup-studentfinance-raises-5-3m-seed-from-giant-and-armilar/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154236</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
