<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 22:01:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>01 Advisors, the venture firm of Dick Costolo and Adam Bain, has closed fund two with $325 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/01-advisors-the-venture-firm-of-dick-costolo-and-adam-bain-has-closed-fund-two-with-325-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/01-advisors-the-venture-firm-of-dick-costolo-and-adam-bain-has-closed-fund-two-with-325-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 21:46:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2113199</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dick Costolo and Adam Bain, renowned early Twitter execs who served as company&#8217;s CEO and its chief operating officer, respectively, have quietly closed a second venture fund just one-and-a-half years after disclosing they&#8217;d secured $135 million for a debut fund under their firm, 01 Advisors. According to an SEC filing, they wrapped up their second [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Dick Costolo and Adam Bain, renowned early Twitter execs who served as company&#8217;s CEO and its chief operating officer, respectively, have quietly closed a second venture fund just one-and-a-half years after disclosing they&#8217;d secured $135 million for a debut fund under their firm, <a href="https://01a.com/">01 Advisors</a>.</p>
<p>According to an<a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1841862/000184186221000001/xslFormDX01/primary_doc.xml"> SEC filing</a>, they wrapped up their second fund late last week with $325 million in capital commitments from 81 investors.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve reached out to the firm and hope to share more soon. In the meantime, its strategy appears to center around more concentrated bets in both the consumer and enterprise spheres &#8212; with checks going out both early and sometimes later in a startup&#8217;s trajectory.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Among these recipients is <a href="https://literati.com/">Literati</a>, a nearly five-year-old, Austin, Tex.-based book club subscription service that raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/literati-raises-40m-for-its-book-club-platform/">$40 million</a> in Series B funding in January led by Felicis Ventures; <a href="https://tipalti.com/">Tipalti</a>, a 10-year-old, Israel-based company that develops automation software for global payments and raised $150 million in Series E funding at a <a href="https://www.calcalistech.com/ctech/articles/0,7340,L-3854791,00.html">$2 billion valuation</a> back in October (01 Advisors joined as a follow-on investor); and <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/spoton">SpotOn Transact</a>, a payments software startup that raised <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/spoton-raises-50m-to-help-smbs-operate-more-efficiently/">$50 million</a> in Series B funding last year led by 01 Advisors. (Worth noting: the company raised a $60 million <a href="https://finledger.com/2020/09/23/payments-software-startup-spoton-raises-60-million-to-help-smbs/">Series C round</a> just six months later. DST Global led that next round, with participation from 01 Advisors and others.)</p>
<p>In fact, numerous of the outfit&#8217;s investments have hit the gas during the pandemic, including the San Francisco-based mental health and wellness platform <a href="https://www.modernhealth.com/">Modern Health</a>, which last week announced <a href="https://www.mobihealthnews.com/news/modern-health-raises-another-74m-meet-employers-demand-mental-health-benefits">$74 million</a> in Series D funding just a few months after announcing $51 million Series C funding. The startup, reportedly now valued at $1.17 billion, has raised roughly $170 million to date; 01 Advisors has joined the last two rounds.</p>
<p>01 Advisors has itself largely remained the same size since it publicly launched in August 2019, years after Costolo and Bain had begun investing in startups on an individual and joint basis.</p>
<p>In addition to Costolo and Bain and Dave Rivinus, who spent four years in corporate development and finance at Twitter and is also a founding partner of the firm, Kelly Kovacs is a partner at the firm. Kovacs was Costolo&#8217;s chief of staff at Twitter before joining Color Genomics in a similar capacity, then founding her own startup meant to empower executive assistants. She joined 01 Advisors full time in 2018.</p>
<p>Jenny Pater is meanwhile the firm&#8217;s operations manager.</p>
<p>01 Advisors did recently list a position for a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/2402733898/?refId=mQHT%2BbwWSZKMXf4ODhRcqw%3D%3D">senior associate</a>.</p>
<p>Costolo, who great up in Troy, Michigan, found himself in the <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/abrambrown/2020/10/01/some-business-leader-should-face-a-firing-squad-former-twitter-ceo-dick-costolo-suggests-in-angry-tweet/?sh=4f51d65d7b94">headlines</a> in October when he fired off an incendiary tweet about the decision of Coinbase founder and CEO Brian Armstrong to publicly discourage employee activism and political discussions at work, a stance that drove <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/09/brian-armstrongs-new-problem-60-plus/">at least 60 employees</a> to take a severance package offered to them afterward.</p>
<p>While some business leaders were quick to praise Armstrong, Costolo wasn&#8217;t shy about hiding his disgust over Armstrong&#8217;s position. “Me-first capitalists who think you can separate society from business are going to be the first people lined up against the wall and shot in the revolution,” he tweeted. “I&#8217;ll happily provide video commentary.”</p>
<p>Bain, a long-suffering Browns fan (like all native Clevelanders), has meanwhile been busy, too. In addition to scouting for startups, he now sits on the public company boards of both the real estate tech outfit Opendoor and the space tourism company Virgin Galactic.</p>
<p>01 Advisors served as a co-sponsor of the SPAC that took Opendoor public, along with investor Chamath Palihapitiya. Palihapitiya also spun up the blank-check company that took public Virgin Galactic and the company invited Bain to be a director as that merger was coming together.</p>
<p>Earlier bets by the pair &#8212; as angel investors &#8212; include the corporate travel site TripActions and the connected fitness startup Tonal.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/01-advisors-the-venture-firm-of-dick-costolo-and-adam-bain-has-closed-fund-two-with-325-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2113199</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>After raising $150 million in equity and debt, Nature&#8217;s Fynd opens its fungus food for pre-orders</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/after-raising-150-million-in-equity-and-debt-natures-fynd-opens-its-fungus-food-for-pre-orders/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/after-raising-150-million-in-equity-and-debt-natures-fynd-opens-its-fungus-food-for-pre-orders/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 21:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakthrough Energy Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fermentation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generation investment management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat substitutes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2113144</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nature’s Fynd, the food technology company with a new food offering cultivated from fungus found in the wilds of Yellowstone National Park, is releasing its first products for pre-order.  Pitching both a non-dairy cream cheese and meatless breakfast patties, Nature&#8217;s Fynd had managed to attract some serious investors including Al Gore&#8217;s Generation Investment Management and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.naturesfynd.com/">Nature’s Fynd</a>, the food technology company with a new food offering cultivated from fungus found in the wilds of Yellowstone National Park, is releasing its first products for pre-order. </span></p>
<p>Pitching both a non-dairy cream cheese and meatless breakfast patties, Nature&#8217;s Fynd had managed to attract some serious investors including Al Gore&#8217;s Generation Investment Management and the Bill Gates-backed investment fund, Breakthrough Energy Ventures. The company most recently<a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/natures-fynd-raises-80m-series-b-for-alternative-protein/"> raised $80 million in its last round of funding</a>.</p>
<p>The company is<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/20/from-lab-grown-meat-to-fermented-fungus-heres-what-corporate-food-vcs-are-serving-up/"> part of a wave of innovative products</a> using a range of bacteria, fungi, and plants to create meat alternatives.  Last year, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/17/alternative-protein-companies-have-raised-a-whopping-1-5-billion-through-july-of-this-year/">companies developing meat alternatives raised well over $1 billion in financing</a> and investors show no sign of slowing down in their commitments to the industry.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The commercial launch of the Fy Breakfast Bundle, vegan and non-GMO alternatives to traditional breakfast products will be the first commercial test for Nature&#8217;s Fynd as it looks to go to market.</p>
<p>These limited release bundles are available for $14,99 plus shipping, according to the company, and the products will be available across the 48 contiguous U.S. states.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s product is grown using fermentation technology to cultivate the bacteria that Nature&#8217;s Fynd&#8217;s chief scientists discovered during their research into organisms around Yellowstone National Park.</p>
<p>Nature&#8217;s Fynd touts the resilience and efficiency of the microbe it discovered, leading to a more sustainable production process that uses a fraction of the land, water, and energy resources that traditional animal husbandry requires, the company said.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We choose optimism so that we can find a way to do more with less. Using our novel liquid-air surface fermentation technology, we&#8217;re creating a range of sustainable foods that nourish our bodies and nurture our planet for generations to come. We&#8217;re really excited to be at the beginning of this journey with the launch of our first-ever limited release of Fy Breakfast Bundles,” said Nature’s Fynd CEO Thomas Jonas. “We’ve deeply studied our consumers and we know that Fy’s unique versatility, which delivers great tasting meat and dairy alternatives for every occasion, is highly appealing.” </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2113216" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2113216" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2113216" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CEO-Thomas-Jonas-1.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CEO-Thomas-Jonas-1.jpg 4000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CEO-Thomas-Jonas-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CEO-Thomas-Jonas-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CEO-Thomas-Jonas-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CEO-Thomas-Jonas-1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CEO-Thomas-Jonas-1.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CEO-Thomas-Jonas-1.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CEO-Thomas-Jonas-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2113216" class="wp-caption-text">Nature&#8217;s Fynd chief executive, Thomas Jonas. Image Credit: <a href="https://www.naturesfynd.com/">Nature&#8217;s Fynd</a></p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/after-raising-150-million-in-equity-and-debt-natures-fynd-opens-its-fungus-food-for-pre-orders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2113144</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>From dorm rooms to board rooms: How universities are promoting entrepreneurship</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/from-dorm-rooms-to-board-rooms-how-universities-are-promoting-entrepreneurship/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/from-dorm-rooms-to-board-rooms-how-universities-are-promoting-entrepreneurship/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 19:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CalTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Manufacturing and Supply Chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC News Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[harvard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intellectual property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stephen elop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uc-berkeley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ucla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yale]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2112679</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An increasing number of higher education institutions are investing in entrepreneurial pipelines that help students launch startups after graduation.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Earlier this year, 15 top U.S. universities joined forces to launch a one-stop shop where corporations and startups can discover and license patents.</p>
<p>Working in concert, Brown, Caltech, Columbia, Cornell, Harvard, the University of Illinois, Michigan, Northwestern, Penn, Princeton, SUNY Binghamton, UC Berkeley, UCLA, the University of Southern California and Yale formed The University Technology Licensing Program LLC (UTLP)  to create a centralized pool of licensable IP.</p>
<p>The UTLP arrives as more higher education institutions are beefing up their investment in the entrepreneurial pipeline to help more students launch startups after graduation. In some instances, schools serve as accelerators, providing students with resources and helping them connect with VCs to find seed funding.</p>
<p>To get a better look at the new program and more insight into the university-to-startup pipeline, we spoke to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Jennifer Dyer, executive director, <a href="https://stevens.usc.edu/jennifer-dyer/">USC Stevens Center for Innovation</a></li>
<li>Orin Herskowitz, senior vice president of Intellectual Property and Tech Transfer, <a href="https://techventures.columbia.edu/orin-herskowitz">Columbia University</a></li>
<li>Marc De Leeuw, partner, <a href="https://www.sullcrom.com/lawyers/Marc-DeLeeuw">Sullivan &amp; Cromwell LLP</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h2><strong>The UTLP initiative seems to be more focused on licensing IP to existing companies, rather than accelerating university startups.</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Orin Herskowitz:</strong> The UTLP effort is really much more about licensing to the somewhat broken interface between universities and very large companies in the tech space when it comes to licensing intellectual property. But I know USC and Columbia and many of our peers, especially over the last three to seven years, have pivoted in a massive way to helping our faculty students fulfill their entrepreneurial dreams and launch startups around this exciting university technology.</p>
<h2><strong>The word “broken” jumped out at me. Historically, what has the problem been?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Orin Herskowitz:</strong> Universities have traditionally been a source of amazing, life-saving and life-improving inventions, for decades. There&#8217;s been a ton of new drugs and medical devices, cybersecurity improvements, and search engines, like Google, that have come out of universities over the years, that were federally funded and developed in the labs, and then licensed to either a startup or the industry. And that&#8217;s been great. At least over the last couple of decades, that interface has worked really, really well in some fields, but less well in others. So, in the life sciences, in energy, in advanced materials, in those industries, a lot of the time, these innovations that end up having a huge impact on society are based really on one or two or three core eureka moments. There&#8217;s like one or two patents that underlie an enormous new cancer drug, for instance.</p>
<p>In the tech space though, it&#8217;s a very different dynamic because, a lot of the time, these inventions are incredibly important and they do launch a whole new generation of products and services, but the problem is that a new device, like an iPhone, or a piece of software, might rely on dozens or even hundreds of innovations from across many different universities, as opposed to just one or two.</p>
<h2><strong>Obviously not every breakthrough necessitates the launch of a startup. I assume that the vast majority of these things that are coming would make the most sense to work with existing companies.</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Jennifer Dyer:</strong> We&#8217;ve all had this renewed focus on innovation within the university and really helping our students and faculty that want to start companies, launch those companies. If you look at the space, helping educate our students that launching a company in a high-tech space may mean that they have to go out and acquire 100 different licenses, so maybe it doesn&#8217;t make sense. We&#8217;re going to be doing nonexclusive licensing, and it doesn&#8217;t preclude anyone from moving forward with this technology. This is probably the first pool for nonstandard essential patents in the high-tech space, which makes it somewhat unique. Because if you look back, most of the pools have been around standard essential patents.</p>
<h2><strong>The question of exclusivity is an interesting one. You wouldn’t grant exclusive rights for the right fee?<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/from-dorm-rooms-to-board-rooms-how-universities-are-promoting-entrepreneurship/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2112679</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trafi takes its mobility-as-a-service platform to LatAm, starting with Bogota</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/trafi-takes-its-mobility-as-a-service-platform-to-latam-starting-with-bogota/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/trafi-takes-its-mobility-as-a-service-platform-to-latam-starting-with-bogota/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 19:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trafi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2112526</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trafi, the Lithuanian startup that created a platform that lets users plan, book and pay for various modes of transportation within a city, is expanding beyond the European market where it got its start to tackle one of the most congested urban areas in the world. The company said it has reached an agreement to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.trafi.com/">Trafi</a>, the Lithuanian startup that created a platform that lets users plan, book and pay for various modes of transportation within a city, is expanding beyond the European market where it got its start to tackle one of the most congested urban areas in the world.</p>
<p>The company said it has reached an agreement to provide its mobility-as-a-service platform in Bogota, Colombia.</p>
<p>Trafi&#8217;s platform is a white label product. But underneath the name — whether it&#8217;s Yuomov in Zurich, Jelbi in Berlin or MVG in Munich — is the same underlying technology. The company, which operates in seven European cities, is able to capture transportation data to provide real-time route planning for users. It also handles the payment system, which helps it stand apart from some of its competitors.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Trafi doesn&#8217;t just work with cities, however. The company&#8217;s tech is also used by Google, Lyft and Gojek — to name a few.</p>
<p>In Bogota, the platform will pull together all the forms of public transit, including buses and trams, as well as local taxis and e-bikes. Users can use the single-payment system to book and pay for the various modes of transportation. The app includes real-time departure information, a &#8220;nearby function&#8221; that will show the user all mobility options available within their location and &#8220;intermodal routing,&#8221; which proposes combinations of up to three different modes such as taking an e-bike to the bus stop.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2112601" style="width: 3010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/trafi.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2112601" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2112601 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/trafi.jpg" alt="Trafi" width="3000" height="2000" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/trafi.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/trafi.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/trafi.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/trafi.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/trafi.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/trafi.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/trafi.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/trafi.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 3000px) 100vw, 3000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2112601" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Trafi</p></div></p>
<p>Bogota is just the start. Trafi co-founder and CEO Martynas Gudonavičius told TechCrunch that the company plans to expand to other LatAm cities. The company will target capital cities in other LatAm countries first, places like São Paulo in Brazil. Gudonavičius said Trafi will seek out contracts with smaller and medium-sized cities in the region as well. Any city with digital ticketing and various modes of transportation, including scooter and bicycles, buses and ride-hailing, is a good fit for the company, he added.</p>
<p>&#8220;Latin America is a superb example where mobility-as-a-service can really strive,&#8221; Gudonavičius said. &#8220;This is why we&#8217;re in Bogota, it&#8217;s this young, dynamic, fast-growing population. And we are here to help them do the big transition from transportation patterns and behavior they have at the moment, to a mobility-as-a service concept.&#8221;</p>
<p>Trafi is hiring for a director in the region and plans to hire more people in all departments this year. It&#8217;s also eyeing an expansion into Asia in the second half of 2021. Gudonavičius wouldn&#8217;t provide specific details, but said the company had a short list of cities it wanted to enter. He specifically noted that Trafi planned to expand to a city in Japan.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/trafi-takes-its-mobility-as-a-service-platform-to-latam-starting-with-bogota/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2112526</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jigsaw scores $3.7M to slow down your dating swipes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/jigsaw-scores-3-7m-to-slow-down-your-dating-swipes/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/jigsaw-scores-3-7m-to-slow-down-your-dating-swipes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 19:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dating apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jigsaw]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Relationship Corp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2113034</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chalk one up for Jigsaw, an &#8220;anti-superficial&#8221; dating app that has scored £2.7 million ($3.7 million) in seed funding to put toward U.S. expansion. The round is led by a lead generation company for online dating companies, called The Relationship Corp., with backing from angel investors in the U.S. and U.K. &#8220;primarily&#8221; in the tech [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Chalk one up for <a href="https://jigsaw.co">Jigsaw</a>, an &#8220;anti-superficial&#8221; dating app that has scored £2.7 million ($3.7 million) in seed funding to put toward U.S. expansion. The round is led by a lead generation company for online dating companies, called The Relationship Corp., with backing from angel investors in the U.S. and U.K. &#8220;primarily&#8221; in the tech sector.</p>
<p>As the startup&#8217;s name suggests, Jigsaw adds a little cryptic fun to the transactional business of swiping photos of other singles in search of dating chemistry in a bid to offer a less superficial experience.</p>
<p>Albeit their (patented) anti-superficial twist looks a tad gimmicky at first blush: They literally superimpose a digital jigsaw over the faces of users, with pieces removed gradually the more you interact &#8212; and the f<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">ull face only revealed after a pre-set amount of in-app engagement. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Digital filters are also banned, per the app&#8217;s <a href="https://jigsaw.co/faq/topics#?category=account-and-settings&amp;question=XtpCCRAAACEAXF1W&amp;topic=support">FAQ</a>; they only want &#8220;real&#8221; selfies. So no cute cat ears, etc. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">They&#8217;ve got a few more tricks up their sleeve but don&#8217;t want to offer a public reveal of the planned features we guessed were coming just yet (but, well, a quick glance at the app and it&#8217;s basically a half finished jigsaw puzzle of their product roadmap).</span></p>
<p>The U.K. startup &#8212; which was founded back in 2016 by a couple of friends, Alex Durrant (co-founder and CEO) and Max Adamski (co-founder and CPO), when they were at university (and finding the dating app scene frustratingly superficial, as they tell it, going on to quit their jobs and go all in on the project in 2018) &#8212; launched its puzzle-faced dating experience in London in 2019; and opened up to the U.S. in November last year.</p>
<p>Jigsaw has some 150,000+ registered users across those two markets at this point, with 50,000 in the U.S. &#8212; and an appetite to step things up over the pond now that they&#8217;re flush with new funds.</p>
<p>Durrant says the team is hoping to hit half a million U.S. users in the next six months. They reckon there&#8217;s a trend toward less superficial swiping in the American dating app scene that Jigsaw is well-positioned to tap into.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re not insane and think people look better with puzzles over their faces, I promise, the puzzle is our middle finger to the superficial dating industry,&#8221; he says. &#8220;It exists as you say to encourage more meaningful/sustained interactions and to help users look beyond the looks.&#8221;</p>
<p>Currently, Jigsaw&#8217;s face-shielding mechanism involves a puzzle made up of 16 pieces. All photos start with one piece removed &#8220;so you get a sneak peek&#8221;. Another then comes off when a user likes (matches with) the person so at the start of chatting there are two pieces revealed.</p>
<p>More pieces are removed as the pair mutually exchange messages until there&#8217;s no more puzzle bits left. Hopefully you also won&#8217;t run out of conversation at that point.</p>
<p>&#8220;Over six messages each (12 in total) is what we believe is the minimum needed for a meaningful conversation,&#8221; says Durrant. &#8220;That’s why the jigsaw puzzle currently unveils fully after seven messages are exchanged (14 pieces revealed in total), revealing the face underneath. This number has been tested and this is the current sweet spot for our users.&#8221;</p>
<p>Jigsaw isn&#8217;t unique in the concept of shielding facial visuals to encourage dating app users to do more chatting and less mindless swiping. There are a whole bunch of &#8220;slower reveal&#8221; style twists aimed at reducing &#8220;dating app fatigue&#8221; &#8212; as another app, <a href="https://inyn.app">INYN</a>, which also limits the velocity of the profile reveal, puts it.</p>
<p>Another app which blurs users&#8217; photos until they do some chatting is <a href="http://taffy.chat">Taffy</a>. There&#8217;s also Muslim matchmaking app <a href="https://www.veil.mobi/">Veil</a> &#8212; which offers a “digital veil” feature (aka an opaque filter) that it applies to all profile photos, male and female, until a mutual match is made.</p>
<p>Other &#8220;anti-superficial&#8221; dating apps, like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/02/11/meet-willow-the-dating-app-where-love-isnt-based-on-lust/">Willow</a>, try a Q&amp;A style approach &#8212; getting users to answer questions to see more photos. The list goes on.</p>
<p>Still, Jigsaw has come up with perhaps the most visually obvious (and gamified) twist on this slow-reveal format. And being so immediately, well, obvious, it might make its &#8220;slow reveal&#8221; twist stick for longer than the average &#8220;love is blind&#8221; alternative dating app.</p>
<p>Its seed investment is not about buying users, either. We made sure to check.</p>
<p>The Relationship Corp. does offer user acquisition/traffic generation services to dating apps &#8212; including those it invests in &#8212; but in Jigsaw&#8217;s case the investment is a straight equity investment, per Durrant. So it&#8217;s at least sounding confident in its ability to grow.</p>
<p>&#8220;They&#8217;re super low-key but are known in the industry,&#8221; says Durrant of the lead seed investor. &#8220;Steve Happas their CEO is ex-Match and&#8230; sits on our advisory board [as part of the investment]. We had an option to work with them to acquire users but instead, they are supporting our internal team in an advisory capacity.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="d2ilLZqA9I"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/bumble-ipo-could-raise-more-than-1b-for-dating-service/">Bumble IPO could raise more than $1B for dating service</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bumble IPO could raise more than $1B for dating service&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/bumble-ipo-could-raise-more-than-1b-for-dating-service/embed/#?secret=d2ilLZqA9I" data-secret="d2ilLZqA9I" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/jigsaw-scores-3-7m-to-slow-down-your-dating-swipes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2113034</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Parler crawls back online empty and with a Tea Party CEO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/parler-crawls-back-online-empty-and-with-a-tea-party-ceo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/parler-crawls-back-online-empty-and-with-a-tea-party-ceo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 18:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2113015</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Parler, a social network adopted by the far right and recently kicked off AWS for its userbase&#8217;s habit of advocating violence, is back online. The restoration questions the notion that &#8220;big tech&#8221; can take and keep an unwanted presence offline, but Parler&#8217;s return is not quite a triumph, and its new CEO doesn&#8217;t suggest much [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Parler, a social network adopted by the far right and recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/parler-is-officially-offline-after-aws-suspension/">kicked off AWS</a> for its userbase&#8217;s habit of advocating violence, is back online. The restoration questions the notion that &#8220;big tech&#8221; can take and keep an unwanted presence offline, but Parler&#8217;s return is not quite a triumph, and its new CEO doesn&#8217;t suggest much of a change in philosophy.</p>
<p>Users can now log in to Parler on the web, but when they do they will find that all their old posts and content have been removed. It&#8217;s unclear whether this was a consequence of the hurried exit from AWS last month, a scorched-earth policy regarding the content that got the site in hot water in the first place or for some other reason.</p>
<p>Fortunately <em>someone </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/scraped-parler-data-is-a-metadata-goldmine/">had the presence of mind to make a backup</a>, though not with the intention of restoring it. <a href="https://twitter.com/donk_enby">@donk_enby</a> scraped millions of posts and media files from the site for posterity, something that has already borne fruit as researchers have used the files to show, for example, where certain users were on the day of the Capitol riots. (She is currently pointing out various problems with the new Parler&#8217;s web rollout.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The new site is described in a statement as using &#8220;sustainable, independent technology and not reliant on so-called &#8216;Big Tech&#8217; for its operations.&#8221; The new host is SkySilk, seemingly a reseller of OVHcloud, and I&#8217;ve asked if the company plans to enforce its <a href="https://www.skysilk.com/terms/">terms</a>, which generally but not specifically prohibit things like threats of violence. (The details of the terms violations were made more public in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/judge-denies-parlers-bid-to-make-amazon-restore-service/">Parler&#8217;s attempt to force Amazon to reinstate it</a>.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jHzs3HQK9i"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/judge-denies-parlers-bid-to-make-amazon-restore-service/">Judge denies Parler&#8217;s bid to make Amazon restore service</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Judge denies Parler&#8217;s bid to make Amazon restore service&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/judge-denies-parlers-bid-to-make-amazon-restore-service/embed/#?secret=jHzs3HQK9i" data-secret="jHzs3HQK9i" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Parler, for its part, aims to make itself a bit less of an easy target by upping its moderation game. The site will supposedly be using both AI and human moderators to watch for content that could rock the boat — though Facebook has been trying this for years and still hasn&#8217;t quite got the hang of it.</p>
<p>They may have an easier job of it, considering Parler is still <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/parler-removed-from-google-play-store-as-apple-app-store-suspension-reportedly-looms/">barred from the Google Play Store and iOS App Store</a>. That&#8217;s a huge damper on activity, since mobile users make up a large part of social networks. So the flood of content the site could not adequately monitor in early January may have slowed to a trickle. (I&#8217;ve asked the company for more information on this and other matters and will update this post if I hear back.)</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the operation is being overseen by a new interim CEO after the ouster of John Matze by the board. The one to fill the role is Mark Meckler, founder of the Tea Party Patriots, staunch opponents of Obamacare and big fans of debunked COVID-19 treatment hydroxychloroquine. The group was also behind the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/28/twitter-donald-trump-jr-frontline-doctors-viral-video-misinformation/">infamous &#8220;America&#8217;s Frontline Doctors&#8221;</a> event and was one of the organizers of the March to Save America that turned into the Capitol Riots.</p>
<p>Meckler&#8217;s pedigree suggests that despite the claimed moderation improvements, this is hardly Parler turning a new leaf. With the deliberate (and apparently unavoidable) break with &#8220;Big Tech,&#8221; however it is defined, and a CEO who embodies the same qualities that ran amok before, it seems a lot more like stubborn defiance than introspection and graceful compromise.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Os4GIN3I2h"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/scraped-parler-data-is-a-metadata-goldmine/">Scraped Parler data is a metadata gold mine</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Scraped Parler data is a metadata gold mine&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/scraped-parler-data-is-a-metadata-goldmine/embed/#?secret=Os4GIN3I2h" data-secret="Os4GIN3I2h" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/parler-crawls-back-online-empty-and-with-a-tea-party-ceo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2113015</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Delivery company goPuff is in talks to acquire the UK&#8217;s Fancy</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/go-fancy/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/go-fancy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 18:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2113019</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[GoPuff, the U.S.-based startup that operates its own &#8220;microfulfillment&#8221; network and promises to deliver items such as over-the-counter medicine, baby food and alcohol in 30 minutes or less, is in talks to acquire the U.K.&#8217;s Fancy Delivery, TechCrunch has learned. According to sources, terms of the acquisition are still being fleshed out, and the deal [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">GoPuff, the U.S.-based startup that operates its own &#8220;microfulfillment&#8221; network and promises to deliver items such as over-the-counter medicine, baby food and alcohol in 30 minutes or less, is in talks to acquire the U.K.&#8217;s <a href="https://www.fancyapp.live/">Fancy Delivery</a>, TechCrunch has learned.</p>
<p>According to sources, terms of the acquisition are still being fleshed out, and the deal has yet to get over the line. However, an announcement could come in the next few weeks if not sooner. GoPuff declined to comment. Fancy&#8217;s founders couldn&#8217;t be reached before publication, either.</p>
<p>Launched late last year, Fancy currently operates in four cities in the U.K. and is a graduate of the Silicon Valley accelerator Y Combinator. It has a strikingly similar model to its potential buyer, leading some to describe it as a mini goPuff. The two companies are fully vertically integrated, meaning they each contract their own fleet of drivers and operate their own microfulfillment centres &#8212; sometimes dubbed &#8220;dark stores&#8221; &#8212; designed specifically for online ordering and hyperlocal delivery.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Strategically, the potential acquisition of Fancy looks to be a good fit, and most notably would signal goPuff&#8217;s intent to expand to the U.K. via purchasing a nascent local player rather than starting entirely from scratch. Sources tell me Fancy will continue to operate under the Fancy brand and that goPuff intends to invest in its growth, including hiring and opening additional fulfillment centers. One source tells TechCrunch the acquisition will be an all-stock deal.</p>
<p>GoPuff was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/gopuff-funding/">recently valued at $3.9 billion</a> and has raised $1.35 billion in funding to-date (backers include Accel, D1 Capital Partners, Luxor Capital and SoftBank Vision Fund). It already operates in 500 U.S. cities, and isn&#8217;t shy of making acquisitions, either, most recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/gopuff-acquires-bevmo/">purchasing alcohol-focussed BevMo</a>.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Europe is seeing a slew of startups inspired by goPuff&#8217;s vertically integrated model sprouting up. They include Berlin&#8217;s much-hyped <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/gorillas/">Gorillas</a> and London&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/dija/">Dija</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/london-based-weezy-raises-seed/">Weezy</a>, and France&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/cajoo-promises-grocery-deliveries-in-15-minutes/">Cajoo</a>, all of which claim to focus more on fresh food and groceries, where margins are arguably tighter. There&#8217;s also the likes of <a href="https://tryzapp.com/">Zapp</a>, which is still in stealth and more focused on a higher-margin convenience store offering.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="x9XkdlORY6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/gopuff-acquires-bevmo/">Delivery startup goPuff acquires BevMo for $350M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Delivery startup goPuff acquires BevMo for $350M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/gopuff-acquires-bevmo/embed/#?secret=x9XkdlORY6" data-secret="x9XkdlORY6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/go-fancy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2113019</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Severe weather, blackouts shows the grid&#8217;s biggest problem is infrastructure, not renewables</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/severe-weather-blackouts-shows-the-grids-biggest-problem-is-infrastructure-not-renewables/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/severe-weather-blackouts-shows-the-grids-biggest-problem-is-infrastructure-not-renewables/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 18:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electrical grid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Georgia Institute of Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[natural gas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[power outage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart grid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swell Energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2112973</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s becoming harder for the U.S. to ignore the very real effects of global climate change &#8212; and despite the efforts of naysayers, it&#8217;s not a push to renewables that&#8217;s to blame for the outages sweeping the nation. It&#8217;s the country&#8217;s energy infrastructure. Severe weather conditions caused by global warming have now caused massive blackouts [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s becoming harder for the U.S. to ignore the very real effects of global climate change &#8212; and despite the efforts of naysayers, it&#8217;s not a push to renewables that&#8217;s to blame for the outages sweeping the nation. It&#8217;s the country&#8217;s energy infrastructure.</p>
<p>Severe weather conditions caused by global warming have now caused massive blackouts across some of the largest cities in the United States. The inability of the U.S. power grid to withstand the stresses caused by extreme weather events show that the nation needs a massive investment plan to upgrade energy infrastructure in an effort to make it more resilient.</p>
<p>These problems are now painfully apparent to the 29 million residents of Texas who are now subject to rolling blackouts caused by the frigid weather sweeping across the country.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Electric Reliability Council of Texas said it had &#8220;entered emergency conditions and initiated rotating outages at 1:25 a.m. today,&#8221; <a href="http://www.ercot.com/news/releases/show/225210">in a statement</a>. The Texas grid shed 10.5 gigawatts of load &#8212; or enough to power 2 million homes at its peak.</p>
<p>&#8220;Extreme weather conditions caused many generating units – across fuel types – to trip offline and become unavailable,&#8221; the energy provider said in a statement.</p>
<p>Part of the problem lies with natural gas generators that supply much of the power to the grid in Texas, according to Princeton professor, Jesse Jenkins, who has a joint appointment in the Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering and the Andlinger Center for Energy and Environment.</p>
<p>Citing a market participant, Jenkins <a href="https://twitter.com/JesseJenkins/status/1361348544154664961?s=20">noted on Twitter</a> that roughly 26 gigawatts of thermal energy is offline because natural gas is being diverted to provide heat instead of power. Only about 4 gigawatts of wind is offline because of icing, Jenkins noted.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Confidential info from a market participant in ERCOT: As of ~10 AM Eastern time, the system has ~30 GW of capacity offline, ~26 GW of thermal &#8212; mostly natural gas which cant get fuel deliveries which are being priorities for heating loads &#8212; and ~4 GW of wind due to icing. <a href="https://t.co/Bfpn0WeRIq">https://t.co/Bfpn0WeRIq</a></p>
<p>&mdash; JesseJenkins (@JesseJenkins) <a href="https://twitter.com/JesseJenkins/status/1361348544154664961?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 15, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The current blackouts have nothing to do with renewables and everything to do with cold weather slowing down natural gas production because of freeze offs and spiking demand for heating at the same time.</p>
<p>As Dr. Emily Grubert, an assistant Professor of Civil and Environmental Engineering and, by courtesy, of Public Policy at the Georgia Institute of Technology, noted, the problem is more of a total systems issue than one associated with renewable power.</p>
<p>&#8220;Let us be absolutely clear: if there are grid failures today, it shows the <em>existing</em> (largely fossil-based) system cannot handle these conditions either,&#8221; Grubert <a href="https://twitter.com/emilygrubert/status/1361011767439220748?s=20">wrote on Twitter</a>. &#8220;These are scary, climate change-affected conditions that pose extreme challenges to the grid. We are likely to continue to see situations like this where our existing system cannot easily handle them. <em>Any</em> electricity system needs to make massive adaptive improvements.&#8221;</p>
<p>Renewable energy and energy storage can potentially provide a solution to the problem and help contribute to a more resilient grid. Residential energy developer <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/residential-renewable-energy-developer-swell-is-raising-450-million-for-distributed-power-projects-in-three-states/">Swell Energy raised $450 million</a> in financing late last year to begin development of several projects across three states that would pair distributed, residential solar energy generation with battery storage to create what are called virtual power plants that can ease stress on energy grids in times of increased demand.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gy9WGHdfEZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/residential-renewable-energy-developer-swell-is-raising-450-million-for-distributed-power-projects-in-three-states/">Residential renewable energy developer Swell is raising $450 million for distributed power projects in three states</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Residential renewable energy developer Swell is raising $450 million for distributed power projects in three states&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/residential-renewable-energy-developer-swell-is-raising-450-million-for-distributed-power-projects-in-three-states/embed/#?secret=gy9WGHdfEZ" data-secret="gy9WGHdfEZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“Utilities are increasingly looking to distributed energy resources as valuable ‘grid edge’ assets,” said Suleman Khan, CEO of Swell Energy, in a statement, at the time of the announcement. “By networking these individual homes and businesses into virtual power plants, Swell is able to bring down the cost of ownership for its customers and help utilities manage demand across their electric grids.&#8221;</p>
<p>Other companies, like <a href="https://www.evolvemyenergy.com/">Evolve Energy</a> or <a href="https://www.griddy.com/">Griddy</a>, try to help consumers manage costs by charging them wholesale rates for power. Those companies can only be economical when the rates for wholesale power are low. Right now, with demand for power skyrocketing, prices for energy in the ERCOT have surged above $5,000 per MW and hit the $9,000 cap in many nodes, according to Bloomberg Energy reporter Javier Bias.</p>
<p>The blackouts in Texas today and in California in January show that the current grid in the United States needs an overhaul. Whether it’s heavily regulated markets like California or a free market like Texas, current policy can&#8217;t stop the weather from wreaking havoc and putting people&#8217;s lives at risk.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/severe-weather-blackouts-shows-the-grids-biggest-problem-is-infrastructure-not-renewables/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2112973</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Private equity firm Marlin snatches up e-commerce optimization platform Lengow</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/private-equity-firm-marlin-snatches-up-e-commerce-optimization-platform-lengow/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/private-equity-firm-marlin-snatches-up-e-commerce-optimization-platform-lengow/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 17:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lengow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marlin equity partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2113042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup Lengow has a new landlord as Marlin Equity Partners has acquired a majority stake in the company. Lengow operates a software-as-a-service platform to optimize e-commerce listings. Terms of the deal are undisclosed. In particular, many sellers now list their items on multiple e-commerce websites at once. For instance, a company could have its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://www.lengow.com">Lengow</a> has a new landlord as <a href="https://www.marlinequity.com">Marlin Equity Partners</a> has acquired a majority stake in the company. Lengow operates a software-as-a-service platform to optimize e-commerce listings. Terms of the deal are undisclosed.</p>
<p>In particular, many sellers now list their items on multiple e-commerce websites at once. For instance, a company could have its own e-commerce website and also sell products on Amazon, eBay, etc. And you may have noticed the same third-party sellers on different marketplaces.</p>
<p>Manually listing items across multiple e-commerce platforms would be extremely tedious. Behind the scenes, Lengow tries to automate as many steps as possible. First, you can import your products by connecting Lengow with your product information management system (PIM) or your e-commerce back end — it can run on Akeneo, Shopify, Magento, WooCommerce, etc.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>You can then publish your products on multiple sales channels at once. It can be a marketplace, a price comparison website, a social network or an adtech platform. Examples include Amazon, Google Shopping, Criteo, Instagram, etc.</p>
<p>Lengow also helps you track orders, create rules when you’re running low on stock and manage your advertising strategy. Essentially, it’s the glue that makes all the moving parts of e-commerce stick together. There are 4,600 merchants using Lengow globally.</p>
<p>Marlin describes the deal as a growth investment. The firm plans to increase the value of Lengow in the coming years as it hasn’t reached its full potential yet. “We are looking forward to leveraging our operational and financial resources to support Lengow’s growth trajectory and continued international expansion,” Marlin principal Roland Pezzutto said in a statement.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Eb4tIJQSJA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/thrasio-raises-750m-more-in-equity-for-its-amazon-roll-up-play/">Thrasio raises $750M more in equity for its Amazon roll-up play</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Thrasio raises $750M more in equity for its Amazon roll-up play&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/thrasio-raises-750m-more-in-equity-for-its-amazon-roll-up-play/embed/#?secret=Eb4tIJQSJA" data-secret="Eb4tIJQSJA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/private-equity-firm-marlin-snatches-up-e-commerce-optimization-platform-lengow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2113042</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google slapped in France over misleading hotel star ratings</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/google-slapped-in-france-over-misleading-hotel-star-ratings/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/google-slapped-in-france-over-misleading-hotel-star-ratings/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 17:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[algorithms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ratings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2112986</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google has agreed to pay a €1.1 million fine over misleading star ratings for hotels in France. The tech giant had been applying its own (algorithmic) system of ratings for hotels applied via its search engine and on Google Maps. But back in 2019, following a number of complaints by hoteliers, the French national competition [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google has agreed to pay a €1.1 million fine over misleading star ratings for hotels in France.</p>
<p>The tech giant had been applying its own (algorithmic) system of ratings for hotels applied via its search engine and on Google Maps. But back in 2019, following a number of complaints by hoteliers, the French national competition and consumer watchdog (DGCCRF) instigated an investigation into this propriety rating system.</p>
<p>The probe revealed that the tech giant had replaced the standard classification system of the public tourist board (Atout France) with a star rating system powered by its own criteria &#8212; and which it had applied to more than 7,500 establishments.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Safe to say Google&#8217;s concept of a &#8220;five star&#8221; hotel was not the same as the Atout France version. And the consumer watchdog found that Google&#8217;s presentation for classifying tourist accommodation &#8212; including identical use of the term &#8220;stars&#8221; on the same scale from 1 to 5 &#8212; to be confusing for consumers.</p>
<p>&#8220;This practice was particularly damaging for consumers, misled about the level of services what they could expect when booking accommodation. It also resulted in prejudice for hoteliers whose establishments were wrongly presented as lower ranked than in the official ranking of Atout France,&#8221; the watchdog writes in a <a href="https://www.economie.gouv.fr/dgccrf/classement-trompeur-des-hebergements-touristiques-par-google-une-enquete-de-la-dgccrf-0">press release</a> on the sanction (which we&#8217;ve translated from French).</p>
<p>The DGCCRF concluded that Google had engaged in a deceptive business practice &#8212; and, with the public prosecutor, it proposed the sanction announced today on Google Ireland (the tech giant&#8217;s European HQ) and Google France.</p>
<p>As well as agreeing to pay the fine, Google has changed hotel star ratings in France &#8212; agreeing to display the official Atout France ratings. So tourists in France can be confident that a five-star hotel they see on Google Maps has an official standard attached to it which can&#8217;t be influenced by any of the usual online growth hacking tactics.</p>
<p>A spokesperson for Google confirmed the conclusion of the DGCCRF&#8217;s action, telling TechCrunch: &#8220;We have now settled with the DGCCRF and made the necessary changes to only reflect the official French star rating for hotels on Google Maps and Search.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gJM8BfLEMr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/08/google-play-is-changing-how-app-ratings-work/">Google Play is changing how app ratings work</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google Play is changing how app ratings work&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/08/google-play-is-changing-how-app-ratings-work/embed/#?secret=gJM8BfLEMr" data-secret="gJM8BfLEMr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/google-slapped-in-france-over-misleading-hotel-star-ratings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2112986</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Station: Archer Aviation&#8217;s two big scores, a boost for e-bikes and how Uber defines adjusted EBITDA</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/the-station-archer-aviations-two-big-scores-a-boost-for-ebikes-and-how-uber-defines-adjusted-ebitda/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/the-station-archer-aviations-two-big-scores-a-boost-for-ebikes-and-how-uber-defines-adjusted-ebitda/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 17:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archer Aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Argo AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Station]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2112991</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Station is a weekly newsletter dedicated to all things transportation. Sign up here — just click The Station — to receive it every weekend in your inbox.  Hi friends and new readers, welcome back to The Station, a newsletter dedicated to all the present and future ways people and packages move from Point A to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>The Station is a weekly newsletter dedicated to all things transportation. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">Sign up here — just click The Station — to receive it every weekend in your inbox</a>. </em></p>
<p>Hi friends and new readers, welcome back to The Station, a newsletter dedicated to all the present and future ways people and packages move from Point A to Point B.</p>
<p>There is quite a bit to get to this week, so let&#8217;s charge forward.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Email me at <a href="mailto:kirsten.korosec@techcrunch.com">kirsten.korosec@techcrunch.com</a> to share thoughts, criticisms, opinions or tips. You also can send a direct message to me at Twitter — <a href="https://twitter.com/kirstenkorosec">@kirstenkorosec</a>.</p>
<h2>Micromobbin&#8217;</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1894192 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png" alt="the station scooter1a" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>The spike in electric bike sales was one of the rosier outcomes of the COVID-19 pandemic. Now, new legislation introduced this past week by U.S. representatives Jimmy Panetta (D-CA) and Earl Blumenauer (D-OR) could push sales even higher. The Electric Bicycle Incentive Kickstart for the Environment (E-BIKE) Act proposes creating a consumer tax credit that would cover 30% of the cost of an electric bicycle up to a $1,500 credit. The proposed bill applies to new electric bicycles that cost less than $8,000 and is fully refundable, allowing lower-income workers to claim the credit, according to <a href="https://panetta.house.gov/media/press-releases/congressman-panetta-introduces-e-bike-act-encourage-use-electric-bicycles-and">Panetta&#8217;s announcement</a>.</p>
<p>Individuals can use the credit once every three years, or twice for a joint-return couple buying two electric bicycles. The bill also mandates that the IRS provide a report after two years to help lawmakers understand how the credit is being distributed across income tax brackets. There is an existing tax credit for two-wheeled plug-in electric vehicles. However, that tax credit only applies to motorcycles that travel at least 45 miles per hour, not bicycles.</p>
<p>While support from bicycle advocacy groups has poured in (my inbox overfloweth), it&#8217;s unclear if the E-BIKE Act will gain enough support within Congress to actually become law. PeopleForBikes, one of several groups that supports the legislation, noted that studies show a 15% increase in electric bicycle mode share in the United States will cause carbon emissions to fall 11%.</p>
<p>There is at least one other effort to deliver tax benefits to bicyclists. Blumenauer is also working to reinstate the bicycle commuter tax benefit, which was axed in 2018 under the Tax Cuts and Jobs Act. The original benefit let employers reimburse workers up to $20 per month for bicycle commuting expenses. Blumenauer introduced last month the <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/384/text?q=%7B%22search%22%3A%5B%22Bicycle+Commuter+Act+of+2021%22%5D%7D&amp;r=1&amp;s=6">Bicycle Commuter Act of 2021</a>, which would extend benefits to commuters who use e-bikes, bike share and more traditional bicycles.</p>
<p><strong>Meanwhile, on the micromobbin&#8217; SPAC front &#8230;</strong></p>
<p>Helbiz, the micromobility startup that offers e-scooters, e-bicycles and e-mopeds and operates across Europe and in several U.S. cities, announced it will merge with a special purpose acquisition company to become a publicly listed company. The deal with GreenVision Acquisition Corp. is expected to close in the second quarter. The combined entity, which will be named Helbiz Inc. and listed on the Nasdaq exchange under HLBZ, will have a valuation of $408 million.</p>
<p>Notably, the company is going to use capital from this deal to expand into &#8220;cloud&#8221; or &#8220;ghost&#8221; kitchens as part of a move into food delivery.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uZEepGJ95L"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/micro-mobility-startup-helbiz-to-go-public-via-a-spac-and-will-expand-into-ghost-kitchens/">Micromobility startup Helbiz to go public via a SPAC, and will expand into ghost kitchens</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Micromobility startup Helbiz to go public via a SPAC, and will expand into ghost kitchens&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/micro-mobility-startup-helbiz-to-go-public-via-a-spac-and-will-expand-into-ghost-kitchens/embed/#?secret=uZEepGJ95L" data-secret="uZEepGJ95L" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Taking a tour of the companies&#8217; <a href="https://sec.report/Document/0001213900-21-007446/">SEC filings</a>, it looks like that valuation is based off of the more than $4 million in revenue that Helbiz generated in 2020. About 96% of that revenue came from its mobility rentals and the remaining 4% from advertising through its app and at charging docks. Helbiz is projecting that by 2025 (just four years from now) it will have $449 million in revenue from its mobility and advertising streams as well as &#8220;new verticals.&#8221; Presumably, this is the ghost kitchens.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll be curious to see if other micromobility SPACs follow Helbiz&#8217; announcement and if this activity helps push up valuations of rivals like Lime. (You might recall that last May Lime raised $170 million at a reduced valuation of $510 million. However, Lime CEO Wayne Ting has more recently painted a more <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/lime-touts-a-2020-turnaround-and-2021-profitability/">positive financial picture</a> of the company.)</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve also heard plenty of SPAC rumors swirling around Bird. But what about the others?</p>
<h2>Deal of the week</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1896226 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png" alt="money the station" width="1600" height="400" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=1536,384 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>Electric aircraft startup <strong>Archer Aviation</strong> landed two deals this past week that helped it earn &#8220;deal of the week&#8221; status. The company, which is targeting the urban air mobility market, reached an agreement to merge with special purpose acquisition company Atlas Crest Investment Corp. for an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/archer-lands-1-1b-order-from-united-airlines-and-a-spac-deal/">equity valuation of $3.8 billion</a>.</p>
<p>It <em>also</em> snagged United Airlines as a customer and an investor. United placed an order for $1 billion of Archer&#8217;s aircraft and has the option to buy an additional $500 million of aircraft, according to Archer.</p>
<p>On the SPAC side of things, Archer said it expected to receive $1.1 billion of gross proceeds, including $600 million in private investment in public equity, or PIPE, from investors such as United Airlines, Stellantis and the venture arm of Exor, Baron Capital Group, the Federated Hermes Kaufmann Funds, Mubadala Capital, Putnam Investments and Access Industries. Ken Moelis and affiliates, along with Marc Lore, who is one of Archer&#8217;s primary and initial backers, are investing $30 million in the PIPE.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yljW6sB3kC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/archer-lands-1-1b-order-from-united-airlines-and-a-spac-deal/">Archer lands $1B order from United Airlines and a SPAC deal</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Archer lands $1B order from United Airlines and a SPAC deal&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/archer-lands-1-1b-order-from-united-airlines-and-a-spac-deal/embed/#?secret=yljW6sB3kC" data-secret="yljW6sB3kC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The combined company will be listed on the New York Stock Exchange with ticker symbol &#8220;ACHR.&#8221;</p>
<p>Archer has yet to mass produce its electric vertical take-off and landing aircraft, which is designed to travel up to 60 miles on a single charge at speeds of 150 miles per hour. The company has said it plans to unveil its full-scale eVTOL later this year and is aiming to begin volume manufacturing in 2023.</p>
<p><strong>Other deals that got my attention &#8230;</strong></p>
<p><strong>BusUp</strong>, the bus commuter platform startup raised $6 million in a Series A round led by Latin American mobility investment firm Proeza Ventures. Autotech Ventures and IESE&#8217;s Business School venture fund Finaves V also participated. BusUp has focused on the Europe and LatAm markets. This new funding will be used to expand operations in the United States and consolidate other existing markets in response to growing interest in employer-provided commuter benefits and mobility services. You might recall that just last week, I wrote about a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/commuting-platform-startup-hip-lands-12-million-to-help-companies-bring-employees-back-to-the-office/">similar company called</a> Hip.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KibaYtZC58"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/commuting-platform-startup-hip-lands-12-million-to-help-companies-bring-employees-back-to-the-office/">Commuting platform startup Hip lands $12 million to help companies bring employees back to the office</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Commuting platform startup Hip lands $12 million to help companies bring employees back to the office&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/commuting-platform-startup-hip-lands-12-million-to-help-companies-bring-employees-back-to-the-office/embed/#?secret=KibaYtZC58" data-secret="KibaYtZC58" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Chowbotics</strong>, a Bay Area-based robotics best known for its salad-making robot, Sally, is about to be gobbled up by delivery service DoorDash. Terms of the deal aren&#8217;t known yet. Chowbotics has raised around $21 million to date, including an $11 million round back in 2018. The company&#8217;s vending machine-style salad bar robot was already well-positioned for the pandemic, removing a human element from the food preparation process &#8212; not to mention the fact that salad bars and buffets tend to be open air affairs. In October, the startup added a contactless feature to the robot, letting users order ahead of time, via app, per <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/doordash-acquires-salad-making-robotics-startup-chowbotics/">TechCrunch hardware editor Brian Heater</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="f97W7t1vlF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/doordash-acquires-salad-making-robotics-startup-chowbotics/">DoorDash acquires salad-making robotics startup, Chowbotics</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;DoorDash acquires salad-making robotics startup, Chowbotics&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/doordash-acquires-salad-making-robotics-startup-chowbotics/embed/#?secret=f97W7t1vlF" data-secret="f97W7t1vlF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Joby Aviation</strong> is in talks to go public in a SPAC deal that would value the electric plane manufacturer at nearly $5.7 billion, the <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/42feff1d-8228-4c93-bd78-b537d9eb9fa7">Financial Times reported</a>. You might recall that Joby recently picked up Uber&#8217;s air taxi unit Elevate. Last year, the company raised $590 million from investors in a round led by Toyota.</p>
<p><strong>Kargo</strong>, a smart loading dock platform startup founded in late 2019, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/kargo-raises-6m-to-smarten-up-loading-docks-for-the-coming-wave-of-autonomy/">raised $6 million</a> in seed money from Founders Fund, Accomplice, Sozo Ventures and other unnamed investors. Kargo is a hardware and software company. Kargo sells sensor towers, which are mounted to a loading dock. The computer vision sensor is able to automatically identify and verify all incoming and outgoing freight in real time. The accompanying software platform, which Kargo offers as a subscription, takes in all of that data. Customers use the platform to take a macro or micro view of its supply chain.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pq742CXqfw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/kargo-raises-6m-to-smarten-up-loading-docks-for-the-coming-wave-of-autonomy/">Kargo raises $6M to smarten up loading docks for the coming wave of autonomy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Kargo raises $6M to smarten up loading docks for the coming wave of autonomy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/kargo-raises-6m-to-smarten-up-loading-docks-for-the-coming-wave-of-autonomy/embed/#?secret=pq742CXqfw" data-secret="pq742CXqfw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Hyzon Motors</strong>, a hydrogen fuel cell startup focused on commercial vehicles, reached an <a href="https://hyzonmotors.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Hyzon-DCRB-Transaction-Press-Release-02.09.21-Final.pdf">agreement to go public</a> via a merger with special purpose acquisition company Decarbonization Plus Acquisition Corporation at a $2.7 billion valuation.</p>
<p><strong>Instabox</strong>, the Sweden-based startup that focuses on last-mile deliveries for e-commerce, <a href="https://sifted.eu/articles/instabox-series-b-raise/">raised $90 million</a> in a Series B funding round was led by EQT Ventures, Sifted reported.</p>
<p><strong>Plus.ai</strong>, the self-driving truck technology startup that operates in China and the United States, raised $200 million in a round led by new investors Guotai Junan International, CPE and Wanxiang International Investment. Existing investors including FTA also participated. The company plans to use the new funds to &#8220;accelerate the global commercialization and deployment of its automated trucking system.&#8221; The company is developing a sales and support network to help fleets integrate the Plus automated trucking system into their daily operations. Plus will also scale deployments in the U.S. and China, and expand internationally to Europe and other parts of Asia, CEO and co-founder David Liu told me in a recent interview. I may run snippets of our chat in next week&#8217;s newsletter, so stay tuned.</p>
<p><strong>Siemens</strong> is preparing to sell off Intelligent Traffic Systems, its traffic light technology and equipment unit, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-siemens-divestiture/siemens-to-put-traffic-lights-unit-its-up-for-sale-sources-idUSKBN2A91YB">Reuters reported</a>. The company is targeting a valuation of between $604 million and $725 million.</p>
<h2>A little bird</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/blinky-cat-bird-green.gif"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1896211 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/blinky-cat-bird-green.gif" alt="blinky cat bird green" width="1600" height="400" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Veoneer</strong> reported during its earnings call February 3 that it had lost an existing lidar production contract with an autonomous vehicle customer. Veoneer indicated that this unknown OEM customer had chosen a different path for it lidar core technology. This is actually a loss for Velodyne as well, as Veoneer announced back in 2019 that it was leveraging the lidar company&#8217;s technology for a contract to supply the sensor to this same unnamed AV customer.</p>
<p>Veoneer CEO Jan Carlson said during the call that volumes from this OEM customer have decreased over time and emphasized it would not affect its order book. &#8220;But we are seeing a big shift in lidar technologies overall over-time,&#8221; Carlson said. &#8220;Our strategy, as I mentioned before is to be a strong integrator. We provide, of course, experience in cybersecurity. We provide automotive-grade experience. We can provide functional safety to startup companies that have a tech know-how, but not really or into the automotive environment.&#8221;</p>
<p>So who is this AV customer? Emmanuel Rosner, over at Deutsche Bank, said his educated guess is Ford (Argo). His explanation: &#8220;Ford has been an early investor in Velodyne, and it stands to reason it had placed a contract to use Velodyne sensors in its Argo robo-taxis, but it has now canceled the order. It&#8217;s unclear whether Argo will now be using another LiDAR supplier, or if it will use its own sensors developed in-house through Argo&#8217;s acquisition of Princeton Lightwave.&#8221;</p>
<p>My own sources confirm that this is indeed Ford/Argo. It seems that the intention was to use Velodyne for its autonomous vehicles, but that was scrapped in large part because Argo made faster progress on its own in-house lidar from Princeton Lightwave.</p>
<p><strong><em>Update</em>:</strong> This newsletter ran over the weekend. Ford reported via an <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/37996/000110465921021932/tm213752d1_sc13ga.htm">SEC regulatory filing</a> that it no longer held any shares of Velodyne. Apparently it sold off its remaining stake by the end of 2020. Ford had held almost 13.1 million shares — a value of about $244 million — in Velodyne at the close of the third quarter of 2020.</p>
<p>Speaking of Argo, I missed an <a href="https://twitter.com/argoai/status/1357667172324159488?s=20">interesting tweet</a> from the company in early February that explains it has expanded its operating domain to include highways. This means that Argo is now testing and operating in urban and suburban areas as well as highway environments. That highway piece is important for any aspiring robotaxi as airports are a common drop-off and pickup point for today&#8217;s ride-hailing customers (OK, well at least in pre-COVID times).</p>
<h2>Notable reads and other tidbits</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-2037863 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png" alt="the-station-delivery" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>A bunch of other transportation-related news happened, so let&#8217;s dig in.</p>
<h3>Automotive tech</h3>
<p>Analyst firm <strong>LMC</strong> said that the semiconductor shortage cost the auto industry at least 450,000 units of lost production in January and February, an issue that will likely continue through the first half of the year, <a href="https://www.autonews.com/automakers-suppliers/chip-shortage-toll-450000-vehicles-and-counting-analyst-firm-says?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+autonews%2FBreakingNews+%28Automotive+News+Breaking+News+Feed%29">Automotive News reported</a>. But there might be some good news in LMC&#8217;s report.</p>
<p>LMC forecasts that vehicle production will fall 10% globally in the first quarter from 2019 figures. That means an overall loss of 1.1 million units with 600,000 to 700,000 due to the chip shortage and the remainder from renewed COVID-19 lockdowns.</p>
<p><strong>Luminar</strong>, the lidar startup that recently became a publicly traded company via a SPAC, has added Dr. Mary Lou Jepsen and Katharine A. Martin to its board of directors. Jepsen is the CEO, founder and chairman of Openwater, a company focused on replacing the functionality of Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI). She also currently serves on the board of Lear Corporation. Martin is the chair of Wilson Sonsini Goodrich &amp; Rosati&#8217;s board of directors and a partner in the firm&#8217;s Palo Alto office. Jepsen and Martin will join existing board members Austin Russell (founder and CEO), Alec Gores, Matthew Simoncini, Scott McGregor and Ben Kortlang.</p>
<h3>Autonomous vehicles</h3>
<p><strong>Aurora</strong> reached a deal with Toyota and auto-parts supplier Denso to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/aurora-to-strikes-deal-with-toyota-denso-to-develop-test-self-driving-sienna-minivans/">develop and test vehicles</a> equipped with the self-driving startup&#8217;s technology, beginning with a fleet of Toyota Sienna minivans. Engineering teams from Aurora and Toyota will work together to design and build the self-driving Sienna minivans with an aim to start testing a fleet by the end of 2021, according to the companies.</p>
<p>Lest you forget, Aurora acquired in December Uber Advanced Technologies Group, the self-driving vehicle unit that spun out from Uber in 2019 after raising $1 billion in funding from Toyota, Denso and SoftBank&#8217;s Vision Fund. Aurora&#8217;s acquisition, which closed January 20, was actually a pretty complex deal in which Uber handed over its equity in ATG and invested $400 million into Aurora. Uber now holds a 26% stake in the combined company. Toyota also has a minority stake in Aurora as a result of the acquisition.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vdGueXIb5K"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/aurora-to-strikes-deal-with-toyota-denso-to-develop-test-self-driving-sienna-minivans/">Aurora strikes deal with Toyota, Denso to develop, test self-driving Sienna minivans</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Aurora strikes deal with Toyota, Denso to develop, test self-driving Sienna minivans&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/aurora-to-strikes-deal-with-toyota-denso-to-develop-test-self-driving-sienna-minivans/embed/#?secret=vdGueXIb5K" data-secret="vdGueXIb5K" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Aurora co-founder and chief product officer Sterling Anderson emphasized that this is a new partnership and not just an extension of Toyota&#8217;s agreement with Uber ATG. However, there are a lot of similarities to an agreement reached in 2018 between Toyota and Uber to bring an on-demand autonomous ride-hailing service to market. Under that deal, which included a $500 million investment by Toyota, the companies agreed to integrate Uber ATG&#8217;s self-driving technology into the Sienna minivans for use in Uber&#8217;s ride-hailing network. The vehicles later could be owned and operated by third-party fleet managers, Toyota and Uber ATG said at the time.</p>
<p><strong>Hyundai Motor Group</strong> showed off a new version of its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/hyundai-shrinks-its-walking-car-robot-to-carry-cargo-get-rides-from-drones/">&#8220;walking car&#8221; robot concept</a> that can use its wheels to roll along a path or stand up and navigate tougher terrain on its legs. This time, the concept is designed to carry cargo and is small enough to be carried by a drone. The TIGER robot &#8212; short for transforming intelligent ground excursion robot &#8212; is the first &#8220;uncrewed&#8221; ultimate mobility vehicle (UMV) concept to come out of New Horizons Studio, the Mountain View, California facility that is home to Hyundai Motor Group&#8217;s UMV development.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Z9n48pJypZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/hyundai-shrinks-its-walking-car-robot-to-carry-cargo-get-rides-from-drones/">Hyundai shrinks its &#8216;walking car&#8217; robot to carry cargo, get rides from drones</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hyundai shrinks its &#8216;walking car&#8217; robot to carry cargo, get rides from drones&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/hyundai-shrinks-its-walking-car-robot-to-carry-cargo-get-rides-from-drones/embed/#?secret=Z9n48pJypZ" data-secret="Z9n48pJypZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>While concepts oftentimes never become a reality, New Horizons Studio head John Suh told me that his aim is to bring Tiger to life &#8220;as soon as possible,&#8221; adding that it would likely be a five-year process. Suh said the team will spend the next two years focused on solving some core technical problems to establish a baseline design. In 2023 and 2024, the team will get to the beta-product stage and advanced testing will begin before finally becoming a product customers can buy.</p>
<h3>Delivery</h3>
<p><strong>Cajoo</strong>, a new French startup that raised a $7.3 million (€6 million) funding round, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/cajoo-promises-grocery-deliveries-in-15-minutes/">launched in Paris</a> this week. The company&#8217;s pitch: to make it easier to order groceries from your phone and receive them 15 minutes later. The company was founded by CEO Henri Capoul, who previously was at Bolt, along with Guillaume Luscan and Jeremy Gotteland. As Techcrunch&#8217;s Romain Dillet reported, Cajoo wants to differentiate itself with a full-stack approach. The startup operates its own micro-fulfillment centers. It has its own inventory of products. It manages the fleet of delivery people as much as possible. And, of course, it sells directly to customers.</p>
<h3>Electric</h3>
<p><strong>Audi</strong> revealed the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/audis-new-2022-e-tron-gt-is-a-real-electric-performance-sedan-not-just-another-electrified-crossover/">2022 e-tron Quattro GT</a> and its higher-performing sibling the RS e-tron GT — flagships of the German automaker’s growing electric vehicle portfolio and its first departure from the crossovers and SUVs that have so far dominated the lineup.</p>
<p><strong>Royal Dutch Shell Group </strong>laid out a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/ev-charging-stations-biofuels-the-hydrogen-transition-and-chemicals-are-pillars-of-shells-climate-plan/">five-pillar plan</a> that outlines how it will survive in a zero-emission, climate-conscious world. The plan includes installing 500,000 electric vehicle charging stations; the continued development of hydrogen and natural gas assets while slashing oil production by 1% to 2% per year; a greater emphasis on lubricants, chemicals and biofuels; expanding its renewable energy generation portfolio and carbon offsets; and investing in carbon capture and storage. As TechCrunch climate editor Jon Shieber noted, Shell&#8217;s plan to rollout 500,000 EV charger in just four years is the latest sign of an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/planning-500000-charging-points-for-evs-by-2025-shell-becomes-the-latest-company-swept-up-in-ev-charging-boom/">EV charging infrastructure boom</a> that has prompted investors to pour cash into the industry and inspired a few companies to become public companies in search of the capital needed to meet demand.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HCt5d2ISsA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/ev-charging-stations-biofuels-the-hydrogen-transition-and-chemicals-are-pillars-of-shells-climate-plan/">EV charging stations, biofuels, the hydrogen transition and chemicals are pillars of Shell&#8217;s climate plan</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;EV charging stations, biofuels, the hydrogen transition and chemicals are pillars of Shell&#8217;s climate plan&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/ev-charging-stations-biofuels-the-hydrogen-transition-and-chemicals-are-pillars-of-shells-climate-plan/embed/#?secret=HCt5d2ISsA" data-secret="HCt5d2ISsA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Tesla </strong>has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/tesla-summoned-by-chinese-regulators-for-quality-concerns/">been in talks</a> with a group of Chinese authorities, including the country&#8217;s top market regulator, cyberspace watchdog and transportation authority, after consumers complained about acceleration irregularities, battery fires, software upgrade failures and other vehicle problems, according to a government notice posted late Monday.</p>
<p>Tesla said on microblogging platform Weibo that it &#8220;sincerely accepts the government departments&#8217; guidance&#8221; and will &#8220;strictly comply with Chinese laws.&#8221; It will also work to strengthen its &#8220;internal operational structure and workflow&#8221; under the direction of the regulators in order to ensure safety and consumer rights. It&#8217;s hard not to notice the differences in Tesla&#8217;s tone between its dealings with China and the United States.</p>
<p><strong>Toyota Motor North America</strong> said it will bring <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/toyota-to-bring-three-new-electrified-vehicles-to-u-s-market/">three new electrified vehicles</a> to the U.S. market, as the automaker seeks to win over customers by offering a variety of lower emission and zero-emission cars and SUVs. Two of the new vehicles will be all-electric and one will be a plug-in hybrid, the company said Wednesday. Sales of the vehicles are expected to begin in 2022.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ve1CTK8fZQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/toyota-to-bring-three-new-electrified-vehicles-to-u-s-market/">Toyota to bring 3 new electrified vehicles to US market</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Toyota to bring 3 new electrified vehicles to US market&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/toyota-to-bring-three-new-electrified-vehicles-to-u-s-market/embed/#?secret=ve1CTK8fZQ" data-secret="ve1CTK8fZQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Flight</h3>
<p><strong>Aerion</strong>, which has been working on commercial supersonic flight for nearly a decade, signed a new partnership with NASA on supersonic point-to-point travel. The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/supersonic-jet-company-aerion-partners-with-nasa-on-high-speed-point-to-point-travel/">new collaboration</a> comes via the Space Act Agreement, which allows NASA to enlist the aid of private companies to help it achieve its various goals.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DqgxoqkFnE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/supersonic-jet-company-aerion-partners-with-nasa-on-high-speed-point-to-point-travel/">Supersonic jet company Aerion partners with NASA on high-speed point-to-point travel</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Supersonic jet company Aerion partners with NASA on high-speed point-to-point travel&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/supersonic-jet-company-aerion-partners-with-nasa-on-high-speed-point-to-point-travel/embed/#?secret=DqgxoqkFnE" data-secret="DqgxoqkFnE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Ride-hailing</h3>
<p><strong>Uber</strong> and <strong>Lyft</strong> lost a lot of money in 2020. As TechCrunch&#8217;s Alex Wilhelm noted this week (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/will-ride-hailing-profits-ever-come/">sub required</a>), that&#8217;s not a surprise, considering the COVID-19 headwinds that caused many ride-hailing markets to freeze as demand fell. Wilhelm unpacked both companies&#8217; full-year earnings, which were reported this past week. <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Uber&#8217;s revenue fell from $13 billion in 2019 to $11.1 billion in 2020. Lyft&#8217;s fell from $3.6 billion in 2019 to a far-smaller $2.4 billion in 2020.</span></p>
<p>Using normal accounting rules (which we like here), Uber <a href="https://investor.uber.com/news-events/news/press-release-details/2021/Uber-Announces-Results-for-Fourth-Quarter-and-Full-Year-2020/">lost $6.77 billion in 2020</a>, an improvement from its 2019 loss of $8.51 billion. However, if you lean on Uber’s definition of adjusted EBITDA, its 2019 and 2020 losses fall to $2.73 billion and $2.53 billion, respectively.</p>
<p>So what is this magic wand Uber is waving to make billions of dollars&#8217; worth of red ink go away? Answer: an adjusted EBITDA definition with <em>12</em> different categories of exclusion. Hey-o!</p>
<p>Wilhelm continues &#8230; if investors get what Uber promises, they will get an unprofitable company at the end of 2021, albeit one that, if you strip out a dozen categories of expense, is no longer running in the red. This, from a company worth north of $112 billion, feels like a very small promise.</p>
<p>And yet Uber shares have quadrupled from their pandemic lows, during which they fell under the $15 mark. Today Uber is worth more than $60 per share, despite shrinking last year and projecting years of losses (real), and possibly some (fake) profits later in the year. Wild.</p>
<p>Check out the rest of his piece at Extra Crunch, which reveals some of the good news that came out of Uber&#8217;s earnings as well as a dive into Lyft&#8217;s results.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oKKDsci5E9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/will-ride-hailing-profits-ever-come/">Will ride-hailing profits ever come?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Will ride-hailing profits ever come?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/will-ride-hailing-profits-ever-come/embed/#?secret=oKKDsci5E9" data-secret="oKKDsci5E9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/the-station-archer-aviations-two-big-scores-a-boost-for-ebikes-and-how-uber-defines-adjusted-ebitda/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2112991</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meet the Black Female Founders from TC Include at TC Sessions: Justice 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/meet-the-black-female-founders-from-tc-include-at-tc-sessions-justice-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/meet-the-black-female-founders-from-tc-include-at-tc-sessions-justice-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 16:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Include]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Sessions: Justice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2110191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On March 3, we’re hosting TC Sessions: Justice 2021, a day-long virtual conference dedicated to examining diversity and inclusion in tech. Tune in to presentations, panel discussions, breakout sessions and interactive Q&#38;As with key tech leaders. Topics range from accessible product design and fighting algorithmic bias to the justice system, workplace organizing and support for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">On March 3, we’re hosting <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/">TC Sessions: Justice 2021</a>, a day-long virtual conference dedicated to examining diversity and inclusion in tech. Tune in to presentations, panel discussions, breakout sessions and interactive Q&amp;As with key tech leaders. Topics range from accessible product design and fighting algorithmic bias to the justice system, workplace organizing and support for underrepresented founders — and that’s just for starters.</p>
<p>Don’t miss your chance to meet some founders currently participating in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/include/">TechCrunch&#8217;s Include</a> program. We partnered with various founder organizations — who in turn nominated promising early-stage startup founders — and collectively provide educational resources and mentorship to help these young founders develop and succeed over the course of the year. This collaborative program also includes prominent VC organizations like Kleiner Perkins, Salesforce Ventures and Initialized Capital to develop lasting mentorships with the TC Include founder cohort.</p>
<p>We joined forces with <a href="https://www.blackfemalefounders.org/">Black Female Founders</a>, and they nominated an impressive posse of early-stage startup founders. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/#tickets">Register for TC Sessions: Justice</a> to meet some of the visionary female founders who are part of the <a href="https://www.blackfemalefounders.org/">Black Female Founders</a> organization and watch them take part in a live pitch feedback session with TechCrunch during the event.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>We’ll be highlighting many more TC Include startups and founder organizations over the coming weeks, so keep checking back. And now, without further ado, behold the TC Include program startups sponsored by <a href="https://www.blackfemalefounders.org/">Black Female Founders</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://fivetonine.co/">Five to Nine</a>:</strong> Five to Nine is a Black and women-owned software company that enables organizers to track, manage and evaluate their events and programs for impact. Founded by Denise Umubyeyi.</li>
<li><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;MYAVANA&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:322,&quot;4&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:16773836},&quot;9&quot;:1,&quot;11&quot;:4}"><strong><a href="https://www.myavana.com/">MYAVANA</a></strong>: Myavana is a virtual hair care company that provides product recommendations and personalized guidance using AI technology and professional experts. Founded by Candace Mitchell Harris.</span></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.carpooltoschool.com/">Go Together, Inc.</a>:</strong> Go Together’s Carpool to School is a B2B SaaS platform that’s equitable, makes organizing school transportation convenient for parents and reduces per-student transportation cost for schools/districts. Founded by Kimberly Moore.</li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.kweli.tv/">kweliTV</a>:</strong> KweliTV allows you to discover and celebrate critically acclaimed and award-winning Black stories across the globe through curated indie films, documentaries, web series and live experiences. Founded by DeShuna Spencer.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://viledge.com/">Viledge</a>:</strong> Viledge connects Black businesses to new fans by curating gift boxes full of dope finds. Friends, co-workers and families can discover and share together in live unboxing experiences. Founded by Zuley Clarke.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.civiceagle.com/">Civic Eagle</a>:</strong> Civic Eagle is a SaaS company that helps organizations gain a strategic edge in advocacy and lobbying by using AI to unlock legislative data insights. Founded by Shawntera Hardy.</li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.unpacking.co/">Unpacking</a>:</strong> Unpacking is the No. 1 online learning platform for social impact. We&#8217;re disrupting boring, inefficient and outdated diversity training through real talk and interactive gaming. Founded by Kristina Williams.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://officialblackwallstreet.com/">Official Black Wall Street</a>:</strong> Official Black Wall Street is a digital platform and app connecting consumers to Black-owned businesses, while giving Black entrepreneurs the resources and exposure needed to thrive. Founded by Mandy Bowman.</li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.goseethecity.com/">Go See The City</a>:</strong> We drive foot traffic to local restaurants, brands and events by connecting customers to deep-discounted coupons. We then provide consumer analytics to small businesses and municipalities. Founded by Aneshai Smith.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/">TC Sessions: Justice </a>2021 takes place virtually on March 3. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/#tickets">Register today</a> and join us as we explore diversity, equity and inclusion in tech.</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring TC Sessions: Justice 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954"
			width="99%"
			height="500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/meet-the-black-female-founders-from-tc-include-at-tc-sessions-justice-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2110191</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calling Danish VCs: Be featured in The Great TechCrunch Survey of European VC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/calling-danish-vcs-be-featured-in-the-great-techcrunch-survey-of-european-vc/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/calling-danish-vcs-be-featured-in-the-great-techcrunch-survey-of-european-vc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 16:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Copenhagen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denmark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investor surveys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mediterranean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[survey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VC surveys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2112982</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TechCrunch is embarking on a major project to survey the venture capital investors of Europe, and their cities. Our survey of VCs in Copenhagen and Denmark will capture how the country is faring, and what changes are being wrought amongst investors by the coronavirus pandemic. We’d like to know how Denmark&#8217;s startup scene is evolving, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TechCrunch is embarking on a major project to <a href="https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6">survey</a> the venture capital investors of Europe, and their cities.</p>
<p>Our <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScxIbsFwgX_eWgro459gviqKSUxtVEFHOLirTBzp5IhvZOijw/viewform">survey</a> of VCs in Copenhagen and Denmark will capture how the country is faring, and what changes are being wrought amongst investors by the coronavirus pandemic.</p>
<p>We’d like to know how Denmark&#8217;s startup scene is evolving, how the tech sector is being impacted by COVID-19 and, generally, how your thinking will evolve from here.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Our survey will only be about investors, and <strong>only the contributions of VC investors will be included.</strong> More than one partner is welcome to fill out the survey. (Please note, if you have filled out the survey already, there is no need to do it again).</p>
<p>The shortlist of questions will require only brief responses, but the more you can add, the better.</p>
<p><a href="https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6"><strong>You can fill out the survey here.</strong></a></p>
<p>Obviously, investors who contribute will be featured in the final surveys, with links to their companies and profiles.</p>
<p>What kinds of things do we want to know? Questions include: Which trends are you most excited by? What startup do you wish someone would create? Where are the overlooked opportunities? What are you looking for in your next investment, in general? How is your local ecosystem going? And how has COVID-19 impacted your investment strategy?</p>
<p>This survey is part of a broader <a href="https://techcrunch.com/extra-crunch/investor-surveys/">series of surveys</a> we’re doing to help founders find the right investors.</p>
<p>For example, here is the recent <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/14-vcs-discuss-covid-19-and-londons-future-as-a-tech-hub/">survey of London</a>.</p>
<p>You are not in Denmark, but would like to take part? That&#8217;s fine! Any European VC investor can STILL fill out the survey, as we probably will be putting a call out to your country next anyway! And we will use the data for future surveys on vertical topics.</p>
<p>The survey is covering almost every country on in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Union_for_the_Mediterranean">Union for the Mediterranean</a>, so just look for your country and city on the <a href="https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6">survey</a> and please participate (<em>if</em> you&#8217;re a venture capital investor).</p>
<p>Thank you for participating. If you have questions you can email mike@techcrunch.com</p>
<p>(Please note: Filling out the survey is not a guarantee of inclusion in the final published piece.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rEzBclwyNQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/14-vcs-discuss-covid-19-and-londons-future-as-a-tech-hub/">14 VCs discuss COVID-19 and London&#8217;s future as a tech hub</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;14 VCs discuss COVID-19 and London&#8217;s future as a tech hub&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/14-vcs-discuss-covid-19-and-londons-future-as-a-tech-hub/embed/#?secret=rEzBclwyNQ" data-secret="rEzBclwyNQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/calling-danish-vcs-be-featured-in-the-great-techcrunch-survey-of-european-vc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2112982</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Investors&#8217; SPAC push could revamp the private market money game</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/investors-spac-push-could-revamp-the-private-market-money-game/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/investors-spac-push-could-revamp-the-private-market-money-game/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 16:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[khosla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lerer hippeau]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ribbit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2112946</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new era of venture, or just another temporary weirdness caused by zero-cost money and an overabundance of bored cash?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Since last year, we&#8217;ve been tracking the growing list of capitalists who got into the SPAC game. You can read an interview we conducted with Amish Jani, the co-founder of FirstMark Capital, about his SPAC <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/12/why-are-vcs-launching-spacs-amish-jani-of-firstmark-shares-his-firms-rationale/">here</a>. And if you need a refresher on all things SPAC, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/almost-everything-you-need-to-know-about-spacs/">we have that for you as well</a>.</p>
<p>This morning, I want to better understand the trend by parsing a few new venture capitalist SPACs. We&#8217;ll examine <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1841948/000119312521041594/d87587ds1.htm">Lerer Hippeau Acquisition Corp.</a> and <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1841873/000119312521041902/d32231ds1.htm">Khosla Ventures Acquisition Co. I</a>, <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1846069/000119312521041928/d255103ds1.htm">II</a> and <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1846068/000119312521041936/d111800ds1.htm">III</a>. The SPACs are, somewhat obviously, associated with New York-based Lerer Hippeau and Menlo Park&#8217;s Khosla Ventures. And all four dropped formal S-1 filings last week.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a>, or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>Today&#8217;s topic may sound dry, but it really does matter. As we&#8217;ve reported, Lux Capital <a href="https://luxcapital.com/companies/lux-health-tech-acquisition-corp/">is in</a> on the SPAC wager, along <a href="https://www.renaissancecapital.com/IPO-Center/News/71057/Ribbit-Capitals-fintech-SPAC-Ribbit-LEAP-prices-$350-million-IPO-at-$10">with Ribbit</a> and, of course, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2020-12-23/softbank-billionaire-masa-son-puts-a-new-spin-on-spac-mania">SoftBank</a>. Adding our latest names to the mix and you have to wonder if every VC worth a damn in the future will have their own raft of SPAC offerings.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995211 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>In that way, as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/17/the-paradox-of-2020-vc-is-that-the-largest-funds-are-doing-the-smallest-rounds/">some late-stage venture capital funds invest earlier</a> &#8212; and now later &#8212; full-service VC outfits will offer first check to final liquidity, will such a full-stack venture outfit be able to win more deals than a group offering a limited set of financing options? If so, the recent venture capital SPAC wave could become more of a rising tide in time, to torture a metaphor.</p>
<p>Regardless, let&#8217;s quickly parse what Khosla and Lerer Hippeau are telling <em>public</em> investors about why they will be great SPACers before working our way backward to what the resulting pitch must be to startups themselves.</p>
<h2>Full-stack capital</h2>
<p>The Lerer Hippeau SPAC is the most interesting of the two firms&#8217; combined four offerings, so we&#8217;ll start there. That isn&#8217;t to diss Khosla, but the Lerer Hippeau blank check has some explicit wording I want to highlight.</p>
<p>From the Lerer Hippeau Acquisition Corp. S-1 filing, read the following (bolding: TechCrunch):</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>As our seed portfolio matured over the last decade, we added a growth strategy to our platform through our select funds</strong>. This capital enables us to continue providing financial support to our top performing early-stage companies as they scale, and to selectively make new investments in later-stage companies in the Lerer Hippeau network. <strong>With our portfolio now maturing to the stage at which many are considering the public markets, we view SPACs as a natural next step in the evolution of our platform.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>After writing that it has had four portfolio companies &#8220;publicly announced business combination agreements with SPACs&#8221; and noting that it expects more of the same, Lerer Hippeau added that it considers its &#8220;expansion into the SPAC market as a highly complementary element of our strategy to support founders throughout their entrepreneurial journeys.&#8221;<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/investors-spac-push-could-revamp-the-private-market-money-game/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2112946</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notion&#8217;s hours-long outage was caused by phishing complaints</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/notions-hours-long-outage-was-caused-by-phishing-complaints/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/notions-hours-long-outage-was-caused-by-phishing-complaints/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 16:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Notion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sonic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spamming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top level domain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2112867</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last week&#8217;s hours-long outage at online workspace startup Notion was caused by phishing complaints, according to the startup&#8217;s domain registrar. Notion was offline for most of the morning on Friday, plunging its more than four million users into organization darkness because of what the company called a &#8220;very unusual DNS issue that occurred at the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last week&#8217;s hours-long outage at online workspace startup Notion was caused by phishing complaints, according to the startup&#8217;s domain registrar.</p>
<p>Notion was offline for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/notion-outage-dns-domain-issues/">most of the morning on Friday</a>, plunging its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/01/notion-hits-2-billion-valuation-in-new-raise/">more than four million users</a> into organization darkness because of what the company called a &#8220;very unusual DNS issue that occurred at the registry operator level.&#8221; With the company&#8217;s domain offline, users were unable to access their files, calendars, and documents.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">We&#39;re experiencing a DNS issue, causing the site to not resolve for many users. We are actively looking into this issue.</p>
<p>&mdash; Notion Status (@NotionStatus) <a href="https://twitter.com/NotionStatus/status/1360220589743480838?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 12, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Notion registered its domain name <code>notion.so</code> through Name.com, but all <code>.so</code> domains are managed by Hexonet, a company that helps connect Sonic, the <code>.so</code> top-level domain registry, with domain name registrars like Name.com.</p>
<p>That complex web of interdependence is in large part what led to the communications failure that resulted in Notion falling offline for hours.</p>
<p>In an email to TechCrunch, Name.com spokesperson Jared Ewy said: &#8220;Hexonet received complaints about user-generated Notion pages connected to phishing. They informed Name.com about these reports, but we were unable to independently confirm them. Per its policies, Hexonet placed a temporary hold on Notion&#8217;s domain.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Noting the impact of this action, all teams worked together to restore service to Notion and its users. All three teams are now partnering on new protocols to ensure this type of incident does not happen again. The Notion team and their avid followers were responsive and a pleasure to work with throughout. We thank everyone for their patience and understanding,&#8221; said Ewy.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lqKgtkLzuv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/notion-outage-dns-domain-issues/">Online workspace startup Notion hit by outage, citing DNS issues</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Online workspace startup Notion hit by outage, citing DNS issues&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/notion-outage-dns-domain-issues/embed/#?secret=lqKgtkLzuv" data-secret="lqKgtkLzuv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>It sounds like there&#8217;s no immediate danger of a repeat outage.</p>
<p>Notion did not respond to our emails prior to publication, but spokesperson Camille Ricketts later told TechCrunch: &#8220;We do not allow Notion to be used to host phishing sites. We have automated security software that scans for suspicious links on any pages associated with our domain and removes them.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;In this instance, a user had created a Notion page that linked out to a phishing site hosted elsewhere, and it was not flagged,&#8221; said Ricketts. &#8220;Even in this case, we&#8217;d typically be alerted to the issue by our domain vendors before service is blocked. This time, we weren&#8217;t notified. Now that we have a new communication protocol in place, we&#8217;re confident this type of issue won&#8217;t happen again.&#8221;</p>
<p>There are <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Notion/comments/hzje9k/people_using_notion_for_malicious_activities/">several</a> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Notion/comments/fpegan/notionso_blocked_at_work_help/">threads</a> on Reddit discussing concerns about Notion being used to host phishing sites, and security researchers <a href="https://www.trustwave.com/en-us/resources/blogs/spiderlabs-blog/phishing-in-the-cloud/">have shown examples</a> of Notion used in active phishing campaigns. A Notion employee <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Notion/comments/f6x9mk/why_the_so_domain/">said almost a year ago</a> that Notion would &#8220;soon&#8221; move its domain to <code>notion.com</code>, which the company owns.</p>
<p>Notion&#8217;s outage is almost identical to what happened with Zoho in 2018, which like Notion, resorted to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/24/zoho-pulled-offline-after-phishing-complaints-ceo-says/">tweeting at its domain registrar</a> after it blocked <code>zoho.com</code> following complaints about phishing emails sent from Zoho-hosted email accounts.</p>
<p><em>Updated with comment from Notion.</em></p>
<p><strong>Read more:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/notion-outage-dns-domain-issues/">Online workspace startup Notion hit by outage, citing DNS issues</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/ancestry-police-warrant-dna-database/">Ancestry says it fought two police requests to search its DNA database</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/a-webcam-app-left-thousands-of-user-accounts-exposed-online/">A webcam app left thousands of user accounts exposed online</a></li>
<li><strong>Extra Crunch:</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/decrypted-hackers-attempt-to-poison-florida-towns-water-supply/">A hacker attempted to poison Florida town’s water supply</a></li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CTP0IUeXMJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/decrypted-hackers-attempt-to-poison-florida-towns-water-supply/">Decrypted: A hacker attempted to poison Florida town&#8217;s water supply</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Decrypted: A hacker attempted to poison Florida town&#8217;s water supply&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/decrypted-hackers-attempt-to-poison-florida-towns-water-supply/embed/#?secret=CTP0IUeXMJ" data-secret="CTP0IUeXMJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/notions-hours-long-outage-was-caused-by-phishing-complaints/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2112867</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Equity Monday: The electric car boom, tech regulation and some sad American VC data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/equity-monday-the-electric-car-boom-tech-regulation-and-some-sad-american-vc-data/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/equity-monday-the-electric-car-boom-tech-regulation-and-some-sad-american-vc-data/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 15:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Libeo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vw]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2112939</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. This is Equity Monday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/940a54d9-015f-4961-93a1-d7527556a3be?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>This is Equity Monday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You can follow the show on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/equitypod">here</a> and myself <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">here</a> — and be sure to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/does-softbank-have-20-more-doordashes/">check out our riff on whether SoftBank has another 20 DoorDashes waiting in the wings</a>.</p>
<p>This morning was a more relaxed Monday than I can recall in months, thanks to a holiday in many parts of the world. But that didn&#8217;t stop us from parsing the news:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Weekend: </strong>This <a href="https://cyber.fsi.stanford.edu/io/news/clubhouse-china">investigation</a> into Clubhouse&#8217;s data security is getting results, while over the weekend Dispo got huge in a hurry, and the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-meets-apple-in-clash-of-the-tech-titanswe-need-to-inflict-pain-11613192406?mod=djemalertNEWS">Apple-Facebook dynamic got a better explaining</a>. Increasingly the tech-giant world feels like ad engines (Facebook, Alphabet) in opposition to software-and-hardware shops (Microsoft, Apple).</li>
<li><strong>This morning: </strong>GM has new electric cars, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/14/gm-unveils-a-refreshed-chevy-bolt-ev-and-its-bigger-yet-compact-crossover-sibling/">TechCrunch reports</a>. VW <a href="https://appleinsider.com/articles/21/02/14/vw-chief-not-afraid-of-apple-car-entering-the-market">isn&#8217;t worried</a> about Apple. And every EV company in the world is going public via a SPAC. Who will win? You can place your own bets. And <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/india-lifts-restrictions-on-mapping-and-surveying-to-help-local-firms/">India is loosening some tech regulation</a>. The American stock market is closed.</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LUtD0MeqyV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/14/gm-unveils-a-refreshed-chevy-bolt-ev-and-its-bigger-yet-compact-crossover-sibling/">GM unveils a refreshed Chevy Bolt EV and its bigger, yet compact crossover sibling</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GM unveils a refreshed Chevy Bolt EV and its bigger, yet compact crossover sibling&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/14/gm-unveils-a-refreshed-chevy-bolt-ev-and-its-bigger-yet-compact-crossover-sibling/embed/#?secret=LUtD0MeqyV" data-secret="LUtD0MeqyV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<ul>
<li><strong>Funding Rounds: </strong>We chatted about <a href="https://tech.eu/brief/libeo-series-a/">the recent Libeo round</a>, and <a href="https://www.pymnts.com/news/investment-tracker/2021/startup-nymbus-closes-53-million-series-c-to-scale-baas/">the latest on Nymbus</a>, both of which are more than cool.</li>
</ul>
<p>And, finally, read this if you want to feel let down by American VCs. (American media, to be clear,<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/may/25/enduring-whiteness-of-american-journalism"> has similar issues</a>.)</p>
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST and Thursday afternoon as fast as we can get it out, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts.</i></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fHbr4zDjXe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/does-softbank-have-20-more-doordashes/">Does SoftBank have 20 more DoorDashes?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Does SoftBank have 20 more DoorDashes?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/does-softbank-have-20-more-doordashes/embed/#?secret=fHbr4zDjXe" data-secret="fHbr4zDjXe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/equity-monday-the-electric-car-boom-tech-regulation-and-some-sad-american-vc-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2112939</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Uber lobbies for &#8216;Prop 22&#8217;-style gig work standards in the EU</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/uber-lobbies-for-prop-22-style-gig-work-standards-in-the-eu/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/uber-lobbies-for-prop-22-style-gig-work-standards-in-the-eu/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 14:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gig economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[platform regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2112465</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Uber is shooting its shot at EU lawmakers as they dial up scrutiny of working conditions on gig platforms to decide whether new rules are needed to improve the lot of gig workers. The ride-hailing and on-demand food delivery giant has published a white paper today in which it lobbies European policymakers for what it [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Uber is shooting its shot at EU lawmakers as they dial up scrutiny of working conditions on gig platforms to decide whether new rules are needed to improve the lot of gig workers.</p>
<p>The ride-hailing and on-demand food delivery giant has published a <a href="https://www.uber.com/global/en/reports/a-better-deal">white paper</a> today in which it lobbies European policymakers for what it couches as a &#8220;new standard&#8221; for platform work.</p>
<p>In the paper Uber talks of the need to expand some benefits to gig workers &#8212; seeking to eschew the nightmare scenario (for Uber) of having to fund the full suite of employment rights if its drivers and riders were reclassified as workers/employees.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It&#8217;s also trying to steer policy discussion away from issue of collective bargaining &#8212; with the paper floating the notion that app workers need more &#8220;meaningful&#8221; representation, which they say is needed to reflect varying (aka individualized) needs, and suggest could be achieved via a variety of channels of ongoing engagement between platform and worker.</p>
<p>Uber&#8217;s white paper is framed with the title: &#8220;A Better Deal&#8221;. And the ride-hailing giant is unquestionably after the best possible deal for its business as lawmakers look at whether new laws are needed to ensure a fairer deal for app-based workers.</p>
<p>The question EU lawmakers will need to pay close attention to in the coming months is exactly what kind of deal platforms workers are getting and, as they dig into the detail underlying tech giants&#8217; PR, whether and how to create a legislative framework that improves conditions for armies of &#8220;contractors&#8221; without undermining the much vaunted European social contract.</p>
<p>Uber has said it will <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/after-prop-22s-passage-uber-is-taking-its-lobbying-effort-global/">push for a California style &#8220;Prop 22&#8221; outcome globally</a> &#8212; after successfully defeating a law to reclassify gig workers in its own backyard last year.</p>
<p>But the legal and social context is very different in Europe, where many platforms have faced litigation on the issue of employment classification and courts have frequently found in workers&#8217; favor.</p>
<p>On Friday Uber faces perhaps its biggest regional court test yet when the U.K. Supreme Court is expected to hand down its verdict on a long-running challenge by a group of former Uber drivers to its classification of them as self-employed. (The U.K. is now outside the EU but the outcome of the case is nonetheless likely to influence courts across the region.)</p>
<p>Greater clarification and enforcement of existing employment laws could be a way for policymakers in Europe to clamp down on platform giants that, critics say, have used self-serving classifications of algorithmic micromanagement as a high-tech hack of the legal system to profit at the expense of society (in lost tax revenue) and off the labor of individual workers deprived of stable employment (and its associated rights).</p>
<p>At the same time, increasing consolidation in the on-demand space is concentrating the power of gig giants. So how can platform workers expect &#8220;meaningful&#8221; representation or &#8220;improved&#8221; conditions when a handful of mega platforms are busy closing off the possibility of something better by assimilating the competition &#8212; unless there&#8217;s a legislative intervention to protect them?</p>
<p>In a blog post accompanying Uber&#8217;s white paper today, CEO Dara Khosrowshahi reiterates the tech giant&#8217;s preferred &#8220;new standard&#8221; for gig worker rights should be &#8220;grounded in the principles drivers and couriers say are most important to them: Flexibility and control over when and where they want to work, earning a decent wage, access to relevant benefits and protections, and meaningful representation&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;To make a real difference, reform must also be industry-wide, requiring all platform companies to offer benefits and protections that are standardised across the sector, so that workers are protected no matter which apps they use,&#8221; Khosrowshahi goes on.</p>
<p>A universal standard for platform benefits may sound progressive, but the notion of &#8220;relevant&#8221; benefits for gig workers risks fixing this labor force to a floor far below agreed standards for employment &#8212; closing off any chance of a better deal for a class of workers who are subject to persistent, algorithmic management.</p>
<p>Such an industry-wide standard may also kill the imperative for gig platforms to compete with each other by offering workers a better deal. So policymakers need to tread carefully to avoid cementing a bad deal for workers they claim they want to help.</p>
<p>Uber&#8217;s white paper is pushing for some key principles at this point, rather than delineating a detailed &#8220;deal&#8221; model for workers &#8212; which the company says would need to be developed in consultation with stakeholders.</p>
<p>It also says it recognizes that platforms are likely to remain subject to a patchwork of national rules across the EU. And even if the Commission opts to legislate it would be years before such laws take effect &#8212; so case law will remain hugely important. But Uber is evidently keen to try to steer any overarching EU guidance which might exert top-down pressure on how Member States approach and apply policy in the area of gig work.</p>
<p>Platform giants have long sought to frame employment classification as a question of &#8220;flexibility vs benefits&#8221; &#8212; claiming workers value flexibility (which they define as meaning &#8220;the ability to choose when to work&#8221;) above all else, even as they apply datafication and tracking to manage individuals&#8217; service delivery via high-tech micromanagement of a non-employed labor force.</p>
<p>Thing is: Sure you can log on to such a platform to work &#8220;when you choose&#8221; but without legal protections such as a mandatory minimum wage there&#8217;s no guarantee that gig work &#8220;flexibility&#8221; will sum to a livable income for the individual. Which in turn means platform workers may not have <em>de facto</em> flexibility/freedom to choose when and how they work &#8212; unless they have other income to rely on.</p>
<p>The platforms are therefore often pushing a paradoxical defence of a business model that critics accuse of being abusive by design &#8212; with critical unions dubbing it exploitative and extractive of human labor, accusing platforms of circumventing the social contract and stability offered by traditional employment.</p>
<p>In a section of Uber&#8217;s white paper that argues why &#8220;employment is not the answer for platform workers&#8221; the tech giant points on cue to &#8220;flexibility&#8221; &#8212; saying its model means that &#8220;drivers can connect freely to meet that demand or choose a quieter time of day if they wish&#8221;. Yet people who need to earn a living may not be able to &#8220;choose&#8221; a quieter time of day if they&#8217;re being paid by the job, since doing so would reduce their earnings, so how much flexibility (or pay decency) does Uber really offer?</p>
<p>(Related: The large sums of money many of these gig giants have spent on trying to accelerate the development of automation technologies; ergo, money they save on not paying employment-linked taxes is being ploughed into trying to replace human workers entirely. So where&#8217;s the dignity in that?)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="V7ommeQe3M"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/12/ubers-self-driving-car-unit-was-burning-20-million-a-month/">Uber&#8217;s self-driving car unit was burning $20 million a month</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Uber&#8217;s self-driving car unit was burning $20 million a month&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/12/ubers-self-driving-car-unit-was-burning-20-million-a-month/embed/#?secret=V7ommeQe3M" data-secret="V7ommeQe3M" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Decision time for the gig economy</h2>
<p>In her December 2019 <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/commissioners/sites/comm-cwt2019/files/commissioner_mission_letters/mission-letter-nicolas-schmit_en.pdf">mission letter</a> to the job commissioner, the European Commission president Ursula Von der Leyen tasked Nicolas Schmit with looking at<em> &#8220;</em>ways to improve the labour conditions of platform workers<em>&#8221; &#8212;</em> including by ensuring that enforcement of current laws is working &#8212; writing that: <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;Dignified, transparent and predictable working conditions are essential to our economic model.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Soon after Schmit got his instructions, he sounded a balanced tone on the contentious issue of platform (profits) versus worker (rights), telling <a href="https://www.euractiv.com/section/global-europe/news/nicolas-schmit-the-first-dignity-of-work-is-to-pay-people-a-fair-wage/">Euroactiv</a> that he&#8217;s &#8220;not against platforms&#8221;, and sees them as &#8220;part of our new economy&#8221; &#8212; arguing too that it&#8217;s &#8220;important for Europe, not to lose the edge with this economy&#8221;.</p>
<p>But he also warned that the bloc must not allow high-tech tools to be used to embed a new &#8220;underprivileged&#8221; worker underclass, saying: &#8220;We cannot have the economy of the 21st century with working conditions that are more comparable to those in the 19th century.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TAK7PPOfRw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/24/deliveroos-flexible-labor-model-likened-to-20th-century-dockyards/">Deliveroo&#8217;s &#8216;flexible&#8217; labor model likened to 20th century dockyards</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Deliveroo&#8217;s &#8216;flexible&#8217; labor model likened to 20th century dockyards&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/24/deliveroos-flexible-labor-model-likened-to-20th-century-dockyards/embed/#?secret=TAK7PPOfRw" data-secret="TAK7PPOfRw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Quite how the Commission will square the circle of &#8220;improving&#8221; precarious platform work in policy terms remains to be seen. But the imperative for it to do good work here has only increased since Von der Leyen issued the instruction: The coronavirus pandemic has shone an excoriating spotlight on the risks &#8212; individual and societal &#8212; of the lack of a proper social safety net for platform workers, even as on-demand platform work (especially in areas like food and grocery delivery) has been fired up as a side effect of COVID-19.</p>
<p>Uber&#8217;s white paper riffs on the theme of the pandemic and the need for platform businesses to &#8220;go further&#8221; in supporting workers &#8212; aka &#8220;to ensure independent workers have access to benefits and protections when they need them most&#8221;, as it puts it &#8212; even as it lobbies against providing all the rights and benefits of employment.</p>
<p>&#8220;It makes sense for them to be pushing for a minimum standard of benefits,&#8221; says Joe Aiston, senior associate in the employment group at international law firm Taylor Wessing, discussing Uber lobbying for a &#8220;new standard&#8221; for gig work in the white paper. &#8220;As sort of appropriate minimums/protections. And perhaps things which are easier to give without significant disruption to the business model.</p>
<p>&#8220;Whereas having to reclassify everyone as employees or as workers would involve quite significant disruption to the business model &#8212; and is obviously going to result in significant extra cost for them as a business. Both from the point of view of things like minimum wage and holiday pay, but also the potential knock-on effect from a tax perspective as well.&#8221;</p>
<p>And whilst analysis of worker status does not automatically make those people employees for tax purposes,  Aiston says tests are &#8220;pretty similar&#8221;. Hence litigation over employment classification presents a clear risk to Uber&#8217;s tax status &#8212; and thus to its (potential) profitability.</p>
<p>On the issue of how to improve gig work, the European Commission has been gathering evidence as it works toward determining how best to proceed &#8212; including holding a conference on platform work last September. But big decisions are looming for EU lawmakers this year.</p>
<p>Later this month the Commission will launch a formal consultation of workers&#8217; and employers&#8217; representatives. And Uber&#8217;s white paper is clearly targeted at that process so we&#8217;re likely to see a number of self-interested attempts to influence platform working condition &#8220;improvements&#8221; kick off in earnest.</p>
<p>Exactly what will be in play, policy wise, isn&#8217;t yet clear. But, last March, the Commission published a 285-page <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/social/main.jsp?langId=en&amp;catId=89&amp;newsId=9582&amp;furtherNews=yes">study</a> in which it said the &#8220;main&#8221; challenges identified vis-à-vis the working conditions of platform workers include: Employment status; information available to the workers about their working conditions; dispute resolution; collective rights and non-discrimination. (So pretty much a full house, then.)</p>
<p>Dig into the actual study and it also discusses low remuneration and insecure income in plenty of detail and as &#8220;significant stressors&#8221; for platform workers.</p>
<p>Pay certainly looks set to be a significant area of discussion/contention &#8212; not least because another of Von der Leyen&#8217;s instructions to Schmit asked him to put forward a legal instrument &#8220;to ensure that every worker in our Union has a fair minimum wage&#8221;.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a common criticism of platform work that earnings may fall below the legal minimum for a worker (as pay by gig jobs typically only generate earnings during a job or on completion of a delivery, not for all the down time spent waiting to score a gig or pick up the goods). So if the EU&#8217;s fair minimum wage for &#8220;every worker&#8221; ends up meaning &#8220;except platform workers&#8221; that will sum to the Commission rubberstamping a tech-enabled &#8220;underprivileged&#8221; worker class &#8212; just as Schmit said it mustn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>Uber&#8217;s approach to the issue of pay in its white paper sidesteps the minimum wage issue by talking only of &#8220;fair and transparent earnings&#8221; (or &#8220;decent&#8221; pay) for platform workers.</p>
<p>The tech giant also says it&#8217;s &#8220;ready to lead the industry by advocating for changes to the way platform workers are paid&#8221; &#8212; though it makes it clear it won&#8217;t budge on remuneration without the sought for industry-wide enabling framework (&#8220;for flexible earning opportunities, with industry-wide benefits and protections that all platform companies must offer independent workers&#8221;).</p>
<p>&#8220;This could include universal standards, such as the Proposition 22 legislation recently introduced in California. Or it could be based on a European model of social dialogue, where platform workers, policy-makers and industry representatives work together to set earning principles for the industry,&#8221; Uber suggests.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PsCwy8TOYn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/after-prop-22s-passage-uber-is-taking-its-lobbying-effort-global/">After Prop 22&#8217;s passage, Uber is taking its lobbying effort global</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;After Prop 22&#8217;s passage, Uber is taking its lobbying effort global&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/after-prop-22s-passage-uber-is-taking-its-lobbying-effort-global/embed/#?secret=PsCwy8TOYn" data-secret="PsCwy8TOYn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;For example, in Italy the food delivery industry and the General Labour Union signed an agreement confirming the self employed status of couriers while requiring the industry to provide working standards for couriers, including provisions about earnings, injury, third-party insurance and training.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Critically, whatever the earning model, it must be based on an industry-wide level playing field to ensure all independent workers have a consistent earnings baseline, whichever platform they choose to work with,&#8221; Uber adds.</p>
<p>Clearly, then, the stakes are high all round on this one: For gig workers&#8217; rights; for platform giants&#8217; profits; and for EU lawmakers&#8217; credibility in claiming a socially progressive agenda.</p>
<p>Although it&#8217;s not 100% certain the bloc will come with legislation at this point, either. A Commission spokeswoman suggested policymaking could be off the table if platforms and workers can come to a consensus agreement over what &#8220;better&#8221; precarious work looks like. (But, yeah, good luck with that.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aCQSxcME75"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/jobandtalent-tops-up-with-108m-for-its-workforce-as-a-service-platform/">Jobandtalent tops up with $108M for its &#8216;workforce as a service&#8217; platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Jobandtalent tops up with $108M for its &#8216;workforce as a service&#8217; platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/jobandtalent-tops-up-with-108m-for-its-workforce-as-a-service-platform/embed/#?secret=aCQSxcME75" data-secret="aCQSxcME75" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The formal consultation of &#8220;social partners&#8221; that&#8217;s set to kick off later this month will consist of two stages, per the Commission spokeswoman.</p>
<p>&#8220;The first stage seeks their views on the need of a possible EU initiative to improve the working conditions of people working through platforms. In the second stage, they will be consulted on the possible content of such an initiative,&#8221; she said, noting that the Commission will &#8220;carefully assess social partners’ replies&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;Provided social partners do not decide to negotiate an agreement among themselves, the Commission intends to put forward a legislative initiative by the end of 2021,&#8221; she added.</p>
<p>The spokeswoman confirmed that the policy areas where challenges had been identified &#8212; and where &#8220;improvements may be needed&#8221; &#8212; include &#8220;precarious working conditions, transparency and predictability of contractual arrangements, health and safety challenges and adequate access to social protection&#8221;.</p>
<p>Asked to confirm whether &#8220;precarious working conditions&#8221; includes low and unstable remuneration she declined to specify, saying: &#8220;I’m afraid the [aforementioned list] is as far as we can go regarding the initiative at this stage.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Employment status</h2>
<p>Among a number of policy considerations summarized at the end of the Commission-instigated study into gig worker conditions is the statement that employment status remains a core challenge.</p>
<p>&#8220;Some platforms seem to operate at the margins between self-employed and employee, adjusting practices to maximise control over platform workers without unequivocally assuming the role of employers,&#8221; the report observes, noting the discrepancy between the (plodding) pace of case law clarifying where the employment classification line lies and the &#8220;fast-changing business practices characterising platform work&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;Unless Member States widen the concept of employee or introduce a rebuttable presumption on the employment status of platform workers [through legislation or case law], platforms are likely to continue or expand their reliance on labour from self-employed individuals,&#8221; it continues.</p>
<p>&#8220;Reclassification of individual cases may happen on the basis of EU law or on national legislation, but it is unlikely that this will drastically reverse the main trend.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Actions aimed at protecting self-employed platform workers who are economically dependent on the platforms to ensure some minimum standards as to their ‘working conditions’ seem advisable,&#8221; the report also adds &#8212; while an associated &#8220;policy implication&#8221; suggests that the EU and Member States &#8220;should consider clarifying which platform practices are incompatible with self-employment for platform workers&#8221;.</p>
<p>Clarification of self-employment tests &#8212; or of practices that should fail the test &#8212; is one way for pan-EU policymakers to move. Though, again, it remains to be seen which ideas the Commission will choose to champion as it takes more feedback on the gig economy.</p>
<p>On the employment classification case law front, a major decision is looming in the U.K. in relation to Uber&#8217;s ride-hailing business. A 2016 employment tribunal challenge to Uber&#8217;s classification drivers as self employed is headed for a final judgement on Friday &#8212; when the U.K. Supreme Court is expected to deliver its verdict on a case that has seen <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/10/uber-loses-uk-tribunal-appeal-over-driver-employment-rights/">Uber lose</a> a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/19/uber-loses-another-appeal-against-drivers-rights-in-uk/">number of appeals</a> over the last five years.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court ruling will likely have ramifications for the ~45,000 drivers who Uber says operate on its platform in London &#8212; and likely more widely across the U.K.</p>
<p>It could also ripple out beyond that, given the active attention now being paid to improving the lot of gig workers by EU policymakers.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/04/uber-driver-reclassified-as-employee-in-france/">Last year</a> a French court of last resort<a href="https://www.courdecassation.fr/jurisprudence_2/communiques_presse_8004/prestation_chauffeur_9665/press_release_44526.html"> ruled</a> that a former Uber driver should have been considered an employee instead of a self-employed partner. It found there was a relationship of subordination between the company and the driver &#8212; flagging issues such as the inability of drivers to set prices; build their own customer base; or choose how to execute a task. “The driver participates in a managed transportation service and Uber unilaterally defines the operating terms,” it wrote.</p>
<p>However, Uber denied the case set a precedent while also claiming to have made a number of changes to how its platform operates since the challenge was lodged in 2017 &#8212; suggesting drivers have been given more control over how they use Uber and now have greater &#8220;stronger social protections&#8221; (such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/07/25/uber-is-going-to-provide-accident-insurance-in-france-for-free/">free accident insurance</a>).</p>
<p>The case underlines the difficulties of relying on complaint-based case law to shape coherent outcomes for platform workers, plural.</p>
<p>The length of time such challenges take to reach a final outcome also give the platforms plenty of time to reconfigure their operations so they can at least try to claim specific findings no longer apply.</p>
<p>So legislation may indeed be required to lock in improvements for the conditions of gig workers.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s true to say that things can change &#8212; so if Uber, following [the Supreme Court] decision materially change how the business model works then it&#8217;s possible they could then bring the drivers outside of the definition again,&#8221; says Aiston, although he points out the required changes in that context may, as it turns out, not be &#8220;acceptable&#8221; to Uber.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ll have to wait to see what the variables the Supreme Court decides push it one way or the other but they would have to make a determination as to whether it works in the context of their business model to make such potentially significant changes to how things work,&#8221; he goes on, adding: &#8220;I suspect that they may already have been putting in place changes to how the business model works &#8212; perhaps to prepare for the judgement.</p>
<p>&#8220;So I guess the point there is the case law is so context-specific that that&#8217;s an argument to say that actually legislation and specific definitions are key rather than perhaps relying on very specific case law.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Commission&#8217;s study also notes a number of challenges holding back policymaking in this area &#8212; even things as basic as clearly defining platform work; or gathering sufficiently comprehensive data to inform evidence-based policymaking.</p>
<p>&#8220;Once someone is classified as a worker, rather than an independent contractor, then that does potentially increased their ability and right to collectively bargain &#8212; so it&#8217;s another potential knock on effect should the Supreme Court decision go against Uber,&#8221; adds Aiston. &#8220;It might lead to the potential for a greater ability for their drivers/riders to collectively bargain so that will be something the relevant unions are looking out for keenly as well.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QzQgL8lJA2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/23/spains-top-court-rejects-glovos-classification-of-couriers-as-self-employed/">Spain&#8217;s top court rejects Glovo&#8217;s classification of couriers as self-employed</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Spain&#8217;s top court rejects Glovo&#8217;s classification of couriers as self-employed&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/23/spains-top-court-rejects-glovos-classification-of-couriers-as-self-employed/embed/#?secret=QzQgL8lJA2" data-secret="QzQgL8lJA2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Attempts to regulate and legislate are, meanwhile, in train in Europe at a national level. Such as in Spain where the government has sought for several years to crack down on platforms using so called &#8220;<em>falsos autonomos</em>&#8221; (aka falsely self-employed workers), and is in the process of <a href="https://www.businessinsider.es/trabajo-creara-ley-acabar-falsos-autonomos-riders-586109">reforming labor laws</a> to reflect and capture platform work.</p>
<p>That national labor reform process could result in platforms being required to hire delivery workers, per <a href="https://www.elmundo.es/economia/2021/02/10/6024035e21efa06b6c8b465a.html">recent reports</a> &#8212; and such moves give platform giants added incentive to lobby the Commission for &#8220;more flexible&#8221; pan-EU rules which may at least limit how far national law can travel to influence rules on the grounds elsewhere in the bloc (so limit potential damage to their business model).</p>
<p>The U.K. government has also suggested legislation is coming. It conducted a major <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/good-work-the-taylor-review-of-modern-working-practices">review of modern working practices</a> back in 2017 &#8212; which included looking at gig work. And among the Taylor Review&#8217;s recommendations was that the current (U.K.) legal classification of &#8220;worker&#8221; should be updated to better reflect gig work &#8212; with the report suggesting &#8220;dependent contractor&#8221; would be a more appropriate framing now &#8212; and also that greater focus should be paid to the control exercised over workers by platforms.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The review led to a </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/07/uk-outs-plan-to-bolster-gig-economy-workers-rights/">government plan</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> to bolster worker rights, as it was billed with much fanfare. </span>However, the &#8220;Good Work Plan&#8221; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/17/uk-workplace-rights-reform-doesnt-look-disruptive-to-gig-economy-giants/">reform package</a> unveiled at the end of 2018 was instantly dismissed as weak and lacking substance by labor unions (versus the government trumpeting it as a massive expansion of workers rights). Not that it seems to have done much to address gig work specifically, as yet.</p>
<p>A commitment by the U.K. government as part of that plan in 2018 by the U.K. government to legislate to improve the clarity of employment status tests &#8212; in order to “reflect the reality of the modern working relationships” &#8212; has not <a href="https://commonslibrary.parliament.uk/employment-law-in-the-modern-economy-the-good-work-plan/">amounted to anything yet</a>.</p>
<p>The planned legislation may have been delayed as a result of the pandemic. Aiston suggests it&#8217;s also possible the government is waiting for the Supreme Court judgement in the Uber tribunal case to inform its policy thinking. So for all Uber&#8217;s slick regional PR push to influence policymaking, it may have relatively little say in the matter versus European case law and the court of public opinion.</p>
<p>&#8220;If the Supreme Court judgement does against [Uber] in the sense that the drivers were workers I think that&#8217;s probably going to make things at least a bit more difficult for them. Because in the UK at least they&#8217;re going to have decide that well either we accept that all drivers are workers or &#8212; depending on reasons given for the judgement &#8212; can we adjust our business model to bring it away from that analysis,&#8221; says Aiston.</p>
<p>&#8220;They may be keen to do the latter, on the basis that they are obviously keen to keep people being self-employed rather than workers but I guess from a PR perspective that might not look great for them to do that. Once a judgement has been made that they are workers, one view is that you just need to accept that now and move on and acknowledge that they have those rights.&#8221;</p>
<p>He points to examples of gig economy companies trying to &#8220;pre-empt or negate&#8221; the risk of reclassification of &#8220;self-employed&#8221; contractors as workers by putting in place benefits packages &#8212; such as Uber offering free or low cost insurances to drivers and riders in Europe &#8212; &#8220;to show that they are a &#8216;good&#8217; company and they want to look after people&#8221;.</p>
<p>Such efforts fall short of the suite of rights reclassified platform workers <em>could</em> get so there&#8217;s more movement that could happen here &#8212; and may have to in order to keep the travelling public on side.</p>
<p>&#8220;They tend not to go to the extreme and say well we&#8217;ll acknowledge that they&#8217;re workers and therefore they&#8217;re entitled to minimum wage and their rest breaks and that kind of thing. So it&#8217;s something to look out for as well with these gig economy businesses,&#8221; Aiston suggests. &#8220;I think it will become more competitive from that perspective.</p>
<p>&#8220;Whether or not they acknowledge that people are workers is one thing but I think you can see a definite move towards gig economy businesses realizing that they have a duty to look after people&#8230; Obviously that serves a dual purpose of people getting some benefits but also it being a positive thing from a PR perspective and the point of view of the public view of these companies.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also worth noting that U.K. employment law is more nuanced than some national employment law &#8212; as it does already recognize the concept of a &#8220;worker&#8221; (i.e. not an employee and not self-employed) &#8212; while Aiston notes some other European countries (and also the U.S.) have a more limited set of classifications (i.e. employed versus self employed).</p>
<p>&#8220;European courts will look to things like the Supreme Court decision in the UK. And whilst they&#8217;re not bound by that decision you can imagine that the way that this swings will have at least some kind of knock-on effect to how any similar judgements are taken across Europe,&#8221; he suggests. &#8220;The interesting thing to bear in mind is that in the UK we have this middle classification of a worker. Whereas in most European countries you&#8217;re either self employed, a contractor or an employee. So there&#8217;s a bigger dichotomy elsewhere in Europe.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;In a way the UK&#8217;s in a better position because we have this middle ground. And some people might say that has made the UK courts be in a position more easily to reclassify &#8212; assuming that the Supreme Court goes the same was as the court of appeal did [in the Uber employment tribunal case], which was to state that these drivers were in fact workers. So it&#8217;s important to note there&#8217;s a difference there,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p>&#8220;In the UK you can understand why it has perhaps been a bit more easy for a court to make a decision that the driver should fit within this middle category where they attract some protections but not all of them.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iJbmMuHcpy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/17/uk-workplace-rights-reform-doesnt-look-disruptive-to-gig-economy-giants/">UK workplace rights reform doesn&#8217;t look disruptive to gig economy giants</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;UK workplace rights reform doesn&#8217;t look disruptive to gig economy giants&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/17/uk-workplace-rights-reform-doesnt-look-disruptive-to-gig-economy-giants/embed/#?secret=iJbmMuHcpy" data-secret="iJbmMuHcpy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>If EU policymakers were to decide to create a pan-EU standard akin to &#8220;worker&#8221; that would present a huge opportunity/risk for Uber et al. &#8212; with the chance to influence key parameters in their interests as a means of reducing the threat employment litigation poses to their core business model (and staving off a larger tax bill).</p>
<p>Though there will clearly be costs involved in an expansion of the level of protection offered to gig workers. The question for tech giants would be how much they can shrink those costs &#8212; aka what&#8217;s the bare minimum in &#8220;relevant&#8221; standards they can sell across Europe?</p>
<p>Alternatively, EU lawmakers could seek to stipulate and enforce a list of &#8220;dos and don&#8217;ts&#8221; for platforms vis-à-vis workers &#8212; as a way to establish appropriately &#8220;fair&#8221; operational employment limits &#8212; which in turn might have the potential to be disruptive to the business model of on-demand giants whose profits (often still <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-uber-results/uber-sees-profit-by-end-of-2020-but-still-expects-full-year-loss-idINKBN2002UQ">theoretical</a> at this point) depend on access to plentiful, low cost labor supplied by lots of people they claim not to employ.</p>
<p>Setting a list of specific operational requirements for platforms is exactly what the Commission has proposed in an overarching platform regulation that EU lawmakers set out in December (the Digital Markets Act) &#8212; in that case aimed at intermediating platforms which have the most market power to push for fair dealing with other businesses (and foster digital competition).</p>
<p>Something similar for gig platforms that aims to ensure a fair deal for workers is at least conceivable.</p>
<p>It would surely be preferable to Uber et al. versus being legally required to put hundreds of thousands of on-demand workers on the payroll. But it would also put an end to the free ride these giants used to scale in the first place.</p>
<p>So it may not be the end of the road for the platform economy in Europe but a period of considerable adjustment looks inevitable &#8212; and business models will need to adapt to changing (and/or better enforced) employment laws.</p>
<p>Aiston says organisations will have to weigh up the pros and cons of adjusting their business models &#8212; with a view to either seeking to keep arrangements away from employee or worker status (but potentially reducing how much control they can apply, e.g. over price); or to accept people are workers and adapt the business model and pricing structure accordingly (such as by, say, restricting the ability to work for rival platforms).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zR9OkhjADe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/embed/#?secret=zR9OkhjADe" data-secret="zR9OkhjADe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/uber-lobbies-for-prop-22-style-gig-work-standards-in-the-eu/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2112465</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India lifts restrictions on mapping and surveying to help local firms</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/india-lifts-restrictions-on-mapping-and-surveying-to-help-local-firms/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/india-lifts-restrictions-on-mapping-and-surveying-to-help-local-firms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 13:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flipkart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google-Maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MapMyIndia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2112915</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[India said on Monday local firms will no longer need a license or other permission to collect, generate, store and share geospatial data of the country, bringing sweeping changes to its earlier stance that it admitted hindered innovation. Until now, New Delhi required Indian firms to seek licenses and additional approvals to create and publish [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">India said on Monday local firms will no longer need a license or other permission to collect, generate, store and share geospatial data of the country, bringing sweeping changes to its earlier stance that it admitted hindered innovation.</p>
<p>Until now, New Delhi required Indian firms to seek licenses and additional approvals to create and publish topographical data. India’s Prime Minister Narendra Modi said today’s &#8220;deregulation&#8221; step will help the country become more self-reliant and reach its $5 trillion GDP goal.</p>
<p>“The regulations that apply to geospatial data and maps henceforth stand radically liberalised. The Department of Science and Technology is announcing sweeping changes to India’s mapping policy, specifically for Indian companies. What is readily available globally does not need to be restricted in India and therefore geospatial data that used to be restricted will now be freely available in India,” the government said in a statement.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In its <a href="https://www.slideshare.net/dev3/final-approved-guidelines-on-geospatial-data">guidelines</a>, New Delhi said local firms will be permitted access to &#8220;ground truthing/verification&#8221; that includes access to Indian ground stations and augmentation services for real-time positioning. Indian firms will also be provided access to terrestrial mobile mapping surveys, street view surveys and surveying in Indian territorial waters.</p>
<p>New Delhi said in the guidelines that only Indian firms shall be permitted access to the aforementioned surveys. Google has previously <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/politics-and-nation/google-street-view-proposal-rejected-by-govt/articleshow/63482412.cms?from=mdr">made unsuccessful attempts</a> to launch its Street View service in India. A Google spokesperson told TechCrunch that the company was reviewing the guidelines and had no immediate comment to offer.</p>
<p>&#8220;Foreign companies and foreign owned or controlled Indian companies can license from Indian Entities digital Maps/Geospatial Data of spatial accuracy/value finer than the threshold value only for the purpose of serving their customers in India. Access to such Maps/Geospatial Data shall only be made available through APIs that do not allow Maps/Geospatial Data to pass through Licensee Company or its servers. Re-use or resale of such map data by licensees shall be prohibited,&#8221; the guidelines added.</p>
<p>Devdatta Tengshe, who works in the GIS space, told TechCrunch that the government&#8217;s move today was significant for the local ecosystem, including citizens, as previous restrictions had created an uncertainty on what precisely was permitted.</p>
<p>“Today’s announcement makes it explicitly clear that Indian entities can perform any location data collection and we can collect data on our own,” he said. “Additionally, the location data from agencies like municipality will be made available to Indian entities.”</p>
<p>Flipkart-backed 25-year-old firm MapMyIndia said today’s move by the government is “historic” as it opens up maps and the geospatial sector and ushers the self-reliance era in “strategic areas of maps to empower all 1.3 billion Indians and give unprecedented opportunities and growth for Indian companies.”</p>
<p>Modi said: &#8220;The reforms will unlock tremendous opportunities for our country’s start-ups, private sector, public sector and research institutions to drive innovations and build scalable solutions. India’s farmers will also be benefited by leveraging the potential of geo-spatial &amp; remote sensing data. Democratizing data will enable the rise of new technologies &amp; platforms that will drive efficiencies in agriculture and allied sectors. These reforms demonstrate our commitment to improving ease of doing business in India by deregulation.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LMHyic2QwL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/03/live-train-status-india-maps/">Google Maps now allows users in India to check live status of trains, bus travel times and more</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google Maps now allows users in India to check live status of trains, bus travel times and more&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/03/live-train-status-india-maps/embed/#?secret=LMHyic2QwL" data-secret="LMHyic2QwL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/india-lifts-restrictions-on-mapping-and-surveying-to-help-local-firms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2112915</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GM unveils a refreshed Chevy Bolt EV and its bigger, yet compact crossover sibling</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/14/gm-unveils-a-refreshed-chevy-bolt-ev-and-its-bigger-yet-compact-crossover-sibling/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/14/gm-unveils-a-refreshed-chevy-bolt-ev-and-its-bigger-yet-compact-crossover-sibling/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 05:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2112875</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[GM revealed Sunday a refreshed Chevrolet Bolt EV and a new, bigger — yet still compact — crossover called the Chevrolet Bolt EUV as part of the automaker&#8217;s goal to introduce 30 electric vehicles in the next four years. The vehicles, which are expected to go on sale this summer, are like siblings: The pair [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">GM revealed Sunday a refreshed Chevrolet Bolt EV and a new, bigger — yet still compact — crossover called the Chevrolet Bolt EUV as part of the automaker&#8217;s goal to introduce 30 electric vehicles in the next four years.</p>
<p>The vehicles, which are expected to go on sale this summer, are like siblings: The pair share much of the same DNA but have their own distinct differences. The 2022 Chevy Bolt EUV is bigger than the Chevy Bolt hatchback. GM lengthened the wheelbase of the EUV by about 3 inches. In all, the EUV sits some 6 inches longer than the Bolt EV. The result is a compact crossover with 39.1 inches of rear seat legroom.</p>
<p>The EUV — a GM acronym that means electric utility vehicle — also has the notable distinction of being the first Chevrolet to have the hands-free driver assistance system known as Super Cruise. The hands-free system won&#8217;t come standard, however. Drivers will have to upgrade beyond the EUV&#8217;s $33,995 base price.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That $33,995 price point stands out because it&#8217;s actually slighter cheaper than the 2021 Chevy Bolt that is currently sitting in dealerships. The new refreshed Chevy Bolt, which is described in greater detail below, has also received a price cut.</p>
<p>The takeaway: GM is using its scale to keep prices low in hopes of attracting customers who have a growing pool of EV options.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2112881" style="width: 5020px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEUV-017.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2112881" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2112881 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEUV-017.jpg" alt="2022 Chevrolet Bolt EUV" width="5010" height="3800" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEUV-017.jpg 5010w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEUV-017.jpg?resize=150,114 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEUV-017.jpg?resize=300,228 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEUV-017.jpg?resize=768,583 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEUV-017.jpg?resize=680,516 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEUV-017.jpg?resize=1536,1165 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEUV-017.jpg?resize=2048,1553 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEUV-017.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 5010px) 100vw, 5010px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2112881" class="wp-caption-text">2022 Chevrolet Bolt EUV. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> GM</p></div></p>
<p>The EUV will have an estimated range of 250 miles, which is a few miles lower than the Bolt EV. The vehicle will also come with a standard dual level charge cord with a changeable plug that lets drivers choose 120V or 240V charging.</p>
<p>The EUV will also come with native navigation. That&#8217;s an important addition in this two-member Bolt portfolio. The Chevy Bolt EV, which first debuted in 2016, doesn&#8217;t have a native in-car navigation and instead relies on either Android Auto or Apple CarPlay for maps and driving directions.</p>
<p>Importantly, neither one of these vehicles is part of the new Ultium battery platform that GM revealed in spring 2020. The Ultium platform is designed to support a wide range of products across its brands, including compact cars, work trucks, large premium SUVs and performance vehicles. The Bolt EUV and Bolt EV should be viewed as an important placeholder, two vehicles that will help keep it in the game while it works on its more ambitious EV strategy.</p>
<h2>The 2022 Chevrolet Bolt</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2112879" style="width: 5710px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-005.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2112879" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2112879 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-005.jpg" alt="2022 Chevrolet Bolt EV" width="5700" height="3800" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-005.jpg 5700w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-005.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-005.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-005.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-005.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-005.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-005.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-005.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 5700px) 100vw, 5700px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2112879" class="wp-caption-text">2022 Chevrolet Bolt EV. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> GM</p></div></p>
<p>The Bolt EUV wasn&#8217;t the only vehicle GM revealed Sunday. The automaker has also refreshed the Chevrolet Bolt, the hatchback electric vehicle that first debuted more than four years ago.</p>
<p>The upshot: Many of the specs stayed the same, the interior got an upgrade and the price dropped by $5,500.<br />
The 2022 Chevy Bolt&#8217;s underlying battery platform, the BEV2, has remained unchanged.</p>
<p>The car, which goes on sale this summer, has a 65 kilowatt-hour battery pack that provides an estimated 259 miles of range. It is also still powered by a single motor &#8212; just like the original &#8212; that generates 200 horsepower and 266 pound-feet of torque. The vehicle is the same width as before, but gained a skosh in height and is now 63.4 inches taller, while losing less than an inch in length.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2112878" style="width: 5710px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-014.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2112878" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2112878 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-014.jpg" alt="" width="5700" height="3800" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-014.jpg 5700w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-014.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-014.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-014.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-014.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-014.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-014.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2022-Chevrolet-BoltEV-014.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 5700px) 100vw, 5700px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2112878" class="wp-caption-text">2022 Chevrolet Bolt EV. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> GM</p></div></p>
<p>The 2022 Chevy Bolt, which starts at $31,995, is a couple grand cheaper than the new Bolt EUV. For that price, GM tried to pack in a bit more such as an updated modern interior and &#8220;more comfortable&#8221; bucket seating, according to the company. GM said the improvements were based on customer feedback.</p>
<p>The vehicle includes a touchscreen display that is a bit larger at 10.2 inches as well as an 8-inch digital instrument cluster. Just like the previous version, the 2022 model comes standard with Android Auto and Apple CarPlay. As mentioned before, the 2022 Chevy Bolt still doesn&#8217;t come standard with in-car navigation, relying instead on CarPlay or Android Auto.</p>
<p>One new feature is a button in the center console that when engaged allows one-pedal driving. The driver depresses the accelerator pedal to move; once the driver&#8217;s foot leaves the pedal, the vehicle&#8217;s regenerative braking kicks in and will bring the vehicle to a stop.</p>
<p>The Chevy Bolt doesn&#8217;t come with GM&#8217;s hands-free driver assistance system known as Super Cruise. GM chose the Chevy Bolt EUV for that system, which has been corralled over in Cadillac for the past several years. The Bolt hatchback does come standard with the &#8220;Chevy Safety Assist,&#8221; six features that include lane-keeping assist and a warning if the vehicle leaves the lane.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="x3WMBvZPtH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/toyota-to-bring-three-new-electrified-vehicles-to-u-s-market/">Toyota to bring 3 new electrified vehicles to US market</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Toyota to bring 3 new electrified vehicles to US market&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/toyota-to-bring-three-new-electrified-vehicles-to-u-s-market/embed/#?secret=x3WMBvZPtH" data-secret="x3WMBvZPtH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/14/gm-unveils-a-refreshed-chevy-bolt-ev-and-its-bigger-yet-compact-crossover-sibling/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2112875</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Series A deal that launched a near unicorn: Meet Accel&#8217;s Steve Loughlin and Ironclad&#8217;s Jason Boehmig</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/14/the-series-a-deal-that-launched-a-near-unicorn-meet-accels-steve-loughlin-and-ironclads-jason-boehmig/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/14/the-series-a-deal-that-launched-a-near-unicorn-meet-accels-steve-loughlin-and-ironclads-jason-boehmig/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 18:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch live announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ironclad]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2112587</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The only people who truly understand a relationship are the ones who are in it. Luckily for us, we&#8217;re going to have a candid conversation with both parties in the relationship between Ironclad CEO and co-founder Jason Boehmig and his investor and board member Accel partner Steve Loughlin. Loughlin led Ironclad&#8217;s Series A deal back [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The only people who truly understand a relationship are the ones who are in it. Luckily for us, we&#8217;re going to have a candid conversation with both parties in the relationship between Ironclad CEO and co-founder Jason Boehmig and his investor and board member Accel partner Steve Loughlin.</p>
<p>Loughlin led Ironclad&#8217;s Series A deal back in 2017, making it one of his first Series A deals after returning to Accel.</p>
<p>This episode of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">Extra Crunch Live</a> goes down on Wednesday at 3 p.m. EST/12 p.m. PST, just like usual.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll talk to the duo about how they met, what made them &#8220;choose&#8221; each other, and how they&#8217;ve operated as a duo since. How they built trust, maintain honesty and talk strategy are also on the table as part of the discussion.</p>
<p>Loughlin was an entrepreneur before he was an investor, founding RelateIQ (an Accel-backed company) in 2011. The company was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/07/11/salesforce-buys-big-data-startup-relateiq-for-up-to-390m/">acquired by Salesforce in 2014 for $390 million</a> and later became Salesforce IQ. Loughlin then &#8220;came back home&#8221; to Accel in 2016 and has led investments in companies like Airkit, Ascend.io, Clockwise, Ironclad, Monte Carlo, Nines, Productiv, Split.io and Vivun.</p>
<p>Not entirely unsurprising for a man who has dominated the legal tech sphere, Jason Boehmig is a California barred attorney who practiced law at Fenwick &amp; West and was also an adjunct professor of law at Notre Dame Law School. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ironclad/">Ironclad</a> launched in 2014 and today the company has raised more than $180 million and, according to <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/mary-meekers-vc-firm-bond-invests-in-ironclad-at-nearly-1-billion-valuation">reports</a>, is valued just under $1 billion.</p>
<p>Not only will we peel back the curtain on how this investor/founder relationship works, but we&#8217;ll also hear from these two tech leaders on their thoughts around bigger enterprise trends in the ecosystem.</p>
<p>Then, it&#8217;s time for the pitch deck teardown. On each episode of Extra Crunch Live, we take a look at decks submitted by the audience and our experienced guests give their live feedback. If you want to throw your deck in the ring, <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/Lutrgz8Q">submit your deck</a> for a future episode.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JfZLJslDzm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/felicis-aydin-senkut-and-guidelines-kevin-busque-on-the-value-of-simple-pitch-decks/">Felicis&#8217; Aydin Senkut and Guideline&#8217;s Kevin Busque on the value of simple pitch decks</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Felicis&#8217; Aydin Senkut and Guideline&#8217;s Kevin Busque on the value of simple pitch decks&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/felicis-aydin-senkut-and-guidelines-kevin-busque-on-the-value-of-simple-pitch-decks/embed/#?secret=JfZLJslDzm" data-secret="JfZLJslDzm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As with just about everything we do here at TechCrunch, audience members can also ask their own questions.</p>
<p>Extra Crunch Live has left room for you to network (you gotta network to get work, amirite?). Networking is open starting at 2:30 p.m. EST/11:30 a.m. PST and stays open a half hour after the episode ends. Make a friend!</p>
<p>As a reminder, Extra Crunch Live is a members-only series that aims to give founders and tech operators actionable advice and insights from leaders across the tech industry. If you&#8217;re not an Extra Crunch member yet, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=accelguildeline">what are you waiting for?</a></p>
<p>Loughlin and Boehmig join a stellar cast of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/check-out-the-amazing-speakers-joining-us-on-extra-crunch-live-in-february/?tpcc=ECTW2020">speakers on Extra Crunch Live</a>, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/05/pitch-decks-pricing-and-how-to-nail-the-narrative-with-lightspeeds-gaurav-gupta-and-grafanas-raj-dutt/">Lightspeed&#8217;s Gaurav Gupta and Grafana&#8217;s Raj Dutt</a>, as well as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/felicis-aydin-senkut-and-guidelines-kevin-busque-on-the-value-of-simple-pitch-decks">Felicis&#8217; Aydin Senkut and Guideline&#8217;s Kevin Busque</a>. Extra Crunch members can catch every episode of Extra Crunch Live on demand <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">right here</a>.</p>
<p>You can find details for this episode (and upcoming episodes) after the jump below.</p>
<p>See you on Wednesday!</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/14/the-series-a-deal-that-launched-a-near-unicorn-meet-accels-steve-loughlin-and-ironclads-jason-boehmig/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2112587</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
