<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 15:33:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Get in, nerds, we’re going to the metaverse</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/22/get-in-nerds-were-going-to-the-metaverse/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/22/get-in-nerds-were-going-to-the-metaverse/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Henry Pickavet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 18:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The TechCrunch Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2260866</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Excerpt: Welcome back to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter for your weekend enjoyment.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter. It’s inspired by the </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/the-exchange/"><em>daily TechCrunch+ column</em></a><em> where it gets its name. </em><em>Want it in your inbox every Saturday? Sign up </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters"><em>here</em></a><em>. </em></p>
<p>Hello friends, I hope you are well and warm and healthy and happy and good. If not, some of those things. If you are none, well there’s a reason we invented ice cream.</p>
<p>In good news I have a few tasty nuggets for you this fine Saturday. We’re talking the metaverse, a venture capital story that I’ve watched from its genesis, and a funding round for a very cool startup that I accidentally blanked this week, so we’re talking about it here. Ready? Let’s have some fun.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2260866" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The most fun that I had this week was <a href="https://twitter.com/alex/status/1484180969057710084">a visit to Decentraland</a>. In short, I was in edit and trying to distract myself so that I wouldn’t bother the editing team while they worked, so I fired up the social-crypto environment – metaverse, in other words – and went for a tour. Rocking a mohawk and some pretty cool pants I managed to get lost, visit an NFT gallery, and fail to gain access to an arena.</p>
<p>Look, the metaverse as it exists today looks a lot like Runescape. That’s not that big a diss, given the sheer historical footprint that the online RPG has built for itself. But what I don’t really need is a less featured MMORPG that includes, oddly, a more financial angle <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/despite-blockchain-gamings-play-to-earn-angle-i-prefer-to-pay/">than I tend to like in my games</a>.</p>
<p>I am neutral at the moment, and open to the metaverse becoming sufficiently cool that I log in daily. But today it seems that some Web 2.0 properties that include community creation and social interaction are superior to what we’ve yet seen from the crypto team.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zyY9RF1u4f"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/despite-blockchain-gamings-play-to-earn-angle-i-prefer-to-pay/">Despite blockchain gaming&#8217;s play-to-earn angle, I prefer to pay</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Despite blockchain gaming&#8217;s play-to-earn angle, I prefer to pay&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/despite-blockchain-gamings-play-to-earn-angle-i-prefer-to-pay/embed/#?secret=zyY9RF1u4f" data-secret="zyY9RF1u4f" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Amplify’s newest general partner</h2>
<p>Roughly 1,000 years ago, a startup named Mattermark hired me to build an independent news room for their company. It was a great learning experience, frankly, and had the added edge of introducing me to some lifetime friends. <a href="https://twitter.com/ckevinliu?lang=en">Kevin Liu now of TechStars</a>, for example.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/sarahcat21">Sarah Catanzaro</a> was another standout from the Mattermark team. Her work on the company’s data team was later translated into work in venture, first at <a href="https://www.canvas.vc/">Canvas Ventures</a>, and later <a href="https://amplifypartners.com/">Amplify Partners</a>. Amplify, for reference, last <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/fund/amplify-partners-raised-amplify-partners-iv--ade45263">announced a fund in late 2020</a> worth $275 million. Given that timeframe, I expect the group to announce a new capital vehicle in short order.</p>
<p>At Amplify, Catanzaro went from principal, to partner, to, most recently, general partner. Her journey from the lowest ranks of the VC world to its top-tier has been enjoyable to watch. And, she told TechCrunch during a call the other week, she’s the first woman to reach her level at Amplify. I highlight that to remind myself that promotions in the yet-cottage industry of venture capital are unlike startup level gains in their pace.</p>
<p>Regardless, Catanzaro told us something that I wanted to write down here, so that we can circle back to it later on. We discussed her firm’s investment approach, check size targets, and how often they enter companies at seed versus Series A maturity levels. Per the newly minted GP, Series A rounds have gotten much bigger <em>without</em> a commensurate decrease in risk. This is something that I have had as a hunch for some time, but hadn’t heard someone say out loud before.</p>
<p>This means that Series A risk, from a venture perspective, is going up as more capital is put to work at the startup stage. The math could work out in the end, provided that enough mega-exits are made in the coming years. But with the market in free-fall, and Concern now getting more column inches than Unbridled Enthusiasm, well, I wonder a bit.</p>
<h2>The pride of Rhode Island</h2>
<p>Living as I do in the Ocean State, I am slightly afield from the best-known technology hubs in the United States. But that doesn’t mean that fascinating tech companies are being built here in my small state. TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/student-labor-marketplace-pangea-closes-2m-seed-round/">has spilt ink</a>, to pick an example, on <a href="https://www.about.pangea.app/">Pangea</a>, a startup founded in Providence that is building a freelance labor marketplace for college kids.</p>
<p>Another startup in Lil Rhody is <a href="https://dockwa.com/">The Wanderlust Group</a>, which has built Dockwa, a software platform for marinas and boaters. In short, the world of managing boat slip reservations was stuck floating in the world of pen and paper, and Wanderlust decided to to modernize it through software.</p>
<p>We last touched on the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/the-wanderlust-group-raises-14-2m-to-double-down-on-getting-folks-outdoors/">in 2020 when it raised $14.2 million</a>. At that time, CEO <a href="https://twitter.com/mdmelillo">Mike Melillo</a> told TechCrunch that his company had merely been on the hunt for $7 million, a figure that it doubled.</p>
<p>So I was not surprised to hear from the company recently that it has raised again. This time Wanderlust has raised a $30 million Series C at a $150 million pre-money valuation. The funding event was led by <a href="https://www.thursday.vc/">Thursday Ventures</a>.</p>
<p>Happily for you and I, Wanderlust was willing to share ARR growth for 2021, which came in at 71%. More fun, after moving to a four-day workweek, the company saw its ARR expand 100% from June 2020 to June 2021; there’s a real datapoint for one of the more interesting labor experiments I am tracking in startup-land.</p>
<p>But most interesting from the company is that it’s building a fund. Not another corporate venture capital fund, but something else. Called Wanderfund, the company is funding the vehicle with $300,000 this year for what it describes as “environmental causes at the national and local level.” It’s starting, in part, with putting money in its local Boys &amp; Girls Club to help kids get out of the house and into nature.</p>
<p>The company is building a Dockwa-like product for camping, so the “go outside” theme is pretty core to what the aptly named <em>Wanderlust</em> Group is building.</p>
<h2>Miscellania and Various</h2>
<ul>
<li>The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/transactional/investing-app-acorns-pioneer-spac-scrap-22-bln-merger-2022-01-18/">Acorns SPAC deal is off</a>, which caught our eye. It’s not a huge shock given how poor some SPACs have performed post-combination, but we had honestly been looking forward to Acorns as a public company.</li>
<li>Acorns S-1, please.</li>
<li>And the <a href="https://markets.businessinsider.com/news/stocks/robinhood-adds-feature-letting-users-pose-questions-to-tesla-coinbase-2022-1">Robinhood experiment</a> with making the financial market more open to regular folks through IPO access and corporate democracy has good sides, and <a href="https://www.readmargins.com/p/robinhood-and-ipo-access">sharper edges worth keeping in mind</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Ok that’s enough for now. Chat you all next week!</p>
<p><a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/22/get-in-nerds-were-going-to-the-metaverse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2260866</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are embedded devices the next ransomware target?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/22/embedded-devices-ransomware/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/22/embedded-devices-ransomware/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 16:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[co CEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyberwarfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet of Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operational technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Window Snyder]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2260194</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[2021 will be remembered as the year that ransomware gangs turned their attention to critical infrastructure, targeting companies built around manufacturing, energy distribution, and food production. The Colonial Pipeline ransomware alone resulted in the shutdown of 5,500 miles of pipeline over fears that the ransomware attack on its IT network would spread to the operational [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">2021 will be remembered as the year that<a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ransomware/"> ransomware</a> gangs turned their attention to critical infrastructure, targeting companies built around manufacturing, energy distribution, and food production.</p>
<p>The Colonial Pipeline ransomware alone resulted in the shutdown of 5,500 miles of pipeline over fears that the ransomware attack on its IT network would spread to the operational network that controls the pipeline for distributing fuel.</p>
<p>Operational technology (OT) networks control the devices critical to the continued operations of production lines, power plants, and energy supplies, and as such are typically segmented from a company&#8217;s internet-facing IT networks to better isolate critical hardware from cyberattacks. Successful attacks against OT networks <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/09/triton-malware-strike/">are rare</a>, but in the wake of the Colonial ransomware attack, CISA warned of a <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/publication/ransomware-threat-to-ot">growing threat</a> for critical infrastructure owners.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2260194" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Now security researchers are warning of the risks posed by the embedded devices that sit on those OT networks. Red Balloon Security, a security provider for embedded devices, found in new research that it&#8217;s <a href="https://redballoonsecurity.com/ransomware-installation-on-embedded-devices-is-possible-because-weve-done-it/index.html">possible to deploy ransomware</a> on embedded systems that are used in real-world networks.</p>
<p>The company said it found vulnerabilities in the Schneider Electric Easergy P5 protection relay, a device that&#8217;s key to the operation and stability of the modern electric grids by triggering circuit breakers if a fault is discovered.</p>
<p>This vulnerability could be exploited to deploy a ransomware payload, a “sophisticated but reproducible” process that Red Balloon said it achieved. A Schneider Electric spokesperson told TechCrunch &#8220;it is extremely vigilant of cyber threats,&#8221; and that &#8220;upon learning of the vulnerabilities with the Schneider Electric Easergy P5 protection relay, we worked immediately to resolve them.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ang Cui, founder and co-CEO of Red Balloon told TechCrunch that while ransomware attacks have hit IT networks of critical infrastructure providers, a successful compromise of an OT embedded device can be &#8220;far more damaging.&#8221;</p>
<p>“Companies are not used to or experienced in recovering from an attack on the embedded devices themselves,&#8221; he said. &#8220;If the device is destroyed or made unrecoverable, then a replacement device needs to be sourced, and this can take weeks as there is a limited supply.&#8221;</p>
<p>Security veteran Window Snyder, who last year<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/thistle-technology-seed-security-iot/"> launched a startup to help IoT manufacturers reliably and securely deliver software updates</a> to their devices, said that embedded devices could become an easy target, particularly as other points of entry become more resilient.</p>
<p>Speaking of embedded systems: “A lot of them don’t have separation of privilege on them, a lot of them don’t have separation between code and data, and a lot of them were developed with the idea that they’d be sitting on air-gapped networks — it’s insufficient,” Snyder told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Red Balloon says its research demonstrates that the security built into these devices — many are several decades old — needs to be improved, and is calling for end-users in government and commercial sectors to call for higher standards from the vendors who make those devices.</p>
<p>“Issuing firmware fixes is a reactive, inefficient approach that will not address the overall insecurity of our most mission-critical industries and services,” says Cui. “Vendors need to bring more security down to the embedded device level.” He also believes also that more work needs to be done by the U.S. government on a regulation level, and thinks more pressure needs to be put onto device manufacturers who currently aren’t incentivized to build in more security at a device level.</p>
<p>Snyder, however, thinks a regulation-led approach is unlikely to help: “I think the thing that helps most is reducing the attack surface and increasing compartmentalization,&#8221; she says. &#8220;We’re not going to regulate our way out of more secure devices. Somebody has to go out there and build resilience into them.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZzWXwEp91f"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/the-year-the-tide-turned-on-ransomware/">The year the tide turned on ransomware</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The year the tide turned on ransomware&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/the-year-the-tide-turned-on-ransomware/embed/#?secret=ZzWXwEp91f" data-secret="ZzWXwEp91f" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/22/embedded-devices-ransomware/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2260194</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 cloud trends to watch in 2022</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/22/6-cloud-trends-to-watch-in-2022/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/22/6-cloud-trends-to-watch-in-2022/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 14:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[collaboration tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data warehouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Cloud and Enterprise Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google cloud platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ML]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258894</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The past two years have been exciting years of growth for the cloud market, driven by increased demand for access to new technology during COVID-19 and the proliferation of the “work-from-anywhere” culture.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Josh Berman</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/meetC2C">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Josh Berman is president of <a href="https://www.c2cglobal.com/">C2C</a>, an independent and vetted Google Cloud community with a unique pulse on the cloud market.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The past two years have been exciting periods of growth for the cloud market, driven by increased demand for access to new technology during COVID-19 and the proliferation of the “work-from-anywhere” culture. IT leaders worked to shift workloads to the cloud to ensure business continuity for the remote workforce, leading to skyrocketing adoption of cloud computing. This momentum is expected to pick up in 2022 and beyond.</p>
<p>For many businesses, the pandemic accelerated their digital transformation plans by months, or even years. Reliance on cloud infrastructure will only continue to grow as organizations adjust to the hybrid work model. Gartner <a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2021-08-02-gartner-says-four-trends-are-shaping-the-future-of-public-cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener">projects</a> that global spending on cloud services is expected to reach over $482 billion in 2022, up from $313 billion in 2020.</p>
<p>As we start the new year, C2C, an independent Google Cloud community, has identified six cloud computing trends to watch in 2022.</p>
<h2>More people are harnessing new technologies</h2>
<p>The pandemic inspired a new generation of entrepreneurs. Whether out of necessity from mass layoffs, a desire for a more flexible lifestyle, or finding the inspiration to finally pursue a passion, millions have started their own ventures.</p>
<p>As their businesses grow and digitize, entrepreneurs across industries are embracing the cloud and adopting technologies like machine learning and data analytics to optimize business performance, save time and cut expenses. There are countless benefits to small businesses and startups. For one, the cloud makes data accessible from anywhere with an internet connection, enabling the seamless collaboration necessary in a hybrid work environment. Without having to spend on expensive hardware and software, entrepreneurs can invest in other areas as they scale their businesses.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/22/6-cloud-trends-to-watch-in-2022/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258894</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is algorithmic VC investment compatible with due diligence?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/22/algorithmic-investing-cant-entirely-eliminate-the-emotional-element-of-deal-making/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/22/algorithmic-investing-cant-entirely-eliminate-the-emotional-element-of-deal-making/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 13:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2258202</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In algorithmic investing, investors use a company’s metrics to decide whether to participate in a deal. But when the art of choice is factored out, it becomes more difficult to perform deep due diligence on founders who may be about to receive millions of dollars via a wire transfer. In practice, attempts to remove bias [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In algorithmic investing, investors use a company’s metrics to decide whether to participate in a deal. But when the art of choice is factored out, it becomes more difficult to perform deep due diligence on founders who may be about to receive millions of dollars via a wire transfer.</p>
<p>In practice, attempts to remove bias can create newer, blind spots that are harder to identify.</p>
<p>In theory, algorithmic investing hedges against investors&#8217; preconceived notions and pushes emotions to the side. Fintech unicorn Clearco and venture firm SignalFire have spent years implementing data-focused investment processes, joined more recently by AngelList and Hum Capital. While this approach isn’t new, the movement against solely emotion-based decisions feels louder given the proliferation of dollars out there.</p>
<p>Metrics, even in the earliest stages, are becoming more mainstream.</p>
<p>AngelList’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/22/angellist-just-closed-a-25m-fund-to-back-startups-based-on-hiring-velocity/?tpcc=tcplustwitter">recently closed early-stage venture fund </a>is basing all of its investments off of one key metric that AngelList has been tracking for years: a startup’s ability to hire.</p>
<p>When I spoke to Abraham Othman, head of the investment committee and data science at AngelList Venture, he told me they win deals because they are less adversarial to portfolio companies than other firms.“Our approach? This is our data set &#8212; let’s see if we can put money into them,” he said.</p>
<p>No further due diligence? No problem.</p>
<p>It’s no small set. About 2 million individuals use AngelList Talent to apply to startups each quarter. About 35,000 companies per quarter are contenders for AngelList talent, but only half of those companies are investable early-stage businesses.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/22/algorithmic-investing-cant-entirely-eliminate-the-emotional-element-of-deal-making/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2258202</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FarmRaise aims to become a financial services giant, starting with farm grants</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/farmraise-aims-to-become-a-financial-services-giant-starting-with-farm-grants/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/farmraise-aims-to-become-a-financial-services-giant-starting-with-farm-grants/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 02:44:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Better Tomorrow Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cendana Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FarmRaise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Incite Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pear vc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seed round]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[susa ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ulu Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2260741</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You have to begin somewhere. So when Jayce Hafner and Sami Tellatin bonded as Stanford MBA classmates over their shared belief that helping U.S. farms run more efficiently would be good for farmers, good for the country, and a great business, they decided to start with grants. For her part, Hafner grew up on a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">You have to begin somewhere. So when Jayce Hafner and Sami Tellatin bonded as Stanford MBA classmates over their shared belief that helping U.S. farms run more efficiently would be good for farmers, good for the country, and a great business, they decided to start with grants.</p>
<p>For her part, Hafner grew up on a cattle ranch in Virginia and knew firsthand that applying for grants &#8212; even to improve the sustainable farming practices of her family&#8217;s farm &#8212; was a confusing and time-intensive process. As for Tellatin, she studied biological engineering as an undergrad and spent three years with the USDA, researching the impacts of cover crops on ecosystems and farm economics. She knew, too, that farmers might make better choices if grants were more available to them.</p>
<p>Enter <a href="https://farmraise.com">FarmRaise</a>, a now 12-person, two-year-old, San Diego, Ca.-based company that has made considerable progress since the two joined forces with another cofounder, Albert Abedi, who they met through the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/15/check-out-these-startups-from-pears-demo-day-theres-usually-a-breakout-or-two-in-the-bunch/">accelerator program</a> of Pear VC, the Palo Alto-based firm.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2260741" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>According to Hafner, the company already has nearly 10,000 farms on the platform thanks to word of mouth, a dash of search-engine magic, and, importantly, partnerships it has struck with agriculture giants like Cargill and Corteva (spun out of DuPont in 2018) that have carbon emission reduction goals to meet and have begun directing farmers to FarmRaise for help with grants tied to low-carbon farming.</p>
<p>FarmRaise&#8217;s platform &#8212; which asks for granular farm insights, then structures the data in a way that allows FarmRaise to quickly apply for a wide variety of grant programs on its customers&#8217; behalf &#8211; also has enough momentum that investors are now in the mix. (The team just landed $7.2 million in seed funding led by Susa Ventures, which was joined by Cendana Capital, Ulu Ventures, Pear, Better Tomorrow Ventures, Incite Ventures, and Financial Ventures Studio, among others.)</p>
<p>Still, as with so many startups, Hafner says grants &#8212; both federal and private &#8212; are just the starting point for the very broad financial services company that FarmRaise intends to become. Imagine, suggests Hafner, that once a farm has provided much of its data to the company, that FarmRaise can help it secure loans, secure equipment at bulk prices, lower its operating expenses, and help with both the farm&#8217;s banking and tax planning.</p>
<p>Many of these services will be provided through third parties, she says, with FarmRaise collecting finders&#8217; fees. FarmRaise isn&#8217;t looking to reinvent the wheel. But there&#8217;s also no reason that farmers shouldn&#8217;t have a &#8220;full-stack&#8221; resource to which to turn, she adds.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Grants are &#8220;our wedge,&#8221; she says. &#8220;They are not the end of the story.&#8221;</p>
<p>In the meantime, FarmRaise is focused on hiring more employees, lining up more grants, and making sure its customers are happy with the services it&#8217;s already providing and for which it charges a monthly subscription, along with 10% of the value of the grants it secures.</p>
<p>It&#8217;ll will take some time to understand FarmRaise&#8217;s success rate, given that some grants have wait times of six to 12 months. But it&#8217;s a big opportunity unto itself, suggests Hafner, including because USDA funding has &#8220;been growing like crazy,&#8221; she says.</p>
<p>She points to the Trump administration, which distributed &#8220;tens of billions of dollars&#8221; in funding to support farmers who struggled with Covid-related supply-chain disruptions.</p>
<p>The Biden administration also has FarmRaise feeling encouraged, she adds, &#8220;We&#8217;re seeing this keen focus on growing the size of the pie for conservation funding and it likely doubling in the years to come.&#8221; It only makes sense, she suggests. &#8220;Not only does [sustainable farming] increase farm profitability but it also sequesters carbon and can help to address climate change. They are just many, many, many benefits that come with it.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>Above, pictured left to right: FarmRaise cofounders Jayce Hafner (CEO), Albert Abedi (who is the company&#8217;s head of product), and COO Sami Tellatin.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/farmraise-aims-to-become-a-financial-services-giant-starting-with-farm-grants/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2260741</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google asks a judge to dismiss Texas antitrust lawsuit about its ad business</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/google-asks-a-judge-to-dismiss-texas-antitrust-lawsuit-about-its-ad-business/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/google-asks-a-judge-to-dismiss-texas-antitrust-lawsuit-about-its-ad-business/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 23:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alaska]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arkansas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[attorney general]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[complaint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Trade Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indiana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kentucky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Louisiana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mississippi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Missouri]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[montana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nevada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[North Dakota]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[puerto rico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Carolina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The New York Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[utah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2260864</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google filed a motion Friday asking a federal court to dismiss most of the counts in an antitrust lawsuit led by the state of Texas. In the filing, the company argued that the Texas lawsuit isn&#8217;t &#8220;credible&#8221; and that the state failed to establish that the company&#8217;s ad business has run afoul of antitrust laws. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google filed a motion Friday asking a federal court to dismiss most of the counts in an antitrust lawsuit led by the state of Texas. In the filing, the company argued that the Texas lawsuit isn&#8217;t &#8220;credible&#8221; and that the state failed to establish that the company&#8217;s ad business has run afoul of antitrust laws.</p>
<p>&#8220;AG Paxton&#8217;s allegations are more heat than light, and we don&#8217;t believe they meet the legal standard to send this case to trial,&#8221; Google Director of Economic Policy Adam Cohen <a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/public-policy/ag-paxtons-false-claims-still-dont-add-up/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote in a blog post</a>. &#8220;The complaint misrepresents our business, products and motives, and we are moving to dismiss it based on its failure to offer plausible antitrust claims.&#8221;</p>
<p>Texas Attorney General Ken Paxton announced the suit, which alleges that Google illegally maintained a monopoly in online advertising, in late 2020. Texas <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/01/14/facebook-google-ad-market-lawsuit-527108" target="_blank" rel="noopener">updated the suit with a new complaint</a> last week that was first filed in November but redacted at the time, before a judge ordered the details of the complaint to be made public.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2260864" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Alaska, Arkansas, Florida, Idaho, Indiana, Louisiana, Mississippi, Missouri, Montana, Nevada, North Dakota, South Carolina, South Dakota, Utah, Kentucky and Puerto Rico have also joined the lawsuit seeking to hold the tech giant accountable.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="glQOH5KlJh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/google-state-antitrust-lawsuit-texas-paxton/">Texas leads ten states in lawsuit over Google&#8217;s ad business</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Texas leads ten states in lawsuit over Google&#8217;s ad business&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/google-state-antitrust-lawsuit-texas-paxton/embed/#?secret=glQOH5KlJh" data-secret="glQOH5KlJh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Google claims that Paxton &#8220;overlooks, or misstates, a litany of clear facts,&#8221; including allegations that the company made a deal with Facebook to maintain its online ad dominance by crushing an emerging ad buying process called &#8220;header bidding.&#8221;</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/17/technology/google-facebook-ad-deal-antitrust.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reporting from The New York Times</a>, Facebook announced the relationship in 2018 but did not disclose that Google granted its competitor &#8220;special information and speed advantages to help the company succeed in the auctions that it did not offer to other partners — even including a guaranteed &#8216;win rate.'&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Mired in its own antitrust woes, Meta similarly asked the court to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2022/jan/12/lawsuit-aiming-to-break-up-facebook-group-meta-can-go-ahead-us-court-rules" target="_blank" rel="noopener">dismiss an antitrust lawsuit</a> that could force the company to sell Instagram and WhatsApp, but a judge ruled earlier this month that the FTC&#8217;s refiled suit would be allowed to proceed.</p>
<p><iframe class="scribd_iframe_embed" src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/554324365/content?start_page=1&view_mode&access_key=key-kf2nhsGWqYnIni5cZ3aq"  data-auto-height="true" scrolling="no" id="scribd_554324365" width="100%" height="500" frameborder="0"></iframe>
		<div style="font-size:10px;text-align:center;width:100%"><a href="https://www.scribd.com/doc/554324365" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">View this document on Scribd</a></div></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xnbrfkNvLN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/google-state-lawsuit-android-attorneys-general/">Google faces a major multi-state antitrust lawsuit over Google Play fees</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google faces a major multi-state antitrust lawsuit over Google Play fees&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/google-state-lawsuit-android-attorneys-general/embed/#?secret=xnbrfkNvLN" data-secret="xnbrfkNvLN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sSFBQuQxNZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/justice-department-will-reportedly-file-its-antitrust-lawsuit-against-google-today/">The Justice Department has filed its antitrust lawsuit against Google</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Justice Department has filed its antitrust lawsuit against Google&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/justice-department-will-reportedly-file-its-antitrust-lawsuit-against-google-today/embed/#?secret=sSFBQuQxNZ" data-secret="sSFBQuQxNZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/google-asks-a-judge-to-dismiss-texas-antitrust-lawsuit-about-its-ad-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2260864</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2022 crypto predictions from Prime Trust CFO Rodrigo Vicuna</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/2022-crypto-predictions-from-prime-trust-cfo-rodrigo-vicuna/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/2022-crypto-predictions-from-prime-trust-cfo-rodrigo-vicuna/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 23:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Decentralized Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[p2p]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2260136</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Even though DeFi, cryptocurrencies, blockchains, NFTs and a slew of other products came online in 2021, only about 1% of the world’s population has a unique crypto wallet.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Rodrigo Vicuna</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/raaadrigo">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rodrigovicuna/">Rodrigo Vicuna</a> is chief financial officer at <a href="https://www.primetrust.com/">Prime Trust</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Cryptocurrency and blockchain had a breakout year in 2021.</p>
<p>ust look at the numbers: 80 million unique crypto wallets; Bitcoin and Ether grew 60% and 407%, respectively; El Salvador adopted bitcoin as official currency; the NFT market generated $2.5 billion in trades. Even Burger King announced a whopper when they got in on the NFT action. Impressive? Absolutely. Have we reached a point where crypto and blockchain reach mass adoption? Well, not quite.</p>
<p>Even though DeFi, cryptocurrencies, blockchains, NFTs and a slew of other products came online in 2021, only about 1% of the world’s population has a unique crypto wallet. Media coverage, financial institutions, and companies with hefty marketing budgets jumped in and made it seem as if mass adoption was already here. But in reality, we’re not there yet.</p>
<p>However, we anticipate that changing in 2022. From more creative crypto entries to the impact of inflation and new technologies, here are five trends we expect in 2022, and what you can do to navigate the challenges ahead.</p>
<h2>Expect more diverse uses for crypto</h2>
<p>For the most part, consumers are aware that crypto exists, but they don’t understand its benefits in their day-to-day lives. For many, it’s seen as an investment tool for institutional or retail investors, a novelty, or something that caters primarily to the trendiest of the Gen Z crowd. With blockchain games and GameFi, as well as reward redemption platforms that trade airline miles into crypto on the horizon, expect this to change in 2022.</p>
<p>We’ve seen some of this already in 2021 with NFTs that cater to art collectors and sports enthusiasts. We&#8217;ll see it branch out into other areas such as wine, sneakers and other collectibles, bringing in new users.</p>
<p>For the mass consumer, understanding these technologies can be challenging, but when NFTs are tied to something they know and are enthusiastic about, it’ll start growing among that community. Keep an eye on enterprising companies pushing into these areas – specifically collectibles – as a way to broaden the reach of crypto and blockchain in 2022.</p>
<h2>A surge in crypto apps</h2>
<p>Crypto is considered technically complicated to hold, and for the layperson, even the terminology is difficult to understand. Crypto and blockchain need to be easy to use and understand before mass adoption can happen, and that’s what we’ll see in 2022.</p>
<p>Cheaper blockchains are allowing new users to onboard with DApps, which are decentralized applications that run on a P2P or blockchain network. They don’t require users to submit their personal information. It’ll start with global digital asset payments, recurring buys, or tipping, but will grow to include multiple types of transactions, which will only increase user adoption.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/2022-crypto-predictions-from-prime-trust-cfo-rodrigo-vicuna/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2260136</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: IBM sells off Watson Health unit to private equity firm Francisco Partners</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/daily-crunch-ibm-sells-off-watson-health-unit-to-private-equity-firm-francisco-partners/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/daily-crunch-ibm-sells-off-watson-health-unit-to-private-equity-firm-francisco-partners/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 23:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Columbus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entreé Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Francisco Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IBM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ohio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raven software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Secfi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Watson]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2260840</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I normally try to bring some pep to my little intros in this missive. But today I am going to avoid astruturning my own mood to simply say, hey, what's up with the stock market?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PST, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for January 21, 2022! I normally try to bring some pep to my little intros in this missive. But today I am going to avoid astroturfing my own mood to simply say, hey, what&#8217;s up with the stock market? After a period of time when things only went up, have we flipped the coin? I am not going to say that I love it, but hey, at least it’s the weekend. – <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/activision-blizzard-union-raven-software/">Is Microsoft buying a union?</a> </strong>Raven Software’s quality assurance department is forming a union at Activision Blizzard. TechCrunch called the move the “first union to form at a major U.S. gaming company.” Given that Microsoft is supposed to buy Raven Software’s parent company, the union situation has an even more interesting flavor than most tech union news that we’ve seen lately.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/vcs-approached-facebook-to-fund-a-spinout-of-workplace-valued-at-over-1b-but-facebook-declined/">VCs wanted to spin-out Facebook’s Slack competitor</a>:</strong> Facebook’s internal work tool that it turned into a product won’t be leaving the confines of the Meta corporation. TechCrunch learned that VCs wanted the social giant to spin it out at a valuation north of $1 billion, but Team Zuck didn’t bite.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/netflixs-dismal-results-are-more-evidence-that-the-pandemic-trade-is-over/">Netflix’s poor results prove the pandemic trade is over</a>:</strong> After <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/20/netflix-q4-2021-results-subscriber-numbers/">reporting numbers</a> that left Wall Street less than enthused, the value of Netflix stock tanked today. The result, and resulting investor reaction underscores our general belief that the pandemic trade is behind us. Recall that in late December, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/the-era-of-ultra-rich-software-valuations-could-be-behind-us/">TechCrunch asked</a> if the era of super-rich tech valuations was behind us. The answer? Yeah, it looks like it.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/european-spend-management-platform-moss-raises-86-million/">If you are working on corporate spend, please collect your check</a>: </strong>As Ramp, Brex, and Airbase battle it out in the United States, Moss’ work to build a corporate spend behemoth in Europe is attracting allies. Rich ones, it turns out, as the company just landed $86 million. The company is now worth nearly $600 million, thanks to its latest share sale.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/cana-technology-raises-glass-to-new-capital-as-it-readies-beverage-printer-for-market/">Please print me one (1) mocktail</a>: </strong>One of the funniest bits of a Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy series of novels is the silly spaceship that can’t make tea. It can, to paraphrase, make something that is <em>akin</em> to tea, but not quite. That’s a long-winded way of saying that beverage printing is not a new concept. But it is a new reality, at least to my brain. Cana Technology just unveiled what it calls “the world’s first molecular beverage printer.” To which we ask: Can it make tea? Either way, this sounds dope.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/paris-based-vc-firm-partech-unveils-chapter54-accelerator-to-help-european-startups-cross-into-africa/">Europe -&gt; Africa</a>:</strong> The African technology startup market is accelerating. That’s known. But what if you are building a company, say in Europe, and want to move into the African market? Venture firm Partech’s new Chapter54 accelerator is working on just that problem, TechCrunch reports.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/israels-entree-capital-raises-300m-for-israel-focused-fund-adi-gozes-becomes-partner/">Another Israeli VC puts together a new fund</a>: </strong>2022 is shaping up to be a hot year for the Israeli technology scene, with Entrée Capital announcing a $300 million fund. That’s the second new fund from Israel thus far this year that we can name. So much for a slowdown, yeah?</li>
</ul>
<h2>Inside Secfi’s 2021 state of stock options equity report</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2260326" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2260326" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2260326" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg" alt="Image of abstract multi colored pie chart made out of different pie peces on purple background." width="1024" height="717" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg 2070w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg?resize=300,210 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg?resize=768,538 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg?resize=680,476 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg?resize=1536,1075 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg?resize=2048,1434 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2260326" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Andriy+Onufriyenko" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Andriy Onufriyenko <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2260840" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>It’s great to have a stake in the company you’re helping to build, but when employees don’t know the optimal way to exercise their stock options, they usually end up with a raw deal.</p>
<p>Last year, startup employees paid an estimated $11 billion in avoidable taxes by exercising their options post-exit, rather than pre-exit, according to Secfi data.</p>
<p>In a post for TechCrunch+, CEO Frederik Mijnhardt shared his analysis of the biggest trends around stock options in 2021, including why, despite stellar IPOs, most employees couldn’t exercise their options until after the exit, dramatically increasing their tax liability.</p>
<p>&#8220;Looking ahead to 2022, it seems that the industry’s current trend toward mega-sized rounds of funding and longer exit timelines mean that for the average startup employee, their total cost to exercise stock options will continue to rise,&#8221; says Mijnhardt.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="64xfY6zkaB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/20/inside-secfis-2021-state-of-stock-options-equity-report/">Inside Secfi&#8217;s 2021 state of stock options equity report</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Inside Secfi&#8217;s 2021 state of stock options equity report&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/20/inside-secfis-2021-state-of-stock-options-equity-report/embed/#?secret=64xfY6zkaB" data-secret="64xfY6zkaB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/20/peloton-ceo-acknowledges-corrective-actions-denies-halting-all-production-of-bikes-and-treadmills/">Peloton (kinda) answers production stories</a>:</strong> Yes, the company is “resetting our production levels for sustainable growth,” its CEO admitted in a note that kinda, sorta, dealt with a wave of stories about Peloton’s consumer demand. More when the company reports earnings, as this story is far from over.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/intel-eyes-ohio-for-a-pair-of-chip-factories-amid-global-shortage/">Intel could build a huge plant in Ohio</a>:</strong> Building chips is expensive, and hard to spin up. So it’s good news that Intel intends to “build two chip manufacturing facilities outside of Columbus, Ohio.” The total work could cost $20 billion. Score one point for domestic production, I suppose.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/francisco-partners-scoops-up-remains-of-ibms-watson-health-unit/">IBM manages to divest its Watson Health unit</a>: </strong>Francisco Partners is buying the asset, though we don’t know for how much. The Watson push seems to be stumbling to a conclusion, selling for a price that is expected to be a fraction of what IBM paid to compile the corporate assets behind its health-focused AI push.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1617176" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1617176" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1617176" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-639546999-1.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="681" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-639546999-1.jpg 5196w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-639546999-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-639546999-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-639546999-1.jpg?resize=768,511 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-639546999-1.jpg?resize=680,452 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-639546999-1.jpg?resize=1536,1022 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-639546999-1.jpg?resize=2048,1362 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/gettyimages-639546999-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1617176" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Pete Saloutos / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants to know which software consultants you’ve worked with for anything from UI/UX to cloud architecture. Let us know <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/MXehi2kl?typeform-source=techcrunch.com">here</a>.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re curious about how these surveys are shaping our coverage, check out this interview Miranda Halpern did with Wolfpack Digital CEO Georgina Lupu-Florian, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/how-should-non-technical-founders-collaborate-with-software-developers/">“How should non-technical founders collaborate with software developers?”</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MfUX9gznKa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/how-should-non-technical-founders-collaborate-with-software-developers/">How should non technical founders collaborate with software developers?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How should non technical founders collaborate with software developers?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/how-should-non-technical-founders-collaborate-with-software-developers/embed/#?secret=MfUX9gznKa" data-secret="MfUX9gznKa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/daily-crunch-ibm-sells-off-watson-health-unit-to-private-equity-firm-francisco-partners/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2260840</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Experts Roundup: lead magnets, e-commerce trends, software developer Q&#038;A</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/experts-roundup-lead-magnets-e-commerce-trends-software-developer-qa/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/experts-roundup-lead-magnets-e-commerce-trends-software-developer-qa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Halpern]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 22:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agile software development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Experts Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growth Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Octane AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software Consultants Roundup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259954</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week: how to set up lead magnets that attract prospective customers who are ready to purchase.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Let&#8217;s get into it!</p>
<h2>Software consulting</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/how-should-non-technical-founders-collaborate-with-software-developers/">(TechCrunch+) How should non technical founders collaborate with software developers?</a> Miranda Halpern continues the TechCrunch Experts project by interviewing CEO of Wolfpack Digital, Georgina &#8216;Gina&#8217; Lupu Florian.</p>
<p><strong>What percentage of your clients are non-technical people who have an idea, but no coding experience? How much of a limitation is that for launching an app?</strong></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259954" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>I would say probably around 50% of our clients are in this situation, either as founders of a startup, or as representatives of companies (product owners in scale-ups, or people in corporate innovation departments, for example). We are here to help with every step of the way, so we don’t see it as a limitation at all.</p>
<p>However, it’s true that having previous experience working with agencies/developers may be useful in terms of familiarity with the software development processes. But absolutely anyone, regardless of their background, can get up to speed quickly, and we are here to support them.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="a4vVuDxy8M"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/how-should-non-technical-founders-collaborate-with-software-developers/">How should non technical founders collaborate with software developers?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How should non technical founders collaborate with software developers?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/how-should-non-technical-founders-collaborate-with-software-developers/embed/#?secret=a4vVuDxy8M" data-secret="a4vVuDxy8M" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><script src="//embed.typeform.com/next/embed.js"></script></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>Growth marketing</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/4-trends-that-will-define-e-commerce-in-2022/">(TechCrunch+) 4 trends that will define e-commerce in 2022:</a> We featured this in our<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/07/this-week-in-techcrunch-experts-e-commerce-trends-growth-marketing-predictions/"> last roundup</a>, but it&#8217;s still timely! Ben Parr, president and co-founder of Octane AI, shares his e-commerce predictions for the year:</p>
<ul>
<li>Personalization and zero-party data become critical</li>
<li>E-commerce embraces web3 and NFTs, but what will that look like?</li>
<li>Liveshopping goes mainstream</li>
<li>Slow but gradual improvement to the supply chain</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cjkWi3D3TF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/4-trends-that-will-define-e-commerce-in-2022/">4 trends that will define e-commerce in 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;4 trends that will define e-commerce in 2022&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/4-trends-that-will-define-e-commerce-in-2022/embed/#?secret=cjkWi3D3TF" data-secret="cjkWi3D3TF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/setting-up-high-conversion-lead-magnets-that-deliver-value/">(TechCrunch+) Setting up persuasive lead magnets that deliver value:</a> Aleksandra Korczynska, CMO of GetResponse, covers the essentials for creating lead magnets and where to place them for maximum effect.</p>
<blockquote><p>Today, 96% of visitors to your website aren’t ready to buy. Instead, they are either becoming familiar with your brand (awareness stage) or considering your products as one of many options (consideration stage). In these initial phases, you want potential prospects to put their contact details down so that you can engage them with personalized emails in the future. Unfortunately, very few customers just hand over their data like that. This is exactly where alluring magnets enter the equation.</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RgdaH0D1NX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/setting-up-high-conversion-lead-magnets-that-deliver-value/">Setting up high-conversion lead magnets that deliver value</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Setting up high-conversion lead magnets that deliver value&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/setting-up-high-conversion-lead-magnets-that-deliver-value/embed/#?secret=RgdaH0D1NX" data-secret="RgdaH0D1NX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div style="width: 100%; height: 400px;" data-tf-widget="bwwIWF03" data-tf-iframe-props="title=TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketers" data-tf-medium="snippet">We don&#8217;t have any new recommendations to highlight this week, but if there&#8217;s a growth marketer you think we should know about, tell us in the survey below.</div>
<p><script src="//embed.typeform.com/next/embed.js"></script></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/experts-roundup-lead-magnets-e-commerce-trends-software-developer-qa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259954</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TechCrunch+ roundup: 2022 VC predictions, how to hook an angel, product advisory councils</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/techcrunch-roundup-2022-vc-predictions-how-to-hook-an-angel-product-advisory-councils/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/techcrunch-roundup-2022-vc-predictions-how-to-hook-an-angel-product-advisory-councils/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 21:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Angel Investor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christine Tsai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2260745</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well-researched personas are useful, but nothing is better than talking to a customer if you want to understand what delights them — and what they're willing to pay for.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">I&#8217;ve worked at early-stage startups where we relied on our best guesses to shape product pipelines and develop marketing strategies.</p>
<p>I have also held jobs at companies where we engaged directly with current and past customers to ask them what they wanted. You can probably guess which approach generated more favorable outcomes.</p>
<p>Whether it&#8217;s done informally via a Reddit AMA or a Twitter Space, it&#8217;s never a bad idea to interact with people who use your products and services.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2260745" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><i>Full TechCrunch+ articles are only available to members<br />
<a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">Use discount code <strong>TCPLUSROUNDUP</strong></a> to save 20% off a one- or two-year subscription</i></p>
<hr />
<p>Well-researched personas are useful, but nothing is better than talking to a customer if you want to understand what delights them — and what they&#8217;re willing to pay for.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/20/how-to-build-a-product-advisory-council-for-your-startup/">With a product advisory council (PAC)</a>, early-stage startups can tap into the their users&#8217; hive mind. The benefits are many: PACs can help validate everything from marketing campaigns to future product planning.</p>
<p>But to build one, founders must first define clear goals and create value for participants. In this seven-step guide, you&#8217;ll find strategies and tactics for identifying key members and influencers, streamlining the communication process, and creating &#8220;a little FOMO.&#8221;</p>
<p>Thanks very much for reading TechCrunch+ this week. I hope you have a relaxing weekend!</p>
<p>Walter Thompson<br />
Senior Editor, TechCrunch+<br />
<a href="https://www.twitter.com/yourprotagonist">@yourprotagonist</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PDB8IJdeN9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/20/how-to-build-a-product-advisory-council-for-your-startup/">How to build a product advisory council for your startup</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to build a product advisory council for your startup&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/20/how-to-build-a-product-advisory-council-for-your-startup/embed/#?secret=PDB8IJdeN9" data-secret="PDB8IJdeN9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Why Microsoft’s $2T+ market cap makes its $68B Activision buy a cheap bet</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2259527" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2259527" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2259527 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237816149.jpg" alt="Microsoft's Xbox One video game console and Activision Blizzard's Call of Duty: Modern Warfare video game arranged in Denver, Colorado, U.S., on Tuesday, Jan. 18, 2022. Microsoft Corp. agreed to buy Activision Blizzard Inc. in a $68.7 billion deal, uniting two of the biggest forces in video games to create the worlds third-biggest gaming company. Photographer: Michael Ciaglo/Bloomberg via Getty Images" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237816149.jpg 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237816149.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237816149.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237816149.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237816149.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237816149.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2259527" class="wp-caption-text">Microsoft&#8217;s Xbox One video game console and Activision Blizzard&#8217;s Call of Duty: Modern Warfare video game arranged in Denver, Colorado, U.S., on Tuesday, Jan. 18, 2022. Microsoft Corp. agreed to buy Activision Blizzard Inc. in a $68.7 billion deal, uniting two of the biggest forces in video games to create the worlds third-biggest gaming company. Photographer: Michael Ciaglo/Bloomberg via Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Risk is an essential part of gambling, so it may be improper to describe Microsoft’s planned purchase of Activision Blizzard as a “bet.”</p>
<p>Considering that Microsoft has a market cap over $2 trillion, purchasing a gaming company that pumps out titles like Call of Duty, Guitar Hero and Candy Crush for $68 billion isn’t exactly fraught with danger.</p>
<p>According to Box CEO Aaron Levie, the move solidifies Redmond’s entry into AR/VR gaming.</p>
<p>“If you believe VR and immersive computing is the future — whether for consumer or business use cases — Activision helps Microsoft build a flywheel of content and technology that gets more users on board to this future.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oC74NEbDfR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/why-microsofts-2t-market-cap-makes-its-78b-activision-buy-a-cheap-bet/">Why Microsoft&#8217;s $2T+ market cap makes its $68B Activision buy a cheap bet</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why Microsoft&#8217;s $2T+ market cap makes its $68B Activision buy a cheap bet&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/why-microsofts-2t-market-cap-makes-its-78b-activision-buy-a-cheap-bet/embed/#?secret=oC74NEbDfR" data-secret="oC74NEbDfR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>500 Global’s Christine Tsai shares her 2022 VC predictions</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2259168" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2259168" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2259168" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-976372274-1.jpg" alt="Christine Tsai, co-founder and chief executive officer of 500 Startups Management Co., listens during a Bloomberg Technology Television interview in San Francisco, California, U.S., on Tuesday, June 12, 2018. Tsai discussed Abu Dhabi Financial Group's stake in the company as well as international expansion and running the firm after co-founder Dave McClure's departure. Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-976372274-1.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-976372274-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-976372274-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-976372274-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-976372274-1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-976372274-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2259168" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=editorial&amp;photographer=Bloomberg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bloomberg <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>2021 was a year like no other when it came to venture investment, and this year is poised to tread a similar path, writes 500 Global’s CEO and co-founder, Christine Tsai.</p>
<p>According to Tsai, 2022 will see web3 going mainstream, more capital flowing to underestimated founders, and broader investments in regions that have traditionally been overlooked.</p>
<p>“All signs point to a continued abundance of opportunities for startup founders and investors in the year ahead.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OVkzuYwKtI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/500-globals-christine-tsai-shares-her-2022-vc-predictions/">500 Global&#8217;s Christine Tsai shares her 2022 VC predictions</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;500 Global&#8217;s Christine Tsai shares her 2022 VC predictions&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/500-globals-christine-tsai-shares-her-2022-vc-predictions/embed/#?secret=OVkzuYwKtI" data-secret="OVkzuYwKtI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Will quantum computing remain the domain of the specialist VC?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2258963" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2258963" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2258963" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1346925522.jpg" alt="Central Computer Processor digital technology and innovations" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1346925522.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1346925522.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1346925522.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1346925522.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1346925522.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1346925522.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2258963" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Olemedia" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Olemedia <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Quantum computing’s potential applications include machine learning and computer-aided drug design, but the industry is still very much in its early days.</p>
<p>In 2021, there were approximately 90 quantum investments that totaled $1.4 billion. A significant jump from $700 million the year before, but compared to SaaS, not even a drop in the bucket.</p>
<p>Even so, we’re already seeing quantum exits: IonQ reached a $2 billion valuation after its 2021 SPAC, and Rigetti plans to do the same this year as it develops its superconducting quantum computer.</p>
<p>In a comprehensive market map of the quantum computing industry, Maria Lepskaya, a senior associate at Runa Capital, sorted the top companies in the space into 12 quadrants, “each corresponding to particular quantum technology and a stage of startups.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WUq8V0wruh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/will-quantum-computing-remain-the-domain-of-the-specialist-vc/">Will quantum computing remain the domain of the specialist VC?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Will quantum computing remain the domain of the specialist VC?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/will-quantum-computing-remain-the-domain-of-the-specialist-vc/embed/#?secret=WUq8V0wruh" data-secret="WUq8V0wruh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Dear Sophie: How do I successfully expand my company to the US?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2099516" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2099516" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2099516" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg" alt="lone figure at entrance to maze hedge that has an American flag at the center" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2099516" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin/TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Dear Sophie,</strong></p>
<p><strong>I’m an entrepreneur in Guatemala and would like to come to the United States to expand my tech company.</strong></p>
<p><strong>What is the best way to do that?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Groundbreaking Guatemalan</strong></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TTQo7594vo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/dear-sophie-how-do-i-successfully-expand-my-company-to-the-us/">Dear Sophie: How do I successfully expand my company to the US?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Dear Sophie: How do I successfully expand my company to the US?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/dear-sophie-how-do-i-successfully-expand-my-company-to-the-us/embed/#?secret=TTQo7594vo" data-secret="TTQo7594vo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>5 areas where VCs can play an outsized role in addressing climate change</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2259562" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2259562" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2259562" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1347503244.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1347503244.jpg 2120w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1347503244.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1347503244.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1347503244.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1347503244.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1347503244.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1347503244.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1347503244.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2259562" class="wp-caption-text">Five green rocker switches, all switched in the power-on position except the last one, arranged in a horizontal row on blue colored background</p></div></p>
<p>Climate tech startups raised $32 billion in 2021, but that amount is nowhere close to the estimated $2.5-$4.8 trillion required to fund enough adaptation and mitigation projects to make a meaningful difference.</p>
<p>Private investors can&#8217;t fill the gap alone, but VCs are in a unique position to change this dynamic.</p>
<p>By backing climate startups, they can de-risk proven climate tech, build legitimacy to attract talent, help with scaling, attract new kinds of investors, and shape the overall ecosystem, write investor Jamil Wyne and climate finance researcher Abrar Chaudhury.</p>
<p>“While most VC verticals will be assessed in terms of how much they return to investors, climate tech may be unique in that its success will also be determined, essentially, by its contribution to the preservation of our livelihoods and how much it can avoid a winner-take-all dynamic.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uL4A3pZln8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/20/5-areas-where-vcs-can-play-an-outsized-role-in-addressing-climate-change/">5 areas where VCs can play an outsized role in addressing climate change</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 areas where VCs can play an outsized role in addressing climate change&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/20/5-areas-where-vcs-can-play-an-outsized-role-in-addressing-climate-change/embed/#?secret=uL4A3pZln8" data-secret="uL4A3pZln8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Inside Secfi’s 2021 state of stock options equity report</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2260326" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2260326" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2260326" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg" alt="Image of abstract multi colored pie chart made out of different pie peces on purple background." width="1024" height="717" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg 2070w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg?resize=300,210 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg?resize=768,538 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg?resize=680,476 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg?resize=1536,1075 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg?resize=2048,1434 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1314946854.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2260326" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Andriy+Onufriyenko" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Andriy Onufriyenko <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>It’s great to have a stake in the company you’re helping to build, but when employees don’t know the optimal way to exercise their stock options, they usually end up with a raw deal.</p>
<p>Last year, startup employees paid an estimated $11 billion in avoidable taxes by exercising their options post-exit, rather than pre-exit, according to Secfi data.</p>
<p>In a post for TechCrunch+, CEO Frederik Mijnhardt shared his analysis of the biggest trends around stock options in 2021, including why, despite stellar IPOs, most employees couldn’t exercise their options until after the exit, dramatically increasing their tax liability.</p>
<p>&#8220;Looking ahead to 2022, it seems that the industry’s current trend toward mega-sized rounds of funding and longer exit timelines mean that for the average startup employee, their total cost to exercise stock options will continue to rise,&#8221; says Mijnhardt.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="b7gky6Hjqi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/20/inside-secfis-2021-state-of-stock-options-equity-report/">Inside Secfi&#8217;s 2021 state of stock options equity report</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Inside Secfi&#8217;s 2021 state of stock options equity report&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/20/inside-secfis-2021-state-of-stock-options-equity-report/embed/#?secret=b7gky6Hjqi" data-secret="b7gky6Hjqi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>If you want startup funding, don’t make VCs feel ignorant</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2259121" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2259121" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2259121" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1147501128.jpg" alt="Concept of the phrase physics in a nutshell. Physics formulas drawn on black paper with walnuts" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1147501128.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1147501128.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1147501128.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1147501128.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1147501128.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1147501128.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2259121" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Andreas+Mann++EyeEm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Andreas Mann/yeEm <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>It’s important to ask potential investors questions, but first-time founders often alienate VCs by quizzing them about the breadth and depth of their knowledge.</p>
<p>The trick, according to Prashant Fonseka, a partner at Tuesday Capital: only ask <em>easy</em> questions.</p>
<p>“Save the challenging questions for a time when you’re selecting from multiple investors who are ready to write checks after you’ve convinced them your company is fundable.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MlTHWPQjdU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/if-you-want-startup-funding-dont-make-vcs-feel-ignorant/">If you want startup funding, don&#8217;t make VCs feel ignorant</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;If you want startup funding, don&#8217;t make VCs feel ignorant&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/if-you-want-startup-funding-dont-make-vcs-feel-ignorant/embed/#?secret=MlTHWPQjdU" data-secret="MlTHWPQjdU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The berserk pace of fintech investing outshines the global VC boom</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1909062" style="width: 860px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1909062" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1909062" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1127063674-1.jpg" alt="fintech" width="850" height="492" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1127063674-1.jpg 850w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1127063674-1.jpg?resize=150,87 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1127063674-1.jpg?resize=300,174 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1127063674-1.jpg?resize=768,445 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1127063674-1.jpg?resize=680,394 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-1127063674-1.jpg?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1909062" class="wp-caption-text">Financial technology concept.</p></div></p>
<p>From Buy Now, Pay Later to open banking and social finance, fintech has scaled rapidly since the pandemic began. Investment has kept pace with growth: last year, fintech accounted for more than 20% of all venture investments.</p>
<p>In a deeply researched post, Mary Ann Azevedo and Alex Wilhelm examine how fintech overtook and outperformed every other sector to the point where its outlines mirror that of the broader venture market.</p>
<p>“To some degree, it appears that what is true for the venture capital market is also true for the fintech market, but in a more exaggerated form. Fintech is like most venture, but simply more extreme.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FKTmckqkhL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/the-berserk-pace-of-fintech-investing-outshines-the-global-vc-boom/">The berserk pace of fintech investing outshines the global VC boom</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The berserk pace of fintech investing outshines the global VC boom&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/the-berserk-pace-of-fintech-investing-outshines-the-global-vc-boom/embed/#?secret=FKTmckqkhL" data-secret="FKTmckqkhL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Changes to corporate investing rules could diminish China’s resilient venture landscape</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996006" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996006" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996006" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996006" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>China has a mature venture investment ecosystem, but recent interventions by the country’s government to rein in the tech sector have left many wondering whether startup investment in the country may suffer permanently.</p>
<p>In The Exchange, Alex Wilhelm makes the case that the country’s venture market will take a hit — but not a lethal one.</p>
<p>“There are lots of non-corporate investors in China who are still active. So long as they persist, the numbers will not collapse,&#8221; writes Alex.</p>
<p>&#8220;But potential new regulatory rules regarding major tech companies could prove to be a material knock to the country’s venture scene.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NbKbdsyCvc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/20/changes-to-corporate-investing-rules-could-diminish-chinas-resilient-venture-landscape/">Changes to corporate investing rules could diminish China&#8217;s resilient venture landscape</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Changes to corporate investing rules could diminish China&#8217;s resilient venture landscape&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/20/changes-to-corporate-investing-rules-could-diminish-chinas-resilient-venture-landscape/embed/#?secret=NbKbdsyCvc" data-secret="NbKbdsyCvc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>5 essential factors for attracting angel investment</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2257671" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2257671" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2257671" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-549605205.jpg" alt="Image of bills rolled up." width="1024" height="819" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-549605205.jpg 4674w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-549605205.jpg?resize=150,120 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-549605205.jpg?resize=300,240 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-549605205.jpg?resize=768,614 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-549605205.jpg?resize=680,544 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-549605205.jpg?resize=1536,1229 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-549605205.jpg?resize=2048,1638 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-549605205.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2257671" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=KTSDESIGNSCIENCE+PHOTO+LIBRARY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">KTSDESIGN/SCIENCE PHOTO LIBRARY <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">In a guest post by Marjorie Radlo-Zandi, the veteran angel investor shared five key elements she considers before investing.</span></p>
<p>Her advice is clear and simple, which makes it particularly valuable in an environment where startup funding is flowing faster than ever.</p>
<p>Few investors expect a first-time founder&#8217;s pitch deck to be the most definitive analysis of a particular sector, but you&#8217;re better off being cautious instead of overly optimistic.</p>
<p>&#8220;An extraordinarily high projection signals you’re not altogether credible, and I advise you to avoid this mistake at all costs,&#8221; says Radlo-Zandi.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s never been a better time to found a startup, but you can&#8217;t catch pennies from VC heaven if there are holes in your story.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1Xn7sunCoq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/13/5-essential-factors-for-attracting-angel-investment/">5 essential factors for attracting angel investment</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 essential factors for attracting angel investment&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/13/5-essential-factors-for-attracting-angel-investment/embed/#?secret=1Xn7sunCoq" data-secret="1Xn7sunCoq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>NFT volume, DAOs and the curious case of LooksRare</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996010" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996010" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996010" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996010" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>NFT marketplace OpenSea largely had the field to itself, but after competitor LooksRare announced an airdrop for its $LOOKS token last week, it overtook OpenSea in trading volume.</p>
<p>&#8220;Let’s talk about incentives and governance tokens to parse out what’s up with LooksRare and the larger future of the financialization of everything,&#8221; wrote Alex Wilhelm in The Exchange.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="all4Tr9fdV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/14/nft-volume-daos-and-the-curious-case-of-looksrare/">NFT volume, DAOs and the curious case of LooksRare</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;NFT volume, DAOs and the curious case of LooksRare&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/14/nft-volume-daos-and-the-curious-case-of-looksrare/embed/#?secret=all4Tr9fdV" data-secret="all4Tr9fdV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>LG and the hunt for the next-gen corporate incubator</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2258179" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2258179" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2258179" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Mission-Launch-2021-6-e1642197109968.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="579" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Mission-Launch-2021-6-e1642197109968.jpeg 1367w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Mission-Launch-2021-6-e1642197109968.jpeg?resize=150,85 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Mission-Launch-2021-6-e1642197109968.jpeg?resize=300,170 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Mission-Launch-2021-6-e1642197109968.jpeg?resize=768,434 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Mission-Launch-2021-6-e1642197109968.jpeg?resize=680,385 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Mission-Launch-2021-6-e1642197109968.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2258179" class="wp-caption-text">On stage announcing LG Nova&#8217;s launch &#8212; Sokwoo Rhee, LG&#8217;s corporate SVP and head of LG Nova. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> LG</p></div></p>
<p>South Korean conglomerate LG produces everything from flat-screen TVs to soft drinks, so the idea that it would set up a startup incubator program isn&#8217;t a huge leap.</p>
<p>To learn more about the initiative, Haje Jan Kamps interviewed Sokwoo Rhee, LG’s corporate SVP and head of its North America Innovation Center.</p>
<p>“When I say new businesses, that can mean a lot of different things,&#8221; said Rhee. &#8220;We are willing to create a new business unit if the idea, suggestions and partnership hit a home run.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PZIPq7YtOj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/14/lg-and-the-hunt-for-the-next-gen-corporate-incubator/">LG and the hunt for the next-gen corporate incubator</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;LG and the hunt for the next-gen corporate incubator&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/14/lg-and-the-hunt-for-the-next-gen-corporate-incubator/embed/#?secret=PZIPq7YtOj" data-secret="PZIPq7YtOj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Fintech and insurtech innovation in Brazil set to take off on regulatory tailwinds</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2164888" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164888" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2164888" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1233359062.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="653" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1233359062.jpg 4528w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1233359062.jpg?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1233359062.jpg?resize=300,191 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1233359062.jpg?resize=768,490 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1233359062.jpg?resize=680,434 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1233359062.jpg?resize=1536,980 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1233359062.jpg?resize=2048,1306 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1233359062.jpg?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164888" class="wp-caption-text">Nubank&#8217;s present day headquarters in Sao Paulo, Brazil. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> NELSON ALMEIDA/AFP via Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>A substantial portion of Brazil&#8217;s population remains underbanked, but instant payment system Pix processed more than 8 billion transactions last year.</p>
<p>Launched by Brazil&#8217;s central bank in November 2020, Pix is already used by 60% of the population.</p>
<p>To better understand how shifting regulations and increased adoption are impacting LatAm fintech startups, Anna Heim spoke to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Amy Cheetham, partner, Costanoa Ventures</li>
<li>Javier Santiso, founder and general partner, Alma Mundi Ventures</li>
<li>Rodrigo Teijeiro, CEO, RecargaPay</li>
<li>Pedro Sônego de Oliveira, CEO TruePay</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Law9LFisjp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/14/fintech-and-insurtech-innovation-in-brazil-set-to-take-off-on-regulatory-tailwinds/">Fintech and insurtech innovation in Brazil set to take off on regulatory tailwinds</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fintech and insurtech innovation in Brazil set to take off on regulatory tailwinds&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/14/fintech-and-insurtech-innovation-in-brazil-set-to-take-off-on-regulatory-tailwinds/embed/#?secret=Law9LFisjp" data-secret="Law9LFisjp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/techcrunch-roundup-2022-vc-predictions-how-to-hook-an-angel-product-advisory-councils/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2260745</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 factors to consider when adding remote visual assistance software to your tech stack</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/3-factors-to-consider-when-adding-remote-visual-assistance-software-to-your-tech-stack/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/3-factors-to-consider-when-adding-remote-visual-assistance-software-to-your-tech-stack/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 21:13:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business process management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[groupware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[industrial equipment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[team]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telecommunications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workflow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2260696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With AR solutions now projected to be a $175 billion market by 2026, a technology like remote visual assistance has the potential to seamlessly integrate into current support processes and systems.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Gary York</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/GaryYorkTech">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Gary York is the CEO of <a href="https://helplightning.com/">Help Lightning</a>. He is a serial entrepreneur with four successful software and services exits: three private sales and one IPO.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Business leaders are responsible for examining and implementing technologies that are proven, cost-effective and easy to use while also offering long-term solutions that reimagine workflows, speed up processes and increase productivity.</p>
<p>Prior to the pandemic, executives predicted that increasing the use of advanced technologies in their organizations would take more than a year-and-a-half to implement. The actual timeline for advanced implementation over the past couple of years was <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/strategy-and-corporate-finance/our-insights/how-covid-19-has-pushed-companies-over-the-technology-tipping-point-and-transformed-business-forever">27 days</a>. Following that digital transformation, companies across industries are looking to pinpoint tools that support long-term growth and predictable outcomes in a constantly changing landscape.</p>
<p>One such technology proved an especially vital addition to businesses that had to quickly implement tools to meet customer service and training needs while maintaining essential safety protocols. Remote visual assistance software fulfilled those demands by offering users the virtual presence of company expertise through real-time video collaboration.</p>
<p>With augmented reality-enabled solutions now projected to be a <a href="https://www.abiresearch.com/press/demand-augmented-reality-enterprise-and-consumer-markets-create-us175-billion-ar-market-2026/?utm_campaign=PRs%20not%20media&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;_hsmi=132681345&amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-8Gqm6Of9GPnocyF4-qq_iOkYDwQoWl2WJ_2yGRX84pBx35Rh_mRHclxAORcuwek2FQs-oFbMqcLUhE2x_rY2RPK7RNBG2r62JCt9Yw1XI6ws79Eag&amp;utm_content=132681345&amp;utm_source=hs_email">$175 billion market by 2026</a>, a technology like remote visual assistance has the potential to seamlessly integrate into current support processes and systems, with intuitive features that make it a good fit for many potential users, including customers and technicians.</p>
<p>Businesses in industries such as office equipment, medical and scientific equipment, telecommunications and industrial equipment have all seen measurable improvement in critical business metrics after adopting remote visual assistance software, particularly in their manufacturing, field service, HR, engineering and customer service departments.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			To make your sessions more effective, users should prepare to share documents, photos and other helpful files in real time.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>As leaders contemplate how to incorporate AR-enabled technology into their current systems, they’ll need to understand the tangible benefits of the solution, as well as how it will impact existing workflows and the environment needed to optimize its implementation.</p>
<p>Consider these factors as you assess the value of implementing remote visual assistance software into your tech stack.</p>
<h2>Workflow reviews</h2>
<p>Be prepared to <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00170-021-06871-4">review your workflows</a> in any area where you’re planning to incorporate remote visual assistance software. While the technology will streamline many processes, it may also change who’s involved and when they join the process. The best way to prepare for any changes to those workflows is to scrutinize current processes and identify where remote visual assistance can make the most significant impact.</p>
<p>In the customer service domain, for instance, a customer service agent who can use the software to virtually reach into the customer’s field of view, quickly inspect equipment, and demonstrate how to complete a repair will offset numerous calls from being escalated to additional technicians. In another case, an agent might use the software to help identify and troubleshoot a problem remotely and, in doing so, realize the issue requires a higher level of expertise. The next step for that customer would be another remote visual assistance session, this time with an experienced technician.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/3-factors-to-consider-when-adding-remote-visual-assistance-software-to-your-tech-stack/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2260696</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FCC proposal would curb ISP lock-ins at apartment complexes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/fcc-proposal-would-curb-isp-lock-ins-at-apartment-complexes/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/fcc-proposal-would-curb-isp-lock-ins-at-apartment-complexes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 20:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broadband providers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FCC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[isp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[isps]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2260800</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Most anyone who&#8217;s moved to a new apartment has had the same experience: Whatever broadband provider everyone else in the building has, you have. This kind of lock-in could become less common if a new proposal from the FCC is adopted, preventing revenue-sharing between providers and building owners and opening the door to competitors. It&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Most anyone who&#8217;s moved to a new apartment has had the same experience: Whatever broadband provider everyone else in the building has, you have. This kind of lock-in could become less common if <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/document/chairwoman-rosenworcel-aims-promote-broadband-choice-apartments" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a new proposal from the FCC</a> is adopted, preventing revenue-sharing between providers and building owners and opening the door to competitors.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s largely because of the cost of wiring a building that an address tends to be served by a single broadband provider. And while investments should be rewarded to a certain extent, ISPs have found ways to keep strangleholds on whole neighborhoods.</p>
<p>Sometimes they&#8217;re (technically) above-board, like an agreement with a big apartment complex where the building management gets kickbacks. And sometimes they&#8217;re loopholes in existing rules, where an ISP arranges things so that it would be prohibitively expensive for a competitor to share infrastructure.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2260800" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The new proposal, circulated internally today by FCC Chair Jessica Rosenworcel but summarized in a release, would prevent or mitigate some of these dirty tricks. It would ban revenue sharing agreements outright, require other arrangements (like marketing) to be disclosed to tenants and close loopholes that allow wiring to be effectively exclusive when it is meant to be leased or shared.</p>
<p>&#8220;With more than one-third of the U.S. population living in apartments, mobile home parks, condominiums, and public housing, it’s time to crack down on practices that lock out broadband competition and consumer choice,&#8221; said Rosenworcel. &#8220;Consumers deserve access to a choice of providers in their buildings. I look forward to having my colleagues join me in lifting the obstacles to competitive choice for broadband for the millions of tenants across the nation.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Commission recently began looking into the issue, <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-seeks-comment-broadband-access-multi-tenant-buildings-0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">opening a comment period</a> and investigating the evidence — not surprisingly, they found &#8220;a pattern of new practices that inhibit competition, contrary to the Commission’s goals, and limit opportunities for competitive providers to offer service for apartment, condo and office building unit tenants.&#8221;</p>
<p>Rosenworcel&#8217;s current proposal is the result of t1his — not a sweeping new rule but a bit of problem solving aimed squarely at bad faith activity commonly undertaken by ISPs. The proposal will be made public at some point ahead of the FCC&#8217;s vote — and even if that was tomorrow, there would likely be a considerable grace period before any of these shady arrangements are revised. So if you&#8217;re hoping to switch providers soon somewhere you&#8217;ve got no choice&#8230; keep hoping. But maybe next year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/fcc-proposal-would-curb-isp-lock-ins-at-apartment-complexes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2260800</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How should non technical founders collaborate with software developers?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/how-should-non-technical-founders-collaborate-with-software-developers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/how-should-non-technical-founders-collaborate-with-software-developers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Halpern]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 19:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agile development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Software Consulting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outsourcing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software consulting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Experts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259965</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We caught up with Georgina Lupu Florian, CEO of Wolfpack Digital, to talk about her company, how they operate, and the nuances of running a consultancy.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Software consultants come in many forms, but if you cannot write your own code, finding a developer who meets your needs can be a stressful process that involves much trial and error.</p>
<p>To narrow down good consultancies, we polled experts across the world about the best software development consultants through our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/who-are-the-best-software-development-consultants-for-startups/">TechCrunch Experts</a> program. One of the most-recommended firms we learned about is <a href="https://www.wolfpack-digital.com/">WolfPack Digital</a>. We caught up with <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/georginalupu/">Georgina &#8216;Gina&#8217; Lupu Florian</a>, CEO of Wolfpack Digital, to talk about her company, how they operate, and the nuances of running a consultancy.</p>
<p><em>(This interview has been edited for clarity and length.)</em></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259965" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><strong>TechCrunch: As a developer for hire, how involved do you get when helping clients validate ideas before they bring their apps to market?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Gina Lupu Florian:</strong> Our clients often choose us as their sole product and technical partner for their project, which means that we are highly involved in helping them with idea validation. We are here to help them with product discovery and strategy, market analysis, UX/UI design, smoke testing, usability testing, and everything else that is needed to get it right. After the coding phase is completed for any iteration, we support with rolling out the app to beta-testers, and for learning iteratively from the results in a lean way so that an optimal first version reaches the targeted audience at the official launch of the product.</p>
<p>The degree to which we get involved with the idea validation may vary depending on the goals and needs of the project, the founders and/or stakeholders, and the stage at which the project is when we begin our collaboration. Developer-for-hire is a model that has been less common for us in the past few years given our product-oriented approach, although we have ongoing collaborations fitting that model too. We are open to accommodating any setup that works best for our clients and their mobile apps or web platforms.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>Can you describe the intake process for new clients? How do you assess their requirements, and what information do you need before you can share timelines and budgets?</strong></p>
<p>The intake process can vary a lot depending on the particularities of each project and collaboration. We typically assess the information provided by our clients and put together a proposal that we refine afterwards with the client as we discover more about the product along the way.</p>
<p>To get to a robust estimated project timeline and budget, we consider user stories, wireframes, and/or a requirements document as the perfect starting point. We can either collect them directly from our clients (if they have them ready after attending incubators, etc.), or we can help with putting them together and join a discovery phase, which typically takes from a few hours to a few days. From the moment we have enough information to prepare a proposal, it usually takes less than a week to deliver it.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Help TechCrunch find the best software consultants for startups. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/MXehi2kl">this quick survey</a> and we&#8217;ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>What&#8217;s a ballpark quote for the average project, and how frequently do you communicate with clients once the work is underway? </strong></p>
<p>In general, questions about quotes are probably amongst the most difficult and yet most common. This is because quotes for web and/or mobile projects can range all the way from a few thousand  dollars to millions. It all depends on the scope, and the more clarity there is, the more accurate the estimation. However, when we start a project, we want to make sure that we keep it agile and adapt so as to bring the best product to the market. It’s all about balancing being adaptable while keeping an eye on the budget.</p>
<p>Based on the projects we have taken on recently, the average project size has been in the $100,000 to $200,000 range. Since we are an Agile company, we communicate with clients very often, typically weekly. The communication frequency depends a lot on how hands-on the client wishes to be during the development process — we have projects where we sync with them almost daily, while on others our clients prefer fewer interactions so that they can focus on different parts of their business.</p>
<p><strong>What percentage of your clients are non-technical people who have an idea, but no coding experience? How much of a limitation is that for launching an app?</strong></p>
<p>I would say probably around 50% of our clients are in this situation, either as founders of a startup, or as representatives of companies (product owners in scale-ups, or people in corporate innovation departments, for example). We are here to help with every step of the way, so we don’t see it as a limitation at all.</p>
<p>However, it’s true that having previous experience working with agencies/developers may be useful in terms of familiarity with the software development processes. But absolutely anyone, regardless of their background, can get up to speed quickly, and we are here to support them.</p>
<p><strong>As a consultant, is helping clients avoid scope creep part of your role? If so, how do you help manage their expectations?</strong></p>
<p>Definitely! I think it’s part of our responsibility, and the most important ingredient is clarifying what the priorities are. We encourage ideation, of course, but in the end, we need to focus together on what brings the most value to the product. Besides having clarity with priorities, keeping an eye on a project’s budget and considering it in all decision-making contexts is crucial, as it can be quite eye-opening.</p>
<p>Estimating the work needed for any new feature/change so that informed decisions can be made is also part of the process. Our project managers/product owners also offer their support with relevant questions along the way, and we contribute with suggestions from our team to pragmatically reach the client’s goals with the best results given all the factors involved.</p>
<p><strong>What&#8217;s your average timeline for delivering a working app after you&#8217;ve signed a contract? What do you need to accomplish before you can share wireframes?</strong></p>
<p>If we are to start a web or mobile app from scratch, respectively, from a set of requirements, and discover it, design it, code it, validate it, etc., it usually takes anywhere from three months to over a year to get to the first version. Most often it’s around six to nine months. It has a lot to do with the complexity of the product, not just from a technical standpoint, but also from a functionalities and product experience perspective to make it attractive to users.</p>
<p>You want your app to have everything it needs so that it’s useful and gets adopted by users by turning it into a better option than whatever it is they are currently using to solve a problem. For a banking app, for example, delivering an app can take longer, because there are many integrations that need to be created, and the fintech market is quite competitive, so you need to have a strong backbone in terms of functionalities in your app. At the same time, the investment brings greater benefits.</p>
<p><strong>Do you also oversee the QA process? Can Wolfpack Digital help clients navigate the approval process for app stores?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. We have an in-house QA team with a special knack for finding hidden issues, and they work closely with our developers and everyone else on the project. We have done App Store submissions hundreds of times, and we have handled a wide palette of scenarios with grace.</p>
<p>We find that approvals work seamlessly 90% of the time, but it may happen that some blockers are encountered (related to terms and conditions, for example), in which case we are ready to take on the communication on behalf of our clients and find a solution, as well as translate to accessible language what the issue and the steps needed are.</p>
<p><strong>Do you provide any marketing services?</strong></p>
<p>This has been part of our plan for a while as we actively receive requests for such services, but we are currently only marketing our own brand and don’t offer marketing execution services to clients. Based on the in-house knowledge that we have on the topic, though, we help our clients with market and audience analysis for their digital products — not just in the beginning, but also as the app scales, to suggest new features based on available data, for example.</p>
<p>So we cover marketing strategy for our clients as part of our product strategy and consultancy service. As a company, we have won awards in global competitions focusing on app concepts and product strategy, and therefore we are particularly passionate about this topic, which includes some strong marketing elements.</p>
<p><strong>Do you work on both hybrid and native apps? What can you tell us about the benefits and drawbacks of each, and when do you encourage clients to go hybrid?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, we work on both native and hybrid technologies for mobile apps, and the choice depends on each project&#8217;s type and particularities. There are a few important scenarios where we believe in the power of native iOS and Android. The first one is when scalability and stability are very important right from the beginning — with fintech apps, for example. It&#8217;s very likely they will grow in both complexity and user base, so it&#8217;s crucial to have a stable app that people can rely on.</p>
<p>Native apps scale better over time, as they use the native frameworks created by Apple and Google, so you don&#8217;t have any limits in terms of what can you do. Furthermore, with each new iOS or Android update, the native tech gets updates first, so you can tackle any OS surprises upfront.</p>
<p>Another scenario would be when the app needs to use the hardware capabilities of the phone: Bluetooth, camera, GPS, gyroscope, etc. On the native side, you have direct access to those SDKs, but with hybrid, you need to write your own plugins (in native code), or rely on existing ones from the open-source community. This can become problematic, especially with certain edge-cases (auto-reconnect, change the camera&#8217;s parameters, etc).</p>
<p>Hybrid technologies are a good fit when you are looking for quick validation of an idea, or when you&#8217;re dealing with a simple mobile app that relies pretty much on the backend. If 90% of the app is just data that you input (forms or questionnaires, for example, for a healthcare app to collect feedback), or display data from the server-side (numbers, charts, or recommendations), then Flutter can be the best option because there aren&#8217;t any functionality-related surprises to expect here. Moreover, Flutter allows you to create identical UIs for iOS and Android, if that&#8217;s one of the goals, although it&#8217;s mostly better to use native elements for each one.</p>
<p>The development time to market is typically shorter if you go for native, because you can move swiftly on two tracks in parallel, while the overall budget, at least initially, is probably higher for native. In the long run, however, hybrid may raise certain challenges that bring the budget of the project to a similar level or even exceed what native offers, depending on what challenges you find on the way, or what new functionality you need to implement.</p>
<p>The maintainability of hybrid is definitely a strong pro, as you have one single code base to maintain. Nonetheless, you need to have devs working on it who are knowledgeable on the chosen hybrid technology as well as on native, in case any plugins are needed, which may make staffing difficult. Overall, there is no right or wrong answer between native and hybrid, and the best choice depends a lot on the particularities of your app.</p>
<p><strong>Have you ever turned down a client? Are there kinds of apps you won’t work on, like e.g, games or dating?</strong></p>
<p>We have turned down clients, and, although our portfolio is quite diverse, it’s important for us that we work on projects that match our values and ethics. We have worked on dating apps, for example, but we’d turn down requests for websites or apps dealing with weapons, illegal drugs, etc.</p>
<p>Games represent a space we have not entered, as the technologies and design capabilities needed to develop games are quite different from our own (including the programming languages used — for example, we use Ruby on Rails, Vue.js, Swift, Kotlin, and Flutter, while Unity is used for games quite commonly). However, many of the apps we develop have a very strong gamification aspect.</p>
<p><strong>Who owns the source code once the project is complete? How is the source code managed?</strong></p>
<p>Typically the client owns the source code, and all the intellectual property rights belong to them, from day one. This is something that is also specified in our service agreement. When it comes to managing the source code, we cover different scenarios, but we usually have a private version-control (Git) repository on our side for each project. The team that works on the project has access to this repository, pushing code regularly while following the Git-flow guidelines.</p>
<p>Once the project is complete, or even at intermediate steps, we transfer the source code to a repository owned by the client. If needed, we assist them with creating a version-control account, then one or more repositories (depending on how many technologies are needed for that project — iOS, Android, backend, etc.), and finally with giving us access to transfer the source code to them.</p>
<p>They will of course also be able to see the commit history and each step along the way. In case any updates are needed, we can either continue to work on our own repositories and transfer the code updates again or push the code updates directly to their repositories. We also have collaborations where we work with the client’s in-house dev team, and therefore the entire team is active on the same repository at all times.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/how-should-non-technical-founders-collaborate-with-software-developers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259965</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How our SaaS startup broke into the Japanese market without a physical presence</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/how-our-saas-startup-broke-into-the-japanese-market-without-a-physical-presence/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/how-our-saas-startup-broke-into-the-japanese-market-without-a-physical-presence/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 19:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitrise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeNA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deploygate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC East Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[line]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Product Hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rakuten]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real time Web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2260643</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As a SaaS company with a community-led growth model, our journey to breaking into Japan might be different to companies with other models, but the core tenets remain the same. Here's what we learned.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Barnabas Birmacher</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/birmacher">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Barnabas Birmacher is the CEO of <a href="https://www.bitrise.io/">Bitrise</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Breaking into Japan is often one of the biggest challenges a growing tech company will encounter. The country is home to some of the world’s most advanced software and hardware leaders. For the startups that cater to these companies, “cracking Japan” is inevitably part of their growth and expansion roadmaps.</p>
<p>But the barriers to entry are high. From language and culture differences to the need to tailor offerings for a Japanese audience, many early-stage tech companies write off Japan as impossible or too difficult to break into, even if the country is inevitably part of their growth and expansion roadmap.</p>
<p>In 2014, our company attracted its first Japanese client when we were featured on product discovery platform <a href="https://www.producthunt.com/">Product Hunt</a>. While this initial awareness got us on users’ radar, awareness alone wasn’t enough to sustain and grow a reliable pipeline. We grew this initial interest to 400+ of our highest paying clients over the past eight years by making community — both virtual and in-person — central to our offering and our approach to relationship-building, all without having a dedicated presence in the county.</p>
<p>As a SaaS company with a community-led growth model, our journey to breaking into Japan might be different to companies with other models, but the core tenets remain the same. Here’s what we learned along the way.</p>
<h2>Follow the first user(s)</h2>
<p>The tech community in Japan is extremely active and interconnected, so a single customer can play a disproportionately large role in facilitating your expansion there. Our experience is that if the first users like it, they’ll be your number one ambassadors. If they don’t, their indifference will also speak volumes. With this in mind, your product should be ready for prime time before you begin working with Japanese prospects. Japan is not a testing ground for MVP products.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			As much as companies want to “be in Japan,” they don’t always spend enough time in the country.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Once you have even the smallest amount of traction or market adoption, consider setting up Japanese-language mention tracking. It can be surprising how quickly – and publicly – word about good technology will proliferate through social channels.</p>
<p>Our first user was a developer at one of Japan’s largest emerging tech companies. As Bitrise began spreading throughout his organization, we began seeing a number of new customers organically popping up at other companies as well.</p>
<p>Through our mention tracking service (we use <a href="https://mention.com/en/">Mention.com</a>), we were able to see how the user adoption we were experiencing directly correlated with local discussions about us on social media.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/how-our-saas-startup-broke-into-the-japanese-market-without-a-physical-presence/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2260643</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>VCs approached Facebook to fund a spinout of Workplace valued at over $1B, but Facebook declined</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/vcs-approached-facebook-to-fund-a-spinout-of-workplace-valued-at-over-1b-but-facebook-declined/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/vcs-approached-facebook-to-fund-a-spinout-of-workplace-valued-at-over-1b-but-facebook-declined/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 18:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bravo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Francisco Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[head]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IBM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Julien Codorniou]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Karandeep Anand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kustomer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoma bravo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Workplace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2244190</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Workplace &#8212; the app originally built as a version of Facebook for employees to communicate with each other &#8212; now has more than 7 million users, carving out a place for itself as an app to help companies communicate internally using essentially the same tools that have proven sticky in their lives with friends and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.workplace.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Workplace</a> &#8212; the app <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/10/10/facebook-workplace" target="_blank" rel="noopener">originally built</a> as a version of Facebook for employees to communicate with each other &#8212; now has more than 7 million users, carving out a place for itself as an app to help companies communicate internally using essentially the same tools that have proven sticky in their lives with friends and family. That traction, it turns out, has been giving Workplace attention of another kind.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve learned that Facebook (before it was rebranded as Meta) was approached by enterprise investors offering the social network a proposition: spin off the organization, they said, and let us back it as a startup. A deal would have valued a newly independent Workplace as a &#8220;unicorn&#8221; (at least at $1 billion) according to the source.</p>
<p>A source tells us that conversations didn&#8217;t progress, primarily because Facebook (and now Meta) saw Workplace as a &#8220;strategic asset&#8221; &#8212; not because Workplace generates sales anywhere close to the billions Meta makes from advertising on platforms like Facebook and Instagram, but important rather for presenting a more diverse face to the market. For regulators, it shows that Facebook/Meta is more than just a too-powerful social network; and for organizations, that Facebook can do more for them than just sell ads.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2244190" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;It helps make Facebook [and Meta] look like an adult,&#8221; the source said.</p>
<p>Spokespeople from Meta and Workplace said that they had nothing to share and declined to comment for this article.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not clear which investors were involved, but a source says that they were among those focused on late-stage, growth round investments with a view to injecting capital specifically in enterprise opportunities.</p>
<p>Their approach to fund a spun-out Workplace last year would have come at a time when late-stage and private equity investors were (and still are) ramping up their activities to snap up big, mature tech businesses. Thoma Bravo last year was reported to be <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/456f2fd7-f868-4ea6-abd7-fce34e783333" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raising $35 billion</a> to home in on more acquisition opportunities in the space (and it&#8217;s been making a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/israeli-fintech-personetics-raises-85m-for-tools-to-help-incumbents-personalize-banking-services-to-compete-with-neobanks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wide</a> number of investments and <a href="https://www.bottomline.com/us/newsroom/press-releases/bottomline-be-acquired-thoma-bravo-26-billion" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquisitions</a> to that end). Bloomberg estimates that private equity acquisitions totaled <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-30/private-equity-s-taste-for-tech-sparks-record-80-billion-spree" target="_blank" rel="noopener">some $80 billion in 2021</a>, up more than 140% compared to 2020.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That pace does not look like it is slowing down this year, and it includes PE firms approaching larger technology behemoths to spin out operations as they look to streamline and realise more capital from less core, or possibly unprofitable, or more generally lagging, assets. Just earlier today, Francisco Partners <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/francisco-partners-scoops-up-remains-of-ibms-watson-health-unit/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> a deal to snap up IBM&#8217;s Watson Health business, reportedly for around $1 billion.</p>
<h2>Building a SaaS beachhead</h2>
<p>For Meta, an approach to spin out Workplace highlights developments on two fronts.</p>
<p>On the corporate side, there have been calls to break up the company &#8212; the latest development on that front from earlier this month is that the courts ruled that the U.S. Federal Trade Commission can proceed with a lawsuit mandating a sale of <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2022/jan/12/lawsuit-aiming-to-break-up-facebook-group-meta-can-go-ahead-us-court-rules" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WhatsApp and Instagram</a>, alongside, reportedly, a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/14/the-ftc-is-reportedly-probing-metas-vr-business-for-antitrust-violations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">separate probe of its VR division</a> for antitrust violations. It&#8217;s a situation that some investors and shareholders will see as an opportunity, a tension that Meta might increasingly need to weigh up as it justifies holding on to its various assets.</p>
<p>For Workplace, the division has found itself at a key crossroads in the last several months.</p>
<p>On one side, Workplace has seen a number of key departures, including no less than its top two executives, Karandeep Anand (who this month was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/brex-confirms-12-3b-valuation-hires-meta-exec-to-serve-as-its-chief-product-officer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">named</a> chief product officer at Brex) and Julien Codorniou, who left to become a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/07/felix-capital-adds-julien-codorniou-ex-head-of-metas-workplace-susan-lin-as-newest-partners/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">partner at London VC Felix Capital</a>. A number of others have also left the building to move on to other opportunities elsewhere.</p>
<p>The logic behind some of that movement was described to me, charitably, not as a response to the bad PR that Meta has faced, but natural attrition: Here was a group of people assembled to create and build Workplace from the ground up, and now that it&#8217;s a more mature product with a clearer focus, it&#8217;s the right time for new people to come in and work on the next stage. (My personal opinion: Workplace&#8217;s new head, Ujjwal Singh, feels like a solid choice to lead it right now.)</p>
<p>But even if there has been reporting <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2021/11/the-great-facebook-employee-exodus-that-wasnt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">contradicting</a> that workers might feel worn down by Meta constantly being bashed in the court of public opinion, Workplace has not been immune to it, either. We understand that Workplace signed a huge deal with a major chain of restaurants, one of the biggest, but the customer asked to hold off on announcing the win last autumn because of the bad news cycle and &#8220;reputation issues.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;That shit doesn&#8217;t happen to other SaaS companies,&#8221; one person said.</p>
<p>That, it seems, would have been one argument in favor of distancing Workplace further from its parent, perhaps by way of a spinout, but it seems that Meta has the opposite idea.</p>
<p>Workplace has actually changed a lot over the years since it was first rolled out as a product.</p>
<p>Founded originally as a &#8220;work&#8221; version of Facebook &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/06/25/facebook-at-work" target="_blank" rel="noopener">expanding how Facebook employees were already using Facebook</a> to communicate to each other in private groups &#8212; Workplace was launched as a response to the rise of Slack and other chat apps for the workplace. Workplace&#8217;s logic was that it had a natural advantage since billions were already using Facebook. And, bringing in a new service targeting a different kind of user, with a different business model &#8212; paid, not ad-supported &#8212; opened the door to new business possibilities for the company.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s largely remained the strategy for the company even as the focus has changed for Workplace. Originally it introduced a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/12/06/facebook-workplace-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">number of integrations with other workplace productivity tools</a> aimed at knowledge workers, part of a bigger effort to compete more directly against the likes of Slack and Teams. But over time, almost on accident, Workplace found an audience with deskless workers who communicated with their employers mainly by mobile. So what has emerged as the sweet spot for Workplace is being a communications app for both categories of workers simultaneously.</p>
<p>&#8220;We realised that instead of asking our customers to choose between Teams or Slack and Workplace, you could have both,&#8221; a source said. &#8220;Others could handle real-time messaging communications for knowledge workers, while Workplace does asynchronous best for everyone.&#8221;</p>
<p>And that appears to be the guiding idea for Workplace&#8217;s strategy now, which has seen it recently integrate <a href="https://www.workplace.com/blog/workplace-and-microsoft-teams" target="_blank" rel="noopener">more functionality from Microsoft Teams</a> into its platform to complement Workplace, and yesterday to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/20/metas-workplace-will-integrate-with-whatsapp-later-this-year-to-expand-communication-with-frontline-employees/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announce a new integration with WhatsApp</a>, which is already very popular with frontline teams, and will now become a more formal interface for Workplace communications. From what we understand, closer integrations and services involving Meta&#8217;s VR business and the Portal are also in the works.</p>
<p>While the company is not due to update on user numbers until later this year, a source told us that there are now closer to 10 million users on Workplace, with key customers including some of the world&#8217;s biggest employers, like Walmart, Astra Zeneca and others.</p>
<p>While Workplace had in the past been sold to customers as a standalone product, &#8220;I don&#8217;t think it will be sold as a standalone application ever again,&#8221; a source said.</p>
<p>Instead, it will be part of a suite, for example selling business messaging plus Workplace, or along with a Facebook login feature, opening up the prospects of how Meta can engage with those businesses. (The wider sales pitch to enterprises is also likely a behind its motivation to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/facebook-confirms-it-has-acquired-kustomer-sources-say-for-1b/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquire Kustomer, the CRM startup</a>, although that deal has yet to close.)</p>
<p>So far from being ready to part with Workplace, it seems that Meta is now positioning it as part of a beachhead comprising a bigger SaaS business. Can it mobilize as an independent company might have done to realize that opportunity? VCs might still be waiting in the wings if it doesn&#8217;t.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/vcs-approached-facebook-to-fund-a-spinout-of-workplace-valued-at-over-1b-but-facebook-declined/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2244190</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>European spend management platform Moss raises $86 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/european-spend-management-platform-moss-raises-86-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/european-spend-management-platform-moss-raises-86-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 18:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spend management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiger Global Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2260750</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Berlin-based startup Moss announced earlier this week that it has closed a new $86 million Series B funding round (€75 million). The company offers corporate credit cards for small and medium companies so that they can more easily spend and track their spending. Following today’s funding round, Moss has reached a valuation of $573 million [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Berlin-based startup <a href="https://en.getmoss.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Moss</a> announced earlier this week that it has closed a new $86 million Series B funding round (€75 million). The company offers corporate credit cards for small and medium companies so that they can more easily spend and track their spending.</p>
<p>Following today’s funding round, Moss has reached a valuation of $573 million (€500 million). Tiger Global Management is leading the Series B with A-Star also participating. Overall, the company has raised nearly $150 million in total (€130 million).</p>
<p>Moss could be considered as a spend management platform. It competes with other European players, such as <a href="https://www.spendesk.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Spendesk</a>, <a href="https://www.pleo.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pleo</a> and <a href="https://www.soldo.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Soldo</a>. What sets Moss apart from its competitors is that it offers credit cards, not debit cards. But transactions still show up in your Moss dashboard seconds after each payment.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2260750" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In addition to physical cards, employees can also generate virtual cards for online payments. Every time they make a purchase, Moss customers get 0.4% in cash back on all expenses.</p>
<p>This way, small companies don’t have to share one corporate card for all expenses. Team leaders can set budgets for each employee and track expenses more easily.</p>
<p>For employees themselves, corporate cards aren’t that common in Europe. By switching to Moss they don’t have to pay out of pocket for employee expenses. They can use a Moss card and attach the receipt to the transaction. And if a restaurant doesn’t accept card payments, Moss also handles cash expenses and reimbursements.</p>
<p>In addition to card payments, you can rely on Moss for other types of payments by centralizing all your invoices in your Moss account. Moss users can set up approval rules and export payments lists for the business bank account.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Finally, Moss can speed up accounting tasks as it integrates with Datev, a popular accounting software on the German market. Going forward, the startup is going to make its product more modular. You won’t have to use the entire spend management stack if you don’t need everything.</p>
<p>Overall, Moss has processed 250,000 transactions and issued 20,000 cards. The product is live in Germany and the Netherlands. The company now plans to expand to the U.K.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/european-spend-management-platform-moss-raises-86-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2260750</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calii bags $22.5M to build Latin America’s grocery shopping future</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/calii-bags-22-5m-to-build-latin-americas-grocery-shopping-future/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/calii-bags-22-5m-to-build-latin-americas-grocery-shopping-future/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 17:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Base10 Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Calii]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dalus Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Eduardo Arrambide Montemayor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forerunner ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grocery store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JAM Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maurizio Caló Caligaris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streamlined ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2260422</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The mobile grocery app automates the supply chain, enabling customers to choose over 5,000 products delivered via a network of micro-fulfillment centers in less than two hours. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Grocery delivery startup <a href="https://calii.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Calii</a> is carving out a piece of Latin America’s <a href="https://sacra.com/research/rappi-the-meituan-of-latin-america/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$1 trillion groceries and food delivery market</a> with its approach to cut inefficiencies in the food supply chain so it can bring produce and thousands of other grocery items to customers’ doorsteps in less than two hours.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2260534" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2260534" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2260534" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/calii_app_screenshot_4.png?w=314" alt="Calii" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/calii_app_screenshot_4.png 828w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/calii_app_screenshot_4.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/calii_app_screenshot_4.png?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/calii_app_screenshot_4.png?resize=768,1662 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/calii_app_screenshot_4.png?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/calii_app_screenshot_4.png?resize=710,1536 710w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/calii_app_screenshot_4.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2260534" class="wp-caption-text">Calii app</p></div></p>
<p>To continue on that mission, the company announced Friday $22.5 million in Series A funding co-led by Dalus Capital and JAM Fund, with participation from backers including Forerunner Ventures, Streamlined Ventures, Y Combinator and Base10 Partners. To date, it has raised nearly $35 million.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2260422" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>David Eduardo Arrambide Montemayor and Maurizio Caló Caligaris, both Stanford-educated engineers, started Calii, a mobile grocery app that connects with producers and brands to automate the supply chain end-to-end and deliver more than 5,000 products, like produce, meat, seafood and prepared items, via a network of micro-fulfillment centers.</p>
<p>This not only provides customers with food savings, but reduces environmental waste by up to three times, CEO Arrambide Montemayor told TechCrunch via email.</p>
<p>“By cutting middlemen and reducing inefficiencies, we generate more profits for producers and pass on greater savings to our users,” he added. “Our products are priced at par or lower than traditional supermarkets, such as Walmart.”</p>
<p>Calii is operating in what has become quite a crowded space aiming to lift Latin America’s current less than 5% online grocery sales within the retail market. Arrambide Montemayor considers the company’s competitors to fall into three categories: marketplaces, like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/uber-to-become-the-sole-owner-of-grocery-delivery-startup-cornershop/">Cornershop</a>, quick commerce, like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/instant-grocery-delivery-startup-jokr-bags-another-huge-round-to-enter-unicorn-status/">Jokr</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/colombian-on-demand-delivery-startup-rappi-raises-over-500m-at-a-5-25b-valuation/">Rappi Turbo</a>, and full groceries, like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/mexican-online-grocer-justo-raises-65m-in-general-atlantic-led-series-a/">Jüsto</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/colombias-merqueo-bags-50m-to-expand-its-online-grocery-delivery-service-across-latin-america/">Merqueo</a>, with the four last companies all attracting venture capital in the past year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>What differentiates Calii from those players is pricing, speed and fewer products.</p>
<p>“Our tech-driven approach of automated micro-fulfillment centers, digitized picking and packing, machine learning and big data algorithms for SKU selection and demand forecasting and focus on ultra-fresh produce and grocery items, make us the top-rated grocery app, replacing the weekly grocery trip to the supermarket,” he added.</p>
<p>When Arrambide Montemayor and Caló Caligaris launched the company in March 2019, the team spent the first 24 months in two markets to perfect the model, user experience and unit economics.</p>
<p>Over the past 12 months Calii grew more than three times in revenue. In Monterrey, its first market, the company delivers over 2,000 orders per day, and the average order value is above $40. During the same time period, the company grew its headcount by 250% to over 250 employees and operators.</p>
<p>With the funding, the company is kicking off a new phase of lightning-fast expansion and growth, Arrambide Montemayor said. It is expanding its footprint in Mexico and the rest of Latin America, with plans to be in more than 14 cities and multiple countries in the next six months.</p>
<p>Additionally, it is rolling out new complementary products, services and categories, including home appliances and electronics; Market, with over 40,000 grocery items with same-day or next-day delivery; and buy now, pay later offering Calii Pay. The funding will also enable the company to triple its headcount on its way to surpassing 10,000 daily orders.</p>
<p>“To truly crack the $1 trillion groceries market in LatAm, we understand that we cannot be a premium service, charging 20% more than supermarket; therefore, we&#8217;re rebuilding and automating the grocery supply chain from first principles, injecting tech and data in every layer, in order to deliver ultra-freshness with savings,” Arrambide Montemayor added.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cwyMlqso5V"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/17/are-rivals-snacking-on-instacarts-core-grocery-delivery-market/">Are rivals snacking on Instacart&#8217;s core grocery delivery market?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Are rivals snacking on Instacart&#8217;s core grocery delivery market?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/17/are-rivals-snacking-on-instacarts-core-grocery-delivery-market/embed/#?secret=cwyMlqso5V" data-secret="cwyMlqso5V" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/calii-bags-22-5m-to-build-latin-americas-grocery-shopping-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2260422</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cana Technology raises glass to new capital as it readies beverage printer for market</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/cana-technology-raises-glass-to-new-capital-as-it-readies-beverage-printer-for-market/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/cana-technology-raises-glass-to-new-capital-as-it-readies-beverage-printer-for-market/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 17:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bharat vasan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cana Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[connected device]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lance Kizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matt Mahar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sodastream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Production Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2260407</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cana focused on identifying the basic set of ingredients, basically deconstructing beverages to figure out what makes it taste like a certain drink.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Following nearly four years in the prototype phase, <a href="https://www.cana.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cana Technology</a> is unveiling what it calls the “world’s first molecular beverage printer” after securing $30 million in funding from venture foundry The Production Board.</p>
<p>If you’re wondering exactly what this might be, it’s basically a SodaStream meets a computer printer. The smart connected device is about the size of a toaster, sits on your kitchen counter and can produce an infinite variety of beverages, from juice to coffee to cocktails, by recombining it with water in your home, all from one “printer” cartridge, by using a touch screen.</p>
<p>Here’s where the “molecular” technology comes into play: Cana focused on identifying the basic set of ingredients, basically deconstructing beverages to figure out what makes it taste like a certain drink, Lance Kizer, Cana’s chief science officer, told TechCrunch.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2260407" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Once you remove the water, there is a small volume of drink that you are actually consuming, around 5% to 10%, so Cana concentrated those ingredients and loaded them into a cartridge that can hold more than 100 different beverages. The company has partnered with certain brands for drinks and also created their own combinations.</p>
<p>“It is all of the same ingredients that you consume in drinks, so we are not recreating them,” Kizer said. “Quality is important, and we are focusing on making beverages in a novel way, and we have now created hundreds of them.”</p>
<p>Not only do you have hundreds of drinks at your fingertips, you also can customize them to your taste: add more sugar or less sugar, and for the alcoholic drinks, more or less alcohol. While learning about the device, I was able to try a few of the drinks — cold brew coffee, root beer and a black cherry mojito — and thought the flavors were more bold than their traditional counterparts and the overall taste had a smooth finish.</p>
<p>Each cartridge holds one to three months&#8217; worth of beverages, and the device senses when the cartridge is low and automatically reorders. The cartridges are designed to be sent back for recycling, Kizer added</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Cana’s goal is to rebuild the $2 trillion beverage industry while also saving waste from going into landfills and excessive water being used at the same time. CEO Matt Mahar explained that Cana’s prototype would save the typical American household roughly 100 beverage containers per month. At scale, Cana could reduce the use of plastic and glass containers, water waste and the CO<sub>2</sub> emissions of the global beverage manufacturing complex by more than 80%.</p>
<p>The new funding is being heavily invested into the supply chain and continued technology development, Mahar said. The company currently has 35 employees, and he expects to double that this year.</p>
<p>Mahar said the company is still working on the device’s price point, but that it will be cheaper than retail prices per use. By the end of February, he expected to have full data on both pricing and when people will be able to begin purchasing the device.</p>
<p>Bharat Vasan, president and COO of The Production Board, said the venture foundry has invested in a number of companies in the food space, and says the Cana team was attractive due to their ambitious outlook on technology and the way they combined hardware, software and science in an entirely new way of making something.</p>
<p>To him, Cana’s device “feels like the Netflix of beverage experiences,” and the same concentration technology used for drinks could be used for a number of other products, like perfume and cosmetics.</p>
<p>“It’s about changing the way things are made and shipped out,” he said. “Distributed manufacturing is made in one place and then shipped out to retailers. Now there is a different system of delivery that is directly to your house that can bypass supply chain constraints. The beverage printer is one manifestation.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pNVin7SD7o"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/07/iot-and-data-science-will-boost-foodtech-in-the-post-pandemic-era/">IoT and data science will boost foodtech in the post-pandemic era</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;IoT and data science will boost foodtech in the post-pandemic era&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/07/iot-and-data-science-will-boost-foodtech-in-the-post-pandemic-era/embed/#?secret=pNVin7SD7o" data-secret="pNVin7SD7o" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/cana-technology-raises-glass-to-new-capital-as-it-readies-beverage-printer-for-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2260407</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Raven Software testers at Activision Blizzard form the first union at a major US gaming company</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/activision-blizzard-union-raven-software/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/activision-blizzard-union-raven-software/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 16:54:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Activision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blizzard Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[call of duty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raven software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wisconsin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2260667</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Raven Software&#8217;s quality assurance (QA) department &#8212; which mostly works on &#8220;Call of Duty&#8221; as part of Activision Blizzard &#8212; became the first union to form at a major U.S. gaming company. With help from the Communications Workers of America (CWA), Raven Software testers launched the Game Workers Alliance, which plans to focus on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today, Raven Software&#8217;s quality assurance (QA) department &#8212; which mostly works on &#8220;Call of Duty&#8221; as part of Activision Blizzard &#8212; became the first union to form at a major U.S. gaming company. With help from the Communications Workers of America (CWA), Raven Software testers launched the <a href="https://gameworkersalliance.com/about-us-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Game Workers Alliance</a>, which plans to focus on &#8220;improving the conditions of workers in the video game industry by making it a more sustainable, equitable place where transparency is paramount,&#8221; even beyond its own company. The <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-01-21/activision-employee-group-forms-union-a-first-in-video-games?sref=gni836kR" target="_blank" rel="noopener">34-worker unit</a> is asking management to recognize their union during a time already marked by change: on Tuesday, Microsoft acquired Activision Blizzard for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/microsoft-acquire-activision-blizzard/">$68.7 billion</a> in one of the priciest tech acquisitions of all time.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ItirjPOyWS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/why-microsofts-2t-market-cap-makes-its-78b-activision-buy-a-cheap-bet/">Why Microsoft&#8217;s $2T+ market cap makes its $68B Activision buy a cheap bet</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why Microsoft&#8217;s $2T+ market cap makes its $68B Activision buy a cheap bet&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/why-microsofts-2t-market-cap-makes-its-78b-activision-buy-a-cheap-bet/embed/#?secret=ItirjPOyWS" data-secret="ItirjPOyWS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But on the heels of that historic acquisition, Activision Blizzard has been embroiled in controversy amid ongoing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/blizzard-sec-investigation/">SEC investigations</a> and <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/activision-videogames-bobby-kotick-sexual-misconduct-allegations-11637075680" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sexual harassment scandals</a>. Internally, employees started laying a grassroots foundation for worker solidarity through groups like the <a href="https://twitter.com/ABetterABK" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ABK Workers Alliance</a>. When Raven Software<a href="https://www.polygon.com/22820273/raven-software-layoffs-walk-out-protest-activision" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> laid off 12 contractors</a> in early December, the team at the Wisconsin-based studio staged a walkout, which has continued for five weeks and counting.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2260667" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Raven Software QA tester Onah Rongstad told TechCrunch that this incident sparked discussions about unionizing.</p>
<p>&#8220;On December 3, about a third of my department was informed that their contracts were going to be terminated early. And this was coming off of a five-week stretch of overtime, consistent work,&#8221; she said. &#8220;We realized in that moment that our day-to-day work and our crucial role in the games industry as QA was not being taken into consideration. And at that time, we decided as Raven QA to start a strike to demonstrate that we are not just disposable parts of the industry, and during that time, it became very apparent that we had majority support within our department for a union.&#8221;</p>
<p>The ABK Workers Alliance used its sizable social media following to<a href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/abk-strike-fund?utm_source=customer&amp;utm_medium=copy_link&amp;utm_campaign=p_cf+share-flow-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> crowdfund over $370,000</a> to assist with wages during the strike. The CWA said that this strike was the third work stoppage at Activision Blizzard after the company was sued in July 2021 over sexual harassment and misconduct claims. Still, about 20 members of the department remain on strike, Rongstad told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are not sure how long [the strike] will continue, because we have not had direct communication with leadership about our demand that the 12 individuals who were let go be reinstated, which is unfortunate,&#8221; said Rongstad, who has been with Raven Software since September 2020. &#8220;We are hoping to be able to go through with our unionization and get voluntary recognition so that we can prevent something like this from happening in the future.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Rongstad added that the news of Microsoft&#8217;s planned acquisition does not change the union&#8217;s plans to seek recognition.</p>
<p>&#8220;At the end of the day, we want to be able to work with leadership to create the most positive and beneficial work environment for all of the workers at ABK, and we are happy to work with leadership, whether that is the current leadership or Microsoft leadership in the future,&#8221; they told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>This level of organizing among workers has little precedent in gaming, despite the industry being notorious for <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/video-games/2021/03/24/crunch-laws/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">over-working</a> employees or deploying <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2021-05-14/even-after-a-boom-year-it-s-hard-to-hold-onto-a-job-in-gaming?sref=gni836kR" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mass layoffs</a> due to closing studios. But only a month ago did the first voluntarily recognized gaming union form in North America at the small indie studio <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22834924/vodeo-games-first-video-game-union-north-america-code-cwa" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vodeo Games</a>, which produces &#8220;Beast Breaker.&#8221; Vodeo&#8217;s union also works with the CWA.</p>
<p>In an emailed statement to TechCrunch, Activision Blizzard responded to the Game Workers Alliance&#8217;s announcement:</p>
<blockquote><p><i>Activision Blizzard is carefully reviewing the request for voluntary recognition from the CWA, which seeks to organize around three dozen of the company’s nearly 10,000 employees. While we believe that a direct relationship between the company and its team members delivers the strongest workforce opportunities, we deeply respect the rights of all employees under the law to make their own decisions about whether or not to join a union. </i><u></u><u></u></p>
<p><i>Across Activision Blizzard, we remain focused on listening closely to our employees and providing the improved pay, benefits and professional opportunities needed to attract and retain the world’s best talent. Over the past couple of years, this has included raising minimum compensation for Raven QA employees by 41%, extending paid time off, expanding access to medical benefits for employees and significant others, and transitioning more than 60% of temporary Raven QA staff into full-time employees.<u></u><u></u></i></p></blockquote>
<p>It&#8217;s yet to be seen whether or not Activision Blizzard will voluntarily recognize the Game Workers Alliance. If Activision Blizzard chooses to recognize the union, then they don&#8217;t need to have a union election and can begin collective bargaining. If the company opts not to recognize them, then the union can conduct an election through the National Labor Relations Board.</p>
<p>&#8220;We do have supermajority, and that&#8217;s why we were able to ask for voluntary recognition. We&#8217;re confident that if it went to a vote, we would win,&#8221; said Rongstad. &#8220;We are hoping that they will voluntarily recognize the union and just show their support for workers rights.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Game Workers Alliance is giving Activision Blizzard until January 25 to respond to their request for voluntary recognition. Read their letter below:</p>
<p><iframe class="scribd_iframe_embed" src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/554309747/content?start_page=1&view_mode&access_key=key-dMs5cNyNTtEVUzW16I9O"  data-auto-height="true" scrolling="no" id="scribd_554309747" width="100%" height="500" frameborder="0"></iframe>
		<div style="font-size:10px;text-align:center;width:100%"><a href="https://www.scribd.com/doc/554309747" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">View this document on Scribd</a></div></p>
<p><em>Update, 1/21/22, 3:00 PM ET with comment from Activision Blizzard and a Raven Software QA tester.</em></p>
<p><em>Update, 1/21/22, 3:25 PM ET with the Game Workers Alliance&#8217;s letter to Activision Blizzard.</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Og1JlxQFuw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/microsoft-acquire-activision-blizzard/">Microsoft to buy Activision Blizzard for $68.7 billion</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Microsoft to buy Activision Blizzard for $68.7 billion&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/microsoft-acquire-activision-blizzard/embed/#?secret=Og1JlxQFuw" data-secret="Og1JlxQFuw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pBmge8qlRn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/blizzard-walkout-activision-lawsuit/">Activision Blizzard workers will stage a walkout after &#8216;abhorrent&#8217; response to harassment suit</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Activision Blizzard workers will stage a walkout after &#8216;abhorrent&#8217; response to harassment suit&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/blizzard-walkout-activision-lawsuit/embed/#?secret=pBmge8qlRn" data-secret="pBmge8qlRn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/activision-blizzard-union-raven-software/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2260667</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Netflix’s dismal results are more evidence that the pandemic trade is over</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/netflixs-dismal-results-are-more-evidence-that-the-pandemic-trade-is-over/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/netflixs-dismal-results-are-more-evidence-that-the-pandemic-trade-is-over/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 16:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peloton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the pandemic trade]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2260644</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The pandemic trade is coming apart, and Netflix is the latest company to suffer.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/20/the-pandemic-trade-is-over/">got its teeth into the pandemic trade</a> and its possible conclusion yesterday. As a refresher: After the initial onset of COVID-19 and the ensuing lockdowns, changes to work environments and restriction of travel, some companies saw their values quickly appreciate as they found investor favor.</p>
<p>The reasons for some sectors gaining luster in the eyes of the investing class were manifold, but can be condensed. Companies and sectors that saw demand accelerated by the pandemic saw their share prices similarly improve. And software companies, which showed resilience thanks to customers not being able to operate without paying for their offerings, quickly appreciated, pushing their valuations higher and higher.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on TechCrunch+</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>Until the trade ended. Software companies <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/the-era-of-ultra-rich-software-valuations-could-be-behind-us/">began to shed their pandemic valuation gains</a> in the final weeks of 2021 and have continued to do so in the new year. For companies like Peloton, which rode a consumer demand shift that gave their products more shine, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/20/peloton-reportedly-pauses-bike-and-treadmill-production-amid-slowed-demand/">the trade is coming apart a little bit later</a>.</p>
<p>Netflix is the latest company to suffer. Recent earnings results were just short of a catastrophe for the U.S. streaming company. Its shares are off around 22% this morning, bringing its value down to around $174 billion from a peak of more than $300 billion set last November.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-2220369 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>As a pandemic trade, Netflix was an obvious contender; it provides inexpensive at-home entertainment. And when everyone stayed home, well, Netflix did quite well.</p>
<p>But that accelerated period of growth has ended. Netflix’s latest earnings report shows that instead of the company enjoying an expanded total market for its services that earlier, faster growth might have hinted at, it may have instead taken future growth and moved it up, leaving the popular video service now in low-growth quicksand, with investor expectations above what it can deliver.</p>
<p>Today, we’re exploring whether international growth can replace lost domestic growth at the company, and what could be ahead for firms like Netflix that find themselves coming down from a period of elevated investor attention and consumer demand. Netflix is an example, but what the company is going through could be an indicator of what’s ahead for other consumer services that had a strong period of growth amid the pandemic. Who else is in danger?</p>
<h2>Understanding Netflix&#8217;s results</h2>
<p>Netflix gained 8.3 million new paid subscriptions in Q4 2021, finishing the year with 222 million paid memberships. That doesn&#8217;t sound bad out of context, but context matters. First, the company projection was 8.5 million, not 8.3 – and markets are never fond of missed forecasts. Second, the 222 million figure means this was its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/20/netflix-q4-2021-results-subscriber-numbers/">lowest year of subscriber growth since 2015</a>.</p>
<p>Taking a step back, this isn&#8217;t so much about missing the mark as it is about trust in numbers. Is Netflix capable of interpreting its situation correctly? And of forecasting accurately? Needing to address this may also explain why the company is more conservative in its Q1 2022 forecast. For the current quarter, it only expects 2.5 million new paid subscriptions, compared to 4 million in Q1 2021 – when, by the way, it expected 6 million.</p>
<p>But even if the company is adjusting its guidance, it still leaves questions about what is going on. For instance, media experts may wonder if the company is affected by increased competition or merely reaching saturation levels. Netflix dismisses the importance of these concerns, and we tend to agree. It isn&#8217;t necessarily good news, though.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/21/netflixs-dismal-results-are-more-evidence-that-the-pandemic-trade-is-over/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2260644</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
