<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 13:24:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Forbes jumps into hot media liquidity summer with a SPAC combo</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/forbes-jumps-into-hot-media-liquidity-summer-with-a-spac-combo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/forbes-jumps-into-hot-media-liquidity-summer-with-a-spac-combo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 13:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buzzfeed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Forbes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magazines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[special-purpose acquisition company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verizon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194388</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Is it the most exciting debut? No. But it does highlight that with enough gumption, one can take a magazine business into the digital age and keep aggregate revenue growing. That's worth something.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">What a busy week in the world of media liquidity.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s a sentence you don&#8217;t get to write often. Regardless, news broke this week that <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210826005451/en/Axel-Springer-to-Acquire-POLITICO">Axel Springer is buying U.S. political journalism outfit POLITICO</a>. The transaction was expected, but the eye-popping roughly $1 billion price tag still has tongues wagging. We even got <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/politico-sells-forbes-spacs-and-vice-cuts/">on the podcast</a> to chat about it.</p>
<p>And <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbespr/2021/08/26/forbes-to-become-public-company-through-business-combination-with-special-purpose-acquisition-company-magnum-opus/?sh=6995b05320eb">Forbes announced</a> that it is going public via a SPAC. The business publication&#8217;s news follows BuzzFeed&#8217;s journey to the public markets through a blank-check company. Hot media liquidity summer? Something like that.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>That TechCrunch is in the process of being sold to private equity, of course, is not something that we should forget. Shoutout to the Verizon bankers who found a way to get rid of us while also deleveraging Verizon&#8217;s debt profile. Ten points.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995212 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>I want to take a quick tour of the Forbes SPAC deck this morning. Our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/5-takeaways-from-buzzfeeds-spac-deck/">notes on BuzzFeed&#8217;s are here</a>, in case you want to run comparisons. This will be easy and fun. Perfect Friday morning fare. Into the data!</p>
<h2>What&#8217;s it worth?</h2>
<p>In corporate-speak, Forbes Global Media Holdings is merging with blank-check company Magnum Opus Acquisition Limited. The <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbespr/2021/08/26/forbes-to-become-public-company-through-business-combination-with-special-purpose-acquisition-company-magnum-opus/?sh=699c8090320e">transaction</a> will close either Q4 2021 or Q1 2022, Forbes estimates.</p>
<p>The deal itself is somewhat modest in scale compared with other SPAC deals we&#8217;ve recently looked into. Forbes reports that it will sport &#8220;an implied pro forma enterprise value of $630 million, net of tax benefits,&#8221; after its completion. Some $600 million in gross proceeds will be derived from Magnum Opus funds &#8220;and $400 million of additional capital through a private placement of ordinary shares of the combined company,&#8221; Forbes writes.</p>
<p>The company will sport an equity valuation of $830 million after the deal closes, per its own calculations. That number will change some depending on redemptions ahead of the combination. The gap between the large dollars going into the deal and the modest final valuation of the public Forbes entity is due to some $440 million in secondary transactions for existing Forbes shareholders.</p>
<p>In case you&#8217;d prefer all of that in table form, <a href="https://d1io3yog0oux5.cloudfront.net/opusacquisition/files/pages/opusacquisition/db/1148/description/Fusion+Investor+Presentation++vFINAL+2.pdf">here&#8217;s the Forbes investor deck</a>:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2194981" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2194981" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2194981 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-27-at-8.22.00-AM.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="321" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-27-at-8.22.00-AM.png 1056w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-27-at-8.22.00-AM.png?resize=150,71 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-27-at-8.22.00-AM.png?resize=300,141 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-27-at-8.22.00-AM.png?resize=768,362 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-27-at-8.22.00-AM.png?resize=680,321 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-27-at-8.22.00-AM.png?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2194981" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Forbes SPAC deck</p></div></p>
<p>Is $830 million a fair price? Let&#8217;s dig into Forbes&#8217; results.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/forbes-jumps-into-hot-media-liquidity-summer-with-a-spac-combo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194388</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stonehenge Technology Labs bags $2M, gives CPG companies one-touch access to metrics</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/stonehenge-technology-labs-bags-2m-gives-cpg-companies-one-touch-access-to-metrics/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/stonehenge-technology-labs-bags-2m-gives-cpg-companies-one-touch-access-to-metrics/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 13:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Angeles Investors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arkansas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bonfire ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bread and butter ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brett brohl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dan Rossignol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaingels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irish Angels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meagan Kinmoth Bowman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Red Tail Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stonehenge Technology Labs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Stonehenge Technology Labs wants consumer packaged goods companies to gain meaningful use from all of the data they collect.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://stonehengelabs.tech/">Stonehenge Technology Labs</a> wants consumer packaged goods companies to gain meaningful use from all of the data they collect. It announced $2 million in seed funding for its STOPWATCH commerce enhancement software.</p>
<p>The round was led by Irish Angels, with participation from Bread and Butter Ventures, Gaingels, Angeles Investors, Bonfire Ventures and Red Tail Venture Capital.</p>
<p>CEO Meagan Kinmonth Bowman founded the Arkansas-based company in 2019 after working at Hallmark, where she was tasked with the digital transformation of the company.</p>
<p>“This was not a consequence of them not being good marketers or connected to mom, but they didn’t have the technology to connect their back end with retailers like Amazon, Walmart or Hobby Lobby,” she told TechCrunch. “There are so many smart people building products to connect with consumers. The challenge is the big guys are doing things the same way and not thinking like the 13-year-olds on social media that are actually winning the space.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mpMozU732l"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/22/end-to-end-operators-are-the-next-generation-of-consumer-business/">End-to-end operators are the next generation of consumer business</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;End-to-end operators are the next generation of consumer business&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/22/end-to-end-operators-are-the-next-generation-of-consumer-business/embed/#?secret=mpMozU732l" data-secret="mpMozU732l" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Kinmonth Bowman and her team recognized that there was a missing middle layer connecting the world of dotcom with brick and mortar. If the middle layer could be applied to the enterprise resource plans and integrate public and private data feeds, a company could be just as profitable online as it could be in traditional retail, she said.</p>
<p>Stonehenge’s answer to that is STOPWATCH, which takes in over 100 million rows of data per workspace per day, analyzes the data points, adds real-time alerts and provides the right data to the right people at the right time.</p>
<p>Dan Rossignol, a B2B SaaS investor, said the CPG world is also about consumerizing our life, and the global pandemic showed that even at home, people could have a productive day and business. Rossignol likes to invest in underestimated founders and saw in Stonehenge a company that is getting CPGs out from underneath antiquated technologies.</p>
<p>“What Meagan and her team are doing is really interesting,” he added. “At this stage, it is all about the people, and the ability to bet on doing something larger.”</p>
<p>Kinmonth Bowman said she had the opportunity to base the company in Silicon Valley, but chose Bentonville, Arkansas instead to be closer to the more than 1,000 CPG companies based there that she felt were the prime customer base for STOPWATCH.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The platform was originally created as a subsidiary of a consulting company, but in 2018, one of their clients told them they just wanted the software rather than also paying for the consulting piece. The business was split, and Stonehenge went underground for eight months to make a software product specifically for the client.</p>
<p>Kinmonth Bowman admits the technology itself is not that sexy — it is using exact transfer loads to extract data from hundreds of systems into a “lake house,” and then siloing it by retailer and other factors and then presenting the data in different ways. For example, the CEO will want different metrics than product teams.</p>
<p>Over the past year, the company has doubled its revenue and also doubled the amount of contracts. It already counts multiple Fortune 100 companies and emerging brands as some of its early users and plans to use the new funding to hire a sales team and go after some strategic relationships.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1eTusqpaUm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/23/checkout-is-the-key-to-frictionless-b2b-e-commerce/">Checkout is the key to frictionless B2B e-commerce</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Checkout is the key to frictionless B2B e-commerce&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/23/checkout-is-the-key-to-frictionless-b2b-e-commerce/embed/#?secret=1eTusqpaUm" data-secret="1eTusqpaUm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Stonehenge is also working on putting together a diverse workforce that mimics the users of the software, Kinmonth Bowman said. One of the challenges has been to get unique talent to move to Arkansas, but she said it is one she is eager to take on.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Brett Brohl, managing partner at Bread and Butter Ventures, said the Stonehenge team “is just crazy enough, smart and driven” to build something great.</p>
<p>“All of the biggest companies have been around for a long time, but not a lot of large organizations have done a good job digitizing their businesses,” he said. “Even pre-COVID, they were building fill-in-the-blank digital transformations, but COVID accelerated technology and hit a lot of companies in the face. That was made more obvious to end consumers, which puts more pressure on companies to understand the need, which is good for STOPWATCH. It went from paper to Excel spreadsheets to the next cloud modification. The time is right for the next leap and how to use data.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/stonehenge-technology-labs-bags-2m-gives-cpg-companies-one-touch-access-to-metrics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194737</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Accounting platform Synder raises $2M to automate e-commerce bookkeeping</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/accounting-platform-synder-raises-2m-to-automate-e-commerce-bookkeeping/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/accounting-platform-synder-raises-2m-to-automate-e-commerce-bookkeeping/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 13:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Igor Shoifot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ilya Kisel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Astreiko]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[omnichannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Synder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TMT Investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194784</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The company bills itself as an easy accounting platform for e-commerce businesses.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As <a href="https://synder.com/">Synder</a>’s two co-founders Michael Astreiko and Ilya Kisel wrap up their time at Y Combinator, they also announced their seed round of $2 million from TMT Investments.</p>
<p>Though the round was acquired before going into the accelerator program, the Belarus-based pair wanted to wait to publicly share the milestone. As they focus their sights on their next journey of growth and expansion, the new funding will go toward attracting more clients, visibility and sales.</p>
<p>The company bills itself as an easy accounting platform for e-commerce businesses. It was originally founded as CloudBusiness in 2016 and developed accounting automation and management of business finances for small and mid-size businesses.</p>
<p>Astreiko and Kisel started Synder, in 2018 and a year later focused on the company full-time to develop an easy way for commerce companies to shift to omnichannel sales, something Astreiko told TechCrunch can be “a huge pain” due to the complexity of different payment systems and high fees.</p>
<p>“There are a lot of solutions on the market, but you still have to have special knowledge to operate within accounting or commerce,” Kisel said. “For us, the simplicity means that it is worth it if you can have access in several clicks to consolidated inventory, profits and liabilities. Small businesses sometimes are not sharing this information due to competition, but if something is working and easy, they will definitely share it.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Synder does the heavy lifting for companies by connecting sales channels like Amazon, Shopify, eBay and Etsy into one platform that users can manage with one-click operations. It also created a way to help the accounting stream so that all of the different payment methods can still be used, Kisel said.</p>
<p>The company is already working with 4,000 clients, and will now be fast-tracking their expansion, but will need the right people on board to help the company grow, Astreiko said.</p>
<p>Igor Shoifot, a partner at TMT Investments, said he will join Synder’s board after the company graduates from YC. He likes the simplicity of what the company is doing.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Vsi66BMbxH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/embedded-procurement-will-make-every-company-its-own-marketplace/">Embedded procurement will make every company its own marketplace</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Embedded procurement will make every company its own marketplace&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/embedded-procurement-will-make-every-company-its-own-marketplace/embed/#?secret=Vsi66BMbxH" data-secret="Vsi66BMbxH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“Often the best solutions are economical, succinct and elegant — you can be onboarded in 10 minutes,” he added. “There is really nobody that really provides a similar solution that was that easy or didn’t require downloading or installing something. I also like their focus on growth, the fact they have no burn and they are making money.”</p>
<p>Synder’s business model is a subscription SaaS model that starts off as a free trial, and users can purchase additional services inside the platform to fit small and large companies.</p>
<p>Its more than 15 employees are spread around Europe, and the company just started hiring in the areas of marketing and sales in the U.S.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/accounting-platform-synder-raises-2m-to-automate-e-commerce-bookkeeping/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194784</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>YC grad Buoyant wants to solve middle-mile delivery with cargo airships</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/yc-grad-buoyant-wants-to-solve-middle-mile-delivery-with-cargo-airships/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/yc-grad-buoyant-wants-to-solve-middle-mile-delivery-with-cargo-airships/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 12:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buoyant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sergey Brin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transportation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Buoyant says its hybrid design solves the notoriously difficult problem of dropping off cargo – difficult because as airships offload weight, they risk shooting back up into the air.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A number of companies have emerged in recent years aiming to resurrect the airship, an early technology that was abandoned in favor of airplanes and helicopters.</p>
<p>Flying Whales in France, Hybrid Air Vehicles in the U.K., Lockheed Martin and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/sergey-brins-airship-will-use-worlds-biggest-mobile-hydrogen-fuel-cell/">billionaire Sergey Brin</a> all have airship projects in development, particularly focused on carrying cargo. None have yet started servicing customers.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.buoyant.aero/">Buoyant</a> wants to be the first.</p>
<p>The startup graduated from Y Combinator this year with the goal of building small unmanned airships to move middle-mile cargo. Think depot-to-depot delivery, rather than depot-to-home. The two founders, Ben Claman and Joe Figura, say they can cut the cost of delivery in half, relative to flights performed by small planes or helicopters. And they say they’ll succeed where others have stalled by staying small &#8212; instead of building massive, multi-hundred-foot airships that need a lot of capital to build and a lot of gas to lift, Buoyant’s final vehicle will only be around 60 feet long.</p>
<p>Claman and Figura are two MIT hardware engineers who cut their teeth building spacecraft and antennas. Both had worked on projects with previous employers that involved providing low-cost connectivity to remote places, like Alaska (Claman also grew up there).</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2194696" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2194696" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2194696" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSCF1093.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="769" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSCF1093.jpg 5328w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSCF1093.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSCF1093.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSCF1093.jpg?resize=768,577 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSCF1093.jpg?resize=680,511 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSCF1093.jpg?resize=1536,1153 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSCF1093.jpg?resize=2048,1538 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSCF1093.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2194696" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Buoyant. Buoyant founders Joe Figura and Ben Claman.</p></div></p>
<p>“What [Joe and I] were talking about when we were working at these companies was how hard it is to get actual goods to these places, not just the internet,” Claman said. “In these places, people are shopping online, they’re getting things sent to them. They sometimes have to wait weeks or months for them to arrive.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Claman added when the company started YC, they had imagined building an airship that’s closer to their existing prototype &#8212; a small craft capable of doing last-mile deliveries for Amazon, for example.</p>
<p>“We&#8217;ve talked to a bunch of companies, and it seemed like from talking to them, that rural middle-mile is a much bigger problem than rural last-mile. Let’s say you have 5,000 people living in a community, you can basically subcontract the postal service to one of those people to do the last-mile delivery. … But getting the parcels from your main hub to that place is actually really challenging and really, really expensive.”</p>
<p>To solve that problem, Buoyant developed a “hybrid” battery electric airship, meaning that it generates around 70% of its lift using lighter-than-air gas &#8212; in this case, helium. The remaining 30% of the lift comes from its tilt-rotor architecture. This hybrid design is what Buoyant says solves the notoriously difficult problem of dropping off cargo – difficult because as airships offload weight, they risk shooting back up into the air. The tilt-rotor allows the airship to operate closer to a helicopter during takeoff and landing.</p>
<p><iframe title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VEYOfVcwRhk" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>But where helicopters need to be capable of lifting their weight &#8212; anywhere from 1,500 to 10,000 pounds of carbon fiber and stainless steel &#8212; Buoyant’s airship will only need to lift the weight of the payload itself and its airframe. Not only do Buoyant&#8217;s founders say this saves on capital costs, but they&#8217;re developing the ship to eventually run autonomously, so the company won’t have to use pilots.</p>
<p>Buoyant has built and flown four prototype airships. The most recent sub-scale ship that went to air is 20 feet long, with airspeeds of up to 35 miles per hour and a payload capacity of 10 pounds, but the ultimate aim is to build an airship that’s capable of delivering up to 650 pounds of cargo at a cruise speed of around 60 miles per hour.</p>
<p>The airship has been operating under a Part 107 license. Before the company can start serving customers, it will need to achieve two certifications: a type certification verifying the airworthiness of the craft and operator certifications for the groups flying them. “Both require a lot of flight hours, which will be our main development activity,” Figura said on <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=28278515">HackerNews</a>.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, the company is planning to continue iterating its flight control system and doing a field demo with the sub-scale prototype in the coming months. Buoyant wants to build a full-scale version next year, which Claman said they will likely manufacture in-house.</p>
<p>These next few steps will be crucial for Buoyant to turn letters of intent worth $5 million that it has signed with several potential customers —  including from an Alaskan regional air carrier — into official contracts.</p>
<p>Buoyant also has two pilot programs in the pipeline: one with the sub-scale prototype this fall, and the second with the full-scale ship in a year&#8217;s time, both with logistics/parcel delivery companies.</p>
<p>&#8220;People were building blimps before computers, people were building blimps before they really understood aerodynamics, so we have some advantage there on just the length of time that people have been building airships,&#8221; Claman added. &#8220;There&#8217;s a lot of data out there. It&#8217;s not like airship development has stopped. People have been developing airships continuously, basically, over 100 years.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/yc-grad-buoyant-wants-to-solve-middle-mile-delivery-with-cargo-airships/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194688</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Andreessen Horowitz just rolled out a $400 million fund that&#8217;s expressly for seed deals</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/andreessen-horowitz-just-rolled-out-a-400-million-fund-thats-expressly-for-seed-deals/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/andreessen-horowitz-just-rolled-out-a-400-million-fund-thats-expressly-for-seed-deals/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 12:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[a16z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[martin casado]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seed Investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seed-stage fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194652</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz is begun to announce new funds almost as routinely as some startups have begun announcing follow-on rounds. After announcing a third biotech fund in February 2020 that&#8217;s currently investing $750 million; a pair of new funds totaling $4.5 billion last November; and, most recently, a new $2.2 billion crypto-focused fund, the firm is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://a16z.com/">Andreessen Horowitz</a> is begun to announce new funds almost as routinely as some startups have begun announcing follow-on rounds. After announcing a third biotech fund in February 2020 that&#8217;s currently investing <a href="https://a16z.com/2020/02/04/bio-fund-iii-announcement/">$750 million</a>; a pair of new funds totaling <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/a16z-is-now-managing-16-5-billion-after-announcing-two-new-funds/">$4.5 billion</a> last November; and, most recently, a new <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/andreessen-horowitz-triples-down-on-blockchain-startups-with-massive-2-2-billion-crypto-fund-iii/">$2.2 billion</a> crypto-focused fund, the firm is rolling out a brand new fund: a $400 million vehicle that is focused expressly on backing seed-stage companies.</p>
<p>In the broader historical context of the firm, it&#8217;s an interesting development. Many years ago, Andreessen Horowitz backed away from making seed stage deals to avoid the appearance of conflicts of interest &#8212; even while the firm didn&#8217;t have a conflict policy around nascent deals. As Marc Andreessen <a href="http://www.strictlyvc.com/2013/10/20/andreessen-horowitz-backs-seed-investing/">explained it back in 2013</a>, there is often too much uncertainty at the earliest stages of company formation, and though it conveyed this thinking to founders, they didn&#8217;t always listen, and bets that evolved to be similar made them feel bad and caused problems.</p>
<p>Of course, things changed over time, competition is competition, and before long, the firm was again writing checks to very young startups. In fact, today, not only have seed-stage investments again become very much part of the program, but that since the beginning of 2020, about half the firm&#8217;s investments have been in seed companies, according to a16z Indeed, General Partner Martin Casado said yesterday that the new fund is largely about optimizing its processes around seed deals, and ensuring investors are rewarded properly for the associated risk. Here&#8217;s some of that conversation, edited lightly for length:</p>
<p><strong>TC: You say this seed fund doesn&#8217;t change anything about your investment strategy, that it&#8217;s more about putting a formal structure around these deals. So we won&#8217;t necessarily see even more seed-stage deals out of Andreessen Horowitz?</strong></p>
<p>MC: Well what&#8217;s interesting is the entire industry has picked up the pace dramatically in the last three years. I think the industry has doubled the number of seed funds, and we&#8217;ve kept pace with the industry. The seed investments from Andreessen Horowitz have gone up dramatically in the last three years in response to the industry. That we have a separate seed fund doesn&#8217;t mean we&#8217;re going to pick up the pace [further still].</p>
<p><strong>TC: How might formalizing this new fund impact your relationship with other seed stage firms?</strong></p>
<p>MC: We work closely with seed funds and we plan to continue to do so. I do think the environment has become more and more competitive at the seed stage, and if you actually look at some seed [stage startups] that I have personally been involved, [they&#8217;ve received] term sheets from hedge funds, growth funds &#8212; all the way down to angel investors. Everybody is in the mix at the seed stage. I think this is an evolution of the industry rather than kind of a key shift.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>TC: Who will be making these seed investments at a16z? Is there a team that will be primarily managing the fund?</strong></p>
<p>MC: We do not have seed specific investors [investing this new capital]. If we do Series A and Series B deals, it&#8217;s the same set of investors.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Andreessen Horowitz has used scouts in the past. Is that true currently and if, so, what percentage of your seed-stage deals come from them?</strong></p>
<p>MC: Yes, we use scouts, but they are responsible for zero percent of our seed-stage deals. That&#8217;s an independent function where they can put small dollars in deals of their choosing, but those, to us, aren&#8217;t seed [deals]. Seeds to us are $1 million to $4 million led by an investor at the firm where we get real ownership and have real involvement.</p>
<p><strong>TC: So these scouts are really just founders and operators who Andreessen Horowitz wants in its ecosystem?</strong></p>
<p>MC: The scouts serves two functions. We get to develop a relationship with key people and key influencers, whether they&#8217;re entrepreneurs are they&#8217;re going to be entrepreneurs. It also gives us access to interesting deal flow to see what activity is happening now and kind of draft off that judgment.</p>
<p><strong>TC: You mention $1 million to $4 million checks.  What constitutes a seed investment, in a16z&#8217;s view?</strong></p>
<p>MC: Typically, for us, let&#8217;s say it&#8217;s $6 million &#8212; these aren&#8217;t hard and fast rules &#8212; and we typically don&#8217;t take board seats.</p>
<p><strong>TC: And you look to own how much with that first check?</strong></p>
<p>MC: We don&#8217;t have target ownership, really. It all depends  on the market dynamics; we tend to respond to the market.</p>
<p><strong>TC: You mention that it&#8217;s gotten very competitive, seed-stage investing. Do you prefer to go it alone or work with a syndicate or investors?</strong></p>
<p>MC: Personally, I love working with other seed funds. We absolutely do not have any sort of internal rules or biases one way or the other on this. I think independent GPs have independent views on this. For myself, I love it because there are great seed funds out there that I love splitting deals with or sharing deals with that we then work on together.</p>
<p><strong>TC: And you want to see what, exactly? How early is too early for the firm to invest?</strong></p>
<p>M: If we know the space very very well, meaning we&#8217;ve done the work in the space and we have a deal partner like myself [who is] particularly expert in a space, it can be just a person and an idea, because we believe that we understand the market. We&#8217;ve invested in solo  founders before their company existed.</p>
<p>If we don&#8217;t understand the space very well, we&#8217;d like to see kind of some maturity in the company, maybe some early customer traction, maybe some early product work, maybe an early demo, because that way we&#8217;ll have a better sense of the market. So I would say the maturity of the actual company we invest in is inversely correlated with our knowledge.</p>
<p><strong>TC: What the decision-making process look like? I&#8217;m guessing it&#8217;s different when you&#8217;re writing a $6 million check versus a check that&#8217;s many times bigger than that.</strong></p>
<p>MC: Yeah, the amount of work and scrutiny that we do for seed tends to be less than for a Series A. The number of people involved is less. And because we&#8217;re not taking a board seat, the firm&#8217;s [time] commitment is a bit less. So it just tends to be a lighter-weight process. Typically, we have at least two GPs take a look [whereas] if we&#8217;re doing an A and above, you want to kind of everybody in the vertical to be involved, and then, for the larger checks, everybody in the fund [is involved].</p>
<p><strong>TC: What are some of the firm&#8217;s most successful seed investments?</strong></p>
<p>MC: We&#8217;ve had some great ones. Slack was first money. Databricks was first money. I believe we had a seed check in Coinbase.</p>
<p><em>Pictured above: Casado at a TechCrunch Disrupt event in 2019.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/andreessen-horowitz-just-rolled-out-a-400-million-fund-thats-expressly-for-seed-deals/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194652</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zeal banks $13M to offer employers a ‘build your own’ payroll product infrastructure</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/zeal-banks-13m-to-offer-employers-a-build-your-own-payroll-product-infrastructure/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/zeal-banks-13m-to-offer-employers-a-build-your-own-payroll-product-infrastructure/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 12:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commerce ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internal Revenue Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kirti Shenoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Natalie Sandman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pranab Krishnan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spark Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zeal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194843</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Enterprises use Zeal to pay large volumes of workers and keep payment data on their own native systems.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Embedded fintech company <a href="https://www.zeal.com/">Zeal</a> secured $13 million in Series A funding to continue developing its platform for building individualized payroll products.</p>
<p>Spark Capital led the Series A, with participation from Commerce Ventures and a group of individual investors, including Marqeta CEO Jason Gardner and CRO Omri Dahan, Robinhood founder Vlad Tenev, UltimateSoftware executives Mitch Dauerman and Bob Manne and Namely founder Matt Straz. The latest round now gives the company $14.6 million in total funding, which includes a $1.6 million seed round in 2020, CEO Kirti Shenoy told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The Bay Area company’s origin was as Puzzl, a payment processing startup for the gig economy, founded in 2018 by Shenoy and CTO Pranab Krishnan. It was part of Y Combinator’s 2019 cohort. The pair had to pivot the company after needing to move some of its thousands of 1099 contractors to W2 employee status.</p>
<p>They went looking for payroll processors that could handle high volumes of payroll automatically, like ADP or Paycor, but found they didn’t match some of the capabilities Shenoy and Krishnan wanted, including to pay workers daily and customize earning components.</p>
<p>To ensure other companies didn’t run into the same problem, they decided to build a payroll API that enables their customers to build their own payroll products, even being able to pay their workers everyday. Traditionally, companies would layer together antiquated third-party payroll tools and spend millions of dollars on consulting fees. Zeal’s API tool modernizes the payroll process and takes on the payroll liability while managing the back-end payment logistics, Shenoy said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Currently, enterprises use Zeal to pay large volumes of workers and keep payment data on their own native systems, while software platforms that sell business-to-business services use Zeal to build their own payroll product to sell to their customers.</p>
<p>“Our mission is to touch every American paycheck with our tax and payment technology, ensuring that American employees are paid correctly and efficiently,” Krishnan said.</p>
<p>And that is a complex goal: there are 200 million American employees, <a href="https://www.bls.gov/cew/publications/employment-and-wages-annual-averages/current/home.htm">over $8.8 trillion of payroll is processed annually</a> in the U.S. and the country’s 11,000 tax jurisdictions produce over 25,000 income tax code changes a year.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Shenoy cited IRS data that showed more than 40% of small and medium businesses pay at least one payroll penalty per year. That was one of the drivers for Zeal’s latest product, the <a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/abacus-3">Abacus</a> gross-to-net calculator, which payroll companies can use to ensure they are compliant in paying their income taxes.</p>
<p>The co-founders intend to use the new funding to build out their team and strengthen compliance measures to ensure its track record with enterprises.</p>
<p>“We are starting to win more enterprise deals and moving millions of dollars each day,” Shenoy said. “This has been a legacy space for so long, so companies want to work with a provider to move fast.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VGitlAgZzN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/embedded-procurement-will-make-every-company-its-own-marketplace/">Embedded procurement will make every company its own marketplace</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Embedded procurement will make every company its own marketplace&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/embedded-procurement-will-make-every-company-its-own-marketplace/embed/#?secret=VGitlAgZzN" data-secret="VGitlAgZzN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Shenoy predicts that more companies will shift to hyper-customized experiences in the next five to 10 years. Whereas the default was a company like ADP, companies will want to control their own data and build products so their customers can do everything payroll-related from one platform.</p>
<p>As part of the investment, Spark Capital’s partner Natalie Sandman has joined Zeal’s board of directors. The firm previously invested in other embedded fintech companies like Affirm and Marqeta, and she thinks there are new experiences in the sector that APIs can unlock.</p>
<p>Sandman felt the payroll-building pain points herself when she worked at Zenefits. At the time, the company was trying to do the same thing, but there were no APIs to connect with. There were all of these spreadsheets to transfer data, but one wrong deduction would trickle down and cause a tax penalty.</p>
<p>Shenoy and Krishnan are both “customer-obsessed,” she said, and are balancing speed with thoughtfulness when it comes to understanding how their customers want to build payroll products.</p>
<p>She is seeing a macro shift to audience-driven human resources where bringing new employees online will mean embedding them into products that will be more valuable versus the traditional spreadsheet.</p>
<p>“To me, it is a no-brainer that APIs provide flexibility in the way wages and deductions need to be made,” Sandman said. “You can lose trust in your employer. Payroll is at the deepest trust point and where you want transparency and a robust solution to solve that need.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="65FN55RZK4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/05/embedded-finance-might-represent-fintechs-future/">Embedded finance might represent fintech&#8217;s future</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Embedded finance might represent fintech&#8217;s future&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/05/embedded-finance-might-represent-fintechs-future/embed/#?secret=65FN55RZK4" data-secret="65FN55RZK4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/zeal-banks-13m-to-offer-employers-a-build-your-own-payroll-product-infrastructure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194843</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Zealand-based Imagr thinks camera-based AI is the future of shopping trolleys</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/new-zealand-based-imagr-thinks-camera-based-ai-is-the-future-of-shopping-trolleys/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/new-zealand-based-imagr-thinks-camera-based-ai-is-the-future-of-shopping-trolleys/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 12:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazon go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imagr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Standard Cognition]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189052</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When it comes to contactless, automated supermarket shopping, Imagr is backing a vision-based approach. But unlike Amazon Go stores, which use cameras and sensors to monitor the shopper as they walk in and out without scanning or paying at checkout, this New Zealand-based company thinks the only images that should be captured and analyzed are [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to contactless, automated supermarket shopping, <a href="https://www.imagr.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Imagr</a> is backing a vision-based approach. But unlike Amazon Go stores, which use cameras and sensors to monitor the shopper as they walk in and out without scanning or paying at checkout, this New Zealand-based company thinks the only images that should be captured and analyzed are those of products going into a shopping cart.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The early-stage startup has invented tech that attaches to the trolley and uses cameras to detect and label products, adding them to a virtual cart where shoppers can checkout without ever interacting with a human or waiting in a line. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The contactless shopping space has been growing slowly for years, but more recently it has seen a boost in the pandemic era, where the less we share air with another human, the better. The value of transactions processed by frictionless checkout technology is estimated to reach $387 billion by 2025, </span><a href="https://www.juniperresearch.com/press/smart-checkout-technologies-to-process-$387-bn"><span style="font-weight: 400;">according to a 2020 study from Juniper Research</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><i></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“With Covid, I think what you probably saw was a huge rush on supermarkets that really exposed a number of things retailers weren&#8217;t prepared for,” Will Chomley, CEO and co-founder, told TechCrunch. “It also really highlighted the fact that the end user wanted a solution that was completely frictionless, and it demonstrated that their infrastructure was not capable of handling that sort of thing. But it also showed that as staff started to refuse to turn up to work because they didn&#8217;t want to catch it, retailers needed solutions to be able to run these stores on less staff.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Amazon Go’s automated convenience stores are expanding internationally, which Chomley says scares retailers who fear competition from the tech giant. At the same time, countries around the world are looking at going cashless, making this a ripe moment to focus on the frictionless checkout space. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Imagr, which recently had a pop-up shop in London to demonstrate its tech, is currently raising its Series A after it raised $9.5 million in seed funding at the end of November 2019 in a round led by Toshiba Tec. Chomley says Imagr has raised a total of $12.5 million to date, and as it raises its next round, is in the market for strategic partners rather than just VC money. The company says the tech is there, it just needs to scale. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup’s original smart shopping carts, complete with a halo on top that houses cameras and lights to detect products going in and out of the cart, can be seen in Japan’s 150 H2O Retailing stores, and the company says it has one contract due to go live this year in the U.K., as well as another two in the works and some other plans in Europe that can’t yet be confirmed publicly. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The haloed version of the shopping cart is not, however, the end product for Imagr. The plan is to roll out a more modular version by Q4, where instead of an entire cart, you get three pieces of hardware that attach to a standard cart. Each module will have its own set of lights and cameras, as well as a microprocessor where data is analyzed then sent up into the cloud and back to the shopper’s app and virtual cart with less than one second latency. Chloe Lamb, brand and communications lead, says Imagr has built a prototype that&#8217;s currently for sale. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lamb also said the modular method just makes more sense when scaling. <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/01/29/smart-shopping-carts-pandemic-innovations/">Smart carts can cost retailers between $5,000 and $10,000</a> per unit and require a lot of maintenance compared to simple shopping carts, which tend to cost retailers under $100 and will get beat up for years before being replaced. <a href="https://chainstoreage.com/will-other-grocers-follow-amazon-go">Amazon&#8217;s walk out tech is expected to cost retailers upwards of $1 million</a> for installation and hardware, and that doesn&#8217;t include maintenance over time. Currently, the full system that it&#8217;s piloting is about $75,000 and includes 10 carts, an imaging station, a server station to run the system, full integration into a customer-facing store and Imagr support over the duration of the pilot. Imagr didn&#8217;t share how much its current model of trolleys cost versus its modular system, but says it&#8217;ll be a cheaper endeavor. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="http://shopic.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shopic</a>, an Israeli smart trolley company, also has a smaller piece of hardware that attaches to a cart, but the difference is it relies on a barcode scanner rather than computer vision.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“They have the hardware, but we have the software,” said Lamb. “Our vision/AI is better. Like, we&#8217;ve cracked the hardest part of it and it&#8217;s the AI, and for us it&#8217;s been figuring out how we put that in a smaller vessel.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shopic and Amazon aren&#8217;t the only other hopefuls in this space. <a href="https://standard.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Standard Cognition</a> has copied Amazon&#8217;s style of walkout tech to distribute to stores. Earlier this year, the San Francisco-based company, which is now valued at $1 billion, <a href="https://standard.ai/blog/standard-raises-150-m-in-its-series-c-becomes-worlds-first-autonomous-checkout-unicorn/">raised $150 million in a Series C</a> and announced a partnership with Circle K, the convenience store chain owned by Alimentation Couch-Tard Inc.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aside from being kind of creepy – the all-seeing cameras may be trained on what you are buying but also are scanning the store, and you, at large – Lamb says the walkout tech that Standard is offering is incredibly expensive and not at all scalable in the short term. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“You couldn&#8217;t overhead that,” said Lamb. “The maintenance alone, having to have AI engineers on site, plus the storage capacity needed for all the data you collect. The server room you would need would be intense.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Running the Imagr system in one store uses the same amount of data as streaming HD Netflix for a day, the company said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Shopping carts just made sense to me because everyone already used carts or baskets, they were what retailers were comfortable buying and what users were comfortable using,” said Chomley. “It didn&#8217;t require a huge overhaul of the systems. It’s the method of least disruption, faster payback period, better customer experience and no privacy concerns.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And while it’s within the realm of possibility that the approach of above-head tech gets cheaper over time, it’s not as quick or clear of a path to market, claimed Chomley. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Amazon proved the market; it proved that the end user wants something frictionless, and I think that’s really healthy for our business,” said Chomley. “But what Amazon did is they built a supermarket for the technology, whereas we have built technology for a supermarket. And that’s where retailers will say we can’t process 1.6 terabytes of information every second. We need something that fits into our store and our operations.”</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2189056" style="width: 599px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2189056" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2189056" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_5736.jpeg?w=300" alt="" width="589" height="444" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_5736.jpeg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_5736.jpeg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_5736.jpeg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 589px) 100vw, 589px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2189056" class="wp-caption-text">As items go into Imagr&#8217;s shopping cart, they appear in the app&#8217;s virtual cart.</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lamb says many retailers look at Imagr as an elevation from the scan-and-shop because it’s not too far off in terms of pricing, but the difference is retailers get to see what’s in the cart. It&#8217;s a lot harder to shoplift by pretending to scan an item when the cart is watching and making a record of what goes in and out.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Imagr offers a white label solution for retailers that they can own, operate and scale themselves. This means the retailer would own all the hardware, software and the white labeled app. Imagr has a shared licensing agreement for data with retailers because it needs to get smarter and keep training its models. Lamb said that Imagr hopes to offer inventory analytics in the future to help retailers avoid inventory distortion. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our intention would be to essentially provide them the ability to track everything that comes in and out,” said Lamb. “In a perfect world, like, I don&#8217;t know all the coke sells out, and it pings one of the retail workers in the store and she’s got to restock, shelf 7A. That’s what we’re working towards. We don&#8217;t have a hard solution for it but there’s definitely demand for that.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/new-zealand-based-imagr-thinks-camera-based-ai-is-the-future-of-shopping-trolleys/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189052</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Atlassian is bringing new insights to its Jira Software Cloud</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/atlassian-is-bringing-news-insights-to-its-jira-software-cloud/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/atlassian-is-bringing-news-insights-to-its-jira-software-cloud/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Michael Kerner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agile software development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlassian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JIRA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194759</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DevOps teams are generally trying to constantly improve themselves, so they can deliver software more quickly and reliably, but often they lack the insights needed to actually make that progress. Atlassian is now offering users of its Jira Software Cloud platform a series of new capabilities that provide data-driven insights into the development process. Jira [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">DevOps teams are generally trying to constantly improve themselves, so they can deliver software more quickly and reliably, but often they lack the insights needed to actually make that progress.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/atlassian/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Atlassian</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is now offering users of its</span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/18/atlassian-launches-the-new-jira-software-cloud/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Jira Software Cloud platform</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a series of new capabilities that provide data-driven insights into the development process. Jira is a popular issue and project tracking technology and has included features that help developers and their teams to understand where they are in their workflow. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The new insights go a step beyond what Jira has traditionally provided to its users, with specific insights into different aspects of an agile software development approach. The goal with the new insights is to help organizations better understand what they&#8217;re doing right and where development teams can improve, which ultimately results in improved overall efficiency.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Data is everywhere, but at the same time the insights and the understanding of the actions that you can take are kind of nowhere,&#8221; Megan Cook, head of product for Jira Software told TechCrunch. &#8220;It&#8217;s hard to work smarter in that sense and that&#8217;s the big problem that we&#8217;re really looking at tackling.&#8221; </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cook explained that development teams need access to metrics on their own progress, so they can make smarter data-driven decisions based on what&#8217;s happening in real time. She noted that one of the big shifts that Atlassian is now doing with Jira Cloud is bringing data from all the different development tracking tools together into one place where those teams can make decisions.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nxd0zdsDBd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/a-pandemic-and-recession-wont-stop-atlassians-saas-push/">A pandemic and recession won&#8217;t stop Atlassian&#8217;s SaaS push</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A pandemic and recession won&#8217;t stop Atlassian&#8217;s SaaS push&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/a-pandemic-and-recession-wont-stop-atlassians-saas-push/embed/#?secret=nxd0zdsDBd" data-secret="nxd0zdsDBd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One example of the insights that Jira Cloud now provides to users is related to sprint commitments. In the agile software development approach, software is developed in what are known as &#8220;sprints&#8221; as developers race to complete a certain task. With the sprint commitment insight capability, the idea is to help teams understand what amount of work they can handle, based on past performance. The business goal is to help better understand if a team is over- or under-committing to a given sprint.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another example is providing an issue type breakdown. Cook explained that the way each team can categorize issues can be very personalized. The categories can include different types of projects, such as whether a project is dealing with fixing bugs and technical debt, or if it&#8217;s an innovation or growth product, or just an incremental feature update. With the issue type breakdown insight there is a visualization to help teams better understand what types of issues and projects they are working on in a more intuitive approach than before. Cook explained that users could have identified the different issues before via a search functionality, but she emphasized the new insights approach is far easier.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2194767" style="width: 3234px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Sprint-Commitment-issue-type-breakdown.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2194767" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2194767 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Sprint-Commitment-issue-type-breakdown.png" alt="Atlassian Jira Software Cloud issue type breakdown" width="3224" height="1896" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Sprint-Commitment-issue-type-breakdown.png 3224w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Sprint-Commitment-issue-type-breakdown.png?resize=150,88 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Sprint-Commitment-issue-type-breakdown.png?resize=300,176 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Sprint-Commitment-issue-type-breakdown.png?resize=768,452 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Sprint-Commitment-issue-type-breakdown.png?resize=680,400 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Sprint-Commitment-issue-type-breakdown.png?resize=1536,903 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Sprint-Commitment-issue-type-breakdown.png?resize=2048,1204 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Sprint-Commitment-issue-type-breakdown.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 3224px) 100vw, 3224px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2194767" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Atlassian</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the coming weeks, Cook said that the company will be adding a few additional insights, including the sprint burndown insight. In the agile software development approach, the burndown is about figuring out what&#8217;s left to finish in a sprint. The sprint burndown insight will provide a visual indicator of how much work is left to be done as well as how likely it is that the work will be completed within an allocated amount of time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Atlassian&#8217;s approach to enabling developer teams to work more efficiently is one of the primary values that the company has been building for years, and it has resulted in strong growth overall. Atlassian</span><a href="https://s2.q4cdn.com/141359120/files/doc_financials/2021/q4/TEAM-Q4-2021-Earnings-Release.pdf"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">reported</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">fourth-quarter fiscal 2021 revenue of $560 million, up 30% year-over-year gain on the strength of its developer collaboration and management tools.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/atlassian-is-bringing-news-insights-to-its-jira-software-cloud/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194759</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Waymo will stop selling its self-driving LiDAR sensors to other companies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/waymo-will-stop-selling-its-self-driving-lidar-sensors-to-other-companies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/waymo-will-stop-selling-its-self-driving-lidar-sensors-to-other-companies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 11:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous trucking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lidar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194960</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just months after a CEO shakeup, Waymo is officially halting sales of its custom sensors to third parties. Waymo added that it's now focusing on deploying its Waymo Driver tech.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Saqib Shah</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Saqib Shah is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/teslas-redesigned-iphone-app-features-two-new-home-screen-widgets/">Tesla&#8217;s redesigned iPhone app features two new home screen widgets</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/palantir-glitch-allegedly-granted-some-fbi-staff-unauthorized-access-to-a-crypto-hackers-data/">Palantir glitch allegedly granted some FBI staff unauthorized access to a crypto hacker&#8217;s data</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><div class="article-text">
<p id="speakable-summary">Just months after a CEO shakeup, Waymo is officially halting sales of its custom sensors to third parties. The move sees the Alphabet-owned self-driving company unwinding a business operation just two years into its lifespan. Waymo confirmed the decision to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/alphabets-waymo-stop-selling-lidar-self-driving-car-sensors-sources-2021-08-27/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1"><em>Reuters</em></a>, adding that it&#8217;s now focusing on deploying its Waymo Driver tech across its Waymo One ride-hailing and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-01-23-waymo-autonomous-truck-tests-texas-new-mexico.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1">Waymo Via</a> trucking divisions.</p>
<p>The decision comes in the wake of long-term <a href="https://www.engadget.com/waymo-ceo-john-krafcik-steps-down-190610549.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="22" data-v9y="1">CEO John Krafcik&#8217;s departure</a>, who was replaced at the helm by Waymo execs Tekedra Mawakana and Dmitri Dolgov. Some <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/02/waymo-ceo-john-krafcik-steps-aside-as-co-ceos-take-over.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="23" data-v9y="1">suggested</a> that Krafcik&#8217;s deliberate approach was hindering the company&#8217;s push toward commercialization. Earlier this month, Waymo hit a milestone of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/waymo-autonomous-vehicles-update-san-francisco-193934150.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="24" data-v9y="1">20 billion miles</a> driven in simulations, with 20 million on public roads. Just days ago, it brought its robotaxis to vetted riders in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/waymo-san-francisco-trusted-tester-170602490.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="25" data-v9y="1">San Francisco</a>.</p>
<div id="max-player-injector" class="vmmi-si" data-maxi="0">
<div class="vdb_player">
<div><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Waymo </span><a style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-03-06-waymo-selling-laser-bear-honeycomb-lidar-sensor.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="26" data-v9y="1">began selling</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> LiDARs — the tech that measures distance with pulses of laser light — to companies barring its autonomous vehicle rivals in 2019. It initially planned to sell its short-range sensor (known as Laser Bear Honeycomb) to businesses in the robotics, security and agricultural technology sectors. A</span><a style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://waymo.com/intl/es_ALL/lidar/?gh_src=2485f9a42us" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="27" data-v9y="1"> form</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> on its website also lists drones, mapping and entertainment as applicable industries.</span></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Waymo&#8217;s fifth-generation Driver technology uses an array of sensors — including radar, lidar, and cameras — to help its cars &#8220;see&#8221; 360 degrees during the day and night, and even in tough weather conditions such as rain or fog. While its simulated and real world driving tests have helped it to amass a massive dataset that is crunched using machine learning-based software. According to anonymous sources cited by <em>Reuters</em>, Waymo intends to use in-house tech and external suppliers for its next-gen LiDARs.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This post originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/waymo-self-driving-car-lidar-103642444.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
</div>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/waymo-will-stop-selling-its-self-driving-lidar-sensors-to-other-companies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194960</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>China proposes strict control of algorithms</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/china-proposes-strict-control-of-algorithms/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/china-proposes-strict-control-of-algorithms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 07:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[didi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194904</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[China is not done with curbing the influence local internet services have assumed in the world’s largest populous market. Following a widening series of regulatory crackdowns in recent months, the nation on Friday issued draft guidelines on regulating the algorithms firms run to make recommendations to users. In a 30-point draft guidelines published on Friday, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">China is not done with curbing the influence local internet services have assumed in the world’s largest populous market. Following <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/the-china-tech-crackdown-continues/">a widening series of regulatory crackdowns</a> in recent months, the nation on Friday issued draft guidelines on regulating the algorithms firms run to make recommendations to users.</p>
<p>In a <a href="http://www.cac.gov.cn/2021-08/27/c_1631652502874117.htm">30-point draft guidelines</a> published on Friday, the Cyberspace Administration of China (CAC) proposed forbidding companies from deploying algorithms that &#8220;encourage addiction or high consumption&#8221; and endanger national security or disrupt the public order.</p>
<p>The services must abide by business ethics and principles of fairness and their algorithms must not be used to create fake user accounts or create other false impressions, said the guidelines from the internet watchdog, which reports to a central leadership group chaired by President Xi Jinping. The watchdog said it will be taking public feedback on the new guidelines for a month (until September 26).</p>
<p>The guidelines also propose that users should be provided with the ability to easily turn off algorithm recommendations. Algorithm providers who have the power to influence public opinion or mobilize the citizens need to get an approval from the CAC.</p>
<p>Friday’s proposal comes at a time when Beijing is increasingly targeting companies for the way they have handled consumer data and the monopolistic positions they have assumed in the nation.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Beijing-backed China Consumers Association said local internet companies had been “bullying” users into purchases and promotions and undermining their privacy rights.</p>
<p>Beijing’s recent data-security crackdown and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/as-china-shakes-up-regulations-tech-companies-suffer/">tightening regulations around tutor services</a> have spooked investors and wiped hundreds of billions of dollars.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Friday’s guidelines appear to target ByteDance, Alibaba Group, Tencent, and Didi and other companies whose services are built on top of proprietary algorithms. Shares of Alibaba and Tencent fell slightly on the news.</p>
<p>In recent years, several governments including those in the U.S. and India have attempted &#8212; to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/whatsapp-sues-india-government/">little to no success</a> &#8212; to get better clarity on how these big tech companies’ algorithms work and put checks in place to prevent misuse.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fzWsbc0JwT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/chinas-regulatory-crackdown-is-good-news-for-startups-aligned-with-ccp-goals/">China&#8217;s regulatory crackdown is good news for startups aligned with CCP goals</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;China&#8217;s regulatory crackdown is good news for startups aligned with CCP goals&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/chinas-regulatory-crackdown-is-good-news-for-startups-aligned-with-ccp-goals/embed/#?secret=fzWsbc0JwT" data-secret="fzWsbc0JwT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/china-proposes-strict-control-of-algorithms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194904</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>KKR to acquire New Zealand bus company Ritchies Transport at value of $347M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/kkr-to-acquire-new-zealand-bus-company-ritchies-transport-at-value-of-347m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/kkr-to-acquire-new-zealand-bus-company-ritchies-transport-at-value-of-347m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 05:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[KKR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194882</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Global investment firm KKR has plans to acquire a New Zealand bus and coach company with an 86-year heritage, Ritchies Transport. The terms of the deal were not disclosed, but sources familiar with the circumstances say the deal values Ritchies at over $347 million ($500 million NZD). On Thursday, the two companies signed the definitive [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id=":flx" class="Am aO9 Al editable LW-avf tS-tW tS-tY" tabindex="1" role="textbox" contenteditable="true" spellcheck="false" aria-label="Message Body" aria-multiline="true">
<p tabindex="1" role="textbox" aria-label="Message Body" aria-multiline="true">Global investment firm KKR has plans to acquire a New Zealand bus and coach company with an 86-year heritage, Ritchies Transport. The terms of the deal were not disclosed, but sources familiar with the circumstances say the deal values Ritchies at over $347 million ($500 million NZD).</p>
<p tabindex="1" role="textbox" aria-label="Message Body" aria-multiline="true">On Thursday, the two companies signed the definitive agreements under which KKR will acquire Ritchies, marking KKR&#8217;s first infrastructure investment in New Zealand. KKR said acquiring the bus company, which currently has a fleet of more than 1,600 vehicles and 42 depots that operate across the country, will help it advance its mission &#8220;to better connect local communities, support the country&#8217;s expanding public transport network and promote greener transportation solutions.&#8221;</p>
<p tabindex="1" role="textbox" aria-label="Message Body" aria-multiline="true">New Zealand is still largely an ICE-fueled nation, but the country has plans to electrify. The government now requires all of its agencies and ministries to electrify fleets within the next five years, and aims to <a href="https://www.smartcitiesworld.net/news/news/christchurch-and-auckland-prepare-to-roll-out-electric-bus-fleets--5614">decarbonize public transport,</a> which mainly relies on buses, entirely by 2035. Kiwi Bus Builders, a New Zealand manufacturer, recently assembled a range of ADL electric buses which have made it to <a href="https://cbwmagazine.com/adl-delivers-first-extra-large-electric-bus-in-new-zealand/">Auckland&#8217;s city streets</a>.</p>
<p tabindex="1" role="textbox" aria-label="Message Body" aria-multiline="true">Director on KKR&#8217;s infrastructure team Andrew Jennings said in a statement that Ritchies buses will represent &#8220;a highly visible opportunity to encourage the adoption of zero-emissions technology&#8221; as New Zealand continues to see &#8220;demand for high quality, greener public transport solutions.&#8221;</p>
<p tabindex="1" role="textbox" aria-label="Message Body" aria-multiline="true">KKR told TechCrunch that it does have a plan to help Ritchies electrify its fleet, and that the firm has made advancements globally across areas related to sustainable transportation, and it will be leveraging those experiences to advance the country as it moves towards zero emissions.</p>
<p tabindex="1" role="textbox" aria-label="Message Body" aria-multiline="true">The investment comes from KKR&#8217;s Asia Pacific Infrastructure Fund. The transaction is still conditional on OIO approval, which KKR says is expected within four to five months. Once the deal is completed, the Ritchie family will continue to hold a stake in the company, and Andrew Ritchie, current director of operations, will be appointed as CEO of the company as Glenn Ritchie, the current CEO, retires.</p>
</d<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>iv>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/kkr-to-acquire-new-zealand-bus-company-ritchies-transport-at-value-of-347m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194882</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indiagold raises $12 million for its gold-focused digital alternative credit platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/indiagold-raises-12-million-for-its-gold-focused-digital-alternative-credit-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/indiagold-raises-12-million-for-its-gold-focused-digital-alternative-credit-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 05:31:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indiagold]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194883</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[India has a unique fascination for gold. The households in the South Asian market are estimated to have a stash of over 25,000 tons of the precious metal whose value today is about half of the country’s nominal GDP. But much of this gold has been sitting idly in lockers in big metal wardrobes for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">India has a unique fascination for gold. The households in the South Asian market are estimated to have a stash of over 25,000 tons of the precious metal whose value today is about half of the country’s nominal GDP. But much of this gold has been sitting idly in lockers in big metal wardrobes for generations.</p>
<p>For generations, Indians across the socio-economic spectrum have preferred to stash their savings — or at least a part of it — in the form of gold. In fact, such is the demand for gold in India — Indians stockpile more gold than citizens in any other country — that the South Asian nation is also one of the world’s largest importers of this precious metal.</p>
<p>Indians use this gold not only as a savings instrument, which protects them from the ups-and-downs of the financial market, but also as an asset against which they could get credit. However, selling off your gold in the form of jewelry or otherwise has a stigma attached to it — &#8220;one is so broke that they had to pawn off their last asset of financial security.&#8221;</p>
<p>The other challenge with keeping gold in the house is that it’s not safe.</p>
<p><a href="https://indiagold.co">Indiagold</a>, a young startup that is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/former-paytm-execs-team-up-indiagold/">attempting to help people put this gold to use</a>, said on Friday it has raised $12 million in its Series A funding. The new financing round was led by Prosus’ PayU &#8212; which typically only backs later stage deals &#8212; and Falcon’s Alpha Wave Incubation (AWI) fund. Better Tomorrow Ventures, 3one4 Capital, Rainmatter Capital and existing investor Leo Capital also participated in the round, which brings the startup&#8217;s all-time raise to $14 million.</p>
<p>Indiagold &#8212; founded by Nitin Misra and Deepak Abbot, two former executives of Paytm &#8212; is building a gold-focused digital alternative credit platform in the world&#8217;s second largest internet market. The startup is using gold to determine the credit worthiness of its customers and providing APIs to banks and other lenders that want to reach this untapped market.</p>
<p>The startup today has two major offerings: It has made it very easy and affordable for people to keep their gold in safe lockers, and it’s enabled them the option to take a loan against their gold reserves.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Once an individual has signed up on Indiagold, the startup’s agents come to their house, inspect and weigh the gold and put it in a RFID sticker-attached tamper-proof bag. Then they put this bag in a steel box and get the customer to lock it with their fingerprint. As the agents leave the premises, Indiagold app provides a livefeed of their journey to the designated vault location.</p>
<p>The idea is to make it very simple for customers to put their gold in a locker. Traditionally, because of the emotional stigma attached to the yellow metal, most people have hesitated to do anything with the gold jewelry they own. Indiagold has devised a procedure that helps them gain trust of their customers.</p>
<p>&#8220;This whole business is built around trust,&#8221; said Misra in an interview with TechCrunch. &#8220;Unlike a norm in some circles of the startup ecosystem where you are expected to break things and move fast, in our business we have to spend time with customers to build that trust,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Indiagold also offers their lockers at a much affordable price &#8212; just a few dollars a year, as opposed to hundreds taken by banks. And unlike banks, Indiagold protects the customers’ gold with insurance coverage.</p>
<p>Customers have access to Indiagold app where they can see realtime value of the gold items they have put in the locker. This is when the startup’s second offering kicks in, should customers need it. In the event these customers need to take a loan, the startup facilitates a line of credit to them within 30 seconds.</p>
<p>Tapping on gold as a loan collateral is a very large market in India &#8212; and also one that remains largely unscratched.</p>
<p>&#8220;Despite the large gold reserves held by Indian household, the gold loan market has barely scratched the surface. The gold collateral (166 tons) held by Muthoot Finance is less than 1% of the estimated gold reserves in Indian households (~25k tons). This is because gold is seen as a family heirloom and passed along generations,&#8221; analysts at Bernstein wrote in a report to clients earlier this year.</p>
<p>Customers have the freedom to take loan against only parts of their gold reserve they have stored in the locker. And because they know that their gold items are tied to their biometric, they are confident that nobody is breaking into the locker and melting their jewelries.</p>
<p>If changing consumer behavior wasn&#8217;t a big enough task already, Indiagold this year has grappled with several other challenges. The devastating second wave of the coronavirus wiped 70% of its business within days, said Misra and Abbot. &#8220;We have gone through a lot in this short journey,&#8221; Misra recalled.</p>
<p>But by first half of this month, business had climbed to an all-time peak, he said.</p>
<p>“Indiagold’s unique doorstep gold loan and gold locker products not only offer unparalleled customer experience but also enable it to offer credit at more affordable rates. The traction Indiagold has seen in a short time is a testament to its superior product capabilities and the deep experience of its pedigreed founders. We believe the gold loan market is ripe for disruption and are thrilled to back Indiagold’s founders,&#8221; said Navroz D. Udwadia, co-founder of Falcon Edge Capital, in a statement.</p>
<p>The startup, which is currently operational in the National Capital Region and Indore, plans to expand to 10 cities by the end of the financial year. The duo said they are also working to broaden their product offerings. PayU said in a statement that it will explore ways to collaborate with Indiagold on some product offerings.</p>
<p>A handful of startups are beginning to explore the gold opportunities in India. Bangalore-based <a href="https://www.myjar.app">Jar</a>, founded this year, is helping young users start their journey of savings by investing in digital gold.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="J9wTxnp02V"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/former-paytm-execs-team-up-indiagold/">Former Paytm execs team up to chase gold in India</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Former Paytm execs team up to chase gold in India&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/former-paytm-execs-team-up-indiagold/embed/#?secret=J9wTxnp02V" data-secret="J9wTxnp02V" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/indiagold-raises-12-million-for-its-gold-focused-digital-alternative-credit-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194883</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple will now let App Store developers talk to their customers about buying direct</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/apple-will-now-let-app-store-developers-talk-to-their-customers-about-buying-direct/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/apple-will-now-let-app-store-developers-talk-to-their-customers-about-buying-direct/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 02:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anti-competition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple-app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawsuit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194862</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple announced today it has reached a proposed settlement (embedded below) in a lawsuit filed against it by developers in the United States. The agreement, which is still pending court approval, includes a few changes, the biggest one being that developers will be able to share information on how to pay for purchases outside of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/08/apple-us-developers-agree-to-app-store-updates/">announced</a> today it has reached a proposed settlement (embedded below) in a lawsuit filed against it by developers in the United States. The agreement, which is still pending court approval, includes a few changes, the biggest one being that developers will be able to share information on how to pay for purchases outside of their iOS app or the App Store—which means they can tell customers about payment options that aren’t subject to Apple commissions. The settlement also includes more pricing tiers and a new transparency report about the app review process.</p>
<p>The class-action lawsuit was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/cbusiness-us-apple-antitrust-idCAKCN1T5249-OCABS">filed against Apple in 2019</a> by app developers Donald Cameron and Illinois Pure Sweat Basketball, who said the company engaged in anticompetitive practices by only allowing the downloading of iPhone apps through its App Store.</p>
<p>In today’s announcement, Apple said it is “clarifying that developers can use communications, such as emails, to share information about payment methods outside of their iOS app. As always, developers will not pay Apple a commission on any purchases taking place outside of their app or the App Stores.”</p>
<p>This would allow developers to communicate with customers by email and “other communication services,” which was difficult to do under the App Store’s rules, which forbid developers from using contact information obtained within an app to contact users outside of the app. The settlement would lift this rule for all app categories, enabling developers to tell consenting users about payment methods that avoid Apple’s commissions.</p>
<p>In terms of pricing tiers, Apple said it will expand the number of price points available to developers from fewer than 100 to more than 500. It also agreed to publish a new annual transparency report that will share information about the app review process, including how many apps are rejected, the number of customer and developer accounts deactivated, “objective data regarding search queries and results,” and the number of apps removed from the App Store.</p>
<p>The company also said it will create a new fund for qualifying developers in America who earned $1 million or less through the U.S. App Store, which includes 99% of developers in America. Hagens Berman, one of the law firms representing plaintiffs in the lawsuit, <a href="https://www.hbsslaw.com/cases/apple-ios-app-developers">said the fund will be $100 million</a>, with payments ranging from $250 to $30,000.</p>
<p style="margin: 12px auto 6px auto; font-family: Helvetica,Arial,Sans-serif; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; font-size: 14px; line-height: normal; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; -x-system-font: none; display: block;"><a style="text-decoration: underline;" title="View Cameron et al v. Apple Inc. proposed settlement on Scribd" href="https://www.scribd.com/document/521897664/Cameron-et-al-v-Apple-Inc-proposed-settlement#from_embed">Cameron et al v. Apple Inc. proposed settlement</a> by <a style="text-decoration: underline;" title="View TechCrunch's profile on Scribd" href="https://www.scribd.com/publisher/17551504/TechCrunch#from_embed">TechCrunch</a> on Scribd</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe id="doc_15106" class="scribd_iframe_embed" title="Cameron et al v. Apple Inc. proposed settlement " src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/521897664/content?start_page=1&amp;view_mode=scroll&amp;access_key=key-pDIbp7Uw6OjnkYi0mqX2" width="100%" height="600" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" data-auto-height="false" data-aspect-ratio="0.75"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/apple-will-now-let-app-store-developers-talk-to-their-customers-about-buying-direct/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194862</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cruise is buying solar energy from California farmers to power its electric, self-driving fleet</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/cruise-is-buying-solar-energy-from-california-farmers-to-power-its-electric-self-driving-fleet/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/cruise-is-buying-solar-energy-from-california-farmers-to-power-its-electric-self-driving-fleet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 23:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cruise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar energy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194777</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cruise, the self-driving car company under General Motors, has launched a new initiative called Farm to Fleet that will allow the company to source solar power from farms in California&#8217;s Central Valley. The San Francisco Chronicle was the first to report the news that Cruise is directly purchasing renewable energy credits from Sundale Vineyards and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Cruise, the self-driving car company under General Motors, has launched a new initiative called <a href="https://www.getcruise.com/news/farm-to-fleet-how-cruise-powers-its-self-driving-cars-with-clean-energy">Farm to Fleet</a> that will allow the company to source solar power from farms in California&#8217;s Central Valley. The <a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/california/article/Cruise-looks-to-Central-Valley-solar-panels-to-16409623.php">San Francisco Chronicle</a> was the first to report the news that Cruise is directly purchasing renewable energy credits from Sundale Vineyards and Moonlight Companies to help power its fleet of all-electric autonomous vehicles in San Francisco.</p>
<p>Cruise <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/cruise-can-now-give-passengers-rides-in-driverless-cars-in-california/">recently secured a permit</a> to shuttle passengers in its test vehicles in San Francisco without a human safety operator behind the wheel. The company is also ramping up its march to commercialization with a recent <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/cruise-secures-5b-credit-line-to-buy-electric-autonomous-cruise-origin-vehicles-from-gm/">$5 billion line of credit</a> from GM Financial to pay for hundreds of electric and autonomous Origin vehicles. While this partnership with California farmers is undoubtedly a boon to the state&#8217;s work in progressing renewable energies while also providing jobs and financial opportunities to local businesses, Cruise isn&#8217;t running a charity here.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JCkEsUVOFa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/cruise-secures-5b-credit-line-to-buy-electric-autonomous-cruise-origin-vehicles-from-gm/">Cruise secures $5B credit line to buy electric, autonomous Cruise Origin vehicles from GM</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cruise secures $5B credit line to buy electric, autonomous Cruise Origin vehicles from GM&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/cruise-secures-5b-credit-line-to-buy-electric-autonomous-cruise-origin-vehicles-from-gm/embed/#?secret=JCkEsUVOFa" data-secret="JCkEsUVOFa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://www.wsj.com/amp/articles/california-scrambles-to-find-electricity-this-summer-as-blackout-risks-grow-11625666400">The California Independent System Operator has been soliciting power producers</a> across the western United States to sell more megawatts to the state this summer in anticipation of heat waves that will boost electricity demand and potentially cause blackouts. Power supplies are lower than expected already due to droughts, outages and delays in bringing new energy generation sources to the grid, causing reduced hydroelectric generation. To ensure California&#8217;s grid can handle the massive increase in fleet size Cruise is planning, it seems that the company has no choice but to find creative ways to bolster the grid. Cruise, however, is holding firm that it&#8217;s got loftier goals than securing the energy from whatever sources are available.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is entirely about us doing the right thing for our cities and communities and fundamentally transforming transportation for the better,&#8221; Ray Wert, a Cruise spokesperson, told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>With droughts continuing to plague California farmers, converting farmland to solar farms is a potential way to help the state meet its climate change targets, according to <a href="https://www.scienceforconservation.org/products/power-of-place">a report from environmental nonprofit Nature Conservancy</a>. Which is why Cruise saw the logic in approaching Central Valley farmers now.</p>
<p>&#8220;Farm to Fleet is a vehicle to rapidly reduce urban transportation emissions while generating new revenue for California’s farmers leading in renewable energy,&#8221; said Rob Grant, Cruise’s vice president of social affairs and global impact, in a blog post.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Cruise is paying negotiated contract rates with the farms through its clean energy partner, BTR Energy. The company isn&#8217;t disclosing costs, but says it&#8217;s paying no more or less than what it would pay for using other forms of renewable energy credits (RECs). RECs are produced when a renewable energy source generates one megawatt-hour of electricity and passes it on to the grid. According to Cruise, Sundale has installed 2 megawatts of solar capacity to power their 200,000 square footage of cold storage, and Moonlight has installed a combined 3.9 MW of solar arrays and two-battery storage system for its sorting and storage facilities. So when Cruise buys credits from these farms, it&#8217;s able to say that a specific amount of its electricity use came from a renewable source. RECs are unique and tracked, so it&#8217;s clear where they came from, what kind of energy they used and where they went. Cruise did not share how many RECs it plans to purchase from the farms, but says it will be enough to power its San Francisco fleet.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cM4WahMHGw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/cruise-can-now-give-passengers-rides-in-driverless-cars-in-california/">Cruise can now give passengers rides in driverless cars in California</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cruise can now give passengers rides in driverless cars in California&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/cruise-can-now-give-passengers-rides-in-driverless-cars-in-california/embed/#?secret=cM4WahMHGw" data-secret="cM4WahMHGw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;While the solar power still flows through the same grid, Cruise purchases and then ultimately &#8216;retires&#8217; the renewable energy credits generated by the solar panels at the farms,&#8221; said Wert. &#8220;Through data that we submit to the California Air Resources Board quarterly, we retire a number of RECs equivalent to the amount of electricity we used to charge our vehicles.&#8221;<span class="im"><br />
</span></p>
<p>Cruise is also working with BTR Energy to finalize a supply of RECs for its operations in Arizona, including its delivery pilot with Walmart.</p>
<p><span class="im">Wert says using fully renewable power is actually profitable for Cruise in California due to the <a href="https://www.peninsulacleanenergy.com/low-carbon-fuel-standard-credits-overview-lcfs/">Low Carbon Fuel Standard</a>, which is designed to decrease the carbon intensity of transportation fuels in the state and provide more low-carbon alternatives. Cruise owns and operates all of its own EV charging ports, so it&#8217;s able to generate credits based on the carbon intensity score of the electricity and amount of energy delivered. Cruise can then sell its credits to other companies seeking to reduce their footprints and comply with regulations. </span></p>
<p><span class="im">Aside from practicalities, Cruise is aiming to set a standard for the industry and create demand for renewable energy, thus incentivizing more people and businesses to create it. </span><b></b></p>
<p>Aram Shumavon, CEO of grid analytics startup Kevala, says Cruise should be applauded for this partnership.</p>
<p>&#8220;What Cruise seems to be trying to acknowledge is that there is carbon intensity associated with the electricity that they&#8217;re consuming, and they&#8217;re offsetting that in some way,&#8221; Shumavon told TechCrunch. &#8220;There&#8217;s a whole category of carbon accounting, that&#8217;s referred to as Scope 3, which is trying to understand how much carbon the supply chain that you use to provide your service actually involves, and Cruise is probably, as a very deliberate decision, getting out in front of their Scope 3 requirements.&#8221;</p>
<p>Shumavon said that by quantifying the total carbon intensity of commercial activity, companies become more accountable to it and can then drive change by asking providers for their supply to source from renewables. For example, an automaker might ask their aluminum provider to source only from an area with hydroelectric power instead of coal power, which would ultimately bring the automaker&#8217;s carbon intensity down.</p>
<p><span class="im">&#8220;Transportation is responsible for over 40% of greenhouse gas emissions, which is why we announced our Clean Mile Challenge in February, where we challenged the rest of the AV industry to report how many miles they’re driving on renewable energy every year,&#8221; said Wert. &#8220;We’re hoping that others follow our lead.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><em>This article has been updated to reflect new information provided by Cruise, as well as expert commentary from Aram Shumavon, CEO of Kevala. </em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="O125ZK7u81"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-regulations/">Why regulators love Nuro&#8217;s self-driving delivery vehicles</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why regulators love Nuro&#8217;s self-driving delivery vehicles&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-regulations/embed/#?secret=O125ZK7u81" data-secret="O125ZK7u81" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/cruise-is-buying-solar-energy-from-california-farmers-to-power-its-electric-self-driving-fleet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194777</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Copenhagen-based Leapwork lands $62M Series B co-led by KKR and Salesforce Ventures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/daily-crunch-55/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/daily-crunch-55/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 22:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194705</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>‘Ello and welcome to Daily Crunch for August 26, 2021. Or as someone called it recently, Friday Jr. We have lots and lots of news today, with a slight bias toward big items from Big Tech companies. But first, do note that we’re going to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/were-focusing-on-fintech-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/">spend a lot of time talking fintech at Disrupt this year</a>, and TechCrunch just <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/techstars-saba-karim-is-coming-to-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/">announced that Techstars’ Saba Karim is coming</a>. It’s going to be great! &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FT0Ufv3fSj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/techstars-saba-karim-is-coming-to-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/">Techstars&#8217; Saba Karim is coming to TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Techstars&#8217; Saba Karim is coming to TechCrunch Disrupt 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/techstars-saba-karim-is-coming-to-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/embed/#?secret=FT0Ufv3fSj" data-secret="FT0Ufv3fSj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/airbnb-to-allow-anyone-not-only-current-hosts-to-sign-up-to-house-afghan-refugees/"><strong>Airbnb expands who can help host Afghan refugees:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Want to help with Airbnb’s push to house refugees fleeing Afghanistan? The company announced today that it will allow anyone to help, not merely existing hosts. Hopefully this expands the pool of housing stock available and gets more folks housed. We’re all human, so let’s help one another.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/apple-lowers-commissions-on-in-app-purchases-for-news-publishers-who-participate-in-apple-news/"><strong>Apple’s commission rigidity fades further:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Apple’s hard-line 30% commission is softening yet again, with the company planning to offer lower take rates for news purchases, at least for publishers who take part in the Apple News app. So it’s good news, with a strong arm-twist to go along with it. Why is Apple fighting so hard to continue rent-seeking in the mobile economy? Because it’s lucrative as heck, that’s why.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/big-tech-pledges-billions-to-bolster-u-s-cybersecurity-defenses/">Major tech companies pledge huge dollars for cybersecurity:</a> </strong>U.S. tech giants Apple, Google and Microsoft are pledging to work on cybersecurity with extra fervor, they said in a White House meeting. Microsoft is pledging to spend $20 billion on the effort, and Google $10 billion. Apple has promised to “establish a new program to drive continuous security improvements throughout the technology supply chain,” TechCrunch writes. All this is good news, but we do wonder how much of the pledged spending was already penciled into future budgets.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>The other day we noted that our own Brian Heater was launching a newsletter. He still is, and one of its pre-launch entries today sports a headline that I cannot improve upon: “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/actuator-2/">I don’t know what to do with those tossed salads and robot legs</a>.” Heater gets 100 points for getting that past the editors. You can sign up for the robot newsletter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters/">here</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/otter-ai-expands-automatic-transcription-assistant-to-microsoft-teams-google-meet-and-cisco-webex/"><strong>Otter.ai expands transcription capabilities:</strong></a><strong> </strong>If you need to record a conversation and transcribe it, Otter is a great tool to use. I know that because I’m an Otter customer &#8212; with my own money &#8212; and depend on it heavily. Its news today is that the service is rolling out its “Otter Assistant feature for Microsoft Teams, Google Meet and Cisco Webex,” after previously launching support for Zoom.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/job-offer-management-platform-compa-emerges-from-stealth-with-3-9m/"><strong>Compa raises $3.9M to build better job offer software:</strong></a> Hiring is a pain in the backside, and in today’s superheated talent market for a number of startup-friendly gigs, it’s even more irksome. To combat those facts, Compa has built software to support recruiters in their work by helping them “manage their compensation strategies to create and communicate offers that are easy to understand and are unbiased.” The startup just came out of stealth.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/playbook-which-aims-to-be-the-dropbox-for-designers-raises-4m-in-round-led-by-founders-fund/"><strong>Playbook wants to build the Dropbox for designers:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Yes, in years past Dropbox was the Dropbox for designers, but today it&#8217;s an enterprise storage and productivity tool. So now there’s Playbook, which wants to assume Dropbox’s old mantle. And it just raised $4 million in a round led by Founders Fund.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/picsart-raises-130m-from-softbank-becomes-unicorn-on-the-back-of-its-visual-creator-tools/"><strong>Picsart raises $130M:</strong></a> Today’s SoftBank and/or Tiger round is Picsart, for whom the Vision Fund 2 just led a $130 million transaction. Details were light, but the company is now a unicorn that crested the $100 million revenue mark. So if you were curious if mobile-first creator tools could scale, well, they can.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/atheneum-150-million/">Atheneum raises $150M for its research and survey product:</a></strong> When I first saw this news I was very excited. Because I live near a private library called the Athenæum. However, this is not that, and so my local temple to books did not just raise $150 million. A startup with the name did, however, and the customer base for its research and survey service is already 500 big companies deep.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/no-code-process-automation-platform-leapwork-fires-up-with-62m-series-b/"><b>Leapwork proves that no-code is still hot by raising $62M Series B:</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Based in Denmark, and raising that country’s largest-ever Series B, Leapwork is making waves with its no-code tool that helps with process automation. I suppose at the union of two hot trends it is not a surprise that the company is doing well &#8212; process automation is booming, and everyone is short on developers.</span></li>
<li>Finally, recent TechCrunch hire Kate Park is out today with a piece digging into <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/ai-voice-synthetic-speech-company-lovo-gets-4-5m-pre-series-a-funding/"><strong>AI voice and synthetic speech startup LOVO</strong></a>, which just put together a $4.5 million round. Perhaps it can fill in for TechCrunchers on our podcasts when we have colds.</li>
</ul>
<h2>You can’t hack your YC application, but here’s what to avoid</h2>
<p>Forget what you&#8217;ve heard: There are many shortcuts to success.</p>
<p>Tapping into someone else&#8217;s experience is a tried-and-true method, which is why two-time Y Combinator participant Chris Morton wrote a guest post for Extra Crunch with advice for founders hoping to be accepted by the famed accelerator.</p>
<p>Morton, who has also reviewed thousands of YC applications, shares his thoughts on when to submit an application, what to do if you miss the deadline and whether you&#8217;ll need to relocate if accepted.</p>
<p>&#8220;Remember that your application should be good enough to get an interview, not win a prize,&#8221; says Morton. &#8220;Go back to work instead of spending more time perfecting an application.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aM9vx3kyLY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/you-cant-hack-your-yc-application-but-heres-what-to-avoid/">You can&#8217;t hack your YC application, but here&#8217;s what to avoid</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;You can&#8217;t hack your YC application, but here&#8217;s what to avoid&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/you-cant-hack-your-yc-application-but-heres-what-to-avoid/embed/#?secret=aM9vx3kyLY" data-secret="aM9vx3kyLY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>To close out our news roundup today, a wall of Big Tech news for your diversion:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/google-confirms-its-pulling-the-plug-on-streams-its-uk-clinician-support-app/"><strong>Google kills Streams, its clinician support app:</strong></a> Google is very good at making things and even better at killing them. If Google was a novelist, it would self-kill so many darlings that it would only produce novellas. Regardless, that Streams is dead is not a huge surprise, but for some likely a real bummer.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/netflix-begins-testing-mobile-games-in-its-android-app-in-poland/">Want some Netflix games? Move to Poland:</a></strong> Netflix is getting into games, which is not a huge surprise given that games are a bigger business than movies, to pick an example. But not everyone is going to get their hands on its mobile titles at once. Poland is up first. That’s not shocking as far as market selection goes, given the popularity of video games in Europe and the reasonable size of the Polish market.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/facebook-elections-oversight-board/"><strong>Facebook considers launching an election policy decision board group oversight Entmoot coven thing:</strong></a><strong> </strong>In more evidence that Facebook may be slightly too large a company to fit into the modern world as a single entity, and that maybe single-human, complete shareholder control should go the way of monarchy, the social giant is “looking to create a standalone advisory committee for election-related policy decisions.” Does that inspire confidence? You tell me.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/lordstown-motors-taps-former-icahn-exec-as-ceo-to-put-its-ev-truck-ambitions-back-on-track/"><strong>Lordstown gets new CEO:</strong></a><strong> </strong>This is a hard, high-profile gig, so it must have been something of an adventure to fill. Still, troubled public EV company Lordstown has secured new leadership that TechCrunch reports is “Daniel A. Ninivaggi, a longtime automotive executive and former head of Carl C. Icahn’s holding company.” Let’s see if he can turn the company around.</li>
<li>Wrapping up, if you are a paid YouTube subscriber, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/youtube-to-roll-out-picture-in-picture-viewing-for-all-u-s-ios-users-starting-with-premium-subscribers/">here’s some good news</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend growth marketers who have expertise in SEO, social, content writing and more! If you’re a growth marketer, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re curious about how these surveys are shaping our coverage, check out this interview Anna Heim conducted with Robert Katai: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/romanian-marketing-expert-robert-katai-explains-how-to-get-the-most-out-of-your-content/">“Romanian marketing expert Robert Katai explains how to get the most out of your content.”</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GKorGSC3xl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/romanian-marketing-expert-robert-katai-explains-how-to-get-the-most-out-of-your-content/">Romanian marketing expert Robert Katai explains how to get the most out of your content</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Romanian marketing expert Robert Katai explains how to get the most out of your content&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/romanian-marketing-expert-robert-katai-explains-how-to-get-the-most-out-of-your-content/embed/#?secret=GKorGSC3xl" data-secret="GKorGSC3xl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/daily-crunch-55/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194705</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Politico sells, Forbes SPACs and Vice cuts</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/politico-sells-forbes-spacs-and-vice-cuts/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/politico-sells-forbes-spacs-and-vice-cuts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 22:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Forbes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[morning brew]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194765</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[﻿ The Equity crew felt that there was enough media news out recently that we simply had no choice but to fire up a Twitter Space and have a chat. The above episode is a discussion of a few things, in a loose and relaxed manner, so don&#8217;t take any of the Verizon jokes too [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/7675bbee-9ef6-463d-bc17-5008709a1f69?dark=false" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""><span style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" data-mce-type="bookmark" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></p>
<p>The Equity crew felt that there was enough media news out recently that we simply had no choice but to fire up a Twitter Space and have a chat. The above episode is a discussion of a few things, in a <em>loose and relaxed manner</em>, so don&#8217;t take any of the Verizon jokes too seriously, Verizon, as we still work for you. For a few more days.</p>
<p>Regardless, here&#8217;s what <a href="https://twitter.com/dannycrichton">Danny</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> got into:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/brianstelter/status/1430870604178202624">Politico sells for $1 billion</a>: </strong>Its new parent company Axel Springer is also buying the rest of Politico Europe and all of Protocol at the same time. This deal exploded everyone&#8217;s Twitter feed due to its scale, and the fact that it was one heck of an exit for a media company. One billion dollars? For media? In this economy? Yes!</li>
<li><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbespr/2021/08/26/forbes-to-become-public-company-through-business-combination-with-special-purpose-acquisition-company-magnum-opus/"><strong>Forbes is going public via a SPAC</strong></a>: Yep, the venerable Forbes magazing and its enormous digital arm are taking the blank-check route to the public markets, which means that we got its numbers and time to stroll through them. Our take is that Forbes has done massive work to take its IRL brand and extend it into the digital world. The company has big plans to boot, and will be worth more than $800 million when it combines.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/vice-media-round-layoffs-1235049824/">Layoffs hit Vice</a>:</strong> As Vice turns its focus to video content — you&#8217;ve heard this story before — it is shedding some of its editorial staff. The layoffs were a stinkbomb on Media Twitter after the other news of the week, but were sadly not a huge surprise. The company&#8217;s union decried them as something of a yearly recurrence. Not good, not good at all.</li>
</ul>
<p>And there&#8217;s more media news to come. Our parent company Verizon Media is expected to close its sale to Apollo on September 1 or sometime soon after, which means we will either be hosting Equity regularly as always, or we&#8217;ll be hosting the RUDE (Recently Unemployed Due to (Private) Equity) podcast.</p>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content"><em>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PDT, Wednesday, and Friday morning at 7:00 a.m. PDT, so subscribe to us on <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity">Overcast</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ">Spotify</a> and all the casts.</em></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/politico-sells-forbes-spacs-and-vice-cuts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194765</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter starts to roll out paid Ticketed Spaces on iOS</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/twitter-starts-to-roll-out-paid-ticketed-spaces-on-ios/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/twitter-starts-to-roll-out-paid-ticketed-spaces-on-ios/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 20:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[live audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ticketed Spaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter Spaces]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194726</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter announced today that some hosts on Spaces, its live audio feature, will now be able to sell access to Ticketed Spaces. Applications for Ticketed Spaces first opened in June for users who are over 18, hosted three Spaces in the last 30 days and have at least 1,000 followers. &#8220;We&#8217;re continuing to work closely [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSpaces/status/1430965572326526990">announced today</a> that some hosts on Spaces, its live audio feature, will now be able to sell access to Ticketed Spaces. Applications for Ticketed Spaces <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/twitter-super-follows-and-ticketed-spaces/">first opened in June</a> for users who are over 18, hosted three Spaces in the last 30 days and have at least 1,000 followers.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re continuing to work closely with people who are already hosting Spaces for Ticketed Spaces,&#8221; a Twitter representative told TechCrunch. Twitter declined to say how many people it&#8217;s rolled out this capability to so far, or when users can expect a more universal rollout. For now, anyone on iOS can buy tickets to Spaces hosted by people who have access to the feature.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">we want to help people creating cool Spaces make $$$. today, some Hosts will be able create Ticketed Spaces! </p>
<p>we’re experimenting on iOS only for now but we hope to get it to everyone soon. know it’s taking us a little time, but we want to get this right for you! <a href="https://t.co/xc68yWkOim">https://t.co/xc68yWkOim</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Spaces (@TwitterSpaces) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSpaces/status/1430965572326526990?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 26, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Twitter <a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/using-twitter/spaces-ticketed-faq">previously stated</a> that it will take a 3% cut of creators&#8217; earnings from Ticketed Spaces. But since the feature is only currently available on iOS, that means that Twitter will be subject to Apple&#8217;s 30% in-app purchase fee, so a creator will only see 67% of each ticket sale. If a creator&#8217;s total lifetime earnings on Twitter &#8212; including Ticketed Spaces and Super Follows &#8212; exceed $50,000, then Twitter will raise its 3% commission to 20%.</p>
<p>Ticketed Spaces would differentiate Twitter aside from its live audio competitors. Clubhouse and Instagram let listeners <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/clubhouse-payments/">tip speakers</a> or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/instagram-rolls-out-fan-badges-for-live-videos-expands-igtv-ads-test/">award badges</a> in a live audio space, but the apps haven&#8217;t enabled advance ticket sales.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Sx18b26IIl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/twitter-super-follows-and-ticketed-spaces/">Super Follows and Ticketed Spaces are coming to Twitter</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Super Follows and Ticketed Spaces are coming to Twitter&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/twitter-super-follows-and-ticketed-spaces/embed/#?secret=Sx18b26IIl" data-secret="Sx18b26IIl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/twitter-starts-to-roll-out-paid-ticketed-spaces-on-ios/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194726</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zendesk acquires AI automation startup Cleverly to advance customer service</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/zendesk-acquires-ai-automation-startup-cleverly-to-advance-customer-service/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/zendesk-acquires-ai-automation-startup-cleverly-to-advance-customer-service/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Michael Kerner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 20:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chatbot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cleverly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lisbon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zendesk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194730</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Zendesk is looking to grow its customer service capabilities, and today it announced the acquisition of early-stage artificial intelligence startup Cleverly. Financial terms of the deal are not being publicly disclosed at this time and Cleverly has not been entirely public about the size of its funding. Founded in 2019, Cleverly is based in Lisbon, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.zendesk.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Zendesk</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is looking to grow its customer service capabilities, and today it announced the acquisition of early-stage artificial intelligence startup Cleverly.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Financial terms of the deal are not being publicly disclosed at this time and Cleverly has not been entirely public about the size of its funding.</span><a href="https://www.cleverly.ai/contact-us"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Founded in 2019, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cleverly</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">is based in Lisbon, Portugal and, according to its site, has received funding from the European Union’s </span><a href="https://ec.europa.eu/programmes/horizon2020/en/home"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Horizon 2020</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> research and innovation programme. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup was also listed by TechCrunch in an article earlier this year looking at the</span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/07/lisbons-startup-scene-rises-as-portugal-gears-up-to-be-a-european-tech-tiger/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">startup scene in Lisbon</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as being one of the most exciting deep tech companies in the region, according to Stephan Morais, partner at Indico Capital Partners.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3PFjBGsx0k"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/07/lisbons-startup-scene-rises-as-portugal-gears-up-to-be-a-european-tech-tiger/">Lisbon&#8217;s startup scene rises as Portugal gears up to be a European tech tiger</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lisbon&#8217;s startup scene rises as Portugal gears up to be a European tech tiger&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/07/lisbons-startup-scene-rises-as-portugal-gears-up-to-be-a-european-tech-tiger/embed/#?secret=3PFjBGsx0k" data-secret="3PFjBGsx0k" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cleverly&#8217;s product platform provides a series of artificial intelligence-powered capabilities, including a triage function to automatically tag incoming service requests to help categorize workflow. The startup also has what it refers to as AI-powered human augmentation with its</span><a href="https://www.cleverly.ai/product/agent-assist"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">agent assist</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> capability that aims to help customer service agents provide the right answers to inquiries. The company&#8217;s technology already integrates with Zendesk, as well as with Salesforce.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As to why Zendesk is acquiring Cleverly, Shawna Wolverton, EVP of product at Zendesk, noted in an email to TechCrunch that the two companies have a similar vision for the future of customer service. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Cleverly and Zendesk want to democratize AI, so companies can create practical applications that make it possible for businesses to get started with AI right out of the box — without a team of data scientists required,&#8221; she said. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wolverton added that AI has the ability to help customer experience teams deliver great customer service. She expects that the next generation of great customer experiences will be created by intelligent software, enabling humans and AI working closely together to deliver this at scale.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wolverton noted that her company will be welcoming all of Cleverly’s team to Zendesk beginning August 30, including founders Christina Fonseca as VP of Product and Pedro Coelho as principal engineering lead, Machine Learning.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Zendesk already has a series of AI-enabled capabilities that can help organizations automate customer conversations, boost agent productivity and increase operational efficiency, including the Answer Bot, which is a chatbot for customer interactions providing answers pulled from Zendesk&#8217;s knowledge base. Zendesk&#8217;s Content Cues AI-powered feature in turn helps to automatically review support tickets and also can identify areas where content in a company&#8217;s help center can be updated to be more useful to users.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zKB2BxzugC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/startups-have-never-had-it-so-good/">Startups have never had it so good</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Startups have never had it so good&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/startups-have-never-had-it-so-good/embed/#?secret=zKB2BxzugC" data-secret="zKB2BxzugC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;With Cleverly, we will deliver a range of capabilities that automate key insights, further reduce manual tasks and improve workflows, and overall lead to happier, more productive support teams,&#8221; Wolverton said. &#8220;We will have more news to share on that front once the team is up and running.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Zendesk&#8217;s business has been growing in 2021 overall,</span><a href="https://investor.zendesk.com/ir-home/financial-reports/financial-releases/financial-releases-details/2021/Zendesk-Announces-Second-Quarter-2021-Results/default.aspx"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">reporting</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">second-quarter fiscal 2021 revenue of $318.2 million for a 29% year-over-year gain.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/zendesk-acquires-ai-automation-startup-cleverly-to-advance-customer-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194730</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Boox tablets are welcome options in the growing oversize e-reader niche</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/boox-tablets-are-welcome-options-in-the-growing-oversize-e-reader-niche/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/boox-tablets-are-welcome-options-in-the-growing-oversize-e-reader-niche/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 20:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[E Ink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-readers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2062122</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When it comes to e-paper devices, the Kindle is of course the first brand people think of, though I&#8217;ve done my best to spread the Kobo and reMarkable gospel as well. Chinese e-reader maker Boox is a relatively new entrant to the space, and its devices are experimental but useful options in the niche market [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When it comes to e-paper devices, the Kindle is of course the first brand people think of, though I&#8217;ve done my best to spread the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/03/kobos-forma-e-reader-takes-on-kindle-oasis-with-an-asymmetric-design-and-premium-price/">Kobo</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/27/the-remarkable-2-improves-on-the-original-in-every-way-but-remains-firmly-in-its-niche/">reMarkable</a> gospel as well. Chinese e-reader maker Boox is a relatively new entrant to the space, and its devices are experimental but useful options in the niche market of monochrome tablets. In fact, they make my new favorite small device.</p>
<p>A brand from parent company Onyx, Boox has a wide array of devices, some might say too wide, ranging from pocketable to medium-sized e-readers to A4-sized tablets. Its branding is not particularly memorable and slightly updated versions come out quite regularly — one device I hoped to test was actually being replaced by the time I got around to writing this article.</p>
<p>The unifying aspect is the OS, a modified version of Android 10 with a few special-made apps for reading and productivity. Made with Chinese consumers in mind, the services probably aren&#8217;t ones you will have heard of.</p>
<p>I tested several devices from Boox, the simplest being the Poke 3 e-reader, then the larger and more complex Note2, followed by the svelte Note Air and enormous Max Lumi. Most recently I have been looking at the Nova3 Color, which uses E Ink&#8217;s latest Kaleido Plus color screen.</p>
<p>The truth is if you didn&#8217;t turn them on you probably wouldn&#8217;t be able to tell that these devices were all from the same company. They have quite different hardware styles, though of course there&#8217;s only so much room for expression in a black tablet with a screen in shades of grey.</p>
<h3>Little and big</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2072187" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-4.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2072187" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2072187" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-4.jpg" alt="A Boox Poke 3 e-reader in a hand." width="1024" height="714" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-4.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-4.jpg?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-4.jpg?resize=300,209 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-4.jpg?resize=768,536 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-4.jpg?resize=680,474 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-4.jpg?resize=1536,1072 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-4.jpg?resize=2048,1429 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-4.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2072187" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Devin Coldewey / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s begin with the simplest and most familiar format, the 6-inch e-reader. In this category we have the Kindle Paperwhite and Kobo Clara HD. The former is probably the best one Amazon makes, but I prefer the latter, even though its build quality is, frankly, poor.</p>
<p>Boox in this space has (among others) the Poke 3, not exactly the catchiest name, but it makes up for that with its form factor: pretty much the platonic ideal for a small reader like this. I liked it so much I broke it out into a separate review, but here are the basics.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="J2Dbe1j9WF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/the-boox-poke-3-is-my-new-favorite-e-reader/">The Boox Poke 3 is my new favorite e-reader</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Boox Poke 3 is my new favorite e-reader&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/the-boox-poke-3-is-my-new-favorite-e-reader/embed/#?secret=J2Dbe1j9WF" data-secret="J2Dbe1j9WF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The 6-inch, 300-PPI screen is of equal quality to the Kindle and Kobo, and like the Clara HD has a temperature-adjustable frontlight. The front of the device is completely flush, just the way I like it, and has just enough bezel to grip without it becoming too much or too little. The seamless design makes it pocketable and resistant to crumbs and spills (though it makes no water resistance claims). There&#8217;s a power button up top (thank you) and a single USB-C port at the bottom.</p>
<p>Regarding the hardware, I find it difficult to come up with any criticism at all. It could, I suppose, be lighter, but its dimensions could not be smaller than they are without adversely affecting the ergonomics; a millimeter could conceivably be shaved off the thickness but it would be barely noticeable.</p>
<p>The OS is a highly customized version of Android, with all the pros and cons that comes with. I have always enjoyed the simplicity of Kobo&#8217;s interface, though they seem bent on complicating it. Boox&#8217;s OS is powerful but busy, uneasy in its decisions of what options to make available and prominent to the user.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2072183" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2072183" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2072183" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-1.jpg" alt="Screen of a Boox Poke 3 e-reader" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-1.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-1.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-1.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-1.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-1.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-1.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-1.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/boox-poke3-1.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2072183" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Devin Coldewey / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>The reader app, NeoReader, supports tons of file formats and has a huge set of controls for changing your view, highlighting and notating books and PDFs, and so on. This is more for the larger devices than the small ones, which really only need font adjustment and other basic stuff.</p>
<p>If all you want to do is read e-books you already have sitting on your computer, it&#8217;s as easy as dragging them into the &#8220;Books&#8221; folder on the device&#8217;s storage. That tab is what you&#8217;ll see when you turn on the device, and it&#8217;s always easy to get to. There&#8217;s a built-in store that takes up a whole tab, though it isn&#8217;t available in the U.S. — then a file manager tab for rooting around in directories — and a tab each for your apps and settings.</p>
<p>The apps are another custom situation: This being a Chinese device, it comes without the usual Google-authenticated App Store, whatever it&#8217;s called these days. Instead, it has its own store with dozens of the most-used reading apps, from Pocket and GoodReader to the Kobo and Kindle apps. But these are essentially side-loaded: for instance, the Kindle app is a few months old. That&#8217;s far from a disaster, but you do need to commit to a certain amount of trust in Boox and its proxy app store in order to use the device as-is.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VSK4ulU5se"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/kobo-elipsa-review-a-sized-up-e-reading-companion-with-clever-note-taking/">Kobo Elipsa review: A sized-up e-reading companion with clever note taking</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Kobo Elipsa review: A sized-up e-reading companion with clever note taking&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/kobo-elipsa-review-a-sized-up-e-reading-companion-with-clever-note-taking/embed/#?secret=VSK4ulU5se" data-secret="VSK4ulU5se" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Of course, you can also enable Google Play services in the settings, which adds the official store into the mix. But for most people this is already far too much work. We are both spoiled and deprived in our e-reader selection in that they are generally simple and extremely straightforward to use. Someone who is not familiar with Android, using this device and a Kobo or Kindle, would probably opt for one of the latter.</p>
<p>Yet the possibilities are many for those who wish to take the plunge. For my part, I like the form factor of the Poke 3 so well that I will brave any OS to use it. Besides, you spend 99% of your time on these things in a book, so as long as that part works, the rest is just icing on the cake.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2123876" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100040.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2123876" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2123876" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100040.jpg" alt="View of a tablet interface with handwriting on it." width="1024" height="762" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100040.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100040.jpg?resize=150,112 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100040.jpg?resize=300,223 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100040.jpg?resize=768,572 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100040.jpg?resize=680,506 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100040.jpg?resize=1536,1143 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100040.jpg?resize=2048,1525 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100040.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2123876" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Devin Coldewey / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>At the 6-inch scale, this all seems like way too much. But on Boox&#8217;s larger devices, the flexibility starts to make more sense. The idea with the Note 2 (now 3), Note Air and Max Lumi is to provide almost all the capabilities of an Android tablet, but with the benefits of an e-paper screen. Admittedly that makes playing racing games something of a non-starter, but it could be very attractive to the types of people for whom their reMarkable is used more than their iPad.</p>
<p>If you read a lot of documents, doing so on a bright tablet screen — or a dim one, for that matter — sucks. An e-paper screen is better for the task, but the best device for that, the reMarkable, is also very deliberately limited in what it can accomplish, since the whole philosophy of the company revolves around <em>focus</em>. So there are definitely people who want the capabilities of an Android device with the readability of an e-paper one. Or at any rate Boox thinks so.</p>
<p>The Note 2 and Max Lumi seem related: They&#8217;re unremarkable black tablets of impressive dimensions and, in my limited explorations of their hardware, what seemed to me excellent build quality. The Note Air, it must be said, is the opposite of unremarkable — in fact, when I saw it, I thought it was a clone of the reMarkable 2!</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2123877" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100041.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2123877" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2123877" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100041.jpg" alt="Side view of a tablet showing its thin profile and metal finish." width="1024" height="673" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100041.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100041.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100041.jpg?resize=300,197 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100041.jpg?resize=768,505 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100041.jpg?resize=680,447 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100041.jpg?resize=1536,1010 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100041.jpg?resize=2048,1347 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PB100041.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2123877" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Devin Coldewey / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>This first impression turned out to be less than generous on my part, as while the two share some significant design elements, they are in fact quite different and Boox&#8217;s facility in creating other devices has led me to give them the benefit of the doubt here. The blue and orange motif isn&#8217;t the greatest, but it does help set it apart, and all the devices (especially the Air) are thin and well designed.</p>
<p>All the tablets feature frontlights, and I&#8217;m happy to say that my skepticism that it could be done with such big screens was needless. It works well and like the Poke 3 the light is adjustable in both brightness and temperature (though it&#8217;s a bit fiddly).</p>
<h3>Color e-paper still isn&#8217;t quite there</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2194716" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2194716" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2194716" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-1.jpg" alt="The Boox Nova3 color e-ink tablet" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-1.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-1.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-1.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-1.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-1.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-1.jpg?resize=1536,1153 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-1.jpg?resize=2048,1537 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-1.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2194716" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Devin Coldewey</p></div></p>
<p>The Nova3 Color has a 7.8-inch screen with the latest color e-paper tech from E Ink. I&#8217;ve always been excited for the possibilities of this side of the technology, but color e-paper screens have always suffered from poor contrast, low refresh speeds, ghosting and other shortcomings. While this latest iteration does go some way toward amending those (and a software update helped further), it is still unfortunately too much of a compromise.</p>
<p>The hardware is similar to the other Boox devices, solid and unassuming. The difference is all in the screen, which shows in color even when the device is off. Color e-paper works by combining the microscopic black and white beads that form images with a layer of color filters that can be changed. This one, like the others, has a frontlight and it helps a lot with making those colors pop, since without it they&#8217;re all rather muted.</p>
<p>There is still the issue of ghosting, though if you&#8217;re reading, say, a comic, you can easily set it to refresh every page (it takes only a fraction of a second) and the problem is gone. It&#8217;s less easy to do this with more dynamic content like a webpage, though of course navigating the web on an e-reader is already something of a novelty.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2194717" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-3.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2194717" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2194717" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-3.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-3.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-3.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-3.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-3.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-3.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-3.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-3.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-3.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2194717" class="wp-caption-text">The color e-paper display still lacks saturation, if not contrast. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Devin Coldewey</p></div></p>
<p>More troubling to me is the decrease in contrast and effective decrease in resolution that the color layer brings. When color content is shown, there&#8217;s a distinct screen door effect to it, not quite like ordinary LCD aliasing but still visible. And when you have greyscale content you sometimes see moire and other interference patterns in mid-tones.</p>
<p>Books look all right but not nearly as clear as an ordinary monochrome E Ink display; the screen door effect is always present and reduces contrast. It&#8217;s still very readable, but when cheaper devices do the job better, it&#8217;s hard to justify.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2194715" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-type.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2194715" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2194715 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-type.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="571" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-type.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-type.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-type.jpg?resize=300,167 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-type.jpg?resize=768,428 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-type.jpg?resize=680,379 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-type.jpg?resize=1536,856 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-type.jpg?resize=2048,1142 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/boox-nova3-color-type.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2194715" class="wp-caption-text">Text is less clear and high contrast on the color screen than on the monochrome one. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Devin Coldewey</p></div></p>
<p>I appreciate Boox making the latest screen from E Ink available, and it may be useful to some who want a little more tablet DNA in their e-reader (at this point the two categories are not very distinct). But for most people the color does not add enough, and subtracts too much.</p>
<h3>Does it all, or stretched too thin?</h3>
<p>The OS is the same on all of these as far as I can tell, but on the these devices the focus shifts to interactivity rather than simply reading. Boox makes a Wacom-like pen that can be used to write on the surface of these larger tablets, and it serves its purpose fine, though with nowhere near the responsiveness or accuracy of reMarkable&#8217;s.</p>
<p>That said, the final result when sketching or writing was a pleasing one, though the OS takes a moment to catch up and anti-alias the marks. I thought the brush in particular had nice gradations.</p>
<p>One thing the Boox tablets have on others like them (that is to say, the reMarkable, the defunct Sony Digital Paper Tablet and a handful of other niche devices) is in the PDF handling. The Boox devices let you navigate and mark up PDFs with ease, and the original files are simply saved over with your doodles and notes added. Though marking up a document is easy on the reMarkable, its slightly clumsy app makes sharing and sorting them a bit of a chore. I prefer the simple approach: modify the original file (there&#8217;s always a copy somewhere) and email it directly from the device. It&#8217;s that simple!</p>
<p>Besides the reader and notebook, there are a handful of included apps that any tablet user might find useful. There&#8217;s a browser that&#8217;s about as functional as you&#8217;d expect — it&#8217;s Chromium-based and renders well but ghosts terribly; a voice recorder, a music player, a calendar&#8230; and of course you could download plenty more from the built-in or Google app stores. If you wanted to, you could make these quite well-rounded devices.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not entirely sure just how large the market is for this kind of e-paper tablet. But I feel these devices offer something interesting and unique, even if they&#8217;re also&#8230; well, it&#8217;s hard to get around the fact that you can get an iPad for half the price of the larger Boox tablets, and then do most of the same stuff and more.</p>
<p>These e-paper devices have a certain draw, though, and if you plan to read and mark up long documents, it&#8217;s way better to do so on one of these than on an iPad, for a number of reasons. With Boox&#8217;s lineup in the mix there are more options than ever, and that&#8217;s definitely a good thing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/boox-tablets-are-welcome-options-in-the-growing-oversize-e-reader-niche/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2062122</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>After community backlash, Pokémon GO reinstates a COVID safety and accessibility feature</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/after-community-backlash-pokemon-go-reinstates-a-covid-safety-and-accessibility-feature/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/after-community-backlash-pokemon-go-reinstates-a-covid-safety-and-accessibility-feature/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 20:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Augmented Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[augmented reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[niantic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pokemon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pokémon Go]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2194393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pokémon GO announced yesterday that it will permanently keep an in-game feature that made the game easier to play while social distancing. Introduced at the onset of the COVID-19 pandemic, the feature doubled the interaction radius around key augmented reality landmarks that are essential to gameplay. Though Niantic &#8212; parent company to Pokémon GO &#8212; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Pokémon GO announced yesterday that it will permanently keep an in-game feature that made the game easier to play while social distancing. Introduced at the onset of the COVID-19 pandemic, the feature doubled the interaction radius around key augmented reality landmarks that are essential to gameplay. Though Niantic &#8212; parent company to Pokémon GO &#8212; removed the feature earlier this month, it chose to <a href="https://twitter.com/PokemonGoApp/status/1430644448929718274">permanently reinstate</a> it after weeks of community- and creator-led backlash.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Trainers &#8211; we’re looking forward to sharing our plans as a result of the task force on September 1, but one thing does not have to wait! From now on, 80 meters will be the base interaction radius for PokéStops and Gyms globally. (1/2)</p>
<p>&mdash; Pokémon GO (@PokemonGoApp) <a href="https://twitter.com/PokemonGoApp/status/1430644448929718274?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 25, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Pre-pandemic, Pokémon GO players needed to be within 40 meters of a PokéStop or Gym to interact with it, but with the now-permanent change, the radius is expanded to 80 meters. Incidentally, players with disabilities found that this feature made the game more accessible to people with limited mobility. As one of the first mainstream AR mobile games, Pokémon GO is virtually unplayable if you&#8217;re unable to travel to real-world landmarks like PokéStops and Gyms &#8212; so allowing users to interact with these landmarks from farther away (for example, if a wheelchair-user can&#8217;t journey off of a paved sidewalk) opened the game up to new players.</p>
<p>Because Pokémon GO has long positioned itself as a game that encourages real-world exploration, worldwide lockdowns posed a unique challenge for Niantic. But by making some <a href="https://nianticlabs.com/blog/stay-safe/">small changes</a> &#8212; like expanding the interaction radius by just 40 meters, increasing Pokémon spawns and making it easier to obtain more PokéBalls &#8212; the game became <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/28/how-niantic-evolved-pokemon-go-for-the-year-no-one-could-go-anywhere/">easier to play from home</a>.</p>
<p>These changes didn&#8217;t break the game or contradict its adventurous spirit, which made the rollback of a well-loved upgrade confusing for players, especially in light of the spreading Delta variant. From a financial standpoint, the app <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/28/how-niantic-evolved-pokemon-go-for-the-year-no-one-could-go-anywhere/">thrived during the pandemic</a>. In 2020, Pokémon GO had its best-earning year since its launch in 2016, earning <a href="https://sensortower.com/blog/pokemon-go-one-billion-revenue-2020">over $1 billion</a>. According to app analytics firm Sensor Tower, this upward trend continued for Pokémon GO in the first half of 2021, with $642 million. This marked a 34% increase in consumer spending compared to the first half of 2020, when it made $479 million.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Dear <a href="https://twitter.com/NianticLabs?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@NianticLabs</a> your community needs you to address the recent in-game changes to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/PokemonGO?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#PokemonGO</a>. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HearUsNiantic?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#HearUsNiantic</a> we love this game and the communities we&#39;ve built together. This game thrives on inclusivity and diversity. Show us you understand that. <a href="https://t.co/1N6EAaM5m2">pic.twitter.com/1N6EAaM5m2</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&mdash; ZoëTwoDots <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f380.png" alt="🎀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@_ZoeTwoDots) <a href="https://twitter.com/_ZoeTwoDots/status/1423282896094208002?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>After <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/pokemon-go-influencers-threaten-a-boycott-after-niantic-removes-covid-safety-measures/">Niantic reduced the interaction radius</a>, Pokémon GO content creators and community members worked together to write an open letter to Niantic, which caused the hashtag <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23HearUsNiantic">#HearUsNiantic</a> to <a href="https://youtu.be/FvDgphKkWiA?t=68">trend on Twitter</a>. The letter expressed that the increased radius made the game safer, more accessible and less intrusive.</p>
<p>Some players organized a boycott of the game on August 5th, which was referred to as &#8220;<a href="https://news.yahoo.com/pok-mon-tries-enticing-players-160000316.html">Pokémon No Day</a>.&#8221; That same day, Niantic issued <a href="https://nianticlabs.com/blog/pgo-exploration-bonus-response/?hl=en">a response letter </a>addressed to the Pokémon GO community.</p>
<p>&#8220;Encouraging people to explore, exercise and safely play together in person remains Niantic’s mission. The health and wellbeing of players is our top priority,&#8221; Niantic&#8217;s statement read. The company formed an &#8220;inter cross-functional team&#8221; to address these concerns and invited prominent Pokémon GO content creators to share community feedback. While expanding the interaction radius is the first result of the task force, Pokémon GO <a href="https://twitter.com/PokemonGoApp/status/1430644448929718274">tweeted</a> that it will share more findings on September 1.</p>
<p>TechCrunch asked Niantic why it initially chose to rebuke these gameplay updates despite positive community feedback, increased revenue and an ongoing pandemic, but Niantic declined to comment.</p>
<p>Despite players&#8217; visible negative response on social media, Sensor Tower told TechCrunch that it didn&#8217;t see any change in consumer spending or active users for Pokémon GO around the time of the in-game strike. However, there was a <a href="https://sensortower.com/ios/us/niantic-inc/app/pokemon-go/1094591345/overview">significant uptick</a> in negative App Store reviews.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Though the wider interaction radius is now reinstated, some players remain frustrated, since community leaders had previously provided this feedback </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://pokemongolive.com/post/hello-world-pokemon-go">in June</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> after Niantic announced its plans to roll back these changes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;Why did it have to take this giant community movement for any of our feedback to be heard?&#8221; said creator ZoëTwoDots in </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A6eBNFpRc8U&amp;">a YouTube video</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iJF1a0LpZD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/pokemon-go-influencers-threaten-a-boycott-after-niantic-removes-covid-safety-measures/">Pokémon GO influencers threaten a boycott after Niantic removes COVID safety measures</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pokémon GO influencers threaten a boycott after Niantic removes COVID safety measures&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/pokemon-go-influencers-threaten-a-boycott-after-niantic-removes-covid-safety-measures/embed/#?secret=iJF1a0LpZD" data-secret="iJF1a0LpZD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wAGOJgTcun"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/29/the-niantic-ec-1/">The Niantic EC-1</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Niantic EC-1&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/29/the-niantic-ec-1/embed/#?secret=wAGOJgTcun" data-secret="wAGOJgTcun" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/after-community-backlash-pokemon-go-reinstates-a-covid-safety-and-accessibility-feature/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2194393</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
