<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 14:01:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Two-year-old Day One Ventures raises new $52.5M fund to invest in Valley startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/two-year-old-day-one-ventures-raises-new-52-5m-fund-to-invest-in-valley-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/two-year-old-day-one-ventures-raises-new-52-5m-fund-to-invest-in-valley-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 14:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078056</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Back in 2018 Day One Ventures launched in Silicon Valley specifically designed to be both a VC and an investor that would also lead marketing and communications for its portfolio. Two years on, Day One has invested in numerous startups to do just that and has today filed with the SEC its new $52.5M fund. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/06/day-one-ventures-launches-fund-which-wraps-vc-and-pr-into-one/">Back in 2018</a> <a href="https://www.dayoneventures.com/">Day One Ventures</a> launched in Silicon Valley specifically designed to be both a VC <em>and</em> an investor that would also lead marketing and communications for its portfolio. Two years on, Day One has invested in numerous startups to do just that and has today filed with the SEC its new $52.5M fund.</p>
<p>The new fund is similar to the first one: investing across industries from pre-seed to seed, with occasional series A investments (from $100K to $5M).</p>
<p>The fund was founded and is headed by Russian émigré Masha Drokova, who, since arriving in the US a few years ago, has been variously a PR and angel investor, but <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-story-of-masha-drokova-a-putin-acolyte-turned-silicon-valley-investor-1494502202">famously dumped her former life</a> in Russia as a politician and TV reporter.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Drokova says the fund focuses on ‘day one’ companies, as defined by Jeff Bezos, which have &#8216;customer obsession&#8217; in-built into their company culture.</p>
<p>She says the fund was raised during the pandemic over zoom with $45 million coming from LPs in the first fund. More than 30% of the capital is invested in POC founders; it has 25 female founders in its portfolio; and 33% of its capital is invested in high-growth ‘impact’ companies. Day one has frequently co-invested with Andreessen, Index Ventures, Founders Fund, and Lightspeed.</p>
<p>The fund has had three exits so far: Lvl5, Acquired, Feastly and has invested in Remote.com (with Index and Sequoia).</p>
<p>So far among its portfolio is:</p>
<p>• <a href="https://donotpay.com/">DoNotPay</a>: British founder Joshua Browder, started a chatbot that pays your parking ticket, cancels subscriptions and gets refunds for you. This raised a $15M series A led by Coatue and Andreessen.<br />
• <a href="https://superhuman.com">Superhuman</a>: An AI-based email client for execs founded by Brit Rahul Vohra &#8211; it has raised $35M series B from Andreessen.<br />
• <a href="https://mschf.xyz">MSCHF</a>: This creates viral and controversial products on a Supreme-drop-like model, invested with Founders Fund.<br />
• <a href="https://www.truebill.com">Truebill</a>: a personal finance &amp; savings app.</p>
<p>The fund says its portfolio companies have now raised $825 million in aggregate; over 25% of its capital is in fintech companies; over 30% in AI-powered startups; and it claims to have hit over 500 media publications for its portfolio.</p>
<p>Speaking to TechCrunch, Drakova said &#8220;We choose startups with &#8216;customer obsession&#8217; as the main focus for selection. Secondly, our value add in communications means we have people like Jack Randall who did comms for Robin Hood on our team. Not many women immigrants to the US have raised as much as this, as fast as this. So it’s a good sign for the market.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/two-year-old-day-one-ventures-raises-new-52-5m-fund-to-invest-in-valley-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078056</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adobe expands customer data platform to include B2B sales</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/adobe-expands-customer-data-platform-to-encompass-b2b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/adobe-expands-customer-data-platform-to-encompass-b2b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 14:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[b2b sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Data Platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer experience management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078041</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The concept of the customer data platform (CDP) is a relatively new one. Up until now, it has focused primarily on pulling data about an individual consumer from a variety of channels into a super record, where in theory you can serve more meaningful content and deliver more customized experiences based on all this detailed [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The concept of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/26/adobe-and-salesforce-announce-customer-data-platforms-to-pull-data-into-single-view/">the customer data platform</a> (CDP) is a relatively new one. Up until now, it has focused primarily on pulling data about an individual consumer from a variety of channels into a super record, where in theory you can serve more meaningful content and deliver more customized experiences based on all this detailed knowledge. <a href="http://adobe.com">Adobe</a> announced its intention today to create such a product for business to business (B2B) customers, a key market where this kind of data consolidation had been missing.</p>
<p>Indeed Brian Glover, Adobe&#8217;s director of product marketing for Marketo Engage, who has been put in charge of this product, says that these kinds of sales are much more complex and B2B sales and marketing teams are clamoring for a CDP.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have spent the last couple of years integrating Marketo Engage across Adobe Experience Cloud, and now what we&#8217;re doing is building out the next generation of new and complimentary B2B offerings on the Experience platform, the first of which is the B2B CDP offering,&#8221; Glover told me.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He says that they face unique challenges adapting CDP for B2B sales because they typically involve buying groups, meaning you need to customize your messages for different people depending on their role in the process.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pBi4IP86uk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/26/adobe-and-salesforce-announce-customer-data-platforms-to-pull-data-into-single-view/">Adobe and Salesforce announce Customer Data Platforms to pull data into single view</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Adobe and Salesforce announce Customer Data Platforms to pull data into single view&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/26/adobe-and-salesforce-announce-customer-data-platforms-to-pull-data-into-single-view/embed/#?secret=pBi4IP86uk" data-secret="pBi4IP86uk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>An individual consumer usually knows what they want and you can prod them to make a decision and complete the purchase, but a B2B sale is usually longer and more complex involving different levels of procurement. For example, in a technology sale, it may involve the CIO, a group, division or department who will be using the tech, the finance department, legal and others. There may be an RFP and the sales cycle may span months or even years.</p>
<p>Adobe believes this kind of sale should still be able to use the same customized messaging approach you use in an individual sale, perhaps even more so because of the inherent complexity in the process. Yet B2B marketers face the same issues as their B2C counterparts when it comes to having data spread across an organization.</p>
<p>&#8220;In B2B that complexity of buying groups and accounts just adds another level to the data management problem because ultimately you need to be able to connect to your customer people data, but you also need to be able to connect the account data too and be able to [bring] the two together,&#8221; Glover explained.</p>
<p>By building a more complete picture of each individual in the buying cycle, you can, as Glover puts it, begin to put the bread crumbs together for the entire account. He believes that a CRM isn&#8217;t built for this kind of complexity and it requires a specialty tool like a CDP built to support B2B sales and marketing.</p>
<p>Adobe is working with early customers on the product and expects to go into beta before the end of next month with GA some time in the first half of next year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3F5TwTU893"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/20/adobe-gets-its-company-snaring-marketo-for-4-75-billion/">Adobe gets its company, snaring Marketo for $4.75 billion</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Adobe gets its company, snaring Marketo for $4.75 billion&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/20/adobe-gets-its-company-snaring-marketo-for-4-75-billion/embed/#?secret=3F5TwTU893" data-secret="3F5TwTU893" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/adobe-expands-customer-data-platform-to-encompass-b2b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078041</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India bans another 43 Chinese apps</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/india-bans-another-43-chinese-apps/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/india-bans-another-43-chinese-apps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 13:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PUBG Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078051</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[India is not done banning Chinese apps. The world’s second largest internet market, which has banned over 175 apps with links to the neighboring nation in recent months, said on Tuesday it was banning an additional 43 such apps. Like with the previous orders, India cited cybersecurity concerns to block these apps. “This action was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">India is not done banning Chinese apps. The world’s second largest internet market, which has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/india-bans-pubg-and-over-100-additional-chinese-apps/">banned over 175 apps with links to the neighboring nation in recent months</a>, said on Tuesday it was banning an additional 43 such apps.</p>
<p>Like with the previous orders, India <a href="https://www.pib.gov.in/PressReleasePage.aspx?PRID=1675335">cited</a> cybersecurity concerns to block these apps. “This action was taken based on the inputs regarding these apps for engaging in activities which are prejudicial to sovereignty and integrity of India, defence of India, security of state and public order,” said India’s IT Ministry in a statement.</p>
<p>The ministry said it issued the order of blocking these apps “based on the comprehensive reports received from Indian Cyber Crime Coordination Center, Ministry of Home Affairs.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The apps that have been banned include popular short video service Snack Video, which had surged to the top of the chart in recent months, as well as e-commerce app AliExpress, delivery app Lalamove, and shopping app Taobao Live. Full list <a href="https://www.pib.gov.in/PressReleasePage.aspx?PRID=1675335">here</a>. At this point, there doesn&#8217;t appear to be any Chinese app left in the top 500 apps used in India.</p>
<p>Tuesday order comes as a handful of apps including PUBG Mobile and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/tiktok" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="tiktok">TikTok <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> explore ways to make a return to the country. In recent weeks, PUBG has registered a local entity in India, partnered with Microsoft for computing needs, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/pubg-mobile-announces-return-to-india-new-game-100-million-investment/">publicly vowed to invest $100 million in the country</a>. Though it is yet to hear from the government.</p>
<p>Tensions between the world’s two most populous nations escalated after more than 20 Indian soldiers were killed in a military clash in the Himalayas in June. Ever since, “Boycott China” sentiment has trended on social media in India as a growing number of people post videos demonstrating destruction of Chinese-made smartphones, TVs and other products.</p>
<p>In April, India also made a change to its foreign investment policy that requires Chinese investors — who have ploughed billions of dollars into Indian startups in recent years — to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/18/to-avoid-hostile-takeovers-amid-covid-19-india-mandates-approvals-on-chinese-investments/">take approval from New Delhi</a> before they could write new checks to Indian firms. The move has significantly reduced Chinese investors’ presence in Indian startups’ deal flows in the months since.</p>
<p><em>More to follow&#8230;</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/india-bans-another-43-chinese-apps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078051</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 top investors in Dutch startups discuss trends, hopes and 2020 opportunities</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/5-top-investors-in-dutch-startups-discuss-trends-hopes-and-2020-opportunities/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/5-top-investors-in-dutch-startups-discuss-trends-hopes-and-2020-opportunities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 13:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amsterdam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deep tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unicorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vc survey]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Netherlands’ ecosystem has been flourishing; more than $85 million was invested in regional startups in 2019 alone. The nation&#8217;s proximity to the U.K., Belgium, France and Germany makes Amsterdam a natural gateway to those markets. Long ago the savvy Dutch realized this, and built up Schiphol to become the world&#8217;s twelfth-busiest airport. Indeed, Amsterdam’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Netherlands’ ecosystem has been flourishing; more than $85 million was invested in regional startups in 2019 alone. The nation&#8217;s proximity to the U.K., Belgium, France and Germany makes Amsterdam a natural gateway to those markets. Long ago the savvy Dutch realized this, and built up Schiphol to become the world&#8217;s twelfth-busiest airport. Indeed, Amsterdam’s logistical and social connectedness is ranked number one in DHL’s Global Connectedness Index.</p>
<p>Plenty of good funding rounds, a highly skilled workforce and a strong entrepreneurial culture have given Amsterdam a booming startup ecosystem. And Brexit is helping: The Dutch are highly proficient in English and Dutch law is similar to English law, which means U.K.-based tech founders are welcomed with open arms.</p>
<p>In 2020, the venture industry continued to invest in startups, despite the COVID-19 crisis. According to <a href="https://nltimes.nl/2020/10/25/venture-capitalists-still-investing-startups-despite-covid-crisis">a study by KPMG and and NL Times</a>, startups raised $591.2 million in the third quarter, more than double the $252.4 million raised in the quarter before.</p>
<p>For obvious reasons, this year has seen more cash go into companies that were able to adapt to the pandemic. KPMG found that while the total amount of investment increased in the past six months, the number of overall investments decreased. New startups pulled in fewer investments, KPMG sees this trend continuing and likely leading to consolidation amongst startups in similar sectors.</p>
<p>According to a report by Dealroom.co and StartupAmsterdam, there are 1,661 tech companies in Amsterdam, while the city ranked fifteenth in Startup Genome’s 2019 report “Global Startup Ecosystem Report,” moving up four places since 2017. The median seed round is $500,000 (above the global average of $494,000) and a median Series A round for a startup is $2.4 million. The average salary for a software engineer is around €54,000.</p>
<p>Amsterdam has tech industry &#8220;schools&#8221; such as <a href="https://growthtribe.io/en/">Growth Tribe</a>, <a href="https://www.thetalentinstitute.nl/">The Talent Institute</a> and THNK for educational courses, as well as accelerators like Rockstart, Startupbootcamp and <a href="https://fashionforgood.com/">Fashion for Good</a>. Co-working is well-catered for with TQ, Startup Village and B.Amsterdam, and workers can cycle everywhere in minutes.</p>
<p>While taxes are high, entrepreneurs won&#8217;t find the staggering income inequality so often seen in cities like San Francisco and New York. In Amsterdam, rich people take public transport, not private buses.</p>
<p>During COVID-19, the Dutch government has also announced support packages such as tax deferrals, temporary employment bridging schemes and other initiatives. It also launched a national program, <a href="http://TechLeap.NL">TechLeap.NL</a>, to boost the ecosystem with more international investor visibility. StartupDelta, a Dutch startup lobby group, keeps the pressure on the politicians.</p>
<p>The Netherlands&#8217; most famous unicorns include Booking.com, Adyen, Virtuagym, MessageBird, Swapfiets, Backbase, Picnic and Takeaway, among several others.</p>
<p>Adyen launched in 2006, and in June 2018, it was listed as one of Europe’s largest tech IPOs with a value of €7 billion. Booking.com started in 1996 and was later acquired by Priceline Group (now called Booking Holdings) in 2005. Elastic, the provider of subscription-based data search software used by Dell, Netflix, The New York Times and others, was another gangbuster IPO in 2018.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">For this survey, we interviewed the following Amsterdam-focused investors:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">• Janneke Niessen, partner, </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://capitaltvc.com">CapitalT VC</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stefanvanduin">• Stefan van Duin</a>, partner, <a href="http://Borskifund.com">Borski Fund</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/nikos-kalliagkopoulos">• Nick Kalliagkopoulos</a>, partner, <a href="http://www.primeventures.com">Prime Ventures</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/bas-godska">• Bas Godska</a>, founder, <a href="http://www.acrobator.vc">Acrobator Ventures</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/renaat-berckmoes">• Renaat Berckmoes</a>, partner, <a href="https://www.fortino.be/">Fortino</a></p>
<h4></h4>
<h2>Janneke Niessen, partner, CapitalT VC</h2>
<p><strong>What trends are you most excited about investing in, generally?</strong><br />
Digital health, education, B2B SaaS.</p>
<p><strong>What’s your latest, most exciting investment?</strong><br />
Wizenoze.</p>
<p><strong>Are there startups that you wish you would see in the industry but don’t? What are some overlooked opportunities right now?</strong><br />
More overlooked founders than opportunities.</p>
<p><strong>What are you looking for in your next investment, in general?</strong><br />
A great team.</p>
<p><strong>Which areas are either oversaturated or would be too hard to compete in at this point for a new startup? What other types of products/services are you wary or concerned about?</strong><br />
Delivery, taxis, scooters.</p>
<p><strong>How much are you focused on investing in your local ecosystem versus other startup hubs (or everywhere) in general? More than 50%? Less?</strong><br />
Less.</p>
<p><strong>Which industries in your city and region seem well-positioned to thrive, or not, long term? What are companies you are excited about (your portfolio or not), which founders?</strong><br />
NL seems well-positioned for fintech, deep tech. I am really excited about Tracy Chou and Diane Janknegt, two incredible founders.</p>
<p><strong>How should investors in other cities think about the overall investment climate and opportunities in your city?</strong><br />
Very positive. Lots of innovation, great infrastructure, good talent.<br />
<strong>Do you expect to see a surge in more founders coming from geographies outside major cities in the years to come, with startup hubs losing people due to the pandemic and lingering concerns, plus the attraction of remote work?</strong><br />
I think startups have always been there, investors just don&#8217;t tend to look at them. I think the opportunity is more that they now will.</p>
<p><strong>Which industry segments that you invest in look weaker or more exposed to potential shifts in consumer and business behavior because of COVID-19? What are the opportunities startups may be able to tap into during these unprecedented times?</strong><br />
None. We look at digital health, education and SaaS and they all thrive in this climate. Of course an economic crisis will have an impact on spending in general.</p>
<p><strong>How has COVID-19 impacted your investment strategy? What are the biggest worries of the founders in your portfolio? What is your advice to startups in your portfolio right now?</strong><br />
It has confirmed our approach. We have a data-driven approach to teams, which is great when people cannot meet.</p>
<p><strong>Are you seeing “green shoots” regarding revenue growth, retention or other momentum in your portfolio as they adapt to the pandemic?</strong><br />
We invest so early that companies are growing regardless.</p>
<p><strong>What is a moment that has given you hope in the last month or so? This can be professional, personal or a mix of the two.</strong><br />
When I explained to my little boy what racism is and he answered: Mummy that is just really weird. That gives me hope that the generations after us might do better.</p>
<h2>Stefan van Duin, partner, Borski Fund<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/5-top-investors-in-dutch-startups-discuss-trends-hopes-and-2020-opportunities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077454</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Europe&#8217;s data strategy aims to tip the scales away from big tech</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/europes-data-strategy-aims-to-tip-the-scales-away-from-big-tech/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/europes-data-strategy-aims-to-tip-the-scales-away-from-big-tech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Governance Act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital Markets Act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital Services Act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EU data strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thierry-breton]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077991</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google wants to organize the world&#8217;s information but European lawmakers are in a rush to organize the local digital sphere and make Europe &#8220;the most data-empowered continent in the world&#8221;, internal market commissioner Thierry Breton said today, setting out the thinking behind the bloc&#8217;s data strategy during a livestreamed discussion organized by the Brussels-based economic think tank, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google wants to organize the world&#8217;s information but European lawmakers are in a rush to organize the local digital sphere and make Europe &#8220;the most data-empowered continent in the world&#8221;, internal market commissioner <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/thierry-breton" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="thierry-breton">Thierry Breton <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> said today, setting out the thinking behind the bloc&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/europe-sets-out-plan-to-boost-data-reuse-and-regulate-high-risk-ais/">data strategy</a> during a <a href="https://vimeo.com/481139367">livestreamed discussion</a> organized by the Brussels-based economic think tank, <a href="https://www.bruegel.org">Bruegel</a>.</p>
<p>Rebalancing big data power dynamics to tip the scales away from big tech is another stated aim.</p>
<p>Breton likened the EU&#8217;s ambitious push to encourage industrial data sharing and rebalance platform power to work done in the past to organize the region&#8217;s air space and other physical infrastructure &#8212; albeit, with a lot less time to get the job done given the blistering pace of digital innovation.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;This will require of course political vision &#8212; that we have &#8212; and willingness, that I believe we have too, and smart regulation, hopefully you will judge, to set the right rules and investment in key infrastructure,&#8221; said Breton.</p>
<p>During the talk, he gave a detailed overview of how the flotilla of legislative proposals which are being worked on by EU lawmakers will set rules intended to support European businesses and governments to safely unlock the value of industrial and public data and drive the next decades of economic growth.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have been brave enough to set our rules in the personal data sphere and this is what we need to do now for government and public and industrial data. Set the rules. The European rules. Everyone will be welcome in Europe, that&#8217;s extremely important &#8212; provided they respect our rules,&#8221; said Breton.</p>
<p>&#8220;We don&#8217;t have one minute to lose,&#8221; he added. &#8220;The battle for industrial data is starting now and the battlefield may be Europe so we need to get ready &#8212; and this is my objective.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QTF7owq2zw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/europe-sets-out-plan-to-boost-data-reuse-and-regulate-high-risk-ais/">Europe sets out plan to boost data reuse and regulate &#8216;high risk&#8217; AIs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe sets out plan to boost data reuse and regulate &#8216;high risk&#8217; AIs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/europe-sets-out-plan-to-boost-data-reuse-and-regulate-high-risk-ais/embed/#?secret=QTF7owq2zw" data-secret="QTF7owq2zw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>EU lawmakers are drafting rules for how (non-personal) data can be used and shared; who will get access to them; and how rights can be guaranteed under the framework, per Breton. And he argued that <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">concerns raised by European privacy challenges to international data transfers &#8212; reflected in the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/16/europes-top-court-strikes-down-flagship-eu-us-data-transfer-mechanism/">recent Schrems II ruling</a> &#8212; are not limited to privacy and personal data. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;These worries are in fact at the heart of the Single Market for data that I am building,&#8221; he said. &#8220;These worries are clear in the world we are entering when individuals or companies want to keep control over its data. The key question is, therefore, how to organize this control while allowing data flow &#8212; which is extremely important in the data economy.&#8221;</p>
<p>An open single European market for data must recognize that not all data are the same &#8212; &#8220;in terms of their sensitivity&#8221; &#8212; Breton emphasized, pointing to the EU&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (<a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/gdpr" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="gdpr">GDPR) <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> data protection framework as &#8220;the proof of that&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;Going forward, there are also sensitive industrial data that should benefit from specific conditions when they are accessed, used or shared,&#8221; he went on. &#8220;This is a case for instance for some sensitive public data [such as] from public hospitals, but also anonymized data that remains sensitive, mixed data which are difficult to handle.&#8221;</p>
<p>At one point during the talk he gave the example of European hospitals during the pandemic not being able to share data across borders to help in the fight against the virus because of the lack of a purpose-built framework to securely enable such data flows.</p>
<p>&#8220;I want our SMEs and startups, our public hospitals, our cities and many other actors to use more data &#8212; to make them available, to value them, to share them &#8212; but for this we need to generate the trust,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>The first legislative plank of the transformation to a single European data economy is a Data Governance Act (DGA) &#8212; which Breton said EU lawmakers will present tomorrow, after a vote on the proposal this afternoon.</p>
<p>&#8220;With this act we are defining a European approach to data sharing,&#8221; he noted on the DGA. &#8220;This new regulation will facilitate data sharing across sectors and Member States. And it will put those who generate the data in the driving seat &#8212; moving away from the current practices of the big tech platforms.</p>
<p>&#8220;Concretely, with this legislation, we create the conditions to allow access to a reuse of sensitive public data, creating a body of harmonized rules for the single market.&#8221;</p>
<p>A key component of building the necessary trust for the data economy will mean creating rules that state &#8220;European highly sensitive data <em>should</em> be able to be stored and processed in the EU&#8221;, Breton also said, signalling that data localization will be a core component of the strategy &#8212; in line with<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> a number of <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/breton-wants-tiktok-data-to-stay-in-europe/">recent public remarks</a> in which he&#8217;s argued it&#8217;s not protectionist for European data to be stored in Europe. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;Without such a possibility Member States will never agree to open their data hold,&#8221; Breton went on, saying that while Europe will be &#8220;open&#8221; with data, it will not be offering a &#8220;naive&#8221; data free-for-all.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2g8FGOKcFi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/11/europe-puts-out-advice-on-fixing-international-data-transfers-thats-cold-comfort-for-facebook/">Europe puts out advice on fixing international data transfers that&#8217;s cold comfort for Facebook</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe puts out advice on fixing international data transfers that&#8217;s cold comfort for Facebook&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/11/europe-puts-out-advice-on-fixing-international-data-transfers-thats-cold-comfort-for-facebook/embed/#?secret=2g8FGOKcFi" data-secret="2g8FGOKcFi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The Commission also wants the data framework to support an ecosystem of data brokers whose role Breton said will be to connect data owners and data users &#8220;in a neutral manner&#8221; &#8212; suggesting this will empower companies to have stronger control over the data they generate, (i.e the implication being rather than the current situation where data-mining platform giants can use their market power to asset-strip weaker third parties).</p>
<p>&#8220;We are shifting here the product,&#8221; he said. &#8220;And we promote also data altruism &#8212; the role of sharing data, industrial or personal, for common good.&#8221;</p>
<p>Breton also noted that the forthcoming data governance proposal will include a shielding provision &#8212; meaning data actors will be required to take steps to avoid having to comply with what he called &#8220;abusive and unlawful&#8221; data access requests for data held in Europe from third countries.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is a major point. It is not a question of calling into question our international judicial or policy cooperation. We cannot tolerate abuses,&#8221; he said, specifying three off-limits examples (&#8220;unauthorized access; access that do offer sufficient legal guarantees; or fishing expeditions), adding: &#8220;By doing so we are ensuring that European law and the guarantees it carries is respected. This is about enforcing our own rules.&#8221;</p>
<p>Breton also touched on other interlocking elements of the policy strategy which regional lawmakers see as crucial to delivering a functional data framework: Namely the Digital Services Act (DSA) and Digital Markets Act (DMA) &#8212; which are both due to be set out in detail early next month.</p>
<p>The DSA will put &#8220;a clear responsibility and obligation on platforms and the content that is spread&#8221;, said Breton.</p>
<p>While the companion <em>ex ante</em> regulation, the DMA, will &#8220;frame the behaviours of gatekeepers &#8212; of systemic actors in the Single Market &#8212; and target their behaviors against their competitors or customers&#8221;; aka further helping to pin and clip the wings of big tech.</p>
<p>&#8220;With this set of regulation I just want to set up the rules and that the rules are clear &#8212; based on our values,&#8221; he added.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="amZmo0mRzN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/europe-to-limit-how-big-tech-can-push-its-own-services-and-use-third-party-data/">Europe to limit how big tech can push its own services and use third-party data</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe to limit how big tech can push its own services and use third-party data&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/europe-to-limit-how-big-tech-can-push-its-own-services-and-use-third-party-data/embed/#?secret=amZmo0mRzN" data-secret="amZmo0mRzN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>He also confirmed that interoperability and portability will be a key feature of the EU&#8217;s hoped for data transformation.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are working on this on several strands,&#8221; he said on this. &#8220;The first is standards for interoperability. That&#8217;s absolutely key for sectoral data spaces that we will create and very important for the data flows. You will see that we will create a European innovation data board &#8212; set in the DGA today &#8212; which will help the Commission in setting and working the right standards.&#8221;</p>
<p>While combating &#8220;blocking efforts and abusive behaviors&#8221; by platform gatekeepers &#8212; which could otherwise put an artificial limit on the value of the data economy &#8212; will be &#8220;the job of the DMA&#8221;, he noted.</p>
<p>A fourth pillar of the data strategy &#8212; which Breton referred to as a &#8220;data act&#8221; &#8212; will be introduced in 2021, with the aim of &#8220;increasing fairness in the data economy by clarifying data usage rights in business to business and business to government settings&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;We will also consider enhanced data portability rights to give individuals more control &#8212; which is extremely important &#8212; over the data they produce,&#8221; he added. &#8220;And we will have a look at the intellectual property rights framework.&#8221;</p>
<p>He also noted that key infrastructure investments will be vital &#8212; pointing to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/europe-will-go-it-alone-on-digital-tax-reform-in-2021-if-it-must-says-eu-president-as-bloc-directs-e150bn-in-covid-19-relief-toward-cloud-ai-and-broadband/">Commission&#8217;s plan</a> to build a European industrial cloud and related <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/07/tech-driven-change-a-key-priority-for-new-ec-president/">strategic tech investment priorities</a> such as in compute power capacity, building out next-gen connectivity and support for cutting edges technologies like quantum encryption.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xJ0qhpDHTP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/europe-will-go-it-alone-on-digital-tax-reform-in-2021-if-it-must-says-eu-president-as-bloc-directs-e150bn-in-covid-19-relief-toward-cloud-ai-and-broadband/">Europe will go it alone on digital tax reform in 2021 if it must, says EU president, as bloc directs €150BN in COVID-19 relief toward cloud, AI and broadband</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe will go it alone on digital tax reform in 2021 if it must, says EU president, as bloc directs €150BN in COVID-19 relief toward cloud, AI and broadband&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/europe-will-go-it-alone-on-digital-tax-reform-in-2021-if-it-must-says-eu-president-as-bloc-directs-e150bn-in-covid-19-relief-toward-cloud-ai-and-broadband/embed/#?secret=xJ0qhpDHTP" data-secret="xJ0qhpDHTP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Privacy campaigner Max Schrems, who had been invited as the other guest speaker, raised the issue of enforceability &#8212; pointing out that Ireland&#8217;s data protection authority, which is responsible for overseeing a large number of major tech companies in the region, still hasn&#8217;t issued any decisions on cross-border complaints filed under the 2.5 year old GDPR framework.</p>
<p>Breton agreed that enforcement will be a vital piece of the puzzle &#8212; claiming EU lawmakers are alive to the problem of enforcement &#8220;bottlenecks&#8221; in the GDPR.</p>
<p>&#8220;We need definitely clear, predictable, implementable rules &#8212; and this is what is driving me when I am regulating against the data market. But also what you will find behind the DSA and the DMA with an ex ante regulation to be able to apply it immediately and everywhere in Europe, not only in one country, everywhere at the same time,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Just to be able to make sure that things are happening quick. In this digital space we have to be fast.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;So we will again make sure in DSA that Member State authorities can ask platforms to remove immediately content cross-border &#8212; like, for example, if you want an immediate comparison, the European Arrest Warrant.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Commission will also have the power to step in via cooperation at the European level, Breton further noted.</p>
<p>&#8220;So you see we are putting in rules, we are not naive, we understand pretty well where we have the bottleneck &#8212; and again we try to regulate. And also, in parallel, that&#8217;s very important because like everywhere where you have regulation you need to have sanctions &#8212; you will have appropriate sanctions,&#8221; he said, adding: &#8220;We learn the lessons from the GDPR.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RzlwSx0W8I"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/">GDPR&#8217;s two-year review flags lack of &#8216;vigorous&#8217; enforcement</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GDPR&#8217;s two-year review flags lack of &#8216;vigorous&#8217; enforcement&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/embed/#?secret=RzlwSx0W8I" data-secret="RzlwSx0W8I" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/europes-data-strategy-aims-to-tip-the-scales-away-from-big-tech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077991</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Looking to emulate Venmo, JoomPay preps a Euro launch for easy bill splitting and cash payments</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/looking-to-emulate-venmo-joompay-preps-a-euro-launch-for-easy-bill-splitting-and-cash-payments/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/looking-to-emulate-venmo-joompay-preps-a-euro-launch-for-easy-bill-splitting-and-cash-payments/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 12:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monzo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[N26]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peer to peer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Revolut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venmo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078012</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[JoomPay, a startup with a similar product to PayPayl-owned Venmo in the US, is set to launch in Europe shortly after being granted a Luxembourg Electronic Money Institution (EMI) license. The app allows people to send and receive money with anyone, instantly and for free. “Venmo me” has become a common phrase in the US, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://joompay.com/">JoomPay</a>, a startup with a similar product to PayPayl-owned Venmo in the US, is set to launch in Europe shortly after being granted a Luxembourg Electronic Money Institution (EMI) license. The app allows people to send and receive money with anyone, instantly and for free. “<a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/venmo" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="venmo">Venmo <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> me” has become a common phrase in the US, where people use it to split bills in restaurants or similar. Venmo is in common use in the US, but it’s not available in Europe, although dozens of other innovative mobile peer to peer transfer options exist, such as Revolut, N26, Monese and Monzo. The waitlist for the app&#8217;s beta is open now (<a href="https://apps.apple.com/mt/app/joompay-mobile-finance/id1480381529">iOS</a>, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.joompay.wallet&#038;hl=en&#038;gl=US">Android</a>).</p>
<p>Europe leads the world&#8217;s instant payments industry, with $18 trillion in worldwide volume predicted by 2025 up from $3 trillion in 2020 – a growth of over 500%. Western Europe &#8211; and COVID-19 &#8211; is now driving that innovation and will account for 38% of instant payment transaction value by 2025. While Europe lacks simple peer-to-peer payments solutions such as <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/venmo" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="venmo">Venmo <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> or Square Cash App in the US, challenger banks have stepped up to provide similar kinds of services. JoomPay’s opportunity lies in being able to be a middle-man between these various banking systems.</p>
<p>Shopping app <a href="http://Joom.com">Joom</a>, which has been downloaded 150M times in Europe, has spun-off JoomPay to solve this problem. The app allows users to send and receive money from any person, regardless of whether they use JoomPay or not – and you only need to know their email or the phone number. JoomPay connects to any existing debit/credit card or a bank account. It also provides its users with a European IBAN and an optional free JoomPay card with cashback and bonuses.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Yuri Alekseev, CEO and co-founder of JoomPay, said: &#8220;Since COVID-19 started, we’ve seen a significant decline in cash usage. People can’t meet as easily as before but still need to send money, and we offer a viable alternative.”</p>
<p>JoomPay may have an uphill struggle. Its main competitors in Europe are the huge TransferWise, Paysend, and of course <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/paypal" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="paypal">PayPal <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> itself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/looking-to-emulate-venmo-joompay-preps-a-euro-launch-for-easy-bill-splitting-and-cash-payments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078012</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New TikTok feature allows users to avoid videos with epileptic seizure triggers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/new-tiktok-feature-allows-users-to-avoid-videos-with-epileptic-seizure-triggers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/new-tiktok-feature-allows-users-to-avoid-videos-with-epileptic-seizure-triggers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 12:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accessibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photosensitive epilepsy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seizures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TikTok announced today it is rolling out a new feature that will allow people with photosensitive epilepsy to automatically skip videos that can trigger seizures. The &#8220;Skip All&#8221; option will be introduced to all users over the next few weeks and comes a few months after TikTok began automatically warning creators if a video contains [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/tiktok" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="tiktok">TikTok <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/making-tiktok-more-accessible-to-people-with-photosensitive-epilepsy">announced</a> today it is rolling out a new feature that will allow people with photosensitive epilepsy to automatically skip videos that can trigger seizures.</p>
<p>The &#8220;Skip All&#8221; option will be introduced to all users over the next few weeks and comes a few months after TikTok began automatically warning creators if a video contains effects, like flashing lights or certain visual patterns, that can be harmful to people with photosensitive epilepsy. If they upload those videos, TikTok automatically prefaces them with a warning screen.</p>
<p>Once a user turns on the &#8220;Skip All&#8221; option, they won&#8217;t see any videos TikTok has identified as potential triggers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2077978" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Photosensitivity-Warning.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2077978" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2077978 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Photosensitivity-Warning.png?w=314" alt="TikTok's warning for videos with content that can trigger epileptic seizures" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Photosensitivity-Warning.png 750w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Photosensitivity-Warning.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Photosensitivity-Warning.png?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Photosensitivity-Warning.png?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Photosensitivity-Warning.png?resize=709,1536 709w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Photosensitivity-Warning.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2077978" class="wp-caption-text">TikTok&#8217;s warning for videos with content that can trigger epileptic seizures</p></div></p>
<p>According to the Epilepsy Foundation, one of several organizations TikTok consulted with, the condition affects about 65 million people worldwide.</p>
<p>While <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-47943607">advocates have called on social media platforms</a>, including YouTube and Facebook, to place warnings before content with potential triggers, the task often falls to individual creators. For example, if a video has flashing lights, they might mention that at the beginning or in its description. But not all creators are aware of photosensitive epilepsy or its triggers.</p>
<p>Furthermore, online trolls have posted harmful content on purpose, sometimes tagging them with keywords related to epilepsy. The Epilepsy Society, another organization that worked with TikTok, <a href="https://www.epilepsysociety.org.uk/zachslaw">has called for malicious posts</a> to be covered by the United Kingdom’s Online Harms bill.</p>
<p>In a statement published with TikTok’s announcement, Nicola Swanborough, the Epilepsy Society’s acting head of external affairs, said &#8220;social media can be a lifeline for many people with epilepsy, allowing them to connect with others with the condition from around the world,&#8221; and that the organization hopes &#8220;other platforms will follow TikTok’s lead in ensuring greater inclusivity.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/new-tiktok-feature-allows-users-to-avoid-videos-with-epileptic-seizure-triggers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077971</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Industrial drone maker Percepto raises $45M and integrates with Boston Dynamics&#8217; Spot</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/industrial-drone-maker-percepto-raises-45m-and-integrates-with-boston-dynamics-spot/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/industrial-drone-maker-percepto-raises-45m-and-integrates-with-boston-dynamics-spot/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 11:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[industrial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[industrial drones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[percepto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPOT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077990</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Consumer drones have over the years struggled with an image of being no more than expensive and delicate toys. But applications in industrial, military and enterprise scenarios have shown that there is indeed a market for unmanned aerial vehicles, and today, a startup that makes drones for some of those latter purposes is announcing a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Consumer drones have over the years struggled with an image of being no more than expensive and delicate toys. But applications in industrial, military and enterprise scenarios have shown that there is indeed a market for unmanned aerial vehicles, and today, a startup that makes drones for some of those latter purposes is announcing a large round of funding and a partnership that provides a picture of how the drone industry will look in years to come.</p>
<p><a href="http://percepto.co" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Percepto</a>, which makes drones &#8212; both the hardware and software &#8212; to monitor and analyze industrial sites and other physical work areas largely unattended by people, has raised $45 million in a Series B round of funding.</p>
<p>Alongside this, it is now working with <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/boston-dynamics" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="boston-dynamics">Boston Dynamics  <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and has integrated its Spot robots with Percepto&#8217;s Sparrow drones, with the aim being better infrastructure assessments, and potentially more as Spot&#8217;s agility improves.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The funding is being led by a strategic backer, <a href="https://www.kochind.com/companies/koch-disruptive-technologies" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Koch Disruptive Technologies</a>, the investment arm of industrial giant <a href="https://www.kochind.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Koch Industries</a> (which has interests in energy, minerals, chemicals and related areas), with participation also from new investors State of Mind Ventures, Atento Capital, Summit Peak Investments, Delek-US. Previous investors U.S. Venture Partners, Spider Capital and Arkin Holdings also participated. (It appears that Boston Dynamics and SoftBank are not part of this investment.)</p>
<p>Israel-based Percepto has now raised $72.5 million since it was founded in 2014, and it&#8217;s not disclosing its valuation, but CEO and founder Dor Abuhasira described as &#8220;a very good round.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;It gives us the ability to create a category leader,&#8221; Abuhasira said in an interview. It has customers in around 10 countries, with the list including ENEL, Florida Power and Light and Verizon.</p>
<p>While some drone makers have focused on building hardware, and others are working specifically on the analytics, computer vision and other critical technology that needs to be in place on the software side for drones to work correctly and safely, Percepto has taken what I referred to, and Abuhasira confirmed, as the &#8220;Apple approach&#8221;: vertical integration as far as Percepto can take it on its own.</p>
<p>That has included hiring teams with specializations in AI, computer vision, navigation and analytics as well as those strong in industrial hardware &#8212; all strong areas in the Israel tech landscape, by virtue of it being so closely tied with its military investments. (Note: Percepto does not make its own chips: these are currently acquired from Nvidia, he confirmed to me.)</p>
<p>&#8220;The Apple approach is the only one that works in drones,&#8221; he said. &#8220;That&#8217;s because it is all still too complicated. For those offering an Android-style approach, there are cracks in the complete flow.&#8221;</p>
<p>It presents the product as a &#8220;drone-in-a-box&#8221;, which means in part that those buying it have little work to do to set it up to work, but also refers to how it works: its drones leave the box to make a flight to collect data, and then return to the box to recharge and transfer more information, alongside the data that is picked up in real time.</p>
<p>The drones themselves operate on an on-demand basis: they fly in part for regular monitoring, to detect changes that could point to issues; and they can also be launched to collect data as a result of engineers requesting information. The product is marketed by Percepto as &#8220;AIM&#8221;, short for autonomous site inspection and monitoring.</p>
<p>News broke last week that Amazon has been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/amazons-drone-delivery-team-hit-with-layoffs-amid-reorganization/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reorganising</a> its Prime Air efforts &#8212; one sign of how some more consumer-facing business applications &#8212; despite many developments &#8212; may still have some turbulence ahead before they are commercially viable. Businesses like Percepto&#8217;s stand in contrast to that, with their focus specifically on flying over, and collecting data, in areas where there are precisely no people present.</p>
<p>It has dovetailed with a bigger focus from industries on the efficiencies (and cost savings) you can get with automation, which in turn has become the centerpiece of how industry is investing in the buzz phrase of the moment, &#8220;digital transformation.&#8221;</p>
<p>“We believe Percepto AIM addresses a multi-billion-dollar issue for numerous industries and will change the way manufacturing sites are managed in the IoT, Industry 4.0 era,” said Chase Koch, President of Koch Disruptive Technologies, in a statement. “Percepto’s track record in autonomous technology and data analytics is impressive, and we believe it is uniquely positioned to deliver the remote operations center of the future. We look forward to partnering with the Percepto team to make this happen.”</p>
<p>The partnership with Boston Dynamics is notable for a couple of reasons: it speaks to how various robotics hardware will work together in tandem in an automated, unmanned world; and it speaks to how Boston Dynamics is pulling up its socks.</p>
<p>On the latter front, the company has been making waves in the world of robotics for years, specifically with its agile and strong dog-like (with names like &#8220;Spot&#8221; and &#8220;Big Dog&#8221;) robots that can cover rugged terrains and handle tussles without falling apart.</p>
<p>That led it into the arms of Google, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/12/14/google-buys-boston-dynamics-creator-of-big-dog/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">acquired it</a> as part of its own secretive moonshot efforts, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/12/14/google-buys-boston-dynamics-creator-of-big-dog/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in 2013</a>. That never panned out into a business, and probably gave Google more complicated optics at a time when it was already being seen as too powerful. Then, SoftBank stepped in to pick it up, along with other robotics assets, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/08/softbank-is-buying-robotics-firm-boston-dynamics-and-schaft-from-alphabet/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in 2017</a>. That hasn&#8217;t really gone anywhere either, it seems, and just this month it was reported that Boston Dynamics was reportedly facing yet another suitor, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/hyundai-reportedly-in-talks-to-buy-softbank-owned-boston-dynamics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hyundai</a>.</p>
<p>All of this is to say that partnerships with third parties that are going places (quite literally) become strong signs of how Boston Dynamics&#8217; extensive R&amp;D investments might finally pay off with enterprising dividends.</p>
<p>Indeed, while Percepto has focused on its own vertical integration, longer term and more generally there is an argument to be made for more interoperability and collaboration between the various companies building &#8220;connected&#8221; and smart hardware for industrial, physical applications.</p>
<p>It means that specific industries can focus on the special equipment and expertise they require, while at the same time complementing that with hardware and software that are recognised as best-in-class. Abuhasira said that he expects the Boston Dynamics partnership to be the first of many.</p>
<p>That makes this first one an interesting template. The partnership will see Spot carrying Percepto’s payloads for high resolution imaging and thermal vision &#8220;to detect issues including hot spots on machines or electrical conductors, water and steam leaks around plants and equipment with degraded performance, with the data relayed via AIM.&#8221; It will also mean a more thorough picture, beyond what you get from the air. And, potentially, you might imagine a time in the future when the data that the combined devices source, results even in Spot (or perhaps a third piece of autonomous hardware) carrying out repairs or other assistance.</p>
<p>“Combining Percepto’s Sparrow drone with Spot creates a unique solution for remote inspection,” said Michael Perry, VP of Business Development at Boston Dynamics, in a statement. “This partnership demonstrates the value of harnessing robotic collaborations and the insurmountable benefits to worker safety and cost savings that robotics can bring to industries that involve hazardous or remote work.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/industrial-drone-maker-percepto-raises-45m-and-integrates-with-boston-dynamics-spot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077990</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calling VCs in Israel: Be featured in The Great TechCrunch Survey of European VC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/calling-vcs-in-israel-be-featured-in-the-great-techcrunch-survey-of-european-vc/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/calling-vcs-in-israel-be-featured-in-the-great-techcrunch-survey-of-european-vc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 11:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077995</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TechCrunch is embarking on a major new project to survey the venture capital investors of Europe, and their cities. Our &#60;a href=&#8221;https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6”>survey of VCs in Israel will capture how the country is faring, and what changes are being wrought amongst investors by the coronavirus pandemic. The Israeli VC eco-system is closely aligned with the European [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TechCrunch is embarking on a major new project to <a href="https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6">survey</a> the venture capital investors of Europe, and their cities.</p>
<p>Our &lt;a href=&#8221;https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6”>survey of VCs in Israel will capture how the country is faring, and what changes are being wrought amongst investors by the coronavirus pandemic. The Israeli VC eco-system is closely aligned with the European one, with many VCs co-investing with VCs in Israel, hence their inclusion in this survey.</p>
<p>We’d like to know how Israel&#8217;s startup scene is evolving, how the tech sector is being impacted by COVID-19, and, generally, how your thinking will evolve from here.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Our survey will only be about investors, and <strong>only the contributions of VC investors will be included.</strong> More than one partner is welcome to fill out the survey. (Please note, if you have filled the survey out already, there is no need to do it again).</p>
<p>The shortlist of questions will require only brief responses, but the more you can add, the better.</p>
<p><a href="https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6"><strong>You can fill out the survey here.</strong></a></p>
<p>Obviously, investors who contribute will be featured in the final surveys, with links to their companies and profiles.</p>
<p>What kinds of things do we want to know? Questions include: Which trends are you most excited by? What startup do you wish someone would create? Where are the overlooked opportunities? What are you looking for in your next investment, in general? How is your local ecosystem going? And how has COVID-19 impacted your investment strategy?</p>
<p>This survey is part of a broader <a href="https://techcrunch.com/extra-crunch/investor-surveys/">series of surveys</a> we’re doing to help founders find the right investors.</p>
<p>https://techcrunch.com/extra-crunch/investor-surveys/</p>
<p>For example, here is the recent <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/14-vcs-discuss-covid-19-and-londons-future-as-a-tech-hub/">survey of London</a>.</p>
<p>You are not in Israel, but would like to take part? That&#8217;s fine! Any European VC investor can STILL fill out the survey, as we probably will be putting a call out to your country next anyway! And we will use the data for future surveys on vertical topics.</p>
<p>The survey is covering almost every country on in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Union_for_the_Mediterranean">Union for the Mediterranean</a>, so just look for your country and city on the <a href="https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6">survey</a> and please participate (<em>if</em> you&#8217;re a venture capital investor).</p>
<p>Thank you for participating. If you have questions you can email mike@techcrunch.com</p>
<p>(Please note: Filling out the survey is not a guarantee of inclusion in the final published piece).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/calling-vcs-in-israel-be-featured-in-the-great-techcrunch-survey-of-european-vc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077995</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kahoot drops $50M on Drops to add language learning to its gamified education stable</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/kahoot-drops-50m-on-drops-to-add-language-learning-to-its-gamified-education-stable/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/kahoot-drops-50m-on-drops-to-add-language-learning-to-its-gamified-education-stable/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 09:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kahoot!]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Languages]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After raising $215 million from SoftBank to double down on the surge of interest in online learning, Kahoot has made an acquisition to expand the scope of subjects that it covers. The popular startup, which lets people build and share educational games, has picked up Drops, a startup that helps people learn languages by way [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After raising <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/13/kahoot-picks-up-215m-from-softbank-for-its-user-generated-gamified-e-learning-platform/">$215 million from SoftBank</a> to double down on the surge of interest in online learning, Kahoot has made an acquisition to expand the scope of subjects that it covers. The popular startup, which lets people build and share educational games, has picked up Drops, a startup that helps people learn languages by way of short picture- and word-based games. The plan is to integrate more Kahoot features into <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/drops-8841" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="drops-8841">Drops&#8217; <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> apps, and to bring some of Drops&#8217; content into the main Kahoot platform.</p>
<p>Kahoot, which trades a part of its shares through Norway&#8217;s alternative exchange the Merkur Market and currently has a <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/KAHOOT-ME.OL?p=KAHOOT-ME.OL&amp;.tsrc=fin-srch" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">market cap of over $3 billion</a>, said in an <a href="https://kahoot.com/press/2020/11/24/kahoot-acquires-drops-to-make-language-learning-awesome/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">announcement</a> that it would pay $31 million in cash, plus up to $19 million more in cash and shares, based on Drops meeting certain targets between now and 2022. The deal is expected to close this month, and is the company&#8217;s biggest to date.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Drops makes three main apps. First in an eponymous freemium app, with free and paid features, that helps adults learn new languages, currently some 42 in all, with a focus on vocabulary, built around five-minute, &#8220;snackable&#8221; sessions. A second app, Scripts, is aimed at learning to read, write and sign, and it covers four alphabets and four character-based writing systems. A third, Droplets, is aimed specifically at language learning for learners aged between eight and 17. Altogether Drops has clocked up 25 million users.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Notably, one reason it might be off TechCrunch&#8217;s (and the startup world&#8217;s) radar is that it was bootstrapped. (It did go through an accelerator, <a href="http://www.gamefounders.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GameFounders</a>.) But it has had some notable accolades, including getting named app of the year by Google in 2018.</span></p>
<p>The startup was founded in Estonia and has 21 employees with no &#8220;head office&#8221; as such, with the team spread across Estonia, US, UK, Spain, Italy, France, Germany, Sweden, the Netherlands, Hungary, Ukraine and Russia. This could be one reason why it&#8217;s kept costs low: in 2019 it reported gross revenues of $7.5 million (€6.3 million), with cash conversion of 40%.</p>
<p>For some more context, Kahoot &#8212; which is also backed by the likes of Microsoft, Disney and Northzone &#8212; says that in the last 12 months, more than 1 billion participating players in over 200 countries attended over 200 million Kahoot! sessions. That figure includes both educational users of its free services, as well as enterprises, which pay to build and use games (for example related to professional development or business compliance) on the platform.</p>
<p>“We are thrilled to welcome Drops to the expanding Kahoot! family as we advance towards our vision to become the leading learning platform in the world,” said Eilert Hanoa, the CEO of Kahoot, in a statement. “Drops’ offerings and innovative learning model are a perfect match to Kahoot!’s mission of making learning awesome through a simple, game-based approach. Drops and language learning becomes the latest addition to our growing offering of learning apps for learners of all ages and abilities. We will continue to expand in new areas to make Kahoot! the ultimate learning destination, at home, school or work, and to make learning awesome!”</p>
<p>The Covid-19 pandemic has led to a bonanza for educational apps, which are collectively seeing a huge rush of usage in the last year.</p>
<p>For students, educators and parents, they have become a way of connecting and teaching at a time when physical schools are either closed, or drastically curtailed in what they can do, in order to help limit the spread of the novel coronavirus.</p>
<p>Businesses and other organizations, on the other hand, are leaning on e-learning as a way of keeping connected with staff, engaging them, and training them at a time when many are working from home.</p>
<p>It might seem ironic that at a time when travel has been drastically limited, if not completely halted altogether, for many of us, that language learning has seen an especially big boom.</p>
<p>Maybe it&#8217;s about making hay &#8212; that is, using the moment to get yourself ready for a time in the future when you might actually get to use your newly acquired foreign language skills. Or maybe it&#8217;s just another option for distracting or occupying ourselves in a more constructive way. Whatever might be the motivation or cause, the effect is that language learning is on the up.</p>
<p>Most recently, Duolingo &#8212; which incidentally also uses game-based concepts, where you enter a leaderboard for your learning and your daily sessions become winning streaks &#8212; raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/language-learning-app-duolingo-confirms-it-has-raised-35m-on-a-2-4b-valuation/\" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$35 million on a $2.4 billion valuation</a>, a huge jump for the company.</p>
<p>Kahoot cites <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/948857/digital-language-learning-global-market-size-language/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">figures</a> that predict that digital language learning will be an $8 billion+ market by 2025 as describes Drops as &#8220;one of the fastest-growing language platforms in the world.&#8221;</p>
<p>“The entire Drops team has spent the last five years building a new way to learn language, and we’re just getting started,” said Daniel Farkas, co-founder and CEO, Drops, in a statement. “We’ve introduced millions of users across the globe to our playful, dynamic approach to language learning. Kahoot! is doing the same for all types of learning. We’re excited to work with such a mission-aligned company to introduce the Drops platform to game-loving learners everywhere.”</p>
<p>This is Kahoot&#8217;s <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/kahoot-/company_financials" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">fourth acquisition</a>, and its biggest to date. As with Drops, previous M&amp;A deals were made to bolt on new areas of expertise to the platform, such <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/08/educational-gaming-platform-kahoot-acquires-math-app-maker-dragonbox-for-18m/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">maths learning</a> for students and more tools to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/user-generated-e-learning-site-kahoot-acquires-actimo-for-up-to-33m-to-double-down-on-corporate-sector/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">manage enterprise users</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/kahoot-drops-50m-on-drops-to-add-language-learning-to-its-gamified-education-stable/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077983</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Caura, the app for U.K. car owners, begins offering insurance</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/caura-protect/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/caura-protect/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 09:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Caura app]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077416</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Caura, the U.K. startup that wants to take the hassle out of car ownership, is launching car insurance &#8212; unveiling its insurtech ambitions. Dubbed &#8220;Caura Protect,&#8221; the new insurance product claims to reduce the cost and time taken to insure a car, building on the app&#8217;s existing car management features. Launched earlier this year by [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://caura.com/">Caura</a>, the U.K. startup that wants to take the hassle out of car ownership, is launching car insurance &#8212; unveiling its insurtech ambitions.</p>
<p>Dubbed &#8220;Caura Protect,&#8221; the new insurance product claims to reduce the cost and time taken to insure a car, building on the app&#8217;s existing car management features.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/22/caura/">Launched earlier this year</a> by Sai Lakshmi, who previously co-founded medication management service Echo, Caura is a mobile app designed to manage all of the vehicle-related admin that car owners endure.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Drivers are on-boarded by entering their vehicle registration number and can manage parking, tolls, MOT, road tax, congestion charges, and now insurance  — a “one-stop shop” app in a similar vein to Echo. The idea is that Caura minimises car ownership admin and helps to mitigate associated penalty fines.</p>
<p>Caura is FCA approved to undergo various insurance activities and enables drivers to compare insurers and manage their policy within the app. The startup also says it has redesigned the signup and verification process to significantly reduce the time needed to find the best insurance policy.</p>
<p>&#8220;Caura instantly verifies users against official sources like the DVLA, simplifying the experience, and reducing the risk of insurance fraud,&#8221; says the company.</p>
<p>The idea is to offer a much more user-friendly insurance search and buying process than is typical of price comparison websites that ask for a multiple page questionnaire to be filled out before sending you &#8212; the &#8220;prospect&#8221; &#8212; to the insurer to complete your purchase. Instead, Caura claims that users can research options, select a quote, pay, and be covered to drive in around a minute (if you navigate the app really fast, I&#8217;m assuming).</p>
<p>The insurance cover itself is provided by six of the leading U.K. insurers, including Aviva and Markerstudy.  In early 2021, Caura users will be able to pay for insurance in monthly instalments.</p>
<p>Asked why no one seems to have made shopping around for car insurance quite so straightforward, Lakshmi tells TechCrunch: &#8220;Startups in insurtech have been so busy finding niches that they&#8217;ve forgotten to innovate for the mainstream consumer&#8221;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/caura-protect/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077416</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google-backed Chinese truck-hailing firm Manbang raises $1.7 billion</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/manbang-1-7-billion-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/manbang-1-7-billion-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 07:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[huochebang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manbang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[truck hailing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vision Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunmanman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077946</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Chinese Uber for trucks Manbang announced Tuesday that it has raised $1.7 billion in its latest funding round, two years after it hauled in $1.9 billion from investors including SoftBank Group and Alphabet Inc&#8217;s venture capital fund CapitalG. The news came fresh off a Wall Street Journal report two weeks ago that Manbang was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Chinese Uber for trucks Manbang announced Tuesday that it has raised $1.7 billion in its latest funding round, two years after it <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-china-truck-idUSKBN1HV0ON">hauled in $1.9 billion</a> from investors including SoftBank Group and Alphabet Inc&#8217;s venture capital fund CapitalG.</p>
<p>The news came fresh off a <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/chinas-uber-for-trucks-raising-1-7-billion-ahead-of-ipo-next-year-11604996654">Wall Street Journal report</a> two weeks ago that Manbang was seeking $1 billion ahead of an initial public offering next year. The company declined to comment on the matter, though its CEO Zhang Hui <a href="https://tech.sina.com.cn/i/2019-05-28/doc-ihvhiqay1843937.shtml">said</a> in May 2019 that the firm was &#8220;not in a rush&#8221; to go public.</p>
<p>Manbang said it achieved profitability this year. Its valuation was <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/chinese-truck-hailing-app-on-course-for-10-billion-valuation-1533726603">reportedly</a> on course to reach $10 billion in 2018.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company, which runs an app matching truck drivers and merchants transporting cargo and provides financial services to truckers, was formed from a <a href="http://www.huochebang.cn/about">merger</a> between rivals Yunmanman and Huochebang in 2017. It was a time when China&#8217;s &#8220;sharing economy&#8221; craze began to see consolidation and shakeup.</p>
<p>The latest financing again attracted high-profile backers, including returning investors <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/softbank" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="softbank">SoftBank <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Vision Fund and Sequoia Capital China, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/permira">Permira</a> and Fidelity, a consortium that co-led the round. Other participants were Hillhouse Capital, GGV Capital, Lightspeed China Partners, Tencent, Jack Ma&#8217;s YF Capital and more.</p>
<p>The company has other Alibaba ties. Its CEO Zhang, who founded <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/yunmanman" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="yunmanman">Yunmanman, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> hailed from Alibaba&#8217;s famed B2B department where Manbang chairman Wang Gang also worked before he went on to fund ride-hailing giant Didi&#8217;s angel round.</p>
<p>Manbang claims its platform has over 10 million verified drivers and 5 million cargo owners. The latest funding will allow it to further invest in research and development, upgrade its matching system, and expand its service capacity to functions like door-to-door transportation.</p>
<p>Sequoia is quite bullish about truck-hailing as it made its sixth investment in Manbang. For Permira, a European private equity fund, the Manbang investment marked the China debut of its <a href="https://www.permira.cn/news-views/%E6%96%B0%E9%97%BB/%E7%92%9E%E7%B1%B3%E8%B5%84%E6%9C%AC%E6%88%90%E5%8A%9F%E4%B8%BA%E4%B8%83%E5%8F%B7%E5%9F%BA%E9%87%91%E5%8B%9F%E9%9B%86110%E4%BA%BF%E6%AC%A7%E5%85%83/">Growth Opportunities Fund</a>.</p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/manbang-1-7-billion-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077946</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>N26 launches mid-tier subscription plan for €4.90 per month</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/n26-launches-mid-tier-subscription-plan-for-e4-90-per-month/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/n26-launches-mid-tier-subscription-plan-for-e4-90-per-month/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 05:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[challenger bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[N26]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[N26 Smart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neobank]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077559</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Challenger bank N26 is adding a third subscription product called N26 Smart. N26 Smart is designed to be a mid-tier subscription plan with advanced banking features but without a travel insurance package. In Europe, in addition to the free plan, N26 already provides two subscription tiers called N26 You and N26 Metal. N26 You costs [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Challenger bank <a href="https://n26.com">N26</a> is adding a third subscription product called <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/n26" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="n26">N26 <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Smart. N26 Smart is designed to be a mid-tier subscription plan with advanced banking features but without a travel insurance package.</p>
<p>In Europe, in addition to the free plan, N26 already provides two subscription tiers called N26 You and N26 Metal. N26 You costs €9.90 per month and comes with higher limits, such as five free ATM withdrawals instead of three and free withdrawals in foreign currencies.</p>
<p>With an N26 You account, you can create sub-accounts (N26 Spaces), share them with other N26 users or use them to save money. As an N26 You subscriber, you also get a travel insurance package with medical travel insurance, trip and flight insurance and more. You can also access some partner offers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>N26 Metal is the most expensive plan and costs €16.90 per month. In addition to everything in N26 You, you get car rental insurance when you’re abroad and phone insurance. As the name suggests, you also get a metal card.</p>
<p>The new N26 Smart subscription costs €4.90 and works well for people who don’t need travel insurance. With an N26 Smart subscription, you can create up to ten sub-accounts. You get five free ATM withdrawals per month. You can also call N26 support directly in addition to in-app support chat.</p>
<p>N26 is launching a new round-up feature for N26 Smart users. It lets you round each purchase up to the nearest Europe and save it in a separate sub-account. N26 Smart account also access colorful debit cards —&nbsp;the same colors as N26 You.</p>
<p>This is just a first step as N26 plans to revamp its subscription products altogether. In the near future, N26 You will become N26 International. There will be more features focused on borderless banking. N26 Metal will become N26 Unlimited.</p>
<p>As for the free N26 Standard account, the company wants to focus on digital cards. Some users are going to switch to the N26 Smart plan to keep some of the features that they’ve been using with a free account. That move should help the company’s bottom line.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2077654" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2077654" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/N26-Smart.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" class="size-full wp-image-2077654" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/N26-Smart.jpg 1601w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/N26-Smart.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/N26-Smart.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/N26-Smart.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/N26-Smart.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/N26-Smart.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/N26-Smart.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2077654" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> N26</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/n26-launches-mid-tier-subscription-plan-for-e4-90-per-month/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077559</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biden-Harris team finally get their transition .gov domain</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/biden-harris-finally-get-their-transition-gov-domain/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/biden-harris-finally-get-their-transition-gov-domain/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 04:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[head]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe Biden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michigan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trump]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077950</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Finally. It only took almost three weeks, but the Biden-Harris transition has officially begun. On Monday, the General Services Administration gave the green light for the Biden-Harris team to transition from political campaign to government administration, allowing the team to receive government resources like office space, but also classified briefings and secure computers. And, with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Finally. It only took almost three weeks, but the Biden-Harris transition has officially begun.</p>
<p>On Monday, the General Services Administration gave the green light for the Biden-Harris team to transition from political campaign to government administration, allowing the team to receive government resources like office space, but also classified briefings and secure computers. And, with it, comes a shiny new <code>.gov</code> domain.</p>
<p>Transitioning is an obscure part of the law that&#8217;s rarely discussed, in large part because outgoing governments and incoming administrations largely get on and try to maintain continuity of government through a peaceful transition of power. The process is formally triggered by the <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">General Services Administration, the lesser-known federal agency tasked with the basic functioning of government, and allows the incoming administration to receive funds, tools, and resources to prepare for entering government.</span></p>
<p>But this time around, the agency&#8217;s head Emily Murphy had <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">been reluctant to trigger the formal transition period after the Trump campaign filed a number of lawsuits challenging the election.</span></p>
<p>Murphy finally approved the transition on Monday after Michigan certified its election results.</p>
<p>Up until now, the Biden-Harris team <code>buildbackbetter.com </code>to host its transition website. Now it&#8217;s hosted at <code>buildbackbetter.gov</code>, a departure from the <code>ptt.gov</code> domain used by the incoming Obama-Biden administration in 2008.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/biden-team-lacks-full-u-s-cybersecurity-support-in-transition-fracas-11605891470">Wall Street Journal reported last week</a> that until now the Biden-Harris team was using a Google Workspace for email and collaboration, secured with hardware security keys that staff need to log into their accounts. That setup might suffice for an enterprise, but had security experts worried that the lack of government cybersecurity support could make the camp more vulnerable to attacks.</p>
<p>As for the domain, which you might not think much about, the shift to a <code>.gov</code> domain marks a significant step forwards in the camp&#8217;s cybersecurity efforts. Government domains, hosted on the <code>.gov</code> domain, are <a href="https://digital.gov/2018/10/29/gsa-steps-up-security-for-dotgov/">toughened</a> to prevent against domain hijacking or spoofing. In simple terms, they&#8217;re far more resilient than your regular web hosting services.</p>
<p>Biden tweeted out the domain marking the change.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="und" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/6aIgLN2bMk">https://t.co/6aIgLN2bMk</a></p>
<p>&mdash; <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/joseph-biden" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="joseph-biden">Joe Biden <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> (@JoeBiden) <a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBiden/status/1331071296235507713?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 24, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/biden-harris-finally-get-their-transition-gov-domain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077950</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Recycling robotics company AMP Robotics could raise up to $70M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/recycling-robotics-company-amp-robotics-could-raise-up-to-70-million-sources-say/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/recycling-robotics-company-amp-robotics-could-raise-up-to-70-million-sources-say/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 02:31:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amp+]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colorado]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[denver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[materials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[matter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michigan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Minnesota]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pepsi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recycling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sidewalk Infrastructure Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sidewalk labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starbucks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toronto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virginia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wisconsin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077917</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[AMP Robotics, the recycling robotics technology developer backed by investors including Sequoia Capital and Sidewalk Infrastructure Partners, is close to closing on as much as $70 million in new financing, according to multiple sources with knowledge of the company&#8217;s plans. The new financing speaks to AMP Robotics&#8217; continued success in pilot projects and with new [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.amprobotics.com/">AMP Robotics</a>, the recycling robotics technology developer backed by investors including <a href="https://www.amprobotics.com/newsroom/2019/11/21/amp-robotics-raises-16-million-series-a-led-by-sequoia-capital-joining-alphabet-backed-sidewalk-infrastructure-partners-and-leaders-in-sustainable-investing">Sequoia Capital and Sidewalk Infrastructure Partners</a>, is close to closing on as much as $70 million in new financing, according to multiple sources with knowledge of the company&#8217;s plans.</p>
<p>The new financing speaks to AMP Robotics&#8217; continued success in pilot projects and with new partnerships that are exponentially expanding the company&#8217;s deployments.</p>
<p>Earlier this month the company announced a new deal that represented<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/sequoia-backed-recycling-robot-maker-amp-robotics-gets-its-largest-purchase-order/"> its largest purchase order</a> for its trash sorting and recycling robots.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DYLZz5VhRG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/sequoia-backed-recycling-robot-maker-amp-robotics-gets-its-largest-purchase-order/">Sequoia-backed recycling robot maker AMP Robotics gets its largest purchase order</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Sequoia-backed recycling robot maker AMP Robotics gets its largest purchase order&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/sequoia-backed-recycling-robot-maker-amp-robotics-gets-its-largest-purchase-order/embed/#?secret=DYLZz5VhRG" data-secret="DYLZz5VhRG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That order, for 24 machine learning-enabled robotic recycling systems with the waste handling company Waste Connections, was a showcase for the efficacy of the company&#8217;s recycling technology.</p>
<p>That comes on the back of a pilot program earlier in the year with one Toronto apartment complex, where the complex&#8217;s tenants were able to opt into a program that would share recycling habits monitored by AMP Robotics with the building&#8217;s renters in an effort to improve their recycling behavior.</p>
<p>The potential benefits of AMP <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/robot-a0fd" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="robot-a0fd">Robotic&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> machine learning enabled robots are undeniable. The company&#8217;s technology can sort waste streams in ways that traditional systems never could and at a cost that&#8217;s far lower than most waste handling facilities.</p>
<p>As TechCrunch reported earlier the tech can tell the difference between high-density polyethylene and polyethylene terephthalate, low-density polyethylene, polypropylene and polystyrene. The robots can also sort for color, clarity, opacity and shapes like lids, tubs, clamshells and cups — the robots can even identify the brands on packaging.</p>
<p>AMP’s robots already have been deployed in North America, Asia and Europe, with recent installations in Spain and across the U.S. in California, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/colorado" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="colorado">Colorado, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Florida, Minnesota, Michigan, New York, Texas, Virginia and Wisconsin.</p>
<p>At the beginning of the year, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/amp-robotics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-type="organization" data-entity="amp-robotics">AMP Robotics </a> worked with its investor, <a href="https://www.sidewalklabs.com/">Sidewalk Labs</a> on a pilot program that provided residents of a single apartment building representing 250 units in Toronto with detailed information about their recycling habits. <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/sidewalk-labs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-type="organization" data-entity="sidewalk-labs">Sidewalk Labs</a> is transporting the waste to a Canada Fibers material recovery facility where trash is sorted by both Canada Fibers employees and AMP Robotics.</p>
<p>Once the waste is categorized, sorted and recorded, Sidewalk communicates with residents of the building about how they’re doing in their recycling efforts.</p>
<p>It was only last November that the Denver-based AMP Robotics raised a $16 million round from <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/sequoia-capital" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="sequoia-capital">Sequoia Capital <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and others to finance the early commercialization of its technology.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="f4qUk7b0RO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/14/recycling-robots-raise-millions-from-top-venture-firms-to-rescue-an-industry-in-turmoil/">Recycling robots raise millions from top venture firms to rescue an industry in turmoil</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Recycling robots raise millions from top venture firms to rescue an industry in turmoil&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/14/recycling-robots-raise-millions-from-top-venture-firms-to-rescue-an-industry-in-turmoil/embed/#?secret=f4qUk7b0RO" data-secret="f4qUk7b0RO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<p>As TechCrunch reported at the time, recycling businesses used to be able to rely on China to buy up any waste stream (no matter the quality of the material). However, about two years ago, <a href="https://e360.yale.edu/features/piling-up-how-chinas-ban-on-importing-waste-has-stalled-global-recycling">China decided it would no longer serve as the world’s garbage dump</a> and put strict standards in place for the kinds of raw materials it would be willing to receive from other countries.</p>
<p>The result has been higher costs at recycling facilities, which actually are now required to sort their garbage more effectively. At the time, unemployment rates put the squeeze on labor availability at facilities where trash was sorted. Over the past year, the COVID-19 pandemic has put even more pressure on those recycling and waste handling facilities, despite their identification as &#8220;essential workers&#8221;.</p>
<p>Given the economic reality, recyclers are turning to AMP’s technology — a combination of computer vision, machine learning and robotic automation to improve efficiencies at their facilities.</p>
<p>And, the power of AMP&#8217;s technology to identify waste products in a stream has other benefits, according to chief executive Matanya Horowitz.</p>
<p>“We can identify… whether it’s a Coke or Pepsi can or a <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/starbucks" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="starbucks">Starbucks <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> cup,” Horowitz told TechCrunch last year. “So that people can help design their product for circularity… we’re building out our reporting capabilities and that, to them, is something that is of high interest.”</p>
<p>AMP Robotics declined to comment for this article.</p>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/recycling-robotics-company-amp-robotics-could-raise-up-to-70-million-sources-say/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077917</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>YC-backed Cashfree raises $35.3 million for its payments platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/yc-backed-cashfree-raises-35-3-million-for-its-payments-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/yc-backed-cashfree-raises-35-3-million-for-its-payments-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 02:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apis Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BigBasket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cashfree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Razorpay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zomato]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077855</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cashfree, an Indian startup that offers a wide-range of payments services to businesses, has raised $35.3 million in a new financing round as the profitable firm looks to broaden its offering. The Bangalore-based startup’s Series B was led by London-headquartered private equity firm Apis Partners (which invested through its Growth Fund II), with participation from [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/cashfree" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="cashfree">Cashfree, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> an Indian startup that offers a wide-range of payments services to businesses, has raised $35.3 million in a new financing round as the profitable firm looks to broaden its offering.</p>
<p>The Bangalore-based startup’s Series B was led by London-headquartered private equity firm <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/apis-partners" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="apis-partners">Apis Partners <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> (which invested through its Growth Fund II), with participation from existing investors <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/y-combinator" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="y-combinator">Y Combinator <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Smilegate Investments. The new round brings the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/09/cashfree-raises-5-5m/">startup’s to-date raise to $42 million</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cashfree.com/">Cashfree</a> kickstarted its journey in 2015 as a solution for restaurants in Bangalore that needed an efficient way for their delivery personnel to collect cash from customers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Akash Sinha and Reeju Datta, the founders of Cashfree, did not have any prior experience with payments. When their merchants asked if they could build a service to accept payments online, the founders quickly realized that Cashfree could serve a wider purpose.</p>
<p>In the early days, Cashfree also struggled to court investors, many of whom did not think a payments processing firm could grow big &#8212; and do so fast enough. But the startup’s fate changed after Y Combinator accepted its application, even though the founders had missed the deadline and couldn’t arrive to join the batch on time. Y Combinator later financed Cashfree’s seed round.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sriWt2GXTp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/15/setu-raises-15m-to-help-developers-connect-with-banks-to-offer-indians-sachet-sized-financial-products/">Setu raises $15M to help developers connect with banks to offer Indians &#8216;sachet-sized&#8217; financial products</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Setu raises $15M to help developers connect with banks to offer Indians &#8216;sachet-sized&#8217; financial products&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/15/setu-raises-15m-to-help-developers-connect-with-banks-to-offer-indians-sachet-sized-financial-products/embed/#?secret=sriWt2GXTp" data-secret="sriWt2GXTp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Fast-forward five years, Cashfree today offers more than a dozen products and services and helps over 55,000 businesses disburse salary to employees, accept payments online, set up recurring payments and settle marketplace commissions.</p>
<p>Some of its customers include financial services startup Cred, online grocer <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/bigbasket-com" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="bigbasket-com">BigBasket, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> food delivery platform <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/zomato" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="zomato">Zomato, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> insurers HDFC Ergo and Acko and travel ticketing service provider Ixigo. The startup works with several banks and also offers integrations with platforms such as Shopify, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/paypal" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="paypal">PayPal <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Amazon Pay.</p>
<p>Based on its offerings, Cashfree today competes with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/15/setu-raises-15m-to-help-developers-connect-with-banks-to-offer-indians-sachet-sized-financial-products/">scores</a> of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/11/razorpay-100-million-billion-valuation-unicorn/">startups</a>, but it has an edge &#8212; if not many. Cashfree has been profitable for the past three years, Sinha, who serves as the startup’s chief executive, told TechCrunch in an interview.</p>
<p>“Cashfree has maintained a leadership position in this space and is now going through a period of rapid growth fuelled by the development of unique and innovative products that serve the needs of its customers,” Udayan Goyal, co-founder and a managing partner at Apis, said in a statement.</p>
<p>The startup processed over $12 billion in payments volumes in the financial year that ended in March. Sinha said part of the fresh fund will be deployed in R&amp;D so that Cashfree can scale its technology stack and build more services, including those that can digitize more offline payments for its clients.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jxBbcKVUic"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/11/razorpay-100-million-billion-valuation-unicorn/">India&#8217;s Razorpay becomes unicorn after new $100 million funding round</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;India&#8217;s Razorpay becomes unicorn after new $100 million funding round&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/11/razorpay-100-million-billion-valuation-unicorn/embed/#?secret=jxBbcKVUic" data-secret="jxBbcKVUic" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Cashfree is also working on building cross-border payments solutions to explore opportunities in emerging markets, he said.</p>
<p>“We still see payments as an evolving industry with its own challenges and we would be investing in next-gen payments as well as banking tech to make payments processing easier and more reliable. With the solid foundation of in-house technologies, tech-driven processes and in-depth industry knowledge, we are confident of growing Cashfree to be the leader in the payments space in India and internationally,” he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/yc-backed-cashfree-raises-35-3-million-for-its-payments-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077855</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AliveCor, which helps its users manage their heart health, scores another FDA approval</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/alivecor-which-helps-its-users-manage-their-heart-health-scores-another-fda-approval/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/alivecor-which-helps-its-users-manage-their-heart-health-scores-another-fda-approval/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 01:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AliveCor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ECG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Khosla Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qualcomm Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WP Global Partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2076918</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last week, AliveCor, a nine-year-old, 92-person company whose small, personal electrocardiogram devices help users detect atrial fibrillation, bradycardia, and tachycardia from heart rate readings taken from their own kitchen tables, raised $65 million from investors. Today, it&#8217;s clearer why investors &#8212; who&#8217;ve now provided the Mountain View, Ca., company with $169 million altogether &#8212;  are [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last week, <a href="https://www.alivecor.com/">AliveCor</a>, a nine-year-old, 92-person company whose small, personal electrocardiogram devices help users detect atrial fibrillation, bradycardia, and tachycardia from heart rate readings taken from their own kitchen tables, raised $65 million from investors.</p>
<p>Today, it&#8217;s clearer why investors &#8212; who&#8217;ve now provided the Mountain View, Ca., company with $169 million altogether &#8212;  are excited about its prospects. <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/alivecor" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="alivecor">AliveCor <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> just received its newest FDA clearance under the agency&#8217;s <a href="https://www.fda.gov/medical-devices/digital-health-center-excellence/software-medical-device-samd">software as a medical device </a>designation for an upgrade that generates enough detail and fidelity that AliveCor says its cardiological services can now serve as stand-in for the vast majority of cases when cardiac patients are not in front of their doctor.</p>
<p>Specifically, the company says the FDA-cleared update can detect premature atrial contractions, premature ventricular contractions, sinus rhythm with wide QRS.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In a world where the pandemic continues to rage and people remain hesitant to visit a hospital, these little steps add up. In fact, CEO Priya Abani, along with AliveCor founder and chief medical officer David Albert, formerly the chief clinical scientist of cardiology at GE, say AliveCor&#8217;s &#8220;Kardia&#8221; devices have been used to record nearly 15 million EKG recordings since March of this year, which is up over 70% year-over-year.</p>
<p>They also claim a 25% increase year-over-year in what they call physician-patient connections, meaning doctors specifically asking their patients to use the device, either at their medical office or at the patient&#8217;s home. Indeed, the pair says that while the company has focused historically on consumer sales, so much new business is coming through doctor referrals that roughly one out of every two of its devices is now sold through these recommendations.</p>
<p>Patients still need to pay out of pocket for AliveCor&#8217;s personal EKG devices, one of which currently sells for $89 while a more sophisticated model sells for $139.</p>
<p>The company also more recently rolled out a subscription product for $99 per year that &#8220;unlocks&#8221; additional features, including monthly summaries of a customer&#8217;s heart data, and hopefully soon, says Abani, access to cardiologists who will be able to answer questions in lieu of one&#8217;s own cardiologist.</p>
<p>Abani &#8212; who joined AliveCor last year from Amazon, where she was a general manager and director of Alexa &#8212; says other offerings are also in the works that should help customers measure their hypertension and blood pressure. She adds that the company more broadly sees itself as becoming a way for people to manage chronic conditions from home and that, if things go AliveCor&#8217;s way, employers will begin offering the service to employees as a way for them to take better care of their own heart health.</p>
<p>In the meantime, AliveCor&#8217;s bigger push into the enterprise appears tied not only to COVID and its ripple effects but also to competition on the consumer front from Apple Watch, which also now enables wearers to records the electrical pulses that make one&#8217;s heart beat and to determine whether the upper and lower chambers are their heart are in rhythm.</p>
<p>Though AliveCor has sung Apple&#8217;s praises for raising awareness around heart health, last year owing to shrinking sales, AliveCor stopped making an earlier product called the KardiaBand that was an FDA-cleared ECG wristband designed for use with Apple Watches.</p>
<p>AliveCor&#8217;s products are currently sold in 12 countries, including India, South Korea, and Germany, and it has clearance to sell in more than 37 altogether.</p>
<p>In addition to selling directly to customers through its site, its devices are available to buy through Best Buy, CVS, and Walgreens.</p>
<p>Very worth noting: Neither Apple nor AliveCor can detect actual heart attacks. While both can detect atrial fibrillation, acute heart attacks are not associated with atrial fibrillation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/alivecor-which-helps-its-users-manage-their-heart-health-scores-another-fda-approval/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2076918</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump didn&#8217;t concede, but he will move Biden&#8217;s transition forward</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/trump-emily-murphy-gsa-election-results/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/trump-emily-murphy-gsa-election-results/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 01:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2020 Election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe Biden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trump administration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077892</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With an unprecedented number of mail-in ballots, election results took a bit longer this year than usual. But if Americans were expecting an election week, November stretched on into a month of election drama, with President Trump mounting an unprecedented effort to undermine election results and stall the transition process, even as states certified Biden&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With an unprecedented number of mail-in ballots, election results took a bit longer this year than usual. But if Americans were expecting an election week, November stretched on into a month of election drama, with President Trump mounting an unprecedented effort to undermine election results and stall the transition process, even as <a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/11/23/937802054/trump-is-running-out-of-time-as-key-states-set-to-certify-that-biden-won">states certified Biden&#8217;s win</a>.</p>
<p>President Trump at last appeared to accept the election results Monday, but not in so many words. It certainly wasn&#8217;t a concession speech, but it was probably the closest thing yet.</p>
<p>&#8220;&#8230; In the best interest of our Country, I am recommending that Emily and her team do what needs to be done with regard to initial protocols, and have told my team to do the same,&#8221; Trump tweeted, seeming to <a href="https://twitter.com/Yamiche/status/1331013212377116673">contradict a fresh claim</a> made by GSA Administrator Emily Murphy that the White House did not influence her decision to block the transition. The General Services Administration (GSA) plays a role in making election results official and moving the transition forward on the federal level.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">&#8230;fight, and I believe we will prevail! Nevertheless, in the best interest of our Country, I am recommending that Emily and her team do what needs to be done with regard to initial protocols, and have told my team to do the same.</p>
<p>&mdash; Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1331013908971261953?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 23, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>President-elect Biden&#8217;s transition work proceeded in spite of the roadblocks, with the incoming leader introducing aspects of his <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-03207-2">plan to get COVID-19 under control</a> and working out the names of <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/22/us/politics/biden-antony-blinken-secretary-of-state.html">officials he plans to appoint</a>. But with the head of the GSA refusing to release $6.3 million in federal funds for the transition, Biden&#8217;s hands were tied in some important ways. Murphy&#8217;s extremely unusual refusal to recognize the election results also blocked the president-elect&#8217;s ability to access secure government devices and receive briefings from federal agencies, including those involved in the pandemic response.</p>
<p>Apart from getting Biden&#8217;s transition on track, Trump&#8217;s words and GSA&#8217;s belated cooperation could help the nation move on in another important way. For weeks, election conspiracies have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/04/trump-election-2020-premature-victory-facebook-twitter/">roiled the internet</a>, inspiring a number of Trump supporters to denounce mainstream social networks, which reminded users of the election results and cracked down on some forms of misinformation. Those conspiracy theories were often spread right from the top, with President Trump promoting <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-11-17/trump-s-election-attacks-put-voting-tech-firm-in-the-crosshairs">baseless claims</a> of fraud involving mail-in ballots and voting machines as he refused to concede.</p>
<p>The president&#8217;s online supporters may not move on from the election quickly, but they&#8217;re likely to follow his lead — and for now at least, it looks like Trump will signal defeat.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8X1w5svJBD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/parler-app-store-facebook/">&#8216;Free speech&#8217; social network Parler tops app store rankings following Biden&#8217;s election win</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;&#8216;Free speech&#8217; social network Parler tops app store rankings following Biden&#8217;s election win&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/parler-app-store-facebook/embed/#?secret=8X1w5svJBD" data-secret="8X1w5svJBD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/2020-election/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/us-2020-election-footer.png" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/trump-emily-murphy-gsa-election-results/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077892</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gift Guide: 22 STEM toy gift ideas for every little builder</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/gift-guide-22-stem-toy-gift-ideas-for-every-little-builder/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/gift-guide-22-stem-toy-gift-ideas-for-every-little-builder/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 23:51:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gift Guide 2020]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[STEM toys]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2069237</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In 2020, parents and guardians are super spoilt for choice in the STEM toys gift department &#8212; which is great news in the midst of a pandemic that&#8217;s supercharging homeschooling needs. The category has matured to offer an interesting range of options for children across a wide span of ages, shedding some of its earlier [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In 2020, parents and guardians are super spoilt for choice in the STEM toys gift department &#8212; which is great news in the midst of a pandemic that&#8217;s supercharging homeschooling needs. The category has matured to offer an interesting range of options for children across a wide span of ages, shedding some of its earlier reliance on Disney IP in favor of more original ideas. Below, we&#8217;ve rounded up 20+ gift ideas to get the (robotic) ball rolling.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s still true the educational value of &#8220;learn to code&#8221; gizmos remains hard to quantify. And some price tags can seem tricky to justify. But there&#8217;s no doubt a lot of thought has gone on creating child-friendly product design and into chunking and structuring the learning. The short story is there&#8217;s plenty to intrigue and inspire developing minds, even if there&#8217;s no guarantee you&#8217;ll have a future Googler on your hands. (But that&#8217;s okay; maybe your kid will invent the <em>next</em> paradigm-shifting platform?)</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also good to see attention continuing to be paid to encouraging children to explore art &amp; design, not just get their heads around engineering &amp; science concepts. Maybe in the coming years we&#8217;ll get a little STEM ethics thrown into the mix &#8212; to further round-out the learning potential. While there&#8217;s clear value in kids understanding how digital tools work under the hood, helping the next generation appreciate that connectivity can change people&#8217;s behavior and reshape the world around them looks no less important a lesson to learn.</p>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic">This article contains links to affiliate partners where available. When you buy through these links, TechCrunch may earn an affiliate commission.</i></p>
<h2><strong>Arcade Coder</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069502" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069502" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069502" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Arcade_Coder_Family_Play_Top_White_Digital-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="499" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Arcade_Coder_Family_Play_Top_White_Digital-1.jpg 3500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Arcade_Coder_Family_Play_Top_White_Digital-1.jpg?resize=150,110 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Arcade_Coder_Family_Play_Top_White_Digital-1.jpg?resize=300,220 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Arcade_Coder_Family_Play_Top_White_Digital-1.jpg?resize=768,563 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Arcade_Coder_Family_Play_Top_White_Digital-1.jpg?resize=680,499 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Arcade_Coder_Family_Play_Top_White_Digital-1.jpg?resize=1536,1126 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Arcade_Coder_Family_Play_Top_White_Digital-1.jpg?resize=2048,1501 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Arcade_Coder_Family_Play_Top_White_Digital-1.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069502" class="wp-caption-text">Arcade Coder targets budding game designers (Image Credit: Tech Will Save Us)</p></div></p>
<p>U.K. startup Tech Will Save Us’ <a href="https://www.techwillsaveus.com/shop/arcade-coder/">Arcade Coder</a> is a STEM toy designed for budding game designers. It takes the form of interactive gaming &#8220;tablet&#8221; with an array of LED-lit buttons rather than a touchscreen &#8212; preloaded with a few retro games. But hook it up to its companion iPad app and kids get guidance on how to tweak gameplay and design their own games via a drag-and-drop learn-to-code interface.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 6-10<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07Y3LJWTS/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B07Y3LJWTS&amp;linkId=9a46795b3d51588df965f6fbbff67cf0">$120 from Amazon</a><br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="https://www.techwillsaveus.com">Tech Will Save Us</a></p>
<h2><strong>Boolean Box</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069510" style="width: 499px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069510" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2069510 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/2019BoxAngle_470.png?w=489" alt="" width="489" height="470" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/2019BoxAngle_470.png 489w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/2019BoxAngle_470.png?resize=150,144 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/2019BoxAngle_470.png?resize=300,288 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/2019BoxAngle_470.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/2019BoxAngle_470.png?resize=50,48 50w" sizes="(max-width: 489px) 100vw, 489px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069510" class="wp-caption-text">The BooleanBox has Raspberry Pi inside (Image Credit: Boolean Girl)</p></div></p>
<p>The <a href="https://booleangirltech.com/product/boolean-box/">Boolean Box</a> is a build-it-yourself <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/raspberry-pi/">Raspberry Pi</a> Model 3-based computer designed with the help of girls in coding camps and school programs run by its not-for-profit maker &#8212; though it&#8217;s designed for kids of any gender. The Pi-powered machine runs Raspbian OS and comes preloaded with STEM-friendly software, including Scratch, Python and Minecraft, so little coders can get to grips with block-based and more sophisticated programming languages once the computer has been put together. The kit also includes a breadboard for building electronics projects. (NB: The basic box needs an HDMI-capable TV to act as a monitor for the computer, or there&#8217;s a $300 bundle that comes with a monitor.)</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 8+<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B071HWPKN5/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B071HWPKN5&amp;linkId=5ea938fe7d44385e7c3af6862e3ca43e">$150 from Amazon</a><br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="https://booleangirl.org">Boolean Girl</a></p>
<h2><strong>Botley 2.0 Coding Robot Activity Set</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069516" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069516" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069516" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/botely_2.0_coding_robot_activity_set_1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/botely_2.0_coding_robot_activity_set_1.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/botely_2.0_coding_robot_activity_set_1.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/botely_2.0_coding_robot_activity_set_1.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/botely_2.0_coding_robot_activity_set_1.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/botely_2.0_coding_robot_activity_set_1.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/botely_2.0_coding_robot_activity_set_1.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/botely_2.0_coding_robot_activity_set_1.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/botely_2.0_coding_robot_activity_set_1.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/botely_2.0_coding_robot_activity_set_1.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/botely_2.0_coding_robot_activity_set_1.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069516" class="wp-caption-text">The battery-powered coding robot, Botley 2.0 (Image Credit: Learning Resources)</p></div></p>
<p>For parents looking for screen-free STEM toys <a href="https://www.learningresources.com/botleyr-the-coding-robot-2-activity-set">Botley 2.0</a> is worth a look. The battery-powered rolling-and-sensing programmable robot comes with a remote control for coding directional sequences (of up to 150 steps) via simple button pressing. There&#8217;s also a loops button to introduce the coding principle of recycling a previous sequence.</p>
<p>Botley&#8217;s maker, Learning Resources, has updated the robot for 2020 with new interactions, color-changing eyes and night vision so it can carry on line-sensing in the dark. There are also new programming sequences for kids to discover that transform the bot into fresh characters &#8212; such as a train, police car, ghost and frog &#8212; expressed via different sounds and movements. The kit also includes a 78-piece activity set so kids can devise obstacle courses for Botley to navigate.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 5-10<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B083T58PKM/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B083T58PKM&amp;linkId=9e3863a6ad7ce8c4b94fdb7305b134aa">Around $70 from Amazon</a><br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="https://www.learningresources.com">Learning Resources</a></p>
<h2><strong>Botzees Go! &#8211; Dino Set &amp; Color Sensor Kit add-on pack</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069519" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069519" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069519" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ProductTilesImage-04_1296x.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ProductTilesImage-04_1296x.jpg 1296w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ProductTilesImage-04_1296x.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ProductTilesImage-04_1296x.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ProductTilesImage-04_1296x.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ProductTilesImage-04_1296x.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ProductTilesImage-04_1296x.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ProductTilesImage-04_1296x.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ProductTilesImage-04_1296x.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ProductTilesImage-04_1296x.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ProductTilesImage-04_1296x.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069519" class="wp-caption-text">The Color Sensor Kit add-on pack for the Botzees Go! &#8212; Dino Set (Image Credit: Pai Technology)</p></div></p>
<p>Pai Technology has been selling robotics kits with an <a href="https://pai.technology/collections/all/products/botzees-robotics-programing-and-augmented-reality">augmented reality twist</a> for a few years now. Newer offerings from the STEM toy maker are aimed at younger kids — offering a first taste of block-based construction plus a companion app to offer build instructions and simple visualization of the finished creation. The <a href="https://pai.technology/collections/all/products/botzees-go-dino-set">Botzees Go! &#8211; Dino Set</a> extends the basic construction element by adding movement and a physical remote control so kids can bring the dino-bots to life. So a very soft introduction to STEM learning. An optional <a href="https://pai.technology/collections/all/products/botzees-color-sensor-kit-add-on-pack">Color Sensor Kit</a> further extends capabilities by enabling the bots to track lines and respond to different colors.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 3+<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> $80 ($40 apiece for the Dino Set and Sensor Kit)<br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="https://pai.technology">Pai Technology</a></p>
<h2><strong>Circuit Explorer</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069523" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069523" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069523" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-11.53.03.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="399" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-11.53.03.png 2050w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-11.53.03.png?resize=150,88 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-11.53.03.png?resize=300,176 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-11.53.03.png?resize=768,451 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-11.53.03.png?resize=680,399 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-11.53.03.png?resize=1536,902 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-11.53.03.png?resize=2048,1203 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-11.53.03.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069523" class="wp-caption-text">Circuit Explorer space themed STEM playsets (Image Credit: Educational Insights)</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://www.educationalinsights.com/circuitexplorer">Circuit Explorer</a> is a simple STEM toy that fuses Lego-style block building with snap-together electronic circuits for a range of space-themed toys — including a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08BXPVWB3">rocket</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08BXPR362">rover</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08BXLZTBL">Deluxe Base Station</a>. Kids get to light up their creations with battery-powered LED lights and synthesized sound effects.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 6+<br />
<strong>Price:</strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08BXPVWB3/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B08BXPVWB3&amp;linkId=4c765ed2027022c43c693458d66721eb"> From $30 on Amazon</a><br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="https://www.educationalinsights.com">Educational Insights</a></p>
<h2><strong>Disney Codeillusion</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069534" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069534" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069534" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Rapunzel_Lifestyle.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="351" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Rapunzel_Lifestyle.png 1730w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Rapunzel_Lifestyle.png?resize=150,77 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Rapunzel_Lifestyle.png?resize=300,155 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Rapunzel_Lifestyle.png?resize=768,396 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Rapunzel_Lifestyle.png?resize=680,351 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Rapunzel_Lifestyle.png?resize=1536,793 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Rapunzel_Lifestyle.png?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069534" class="wp-caption-text">Disney Codeillusion gamifies teaching kids coding (Image Credit: Life is Tech!)</p></div></p>
<p>Edtech company Life is Tech! has licensed Disney IP to inject the latter’s branding magic into a gamified and interactive learning environment that&#8217;s geared toward encouraging kids to acquire coding skills by building their own games, websites and movies featuring some of their favorite Disney characters. The online educational game — called <a href="https://codeillusion.io">Disney Codeillusion</a> — is billed as teaching four coding languages (HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Processing), with a focus on visual arts thanks to the inclusion of Disney&#8217;s animated movie characters. The content features the usual cartoon suspects &#8212; from Queen Elsa and Aladdin to Mickey Mouse.</p>
<p>The web-based course is definitely not a cheap option — and requires an internet connection via a desktop computer (not a mobile device) to work — costing $500 for a package that excludes any physical merch and also strips out some other digital elements (such as an RPG game). The package with all the bells &amp; whistles (aka the &#8220;Enchanted&#8221; edition) weighs in at $900. But with 125 lessons (averaging 30 minutes a pop), kids should at least be kept busy working on their code creations for some time &#8212; which might be magic enough for parents stuck homeschooling during a pandemic.</p>
<p>There is also a free seven-day trial to get a taster of lesson content before committing to shell out.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 8+<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> From $500<br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="https://lifeistech.co.jp/en/">Life is Tech!</a></p>
<h2><strong>Electro Explorers Club</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069537" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069537" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069537" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-12.31.52.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="519" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-12.31.52.png 1528w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-12.31.52.png?resize=150,114 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-12.31.52.png?resize=300,229 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-12.31.52.png?resize=768,586 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-12.31.52.png?resize=680,519 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-12.31.52.png?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069537" class="wp-caption-text">The crafty Electro Explorer Club subscription box (Image Credit: Tech Will Save Us)</p></div></p>
<p>Monthly activity kits have become a well-established STEM toy niche that looks set to be supercharged as more parents take on homeschooling because of the coronavirus pandemic. U.K. STEAM toy maker Tech Will Save Us has been playing in this space for several years now. One of its most recent offerings to keep kids entertained and engaged is the <a href="https://www.techwillsaveus.com/electro-explorers/">Electro Explorers Club</a>: A cutesy craft and electronics projects subscription box with a focus on story-led learning. Expect plenty of squishy <a href="https://www.techwillsaveus.com/new-electro-dough/">electro dough</a> for character-building.</p>
<p>Each box covers a range of tech, science and design concepts — such as simple robotics and programs, electronic circuits, multi-line algorithms with conditions, character design and physics. As the months progress kids also build up a toolset of components to keep expanding their learning. Each box costs $20 a month via a recurring cancel-at-any-time subscription.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 4-6<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> $20 per month<br />
<strong>Made by</strong>: <a href="https://www.techwillsaveus.com">Tech Will Save Us</a></p>
<h2><strong>Evo for Home and Homeschooled</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069540" style="width: 660px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069540" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069540" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Evo-For-Home-03_1200x1200.png?w=650" alt="" width="650" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Evo-For-Home-03_1200x1200.png 1080w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Evo-For-Home-03_1200x1200.png?resize=143,150 143w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Evo-For-Home-03_1200x1200.png?resize=287,300 287w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Evo-For-Home-03_1200x1200.png?resize=768,804 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Evo-For-Home-03_1200x1200.png?resize=650,680 650w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Evo-For-Home-03_1200x1200.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Evo-For-Home-03_1200x1200.png?resize=48,50 48w" sizes="(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069540" class="wp-caption-text">Droid-based learning with Ozobot&#8217;s Evo (Image Credit: Ozobot)</p></div></p>
<p>Ozobot’s programmable droid <a href="https://shop.ozobot.com/products/evo">Evo</a> can be paired with its block-based coding interface or used screen-free with the included color-code markers as the sensing robots responds to different colors like a set of instructions in a program. The K-12 focused STEAM learning company sells plenty of kits direct to schools &#8212; and isn&#8217;t solely focused on teaching computer programming but rather it touts its tech as a teaching assistant for all STEAM subjects &#8212; but the Evo starter package is aimed at home learners, encouraging kids to use the bot to pick up coding by creating and playing with games and tricks.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 5+<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> $100<br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="https://ozobot.com">Ozobot</a></p>
<h2><strong>imagiCharm</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2074889" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2074889" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2074889" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/imagiLabs-app.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/imagiLabs-app.jpg 2560w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/imagiLabs-app.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/imagiLabs-app.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/imagiLabs-app.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/imagiLabs-app.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/imagiLabs-app.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/imagiLabs-app.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/imagiLabs-app.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2074889" class="wp-caption-text">Code your own Tamagotchi? (Image Credit: ImagiLabs)</p></div></p>
<p>Swedish startup imagiLabs is on a mission to get girls coding. The STEM toy they&#8217;ve devised for this inspirational task is a programmable Bluetooth charm &#8212; a sort of personalizable keychain/code-your-own Tamagotchi. The connected gizmo works in conjunction with a companion mobile app that uses gamified tutorials to encourage tweens and teens to tinker with Python to change the look/function of the 8&#215;8 matrix of colored LED lights. There&#8217;s also a social element to the app as girls can share their projects and check out what others have made.</p>
<p><strong>Age: </strong>9-15<br />
<strong>Price: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B089NWTY45/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B089NWTY45&amp;linkId=c84e3f5d81c3137d68e3934675b3be9e">From $85 on Amazon</a><br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="https://imagilabs.com">ImagiLabs</a></p>
<h2><strong>Kano PC</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069545" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069545" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069545" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Kano-PC-Front-Web.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="499" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Kano-PC-Front-Web.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Kano-PC-Front-Web.jpg?resize=150,110 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Kano-PC-Front-Web.jpg?resize=300,220 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Kano-PC-Front-Web.jpg?resize=768,563 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Kano-PC-Front-Web.jpg?resize=680,499 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Kano-PC-Front-Web.jpg?resize=1536,1127 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Kano-PC-Front-Web.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069545" class="wp-caption-text">Not a Microsoft Surface &#8212; a kid-friendly Windows-based Kano PC (Image Credit: Kano)</p></div></p>
<p>As we noted in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/26/gift-guide-stem-toys-for-your-builders-in-training/">last year’s gift guide</a>, U.K. STEM learning startup Kano has pivoted from selling Raspberry Pi-powered build-it-yourself computer kits to a more convention &#8220;my child’s first PC&#8221; proposition. The Windows-based plug-in-the-bits-and-play <a href="https://kano.me/eu/store/products/kano-pc">Kano PC</a> is aimed at parents who want to set their child on the path to STEM learning in a more mainstream computing environment. At $300 the laptop-slash-tablet is hardly a &#8220;toy&#8221; but the advantage of shelling out for a fully fledged computer is increased utility &#8212; and, hopefully, longevity. Kano touts the PC as capable of running “thousands” of applications.</p>
<p>Of most relevance to the STEM side, it comes preloaded with Kano’s <a href="https://kano.me/eu/downloadable">Software Studio package</a>: A set of learning tools geared toward teaching kids design, science, coding and creativity &#8220;in simple and fun ways&#8221;, as it puts it.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> K-12 (from 4+ to 19)<br />
<strong>From:</strong> $300<br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="https://kano.me/us">Kano</a></p>
<h2><strong>Kumiita</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069548" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069548" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069548" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-13.27.30.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="384" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-13.27.30.png 1606w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-13.27.30.png?resize=150,85 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-13.27.30.png?resize=300,170 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-13.27.30.png?resize=768,434 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-13.27.30.png?resize=680,384 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-13.27.30.png?resize=1536,868 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-13.27.30.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069548" class="wp-caption-text">Even very young children can engage with coding concepts by playing with Kumiita (Image Credit: Icon Corp.)</p></div></p>
<p>For very young kids point your peepers at <a href="https://kumiita.com/eng/">Kumiita</a>. The educational toy for kids who haven&#8217;t even reached their first birthday began as a <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1599191780/kumiita-educational-programming-toy-for-0-year-old">Kickstarter</a> side-project. Now its Japanese maker is selling the gizmo globally, via <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/KUMIITA/page/FCBE5355-B75C-4497-8B52-7F379AE9EA03?ref_=ast_bln">Amazon</a>. The idea is to teach foundational programming concepts via screen-free (and internet-free), tile-based floor play.</p>
<p>A battery-powered robot — Kumiita — responds to pictorial instructions on the tiles. Kids choose which tiles to place to &#8220;program&#8221; the robot — getting immediate feedback on their sequence as the bot twirls, changes colour, plays animal sounds or moves off in a new direction. If the bot falls off the pathway there’s obviously a problem and kids have to set about &#8220;debugging&#8221; by changing their choice of tiles. That in turn encourages problem solving and sequential thinking. Tiles in some of the packs also introduce conditional coding concepts.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 7 months+<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> From $200<br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="http://www.e-icon.co.jp/english/">Icon Corp.</a></p>
<h2><strong>littleBits At Home Learning Starter Kit</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069554" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069554" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069554" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LBAtHomeKit_GALLERY_NEW1_1200x.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="486" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LBAtHomeKit_GALLERY_NEW1_1200x.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LBAtHomeKit_GALLERY_NEW1_1200x.jpg?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LBAtHomeKit_GALLERY_NEW1_1200x.jpg?resize=300,214 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LBAtHomeKit_GALLERY_NEW1_1200x.jpg?resize=768,548 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LBAtHomeKit_GALLERY_NEW1_1200x.jpg?resize=680,486 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LBAtHomeKit_GALLERY_NEW1_1200x.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069554" class="wp-caption-text">littleBits kits offer guided electronics projects to spark young minds (Image Credit: Sphero)</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/23/sphero-is-buying-littlebits/">Sphero-owned</a> <a href="https://sphero.com/collections/all/family_littlebits">littleBits</a> makes introductory circuit kits with magnetic snap-together connectors to help children get to grips with basic electronics through interactive learning. This <a href="https://sphero.com/collections/all/products/littlebits-at-home-learning-starter-kit">home starter kit</a> promises to get children brainstorming ideas and tinkering to bring a variety of projects to life &#8212; with five guided inventions in the bundle. The learning activity can be entirely screen-free as introductory paper guides are included in the pack. Additional learning resources are also available online via the <a href="https://classroom.littlebits.com/explore/search">littleBits Classroom</a> platform.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 8+<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> $65<br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> Sphero</p>
<h2><strong>MakeCode Arcade &amp; a codable console to run retro gaming creations</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069559" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069559" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069559" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/4200-01.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="510" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/4200-01.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/4200-01.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/4200-01.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/4200-01.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/4200-01.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/4200-01.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069559" class="wp-caption-text">Inspire kids with the help of a dinky codable games console (Image Credit: Adafruit)</p></div></p>
<p>Budding game designers can have fun coding their own retro games in Microsoft’s arcade game editor, <a href="https://www.adafruit.com/explore/makecode-arcade">MakeCode Arcade</a> — based on its <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/makecode">open-source learn-to-code platform</a>. The free online project builder includes tutorials to create simple games using either a block-based coding interface, JavaScript or Python — building up to more complex types of gameplay. You can then turn this free STEM resource into a gift by adding a codable console that supports MakeCode Arcade projects. Such as KittenBot&#8217;s GameBoy-esque <a href="https://www.kittenbot.cc/collections/frontpage/products/meowbit-codable-console-for-microsoft-makecode-arcade">Meowbit</a> ($40); or the <a href="https://www.adafruit.com/product/4200">Adafruit PyBadge</a> ($35) which can also run CircuitPython and Arduino &#8212; both of which are stocked by Adafruit. The maker-focused and electronics hobbyist brand stocks a <a href="https://www.adafruit.com/explore/makecode-arcade">range of MakeCode compatible hardware</a> and plenty more besides.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> It depends<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> From $35<br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> Adafruit, others</p>
<h2><strong>MindLabs: Energy and Circuits</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069579" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069579" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069579" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-14.49.04.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="462" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-14.49.04.png 2188w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-14.49.04.png?resize=150,102 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-14.49.04.png?resize=300,204 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-14.49.04.png?resize=768,522 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-14.49.04.png?resize=680,462 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-14.49.04.png?resize=1536,1043 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-14.49.04.png?resize=2048,1391 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-14.49.04.png?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069579" class="wp-caption-text">Kids learn about electronics circuits via augmented reality (Image Credit: Explore Interactive)</p></div></p>
<p>This STEM toy lets kids learn about electronics circuits virtually. This means no fiddling with actual wires, batteries or components thanks to augmented reality. Instead, the <a href="https://shop.learnwithexplore.com/products/mindlabs-energy-and-circuits">MindLabs: Energy and Circuits</a> pack has kids play with a set of physical cards &#8212; viewing them through the screen of a tablet where they get to build out circuits that are brought to life digitally via the companion app. The kit offers 20+ interactive lessons with step-by-step instructions on basic circuit concepts. (NB: Children will need access to a tablet.)</p>
<p>The approach offers a relatively affordable way for kids to learn about electronics components and concepts through (virtual) trial and error &#8212; though clearly if it&#8217;s a screen-free toy you&#8217;re after, this isn&#8217;t it. An added advantage is children are able to collaborate remotely with friends for group learning opportunities.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 8+<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> $25<br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="https://exploremindlabs.com">Explore Interactive</a></p>
<h2><strong>NextMaker Box</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069582" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069582" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069582" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ce43cb2129988589b115d6926960b16f_original.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ce43cb2129988589b115d6926960b16f_original.jpg 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ce43cb2129988589b115d6926960b16f_original.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ce43cb2129988589b115d6926960b16f_original.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ce43cb2129988589b115d6926960b16f_original.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069582" class="wp-caption-text">NextMaker Box is a new monthly subscription box stuffed with STEM projects (Image Credit: Makeblock)</p></div></p>
<p>Chinese firm Makeblock is getting in on the the monthly STEM activity kit action this year with its <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/makeblock/nextmaker-box-learn-coding-at-home-with-fun-steam-projects">NextMaker Box</a>. At the time of writing the subscription product is up for pre-order via <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/makeblock/nextmaker-box-learn-coding-at-home-with-fun-steam-projects">Kickstarter</a> with an earliest estimated shipping date of December 2020 &#8212; so the usual &#8220;risk of shipping delay&#8221; caveats apply.</p>
<p>For parents willing to take a gamble on a gift not turning up in time for the festive season, the NextMaker Box is slated to deliver monthly hardware projects and coding courses designed to keep young minds engaged. The content focuses on robotics, coding and engineering concepts and design work. Makeblock also says the boxes will follow a Computer Science Teachers Association standard-aligned coding curriculum.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 6-12<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> From $40<br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="https://www.makeblock.com">Makeblock</a></p>
<h2><strong>Piper Command Center</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069667" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069667" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069667" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-17.27.46.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="454" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-17.27.46.png 1806w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-17.27.46.png?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-17.27.46.png?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-17.27.46.png?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-17.27.46.png?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-17.27.46.png?resize=1536,1026 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-17.27.46.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069667" class="wp-caption-text">Screwdrivers at the ready for this Arduino project (Image Credit: Piper)</p></div></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.playpiper.com/products/piper-command-center-beta">Piper Command Center</a> is an Arduino project for teens to build and configure their own gaming controller &#8212; following instructions available via Piper&#8217;s <a href="https://www.playpiper.com/pages/command-center">online portal</a>. The (beta) project offers a hand-held introduction to physical computing, hardware hacking and the maker movement. Requires access to a desktop computer with Arduino IDE installed for configuring the controller and troubleshooting the firmware.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 13+<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> $60<br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="https://www.playpiper.com">Piper</a></p>
<h2><strong>Raspberry Pi 400</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069587" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069587" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069587" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kit-lg@2x-5e3ad81dda9d89e594ad356da33f9bac.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="366" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kit-lg@2x-5e3ad81dda9d89e594ad356da33f9bac.jpg 2600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kit-lg@2x-5e3ad81dda9d89e594ad356da33f9bac.jpg?resize=150,81 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kit-lg@2x-5e3ad81dda9d89e594ad356da33f9bac.jpg?resize=300,162 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kit-lg@2x-5e3ad81dda9d89e594ad356da33f9bac.jpg?resize=768,414 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kit-lg@2x-5e3ad81dda9d89e594ad356da33f9bac.jpg?resize=680,366 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kit-lg@2x-5e3ad81dda9d89e594ad356da33f9bac.jpg?resize=1536,827 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kit-lg@2x-5e3ad81dda9d89e594ad356da33f9bac.jpg?resize=2048,1103 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kit-lg@2x-5e3ad81dda9d89e594ad356da33f9bac.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069587" class="wp-caption-text">The $100 Pi 400 bundle includes an official beginner&#8217;s guidebook (Image Credit: Raspberry Pi Foundation)</p></div></p>
<p>The U.K.-based, STEM-learning focused not-for-profit Raspberry Pi Foundation’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/02/raspberry-pi-foundation-announces-the-cute-little-raspberry-pi-400/">latest bit of kit </a>— the <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/products/raspberry-pi-400/?resellerType=home">Pi 400</a> — houses its top-of-the-range microprocessor (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/raspberry-pi-foundation-announces-raspberry-pi-4-with-8gb-of-ram/">Pi 4</a>) inside a sleek keyboard in a retro throwback to how home computing started. Add your own TV or monitor — et voila! A powerful STEM learning device in a very affordable package, given the keyboard-computer can be picked up for just $70. For children in need of guidance and all the various accessories to get going with Pi there’s a $100 kit bundle that includes the official beginner’s guide book too.</p>
<p>Kids can cut their teeth coding on the Pi 400 via block-based programming languages like Scratch or by tinkering with Python in <a href="https://minecraft.gamepedia.com/Pi_Edition#:~:text=Minecraft%3A%20Pi%20Edition%20is%20a,educational%20tool%20for%20novice%20programmers.">Minecraft Pi</a> (a version of the popular 3D mining game that comes preloaded on the Pi&#8217;s OS, Raspbian). So there’s plenty to recommend the Pi 400.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> It depends<br />
<strong>Price: </strong>From $70<br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi Foundation</a></p>
<h2><strong>Robo Wunderkind Explorer Kit</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069597" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069597" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069597" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rw3-explorer-pro.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rw3-explorer-pro.png 3500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rw3-explorer-pro.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rw3-explorer-pro.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rw3-explorer-pro.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rw3-explorer-pro.png?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rw3-explorer-pro.png?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rw3-explorer-pro.png?resize=2048,2048 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rw3-explorer-pro.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rw3-explorer-pro.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rw3-explorer-pro.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rw3-explorer-pro.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rw3-explorer-pro.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069597" class="wp-caption-text">The Explorer Pro kit now features an LED block (Image Credit: Robo Wunderkind)</p></div></p>
<p>Austrian STEM toy maker <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/08/robo-wunderkind-wants-to-build-the-lego-mindstorms-for-everyone/">Robo Wunderkind</a> has updated its programmable robotics kits for 2020 with new sensor modules, including an LED display block that can show designs or display scrolling text; a line-follower block so the bots can detect and follow lines; and an accelerometer block to give them spacial awareness.</p>
<p>For those not already familiar with the STEM toy, kids snap together the magnetic blocks to build sensor-laden robots and program them via a drag-and-drop coding interface in the companion app.</p>
<p>Blocks can be combined in multiple ways to build different sensing objects &#8212; from rolling robots to smart flashlights. The cheapest kit comes with six modules and 10 guided projects, while the top-of-the-range Explorer Pro kit ($400) has 15 modules and 30 projects. The blocks are also compatible with Lego pieces so children can augment the design of their constructions with additional elements if they have a few bricks lying around.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 5-14<br />
<strong>Price: </strong>From $200<br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="https://www.robowunderkind.com">Robo Wunderkind</a></p>
<h2><strong>ScoreBot Kit</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069610" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069610" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069610" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/scorebot1.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/scorebot1.png 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/scorebot1.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/scorebot1.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/scorebot1.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/scorebot1.png?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/scorebot1.png?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/scorebot1.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/scorebot1.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/scorebot1.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/scorebot1.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/scorebot1.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069610" class="wp-caption-text">A programmable robot for soccer-mad kids (Image Credit: Ubtech)</p></div></p>
<p>Get soccer-mad kids into STEM with Ubtech&#8217;s <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/UBTECH-Scorebot-JRA0405-Green-Black/dp/B07TZ3LPSZ/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;keywords=ubtech+scorebot&amp;qid=1604423911&amp;sr=8-1">ScoreBot Kit</a> &#8212; from its JIMU Programmable educational robot series. This build-it-yourself, code-controlled robot exhibits ball-dribbling skills that children can hone via the companion app’s block-based coding interface. A memory programming mode allows them to record and replay an action to try to gain a competitive edge when battling against other ScoreBots in a game of competitive floor football.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 8+<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> $120<br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="https://www.ubtrobot.com/products/scorebot-kit?ls=en">Ubtech</a></p>
<h2><strong>Sphero Mini Golf</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069622" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069622" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069622" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.08.47.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="468" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.08.47.png 2117w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.08.47.png?resize=150,103 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.08.47.png?resize=300,207 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.08.47.png?resize=768,529 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.08.47.png?resize=680,468 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.08.47.png?resize=1536,1058 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.08.47.png?resize=2048,1410 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.08.47.png?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069622" class="wp-caption-text">Sphero&#8217;s robotic ball has rolled onto the green (Image Credit: Sphero)</p></div></p>
<p>Edtech player <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/sphero/">Sphero</a> sells learning wares for schools and home focused on its spherical, remote-controlled robot. This version of its programmable gizmo takes the form of a <a href="https://sphero.com/collections/for-home/products/mini-golf">mini golf ball</a> — encouraging kids to devise their own mini golf courses to remote-control the bot around. They can also turn the connected orb into a gaming remote control, making use of the embedded gyroscope and accelerometer. The companion Sphero Edu app is where the coding gets done.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 8+<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> $50<br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="https://sphero.com">Sphero</a></p>
<h2><strong>Spike Prime Set</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069629" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069629" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069629" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.23.41.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="432" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.23.41.png 2166w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.23.41.png?resize=150,95 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.23.41.png?resize=300,191 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.23.41.png?resize=768,488 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.23.41.png?resize=680,432 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.23.41.png?resize=1536,976 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.23.41.png?resize=2048,1301 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-04-at-16.23.41.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069629" class="wp-caption-text">Lego Education&#8217;s kits combine plastic bricks and electronics (Image Credit: Lego Education)</p></div></p>
<p>Lego’s education division has made some of its classroom kits available to the home market to cater to students who are learning at home as a result of the coronavirus pandemic &#8212; such as this <a href="https://www.lego.com/en-us/product/lego-education-spike-prime-set-45678">Spike Prime Set</a>. The STEAM learning kit is aimed at students in grades 6-8. The core piece is a programmable Bluetooth hub that can be used to power a variety of project builds — from robots to rovers — making use of the array of motors, sensors, components, bricks and pieces packed in the 528-piece kit. Programming the hub is done via a Scratch-based drag-and-drop interface or text-based coding with Python so kids will need access to a computer.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 10+<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> $330<br />
<strong>Made by:</strong> <a href="https://education.lego.com/en-us/">Lego Education</a></p>
<h2><strong>Turing Tumble</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2069638" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2069638" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2069638" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kickstarter_main_image_store_1800x1800.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kickstarter_main_image_store_1800x1800.jpg 1794w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kickstarter_main_image_store_1800x1800.jpg?resize=150,85 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kickstarter_main_image_store_1800x1800.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kickstarter_main_image_store_1800x1800.jpg?resize=768,433 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kickstarter_main_image_store_1800x1800.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kickstarter_main_image_store_1800x1800.jpg?resize=1536,866 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/kickstarter_main_image_store_1800x1800.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2069638" class="wp-caption-text">Kids can learn logic concepts with the help of this mechanical computer (Image Credit: Turing Tumble)</p></div></p>
<p>Build logical thinking into your child’s playtime with the help of a marble-based &#8220;computer&#8221;.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://store.turingtumble.com">Turing Tumble</a> is a tilted board game plus an assortment of &#8220;logic&#8221; gates for devising pathways to solve puzzles. The aim of the learning game is to guide colored marbles from top to bottom in the correct sequence. A cartoon puzzle book guides kids through the challenges, making this an entirely screen-free way to approach STEM learning.</p>
<p><strong>Age:</strong> 8 to adult<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> $70<br />
<strong>Made by: </strong><a href="https://www.turingtumble.com">Turing Tumble</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2020/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/gift-guide-2020-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/gift-guide-22-stem-toy-gift-ideas-for-every-little-builder/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2069237</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gift Guide: 7 perfect gifts for podcasters and streamers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/gift-guide-7-perfect-gifts-for-podcasters-and-streamers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/gift-guide-7-perfect-gifts-for-podcasters-and-streamers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 23:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AKG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gift Guide 2020]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Livestreaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasting]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077124</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So, this one is going to be a different from last year. Because everything is different from last year. I know 2020 has been a pretty big change for my own personal podcast. I always prefer conducting interviews in person when I’m able — in fact, around 400 or so episodes were done exactly like [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">So, this one is going to be a different<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/05/gift-guide-gifts-for-the-promising-podcaster/"> from last year</a>. Because everything is different from last year. I know 2020 has been a pretty big change for my own personal podcast. I always prefer conducting interviews in person when I’m able — in fact, around 400 or so episodes were done exactly like that.</p>
<p>But face-to-face interviews are going to continue to be a non-starter for the foreseeable future, so I’ve had to switch the show to a virtual setup. It’s less than ideal for my own creative and aesthetic preferences, but when the world shifts radically, you do your best to adapt along with it.</p>
<p>For me, that’s meant a couple of things. First — and most obviously — shifting from in-person interviews to virtual ones. Another more surprising (for me) aspect has been the addition of a video element. I’ve started doing it less frequently, but I’ve incorporated YouTube live-streaming into my repertoire. After all, most of my interviews are done over Zoom, with the video stripped out. Sometimes it’s fun to do both.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>So here’s a good place to start for the podcaster in your life — whether they’re just starting out or looking to make the transition to remote streaming.</p>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic">This article contains links to affiliate partners where available. When you buy through these links, TechCrunch may earn an affiliate commission.</i></p>
<h2>AKG Lyra</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2077126" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2077126" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2077126" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/akg.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/akg.jpg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/akg.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/akg.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/akg.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/akg.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/akg.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/akg.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2077126" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>This one is a repeat from last year, mostly because I’ve been using the heck out of it. AKG’s mic has become my go-to for podcasts and meetings alike. I’ve used it for television appearances, Disrupt panels and a recent guest hosting appearance on NPR. It sounds good, has simple-to-understand settings, plug-and-play functionality and it looks great.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07Y2PFM1W/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B07Y2PFM1W&amp;linkId=0def2737113fa068ea3d6c0b7719d204">Around $140 from Amazon</a></p>
<h2>Logitech StreamCam</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2077130" style="width: 1606px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2077130" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2077130 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/streamcam-gallery-1-white-e1606174088275.png" alt="" width="1596" height="976" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/streamcam-gallery-1-white-e1606174088275.png 1596w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/streamcam-gallery-1-white-e1606174088275.png?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/streamcam-gallery-1-white-e1606174088275.png?resize=300,183 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/streamcam-gallery-1-white-e1606174088275.png?resize=768,470 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/streamcam-gallery-1-white-e1606174088275.png?resize=680,416 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/streamcam-gallery-1-white-e1606174088275.png?resize=1536,939 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/streamcam-gallery-1-white-e1606174088275.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1596px) 100vw, 1596px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2077130" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits: </strong>Logitech</p></div></p>
<p>The thing about webcams is that there are a lot of them. The other thing about them is they’re mostly pretty cheap. Logitech’s StreamCam is pretty pricey as far as the category goes. Many or most of these products can be had for around $100 or less. The StreamCam comes at a premium — but you get a lot of camera for that price.</p>
<p>It’s probably overkill for most scenarios (see also: our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/gift-guide-7-great-gifts-for-anyone-working-from-home/">work from home gift guide</a>), but it delivers really solid streaming quality in a compact package. That includes 1080p video at 60fps, with face tracking and good low-light shooting.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://www.logitech.com/en-us/products/webcams/streamcam.960-001289.html#buy-streamcam">$170 from Logitech</a></p>
<h2>Yotto Microphone Pop Filter</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2077129" style="width: 766px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2077129" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-full wp-image-2077129" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/619fA1zP2IL._AC_SL1200_.jpg" alt="" width="756" height="1112" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/619fA1zP2IL._AC_SL1200_.jpg 756w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/619fA1zP2IL._AC_SL1200_.jpg?resize=102,150 102w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/619fA1zP2IL._AC_SL1200_.jpg?resize=204,300 204w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/619fA1zP2IL._AC_SL1200_.jpg?resize=462,680 462w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/619fA1zP2IL._AC_SL1200_.jpg?resize=34,50 34w" sizes="(max-width: 756px) 100vw, 756px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2077129" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Yotto</p></div></p>
<p>Okay, this one is less exciting, but man oh man is it important. I suspect most amateur podcasters don’t even consider a wind screen, but after listening to a bit of level-spiking sibilance, you’ll understand exactly why this microphone add-on is so important.</p>
<p>I was using another model until its recent, untimely demise. I just picked this one up for $12 on Amazon and it’s been great. There’s a clamp at the bottom that attaches to most USB mics (including the Blue Yeti and the above AKG). The arm is also super flexible, which is the biggest issue I had with the older model.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07ZYZ7B2Z/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B07ZYZ7B2Z&amp;linkId=80eb48983f50b68df65b7501531ce584">$12 from Amazon</a></p>
<h2>GVM Light Ring</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2077125" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2077125" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2077125" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/8105FNs6Y8L._AC_SL1500_.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="1024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/8105FNs6Y8L._AC_SL1500_.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/8105FNs6Y8L._AC_SL1500_.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/8105FNs6Y8L._AC_SL1500_.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/8105FNs6Y8L._AC_SL1500_.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/8105FNs6Y8L._AC_SL1500_.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/8105FNs6Y8L._AC_SL1500_.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/8105FNs6Y8L._AC_SL1500_.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/8105FNs6Y8L._AC_SL1500_.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/8105FNs6Y8L._AC_SL1500_.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/8105FNs6Y8L._AC_SL1500_.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2077125" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> GVM</p></div></p>
<p>This is the light ring that made most of our staff look great during our first-ever virtual Disrupt. It’s been sitting in the corner of my living room for several months now, and I utilize it for both video streams and meetings.</p>
<p>Like anything involving stills or video, lighting is incredibly important, and the GVM is a real powerhouse with a stated 70,000 hours of life. It’s intense and adjustable/dimmable, offering really solid realistic color settings.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07CBVG1TW/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B07CBVG1TW&amp;linkId=7fe224d1b4d2691072b329acc1fff549">$127 from Amazon</a></p>
<h2>RODEcaster Pro</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2077127" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2077127" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2077127" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/3Q5A6047.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/3Q5A6047.jpg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/3Q5A6047.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/3Q5A6047.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/3Q5A6047.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/3Q5A6047.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/3Q5A6047.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/3Q5A6047.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2077127" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>Another returning item from last year. And honestly, this one is a bit hopeful that some day soon we’ll all be comfortable talking at each other in cramped spaces again. But the RODEcaster Pro is honestly just too good not to include here.</p>
<p>The RODEcaster Pro is a multi-channel mixing board that saves up to four mics&#8217; worth of input (along with effects and guest phone calls via Bluetooth) to an SD card, which will greatly assist in any post-podcast processing. I’m happy to retire it from my list when another podcasting board can offer similar functionality with such an accessible interface and reasonable price. Until then, the RODEcaster Pro continues to be the best way to quickly up your podcasting game.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/1445257-REG/rode_rcp_rodecaster_pro_integrated_podcast.html?sts=pi&amp;pim=Y">$599 from Sweetwater</a></p>
<h2>Zencastr Subscription</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1747505 aligncenter" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/zencastr.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="499" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/zencastr.jpg 1390w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/zencastr.jpg?resize=150,73 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/zencastr.jpg?resize=300,146 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/zencastr.jpg?resize=768,375 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/zencastr.jpg?resize=680,332 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/zencastr.jpg?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>Your results will vary, but I know a lot of folks who rely on Zencastr for remote recording. The interface is great, recording each track remotely, offering levels in-real time and uploading them to the servicer. Files are saved as lossless .wavs and separated by guest.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $20/month <a href="https://zencastr.com/pricing">from Zencastr</a></p>
<h2>Audio-Technica ATH-M50</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2077128" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2077128" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2077128" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ath-m50x_01.png" alt="" width="1024" height="1024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ath-m50x_01.png 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ath-m50x_01.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ath-m50x_01.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ath-m50x_01.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ath-m50x_01.png?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ath-m50x_01.png?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ath-m50x_01.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ath-m50x_01.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ath-m50x_01.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ath-m50x_01.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ath-m50x_01.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2077128" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Audio-Technica</p></div></p>
<p>This is just a great pair of super comfortable and versatile over-ear professional headphones at a reasonable price. Audio-Technica is well regarded in DJ and studio circles, and the $149 price point delivers really excellent quality without breaking the bank.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://www.sweetwater.com/store/detail/ATHM50x--audio-technica-ath-m50x-closed-back-studio-monitoring-headphones">$149 from Sweetwater </a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2020/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/gift-guide-2020-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/gift-guide-7-perfect-gifts-for-podcasters-and-streamers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077124</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
