<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 16:09:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Wellory raises $4.5M for its &#8216;anti-diet&#8217; nutrition app</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/wellory-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/wellory-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 16:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Story Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wellory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Wellory, a startup that bills itself as taking an &#8220;anti-diet approach&#8221; to nutrition and wellness, is announcing that it has raised $4.2 million in funding. The round was led by Story Ventures, with participation from Harlem Capital, Tinder co-founders Sean Rad and Justin Mateen, Ground Up Ventures, NBA Player Wayne Ellington, Hannah Bronfman and others. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.wellory.com">Wellory</a>, a startup that bills itself as taking an &#8220;anti-diet approach&#8221; to nutrition and wellness, is announcing that it has raised $4.2 million in funding.</p>
<p>The round was led by <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/story-ventures" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="story-ventures">Story Ventures, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> with participation from Harlem Capital, Tinder co-founders Sean Rad and Justin Mateen, Ground Up Ventures, NBA Player Wayne Ellington, Hannah Bronfman and others.</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/wellory" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="wellory">Wellory <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> founder and CEO Emily Hochman (who was previously the head of customer success at WayUp) told me that she struggled with dieting in college, to the point where she was risking chronic illness and infertility. As a result, she became determined to gain a better understanding of nutrition and her own health, eventually studying and becoming <a href="https://www.integrativenutrition.com/health-coaching">a certified health coach</a> at the Institute for Integrative Nutrition.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Hochman said that through Wellory, she wants to offer that same understanding to others, which she said has created a &#8220;managed marketplace&#8221; matching users with a licensed nutritionist, registered dietitian or certified health coach. Those coaches create a personalized plan for losing weight or achieving other health goals, then continue to provide feedback as users share photos of each meal and additional health data.</p>
<p>For example, she said that a customer who had just given birth and was interested in postpartum weight loss would get matched with a coach who specializes in that area.</p>
<p>&#8220;The thing that is so important is that we build personalized plans,&#8221; she added. &#8220;We don’t have anything that says, &#8216;At Wellory, we do these 10 things and that’s a standard diet.&#8217; We&#8217;re actually going to help you learn how to make smart and healthy decisions.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2081825" style="width: 666px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2081825" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EMILY-HOCHMAN-CEO.jpg?w=656" alt="Wellory CEO Emily Hochman" width="656" height="680" class="size-large wp-image-2081825" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EMILY-HOCHMAN-CEO.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EMILY-HOCHMAN-CEO.jpg?resize=145,150 145w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EMILY-HOCHMAN-CEO.jpg?resize=290,300 290w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EMILY-HOCHMAN-CEO.jpg?resize=768,796 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EMILY-HOCHMAN-CEO.jpg?resize=656,680 656w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EMILY-HOCHMAN-CEO.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EMILY-HOCHMAN-CEO.jpg?resize=48,50 48w" sizes="(max-width: 656px) 100vw, 656px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2081825" class="wp-caption-text">Wellory CEO Emily Hochman</p></div></p>
<p>Wellory officially launched in September, but Hochman said some beta testers have been using the service for nine, 10 or 11 months. She said early customers include people who are interested in weight loss, those who need nutrition advice due to chronic illness and &#8220;optimizers&#8221; who simply want to make sure they&#8217;re eating as healthily as possible.</p>
<p>She also noted that although customers usually sign up with a specific goal in mind, &#8220;once they hit their goal, because the power of a strong relationship, they say, &#8216;I don’t want to go back to where I was, let’s keep building, let&#8217;s make sure I can sustain this.'&#8221;</p>
<p>The app is available on iOS and Android and currently costs $59.99 per month. Hochman plans to introduce additional pricing tiers. and she said the funding will allow Wellory to expand the technology and marketing teams, and to explore new partnerships.</p>
<p>“As a data technology investor, we get approached by different types of wearable or diagnostic companies nearly every week,” said Jake Yormak of Story Ventures in a statement. “We love the category but what we saw in Wellory was a way to put a human coach at the center of understanding this health data. With nutrition as the wedge, Wellory has built a trusted relationship with people who affirmatively want to better understand and improve their wellbeing.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pIqRzBpygJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/3-growth-tactics-that-helped-us-surpass-noom-and-weight-watchers/">3 growth tactics that helped us surpass Noom and Weight Watchers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 growth tactics that helped us surpass Noom and Weight Watchers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/3-growth-tactics-that-helped-us-surpass-noom-and-weight-watchers/embed/#?secret=pIqRzBpygJ" data-secret="pIqRzBpygJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/wellory-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081794</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: Hacks for the March 2021 H-1B lottery?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/dear-sophie-hacks-for-the-march-2021-h-1b-lottery/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/dear-sophie-hacks-for-the-march-2021-h-1b-lottery/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 16:03:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B visa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081206</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We’ve been so focused on building our startup that we haven’t kept up with all the recent changes. What are we supposed to do?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/dear-sophie-can-an-h-1b-co-founder-own-a-delaware-c-corp/">Dear Sophie: Can an H-1B co-founder own a Delaware C Corp?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/11/dear-sophie-what-does-a-biden-win-for-tech-immigration/">Dear Sophie: What does Biden&#8217;s win mean for tech immigration?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>Extra Crunch members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<hr />
<p><i>Late-breaking update: since the time of writing this Dear Sophie column, U.S. District Judge Jeffrey White struck down two of the H-1B rules mentioned: increasing the prevailing wage and restricting the definition of &#8220;specialty occupation.&#8221; I&#8217;ll keep you posted on any further developments down the road, but for today, the entire nonimmigrant visa classification program is strengthened. Yay!</i></p>
<p><strong>Dear Sophie:</strong></p>
<p><strong> The startup I am co-founding will be sponsoring my co-founder for a visa in the March 2021 H-1B lottery.</strong></p>
<p><strong>We’ve been so focused on building our startup that we haven’t kept up with all the recent changes. What are we supposed to do?</strong></p>
<p><strong>—Focused in Foster City</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Dear Focused:</p>
<p>You are right on track as the time to start is now. In December, we usually kick off our H-1B planning and prep work with startups, companies, HR and people ops, employees and recruits for the spring lottery. Although there are a lot of recent proposals and changes, please go ahead now and initiate retaining counsel to put any and all potential candidates in the lottery.</p>
<p>Although there are several new rules slated to go into effect in December and early January, these are subject to potential removal by President-elect Biden and may also be the topic of a great deal of litigation, so we should proceed as usual. <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/what-we-do/h-1b_speciality_occupations/">H-1B</a> visas for specialty occupations are still available. In my recent <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/046-get-ready-for-h-1b-fy2022-lottery/">H-1B podcast</a>, I discuss what the 2021 lottery will look like and there’s a <a href="https://witty-author-184.ck.page/321063598c">free H-1B guide</a> for you to download. Same as before, you can also check out the podcast episode on <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/episode-09-what-makes-a-strong-h-1b-petition/">What Makes a Strong H-1B Petition</a>.</p>
<p>Looking into my crystal ball, the three new rules that may have the biggest effect on the H-1B process are:</p>
<ul>
<li>A <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/dear-sophie/dear-sophie-how-can-employers-hire-comply-with-all-this-new-h-1b-craziness/">new rule</a> by the U.S. Department of Labor (DOL), which went into effect immediately when it was announced in October. That rule substantially increased the minimum wage that employers are required to pay to H-1B candidates. According to the <a href="https://www.cato.org/blog/dol-said-its-h-1b-wage-rule-should-cost-many-employers-0-it-imposed-billions-costs-anyway?queryID=07311c916ee1204167ab505aef4ad0da">Cato Institute</a>, the average H-1B employer will have to increase wage offers to H-1B candidates by more than 30%. It’s not worth being concerned about this potential wage increase now as you don’t have to commit to a proposed wage for your future H-1B hire until your candidate is actually selected in the lottery and you prepare and file the full petition in Q2. And even then, the new wage wouldn’t take effect until the H-1B is approved and the earliest possible start date is October 1, 2021. So don’t let it scare you.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Another rule proposed by U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) in November seeks to replace the random H-1B selection process — or lottery — with a new selection process that would prioritize the selection of H-1B candidates based solely on the highest wages paid by the employers who sponsor them. It does not consider the experience of the candidate nor whether the candidate is a specialized worker in an in-demand field, such as medicine or research. Once again, we have no idea when and if this will actually go into effect. Although it sounds scary, it might actually be great for funded startups that need more predictability than a random lottery about whether key hires will be able to join the team.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Finally, a <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/dear-sophie/dear-sophie-how-can-employers-hire-comply-with-all-this-new-h-1b-craziness/">rule proposed </a>by USCIS in October requires an H-1B candidate to have a bachelor’s or higher degree specifically related to the specialty occupation the H-1B candidate is applying for and H-1B employers must show the position is directly related to the education degree. This for sure will be the subject of lots of litigation. If you’re hiring folks for professional or tech roles and you have funding to pay them, this isn’t really an issue, just an annoyance, and you can avoid questioning by doing a very thorough job on the original petition, which my firm specializes in.</li>
</ul>
<p>So tips and tricks: I am recommending that everyone begin preparing based on the <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/002-2020-h-1b-lottery-update/">H-1B lottery in 2020</a> and to consult with an immigration lawyer to devise a strategy and discuss options. Your co-founder needs to remain in valid legal status if they are already in the United States. If your startup/co-founder is not selected to apply for an H-1B, check out <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/044-7-of-the-most-startup-friendly-visas-explained/">7 of the Most Startup Friendly Visas Explained</a> for alternative options.</p>
<p>Your startup may want to explore whether it can bypass the H-1B visa altogether by sponsoring your co-founder for either an O-1A extraordinary ability visa, an EB-1A extraordinary ability green card or an EB-2 NIW (National Interest Waiver) green card. If you would like to learn more, we will be hosting a webinar on Wednesday, December 16 at 11 a.m. PST. We will have a special promotion and a freebie for those who attend. <a href="https://us02web.zoom.us/webinar/register/1816063397370/WN_F2X9Gqv4Q_yEJbj0OagBkQ">Register here!</a></p>
<p>If you proceed with pursuing an H-1B, make sure your startup has the appropriate corporate structure and documentation in place that demonstrates a valid employer-employee relationship exists between your startup and your co-founder. That includes making sure your co-founder will have a true employee relationship with the company and they will be hired, supervised and can be fired. Listen to my <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/episode-11-your-startups-first-h-1b/">podcast episode</a> on what startups should know about sponsoring their first H-1B candidate.</p>
<p>Your startup will need to register your co-founder for the H-1B lottery on March 1. The USCIS registration fee is only $10 so it’s easy to do it for everybody who might benefit. The registration process closes on March 20. If your startup is selected to apply for an H-1B on behalf of your co-founder, USCIS will inform your startup by March 31. Your startup will have until June 30 to submit its H-1B petition. Over the next few months, your startup and your co-founder can start assembling documents and evidence so that you’ll be ready if your startup/co-founder is selected to apply for an H-1B. If not selected in March, there may be a second digital lottery at the beginning of Q3 for any remaining H-1B visa slots.</p>
<p>I’ll continue to keep you and the other Dear Sophie readers informed on the latest changes to the H-1B lottery process here in this column, so stay tuned!</p>
<p>You got this — go for it!</p>
<p>Sophie</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">Have a question? Ask it here.</a> We reserve the right to edit your submission for clarity and/or space. The information provided in “Dear Sophie” is general information and not legal advice. For more information on the limitations of “Dear Sophie,” please view our full disclaimer <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/attorney-advertising">here</a>. You can contact Sophie directly at Alcorn Immigration Law.</p>
<p>Sophie&#8217;s podcast, <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/immigration-law-for-tech-startups/id1497746915">Immigration Law for Tech Startups</a>, is available on all major podcast platforms. If you&#8217;d like to be a guest, <a href="https://forms.gle/TsCtSJabKStwiUk88">she&#8217;s accepting applications!</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/dear-sophie-hacks-for-the-march-2021-h-1b-lottery/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081206</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google acquires Actifio to step into the area of data management and business continuity</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/google-acquires-actifio-to-step-into-the-area-of-data-management-and-business-continuity/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/google-acquires-actifio-to-step-into-the-area-of-data-management-and-business-continuity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 16:01:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[actifio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google cloud]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081807</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the same week that Amazon is holding its big AWS confab, Google is also announcing a move to raise its own enterprise game with Google Cloud. Today the company announced that it is acquiring Actifio, a data management company that helps companies with data continuity to be better prepared in the event of a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In the same week that Amazon is holding its big AWS confab, Google is also announcing a move to raise its own enterprise game with Google Cloud. Today the company <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/storage-data-transfer/google-enters-agreement-to-acquire-actifio">announced</a> that it is acquiring <a href="http://actifio.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Actifio</a>, a data management company that helps companies with data continuity to be better prepared in the event of a security breach or other need for disaster recovery. The deal squares Google up as a competitor against the likes of Rubrik, another big player in data continuity.</p>
<p>The terms of the deal were not disclosed in the announcement; we&#8217;re looking and will update as we learn more. Notably, when the company was valued at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/03/23/actifio-100million/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">over $1 billion</a> in a funding round back in 2014, it had said it was preparing for an IPO (which never happened). PitchBook data estimated its value at $1.3 billion in 2018, but earlier this year it appeared to be raising money at about a 60% discount to its recent valuation, according to data provided to us by Prime Unicorn Index.</p>
<p>The company was also involved in a patent infringement suit against Rubrik, which it also <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/actifio-initiates-patent-infringement-litigation-against-rubrik-301085531.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">filed earlier this year</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It had raised around $461 million, with investors including Andreessen Horowitz, TCV, Tiger, 83 North, and more.</p>
<p>With <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/actifio" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="actifio">Actifio, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Google is moving into what is one of the key investment areas for enterprises in recent years. The growth of increasingly sophisticated security breaches, coupled with stronger data protection regulation, has given a new priority to the task of holding and using business data more responsibly, and business continuity is a cornerstone of that.</p>
<p>Google describes the startup as as a &#8220;<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">leader in backup and disaster recovery&#8221; providing virtual copies of data that can be managed and updated for storage, testing, and more. The fact that it covers data in a number of environments &#8212; including SAP HANA, Oracle, Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, and MySQL, virtual machines (VMs) in VMware, Hyper-V, physical servers, and of course Google Compute Engine &#8212; means that it also gives Google a strong play to work with companies in hybrid and multi-vendor environments rather than just all-Google shops.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;We know that customers have many options when it comes to cloud solutions, including backup and DR, and the acquisition of Actifio will help us to better serve enterprises as they deploy and manage business-critical workloads, including in hybrid scenarios,&#8221; writes Brad Calder, VP, engineering, in the blog post. :In addition, we are committed to supporting our backup and DR technology and channel partner ecosystem, providing customers with a variety of options so they can choose the solution that best fits their needs.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company will join Google Cloud.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’re excited to join Google Cloud and build on the success we’ve had as partners over the past four years,” said Ash Ashutosh, CEO at Actifio, in a statement. “Backup and recovery is essential to enterprise cloud adoption and, together with Google Cloud, we are well-positioned to serve the needs of data-driven customers across industries.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/google-acquires-actifio-to-step-into-the-area-of-data-management-and-business-continuity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081807</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Loon&#8217;s stratospheric balloons are now teaching themselves to fly better thanks to Google AI</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/loons-stratospheric-balloons-are-now-teaching-themselves-to-fly-better-thanks-to-google-ai/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/loons-stratospheric-balloons-are-now-teaching-themselves-to-fly-better-thanks-to-google-ai/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 16:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[balloon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybernetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Montreal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081659</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Alphabet&#8217;s Loon has been using algorithmic processes to optimize the flight of its stratospheric balloons for years now – and setting records for time spent aloft as a result. But the company is now deploying a new navigation system that has the potential to be much better, and it&#8217;s using true reinforcement learning AI to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Alphabet&#8217;s Loon has been using algorithmic processes to optimize the flight of its stratospheric balloons for years now – and setting records for time spent aloft as a result. But the company is now deploying a new navigation system that has the potential to be much better, and it&#8217;s using true reinforcement learning AI to teach itself to optimize navigation better than humans ever could.</p>
<p>Loon developed the new reinforcement learning system, which it says is the first to be used in an actual product aerospace context, with its Alphabet colleagues at Google AI in Montreal over the past couple of years. Unlike its past algorithmic navigation software, this one is devised entirely by machine – a machine that&#8217;s able to calculate the optimal navigation path for the balloons much more quickly than the human-made system could, and with much more efficiency, meaning the balloons use much less power to travel the same or greater distances than before.</p>
<p>How does Loon know it&#8217;s better? They actually pitted the new AI navigation against their human algorithm-based prior system directly, with a 39 day test that flew over the Pacific Ocean. The reinforcement learning model kept the Loon balloon aloft over target areas for longer continuous periods, using less energy than the older system, and it even came up with some new navigational moves that the team has never seen or conceived of before.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>After this and other tests proved such dramatic successes, Loon actually then went ahead and deployed across its entire production fleet, which is currently deployed across parts of Africa to serve commercial customers in Kenya.</p>
<p>This is one of few real-world examples of an AI system that employs reinforcement learning to actively teach itself to perform better being used in a real-life setting, to control the performance of real hardware operating in a production capacity and serving paying customers. It&#8217;s a remarkable achievement, and definitely one that will be watched closely by others in aerospace and beyond.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/loons-stratospheric-balloons-are-now-teaching-themselves-to-fly-better-thanks-to-google-ai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081659</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AgentSync lands consecutive rounds as insurtech booms</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/agentsync-lands-consecutive-rounds-as-insurtech-booms/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/agentsync-lands-consecutive-rounds-as-insurtech-booms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 16:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AgentSync]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Craft Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david sacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Operator Collective]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081758</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning AgentSync, an insurtech startup focused on agent compliance management, announced a new funding round worth $6.7 million. The financing event, led by well-known SaaS founder David Sacks&#8217; Craft Ventures, included dollars from both Operator Collective and prior investors. The new capital will help AgentSync move faster, with co-founder and  CEO Niranjan Sabharwal saying [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a href="https://agentsync.io/">AgentSync</a>, an insurtech startup focused on agent compliance management, announced a new funding round worth $6.7 million.</p>
<p>The financing event, led by well-known SaaS founder <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/david-sacks" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="david-sacks">David Sacks&#8217; <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a href="https://www.craftventures.com/">Craft Ventures</a>, included dollars from both <a href="https://operatorcollective.com/">Operator Collective</a> and prior investors.</p>
<p>The new capital will help <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/agentsync" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="agentsync">AgentSync <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> move faster, with co-founder and  CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/akaniji/">Niranjan Sabharwal</a> saying that it is pulling hires earmarked for next year into 2020. He added that this most recent fundraising cycle consumed far less time than the round that preceded it.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>TechCrunch asked what the company is calling this round, which was raised via a SAFE note instead of as a priced equity investment. Sabharwal said that it could be called a Seed-Extension, which seems reasonable.</p>
<p>The new investment was raised at a cap of around 4x its previous conversion ceiling.</p>
<p>TechCrunch last <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/04/agentsync-raises-4-4m-for-its-insurtech-compliance-service/">covered AgentSync this August</a>, when the startup announced a $4.4 million funding round. Akin to fellow early-stage startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/welcome-raises-6m-to-help-your-company-hire-and-keep-employees/">Welcome,</a> which announced a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/welcome-raises-6m-to-help-your-company-hire-and-keep-employees/">second 2020 raise earlier today</a>, AgentSync managed to quickly raise again.</p>
<p>In AgentSync&#8217;s case, it&#8217;s not hard to parse why the company was able to: It&#8217;s growing very quickly.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EC24NtYWdv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/04/agentsync-raises-4-4m-for-its-insurtech-compliance-service/">AgentSync raises $4.4M for its insurtech compliance service</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;AgentSync raises $4.4M for its insurtech compliance service&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/04/agentsync-raises-4-4m-for-its-insurtech-compliance-service/embed/#?secret=EC24NtYWdv" data-secret="EC24NtYWdv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>According to an interview with <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/akaniji/">Sabharwal</a>, the company has seen its revenue scale 4x since the start of the pandemic, and 10x in the last year. The timeframes around those metrics are slightly relaxed, but the raw growth underscores that AgentSync is onto something.</p>
<p>Sabharwal founded the company with his spouse <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jlouiseknight/">Jenn Knight</a> and recently moved the company&#8217;s HQ to Denver from San Francisco.</p>
<p>AgentSync&#8217;s product, born out of a tool <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/10/05/zenefits-makes-licensing-compliance-app-available-for-free-in-the-salesforce-app-exchange/">that Zenefits developed</a> while rebuilding itself, helps insurance companies and other players in the insurance space ensure that agents are compliant (hence its name). And while that conceit might sound like a modest effort, it&#8217;s a complex effort given a multi-stakeholder environment, regulatory conditions, and an antiquated market.</p>
<p>The company saw strong initial traction, reporting $1.9 million ARR during its August round. Doing some mental math, if AgentSync was doing around $1 million ARR in March, it would be at around $4 million ARR today. That feels roughly correct, given the 4x-since-March metric, and the $1.9 million ARR datapoint from mid-Q2 2020.</p>
<p>According to Sabharwal, AgentSync now has more than $10 million in the bank, meaning that the startup is very well capitalized to continue scaling in the coming quarters. New investor Sacks is bullish about how large AgentSync could become, telling TechCrunch in an email that its &#8220;market is huge,&#8221; and that the &#8220;insurtech revolution is [still] in its infancy.&#8221;</p>
<p>But while AgentSync is growing quickly and has found reasonable product-market fit &#8212; 17% of its net ARR today was driven by what the company descried as net-organic expansion, to pick an example &#8212; it still has the hallmarks of an early-stage startup like inconsistent sales cycle length, according to several deals that the CEO detailed during an interview. However, the company recently hired a sales team after a period of time when Sabharwal was in charge of  selling; the company&#8217;s selling process should accelerate in coming quarters.</p>
<p>The CEO told TechCrunch that until recently he was selling AgentSync solo with no enterprise sales experience. If he could do it, he reasoned, others will be able to as well. Sabharwal serves as the startup&#8217;s CEO, while Knight is its CTO.</p>
<p>Closing, Insurtech is hot, meaning that AgentSync is growing amidst fertile market ground and investor interest. Another few quarters of similar growth and we could be hearing about its Series A.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iulvNpZkev"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/insurtechs-big-year-gets-bigger-as-metromile-looks-to-go-public/">Insurtech&#8217;s big year gets bigger as Metromile looks to go public</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Insurtech&#8217;s big year gets bigger as Metromile looks to go public&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/insurtechs-big-year-gets-bigger-as-metromile-looks-to-go-public/embed/#?secret=iulvNpZkev" data-secret="iulvNpZkev" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/agentsync-lands-consecutive-rounds-as-insurtech-booms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081758</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google says its News Showcase will add free access to paywalled stories</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/google-news-showcase-paywalled-stories/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/google-news-showcase-paywalled-stories/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 16:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081765</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google News Showcase visitors will soon be able to read select paywalled articles at no extra charge. That&#8217;s one of several announcements that the search giant made today about News Showcase, the program where it pays publishers (with $1 billion committed initially) to license their content for a new format in Google News. So far, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/google" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="google">Google <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> News Showcase visitors will soon be able to read select paywalled articles at no extra charge.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s one of <a href="https://blog.google/products/news/google-news-showcase-expands">several announcements</a> that the search giant made today about News Showcase, the program where it pays publishers (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/google-to-pay-out-1b-to-publishers-to-license-content-for-new-google-news-showcase/">with $1 billion committed initially</a>) to license their content for a new format in Google News. So far, Google News Showcase has launched in countries including Germany, Brazil, Argentina, Canada, France, U.K. and Australia — in several cases, those are markets where it&#8217;s previously faced legal challenges and antitrust scrutiny.</p>
<p>Google says it will be paying participating publishers to provide &#8220;limited access to paywalled content for News Showcase users.&#8221; Those users will, however, still need to register directly with the publishers, which Google says will give them a way to build a relationship. (Facebook has also been experimenting with ways to present paywalled content, in its case by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/28/facebook-subscription-account-link/">linking Facebook accounts to news subscriptions</a>.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The main News Showcase format is essentially story panel, and Google says it&#8217;s introducing a new panel allowing publishers to curate a daily selection of their most important stories. Those panels will be shown to users who follow those publishers.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2081840" style="width: 365px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2081840" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/DE_Device.gif?w=355" alt="Google News Showcase" width="355" height="680" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2081840" /><p id="caption-attachment-2081840" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>Google is also bringing the News Showcase to new devices and channels. It started out on Google News on Android and is now available on iOS as well, with plans to expand to the news.google.com website and Discover soon. And it says it has doubled the number of partners since the launch in October — the list of nearly 400 publishers participating in the program includes new names like Le Monde, Courrier International, L&#8217;Obs, Le Figaro, Libération and L’Express in France, plus Página12, La Gaceta and El Día in Argentina.</p>
<p>&#8220;As 2020 comes to a close, it is heartening to witness the progress of News Showcase and the enthusiasm from both publishers and readers around the world,&#8221; the company writes. &#8220;We will continue to engage and incorporate feedback as we build out features and grow the product to add to the future sustainability of our news partners.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="76ff54tfrs"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/google-to-pay-out-1b-to-publishers-to-license-content-for-new-google-news-showcase/">Google to pay out $1B to publishers to license content for new Google News Showcase</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google to pay out $1B to publishers to license content for new Google News Showcase&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/google-to-pay-out-1b-to-publishers-to-license-content-for-new-google-news-showcase/embed/#?secret=76ff54tfrs" data-secret="76ff54tfrs" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/google-news-showcase-paywalled-stories/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081765</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sight Tech Global is Live! Join top AI technologists and accessibility innovators discuss the future of assistive tech</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/sight-tech-global-is-live-join-top-ai-technologists-and-accessibility-innovators-discuss-the-future-of-assistive-tech/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/sight-tech-global-is-live-join-top-ai-technologists-and-accessibility-innovators-discuss-the-future-of-assistive-tech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Desmond]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 16:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accessibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sight Tech Global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081494</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today and tomorrow, from 8 a.m. to 12:30 p.m. the first annual, virtual event Sight Tech Global is streaming on TechCrunch. The event looks at how AI-based technologies are rapidly changing the field of accessibility, especially for blind people and those with low vision. Today&#8217;s programming includes AI giants Amnon Shashua and Kai-Fu Lee, as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today and tomorrow, from 8 a.m. to 12:30 p.m. the first annual, virtual event <a href="https://sighttechglobal.com/">Sight Tech Global</a> is streaming on TechCrunch. The event looks at how AI-based technologies are rapidly changing the field of accessibility, especially for blind people and those with low vision. Today&#8217;s programming includes <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/ai" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="ai">AI <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> giants Amnon Shashua and Kai-Fu Lee, as well as accessibility innovators from Waymo, Microsoft, Google, and more. Check out the event&#8217;s <a href="https://sighttechglobal.com/agenda/">full agenda.</a></p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/yiCuIQQ_HwY?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>The Sight Tech Global project aims to showcase the remarkable community of technologists working on accessibility-related products and platforms. It is a project of the non-profit <a href="https://www.vistacenter.org/">Vista Center for the Blind and Visually Impaired</a>, which is based in Silicon Valley. The Vista Center is the recipient of all <a href="https://sighttech.wufoo.com/forms/z1abf5av0bp7u6c/">donations</a> and sponsorships.</p>
<p>This year&#8217;s event sponsors include: Waymo, Verizon Media, TechCrunch, Ford, Vispero, Salesforce, Mojo Vision, iSenpai, Google, Microsoft, Wells Fargo, Amazon, Eyedaptic, Verizon 5G, Humanware, APH, and accessiBe. Our production partners: <a href="http://www.coherestudio.com/">Cohere Studio </a>(design),  <a href="https://www.sunolgroupmedia.com/">Sunol Media Group </a>(video production), <a href="https://makeitfable.com/">Fable </a>(accessibility crowd testing), <a href="https://www.claritymediagroup.com/team/marisa-thomas">Clarity Media</a> (speaker prep), <a href="https://www.bemyeyes.com/">Be My Eyes</a> (customer service), <a href="https://www.3playmedia.com/">3Play</a> and <a href="https://vitac.com/">Vitac</a>  (captioning).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/sight-tech-global-is-live-join-top-ai-technologists-and-accessibility-innovators-discuss-the-future-of-assistive-tech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081494</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Virta Health&#8217;s behavioral diabetes treatment service is now worth over $1 billion</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/virta-healths-behavioral-diabetes-treatment-service-is-now-worth-over-1-billion/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/virta-healths-behavioral-diabetes-treatment-service-is-now-worth-over-1-billion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 15:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alabama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caffeinated capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chronic disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diabetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managing partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obesity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital Global Equities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081801</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new $65 million investment led by the growth capital and public investment arm of Sequoia Capital will give Virta Health, a developer of a behavioral-focused diabetes treatment, a valuation of over $1 billion. Virta&#8217;s approach, which uses a combination of approaches to change diet and exercise to reverse the presence of type 2 diabetes [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A new $65 million investment led by the growth capital and public investment arm of <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/sequoia-capital" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="sequoia-capital">Sequoia Capital <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> will give <a href="http://www.virtahealth.com/?sbrc=1VW1bezOZlFkTyLbc-4r4YA%3D%3D%24K4YX7ewZ3cTb7DC4YVL6ZA%3D%3D&amp;sbrc=1WGUmwtGY-SXg_RzKuFRVJw%3D%3D%24XkFXpcQwJ7rtbyg1Ghx-HQ%3D%3D">Virta Health</a>, a developer of a behavioral-focused diabetes treatment, a valuation of over $1 billion.</p>
<p>Virta&#8217;s approach, which uses a combination of approaches to change diet and exercise to reverse the presence of type 2 diabetes and other chronic metabolic conditions, has shown clinical success and attracted 100 health care payers to endorse the company&#8217;s treatments.</p>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;We partnered with Virta for their ability to deliver unmatched health improvement and cost savings—two clear differentiators from other offerings on the market,” said William Ashmore, CEO of the State Employees’ Insurance Board of <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/alabama" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="alabama">Alabama, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> in a statement. “Especially amid the COVID-19 pandemic, it&#8217;s vital that we provide our members the life-changing results Virta is known for delivering, through expert, virtual care delivered right to their home.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p dir="ltr">The company said it would use the funding to expand sales and marketing efforts for its services as well as expand its research and development into other non-pharmaceutical therapies for metabolic conditions.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The financing came from Sequoia Capital Global Equities and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/caffeinated-capital" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="caffeinated-capital">Caffeinated Capital <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and brings the company&#8217;s total funding to over $230 million and gives it a $1.1 billion valuation, according to a statement.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Alongside Sequoia Capital Global Equities, Caffeinated Capital participated in the round, which brings total funding to more than $230 million and values Virta Health at over $1.1 billion.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Diabetes has long been an attractive condition for startups and has been the first target that companies focused on behavior changes to influence metabolic conditions aim to address. The reason why there are so many diabetes-focused businesses is because of the prevalence of the disease in the U.S. Almost half of adults in the U.S. suffer from obesity, pre-diabetes, or type 2 diabetes and the disease kills thirty people every hour. Diabetes also doubles the risk of death from COVID-19 infections.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Beyond the risks, the costs of treatment are skyrocketing. According to data from the American Diabetes Association released in March 2018, the total costs of treating diagnosed diabetes have risen to $327 billion in 2017 from $245 billion in 2012, when the cost was last examined.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“Given the scope of the metabolic crisis in the U.S. and globally, it cannot be understated how game-changing Virta’s results and care delivery are,” said Patrick Fu, managing partner at Sequoia Capital Global Equities, in a statement. “Virta’s technology-driven, non-pharmaceutical approach has fundamentally changed how diabetes is cared for, and our collective belief in what is possible for population health improvement. This is the future of chronic disease care.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/virta-healths-behavioral-diabetes-treatment-service-is-now-worth-over-1-billion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081801</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Salesforce applies AI to workflow with Einstein Automate</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/salesforce-applies-ai-to-workflow-with-einstein-automate/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/salesforce-applies-ai-to-workflow-with-einstein-automate/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 15:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Einstein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workflows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081780</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While Salesforce made a big splash yesterday with the announcement that it&#8217;s buying Slack for $27.7 billion, it&#8217;s not the only thing going on for the CRM giant this week. In fact Dreamforce, the company&#8217;s customer extravaganza is also on the docket. While it is virtual this year, there are still product announcements aplenty and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">While <a href="http://salesforce.com">Salesforce</a> made a big splash yesterday with the announcement that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/">it&#8217;s buying Slack for $27.7 billion</a>, it&#8217;s not the only thing going on for the CRM giant this week. In fact Dreamforce, the company&#8217;s customer extravaganza is also on the docket. While it is virtual this year, there are still product announcements aplenty and today the company announced Einstein Automate, a new AI-fueled set of workflow solutions.</p>
<p>Sarah Franklin, EVP &amp; GM of Platform, Trailhead and AppExchange at Salesforce says that she is seeing companies facing a digital imperative to automate processes as things move ever more quickly online, being driven there even faster by the pandemic. &#8220;With Einstein Automate, everyone can change the speed of work and be more productive through intelligent workflow automation,&#8221; she said in a statement.</p>
<p>Brent Leary, principal analyst at CRM Essentials says that combined these tools are designed to help customers get to work more quickly. &#8220;It&#8217;s not only about identifying the insight, it&#8217;s about making it easier to leverage it at the the right time. And this should make it easier for users to do it without spending more time and effort,&#8221; Leary told TechCrunch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Einstein is the commercial name given to Salesforce&#8217;s artificial intelligence platform that touches every aspect of the company&#8217;s product line, bringing automation to many tasks and making it easier to find the most valuable information on customers, which is often buried in an avalanche of data.</p>
<p>Einstein Automate encompasses several products designed to improve workflows inside organizations. For starters, the company has created Flow Orchestrator, a tool that uses a low-code, drag and drop approach for building workflows, but it doesn&#8217;t stop there. It also relies on AI to provide help suggest logical next steps to speed up workflow creation.</p>
<p>Salesforce is also bringing <a href="http://Mulesoft.com">Mulesoft</a>, the integration company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/20/salesforce-is-buying-mulesoft-at-enterprise-value-of-6-5-billion/">it bought for $6.5 billion in 2018</a> into the mix. Instead of processes like a mortgage approval workflow, the Mulesoft piece lets IT build complex integrations between applications across the enterprise, and the Salesforce family of products more easily.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Jk53FdQNnW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/20/salesforce-is-buying-mulesoft-at-enterprise-value-of-6-5-billion/">Salesforce is buying MuleSoft at enterprise value of $6.5 billion</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Salesforce is buying MuleSoft at enterprise value of $6.5 billion&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/20/salesforce-is-buying-mulesoft-at-enterprise-value-of-6-5-billion/embed/#?secret=Jk53FdQNnW" data-secret="Jk53FdQNnW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>To make it easier to build these workflows, Salesforce is announcing the Einstein Automate collection page available in AppExchange, the company&#8217;s application marketplace. The collection includes over 700 pre-built connectors so customers can grab and go as they build these workflows, and finally it&#8217;s updating the OmniStudio, their platform for generating customer experiences. As Salesforce describes it, &#8220;Included in OmniStudio is a suite of resources and no-code tools, including pre-built guided experiences, templates and more, allowing users to deploy digital-first experiences like licensing and permit applications quickly and with ease. &#8221;</p>
<p>Per usual with Salesforce Dreamforce announcements, the Flow Orchestrator being announced today won&#8217;t be available in beta until next summer. The Mulesoft component will be available in early 2021, but the OmniStudio updates and the Einstein connections collection are available today.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rjjVm4sK2S"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/">Salesforce buys Slack in a $27.7B megadeal</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Salesforce buys Slack in a $27.7B megadeal&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/embed/#?secret=rjjVm4sK2S" data-secret="rjjVm4sK2S" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/salesforce-applies-ai-to-workflow-with-einstein-automate/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081780</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A roundup of recent unicorn news</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/a-roundup-of-recent-unicorn-news/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/a-roundup-of-recent-unicorn-news/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 15:49:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postmates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081609</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The last few days have been so chock-a-block with news from a host of unicorns, we've all fallen behind.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">So much for a December news slowdown.</p>
<p>The last few days have been so chock-a-block with news from a host of unicorns, we&#8217;ve all fallen behind. This morning, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/army-air-force-exchange-service" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="army-air-force-exchange-service">The Exchange <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is going into summary mode to help us better understand the full scope of recent unicorn activity.</p>
<p>Why unicorns? It would be fun to noodle on early-stage news &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/salut-raises-1-25m-for-its-virtual-fitness-service/">Salut raised $1.25 million this week</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/yc-backed-buildbuddy-raises-3-15m-to-help-developers-build-software-more-quickly/">BuildBuddy picked up $3.15 million</a> &#8212; but as we&#8217;re in the midst of an IPO cycle and 2021 could have even more public debuts than 2020, we have to keep current on unicorn updates.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a>, or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>What will we cover, then? We&#8217;ll go back to Stripe&#8217;s possible new round and new valuation. We&#8217;ll touch on DoorDash and Airbnb&#8217;s expected IPO pricing, along with what we&#8217;ve learned from C3.ai&#8217;s own S-1 filings. There&#8217;s also Gainsight to talk about and the <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/slack" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="slack">Slack <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>-Salesforce deal.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995214 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>That&#8217;s just the tip of the proverbial iceberg. There&#8217;s also recent news from Coinbase, Tanium, Postmates, Olive, Scale AI, Sinch, Gitlab and Kustomer. Then there are rounds for HungryPanda, Flock Freight and Flexe that <em>might</em> make them unicorns — or something rather close. (Update: Also Bizzabo, apparently.)</p>
<p>You can see why it all feels a little overwhelming. But don&#8217;t worry, we can get caught up together. Let&#8217;s go!</p>
<h2>A cavalcade of unicorn updates</h2>
<p>There&#8217;s no way to make it through all of this news in a reasonable number of words without employing bullet points. Out of respect for your time, I&#8217;ll be brief. That said, each of the following news items is worth digging into further if it catches your fancy.</p>
<h3>Financial news</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>C3.ai</strong> dropped an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/c3-ais-initial-ipo-pricing-guidance-spotlights-the-public-markets-tech-appetite/">initial pricing range for its IPO</a>. Given how far the company&#8217;s growth <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/working-to-understand-c3-ais-growth-story/">has slowed</a>, C3.ai&#8217;s comfortable expected IPO valuation underscores how interested public markets are in software and tech shops. As far as a bellwether public offering, we have our eyes <em>fixed</em> on C3 and its expected debut that should come next week.</li>
<li><strong>DoorDash</strong> also released an initial price range this week with a valuation <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/doordash-aims-to-add-11-billion-to-its-valuation-during-public-offering/">that could stretch to $32 billion on a fully-diluted basis</a>. Simpler share counts give the company a valuation of between $23.8 billion and $27 billion at its $75 to $85 per share price target. Regardless of how you prefer to calculate market caps of public companies, DoorDash is expected to see a huge valuation bump in its debut. That&#8217;s great news for its investors and employees alike.</li>
<li><strong>Stripe</strong> could be <a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange-multicolor.jpg?w=430&amp;h=230&amp;crop=1">worth $100 billion in its next fundraise</a>. We don&#8217;t have new gross payment volume data from the company, but its top line has to be in the billions given what we knew a while back. Why doesn&#8217;t Stripe go public? The only good answer to that question is, I reckon, that it is investing in some super complicated stuff that won&#8217;t pay off for a while, so it&#8217;s taking its time to set up for an even more glorious future as a public company. If it is just being shy, I&#8217;ll be cross.</li>
<li><strong>Airbnb</strong> is back, baby! That&#8217;s pretty much all you need to know. In more granular detail, the company&#8217;s valuation <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/in-first-ipo-price-range-airbnbs-valuation-recovers-to-pre-pandemic-levels/">could stretch to $35 billion in its IPO</a>, though if you don&#8217;t count unexercised options and the like, the numbers run between $26.2 billion to $30.1 billion. No matter: The company&#8217;s IPO will be executed at a multiple of its mid-crisis valuation and can only be viewed as an impending fundraising success story. I have zero idea how the company will trade <em>after</em> floating, but Airbnb is about to raise quite a lot of <em>much</em> cheaper capital than it managed earlier in the year.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/a-roundup-of-recent-unicorn-news/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081609</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Space Perspective raises $7M for its plan to ferry tourists to the edge of space</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/space-perspective-raises-7m-for-its-plan-to-ferry-tourists-to-the-edge-of-space/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/space-perspective-raises-7m-for-its-plan-to-ferry-tourists-to-the-edge-of-space/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 15:36:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Base Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prime Movers Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space tourism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World View]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World View Enterprises]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081772</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Space tourism startup Space Perspective has raised a new $7 million in seed funding, from investors including Prime Movers Lab and Base Ventures . The company, founded by Jane Poynter and Taber MacCallum, who previously founded stratospheric balloon company World View, is focused on developing Spaceship Neptune, a pressurized passenger capsule that is meant to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/space-ecb7" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="space-ecb7">Space <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> tourism startup Space Perspective has raised a new $7 million in seed funding, from investors including <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/prime-movers-lab" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="prime-movers-lab">Prime Movers Lab <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/base-vc" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="base-vc">Base Ventures <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>. The company, founded by Jane Poynter and Taber MacCallum, who previously founded stratospheric balloon company World View, is focused on developing Spaceship Neptune, a pressurized passenger capsule that is meant to be carried by an ultra-high altitude balloon to the very edge of space to provide passengers with an unparalleled view.</p>
<p>Spaceship Neptune is designed to carry up to eight passengers per trip, on a six-hour journey that will include two hours spent at the upper edge of Earth&#8217;s atmosphere and a water landing in the Atlantic Ocean. The first test flight is currently targeted for the end of the first quarter of 2021, according to Space Perspective, and it will involve flying an uncrewed Neptune capsule prototype, which also won&#8217;t have the pressurized cabin of the final version.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VyM4Tj7484"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/18/startup-space-perspective-plans-space-tourist-cruises-using-stratospheric-balloons-with-test-flight-set-for-2021/">Startup Space Perspective plans space tourist &#8216;cruises&#8217; using stratospheric balloons, with test flight set for 2021</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Startup Space Perspective plans space tourist &#8216;cruises&#8217; using stratospheric balloons, with test flight set for 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/18/startup-space-perspective-plans-space-tourist-cruises-using-stratospheric-balloons-with-test-flight-set-for-2021/embed/#?secret=VyM4Tj7484" data-secret="VyM4Tj7484" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>From there, the plan is to test and develop systems necessary for Neptune to take up its first human passengers, with the goal of doing that by sometime around 2024, with ticket pre-sales launching from 2021 for interested, deep-pocketed parties.</p>
<p>Poynter and MacCallum&#8217;s prior venture World View originally included human stratospheric space tourism trips as part of its business model, but the company has since pivoted to focus on scientific and commercial communication and observation payloads exclusively under its current leadership. World View appointed Ryan Hartman as CEO in 2018, replacing Poynter in the top spot.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AQfwXnynad"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/03/watch-world-view-explain-its-unique-approach-to-space-business-and-tourism/">Watch World View explain its unique approach to space business and tourism</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Watch World View explain its unique approach to space business and tourism&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/03/watch-world-view-explain-its-unique-approach-to-space-business-and-tourism/embed/#?secret=AQfwXnynad" data-secret="AQfwXnynad" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/space-perspective-raises-7m-for-its-plan-to-ferry-tourists-to-the-edge-of-space/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081772</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Teen banking service Step raises $50M, adds TikTok star Charli D’Amelio to investor list</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/teen-banking-service-step-raises-50m-adds-tiktok-star-charli-damelio-to-investor-list/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/teen-banking-service-step-raises-50m-adds-tiktok-star-charli-damelio-to-investor-list/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 15:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081637</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Step, a mobile banking service aimed at teens, announced this morning it has raised $50 million in Series B funding after growing to over 500,000 users only two months after its official launch. The round was led by Coatue, with returning investors from Stripe, Crosslink Capital, Collaborative Fund, and Will Smith&#8217;s Dreamers VC. The startup [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.step.com/">Step</a>, a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/31/step-targets-teens-and-parents-with-a-no-fees-mobile-bank-account-and-visa-card/">mobile banking service aimed at teens</a>, announced this morning it has raised $50 million in Series B funding after growing to over 500,000 users only two months after its official launch. The round was led by Coatue, with returning investors from Stripe, Crosslink Capital, Collaborative Fund, and Will Smith&#8217;s Dreamers VC. The startup also added some celeb investors to this round, including Charli D’Amelio, Justin Timberlake, The Chainsmokers, as well as big names from the world of sports, like Eli Manning, Kelvin Beachum, Larry Fitzgerald and Andre Iguodala.</p>
<p>This is notably Charli D&#8217;Amelio&#8217;s first startup investment, Step tells TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The company had partnered with the TikTok star only a few weeks ago to promote the product and talk about financial literacy across her TikTok and Instagram accounts, which have 101.9 million and 34.4 million followers, respectively. Now she will do that not only as a partner and customer, but as an investor, as well.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;As a Step partner and customer, I’ve been able to see firsthand how easy Step makes it to manage your money while providing the educational resources that today’s teens need but have largely been unable to find—myself included,&#8221; said D’Amelio, in a statement. &#8220;I’m excited to be able to use my platform to help close this gap and have made a direct investment in Step to help them develop even more useful products.&#8221;</p>
<p>Other celeb investors may also promote the product on social media, including The Chainsmokers, but promotional deals aren&#8217;t finalized with the full list.</p>
<p>Smith, however, has <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/will-smith-7">been investing in startups</a> in recent years at the seed stage.</p>
<p>&#8220;As a person who hasn’t always had financial stability, and made many mistakes in that arena as a young man, I know the importance of financial education and having access to economic platforms that can work for everyone,&#8221; Smith said, in a statement. &#8220;While I’ve tried to instill that same mentality in my own children it was hard to find a banking platform that was intuitive and met our needs as a family. We’ve reinvested in Step because not only are their products built specifically for teens but they’ve started an important conversation around financial literacy that kids are actually engaged in.&#8221;</p>
<p>Other participants in the round include fintech executives from Facebook, Square, Venmo, Visa and others. To date, Step has raised over $75 million.</p>
<p>Though competing in now-crowded space of mobile banking services which replace traditional banks with an app on your phone, Step&#8217;s entry point to the market is different from most. It specifically targets teen users ages 13 to 18, by offering them an FDIC-insured bank account without fees, and a secured Visa card that helps them establish credit before they turn 18.</p>
<p>The app, meanwhile, also serves as a peer-to-peer (P2P) platform so they can send money to friends, similar to Apple Pay or Venmo.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2081789" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2081789" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2081789" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Step-Product-Visuals.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="732" height="322" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Step-Product-Visuals.jpg 2568w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Step-Product-Visuals.jpg?resize=150,66 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Step-Product-Visuals.jpg?resize=300,132 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Step-Product-Visuals.jpg?resize=768,338 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Step-Product-Visuals.jpg?resize=680,299 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Step-Product-Visuals.jpg?resize=1536,676 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Step-Product-Visuals.jpg?resize=2048,901 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Step-Product-Visuals.jpg?resize=50,22 50w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2081789" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Step</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;I think the best way to think about it is &#8216;Venmo meets Chase for the next generation,'&#8221; explains Step founder and CEO CJ MacDonald. &#8220;You have to be 18 to be on Venmo or Cash app, and [with those] you have to have an underlying bank account attached to that to get money in or money out. And most people don&#8217;t use Venmo or Cash app to spend money &#8212; they just use it to send and receive,&#8221; he says.</p>
<p>Combining P2P and banking in one platform has proven so far to be fairly popular. Step says it&#8217;s now adding around 7,000 to 10,000 new accounts per day, on top of the existing 500,000-plus users it already has. Much of this has comes from the organic, word-of-mouth growth offered by Step&#8217;s referral program, not paid ads. Step offers teens $3 (it used to be just $1) for every friend that signs up under their referral. The teens put the link in their Instagram bio or share it on Snapchat and soon they&#8217;ve made a decent amount of cash, even as much as $30 or $40.</p>
<p>In the near-term, Step plans to leverage its newly partnered celebs to help spread the word about mobile banking and financial responsibility across social media, and is hiring across the board in the face of its rapid growth. Longer-term, however, the company envisions helping teens take the next step in their financial future when they turn 18 with new products.</p>
<p>&#8220;The average college student graduates with thousands of dollars of credit card debt. The average college student also overdrafts two or three times a year, and traditional banking overdraft fees cost $35 in most cases,&#8221; says MacDonald. &#8220;When you go to college or you turn 18, you&#8217;re going to need some level of help. So we absolutely will offer new financial products and services tailored toward that demographic,&#8221; he says.</p>
<p>These products may include credit cards, loans, and more.</p>
<p>&#8220;Student loans are a big thing. Being able to extend credit to these folks. Being able to offer new products and services so they&#8217;re not paying these outrageous, predatory banking fees and high interest credit cards,&#8221; MacDonald, says, speaking to Step&#8217;s plans. &#8220;We&#8217;re really going to push the envelope and offer new types of products and services that are cost effective,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p>Step, based in San Francisco, currently has 50 employees and is hiring.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/teen-banking-service-step-raises-50m-adds-tiktok-star-charli-damelio-to-investor-list/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081637</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcome raises $6M to help your company hire and keep employees</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/welcome-raises-6m-to-help-your-company-hire-and-keep-employees/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/welcome-raises-6m-to-help-your-company-hire-and-keep-employees/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 15:14:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FirstMark Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081620</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome, the HR software that helps organizations make and close offers to new candidates, announced the close of a $6 million seed round today, led by FirstMark Capital. Participating investors include Ludlow Ventures, Nat Turner and Zach Weinberg, and Keenan Rice and Ben Porterfield (which were existing investors), as well as a wide array of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.heywelcome.com/">Welcome</a>, the HR software that helps organizations make and close offers to new candidates, announced the close of a $6 million seed round today, led by FirstMark Capital. Participating investors include Ludlow Ventures, Nat Turner and Zach Weinberg, and Keenan Rice and Ben Porterfield (which were existing investors), as well as a wide array of angels.</p>
<p>TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/welcome-raises-1-4m-to-streamline-the-hiring-process/">last covered Welcome in August</a>, when it announced a $1.4 million funding round. That the startup was able to raise more as quickly as it has is testament to how hot the early-stage venture capital market is today, and likely an endorsement of Welcome&#8217;s economic profile and recent growth.</p>
<p>Past the new capital, Welcome is also launching a new product today called Total Rewards, which helps not just new candidates but also existing employees get a complete, easy-to-understand picture of their compensation, across salary, benefits, equity, etc.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>But let&#8217;s back up.</p>
<p>Welcome was founded in 2019 by Nick Gavronsky and Rick Pereira, with a mission to help organizations close offers on candidates by providing a much clearer picture of compensation, particularly around equity. Cofounder and CEO Nick Gavronsky explained that many candidates don&#8217;t truly understand the value of the equity they&#8217;re offered, or how it works.</p>
<p>&#8220;A lot of recruiting teams aren&#8217;t well-equipped to use it as a selling tool and explain it effectively and showcase the value to candidates to help them think about their ownership at the company,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2081771" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2081771" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/4_Candidate-Equity.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="472" class="size-large wp-image-2081771" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/4_Candidate-Equity.png 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/4_Candidate-Equity.png?resize=150,104 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/4_Candidate-Equity.png?resize=300,208 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/4_Candidate-Equity.png?resize=768,533 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/4_Candidate-Equity.png?resize=680,472 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/4_Candidate-Equity.png?resize=1536,1067 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/4_Candidate-Equity.png?resize=2048,1422 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/4_Candidate-Equity.png?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2081771" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Welcome</p></div></p>
<p>Welcome allows companies to organize their compensation offers based on level and position, and deliver that information digitally to candidates in a way that makes sense.</p>
<p>The startup integrates with a variety of other software providers including Slack, Lever, Greenhouse, ADP and Justworks to name a few, simplifying onboarding for Welcome clients and bringing a broad array of information into one place.</p>
<p>Offers sent through Welcome show a description of the role, equity details, total compensation and even include a welcome note and video. This is in stark contrast to the black and white legal PDF often sent to candidates.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1_Candidate-Welcome-Note.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="472" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2081770" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1_Candidate-Welcome-Note.png 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1_Candidate-Welcome-Note.png?resize=150,104 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1_Candidate-Welcome-Note.png?resize=300,208 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1_Candidate-Welcome-Note.png?resize=768,533 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1_Candidate-Welcome-Note.png?resize=680,472 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1_Candidate-Welcome-Note.png?resize=1536,1067 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1_Candidate-Welcome-Note.png?resize=2048,1422 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1_Candidate-Welcome-Note.png?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>The next phase for the company comes in the form of the launch of Total Rewards, which is meant to help retain existing employees, helping them understand their compensation value and their potential at the company.</p>
<p>&#8220;Painting a better picture becomes a pre-retention tool,&#8221; said Gavronsky. &#8220;An employee will sometimes leave thousands of dollars on the table because they don&#8217;t understand what they&#8217;re walking away from. A lot of times companies will wait until that person is going to resign. Let me now bring up all the things that are great about our company and talk through your stock options. But the decision&#8217;s already made. So we wanted something that we can kind of put in with performance reviews.&#8221;</p>
<p>Welcome also has plans to offer a third product pillar in the form of real-time accurate industry-wide compensation data, helping companies understand where they fit into the larger ecosystem with regards to compensation.</p>
<p>Thus far, Welcome has 40 companies on the platform, including Uncork and Betterment, with hundreds on the waitlist according to the cofounders. The company plans to use the funding to build out the team and the product.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/welcome-raises-6m-to-help-your-company-hire-and-keep-employees/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081620</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Self-driving trucks startup TuSimple raises $350M from U.S. rail, retail and freight giants</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/self-driving-trucks-startup-tusimple-raises-350m-from-u-s-rail-retail-and-freight-giants/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/self-driving-trucks-startup-tusimple-raises-350m-from-u-s-rail-retail-and-freight-giants/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 15:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TuSimple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081531</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Self-driving trucks startup TuSimple has closed a $350 million funding round from a diverse consortium of strategic investors that include major U.S. corporations in rail, retail and freight, according to sources familiar with the deal.  The round, which was oversubscribed, was led by VectoIQ LLC, confirming a report by TechCrunch in September. VectoIQ is the consulting [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Self-driving trucks startup TuSimple has closed a $350 million funding round from a diverse consortium of strategic investors that include major U.S. corporations in rail, retail and freight, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">according to sources familiar with the deal. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The round, which was oversubscribed, was led by VectoIQ LLC, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/25/nikolas-steve-girsky-eyes-his-next-transportation-investment/">confirming a report by TechCrunch</a> in September. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">VectoIQ is the consulting and investment company founded by Steve Girsky, the former GM vice chairman, consultant and investor whose special purpose acquisition company merged with hydrogen electric startup Nikola Corp. this summer. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The injection of capital stands out not only because of its size, but the array of companies involved. Goodyear, Union Pacific, CN Rail, freight company U.S. Xpress and retailer Kroger all participated in the round, sources familiar with the deal told TechCrunch.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Existing investors Volkswagen AG’s heavy-truck business The Traton Group and Navistar also participated. (Last month, Traton, which already held a 16.6% stake in Navistar agreed to acquire its remaining shares.)</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/tusimple-llc" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="tusimple-llc">TuSimple <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has raised $648 million since its founding in 2015.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company declined to comment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TuSimple was one of the first autonomous trucking startups to emerge in what has become a small, yet bustling industry that now includes Aurora, Embark, Ike, Kodiak and Waymo. While TuSimple&#8217;s founding team and its earliest </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">backers Sina and Composite Capital are from China, a chunk of its operations are in the United States, including its global headquarters in San Diego. TuSimple also operates an engineering center and truck depot in Tucson and more recently set up a facility in Texas to support its autonomous trips —always with a human safety operator behind the wheel. TuSimple also has operations in Beijing and Shanghai. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As TuSimple has scaled with workforce and testing in the U.S., it has diversified its customer and investor base. The co</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">mpany has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/23/vws-traton-group-strikes-a-deal-with-tusimple-to-develop-autonomous-trucks/">attracted a number of investors</a> and partners in recent years, including UPS, Korean Tier 1 supplier Mando Corporation, Traton Group and now U.S. Xpress. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TuSimple raised $55 million in 2017 with plans to use those funds to scale up testing to two full truck fleets in China and the United States. By 2018, TuSimple began to test on public roads, beginning with a 120-mile highway stretch between Tucson and Phoenix in Arizona and another segment in Shanghai. TuSimple has since expanded operations into Texas. </span></p>
<p>Last year, the company&#8217;s valuation eked over the $1 billion-mark after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/13/autonomous-truck-startup-tusimple-hits-unicorn-status-in-latest-round/">raising $95 million</a> in a Series D funding round. It&#8217;s unclear what TuSimple&#8217;s new post-money valuation is.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/self-driving-trucks-startup-tusimple-raises-350m-from-u-s-rail-retail-and-freight-giants/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081531</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 888 will land on phones in Q1 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/qualcomms-snapdragon-888-will-land-on-phones-in-q1-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/qualcomms-snapdragon-888-will-land-on-phones-in-q1-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 15:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qualcomm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snapdragon 888]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078679</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As promised, more info following yesterday’s Snapdragon 888 announcement. First off, as expected, the company’s next flagship SoC will arrive in the first quarter of next year. We’re still waiting on specific models, but as noted yesterday, the San Diego-based chip giant already has a lineup of smartphone makers planning to employ the 765 follow-up, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As promised, more info following yesterday’s Snapdragon 888 announcement. First off, as expected, the company’s next flagship SoC will arrive in the first quarter of next year. We’re still waiting on specific models, but as noted yesterday, the San Diego-based chip giant already has a lineup of smartphone makers planning to employ the 765 follow-up, including ASUS, Black Shark, LG, MEIZU, Motorola, Nubia, realme, OnePlus, OPPO, Sharp, vivo, Xiaomi and ZTE.</p>
<p>The focuses are also what you’d expect: 5G, AI, speed, security, imaging and gaming. As <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/qualcomm" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="qualcomm">Qualcomm <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> announced earlier, the new system sports the third-gen X60 5G modem, which supports both sub-6 and mmWave variations of the wireless technology with speeds up to 7.5 Gbps. Also on board is support for Wi-Fi 6 and Bluetooth 5.2.</p>
<p>The sixth-gen version of the company’s AI Engine brings faster processing speeds at lower power consumption — specifically up to 3x performance per watt, per Qualcomm’s numbers. That’s capable of up to 26 tera operations per second (TOPS). Compare that to the “incredible” 5.5 TOPS the company was talking up on the Snapdragon 765 roughly this time last year. The AI stuff is primarily used to boost camera, gaming, connectivity and voice assistants like Google’s.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>On the camera side, the new chip features the improved Spectra 580, sporting the line’s first triple ISP (image signal processor). That’s going to go a ways toward fostering multi-camera setup, with the ability to simultaneously have three cameras at up to 2.7 gigapixels a second. The system also supports capture of three 4K HDR videos at once — overkill, perhaps, but neat. There’s improved low-light support as well, to brighten up dark shots — always a nice thing.</p>
<p>The on-board Adreno 660 GPU can do up to 35% faster graphics. The Kryo 680 — based on the new Arm Cortex-X1 architecture — brings up to a 25% uplift in CPU performance. Game rendering has been improved by up to 30%, and titles will get access to Variable Rate Shading — a first for a Qualcomm chip. As for security, the new chip offers a number of new features aimed at protecting on-device data, including the Qualcomm Secure Processing Unit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/qualcomms-snapdragon-888-will-land-on-phones-in-q1-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078679</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jitsu nabs $2M Seed to build open source data integration platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/jitsu-nabs-2m-seed-to-build-open-source-data-integration-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/jitsu-nabs-2m-seed-to-build-open-source-data-integration-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 15:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data integration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data warehouses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081639</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jitsu, a graduate of the Y Combinator Summer 2020 cohort, is developing an open source data integration platform that helps developers send data to a data warehouse. Today, the startup announced a $2 million seed investment. Costanoa Ventures led the round with participation from YCombintaor, The House Fund and SignalFire. In addition to the open [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://jitsu.com/">Jitsu</a>, a graduate of the Y Combinator Summer 2020 cohort, is developing an open source data integration platform that helps developers send data to a data warehouse. Today, the startup announced a $2 million seed investment.</p>
<p>Costanoa Ventures led the round with participation from YCombintaor, The House Fund and SignalFire.</p>
<p>In addition to the open source version of the software, the company has developed a hosted version that companies can pay to use, which shares the same name as the company. Peter Wysinski, Jitsu&#8217;s co-founder and CEO, says a good way to think about his company is an open source <a href="http://segment.com">Segment</a>, the customer data integration company that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/12/twilios-3-2b-segment-acquisition-about-helping-developers-build-data-fueled-apps/">was recently sold to Twilio for $3.2 billion</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>But he says, it goes beyond what Segment by allowing you to move all kinds of data whether customer data, connected device data or other types. &#8220;If you look at the space in general, companies want more granularity. So let&#8217;s say for example, a couple years ago you wanted to sync just your transactions from QuickBooks to your data warehouse, now you want to capture every single sale at the point of sale. What Jitsu lets you do is capture essentially all of those events, all of those streams, and send them to your data warehouse,&#8221; Wysinski explained.</p>
<p>Among the data warehouses it currently supports include Amazon Redshift, Google BigQuery, PostGres and Snowflake.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7XSRQKqWhu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/07/yc-grad-digitalbrain-snags-3-4m-seed-to-streamline-customer-service-tasks/">YC grad DigitalBrain snags $3.4M seed to streamline customer service tasks</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;YC grad DigitalBrain snags $3.4M seed to streamline customer service tasks&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/07/yc-grad-digitalbrain-snags-3-4m-seed-to-streamline-customer-service-tasks/embed/#?secret=7XSRQKqWhu" data-secret="7XSRQKqWhu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The founders built the open source project called <a href="https://github.com/jitsucom/eventnative">EventNative</a> to help solve problems they themselves were having moving data around at their previous jobs. After putting the open source version on GitHub a few months ago, they quickly attained 1000 stars, proving that they had delivered something that solved a common problem for data teams. They then built the hosted version, Jitsu, which went live a couple of weeks ago.</p>
<p>For now, the company is just the two co-founders, Wysinski and CTO Vladimir Klimontovich, but they intend to do some preliminary hiring over the next year to grow the company, most likely adding engineers. As they begin to build out the startup, Wysinski says that being open source will help drive diversity and inclusion in their hiring.</p>
<p>&#8220;The goal is essentially to go after that open source community and hire people from anywhere because engineers aren&#8217;t just [&#8230;] one color or one race, they&#8217;re everywhere, and being open source, and especially being in a remote world, makes it so so much simpler [to build a diverse workforce], and a lot of companies I feel are going down that road,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>He says along that line, the plan is to be a fully remote company, even after the pandemic ends, as they hire from anywhere. The goal is to have quarterly offsite meetings to check in with employees, but do the majority of the work remotely.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2jMTazLcVh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/12/twilios-3-2b-segment-acquisition-about-helping-developers-build-data-fueled-apps/">Twilio&#8217;s $3.2B Segment acquisition is about helping developers build data-fueled apps</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twilio&#8217;s $3.2B Segment acquisition is about helping developers build data-fueled apps&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/12/twilios-3-2b-segment-acquisition-about-helping-developers-build-data-fueled-apps/embed/#?secret=2jMTazLcVh" data-secret="2jMTazLcVh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/jitsu-nabs-2m-seed-to-build-open-source-data-integration-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081639</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shop-Ware raises cash as cars make a comeback</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/shop-ware-raises-cash-as-cars-make-a-comeback/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/shop-ware-raises-cash-as-cars-make-a-comeback/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 14:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bessemer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carolyn Coquillette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Series A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shop-Ware]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078764</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shop-Ware has been waiting for a year like 2020 since 2015. The startup, which sells software to neighborhood automotive shops to digitize their operations, had struggled to capture capital from venture firms. Until recently, its sole major investor was aftermarket automotive giant Bosch. For companies like Shop-Ware, the disruptive wake of COVID-19 has cleared a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.shop-ware.com/">Shop-Ware </a>has been waiting for a year like 2020 since 2015.</p>
<p>The startup, which sells software to neighborhood automotive shops to digitize their operations, had struggled to capture capital from venture firms. Until recently, its sole major investor was aftermarket automotive giant Bosch.</p>
<p>For companies like Shop-Ware, the disruptive wake of COVID-19 has cleared a path to capital as mainstream investors have sought out startups with services and products needed in the pandemic era. Investors finally get Shop-Ware founder <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/carolyn-coquillette/">Carolyn Coquillette</a>’s vision and business. Their endorsement: $15 million in funding through a Series A round led by Insight Partners.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“It’s a different level of validation in terms of this industry going through a transition and catching the eye of traditional investors,” Coquillette said.</p>
<p>Coquillette says Shop-Ware will use he funds to fuel growth across its operations, sales and marketing teams.</p>
<p>The fresh capital comes as Shop-Ware has tripled its customer base while also lowering churn, Coquillette said, although she would not disclose total revenue numbers or whether the company is profitable.</p>
<p>The idea of Shop-Ware began when Coquillette started her own San Francisco-based auto shop, Luscious Garage, in 2007. The goal from the get-go was to offer customers a peek into what happens in an auto shop. It meant more communications from the repair-person to the car-owner, and a software platform was the best way to do it. Eventually, the push for modernized software became less of an in-house project and more of a standalone company. By 2015, she had a product and an incorporated company.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Wh6pBCorYv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/10/12/how-a-unique-approach-to-auto-repair-led-to-a-new-kind-of-shop-software/">How a unique approach to auto repair led to a new kind of shop software</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How a unique approach to auto repair led to a new kind of shop software&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2016/10/12/how-a-unique-approach-to-auto-repair-led-to-a-new-kind-of-shop-software/embed/#?secret=Wh6pBCorYv" data-secret="Wh6pBCorYv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Shop-Ware helps auto-repair shops streamline operations both inside and out of the shop. Auto-repair shops are able to use Shop-Ware to track employee hours, inventory ordering and management and integrate with third-party tools such as Quickbooks. Shop-Ware also helps the neighborhood auto-repair worker communicate and charge customers through text or a web-based interface.</p>
<p>The intricacies of car ownership are something that Coquillette thinks that the average consumer doesn’t understand, so she built an entire business around adding more transparency to the clunky process.</p>
<p>“There is no way that a normal person is going to appreciate what it takes to fix their car,” Coquillette said. “The car is built to distract you and hide its complication for you by design so that you agree to buy it.” In other words, she says, you’re buying a “magic carpet.”</p>
<p>It’s an easy pitch for the most part, the founder says.</p>
<p>“Everybody who owns the car has gone to a repair shop and had an unsavory experience,” she said. “It&#8217;s pretty obvious to be like ‘oh yeah, you can make that experience less unsavory.’”</p>
<p>The real roadblock for the startup is convincing a business to adopt technology to change a process that isn’t technically broken. COVID-19 has been the impetus for auto shops — some of which have been steadfast in their pen-and-paper approach —to turn to a digital platform to communicate and operate.</p>
<p>The sector of digitizing auto-repair processes has grown considerably since Shop-Ware first launched five years ago.</p>
<p>Concierge startups such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/08/08/cardash-5-3-million/">CarDash</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/07/wrenchs-on-demand-vehicle-repair-and-maintenance-service-picks-up-20-million/">Wrench</a> have popped up over the past several years to give customers an easier way to request maintenance checks. The services consolidate auto repair shops under one, approachable umbrella, which Coquillette thinks is the wrong approach.</p>
<p>“I&#8217;m a real big believer that you need to enable those independent providers,” she said. “You have to basically let those special snowflakes be their own snowflakes.”</p>
<p>A closer competitor to Shop-Ware is <a href="https://www.shopmonkey.io/">Shopmonkey</a>, which raised a <a href="https://www.shopmonkey.io/post/shopmonkey-raises-a-25-million-series-b-led-by-bessemer-venture-partners">$25 million Bessemer-led Series B</a> in August. It is welcome competition, Coquillette remarks, because it has put an investment spotlight on the category.</p>
<p>“There’s been a wakeup call around autonomy and how we related to our cars,” she said.</p>
<p>Now it’s up to Shop-Ware to take that wakeup call and turn it into cash.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/shop-ware-raises-cash-as-cars-make-a-comeback/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078764</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Looking Glass’s next product is a holographic digital photo frame</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/looking-glasss-next-product-is-a-holographic-digital-photo-frame/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/looking-glasss-next-product-is-a-holographic-digital-photo-frame/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 14:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holograms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[looking glass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[portrait]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2077809</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Looking Glass’s technology is extremely cool, but has, thus far, been prohibitively expensive, ranging from $600 for its 8.9-inch product to $6,000 for the 15-inch model &#8212; and an undisclosed sum for its 32-inch 8K display. Portrait might not be the most technically ambitious or versatile product the Brooklyn-based startup has produced, but it&#8217;s easily [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Looking Glass’s technology is extremely cool, but has, thus far, been prohibitively expensive, ranging from $600 for its 8.9-inch product to $6,000 for the 15-inch model &#8212; and an undisclosed sum for its 32-inch 8K display. Portrait might not be the most technically ambitious or versatile product the Brooklyn-based startup has produced, but it&#8217;s easily the most accessible.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/4pJxdNRA1CM?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>At $349, it’s still not cheap (though it&#8217;s <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/lookingglass/looking-glass-portrait">$199 if you get in early via Kickstarter</a>), but it has to be one of the most affordable holographic displays on the market. Along with the pricing, the company is taking a more populist approach to functionality, as well, offering up what is essentially a very advanced digital photo frame. The system offers up to 100 different perspectives on a 3D image, which, unlike products like Sony’s new 3D display, can be viewed by multiple people at once.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2077814" style="width: 710px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2077814" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2077814" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Sloth-Face-Tracking.gif" alt="" width="700" height="369" /><p id="caption-attachment-2077814" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Looking Glass</p></div></p>
<p>The system can also be run without being tethered to a computer. Its standalone mode relies on a built-in computer to deliver a 60 FPS holographic image. Those photos, meanwhile, can be captured with an iPhone and edited into a 3D image using the included HoloPlay Studio software. Holographic videos can also be captured with Azure Kinect and Intel RealSense cameras.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uD2umxA6bc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/07/looking-glass-is-targeting-enterprises-and-eventually-gamers-with-8k-holographic-display/">Looking Glass is targeting enterprises and eventually gamers with 8K holographic display</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Looking Glass is targeting enterprises and eventually gamers with 8K holographic display&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/07/looking-glass-is-targeting-enterprises-and-eventually-gamers-with-8k-holographic-display/embed/#?secret=uD2umxA6bc" data-secret="uD2umxA6bc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“It’s the first step toward holographic video calls,” the company notes, perhaps tipping its hand a bit about future plans.</p>
<p>“Ever since I was a little kid, I dreamed of the moment that I’d be able to have a holographic display of my own,” CEO Shawn Frayne says in the release. “I imagined what it would be like to send someone a holographic birthday message, or to say hello as a hologram to my great-great-great granddaughter. Looking Glass Portrait, the culmination of six years of work by our Brooklyn and Hong Kong based team, makes those dreams real for more people than ever before.”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2077815" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/58o-View-Cone.gif" alt="" width="700" height="394" /></p>
<p>The Portrait goes up on Kickstarter today, and will be available to early backers for $199.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tGVoZGkCZX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/26/looking-glass-starts-shipping-its-8k-holographic-display/">Looking Glass starts shipping its 8K holographic display</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Looking Glass starts shipping its 8K holographic display&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/26/looking-glass-starts-shipping-its-8k-holographic-display/embed/#?secret=tGVoZGkCZX" data-secret="tGVoZGkCZX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/looking-glasss-next-product-is-a-holographic-digital-photo-frame/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2077809</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jio Platforms backs SF-based AR gaming startup Krikey</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/reliance-jio-platforms-backs-sf-based-ar-gaming-startup-krikey/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/reliance-jio-platforms-backs-sf-based-ar-gaming-startup-krikey/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 13:59:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jio Platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reliance jio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081624</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jio Platforms, the biggest telecom operator in India and which has raised over $20 billion from Facebook, Google and other high-profile investors this year, is leading a financing round of a San Francisco-based startup that develops augmented-reality mobile games. Jio has led the Series A fundraise of Krikey, founded by sisters Jhanvi and Ketaki Shriram, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Jio Platforms, the biggest telecom operator in India and which has raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/15/google-invests-4-5-billion-in-indias-reliance-jio-platforms/">over $20 billion from Facebook, Google</a> and other high-profile investors this year, is leading a financing round of a San Francisco-based startup that develops augmented-reality mobile games.</p>
<p>Jio has led the Series A fundraise of Krikey, founded by sisters Jhanvi and Ketaki Shriram, the Indian firm said on Wednesday. They did not disclose the size of Krikey&#8217;s Series A round, but Jio said Krikey has raised $22 million to date.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.krikey.com/">Krikey</a> has previously not disclosed any financing rounds, according to their listings on Crunchbase, CBInsights, and Tracxn. Jio also did not share who else participated in Krikey&#8217;s new round.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As part of the announcement, Krikey has launched Yaatra, a new AR game that invites users to step in an action-adventure story to defeat a monster army. “Using weapons such as the bow and arrow, chakra, lightning and fire bolts, players can battle through different levels of combat and puzzle games,” Krikey said.</p>
<p>Jio subscribers in India will get exclusive access to a range of features in Krikey, available on Android and iOS, including a 3D avatar, and entry to some game levels and weapons. Jio said Yaatra game would also be made available to JioPhone feature phone users.</p>
<p>Krikey has developed two additional games in the past, including Gorillas, a game the startup developed in partnership with Ellen DeGeneres&#8217;s wildlife foundation.</p>
<p>&#8220;We believe AR has a huge potential in not just gaming but in many other industries to disrupt the way people interact with the world around them. We are very excited to use the phone as the window back into the natural world and hope that people&#8217;s experiences in empathising with birds and guerrillas and different ecosystems will encourage them to start to take real-world conservation behaviour changes,&#8221; said Jhanvi in an <a href="https://cheddar.com/media/how-krikey-is-using-ar-to-support-ellens-wildlife-fund">interview with Cheddar</a> last year.</p>
<p>“Our vision with Krikey is to bring together inspiration and reality in an immersive way. With augmented reality, we are able to bring fantasy worlds into your home, straight through the window of your mobile phone,” said Jhanvi and Ketaki Shriram in a joint statement today. They have previously participated in Apple&#8217;s female entrepreneur camp.</p>
<p>In a statement, Akash Ambani, Director of Jio, said, “Krikey will inspire a generation of Indians to embrace Augmented Reality. Our vision is to bring the best experiences from across the world to India and the introduction of Yaatra is a step in that direction. Augmented Reality gaming takes the user into a world of its own, and we invite every Jio and non-Jio user to experience AR through Yaatra.”</p>
<p>Jio has previously <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/05/jiosaavn/">acquired music streaming service Saavn</a> (which has since been rebranded to JioSaavn), and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/04/reliance-jio-buys-haptik-for-100-million/">Haptik</a>, a startup that develops conversational platforms and virtual assistants.</p>
<p>We have reached out to Jio and Krikey for more details.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/reliance-jio-platforms-backs-sf-based-ar-gaming-startup-krikey/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081624</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Florida-based logistics provider ShipMonk raises $290 million on the back of rising eCommerce demand</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/florida-based-logistics-provider-shipmonk-raises-290-million-on-the-back-of-rising-ecommerce-demand/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/florida-based-logistics-provider-shipmonk-raises-290-million-on-the-back-of-rising-ecommerce-demand/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 13:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief technology officer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[czech republic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online purchases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[order management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pennsylvania]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programmer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summit partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081606</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jan Bednar started ShipMonk with $70,000 in winnings from a string of student business plan competitions and launched the business that just closed on $290 million in new funding from a small warehouse with no air conditioning in the middle of Florida. While Bednar&#8217;s new offices are still inside the warehouse his company operates, they [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Jan Bednar started <a href="https://www.shipmonk.com/">ShipMonk</a> with $70,000 in winnings from a string of student business plan competitions and launched the business that just closed on $290 million in new funding from a small warehouse with no air conditioning in the middle of Florida.</p>
<p>While Bednar&#8217;s new offices are still inside the warehouse his company operates, they now have air conditioning&#8230; and a $290 million financing round from <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/summit-partners" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="summit-partners">Summit Partners <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> to grow its business.</p>
<p>The Ft. Lauderdale, Fla.-based ShipMonk provides a slew of shipping and logistics services for small to medium-sized eCommerce businesses and right now &#8212; given the continuing COVID-19 pandemic &#8212; business is good.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">We help SMBs and mid-market direct to consumer companies manage their supply chains. Help get their products from suppliers to facilities and connect with all of their sales channels including B2B … order management, transportation management, reverse logistics,&#8221; said Bednar. </span></p>
<p>The company&#8217;s largest customers can book anywhere from $150 million to $250 million in revenue, but most of ShipMonk&#8217;s customers are actually small businesses pulling in between $1 million and $10 million on average.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s for these businesses that ShipMonk will fill its warehouses in Pennsylvania, California and Florida with 60,000 stock keeping units &#8212; managing around 50 different items for each customer it serves.</p>
<p>Bednar said ShipMonk would use the new cash to continue to upgrade its automation services and increase its staffing while also looking to expand internationally.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Profitable from the outset, ShipMonk just came off one of its best years, taking in upwards of $140 million in revenue. </span></p>
<p>Bednar began the business alone, but quickly brought on co-founders Kevin Seitz, who handles marketing for the business, and Bosch Jares, a fellow native of the Czech Republic (like Bednar) who serves as the company&#8217;s chief technology officer.</p>
<p>The story of how Jares joined the business is indicative of the type of hustle that&#8217;s allowed Bednar to grow a booming tech and logistics business from the Ft. Lauderdale beaches.</p>
<p>It was the Florida weather that sold Jares, a college student from one of the Czech Republic&#8217;s top technical institutions, on the move to ShipMonk. Bednar had posted an internship opportunity to work (unpaid, but offering room and board) at his company on a college job board in the middle of January. The applications came pouring in, but it was Jares, a programmer who had been working with computers since age 14 who took the slot.</p>
<p>The rest&#8230; is ShipMonk history. Jares built the bulk of the backend for the company&#8217;s initial services spending nearly 20 hours a day coding.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The thriftiness and hard work has won ShipMonk a booming business that has grown from 15,000 square feet of warehousing space into nearly 1 million square feet of storage space and a logistics service that spans the U.S. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Timing for the new round couldn&#8217;t be better, as National Retail Federation estimates are banking on a 20% bump in new online sales &#8212; which could reach $202 billion this year. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Black Friday alone raked in $9 billion in online purchases, according to data from Adobe Analytics provided by the company, and consumer spending is only going to continue to move online as the pandemic continues to threaten the health and safety of American consumers.  </span></p>
<p>ShipMonk&#8217;s technology integrates with shopping cart and marketplace platforms like <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/shopify" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="shopify">Shopify <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> to import orders across sales channels, which are then processed at the company&#8217;s warehouse locations. Customers can save up to 50% on their operational costs, according to the company.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We believe ShipMonk truly demonstrates the power of a bootstrapped, durable growth mindset. Jan identified a significant gap in the market and, together with the ShipMonk team, has scaled the business in a deliberate and capital efficient manner to address that need. The results have been impressive,” said Christopher Dean, a Managing Director at Summit Partners who is taking a seat on the company&#8217;s board. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/florida-based-logistics-provider-shipmonk-raises-290-million-on-the-back-of-rising-ecommerce-demand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081606</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
