<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 23:35:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Facebook Oversight Board calls on Meta to evaluate its role in spreading violence in Ethiopia</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/facebook-ethiopia-oversight-board/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/facebook-ethiopia-oversight-board/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 23:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook Misinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[misinformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Oversight Board, a group Facebook created to review its policy decisions, weighed in on a case of misinformation in war-torn Ethiopia Tuesday, warning the company about the risks of allowing hate speech and unverified information to spread freely in conflict zones. The Oversight Board reviewed a post in Amharic from an Ethiopia-based Facebook user [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Oversight Board, a group Facebook created to review its policy decisions, <a href="https://oversightboard.com/news/927673894608838-oversight-board-upholds-meta-s-original-decision-case-2021-014-fb-ua/">weighed in</a> on a case of misinformation in war-torn Ethiopia Tuesday, warning the company about the risks of allowing hate speech and unverified information to spread freely in conflict zones.</p>
<p>The Oversight Board reviewed a post in Amharic from an Ethiopia-based Facebook user that claimed the Tigray People’s Liberation Front (TPLF) was responsible for murder, rape and looting in Raya Kobo and other population centers in the country&#8217;s Amhara region, aided by Tigrayan civilians.</p>
<p>&#8220;While the user claims his sources are previous unnamed reports and people on-the-ground, he does not even provide circumstantial evidence to support his allegations,&#8221; the Oversight Board wrote in its evaluation.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247593" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;Rumors alleging that an ethnic group is complicit in mass atrocities, as found in this post, are dangerous and significantly increase the risk of imminent violence.&#8221;</p>
<p>The post was initially detected by Facebook&#8217;s automated content moderation tools and removed when the platform&#8217;s Amharic language content review team determined it violated the platform&#8217;s rules against hate speech. Facebook reversed its own decision and reinstated the content after the case was escalated to the Oversight Board.</p>
<p>The Oversight Board overturned Facebook&#8217;s decision to reinstate the post, citing a violation of Facebook&#8217;s rules against violence and incitement rather than the hate speech rules the platform had cited previously. In its decision, the group expressed concern that the spread of unverifiable rumors in violence-stricken areas like Ethiopia could &#8220;lead to grave atrocities, as was the case in Myanmar.&#8221;</p>
<p>The month, a group of Rohingya refugees in the U.S. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/rohingya-lawsuit-against-facebook-wake-up-call-social-media-2021-12-10/">filed a $150 billion class-action suit against Meta</a>, alleging that Facebook&#8217;s entrance into the country served as a &#8220;key inflection point&#8221; in the genocide of the Rohingya people. Misinformation stoking ethnic violence in Myanmar spread broadly on Facebook, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/15/technology/myanmar-facebook-genocide.html">often sown by military personne</a>l, and is widely believed to have escalated ethnic violence that targeted and displaced the country&#8217;s Muslim minority.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Facebook <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/facebook-oversight-board-frances-haugen/">whistleblower Frances Haugen</a> has cited algorithmically-amplified ethnic violence in countries like Myanmar and Ethiopia — and Meta&#8217;s failure to adequately address it — as one of the platform&#8217;s biggest dangers. &#8220;What we saw in Myanmar and are now seeing in Ethiopia are only the opening chapters of a story so terrifying, no one wants to read the end of it,” Haugen told Congress in October.</p>
<p>The Oversight Board also instructed Meta to order an independent human rights assessment on Facebook and Instagram&#8217;s role in exacerbating the risk of ethnic violence in Ethiopia and to evaluate how well it can moderate content in the country&#8217;s languages.</p>
<p>Last month, Meta <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/11/update-on-ethiopia/">defended</a> the safety precautions it had taken in the country, highlighting expanded applications of some of its rules against misinformation and hate speech. The company also noted that it had improved its enforcement abilities there in the past two years and now has the capability to review content in Amharic, Oromo, Somali, Tigrinya, the four most common languages.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JNIzS7POaS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/facebook-oversight-board-frances-haugen/">Facebook&#8217;s Oversight Board will meet with the Facebook whistleblower</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook&#8217;s Oversight Board will meet with the Facebook whistleblower&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/facebook-oversight-board-frances-haugen/embed/#?secret=JNIzS7POaS" data-secret="JNIzS7POaS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="w70OIP2n7k"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/06/facebook-still-isnt-taking-myanmar-seriously/">Facebook still isn&#8217;t taking Myanmar seriously</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook still isn&#8217;t taking Myanmar seriously&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/06/facebook-still-isnt-taking-myanmar-seriously/embed/#?secret=w70OIP2n7k" data-secret="w70OIP2n7k" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wkOgPV55IL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-raises-trust-and-security-questions-over-its-e2e-encryption/">Facebook whistleblower, Frances Haugen, raises trust and security questions over its e2e encryption</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook whistleblower, Frances Haugen, raises trust and security questions over its e2e encryption&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-raises-trust-and-security-questions-over-its-e2e-encryption/embed/#?secret=wkOgPV55IL" data-secret="wkOgPV55IL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/facebook-ethiopia-oversight-board/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247593</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Netflix drops subscription fees in India as it battles for market share</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/daily-crunch-103/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/daily-crunch-103/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 23:10:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247482</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PST, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for Tuesday, December 14! Our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/what-to-expect-today-day-one-at-tc-sessions-space-2021/">Space event is underway and kicking maximum Q thus far</a>, I am happy to report. In other TechCrunch news, I just hit my two-year mark being back at the blog. Time flies! Thanks to everyone for reading my rambling so that I can stay aboard the good ship TechCrunch. Now, the news! —<a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/what-to-expect-today-day-one-at-tc-sessions-space-2021/"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-2230086 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/11521.png" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/11521.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/11521.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/11521.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/11521.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/11521.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/11521.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/11521.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247482" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/apple-launches-its-siri-only-apple-music-voice-plan-with-ios-15-2/">Apple’s Siri-only music plan launches:</a></strong> I had forgotten all about Apple’s cheaper, more limited music plan announced earlier this year. But it’s not only real, it’s here. So, if you are big into Apple speaker tech and want to save a few bucks, here’s a music streaming option for you. Notably, part of the innovation is a lower price, which, frankly, given streaming economics, is not the direction I want to see music services go.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/metaverse-startup-with-1m-in-2021-revenues-going-public-via-spac/"><strong>This may be peak SPAC:</strong></a><strong> </strong>To cap 2021’s more silly stories off with a cherry, a metaverse-themed company with around $1 million in revenue is going public via a SPAC. Naturally, it has big expectations for future revenue growth. The company is betting that public-market investors are sufficiently smitten with all things metaverse to bid up its equity. Let’s see.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/big-cartel-staff-are-voluntarily-recognized-as-the-latest-tech-workers-union/"><strong>Big Cartel unionizes:</strong></a> In the wake of news <a href="https://nypost.com/2021/12/12/amazon-worker-texted-girlfriend-he-wasnt-allowed-to-leave-warehouse/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">that Amazon workers died in their facility after a tornado hit it</a>, you might be curious about the progress of unionization among workers for tech companies. Slowly, is the answer to that. But startups are taking the lead again, with Big Cartel choosing to voluntarily recognize its employee union. Confused? Yes, leadership has been scarce in this area from the corporate perspective.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>Kicking off today, here’s a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/gift-guide-5-gifts-for-all-of-us-who-need-less-screen-time/">guide from our own Sarah Perez concerning what gifts to buy</a> if you are looking to cut your, or your loved one’s, screen time. I need this.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/garner-health-raises-45m-series-b-for-totally-objective-doctor-review-service/">How many stars does your doctor have?</a> </strong>Garner Health is betting that you want to look up doctor reviews before picking your provider. The company’s work landed a $45 million Series B, TechCrunch reports. Given just how big the healthcare market is, the company’s TAM is effectively infinite.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/in-the-age-of-remote-work-opal-offers-a-glimpse-at-the-future-of-webcams/"><strong>The new webcam status symbol:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Everyone’s <a href="https://twitter.com/sp990/status/1470857694823079936" target="_blank" rel="noopener">talking about Opal</a>, at least on my Twitter feed. The company built a $300 webcam that looks nifty, and, we presume, will actually be in stock. This deep into the pandemic, lots of folks still have spotty internet, poor lighting and more. Perhaps the startup didn’t miss its window.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/andreessen-horowitz-backs-nft-investor-group-behind-one-of-a-kind-wu-tang-clan-album-purchase/"><strong>a16z backs PleasrDAO:</strong></a> The decentralized autonomous organization (DAO) PleasrDAO has collected backing from a16z, which TechCrunch notes is not the first time that the investing group has backed a DAO. Pleasr’s claims to fame appear to be that it bought a doge NFT for $4 million and spent millions more on a Wu-Tang Clan album.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/pair-eyewear-focuses-in-on-adult-glasses-as-it-takes-in-60m/"><strong>Pair raises $60M:</strong></a><strong> </strong>While we’re sufficiently far past the Warby Parker founding story now <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/warby-parker-makes-it-clear-that-direct-listings-are-unicorn-friendly/">that the company is public</a>, startups aren’t letting the eyeglasses game rest. Pair, which builds eyewear that allows for inexpensive modification, just closed its second round of the year. Previously, the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/pair-eyewear-raises-12m-to-bring-more-personality-to-your-glasses/">raised $12 million in April</a>. A quick perusal of its service while writing this newsletter for you left me wanting a pair, for whatever my limited fashion sense is worth. It’s worth noting that Warby Parker remains above its $40 per-share IPO price. More on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/d2c-specs-purveyor-warby-parker-files-to-go-public/">the Warby DTC IPO from earlier this year</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/in-person-event-sound-streaming-service-mixhalo-raises-24m/"><strong>Mixhalo raises Series B for live audio mixing:</strong></a> The live events business may have been little more than moribund during the last few years, but Mixhalo is far from dead, it turns out. The company, focused on live audio for, well, live events just closed a Series B.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/carto-raises-61-million-to-help-you-visualize-data-on-maps/"><strong>Mapping data is big business:</strong></a> If you go back into the depths of startup time, there was once this big moment for “mashups.” The idea was to take two data sets and smush them together. This led to sites like Mashable — get it? — being formed. The mashup movement wound up subsumed into other tech work. Or was it? Carto just raised a $61 million Series C for what TechCrunch describes as helping companies display “data on interactive maps so that you can more easily compare, optimize, balance and make decisions.” Maps plus data? Sounds like a mashup.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/mesh-payments-racks-up-50m-to-help-corporate-users-manage-spend-and-payments/">Today’s Tiger round is Mesh Payments:</a> </strong>Helping companies manage their spend is a simply huge startup category. Ramp, Brex, Airbase and others are working on the issue in the United States, for example. International competitors abound as well. Today TechCrunch noted that Mesh Payments, another player in the space, just raised a $50 million round led by the ever-present Tiger.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/weather-focused-ibisa-raises-seed-round-to-back-its-microinsurance-solutions-for-low-income-small-farmers/"><strong>Luxembourg-based IBISA raises microround for microinsurance:</strong></a> I dig this one. Focused on providing coverage for “small farmers whose livelihoods might be affected by adverse climate events,” IBISA just raised about $1.7 million in a new capital round. The company, despite its European roots, focuses on developing markets.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/fresha-a-business-platform-for-salons-spas-and-beauty-and-wellness-pros-extends-series-c-by-52-5m-at-a-640m-valuation/"><strong>Vertical SaaS remains an investable category:</strong></a><strong> </strong>In the wake of Squire raising successive rounds for its barbershop vertical SaaS play, we should not be shocked that Fresha has raised a $52.5 million round of capital today. The company sells software for the beauty and wellness industry.</li>
</ul>
<p>Finally, as we segue into today’s TechCrunch+ feature story, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/the-irrational-exuberance-of-web3/"><strong>our own Ron Miller is not as convinced as some about the web3 hype</strong></a>. Others are more excited:</p>
<h2>7 investors discuss web3’s present and peer into its future</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2247293" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/7-investors-discuss-web3s-present-and-peer-into-its-future/"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2247293" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2247293 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1348853917.jpg" alt="Young asian woman with virtual reality simulator while standing in living room and wood material wall background" width="1024" height="633" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1348853917.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1348853917.jpg?resize=150,93 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1348853917.jpg?resize=300,186 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1348853917.jpg?resize=768,475 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1348853917.jpg?resize=680,421 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1348853917.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2247293" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Poca+Wander" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Poca Wander <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’re years away from web3 capturing major market share, and there are valid concerns that its complexity will daunt consumers and regulators. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, our research indicated that the investment landscape is growing increasingly competitive as venture capitalists become more educated and less skeptical.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To get a clearer sense of where the market is, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/7-investors-discuss-web3s-present-and-peer-into-its-future/">we reached out to several active investors</a> to find out where web3 stands and what the future holds:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lior Messika, founder and managing partner, Eden Block</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Atul Ajoy, partner, Horseshoe Capital</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">David Chreng-Messembourg, founding partner, LeadBlock Partners</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Randy Glein, founder/partner, and Sam Shapiro, principal, DFJ Growth</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mercedes Bent, partner, Lightspeed Venture Partners</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jai Das, co-founder, president and partner, Sapphire Ventures</span></li>
</ul>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</span></i><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> You can sign up here</span></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.)</span></i></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/coinbase-will-let-you-view-your-nft-collection-in-its-browser-wallet/">Coinbase adds image viewing feature:</a> </strong>If you use ​​Coinbase Wallet on desktop, you can now check out your NFTs. We’d normally make some jokes here about the tech required to view images on computers, but we don’t want to get into a Twitter war with Bored Ape fans.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/snap-paid-250-million-to-creators-on-its-tiktok-clone-this-year/"><strong>Snap paid out a quarter billion this year to support its TikTok clone:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Snap’s Snapchat service is an interesting social product to watch. It has never given up on its slight angle on the social world, and its parent company has not been shy in using its capital resources — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/06/snap-looks-to-raise-1-billion-in-private-debt-offering/">the company raised debt some years ago</a> — to keep the platform well stocked. Today the company announced that it has paid creators $250 million to make content for Spotlight, which is similar to TikTok.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/cash-app-now-lets-users-gift-stock-and-bitcoin-using-their-usd-balance-or-a-debit-card/">Cash App now lets users gift stock, crypto:</a> </strong>The ability to gift crypto is not new per se, but to see Cash App roll out the capability could allow for more mass-market crypto gifting. Recall that Cash App is no longer owned by Square, it’s owned by <em>Block</em>, its newly rebranded parent company.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/cma-mobile-ecosystem-market-study/"><strong>The UK is looking to shake up Google, Apple:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The war between third-party developers and the major mobile app store companies continues around the world, with news out today that the “U.K.’s antitrust watchdog has given the clearest signal yet that interventions under an upcoming reform of the country’s competition rules will target” Apple (iOS) and Google (Android).</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/pony-ai-suspension-driverless-pilot-california/"><strong>A self-driving setback:</strong></a> Daily Crunch has made much mention of self-driving milestones this year, covering new commercial partnerships and tentative in-market movements. But there was some negative progress today, namely that Chinese autonomous driving startup Pony.ai has had its California test permit revoked following a crash.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/struggling-to-win-subscribers-netflix-cuts-prices-in-india/"><strong>Netflix cuts prices in India:</strong></a><strong> </strong>We’ve noted in this missive that Netflix is getting into the games business. Why? Because there are only so many people with enough money and internet access out there for Netflix to sell streaming services to. Evidence of the company starting to bump up against its natural market size is that the American streaming service is cutting prices in India. As our own Manish Singh notes, this is not the first time that the company has tinkered with its pricing in the country.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2217068" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217068" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217068" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg" alt="dc experts" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217068" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants to know which software consultants you’ve worked with for anything from UI/UX to cloud architecture. Let us know <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/MXehi2kl?typeform-source=techcrunch.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re curious about how these surveys are shaping our coverage, check out this interview by Anna Heim: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/10/from-ph-d-to-boutique-software-developer-an-interview-with-solweys-andrew-drach/">“From Ph.D. to boutique software developer: An interview with Solwey’s Andrew Drach.”</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/daily-crunch-103/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247482</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2022 Porsche Taycan GTS Sport Turismo delivers power and performance in a wagon</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/2022-porsche-taycan-gts-cross-turismo-delivers-power-and-performance-in-a-wagon/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/2022-porsche-taycan-gts-cross-turismo-delivers-power-and-performance-in-a-wagon/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Abigail Bassett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 23:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Electrify America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Porsche]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Porsche Taycan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246933</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[All good things come to those who wait, and Porsche has reserved the most powerful version of its all-electric Taycan for last: the 2022 Porsche Taycan GTS and the wagon-style Taycan GTS Sport Turismo. For those who want power, refined and sporty driving, and the ability to forgo gasoline for an all-electric powertrain, the Taycan [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">All good things come to those who wait, and Porsche has reserved the most powerful version of its all-electric Taycan for last: the 2022 Porsche Taycan GTS and the wagon-style Taycan GTS Sport Turismo.</p>
<p>For those who want power, refined and sporty driving, and the ability to forgo gasoline for an all-electric powertrain, the Taycan GTS and Taycan GTS Sport Turismo both offer a solid blend of high-tech and powerful performance, which TechCrunch had a chance to test recently. GTS now comes in every model line Porsche offers, and the 2022 Porsche Taycan GTS and GTS Sport Turismo round out a total of 10 different Porsche Taycan offerings.</p>
<p>The upshot: The Sport Turismo GTS and its sedan sibling should be the benchmark for any luxury automaker trying to attract customers who want to make the transition from internal combustion to all-electric as smooth, seamless and reliable as possible. The drawback of course is that being a luxury vehicle puts the Taycan — and its many variants — out of reach for most people.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246933" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Before Porsche purists sharpen their knives about how the Taycan and its variants aren&#8217;t &#8220;true Porsches,&#8221; they might consider how the EV has resonated with consumers. The electric vehicle, first announced in 2019, has been a tremendous sales success for the company. Porsche <a href="https://newsroom.porsche.com/en/2021/company/porsche-increase-deliveries-quarter-3-2021-26063.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sold 28,640 Taycan vehicles</a> in the January-to-September period of 2021, outselling its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/15/porsches-all-electric-taycan-outsells-its-flagship-911-sports-car/">flagship 911 sports car</a> as well as the Panamera, 718 Boxster and 718 Cayman vehicles. (Porsche&#8217;s two most popular vehicles, the Cayenne and Macan, still outpaced the Taycan in sales.)</p>
<p>While the Taycan doesn&#8217;t come close to the number of Tesla Model 3 and Y sales reported this year, it has, so far, outstripped Tesla&#8217;s Model S and X sales. Tesla reports show that the company has delivered 13,214 Model S and Xs <a href="https://tesla-cdn.thron.com/static/TWPKBV_TSLA_Q3_2021_Quarterly_Update_SI1AKE.pdf?xseo=&amp;response-content-disposition=inline%3Bfilename%3D%22TSLA-Q3-2021-Quarterly-Update.pdf%22" target="_blank" rel="noopener">through the end of the third quarter</a>.</p>
<p>The sales numbers suggest that Porsche&#8217;s $1 billion investment in the development of the Taycan have paid off. My time in these two latest and last variants verify that those development dollars were well spent. The 2022 Porsche Taycan GTS and Taycan GTS Sport Turismo are a sports sedan and wagon to be reckoned with.</p>
<h2>On the road with the Porsche Taycan GTS Sport Turismo</h2>
<p>Porsche unveiled the new <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/16/porsche-takes-the-gts-electric-with-the-taycan-sedan-and-sporty-wagon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Taycan GTS and Sport Turismo GTS</a> at an event prior to the LA Auto show a few weeks ago, and we got seat time in both vehicles just after the unveiling in and around the Los Angeles area.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Taycan GTS and GTS Sport Turismo sit below the line-topping 670-horsepower Turbo variant. Porsche says that Taycan GTS can accelerate from 0-60 miles per hour in just 3.5 seconds thanks to its 590-horsepower and 626 pound-ft of torque coming from a pair of permanent magnet synchronous motors at the front and rear of the car. That means that both variants of the GTS are all-wheel drive, though during normal driving, the balance of power is pushed down through the rear wheels.</p>
<p>That rear motor comes from the Porsche Taycan Turbo, and Porsche says that this makes the GTS more agile and responsive on the road.</p>
<p>The motors are powered by a 93.4 kWh battery pack on 800-volt architecture, in both vehicles. That allows the vehicle to fast charge from 5% battery power up to 80% in just 22 minutes, which we got to try out at a DC fast charger in a local Walmart parking lot.</p>
<p>I drove a bright red Taycan GTS Sport Turismo from downtown Los Angeles to Willow Springs (a one-way trip of around 90 miles) and back across the winding Angeles Crest Highway and Lake Hughes Road and back to downtown.</p>
<p>The heavier wagon-style GTS Sport Turismo never belied that it had that big ol&#8217; backside hanging out. Agile, responsive, and comfortable in the variety of modes that ranged from the electron-sipping Range setting to Normal, Sport, Sport + and Individual, the GTS Sport Turismo is a luxurious and mighty powerful electric wagon.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2235485" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/8_Taycan-GTS.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2235485" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2235485 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/8_Taycan-GTS.jpg" alt="Porsche Taycan GTS roof" width="2000" height="1333" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/8_Taycan-GTS.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/8_Taycan-GTS.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/8_Taycan-GTS.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/8_Taycan-GTS.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/8_Taycan-GTS.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/8_Taycan-GTS.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/8_Taycan-GTS.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2235485" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Porsche</p></div></p>
<p>Whether making a pass on a two-lane highway near Willow Springs or winding it over the sun-beaten concrete on the Crest, the GTS Sport Turismo lives up to its Porsche-touted moniker as the &#8220;sweet spot,&#8221; between the lower 4S and the top-of-the-line Turbo &#8212; and it&#8217;s specifically geared for those who want a sports car feel in an all-electric people hauler.</p>
<p>Porsche recalibrated the Porsche Active Suspension Management System, retuned the chassis, added an optional rear-steering system and adaptive anti-roll bars in the car we drove. In addition to this, the Taycan GTS and its wagon-y cousin get a new, optional, trick sunroof that goes from opaque to various stages of staggered panels, to clear, with the touch of a button. The roof is actually made of two panes of glass with liquid crystal nestled between, which creates a UV-blocking grey panel when fully activated or closed.</p>
<h2>At the track with the Porsche Taycan GTS</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2247005" style="width: 1610px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-abigail.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2247005" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2247005 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-abigail.jpg" alt="porsche taycan gts electric vehicle willow springs" width="1600" height="812" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-abigail.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-abigail.jpg?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-abigail.jpg?resize=300,152 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-abigail.jpg?resize=768,390 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-abigail.jpg?resize=680,345 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-abigail.jpg?resize=1536,780 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-abigail.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2247005" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Abigail Bassett</p></div></p>
<p>More than likely, most Taycan GTS buyers won&#8217;t ever track their sedan, but, for that very small handful of people who do, there&#8217;s plenty to be impressed with. The Taycan GTS sedan still offers ample room for four passengers and all the bells and whistles of the Taycan GTS Sport Turismo, without the hatchback styling. Instead of hauling a wagon around the track at Big Willow, which honestly, sounds like a blast, I climbed into a Taycan GTS sedan for a 30-minute lead-follow stint.</p>
<p>The Taycan GTS comes with Porsche&#8217;s Track Precision app, which integrates with the new PCM 6.0 system in the car. Connect the app on your phone to the car and you can get detailed, real-time data on speeds, braking force, accelerator and brake input, and other information about just how you&#8217;re driving on the track. Mount your phone on your windshield and you&#8217;ll get the added bonus of a first-person POV video of the track that the app maps to everything from throttle input to steering angle and brake pressure.</p>
<p>Willow Springs is a notoriously gnarly track both because of its age and its sans-landmark, off-camber turns. On the track, the Taycan GTS remained firmly planted as I rocketed up to 120 mph on the front straight. Larger front brakes on the Taycan GTS (the same on the Sport Turismo) helped quickly haul the electric sedan down to more manageable speeds for the series of turns that run up the hill to a blind but sweeping left-hand turn and the vehicle felt connected and precise.</p>
<p>To say that the Taycan GTS is quick is an understatement. I drove Big Willow for the first time in a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/23/lamborghini-huracan-sto-a-final-celebration-before-electrification/">Lamborghini Huracán STO</a> back in September. I don&#8217;t proclaim to be a race car driver, but, for context, my Porsche app-recorded lap time in the Taycan GTS sedan was only four seconds off of my best time in the STO &#8212; and that vehicle is specifically made for the race track. Suffice it to say, the Taycan GTS hauls on a closed course.</p>
<h2>Charging the Porsche Taycan GTS Sport Turismo</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2247003" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-cross-abigail.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2247003" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2247003 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-cross-abigail.jpg" alt="porsche taycan gts sport turismo " width="2000" height="1506" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-cross-abigail.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-cross-abigail.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-cross-abigail.jpg?resize=300,226 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-cross-abigail.jpg?resize=768,578 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-cross-abigail.jpg?resize=680,512 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-cross-abigail.jpg?resize=1536,1157 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/porsche-taycan-gts-cross-abigail.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2247003" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Abigail Bassett</p></div></p>
<p>Once our track time was over, I climbed back into the GTS Sport Turismo for the slog back to downtown Los Angeles. When I set out from the hotel that foggy Saturday morning, I started out with a fully charged battery and a range of 235 miles.</p>
<p>By the time we got to Willow Springs, after some spirited highway and canyon driving, the vehicle had around 130 miles of range left. The route was around 90 miles in total (one way) and I spent most of the drive toggling the wheel on the Race-Tex wrapped steering wheel, between Range, Sport + and Individual settings. These settings adjust the suspension, power and steering feel, and even the synthetic &#8220;engine sound&#8221; you hear on the Taycan GTS. The Individual setting, where I could separately set the steering feel and the ride to my liking, was my favorite.</p>
<p>Los Angeles traffic is perpetual, which can pose a challenge for some electric vehicles and their range. I stopped at a Porsche-appointed stopover to charge the Taycan GTS at one of the public Electrify America chargers in Burbank with around 70 miles of range left.</p>
<p>On a Saturday night, the place was absolutely packed with shoppers and EV chargers alike. There was only one DC fast charger, and according to the Porsche rep manning the charger to help journalists plug in, it had been out of service almost all day. When I arrived a Ford Mustang Mach-E was charging at the spot, so I pulled into one of the others that were vacant. To no EV owner&#8217;s surprise, the charger wouldn&#8217;t initiate for my GTS Sport Turismo. I tried three other chargers in the row, before finally returning to the DC fast charger, which, miraculously, connected and quickly charged my Taycan GTS Sport Turismo from 25% to 80% in just 20 minutes.</p>
<p>While this was a problem specific to the Electrify America charger, not Porsche, it is indirectly a problem for any automaker counting on this network of DC fast chargers to help it compete with Tesla and its proprietary Supercharger network. The Electrify America chargers at that location continually failed to recognize the vehicle I was driving. When other journalists showed up to charge, they too, had a similar issue and we all got to play charger leapfrog with a handful of electric motorcycles and cars to find a charger that would work.</p>
<h2>User experience</h2>
<p>While the charging infrastructure still needs a lot of work, the good news is that Porsche has made locating those chargers in its navigation system far easier than other electric automakers (with the exception of Tesla).</p>
<p>There are three different ways to find available chargers in the system. You can use the capable voice recognition to ask for local chargers, which will then pop up on the navigation system for you choose. You can also use the touchscreen to set search parameters (including the brand of EV charger and speed of charge) to search for chargers nearby.</p>
<p>Finally, you can use the Porsche app or the navigation in the infotainment system to set a route and the system will automatically find chargers along the route based on how much charge you want to have left when you arrive at your destination. The vehicles I drove were European-spec so I wasn&#8217;t able to try this setup myself, but one of the sedans at the track had some limited U.S-features available and a Porsche spokesperson walked me through the process.</p>
<p>In addition to being able to access these features via the center screen, Porsche&#8217;s new infotainment screen stretches across to the passenger side of the car and allows passengers to search for chargers, change stereo inputs and stations, and navigate (amongst other things) while the vehicle is under way. Most automakers lock out access to these features in their vehicles both from the driver and passenger seats when they&#8217;re moving, a &#8220;feature,&#8221; that&#8217;s absolutely infuriating when actively trying to navigate or find locations while moving. It&#8217;s not so in the Taycan GTS and Taycan GTS Sport Turismo, since both the driver and passenger can still interact with numerous features on the infotainment system while the vehicle is rolling.</p>
<p>The 2022 Porsche Taycan GTS and Taycan GTS Sport Turismo will be delivered to customers willing to shell out for the $110,000+ price tag by Q2 of 2022. Pricing starts at $131,400 (plus $1,350 for delivery) for the sedan and $133,300 for the Sport Turismo. And in true Porsche style, nearly everything can be customized to your liking. Both offer plenty of performance and style for the proverbial buck in sleek, sleeper packaging that offers a solid balance of technology and refinement for the enthusiast and their passengers.</p>
<p>The 2022 Porsche Taycan GTS, in any form, is truly an electric vehicle to be reckoned with.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/2022-porsche-taycan-gts-cross-turismo-delivers-power-and-performance-in-a-wagon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246933</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TechCrunch+ roundup: Web3 investor survey, conversational UX, &#8216;insane IPO pops&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/techcrunch-roundup-web3-investor-survey-conversational-ux-insane-ipo-pops/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/techcrunch-roundup-web3-investor-survey-conversational-ux-insane-ipo-pops/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 22:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semantic web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247523</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“I never met a skeptical investor who actually understood what was going on. If you get it, you’re probably strapped in and ready to go."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Most people have experienced the internet only through Web 2.0. Online applications, the social web and software as a service form the fabric of our lives.</p>
<p>Lately, many have championed web3 as the internet’s next phase, but the term encompasses so much territory, conversations can be diffuse and there are valid concerns that its complexity will daunt consumers and regulators.</p>
<p>However, our research indicated that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/7-investors-discuss-web3s-present-and-peer-into-its-future/">the web3 investment landscape is growing increasingly competitive</a> as venture capitalists become more educated.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247523" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><i>Full TechCrunch+ articles are only available to members.<br />
<a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">Use discount code <strong>TCPLUSROUNDUP</strong></a> to save 20% off a one- or two-year subscription.</i></p>
<hr />
<p>To get a clearer sense of where the market is, we reached out to several active investors:</p>
<ul>
<li>Lior Messika, founder and managing partner, Eden Block</li>
<li>Atul Ajoy, partner, Horseshoe Capital</li>
<li>David Chreng-Messembourg, founding partner, LeadBlock Partners</li>
<li>Randy Glein, founder/partner, and Sam Shapiro, principal, DFJ Growth</li>
<li>Mercedes Bent, partner, Lightspeed Venture Partners</li>
<li>Jai Das, co-founder, president and partner, Sapphire Ventures</li>
</ul>
<p>To make things as clear as possible, we asked each respondent to share their elevator pitch: How would they describe the technology if they were trying to convince a skeptic to invest?</p>
<p>Starting with the potential consumer appeal of cartoon apes, we tried to find out what attracted them to invest in the semantic web and where they’re currently seeing demand. Notably, several said they started exploring the space after developing an interest in crypto.</p>
<p>In addition to discussing potential use cases for advertising, fintech and enterprise apps, respondents shared advice for web3 founders who are hunting for funding, along with their concerns about factors that could stall its development.</p>
<p>Finally, we asked each respondent: What are the skeptics missing?</p>
<p>“I never met a skeptical investor who actually understood what was going on. If you get it, you’re probably strapped in and ready to go,” said Lior Messika, founder and managing partner, Eden Block.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading,</p>
<p>Walter Thompson<br />
Senior Editor, TechCrunch+<br />
<a href="https://www.twitter.com/yourprotagonist">@yourprotagonist</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jOWor3DSBK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/7-investors-discuss-web3s-present-and-peer-into-its-future/">7 investors discuss web3&#8217;s present and peer into its future</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;7 investors discuss web3&#8217;s present and peer into its future&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/7-investors-discuss-web3s-present-and-peer-into-its-future/embed/#?secret=jOWor3DSBK" data-secret="jOWor3DSBK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Metaverse startup with $1M in 2021 revenues going public via SPAC</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996008" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996008" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1996008 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996008" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>InfiniteWorld, a metaverse startup that &#8220;anticipates 2021 revenues of around $1 million,&#8221; is going public today via a SPAC that will value the company &#8220;at around $700 million,&#8221; reports Alex Wilhelm in this morning&#8217;s edition of The Exchange.</p>
<p>Alex reviewed the company&#8217;s investor deck to learn more about InfiniteWorld, &#8220;a collection of traditional and blockchain-related efforts that could be used to support crypto work by customer brands.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sah2kkNPd8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/metaverse-startup-with-1m-in-2021-revenues-going-public-via-spac/">Metaverse startup with $1M in 2021 revenues going public via SPAC</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Metaverse startup with $1M in 2021 revenues going public via SPAC&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/metaverse-startup-with-1m-in-2021-revenues-going-public-via-spac/embed/#?secret=sah2kkNPd8" data-secret="sah2kkNPd8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Conversational UX: The missing piece in your chatbot strategy</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2246520" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246520" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2246520 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1146233297.jpg" alt="Close​ up​ robot on a yellow background" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1146233297.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1146233297.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1146233297.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1146233297.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1146233297.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1146233297.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246520" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=krung99" target="_blank" rel="noopener">krung99 <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>We don’t run many TechCrunch+ articles that are focused on basic best practices, but we make exceptions for posts about emerging technology — in this case, conversational UX.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It’s notoriously difficult for software to mimic human conversation. Many chatbots are so inept, it makes one long for the days of &#8220;press 0 for an operator.&#8221;</p>
<p>“Though chatbots are largely meant to handle simple customer service tasks, there is an opportunity to scale both customer service and sales messaging,” writes Raghu Ravinutala, CEO and co-founder of Yellow.ai, a conversational CX platform.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XmdHpExCDM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/conversational-ux-the-missing-piece-in-your-chatbot-strategy/">Conversational UX: The missing piece in your chatbot strategy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Conversational UX: The missing piece in your chatbot strategy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/conversational-ux-the-missing-piece-in-your-chatbot-strategy/embed/#?secret=XmdHpExCDM" data-secret="XmdHpExCDM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>What 2021’s IPO pops tell us about future flotations and SPACs</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996009" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996009" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996009" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996009" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>As we edge closer to the end of the year, we&#8217;re running more articles that look back at some of the trends we covered in 2021, along with a few that offer well-informed predictions for 2022.</p>
<p>Yesterday, Alex Wilhelm looked back at &#8220;insane IPO pops&#8221; for companies like DoorDash, C3.ai, Roblox, Coinbase and others to see whether these debuts were a reflection of &#8220;early exuberance,&#8221; inflated expectations, or possibly, the fact &#8220;that no one knows how to price IPOs during chaotic market moments.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HXZvYP5tdU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/what-2021s-ipo-pops-tell-us-about-future-flotations-and-spacs/">What 2021&#8217;s IPO pops tell us about future flotations and SPACs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What 2021&#8217;s IPO pops tell us about future flotations and SPACs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/what-2021s-ipo-pops-tell-us-about-future-flotations-and-spacs/embed/#?secret=HXZvYP5tdU" data-secret="HXZvYP5tdU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>3 views: The new decentralized venture landscape is changing how we report startup data</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2088024" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2088024" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2088024" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-962687078.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-962687078.jpg 2121w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-962687078.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-962687078.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-962687078.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-962687078.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-962687078.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-962687078.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GettyImages-962687078.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2088024" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Jamie Grill / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Silicon Valley&#8221; is a fixed spot on a map, but it&#8217;s also a figure of speech, like &#8220;Hollywood&#8221; or &#8220;The White House.&#8221;</p>
<p>Investors are no longer fixated on the Bay Area, and neither are founders. That’s a truth that’s been in the making for a while, but now, it’s changing how we cover startups.</p>
<p>The Equity team discussed the trend in a TechCrunch+ post:</p>
<ul>
<li>Natasha Mascarenhas: Funding data doesn’t matter the way it used to.</li>
<li>Mary Ann Azevedo: The decentralization of startups isn’t new, even if it is accelerating.</li>
<li>Alex Wilhelm: The declining impact of aggregated startup funding data is good news.</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8gqH1l8cda"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/10/3-views-the-new-decentralized-venture-landscape-is-changing-how-we-report-startup-data/">3 views: The new decentralized venture landscape is changing how we report startup data</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 views: The new decentralized venture landscape is changing how we report startup data&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/10/3-views-the-new-decentralized-venture-landscape-is-changing-how-we-report-startup-data/embed/#?secret=8gqH1l8cda" data-secret="8gqH1l8cda" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>How optimizing presales productivity can help startups multiply revenue growth</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1992564" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1992564" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1992564" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-1020480798.jpg" alt="woman wearing red nail varnish squeezing lemon with her hand and drops of lemon juice are falling down" width="1024" height="658" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-1020480798.jpg 2159w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-1020480798.jpg?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-1020480798.jpg?resize=300,193 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-1020480798.jpg?resize=768,494 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-1020480798.jpg?resize=680,437 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-1020480798.jpg?resize=1536,987 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-1020480798.jpg?resize=2048,1317 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-1020480798.jpg?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1992564" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Peter+Dazeley" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Peter Dazeley <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Presales is an integral but less discussed aspect of the sales funnel for many tech companies. But the C-suite often tries to pump sales head counts to drive growth.</p>
<p>Presales provides tech firms another avenue, writes Freddy Jose Mangum, CEO and co-founder of Hub. Thanks to their natural technical bent, optimizing the productivity of presales executives can lead to multiplicative growth.</p>
<p>Mangum illustrates the potential of presales with three scenarios while outlining ways leaders can help executives increase their productivity.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QVpabjD57w"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/10/how-optimizing-presales-productivity-can-help-startups-multiply-revenue-growth/">How optimizing presales productivity can help startups multiply revenue growth</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How optimizing presales productivity can help startups multiply revenue growth&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/10/how-optimizing-presales-productivity-can-help-startups-multiply-revenue-growth/embed/#?secret=QVpabjD57w" data-secret="QVpabjD57w" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>As EU’s VAT reform ramps up, marketplaces must focus on compliance to avoid tax risk</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2244902" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2244902" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2244902" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1298268224.jpg" alt="Dominoes in a circle, one falling" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1298268224.jpg 2121w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1298268224.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1298268224.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1298268224.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1298268224.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1298268224.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1298268224.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-1298268224.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2244902" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Jordan+Lye" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jordan Lye <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>The EU’s value added tax reform for e-commerce has significant implications for marketplaces, and companies like Amazon may be liable for hefty tax fines if they don’t comply with the new regulations, writes Roger Gothmann, co-founder and CEO at Taxdoo.</p>
<p>The reform mandates that marketplaces must determine the VAT due for every transaction made on their platform, and establish related processes.</p>
<p>Filing VAT is also more complex now, as different countries have their own local VAT procedures alongside the new ones introduced by the reform.</p>
<p>Gothmann takes us on a deep dive of the VAT reform and the financial and legal risks e-commerce marketplaces face if they don’t hurry up to comply with the new laws.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CT9VpJQ6fU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/10/as-eus-vat-reform-ramps-up-marketplaces-must-focus-on-compliance-to-avoid-tax-risk/">As EU&#8217;s VAT reform ramps up, marketplaces must focus on compliance to avoid tax risk</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As EU&#8217;s VAT reform ramps up, marketplaces must focus on compliance to avoid tax risk&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/10/as-eus-vat-reform-ramps-up-marketplaces-must-focus-on-compliance-to-avoid-tax-risk/embed/#?secret=CT9VpJQ6fU" data-secret="CT9VpJQ6fU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The macro trends forcing change on the investment management industry</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2244206" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2244206" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2244206" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-685007313.jpg" alt="man watching wrecking ball swinging at wall" width="1024" height="640" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-685007313.jpg 2191w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-685007313.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-685007313.jpg?resize=300,187 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-685007313.jpg?resize=768,480 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-685007313.jpg?resize=680,425 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-685007313.jpg?resize=1536,960 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-685007313.jpg?resize=2048,1280 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/GettyImages-685007313.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2244206" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Colin+Anderson+Productions+pty+ltd" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Colin Anderson Productions pty ltd <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Investment management is set to see drastic changes as women and millennials increase their share of the asset ownership pie, write David Teten, founder of Versatile VC, and Katina Stefanova, CIO and CEO of Marto Capital.</p>
<p>The authors also detail other trends such as geopolitical risk, recessions, the changes brought about by tech and innovation, and how today’s investors are more aware of market risks than their older counterparts.</p>
<p>&#8220;VCs tout our industry as frontier technology investors, but many of us are using the same infrastructure tools we have used for the past 20+ years.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lHxpnILRxE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/the-macro-trends-forcing-change-on-the-investment-management-industry/">The macro trends forcing change on the investment management industry</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The macro trends forcing change on the investment management industry&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/the-macro-trends-forcing-change-on-the-investment-management-industry/embed/#?secret=lHxpnILRxE" data-secret="lHxpnILRxE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/techcrunch-roundup-web3-investor-survey-conversational-ux-insane-ipo-pops/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247523</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Six more women sue Tesla over workplace sexual harassment</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/six-more-women-sue-tesla-over-workplace-sexual-harassment/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/six-more-women-sue-tesla-over-workplace-sexual-harassment/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Henry Pickavet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 21:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the wake of Jessica Barraza’s lawsuit last month, six more current and former female employees have come forward to accuse Tesla of fostering a culture of rampant sexual harassment at its Fremont factory in California. In separate complaints filed on Tuesday with the Superior Court in Alameda County, the women said they were consistently subjected to catcalling, unwanted advances, physical contact and discrimination while at work.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In the wake of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-fremont-sexual-harassment-suit-185934119.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="14" data-v9y="1"><ins>Jessica Barraza’s lawsuit last month</ins></a>, six more current and former female employees have come forward to accuse Tesla of fostering a culture of rampant sexual harassment at its Fremont factory in California. In separate complaints filed on Tuesday with the Superior Court in Alameda County, the women said they were consistently subjected to catcalling, unwanted advances, physical contact and discrimination while at work.</p>
<p>Jessica Brooks, one of the women who sued Tesla, alleges she was harassed on her first day of orientation at the automaker. She claims a supervisor told his male subordinates to “check out the new girl.” Brooks says the harassment was so constant she eventually stacked boxes around her workstation to deter her coworkers from whistling at her. Brooks also claims she complained of the situation to Tesla’s HR department. The company allegedly responded by moving Brooks to a different part of the factory instead of addressing the situation directly.</p>
<p>“I was so tired of the unwanted attention and the males gawking at me I proceeded to create barriers around me just so I could get some relief,” Brooks <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/12/14/tesla-sexual-harassment/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="15" data-v9y="1"><ins>told </ins><em><ins>The Washington </ins></em><ins>Post</ins></a>. “That was something I felt necessary just so I can do my job.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247581" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>When Jessica Barraza sued Tesla last month, she said she was subjected to “nightmarish” working conditions at the company’s Fremont plant. Barraza’s lawsuit described a factory floor that looked more like “a crude, archaic construction site or frat house” than the site of one of the most advanced EV makers in the country. Most of the seven women who have sued Tesla have linked the abuse they experienced to the behavior of CEO Elon Musk. “He would make 69 or 420 jokes … which caused the technicians to be even worse,” said one of the complaints.</p>
<p>The suit comes on the same day five former SpaceX employees accused Musk’s other company of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spacex-sexual-harassment-claims-204712046.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="16" data-v9y="1"><ins>doing little to stop sexual harassment</ins></a>. We’ve reached out to Tesla for comment. The automaker does not operate a public relations department. When a federal court recently ordered Tesla to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-must-pay-ex-worker-137-million-in-discrimination-lawsuit-075729021.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="17" data-v9y="1"><ins>pay $137 million</ins></a> to a Black worker who said they were subjected to daily racist abuse at the company’s Fremont factory, the company said: “We continue to grow and improve in how we address employee concerns. Occasionally, we’ll get it wrong, and when that happens we should be held accountable.”</p>
<p><em>This story originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-fremont-factory-sexual-harassment-complaints-212738930.html">Engadget</a>. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/six-more-women-sue-tesla-over-workplace-sexual-harassment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247581</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Using data-driven techniques to beat the Great Resignation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/using-data-driven-techniques-to-beat-the-great-resignation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/using-data-driven-techniques-to-beat-the-great-resignation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 21:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Future of Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peer to peer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recruiting]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246347</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the Great Resignation gathers pace, businesses that differentiate by leveraging their own data will be most likely to win, retain and recruit the people they need.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Meisha-ann Martin</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/meishaannm">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Dr. Meisha-ann Martin is the director of people analytics at Workhuman, a social recognition and performance development platform. Dr. Martin has a Ph.D. in industrial/organization psychology with 15 years of experience working in people analytics and employee engagement.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Much has been written about the long-term impact COVID-19 will have on how people do their jobs. Throughout the pandemic, people had the space and time to consider what really matters to them, and to ask the big questions such as “Am I happy?”</p>
<p>For many people, the crisis has acted as a catalyst for change, leading to the Great Resignation, or the Great Talent Swap for those that lost employees to a competitor or different company. Life goals people perhaps once only daydreamed about are now becoming a reality with the plethora of options and flexibility now available.</p>
<p>Our <a href="https://www.workhuman.com/resources/globoforce-blog/introducing-the-new-workhuman-survey-report-the-great-resignation?utm_source=trdparty&amp;utm_medium=prbyline&amp;utm_campaign=2021Q4_PR_Corporate&amp;utm_content=ExecutiveContent_post_byline_121021" target="_blank" rel="noopener">research</a> at Workhuman bears this out: 30% of people looking for a new job say they are doing so for greater flexibility, and it seems that parents are particularly motivated to change, accounting for 65% of the total of job seekers. Clearly, many workers are looking for ways to better manage family and work responsibilities.</p>
<p>For instance, research we conducted for our Human Workplace Index revealed that 56% of respondents who want to stay at their company say it’s because they like their company and/or co-workers. Culture is therefore key to winning and retaining workers.</p>
<p>All of this is to say that businesses and leaders need to act. The Great Resignation has created an employee market where people have a wealth of openings available to them and they can be more selective about who they work for. Employers therefore need to give current employees a reason to stay and prospective employees a reason to apply.</p>
<p>Building a strong employer brand is now mission critical. Companies that fail to do so risk stifling their own growth for a want of talent, as this voluntary turnover could cost businesses around the world billions of dollars.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Given today’s labor market, ensuring that the employee experience is frictionless, rewarding and based on a culture of reward and recognition is more important than ever. 					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Here are three areas where businesses can leverage data-driven techniques to drive employee satisfaction:</p>
<h2>Human-centered technology</h2>
<p>Traditionally, HR technology has been transactional and focused on the task. The technology needed right now focuses on the people just as much as it does on their experience of the task being done.</p>
<p>Human-centered technology that powers actions such as continuous feedback, employee recognition, celebrating individual and team accomplishments, and building a more human workplace have measurable bottom-line benefits because they strengthen employees’ emotional ties to each other and the organization.</p>
<p>One approach could be to set up a peer-to-peer recognition platform where people can publicly recognize the work of their colleagues. The platform could potentially link to a rewards program whereby employees gain points toward goods or experiences. From an analytics perspective, the approach also provides valuable data on where good work is being done in the organization and by whom, enabling employers to identify high performers and ensure that they are adequately engaged at work.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/using-data-driven-techniques-to-beat-the-great-resignation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246347</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter adds auto captions feature to make videos more accessible</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/twitter-adds-auto-captions-feature-to-make-videos-more-accessible/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/twitter-adds-auto-captions-feature-to-make-videos-more-accessible/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 21:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freeware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Simon Balmain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Washington Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247323</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Starting today, Twitter is rolling out auto-generated captions on videos. This feature will make videos more accessible for deaf and hard-of-hearing users. Auto captions will be available on web, iOS and Android in over 30 languages, including English, Spanish, Japanese, Arabic, Thai, Chinese, Hindi and many more. The captions could become useful in Twitter&#8217;s new [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Starting today, Twitter is rolling out auto-generated captions on videos. This feature will make videos more accessible for deaf and hard-of-hearing users. Auto captions will be available on web, iOS and Android in over 30 languages, including English, Spanish, Japanese, Arabic, Thai, Chinese, Hindi and many more.</p>
<p>The captions could become useful in Twitter&#8217;s new <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/08/twitter-is-the-latest-platform-to-test-a-tiktok-copycat-feature/">vertical feed</a> the company began testing last week. The feed, if rolled out publicly, would make the app&#8217;s Explore tab resemble TikTok, serving one piece of algorithmically recommended content at a time, including videos. On feeds like this, captioned videos have become expected because they make it easier to scroll through feeds when you&#8217;re in a public place and headphones aren&#8217;t in reach.</p>
<p>But unlike the video caption features on TikTok and Instagram Reels &#8212; which allow users to edit the captions&#8217; text before posting &#8212; Twitter won&#8217;t let users tweak its captions. That means users won&#8217;t be able to correct any errors to make the automated captions more accurate.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247323" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3W2H6ygS12"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/08/twitter-is-the-latest-platform-to-test-a-tiktok-copycat-feature/">Twitter is the latest platform to test a TikTok copycat feature</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter is the latest platform to test a TikTok copycat feature&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/08/twitter-is-the-latest-platform-to-test-a-tiktok-copycat-feature/embed/#?secret=3W2H6ygS12" data-secret="3W2H6ygS12" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Accessibility features like auto captions and image alt text have been getting more attention from Twitter after it finally created dedicated <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/18/somehow-twitter-does-not-have-a-team-dedicated-to-accessibility/#:~:text=Somehow%2C%20Twitter%20does%20not%20have%20a%20team%20dedicated%20to%20accessibility,-Devin%20Coldewey%40techcrunch&amp;text=Twitter%20does%20not%20have%20a%20team%20dedicated%20to%20accessibility%2C%20the,about%20doing%20the%20right%20thing.">accessibility teams</a> in September 2020. This staffing change was spurred after users <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2020/making-twitter-more-accessible" target="_blank" rel="noopener">criticized</a> Twitter last summer for piloting a voice tweet feature without auto captions. Now, <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1415806764113670145?s=20" target="_blank" rel="noopener">voice tweets</a> and Spaces, Twitter&#8217;s Clubhouse competitor, both have <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2021/making-spaces-accessible" target="_blank" rel="noopener">captioning</a>.</p>
<p>While Twitter&#8217;s support for captions on videos is new, the company was already using captioning technology in its live audio chatrooms, called Twitter Spaces.</p>
<p>The company notes it retains an audio copy of a Space, including the captions, for thirty days to review the content for violations of Twitter&#8217;s guidelines. If a Space is found to contain a violation, Twitter will hold on to these records for an additional 90 days to offer the speakers a chance to appeal their violation.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Unfortunately for Twitter and users alike, this process doesn&#8217;t go far enough to address issues of abuse on its platform. Twitter Spaces users have been served <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/12/10/twitter-turmoil-spaces/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blatantly harmful content</a> &#8212; including Spaces with racist titles that remained on their feeds even after being reported. Twitter community manager Simon Balmain recently <a href="https://twitter.com/SBkcrn/status/1465659201800347651" target="_blank" rel="noopener" rev="en_rl_none">tweeted</a> the company is working on the problem, but Twitter hasn&#8217;t yet detailed if or how its system will expand beyond its existing reporting features and the retention of Spaces&#8217; audio and captions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/twitter-adds-auto-captions-feature-to-make-videos-more-accessible/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247323</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Proterra to build commercial EV battery factory in South Carolina, its third in US</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/proterra-to-build-commercial-ev-battery-factory-in-south-carolina-its-third-in-us/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/proterra-to-build-commercial-ev-battery-factory-in-south-carolina-its-third-in-us/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 20:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arrival]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BrightDrop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric bus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric van]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EV battery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proterra]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247466</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Proterra, an American commercial electric vehicle company that produces transit buses and electric charging systems, is opening up its third battery factory in Greer, South Carolina. The factory should begin production in the second half of 2022 with &#8220;multiple gigawatt hours of annual battery system production capacity,&#8221; according to the company. Proterra did not disclose [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Proterra, an American commercial electric vehicle company that produces transit buses and electric charging systems, is opening up its third battery factory in Greer, South Carolina. The factory should begin production in the second half of 2022 with &#8220;multiple gigawatt hours of annual battery system production capacity,&#8221; according to the company.</p>
<p>Proterra did not disclose the specific production capacity expected at its South Carolina plant, but its two other plants in Burlingame, California and Los Angeles have a max annual capacity of 345 megawatt hours and 675 megawatt hours, respectively, according to Shane Levy, director of corporate communications.</p>
<p>Globally, the electric commercial vehicle market is <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/en/news-release/2021/07/05/2257591/0/en/Global-Electric-Commercial-Vehicle-Market-is-Expected-to-Grow-at-a-CAGR-of-17-3-from-2021-to-2030.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">estimated to reach $62.4 billion this year</a>. With myriad government and corporate initiatives focused on decreasing emissions, the commercial EV sector is expected to grow at a compound annual growth rate of 17.3% over the next nine years, and automakers are racing to supply that demand. In January this year, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/gm-targets-delivery-companies-with-new-ev-business-unit-brightdrop/">General Motors announced its new commercial electric vehicle brand, Brightdrop</a>, and in September,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/ford-builds-leadership-team-of-commercial-vehicle-unit-ahead-of-e-transit-launch/"> Ford beefed up its commercial EV</a> unit ahead of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/ford-unveils-e-transit-its-45000-electric-workhorse/">Ford E-Transit work van</a> launch, to name a couple.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247466" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>With this new plant, Proterra has committed to creating more than 200 jobs in South Carolina and investing a minimum of $76 million into the 327,000-square-foot plant, which is located at the 42.76-acre Carolina Commerce Center. The factory, which is located near the company&#8217;s electric bus manufacturing facility, is Proterra&#8217;s entry into producing batteries in the eastern U.S., which the company says will bring it closer to its &#8220;Proterra Powered&#8221; customers. In addition to building its own electric vehicles, Proterra partners with other automakers to integrate its powertrains into their vehicles. Daimler&#8217;s Saf-T-Liner C2 Jouley school bus from Thomas Built Buses, for example, is powered by Proterra, as are Volta&#8217;s new refrigerated trucks.</p>
<div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid powered-vehicles-intro-row content-noise-bg-row wpex-vc-row-stretched" data-vc-full-width="true" data-vc-full-width-init="true">
<div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12">
<div class="vc_column-inner">
<div class="wpb_wrapper">
<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element content-heading">
<div class="wpb_wrapper">
<p>The Greer battery production site comes a year after Proterra opened its second battery factory within its existing EV bus manufacturing facility in Los Angeles. It will also be neighbors to commercial EV competitor <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/06/ev-maker-arrival-to-build-high-voltage-battery-module-assembly-plant-in-north-carolina/">Arrival, which recently shared plans to open its own battery module assembly plant</a> in North Carolina. As more automakers begin producing EVs and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/23/automakers-have-battery-anxiety-so-theyre-taking-control-of-the-supply/">wanting to control their own supply chain</a>, more domestic battery assembly plants are sure to follow.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MAQuZoPiCg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/23/automakers-have-battery-anxiety-so-theyre-taking-control-of-the-supply/">Automakers have battery anxiety, so they&#8217;re taking control of the supply</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Automakers have battery anxiety, so they&#8217;re taking control of the supply&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/23/automakers-have-battery-anxiety-so-theyre-taking-control-of-the-supply/embed/#?secret=MAQuZoPiCg" data-secret="MAQuZoPiCg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/proterra-to-build-commercial-ev-battery-factory-in-south-carolina-its-third-in-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247466</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Europe’s final push on the Digital Markets Act must include default settings</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/europes-final-push-on-the-digital-markets-act-must-include-default-settings/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/europes-final-push-on-the-digital-markets-act-must-include-default-settings/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 20:50:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital Markets Act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DuckDuckGo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european parliament]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile devices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247280</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What has been deemed anti-competitive by the EU in the case of the Android choice screen must now be reflected in EU law via the DMA.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Dembinski</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/sophiedembinski">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Sophie Dembinski is head of Public Policy and U.K. lead at <a href="https://www.ecosia.org/">Ecosia</a>, which uses advertising revenues from its search engine to fund tree-planting projects across the world. To date, Ecosia has planted more than 139 million trees in countries such as Brazil, Australia, Burkina Faso, Indonesia, Spain and the U.K. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Europe has a deeply uneven tech playing field. But as members of the European Parliament prepare to vote in plenary on the <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/priorities-2019-2024/europe-fit-digital-age/digital-markets-act-ensuring-fair-and-open-digital-markets_en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Digital Markets Act</a> (DMA) on Wednesday, there’s a chance to correct this course.</p>
<p>MEPs must sustain significant progress made within the legislation, such as with regard to ad platforms, as well as the major wins brought home by the European Commission over recent months such as the <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/3e8e45e6-54b4-4b0f-8bda-69ab1389eabd" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Shopping case</a> and <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-06-08/google-bows-to-eu-rivals-with-android-choice-screen-tweaks?sref=gni836kR" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Android choice screen</a> &#8212; demonstrating the EU’s ability to take concrete action to create a fair and competitive European market.</p>
<p>MEPs must now secure a majority on key amendments tabled ahead of the plenary and following the pivotal <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/ep-imco-dma-vote/">Internal Market and Consumer Protection Committee vote</a> last month. Of most importance are those focused on default settings that would finally prohibit tech giants such as Google from locking up search defaults on gatekeeping platforms and provide European consumers with real choice across mobile and desktop devices once and for all.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247280" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h2>Why do default settings matter?</h2>
<p>The vast majority of internet users have never chosen their search engine and 95% of people stick with their default platform. Data shows the power of default settings and, given the sums that Google currently pays to secure its <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/kateoflahertyuk/2021/09/04/apple-google-search-deal-impacts-millions-of-iphones/?sh=40ac6ec46483" target="_blank" rel="noopener">preset default position on other gatekeeping platforms</a>, it is no wonder that the tech giant is able to maintain <a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/search-engine-market-share/mobile/europe" target="_blank" rel="noopener">97% of search engine market share</a> on mobile across Europe.</p>
<p>Last summer, following sustained pressure from independent search engines such as Ecosia, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/google-ditches-pay-to-play-android-search-choice-auction-for-free-version-after-eu-pressure/">European Commission instructed Google to drop the pay-to-play element of its Android choice screen</a> &#8212; a widely discredited self-devised remedy created by Google following the 2018 Android decision, where it was fined €4.3 billion for monopolistic behavior.</p>
<p>From our preliminary data, we saw our search volumes on Android mobile devices increase by approximately 7% in just two months after Google opened up the choice screen to alternative providers &#8212; which, on current projections, amounts to 50% over the coming year.</p>
<h2>The free choice screen is a great step, but more needs to be done</h2>
<p>We know that when given an opportunity to select their default search engine, more and more Europeans would choose to select alternatives to Google that align more with their environmental or privacy values.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>However Google’s choice screen still falls short in a number of ways, as noted in this <a href="https://ddg-staticcdn.s3.amazonaws.com/press/2110_Search_coalition_letter_calling_on_a_default_ban_in_DMA.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">joint letter</a> signed by Ecosia, DuckDuckGo, Qwant and Lilo and in alignment with <a href="https://www.beuc.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BEUC</a>.</p>
<p>For this reason, we collectively called on legislators to ensure every user is freely able to choose which search engine they use on desktop and mobile operating ecosystems through a “one-click switch” mechanism, as well as banning sweetheart deals between gatekeepers that currently provide default status on a number of web browsers.</p>
<p>The joint letter also highlights the failures of the remedy to only apply to a fraction (just 2%) of the total mobile market. By failing to extend a choice screen beyond new devices, millions of existing Android users are not able to select alternative search engines and Google continues to profit from a proven infringement across the existing mobile devices, not to mention desktops (or other devices).</p>
<p>We’ve advocated for default settings for years and proved our case. What has been deemed anti-competitive by the EU in the case of the Android choice screen must now be reflected in EU law via the DMA. Unfortunately, the current version of the DMA will not prevent Google from hoarding default positions everywhere it can and addressing its entrenched dominant position.</p>
<h2>Crucial time for EU legislators to support default settings in DMA</h2>
<p>As the DMA approaches its final crucial stages, we urge EU legislators to resist bending to pressure from gatekeepers at the expense of millions of consumers and push default settings to the top of the priority list. With calls for mandating choice screens reverberating across regulatory bodies around the world <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/android-search-choice-screen-is-needed-to-tackle-googles-market-power-says-australias-accc/?guccounter=1">in a bid to break Google’s dominance of the search market</a>, the DMA must mandate that all gatekeeper platforms provide users with a fair choice screen at no cost for default settings and allow users to switch their default settings with a clear, accessible one-click switch.</p>
<p>Failing to address default settings in the DMA not only cements the status quo but eradicates the prospect of installing fair competition and real consumer choice for Europeans for years to come, which could undermine the EU’s leading position as it prepares to write the rules for the next chapter of the internet.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/europes-final-push-on-the-digital-markets-act-must-include-default-settings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247280</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In the age of remote work, Opal offers a glimpse at the future of webcams</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/in-the-age-of-remote-work-opal-offers-a-glimpse-at-the-future-of-webcams/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/in-the-age-of-remote-work-opal-offers-a-glimpse-at-the-future-of-webcams/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 20:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[C1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webcam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246268</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In September, Alexis Ohanian sent out a trial balloon, disguised as a tweet. “We quietly backed a team (from Apple, Beats, Uber) reviving a forgotten corner of consumer tech,” the 776 founder wrote. “The beta arrived today and the quality is mind blowing. Webcams, welcome to 2021.” The message was accompanied by an open box, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In September, Alexis Ohanian sent out a trial balloon, <a href="https://twitter.com/alexisohanian/status/1435709529308626946" target="_blank" rel="noopener">disguised as a tweet</a>. “We quietly backed a team (from Apple, Beats, Uber) reviving a forgotten corner of consumer tech,” the 776 founder wrote. “The beta arrived today and the quality is mind blowing. Webcams, welcome to 2021.”</p>
<p>The message was accompanied by an open box, with a few identifying details &#8212; including the company’s name &#8212; pixelated out. That information, ultimately, wasn’t too difficult to come by, with the company and product’s name &#8212; Opal C1 &#8212; printed in white on the border just above the lens.</p>
<p>Reaction was swift. The “shut up and take my money Gifs flowed.” It was, after all, a handsome device, backed by at least one known quantity. And more pressingly, it arrived at the height of a technological pain point that’s been virtually universally acknowledged. Webcams, in a word, suck.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246268" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2246278" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246278" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2246278" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0736.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0736.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0736.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0736.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0736.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0736.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0736.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0736.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0736.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246278" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>That’s not any kind of revelation. It’s not like they just started sucking. It’s just that, until recently, it’s just been a thing that we’ve been able to live with. But by the fiftieth time you’ve peered into some CNN correspondent’s apartment at 480p through a coat of Crisco, you begin questioning the nature of the world.</p>
<p>Of course, you don’t have to appear on cable news every night to want an upgrade. Maybe you bought a Logitech &#8212; or perhaps your work splurged to jury rig a DSLR. Both cases expose what’s ultimately a huge, under-addressed market. And while at the beginning of the pandemic it may have seemed like a momentary blip, even if/when this whole thing ends, it’s clear that there won’t really be a normal to go back to.</p>
<p>As much as corporate offices have dragged their heels, we appear to have turned a corner on the question of remote work. It’s quickly become more rule than exception, leaving many asking the same question: Where’s the iPhone of webcams? It seems simple enough. Take all the learnings from smartphone imaging and apply them to a stagnant market.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2246184" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246184" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2246184" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-10-at-2.40.25-PM.png" alt="" width="1024" height="371" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-10-at-2.40.25-PM.png 3755w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-10-at-2.40.25-PM.png?resize=150,54 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-10-at-2.40.25-PM.png?resize=300,109 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-10-at-2.40.25-PM.png?resize=768,278 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-10-at-2.40.25-PM.png?resize=680,246 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-10-at-2.40.25-PM.png?resize=1536,556 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-10-at-2.40.25-PM.png?resize=2048,742 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-10-at-2.40.25-PM.png?resize=50,18 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246184" class="wp-caption-text">L-R: 2020 iMac Webcam, Opal C1. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>It doesn’t appear to be coming from Apple. Not in the near-term, at least. To the company’s credit, they’ve made some strides, first through digital image processing on its M1 chips and then by actually upgrading the built-in sensors. But for many, better’s not good enough. That was more or less the thinking that sent Opal’s founders down their path.</p>
<p>By the time Ohanian’s tweet arrived, Opal had been working on the C1 for seven months. That’s basically overnight in hardware startupland, but at the very least, they had a good-looking piece of hardware couched in nice packaging, with an air of VC mystery sprinkled in. The company says it’s now managing a 16,000-person waitlist.</p>
<p>“[The response] was overwhelming,” says co-founder and president Stefan Sohlstrom. “It was really gratifying for us to see. We’re the most two bullish people on what we&#8217;re building. We obviously felt like not only is the market big, that&#8217;s obvious, but the need was very deep. It wasn&#8217;t just that, sure, millions of people would buy this. It was for the people that are doing this for their job, this is an important thing for them. This is how they communicate with the world.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2246274" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246274" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2246274" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0739.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0739.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0739.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0739.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0739.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0739.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0739.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0739.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0739.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246274" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>Opal’s journey officially began in November of 2020, with a simple question.</p>
<p>“If we were to build a webcam today, what are the technologies that are available to us that make an iPhone as close to a DSLR as possible?” says co-founder and CEO Veeraj Chugh. “We did a lot of research talking to folks in the industry, talking to users and talking to people who worked at competitors previously. The overwhelming response, ‘this should exist and the technology needs to look very, very different than every webcam that came before.’”</p>
<p>By December, the team raised an undisclosed seed round, and a month later, it began building a team of designers and engineers who had previously worked for companies like Apple, Google and Magic Leap.</p>
<p>The result is a lovinglycrafted $300 piece of hardware with a 7.8mm, 4K Sony sensor and a built-in beamforming mic mesh array. It’s unquestionably the best-looking webcam I’ve tested. I recognize that &#8212; in and of itself &#8212; isn’t saying much, but I do spend a lot of hours every day staring into one, so it might as well be nice to look at.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2246272" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246272" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2246272" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0741.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0741.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0741.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0741.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0741.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0741.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0741.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0741.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0741.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246272" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>It also may end up being the most capable. But here is where I hedge my bets and tell you that my hands-on time with the product has effectively entered me into beta testing. Opal is aiming for an out-of-the-box, plug and play experience &#8212; and for a company that only recently celebrated its first anniversary, it’s well on its way.</p>
<p>As we push closer to a kind of general availability, I’ll feel more comfortable reviewing the product. For now, I’m content to give the C1 a longer leash than I do review products. It’s an exciting new device from an exciting new company. It has problems and unfulfilled promises &#8212; more or less what you’d expect from a limited beta from a brand new company.</p>
<p>The device sitting above the screen of my M1 iMac is final hardware. The software, on the other hand, is still very much in beta. What I received is beginning to roll out to select customers, starting today. Per Opal:</p>
<blockquote><p>Units start shipping to the public on December 14th. Customers on the waitlist can purchase the camera with an invite. We’re slowly rolling out to ensure the customer experience exceeds expectations – once we cross a positive threshold there, we will roll out in quantities in the tens of thousands.</p></blockquote>
<p><div id="attachment_2246271" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246271" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2246271" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0743.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0743.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0743.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0743.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0743.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0743.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0743.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0743.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0743.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246271" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>4K isn’t up and running yet. “We’ve temporarily disabled 4K video, as it is not compatible with most video conferencing apps, and it was giving users a hard time,” the company notes. “We are relaunching shortly with a stronger warning, and will be available for applications that do support, for recording videos and the like.”</p>
<p>Opening the beta control software on my desktop, the Audio tab is grayed out. Using the mic array up front and ambient mics on the rear, the company has some big things planned down the road:</p>
<blockquote><p>We’re focusing on building the markets leading Noise Cancellation, and using the same learnings to build something we call Studio Sound. Studio sound allows you to sound like you’re on a professional podcast, without the $500 boom mic. Using MicMesh inputs piped through a neural net, we’ll be able to make your sound professional quality.</p></blockquote>
<p>The sound, as it stands, is good. And by “good,” I mean work-meeting good, not going on CNN or recording my podcast good. If you do either of those things, you’re going to want to stick to that devoted mic. In the future, who knows? “Studio Sound” could be standard or maybe something for professionals to unlock as part of a monthly service pack. There are still a lot of questions to be answered during these heady beta days.</p>
<p>Another question the company needs to answer is how much control to give the user upfront. I realize this seems like a no-brainer, but in the world of imaging, too much control can get average users quickly in over their heads. The ideal compromise for a majority of users is good quality out of the box, with additional manual user adjustments if you dig in. Auto white balance and skin tones are both challenges ahead for the company.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2246270" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246270" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2246270" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0744.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0744.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0744.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0744.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0744.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0744.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0744.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0744.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0744.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246270" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>But on the whole, I’m satisfied with the image I got out of the box. I’ve done some tweaking, here and there. Having a ring light and natural lighting from windows helps, though I still find myself messing around with settings to get things where I want them.</p>
<p>The camera employs an artificial bokeh effect, similar to the portrait mode you find on most modern smartphones (though the company says it developed its own, in-house). I’ve only got the slider about an eighth of the way at the moment, however. When it’s too intense, it tends to blur out my ears and the sides of my face, owing to the fact that there’s no depth cameras on-board. Opal says it experimented with a stereo camera for depth, but opted not to go with it for the sake of getting the device out in a timely manner.</p>
<p>“I think at the end of the day, when you talk to users, they&#8217;re like, &#8216;just give me anything. I can&#8217;t deal with these Logitechs anymore,’” says Chugh. “So for us, speed was of the utmost importance, because we felt like we can ship something really good. We just need to be a little bit ruthless about prioritization.”</p>
<p>For the C1, that also means no optical zoom. It seems like an odd complaint, perhaps, for a webcam, but it’s something I’ve grown fond of, while using a DSLR desktop setup. Being able to tightly crop a shot without degrading the image quality is huge.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2246276" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246276" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2246276" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0737.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0737.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0737.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0737.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0737.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0737.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0737.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0737.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0737.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246276" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>“For the first camera, the more mechanical components you add, the more risk you have in the supply chain side and the manufacturing side,” says Sohlstrom. “It&#8217;s basically more to break. Canon has had maybe 50 years to get their lenses right. It’s definitely something that in the future we could do.”</p>
<p>For now, the system is able to do 2x zoom in 1080p without degrading the image, courtesy of the 4K sensor. The company says it could theoretically do something like 20-30x, but picture quality is going to suffer accordingly. I used my call with the founders to, in part, give a little constructive feedback. For one thing, I’d love a straight-up zoom setting. For now, the closest thing is Facelock. It’s a feature similar to something like Apple’s Center Stage and similar features on smart displays from companies like Facebook, Google and Amazon.</p>
<p>It’s honestly way too sensitive, however, and could leave you a bit seasick. Hopefully in future editions, the company will let users adjust the sensitivity or just simply zoom in. These are both pretty easy fixes. There are so bigger issues. I found with apps like Google Hangouts and Zoom and I had to turn the camera off and on a few times and/or relaunch the software. The camera also gets really hot, even when it’s not active. The company blames this on both the system’s on-board processing and downscaling the 4K image. It’s working on fixes to the above.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2246273" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246273" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2246273" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0740.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0740.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0740.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0740.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0740.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0740.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0740.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0740.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CMC_0740.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246273" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>For a product a brand new company started building less than a year ago, these feel like relatively minor complaints. I’m going to caution away from telling people to jump ship from their DSLRs &#8212; particularly if video quality is important to their jobs. But there’s so much promise here. The C1 is an extremely thoughtful product, from touches like a magnetic lens cap with a microfiber cloth and a coiled USB-C cable to more complex processing.</p>
<p>This sure feels like the future of webcams, even if it’s still got a ways to get there.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/in-the-age-of-remote-work-opal-offers-a-glimpse-at-the-future-of-webcams/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246268</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>YouTube TV warns customers they may lose access to 18 Disney-owned channels by week&#8217;s end</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/youtube-tv-warns-customers-they-may-lose-access-to-18-disney-owned-channels-by-weeks-end/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/youtube-tv-warns-customers-they-may-lose-access-to-18-disney-owned-channels-by-weeks-end/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 19:23:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube TV]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247409</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fresh on the heels of resolving its months-long carriage dispute with Roku, YouTube now finds itself on the other side of the negotiating table. The company today warned its YouTube TV streaming subscribers they may lose access to all Disney-owned channels by the end of the week if the two companies are not able to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Fresh on the heels of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/08/roku-and-google-reach-a-deal-for-the-continued-distribution-of-youtube-and-youtube-tv-on-roku-devices/">resolving</a> its months-long carriage dispute with Roku, YouTube now finds itself on the other side of the negotiating table. The company today <a href="https://blog.youtube/news-and-events/youtube-tv-and-disney-programming-update/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">warned</a> its YouTube TV streaming subscribers they may lose access to all Disney-owned channels by the end of the week if the two companies are not able to reach a new distribution agreement. YouTube TV&#8217;s current contact with Disney ends on Friday, Dec. 17, the company noted. If a new deal isn&#8217;t struck by then, subscribers will lose access to 18 Disney-owned channels, including their local ABC station, ABC News Live, The Disney Channel, FX, ESPN and many others.</p>
<p>This means customers would lose access to both the live streaming channels and the video-on-demand content, YouTube says.</p>
<p>Other impacted channels include Disney Junior, Disney XD, Freeform, FXX, FXM, National Geographic, National Geographic Wild, ESPN2, ESPN3, ESPNU, ESPNews, SEC Network and ACC Network.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247409" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In other words, failure to get a deal done will take out a large swath of YouTube TV&#8217;s programming lineup. The company says if that&#8217;s the case, it will try to make things right with users by lowering the monthly price for its streaming service. Instead of charging subscribers $64.99 per month, it would decrease its price by $15 to $49.99 per month for however long the Disney-owned content remains off its platform.</p>
<p>The company also said that while it hopes every member will stay subscribed, it will allow customers to either pause or cancel the service if they choose, as usual. But if customers decide to stay with YouTube TV for its other programming, they could access Disney content directly through The Disney Bundle, a $13.99/month subscription.</p>
<p>YouTube&#8217;s past negotiations with Roku appeared to be more about more than just the dollars and cents &#8212; Roku accused YouTube of asking for increased access to user data and preferred treatment on its platform. (Roku never said if it ultimately caved to those demands to get the deal done, though, leaving consumers in the dark as to what will happen with their user data!)</p>
<p>But these Disney negotiations, on the other hand, seem to be breaking down over pricing &#8212; as these sorts of deals usually do. In the past, consumers didn&#8217;t always know when companies were butting heads, as the deals got settled in the final hours and the service remained uninterrupted. These days, it&#8217;s becoming more common to see companies leveraging the power of their customer base &#8212; and their collective outrage &#8212; as a negotiating tactic. That&#8217;s what Roku did over the past several months before it settled with YouTube on a new agreement. And that&#8217;s what YouTube, in turn, is doing now, to some extent &#8212; in addition to making sure customers know the service pricing will drop in the case a deal doesn&#8217;t get done.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Disney is an important partner for us and we’re in active conversations with them and working hard to keep their content on YouTube TV,&#8221; <a href="https://blog.youtube/news-and-events/youtube-tv-and-disney-programming-update/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a YouTube blog post stated</a>. &#8220;Our ask to Disney, as with all our partners, is to treat YouTube TV like any other TV provider — by offering us the same rates that services of a similar size pay, across Disney&#8217;s channels for as long as we carry them.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Update, 12/14/21, 4:25 p.m. EST;</strong> Disney shared the following statement with TechCrunch:</p>
<blockquote><p>Our contract with Google’s YouTube TV for the ABC Owned Television Stations, the ESPN networks, the Disney channels, Freeform, the FX networks and the National Geographic channels is due to expire on Friday, December 17 at 11:59 p.m. ET. Disney Media and Entertainment Distribution has a highly successful track record of negotiating such agreements with providers of all types and sizes across the country and is committed to working with Google to reach a fair, market-based agreement. We are optimistic that we can reach a deal and continue to provide their YouTube TV customers with our live sporting events and news coverage plus kids, family and general entertainment programming.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/youtube-tv-warns-customers-they-may-lose-access-to-18-disney-owned-channels-by-weeks-end/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247409</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cube RM raises $8M round, led by Runa, to create global government tenders platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/cube-rm-raises-8m-round-led-by-runa-to-create-global-government-tenders-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/cube-rm-raises-8m-round-led-by-runa-to-create-global-government-tenders-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 19:22:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bavarian nordic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data scientist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government procurement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marathon Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[natural language processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[procurement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Runa Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salesforce.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web portal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247422</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are millions of tenders and public sector contracts published every year by governments globally. The value of all this is estimated to be about $5 trillion, and is expected to reach $9 billion by 2025. And of course, the pandemic has supercharged the need for digitized government procurement. But navigating government procurement portals is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There are millions of tenders and public sector contracts published every year by governments globally. The value of all this is estimated to be about $5 trillion, and is <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2021/08/30/2288488/0/en/Procurement-as-a-Service-Market-to-Touch-USD-9-Billion-at-8-9-CAGR-by-2025-Report-by-Market-Research-Future-MRFR.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">expected to reach</a> $9 billion by 2025. And of course, the pandemic has supercharged the need for digitized government procurement.</p>
<p>But navigating government procurement portals is far from an easy task. There is currently no global platform to view all these tenders, while only legacy tools help with the application process. But a few years ago most countries in Europe and North America produced online tender portals, making it possible to scrape them at scale. And guess what? A startup has gone and done just that.</p>
<p>Step forth <a href="https://www.cuberm.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cube RM</a>, which combines tender application and management into a single platform. The company claims to help enterprises discover, bid for and win tenders globally. It’s now completed an $8 million Series A round led by Runa Capital with the participation of the existing investor Marathon Venture Capital.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247422" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The startup is mainly targeting pharmaceutical and medical equipment global companies, with plans to expand to other industries. So far, clients include Boston Scientific ($BSX), Takeda ($TYO), Kemira ($KEMIRA), Bavarian Nordic ($BAVA) and others.</p>
<p>As well as helping companies discover new tenders globally, it also claims to prioritize tenders using Natural Language Processing; forecast tenders to be published; deliver tenders as opportunities in Salesforce.com; facilitate bid preparation and submission; and track tender winners and competitive info.</p>
<p>Previously, co-founder Costas Economopoulos founded a few B2B software companies, while data scientist George Boretos was in the business software industry, and Philip Kytinos is an experienced software engineer.</p>
<p>Economopoulos commented:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<blockquote><p>While working with global life sciences customers, we discovered that 25% to 60% of their revenues comes from public sector tenders, which is rather significant considering the trillion-dollar size of the market. Previously, there was no software system to discover new tenders that are being published every day on a global scale and help those companies manage the processes for preparing their quotation and find the best price to win the tender with the use of the latest AI technology.</p></blockquote>
<p>Tender needs have historically been covered by either large revenue management solutions such as ModelN, Apttus/Conga or SAP.</p>
<p>Konstantin Vinogradov, partner at Runa Capital, said:</p>
<blockquote><p>We have been investing in software solutions for regulated industries since 2011 and think that now is the perfect time for tender automation in the life science industry. On one hand, the pandemic boosted budgets and the overall importance of this industry, and on the other hand, it highlighted the ubiquitous lack of digitalization and abundance of inefficient bureaucratic processes at large enterprises. We consider this as an outstanding opportunity.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/cube-rm-raises-8m-round-led-by-runa-to-create-global-government-tenders-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247422</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The irrational exuberance of web3</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/the-irrational-exuberance-of-web3/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/the-irrational-exuberance-of-web3/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 19:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital transformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246210</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This year&#8217;s hottest new tech terms are definitely &#8220;web3&#8221; and &#8220;metaverse.&#8221; The former refers to a decentralized web, based on the blockchain, while the latter is a combination of the internet and augmented and virtual reality. It is possible that we will see a merging of the concepts at some point. That is, if the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This year&#8217;s hottest new tech terms are definitely <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/for-the-love-of-the-loot-blockchain-the-metaverse-and-gamings-blind-spot/">&#8220;web3&#8221; and &#8220;metaverse</a>.&#8221; The former refers to a decentralized web, based on the blockchain, while the latter is a combination of the internet and augmented and virtual reality. It is possible that we will see a merging of the concepts at some point. That is, if the concepts ever turn into anything.</p>
<p>Suddenly, out of nowhere in 2021, we began using these terms like they were a given and we were all privy to the change. Like a giant game of social telephone, the blockchain became &#8220;web3&#8221; and AR and VR morphed into &#8220;the metaverse&#8221; &#8212; and we all went along for the ride.</p>
<p>Yet the blockchain idea has existed for years <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/j5nzx4/what-was-the-first-blockchain">as a concept</a>, long before bitcoin decided to use it <a href="https://www.icaew.com/technical/technology/blockchain-and-cryptocurrency/blockchain-articles/what-is-blockchain/history">as a ledger</a> for its digital currency idea in 2008.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246210" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>I began covering the notion of blockchain in the enterprise in 2017 when a colleague pointed out it could be the next big thing, a way to establish trust through an irrefutable record. It was interesting at first, but was often referred to as a solution looking for a problem, and I eventually lost interest.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s what I wrote<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/22/the-blockchain-begins-finding-its-way-in-the-enterprise/"> in a 2018 article</a> about the blockchain in the enterprise:</p>
<blockquote><p>The blockchain is in the middle of a major hype cycle at the moment, and that makes it hard for many people to take it seriously, but if you look at the core digital ledger technology, there is tremendous potential to change the way we think about trust in business. Yet these are still extremely early days and there are a number of missing pieces that need to be in place for the blockchain to really take off in the enterprise.</p></blockquote>
<p>At the time, I wrote about a number of promising startups. I talked to people in charge of blockchain at larger companies like IBM and SAP as they dabbled in the idea of bringing blockchain-based solutions for the enterprise. I was actually pretty pumped about it, too, until I realized it was more hype than reality and moved on. Three years later, it&#8217;s back, and once again, it&#8217;s the next big thing &#8212; and it&#8217;s got a new name to go with it.</p>
<p>Stephen Diehl, an engineer and blogger from the U.K., sees the web3 moniker as pure repackaging of the same technology with the same issues. &#8220;At its core, web3 is a vapid marketing campaign that attempts to reframe the public’s negative associations of crypto assets into a false narrative about disruption of legacy tech company hegemony,&#8221; Diehl <a href="https://www.stephendiehl.com/blog/web3-bullshit.html">wrote in a December 4 blog post</a> that pulled no punches.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="54RBh1ydMU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/7-investors-discuss-web3s-present-and-peer-into-its-future/">7 investors discuss web3&#8217;s present and peer into its future</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;7 investors discuss web3&#8217;s present and peer into its future&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/7-investors-discuss-web3s-present-and-peer-into-its-future/embed/#?secret=54RBh1ydMU" data-secret="54RBh1ydMU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>What he means is that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/7-investors-discuss-web3s-present-and-peer-into-its-future/">web3 advocates say</a> that decentralization could reduce the power of the biggest internet companies &#8212; Amazon, Google, Microsoft and Facebook &#8212; and give it back to the users. But will it?</p>
<p>Kevin Werbach, a Wharton professor and author of &#8220;<a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/blockchain-and-new-architecture-trust">The Blockchain and the New Architecture of Trust</a>,&#8221; said that the technology might not be as far along as the hype, and the current popularity of digital assets doesn&#8217;t yet equate to a threat to Big Tech.</p>
<p>&#8220;Web3 is, to some extent, a meme or marketing brand around a variety of blockchain and cryptocurrency activity, which was already happening. Like the enterprise blockchain wave of a few years ago, web3 is being hyped as much farther along in adoption than it truly is. Lots of people are trading crypto and buying NFTs, but that doesn’t necessarily mean they are adopting distributed alternatives to major tech platforms,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>But Hilary Carter, VP of research at the Linux Foundation who spent three years at The Blockchain Research Institute in Toronto, sees a promising set of technologies that could be ready to scale to take on web3 hype.</p>
<p>&#8220;Web3 simply could not even exist without the innovation that is blockchain. The road has not been easy, as the technology has been too often dismissed for some early failures. But those failures drove innovation to address issues like scale,&#8221; Carter told me.</p>
<p>She said that the problems around scale and sustainability that I saw in my blockchain coverage several years ago have been solved in the ensuing years. &#8220;I think today, with those issues having been addressed, we&#8217;re seeing the maturity of the blockchain ecosystem, so much so that nation-states are building &#8216;central bank digital currency,&#8217; which is probably the use case that will demand the most throughput,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>Certainly, financial institutions are embracing the technology. In <a href="https://www2.deloitte.com/content/dam/insights/articles/US144337_Blockchain-survey/DI_Blockchain-survey.pdf">its annual blockchain survey</a>, Deloitte reported that nearly 80% of the respondents believed that digital assets would be important or somewhat important to their industries within the next two years. There is also a persistent belief that the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/28/once-a-buzzword-digital-transformation-is-reshaping-markets/">speeding of digital transformation</a> amid the pandemic is driving a corresponding shift to more widespread acceptance of digital currencies.</p>
<p>While the idea of digital currency in an increasingly digital world certainly makes sense, it&#8217;s a bigger leap to say that the blockchain can support a broad set of use cases, including replacing current internet infrastructure, as supporters suggest.</p>
<p>Diehl certainly doesn&#8217;t believe so. &#8220;On a compute basis, blockchain networks don’t scale except by becoming the very same plutocratic and centralized systems they allegedly were designed to replace,&#8221; he wrote.</p>
<p>But Carter sees room for both digital currency and other use cases. &#8220;Sure. I do see both digital currency and blockchain implementations advancing significantly,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>Werbach adds that there are some promising examples, but there is reason to be skeptical about web3 as an overall concept.</p>
<p>&#8220;New systems built from scratch, such as in <a href="https://ethereum.org/en/defi/">DeFi</a> (decentralized finance), don’t have the problem of legacy firms, but they face the challenge of scaling and mass adoption. Many so-called &#8216;web3&#8217; solutions are not as decentralized as they seem, while others have yet to show they are scalable, secure and accessible enough for the mass market. That may change, but it’s not a given that all these limitations will be overcome,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>And there&#8217;s the rub. Whether web3 is a marketing slogan or a true technological trend, there is certainly a lot of money and tech behind it. Yet there are clearly still substantial obstacles and challenges ahead, and only time will tell if web3 can overcome them and live up to the latest hype cycle.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SYcTMfuvtb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/22/the-blockchain-begins-finding-its-way-in-the-enterprise/">The blockchain begins finding its way in the enterprise</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The blockchain begins finding its way in the enterprise&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/22/the-blockchain-begins-finding-its-way-in-the-enterprise/embed/#?secret=SYcTMfuvtb" data-secret="SYcTMfuvtb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/the-irrational-exuberance-of-web3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246210</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rotten Tomatoes partners with TikTok to allow users to link to ratings, reviews and more</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/rotten-tomatoes-partners-with-tiktok-to-allow-users-to-link-to-ratings-reviews-and-more/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/rotten-tomatoes-partners-with-tiktok-to-allow-users-to-link-to-ratings-reviews-and-more/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 19:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rotten Tomatoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rotten Tomatoes announced today that it&#8217;s partnering with TikTok to launch a TikTok Jump that will allow users to link to movies and TV trailers, ratings, reviews, information on where to watch, clips, cast information and more. TikTok Jump is the short-form video app&#8217;s third-party integration tool that aims to deepen its relationships with third-party [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.rottentomatoes.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rotten Tomatoes</a> announced today that it&#8217;s partnering with TikTok to launch a TikTok Jump that will allow users to link to movies and TV trailers, ratings, reviews, information on where to watch, clips, cast information and more. TikTok Jump is the short-form video app&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/tiktok-launches-jump-a-third-party-integration-tool/">third-party integration tool</a> that aims to deepen its relationships with third-party partners.</p>
<p>When posting a video, TikTok users can now select Rotten Tomatoes from the list of available Jumps. From there, you can search for the movie or TV show that you&#8217;d like to link. Then, users will be presented with an &#8220;add to video&#8221; button.</p>
<p>&#8220;Film and TV clips and soundbites have been high on <span class="il">TikTok</span>’s For You feeds, with commenters often requesting more information on the content they’re discovering,&#8221; Rotten Tomatoes said in a press release. &#8220;With the new Rotten Tomatoes <span class="il">TikTok</span> Jump, creators can easily inform and entertain audiences by accessing a treasure trove of movie, TV and streaming-related content, video, information on where to watch, reviews and more on Rotten Tomatoes.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247287" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company’s partnership with TikTok allows it to reach more millennial and Gen Z users. Since launching TikTok Jump in June, the social media giant has partnered with many companies, such as Quizlet, Wikipedia, BuzzFeed and Jumprope, to allow them to create their own integrations within its app. Jumps can only be built by third-party providers after being approved through <a href="http://www.tiktok.com/jump" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an application process</a>.</p>
<p>For a platform that doesn’t let all users include a link in their bio yet, TikTok Jump expands the existing tools creators have to engage their audience.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/rotten-tomatoes-partners-with-tiktok-to-allow-users-to-link-to-ratings-reviews-and-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247287</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gift Guide: 5 gifts for all of us needing less screen time</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/gift-guide-5-gifts-for-all-of-us-who-need-less-screen-time/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/gift-guide-5-gifts-for-all-of-us-who-need-less-screen-time/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 19:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gift Guide 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2239269</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to TechCrunch’s 2021 Holiday Gift Guide! Need help with gift ideas? We’ve got lots of them. Check back from now until the end of December for more!]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome to TechCrunch’s 2021 Holiday Gift Guide! Need help with gift ideas? We’ve got lots of them. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2021/">Check back from now until the end of December for more</a>! </em></p>
<p id="speakable-summary">This is a year where we&#8217;ve all had to reconsider our relationship with tech. Social media has finally been put on trial for its potential harms, including to vulnerable adolescents. Algorithms have been accused of dividing us and sending us down rabbit holes of extremism. Even tech companies with sizable &#8220;fan&#8221; bases, like Apple, have been seen in a new light as they&#8217;re challenged by antitrust lawsuits and investigations.</p>
<p>For some, 2022 may mean looking to find a healthier balance with the sort of tech we&#8217;re using in our lives. In that light, we present a gift guide that&#8217;s focused on tech that allows us to escape tech!</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2239269" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h2><strong>AllTrails Pro </strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2239275" style="width: 2131px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2239275" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2239275 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1203239037-1.jpg" alt="" width="2121" height="1414" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1203239037-1.jpg 2121w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1203239037-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1203239037-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1203239037-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1203239037-1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1203239037-1.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1203239037-1.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1203239037-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2121px) 100vw, 2121px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2239275" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Christoph+Wagner" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Christoph Wagner <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>AllTrails is a popular guide to over 200,000 outdoor trails, offering detailed maps, photos and reviews curated by millions of hikers and more. But the <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/gift?ref=header" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AllTrails Pro subscription</a> is worth it for any dedicated hiker, biker or climber, as it offers downloadable maps &#8212; often necessary for off-the-grid hikes, as well as other handy features, like off-route notifications, a <a href="https://support.alltrails.com/hc/en-us/articles/360019246351-What-is-Lifeline-" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lifeline</a> feature that keeps safety contacts informed as to your trail progress and access to air quality, pollen and weather details on the maps. The company has big plans for the year ahead, too, thanks to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/17/alltrails-raises-150m-after-covid-accelerates-peoples-interest-in-exploring-the-outdoors/">its recent $150 million fundraise</a>, which it plans to invest in further product development.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/gift?ref=header" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$29.99 per year or $59.99 for 3 years</a></p>
<h2><strong>Opal</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2239286" style="width: 2159px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2239286" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2239286 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-24-at-11.12.50-AM.jpg" alt="" width="2149" height="1494" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-24-at-11.12.50-AM.jpg 2149w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-24-at-11.12.50-AM.jpg?resize=150,104 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-24-at-11.12.50-AM.jpg?resize=300,209 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-24-at-11.12.50-AM.jpg?resize=768,534 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-24-at-11.12.50-AM.jpg?resize=680,473 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-24-at-11.12.50-AM.jpg?resize=1536,1068 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-24-at-11.12.50-AM.jpg?resize=2048,1424 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-24-at-11.12.50-AM.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2149px) 100vw, 2149px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2239286" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Opal</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Phones can be distracting, taking us out of the moment and back into our screens. While recent updates like Apple&#8217;s Focus Mode feature have given us back some control, the Opal app takes things even further. The app, essentially a VPN client, lets you completely disconnect distracting apps so you can focus and easily set automatic schedules for things like work or family time where apps and notifications will leave you alone. Unlike some other tools, which can be disabled by the user, you can even configure &#8220;deep focus&#8221; sessions in Opal with a timer you can&#8217;t bypass for when you really need to not be distracted. You can use the app in a number of ways &#8212; on-demand when you need to concentrate or always on to help you craft better routines for your life with more boundaries.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> A <a href="https://www.opal.so/gift" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$40 Gift Subscription</a> offers one year of Opal Pro</p>
<h2><strong>Light Phone</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2239303" style="width: 1410px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2239303" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2239303 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/light-phone.jpeg" alt="" width="1400" height="936" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/light-phone.jpeg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/light-phone.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/light-phone.jpeg?resize=300,201 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/light-phone.jpeg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/light-phone.jpeg?resize=680,455 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/light-phone.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1400px) 100vw, 1400px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2239303" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Light Phone</p></div></p>
<p>When you really need to get off the grid, the best phone could be no phone. But that&#8217;s not always viable in this day and age where we need to be able to reach others in the event of an emergency or have them be able to reach us. Plus, we don&#8217;t really want to go back to the days of printing out our MapQuest directions, right?</p>
<p>The Light Phone is another option, which could allow you to take a break without being fully disconnected. The phone allows you to make calls and texts and includes basic utilities like an alarm, calculator, a hotspot feature and a simple music and podcast player. It also <a href="https://medium.com/the-light-phone/introducing-the-directions-tool-ebf62217b276" target="_blank" rel="noopener">just added a directions tool</a> and will soon add support for public transit routes. The idea is to offer a phone that&#8217;s &#8220;smart&#8221; but not filled with addictive apps and games. The Light Phone may not make sense for everyone as their full-time device, but it could be swapped in for your weekend getaway or any other time you&#8217;re feeling too overwhelmed. The phone offers <a href="https://www.thelightphone.com/plans" target="_blank" rel="noopener">its own SIM plans</a> on AT&amp;T starting at $30/month for unlimited calls and texts with 1 GB of data, billed monthly with no commitment. But the phone itself is unlocked and will work with any compatible 4G VoLTE Nano-SIM (like the one in your current smartphone, probably.)</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $299 (Light Phone II) <a href="https://www.thelightphone.com/products" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in either Light Gray or Black</a></p>
<h2><strong>Speechify</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2239335" style="width: 1992px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2239335" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2239335 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-24-at-11.44.35-AM.jpg" alt="" width="1982" height="1116" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-24-at-11.44.35-AM.jpg 1982w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-24-at-11.44.35-AM.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-24-at-11.44.35-AM.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-24-at-11.44.35-AM.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-24-at-11.44.35-AM.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-24-at-11.44.35-AM.jpg?resize=1536,865 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-24-at-11.44.35-AM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1982px) 100vw, 1982px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2239335" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Speechify</p></div></p>
<p>Listening to podcasts and e-books is already a popular activity, but what if you could reduce your screen time by listening to just about anything with the help of a text-to-speech reader? Speechify makes this possible. The web and mobile app lets you listen to anything with text &#8212; documents, news articles, research papers, school assignments, PDFs, emails and more &#8212; using a selection of natural-sounding AI voices. The app currently supports Gmail, Outlook, Messenger, WhatsApp, Google Docs, Notion, MS Teams, PDFs, Medium, NYT, BBC, Wikipedia, Twitter, Facebook, Reddit and LinkedIn. You can even snap photos of the pages in your books to have them read aloud. But this solution is not cheap &#8212; it&#8217;s more of a commitment to shift much of your screen-based reading to audio.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $139 for 1 year of Speechify Premium (<a href="https://speechify.com/sales?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">special pricing</a> is available for groups, teams and classrooms)</p>
<h2><strong>Reese&#8217;s Book Club box sets</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2239354" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2239354" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2239354 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RBC_cozy-02-IOMT.jpg" alt="" width="2000" height="2000" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RBC_cozy-02-IOMT.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RBC_cozy-02-IOMT.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RBC_cozy-02-IOMT.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RBC_cozy-02-IOMT.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RBC_cozy-02-IOMT.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RBC_cozy-02-IOMT.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RBC_cozy-02-IOMT.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RBC_cozy-02-IOMT.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RBC_cozy-02-IOMT.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RBC_cozy-02-IOMT.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RBC_cozy-02-IOMT.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2239354" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Reese&#8217;s Book Club</p></div></p>
<p>For those who prefer actual books over e-books or audio, Reese&#8217;s Book Club, the online book club and recommendations app from Reese Witherspoon, is offering themed Gift of Reading Box Sets as gifts. The boxes pair a favorite book club pick with other items that make your reading time more enjoyable, like cozy socks or throws, snacks, coffees, bookmarks, towels to go along with your &#8220;beach read,&#8221; skincare products and more. The boxes have enough items to make them feel like a more premium gift, perfect for a favorite mother-in-law or aunt who&#8217;s always got a book in her hand. You also get to select the book the box includes and can even customize your own box with the available items.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://reesesbookclub.com/shop/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$54.95 for a hardcover book pick and $49.95 for paperback</a>. There&#8217;s also a Create Your Own box with select bundles starting at $34.95.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/gift-guide-2021-banner.jpg" alt="TechCrunch Gift Guide 2021" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/gift-guide-5-gifts-for-all-of-us-who-need-less-screen-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2239269</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coinbase will let you view your NFT collection in its browser wallet</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/coinbase-will-let-you-view-your-nft-collection-in-its-browser-wallet/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/coinbase-will-let-you-view-your-nft-collection-in-its-browser-wallet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 18:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinbase Wallet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wallet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247331</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While Coinbase is better known for its cryptocurrency exchange, the company has also been working on a couple of self-custody wallets under the Coinbase Wallet brand. This type of wallets put you in charge of your crypto assets as private keys are stored on your devices. Today the company is bringing NFTs to the desktop [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">While <a href="https://www.coinbase.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Coinbase</a> is better known for its cryptocurrency exchange, the company has also been working on a couple of self-custody wallets under the <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/wallet" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Coinbase Wallet</a> brand. This type of wallets put you in charge of your crypto assets as private keys are stored on your devices.</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.coinbase.com/making-web3-and-the-world-of-crypto-more-user-friendly-and-accessible-7ceda4b844d3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Today</a> the company is bringing NFTs to the desktop browser. People who use Coinbase Wallet for desktop browsers will soon see a new tab called &#8220;NFTs,&#8221; which will let you access the non-fungible tokens (NFTs) associated with your wallet address.</p>
<p>While many mobile wallets let you view your NFT collection, such as <a href="https://rainbow.me" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rainbow</a>, <a href="https://www.argent.xyz" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Argent</a> and also Coinbase Wallet on mobile, browser extensions typically don’t have a native NFT gallery feature. The feature is rolling out in a few days.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247331" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2247340" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2247340" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2247340" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Coinbase-Wallet.gif" alt="" width="1024" height="576" /><p id="caption-attachment-2247340" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Coinbase</p></div></p>
<p>In addition to the new NFT feature, Coinbase has been working on better support for testnets and alternative networks. While you can already switch between multiple networks from the settings, Coinbase Wallet will now display your token balances across all supported networks, such as Arbitrum, Avalanche, Binance Smart Chain, Fantom, Optimism, Polygon and xdai. It’s a sort of unified inbox for your crypto assets.</p>
<p>Coinbase Wallet will also support EIP-3085 (EIP stands for Ethereum Improvement Proposal). If a Coinbase Wallet interacts with a decentralized application that also supports EIP-3085, it’ll lead to a better user experience for the end user.</p>
<p>EIP-3085 allows dApp developers to suggest a specific network for a transaction. In other words, it makes it easier to interact with multiple networks.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The main advantage of using a self-custody wallet is that you’re not limited to what’s available in the app. You can connect to a third-party dApp using WalletLink, WalletConnect, etc.</p>
<p>But Coinbase has also integrated some decentralized exchanges directly in the Coinbase Wallet interface. Interestingly, Coinbase is using Uniswap and 0x for those trades. Coinbase collects a 1% fee on trades through its native DEX feature.</p>
<p>In many ways, Coinbase Wallet feels like Coinbase’s web3 initiative. The company wants to remain relevant as crypto users become more and more educated and start interacting with more dApps.</p>
<p><a href="https://metamask.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MetaMask</a> has been quite popular with new crypto users who want to buy an NFT for the first time. But MetaMask users will tell you that MetaMask is … not great. And Coinbase doesn’t want to stand still. It has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/coinbase-acquihires-team-behind-brd-crypto-wallet/">acqui-hired crypto wallet startup BRD</a> and it plans to launch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/coinbase-is-launching-its-own-nft-platform-to-take-on-opensea/">its own NFT marketplace</a>.</p>
<p><em>Disclosure: I own small amounts of various cryptocurrencies.</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0Y6hXd7KmI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/coinbase-acquihires-team-behind-brd-crypto-wallet/">Coinbase acqui-hires team behind BRD crypto wallet</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Coinbase acqui-hires team behind BRD crypto wallet&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/coinbase-acquihires-team-behind-brd-crypto-wallet/embed/#?secret=0Y6hXd7KmI" data-secret="0Y6hXd7KmI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Xr0yfROqQn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/coinbase-is-launching-its-own-nft-platform-to-take-on-opensea/">Coinbase is launching its own NFT platform to take on OpenSea</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Coinbase is launching its own NFT platform to take on OpenSea&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/coinbase-is-launching-its-own-nft-platform-to-take-on-opensea/embed/#?secret=Xr0yfROqQn" data-secret="Xr0yfROqQn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/coinbase-will-let-you-view-your-nft-collection-in-its-browser-wallet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247331</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 investors discuss web3&#8217;s present and peer into its future</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/7-investors-discuss-web3s-present-and-peer-into-its-future/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/7-investors-discuss-web3s-present-and-peer-into-its-future/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Karan Bhasin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 17:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atul Ajoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Chreng-Messembourg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dfj growth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC investor survey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eden Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Horseshoe Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investor survey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jai Das]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LeadBlock Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lior Messika]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mercedes Bent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Randy Glein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sam Shapiro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sapphire Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246865</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We surveyed select investors in web3 to find out where web3 stands and what the future holds.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Most people have experienced the internet only through Web 2.0: online applications, the social web and software as a service form the fabric of our lives.</p>
<p>But even as other technology rapidly evolves, basic web infrastructure has remained largely unchanged since the turn of the millennium. Lately, many have championed web3 as the internet&#8217;s next phase, but the term encompasses so much territory, conversations can be rather diffuse.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re still years away from web3 capturing major market share, and there are valid concerns that its complexity will daunt consumers and regulators. However, our research indicated that the investment landscape is growing increasingly competitive as venture capitalists become more educated and less skeptical.</p>
<p>To get a clearer sense of where the market is, we reached out to several active investors to find out where web3 stands and what the future holds:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/liormessika/?originalSubdomain=il" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lior Messika</a>, founder and managing partner, <a href="https://www.edenblock.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Eden Block</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/atul-ajoy-833b59123/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Atul Ajoy</a>, partner, <a href="https://www.horseshoe.vc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Horseshoe Capital</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidchreng/?originalSubdomain=uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">David Chreng-Messembourg</a>, founding partner, <a href="https://leadblockpartners.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LeadBlock Partners</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/randyglein/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Randy Glein</a>, founder/partner, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/samshap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sam Shapiro</a>, principal, <a href="https://dfjgrowth.com/index.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DFJ Growth</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mercedesbent/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mercedes Bent</a>, partner, <a href="https://lsvp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lightspeed Venture Partners</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jaidas/">Jai Das</a>, co-founder, president and partner, <a href="https://sapphireventures.com/">Sapphire Ventures</a></li>
</ul>
<p>To make things as clear as possible, we asked each respondent to share their elevator pitch: How would they describe the technology if they were trying to convince a skeptic to invest?</p>
<p>Starting with the potential consumer appeal of cartoon apes, we tried to find out what specifically attracted them to invest in the semantic web and where they&#8217;re currently seeing demand. &#8220;I initially got into web3 through verifiable credentials and data provenance in the enterprise market,&#8221; said Atul Ajoy, a partner at Horseshoe Capital. Several others said they started exploring the space after developing an interest in crypto.</p>
<p>In addition to discussing potential applications in advertising, fintech and enterprise apps, respondents shared their advice for web3 founders who are hunting for funding, along with their concerns about factors that could stall its development. Finally, we asked each respondent: What are skeptical web3 investors missing?</p>
<p>&#8220;I never met a skeptical investor who actually understood what was going on. If you get it, you’re probably strapped in and ready to go,&#8221; said Lior Messika, founder and managing partner, Eden Block.</p>
<p>&#8220;At this point, web3 has proven itself as more than a phenomenon — it is the foundational layer of the metaverse.&#8221;</p>
<hr />
<h2>Lior Messika, founder and managing partner, Eden Block</h2>
<p><strong>Please give us your web3 elevator pitch: What is it, and what role does it play in today’s internet framework? </strong></p>
<p>In two sentences: <strong>Web3 is the key to the <em>real </em>metaverse</strong>. Web3 will house our financial institutions, social interactions, personal identities and much, much more in the not-so-distant future.</p>
<p>Expanding: When I look at web3, I see an amalgam of decentralized infrastructure capable of powering a new world. The two most distinct properties of web3 are composability and decentralization. Firstly, crypto networks are swallowing up value and creating environments where every possible form of on-chain value interlinks and interacts with the other. Web3 has the unique ability to create tangible value systems out of value systems that remained intangible for millennia. It unlocks a world where our social capital, reputations, and historical interactions are given indelible and truthful assets — which often get priced into a market powered by decentralized protocols.</p>
<p>Web3 is where all decentralized systems will learn to interact with each other, building on the security and value (thus network effects) of a broader ecosystem.<strong> It will be multilayered and multifaceted, supported by completely new infrastructure</strong>. Our applications will need to <a href="http://pokt.network" target="_blank" rel="noopener">relay data reliably</a>, <a href="https://nymtech.net/nym-whitepaper.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">transfer data completely privately</a>, <a href="http://ipfs.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">store data</a> and maintain high levels of <a href="https://celestia.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">availability</a> — all on decentralized rails. In web3’s short history, we’ve already seen how <a href="https://www.theblockcrypto.com/post/84232/ethereum-infrastructure-provider-infura-is-down" target="_blank" rel="noopener">centralized infrastructure can be a dangerous tradeoff</a>.</p>
<p><strong>What made you decide to get into the space? Cartoon apes and blockchain games don’t yet have broad consumer appeal: Where are you seeing demand for web3 products today? </strong></p>
<p>Web3 symbolizes a massive societal shift, infused with innovation and supercharged with values. I dove headfirst into the space when I understood that we’re in the midst of a cultural revolution enabled by technology — not the other way around. Crypto and web3 is our technological answer to a societal problem that has plagued us for millenia, so I think that it’s natural for us to treat this movement with respect and passion.</p>
<p>On products: Some of the most powerful web3 products that we’re seeing these days are intensely focused on ownership, creation and other contextual features that ultimately amount to our digital identities. Funnily enough, we’re already starting to see how crypto products are taking hold of our culture and of our shared attention. In the metaverse, your “pfp” is not only a skin of sorts but the key to another dimension. The individualism this basic feature enables over time explains the frenzied NFT market, which will undoubtedly remain a large part of web3 and the metaverse. The technological basis for NFTs will unlock disruptive value systems across gaming, fashion, social and creator economies.</p>
<p>On a less obvious note, coordination in large, decentralized groups (DAOs) will require streamlined frameworks and transparent value systems. As communities grow and scale into multibillion-dollar networks, decentralized governance becomes very difficult. Colony and Coordinape will enable the next generation of DAOs through specialized tooling and automated frameworks for governance and incentives.</p>
<p><strong>What kinds of applications can we expect to reach the market in the near future? Where are you placing your bets, and can you name a few companies to watch?</strong></p>
<p>Within the broader context of web3, we see tremendous growth across two distinct layers in the stack —<strong> infrastructure and applications</strong>. Unlike TCP/IP (a core piece of internet infrastructure that cannot be monetized) at the dawn of the internet, decentralized protocols and baked-in incentive systems make running decentralized infrastructure extremely valuable. Technologies like the <a href="https://www.pokt.network/">Pocket Network</a> manifest this in full force, with billions of relays per week. The Pocket Network provides decentralized infrastructure to an entire ecosystem — and compensates its node runners handsomely for the work. At the current state of relays, the forecasted annualized revenue of the network is in the hundreds of millions.</p>
<p>Another core piece of infrastructure for web3 is <strong>Biconomy</strong>. The Biconomy team is building <b>transactional infrastructure for the decentralized web</b>. Its platform abstracts away crypto transaction complexities for both developers and users. Biconomy has built a series of products that cater to developers building applications in web3 — as protocols continue to grow into mass producers of on-chain services, developers need tools to streamline their operations and integrations to allow for mass scale.</p>
<p>On the application layer, I believe that we’ve only begun to scratch the surface of interoperable value systems within the broader web3 space. Through decentralized finance, we will one day price, value and monetize every single form of capital that can be linked to us on-chain. Our favorite art pieces will pay off our mortgage on lending protocols, and our <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/like-to-earn-nft-platform-rara-looks-to-monetize-the-future-of-online-engagement-2021-08">“likes” will become financial assets</a>. <strong>In simple terms, decentralized finance will kick-start the <em>great monetization of everything</em>.</strong> Protocols like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/vega-raises-5m-to-give-anyone-the-ability-to-launch-a-derivatives-market/">Vega Protocol</a> aim to enable decentralized derivatives at scale through fair and efficient markets.</p>
<p>Another trillion-dollar opportunity in DeFi relates to a massive elephant in the room — since markets need stability to remain competitive and efficient, DeFi has largely sacrificed decentralization for stability, opting for the USD as the main underlying collateral for a huge portion of the market. Protocols like <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/tatianakoffman/2021/10/11/meet-float-protocolthe-algorithmic-stablecoin-built-by-an-anonymous-team/?sh=3ce17360123b" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Float</a> offer an alternative, by creating a low-volatility asset that can remain completely decentralized. Without a truly decentralized collateral in DeFi, web3 is at risk.</p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Can you share a few of your top concerns? What are some of the pitfalls that could prevent web3 from realizing its potential? </span></strong></p>
<p>Firstly, it must be understood that decentralization <em>has </em>to be the basis for all true innovation in what we refer to as web3. <strong>It is the common thread between every truly disruptive application in today’s cryptosphere:</strong> Uniswap and its <a href="https://forkswap.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">many clones</a>, money markets like <a href="https://compound.finance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Compound</a>, Cryptopunks and Bored Apes, and storage solutions like <a href="https://filecoin.io/store/#intro">Filecoin</a> and <a href="https://ipfs.io/">IPFS</a> — all enabled by one underlying property. Future developments across crypto networks will continue to leverage decentralization as a core enabler and build additional utility around it.</p>
<p>In the absence of decentralization, disruption is stifled. For this reason, I believe that the biggest risk for us as we venture deeper into web3 is going back to how things were. Making easy tradeoffs that take us away from the very core premise of web3 — maximal decentralization, often at the cost of performance or scalability.</p>
<p><strong>What are some of the use cases and monetizable opportunities that will encourage major websites to switch over to web3? Will the prospect of increased internet regulation be a factor?</strong></p>
<p>Internet regulation is one extreme, but the more likely case is that web3 will swallow up enough value as it continues to grow for major websites to deem it <em>necessary </em>to switch over to web3. Web3 is akin to an economy, and most players will want to participate.</p>
<p><strong>Over the next decade, what are some of the major leaps you anticipate? Which aspects of web3 are overhyped?</strong></p>
<p>One major leap we will make as a society is to embrace true ownership. Financial freedom is deeply embedded in financial responsibility, and web3 is an interface to the most direct form of responsibility (and freedom) possible.</p>
<p>On the topic of overhyped aspects of web3: I believe the radical openness and permissionless access across web3 open the door to a lot of experimentation and speculation. For this reason, most of the overhyped areas of web3 will actually be found at the bottom of the most valuable markets in the space. For example, looking at anything but the top 15-20 NFT projects and their associated communities is excruciating. In the long term, overhyped segments of the market will continue to act as a signal of where much of the innovation and broader focus currently stirs.</p>
<p><strong>How competitive is the web3 investment market today? What needs to be done to grow interest?</strong></p>
<p>The web3 investment market has <em>never </em>been more competitive. Investors are rallying behind developer teams with an idea and a bank account. I believe that while the capital continues to flow into the space so freely, the fundamentals remain the same yet the stakes (both in risk and upside) have never been higher. The amount of potential value in strong decentralized use cases is almost unimaginable, and teams are scouring the world for talent. To grow even more interest, the funding will have to eventually match talent and human capital, which currently seems extremely difficult to find.</p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">What advice would you give web3 founders who are trying to get their first check? </span></strong></p>
<p>Web3 needs new leaders and will designate them organically as this ecosystem evolves. Nowadays, web3 founders take on the roles of communicators and community builders. In a world where development is open source and contributions are largely permissionless (more often the case in applications built on Ethereum), rallying an entire ecosystem to your cause becomes an extremely unique challenge.</p>
<p>The core drivers for web3 are values-based and financially driven — thus, iterating on web3 will be a cultural and capitalistic mission. It will be incentivized by numbers, algorithms and code, and it will also be supercharged by brand, community and <em>people. </em>Web3 founders should internalize this and leverage that intimacy between developer and community to their advantage. Founders who clearly communicate the values and core missions of their project right from the outset will enable communities to form around that shared goal and propel the project into existence — and mass distribution.</p>
<p><strong>Without market intelligence, are they at a disadvantage when it comes to pitching?</strong></p>
<p>Without a certain amount of market intelligence, founders are severely disadvantaged. Web3 iterates so quickly and so sharply that even a few months of downtime can create fundamental knowledge gaps. In our investing practice, we see the stark difference between founders who are web3-native and those who haven’t taken the plunge yet. By now, it’s become clear that to build a successful product in web3, teams require a certain level of nativity to correctly identify gaps in the market, desires and needs of its user base, and much more.</p>
<p><strong>Do you know any skeptical investors? What do you think they’re missing?</strong></p>
<p>I never met a skeptical investor who actually understood what was going on. If you get it, you’re probably strapped in and ready to go. At this point, web3 has proven itself as more than a phenomenon — it is the foundational layer of the metaverse. Skeptical investors are probably missing the true meaning of Meta’s recent play, Zuck’s rather funny conversation with Gary Vee about NFTs and the general direction of digital life.</p>
<h2>Atul Ajoy, partner, Horseshoe Capital</h2>
<p><strong>Please give us your web3 elevator pitch: What is it, and what role does it play in today’s internet framework? </strong></p>
<p>Web3 is a new decentralized form of the internet where users become owners. Today’s internet, Web 2.0, is largely controlled by centralized players who capture much of the monetary value created on the internet. Web3 replaces these centralized players with decentralized networks that distribute the value to developers, creators and users. This allows these network participants to design new incentive mechanisms in on-chain for organizations like DAOs.</p>
<p><strong>What made you decide to get into the space? Cartoon apes and blockchain games don’t yet have broad consumer appeal: Where are you seeing demand for web3 products today? <div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/7-investors-discuss-web3s-present-and-peer-into-its-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246865</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Andreessen Horowitz backs NFT investor group behind rare Wu-Tang Clan album purchase</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/andreessen-horowitz-backs-nft-investor-group-behind-one-of-a-kind-wu-tang-clan-album-purchase/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/andreessen-horowitz-backs-nft-investor-group-behind-one-of-a-kind-wu-tang-clan-album-purchase/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 17:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Edward Snowden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emerging-Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Friends with Benefits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OpenSea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PleasrDAO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Royal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247180</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The crypto collective that bought Wu-Tang Clan&#8217;s ‘Once Upon a Time in Shaolin’ album and an NFT of the original Doge image has a new member: venture capital firm Andreessen Horowitz. The firm tells TechCrunch it has made an investment in PleasrDAO, a blockchain-aligned group of a few dozen crypto investors that have been teaming [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The crypto collective that bought Wu-Tang Clan&#8217;s ‘Once Upon a Time in Shaolin’ album and an NFT of the original Doge image has a new member: venture capital firm Andreessen Horowitz.</p>
<p>The firm tells TechCrunch it has made an investment in <a href="https://pleasr.org/">PleasrDAO</a>, a blockchain-aligned group of a few dozen crypto investors that have been teaming up to buy high-priced NFTs in recent months. The group&#8217;s purchases include the famous Doge image which they bought for $4 million (1,696.9 ETH to be exact) then later fractionalized and sold to the crypto community (it&#8217;s current implied market cap is just above $100 million). The DAO also paid some $5.4 million for a work from Edward Snowden and $4 million for the Wu-Tang Clan album.</p>
<p>A DAO (or decentralized autonomous organization) is basically a group organized formally around blockchain voting mechanisms to make decisions and invest capital.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247180" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>A16z Crypto&#8217;s investment in PleasrDAO is not their first publicly-announced bet on the organization type. In October, the firm <a href="https://a16z.com/2021/10/27/investing-in-friends-with-benefits-a-dao/">made an investment in</a> Friends With Benefits (FWB) DAO, which they <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/crypto-social-club-got-millions-from-top-vcs-andreessen-horowitz-2021-9">valued at $100 million</a>. Andreessen Horowitz did not disclose the size of their investment in PleasrDAO though council member Santiago Santos specified their overall stake of the DAO&#8217;s governance tokens was &#8220;less than 5 percent.&#8221;</p>
<p>Like many other crypto groups, PleasrDAO had a very singular ambition when it was formed &#8212; to bid on a work by digital artist, in this case one by <a href="https://twitter.com/pplpleasr1">pplpleasr</a>. Said work was an animated video advertisement for the decentralized exchange platform Uniswap. The group formed in March after crypto founder Leighton Cusack <a href="https://twitter.com/lay2000lbs/status/1375195529504829443?s=20">tweeted</a> a link to the auction and asked, &#8220;Anyone want to create a quick DAO to bid on this???&#8221; The group eventually won the bid at 310 Eth (some $525k at the time) with all proceeds for the purchase going to charity.</p>
<p>&#8220;Very quickly on, we thought, a lot of the smartest minds in DeFi are here &#8212; there is an opportunity to really take this in an interesting direction,&#8221; Santos tells TechCrunch. &#8220;I think, over time, the DAO grew to the point where we felt that we needed some more structure and hierarchy.&#8221;</p>
<p>The group has since continued making investments and bulking up its portfolio while aiming to discover new artists that it can support. Santos says he has aims for the group to become a &#8220;<a href="https://www.visitflorence.com/florence-history-and-culture/the-house-of-the-medici.html">Medici house</a>&#8221; of NFTs &#8220;where a lot of digitally native artists can come and get initiated and discovered.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;DAOs are almost the purest manifestation of what Web3 and crypto are all about,&#8221; a16z GP Ali Yahya tells TechCrunch.</p>
<p>While a16z was early to crypto, the rise of so-called &#8220;crypto native&#8221; investment funds operating closer to founder and developer networks in the space has made it necessary for legacy firms like a16z to get bolder in backing new groups like DAOs. Andreessen Horowitz sees plenty of areas where they can help PleasrDAO including policy and regulatory concerns &#8212; an area where DAOs currently seem to be operating in a gray area of as unregulated investment funds of pooled capital.</p>
<p>A16z&#8217;s bet on the group is, in many ways, a leveraged bet on NFTs, which the group has already bet heavily on. This year, the firm backed NFT marketplace OpenSea, NFT gaming giant Sky Mavis and NFT music platform Royal, among others. The firm also anchored Meta4 &#8212; a $100 million venture fund dedicated to buying up pricey NFTs. These investments are being made from the firm&#8217;s massive $2.2 billion crypto-centric fund, which the firm debuted this summer.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s easy to underestimate the potential of NFTs,&#8221; Yahya says. &#8220;It very well could be that NFTs will be enormous and that the total market cap of all NFTs down the line will actually be bigger than the market cap for fungible tokens.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jGfShh295L"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/a-nine-figure-fund-for-jpgs/">A nine-figure fund for JPGs?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A nine-figure fund for JPGs?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/a-nine-figure-fund-for-jpgs/embed/#?secret=jGfShh295L" data-secret="jGfShh295L" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/andreessen-horowitz-backs-nft-investor-group-behind-one-of-a-kind-wu-tang-clan-album-purchase/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247180</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Space Florida&#8217;s incredible shrinking Rivian stake</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/space-florida-shrinking-rivian-stake/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/space-florida-shrinking-rivian-stake/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 17:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[R1T]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rivian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247007</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It would have been a legendary payoff for any investor, let alone a public agency: swapping an undrivable car for a multibillion-dollar stake in a hot new EV startup. Until last year, Space Florida, the state&#8217;s economic development agency for aerospace, believed that it owned 3% of Rivian as a result of a canny lease-back [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It would have been a legendary payoff for any investor, let alone a public agency: swapping an undrivable car for a multibillion-dollar stake in a hot new EV startup.</p>
<p>Until last year, Space Florida, the state&#8217;s economic development agency for aerospace, believed that it owned 3% of Rivian as a result of a canny lease-back agreement made a decade earlier. Following <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/09/rivian-raises-10-5b-in-one-of-the-hottest-ipos-of-2021/">Rivian&#8217;s blockbuster IPO</a> in November, that stake would have been worth nearly $3 billion based on Rivian&#8217;s current market capitalization &#8212; a more than 1,000-fold return on Space Florida&#8217;s investment. That investment, which totaled nearly $2 million, included buying prototypes from Rivian in exchange for warrants in the company as well as the cost of buying the stock.</p>
<p>Instead &#8212; and through a mechanism that neither the agency nor Rivian can explain &#8212; Space Florida has ended up holding just 60,000 shares in the company, worth less than $7 million, public records from the agency show.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247007" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>So why did a commercial space booster get involved with an EV pickup maker in the first place, and how did its supposed ownership evaporate?</p>
<p><a href="https://www.spaceflorida.gov/">Space Florida</a> began working with Rivian before it was called Rivian &#8212; and even before it was making electric vehicles. In 2009, RJ Scaringe founded Mainstream Motors as a spin-out from his father&#8217;s R&amp;D firm in Rockledge, Florida. His original plan was to design an ultra-efficient gas-powered coupe capable of 60 miles per gallon and bring it into production in Florida using lightweight materials and modular manufacturing, all by the end of 2013.</p>
<p>The Florida Energy and Climate Commission committed $2 million in seed money, enough for Scaringe to hire a small team to design a prototype. This is separate from Rivian&#8217;s deal with Space Florida. According <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-05/rivian-founder-s-long-bumpy-road-to-electric-pickup">to a Bloomberg report</a>, the team then worked around the clock to produce plans for the vehicle, apart from its engine. When the plans were ready, they shipped them to a contract manufacturer in Detroit, along with a Mini Cooper for its powerplant.</p>
<p>Scaringe then pulled off what must have seemed to be a stroke of genius. In June 2010, with the company&#8217;s first prototype still just a collection of custom and scavenged parts in Detroit, Scaringe sold it to Space Florida for $500,000.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Originally, there was a potential that it would bring an automobile manufacturing plant to Florida,&#8221; Dale Ketcham, VP of Space Florida, told TechCrunch in a recent interview. &#8220;But it was more the possible applications off-planet, whether on the moon or Mars, that piqued our interest.&#8221;</p>
<p>When the first prototype, nicknamed &#8220;The Blue Thing,&#8221; arrived in Florida in October 2010, Space Florida immediately leased it back to Scaringe for $100 a year. The car was not ready to drive on public roads, let alone move into production, according to Bloomberg. But the company could use it for testing and demonstrations, including a (never-consummated) plan to speed-test it at NASA&#8217;s Shuttle Landing Facility in the Kennedy Space Center, <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/21151621-2011-4-8-rivian-and-nasa-space-act">records obtained through a Freedom of Information Act request show</a>. After the 10-year lease was up, Scaringe could repurchase the vehicle from Space Florida for a final $100.</p>
<p>But as an &#8220;additional consideration,&#8221; according to Space Florida documents, the startup would also issue to Space Florida a warrant to acquire 100 shares of its common stock, redeemable any time in the next decade, for $1,000 per share.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s one of the little things we&#8217;d done in the past with other organizations,&#8221; Ketcham recalled. &#8220;It gave us a little piece of the pie and it gave them some cash.&#8221; Space Florida also assisted the small company with business advice.</p>
<p>Scaringe changed Mainstream Motors&#8217; name to Avera. In March 2011, he changed it again &#8212; to Rivian &#8212; and persuaded Space Florida to repeat the deal. The agency would buy three more vehicles for $1 million, and once more lease them back to Rivian for $100 a year. This time, Rivian issued Space Florida a warrant for a further 200 shares, at $1,843 each. Which means if Space Florida wanted to redeem those shares it would cost them $368,600.</p>
<p>It was a dark time for Rivian. Scaringe was scrambling for investors and down to a skeleton crew of employees. It took Rivian until June 2014 to complete the three promised vehicles, and months more to start the lease. Soon afterward, and following a big investment from Saudi Arabia, Scaringe relocated Rivian to Michigan, bought a factory in Illinois and put Florida in his rearview mirror.</p>
<p>But he left a little bit of his company behind. Space Florida recorded the Rivian warrant agreements<a href="https://www.spaceflorida.gov/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/SFL2014-FinancialStatements.pdf"> in its financial statement</a> for the year 2013. The first warrant for 100 shares, it noted, &#8220;is estimated to equal a 1% ownership interest&#8221; in the company. The second, for 200, &#8220;is equal to a 2% ownership interest.&#8221; Space Florida believed its 300 shares represented a full 3% of the young startup, albeit one whose future was still uncertain.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have our investment fund to make those kinds of investments,&#8221; Ketcham said. &#8220;Everything isn&#8217;t going to be a winner. If a company craters, then you&#8217;re S.O.L. like everyone else.&#8221;</p>
<p>Rivian did not crater, however. In fact, its progress was little short of exponential, with hundreds of millions in funding flowing in from Amazon, Ford and Cox Automotive, then billions more from T. Rowe Price, Amazon&#8217;s Climate Pledge Fund, Ford and others.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1751156" style="width: 2602px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1072928344.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1751156" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-1751156 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1072928344.jpg" alt="" width="2592" height="1728" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1072928344.jpg 2592w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1072928344.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1072928344.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1072928344.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1072928344.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1072928344.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1072928344.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-1072928344.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2592px) 100vw, 2592px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1751156" class="wp-caption-text">Rivian CEO RJ Scaringe speaks in November 2018 before unveiling the company&#8217;s two first electric vehicles at an event at the Griffith Observatory in Los Angeles. <strong>Image Credits</strong>: Getty/Phillip Faraone</p></div></p>
<p>In 2018, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/20/an-inside-look-at-rivians-ev-ambitions-from-ai-batteries-to-electric-jet-skis/">Scaringe told TechCrunch</a>: &#8220;We&#8217;ve got a good relationship with Space Florida. They hoped we would be able to manufacture there but as the company began to grow, the lack of automotive infrastructure became a problem. They do have a significant number of warrants, and I would imagine they&#8217;re quite pleased with the progress of the company given that those warrants are becoming quite valuable.&#8221;</p>
<p>But how valuable exactly? Between 2013 and 2020, Space Florida accounted for those 300 warrants at their cost price of just under $1.5 million. In the meantime, Rivian&#8217;s valuation soared from the $10 million that the 2010 Space Florida transaction implied into the billions, and its stock split multiple times. (This means that even a handful of shares acquired in Rivian&#8217;s early days as a private company could have turned into many thousands as the company grew and eventually went public).</p>
<p>All the while, Space Florida assumed that it still owned 3% of Rivian, according to public financial statements <a href="https://www.spaceflorida.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/FS-2019-Audited-Financial-Statements-Space-Florida-Final.pdf">filed as late as October 2020</a>.</p>
<p>The warrants were finally executed in late 2020. The <a href="https://www.spaceflorida.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/FS-2020-Audited-Financial-Statements-Space-FLorida.pdf">latest financial statement</a>, issued by Space Florida in October, now shows the agency holding just 60,000 Rivian shares, worth less than $7 million. That is about 500 times less than a 3% stake would represent and <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/heres-how-much-a-%241000-investment-in-nasdaq-made-10-years-ago-would-be-worth-today-2021-09">less than half</a> of what Space Florida would have earned if it had simply invested in the Nasdaq instead of Rivian a decade ago.</p>
<p>&#8220;Something does feel a little weird here,&#8221; said Scott Orn, COO at <a href="https://kruzeconsulting.com/">Kruze Consulting</a>, an accounting firm that specializes in funded early-stage companies. He notes that an early ownership interest can be diluted as bigger investors come on board, or be reduced by other strategies, such as recapitalizing the company. &#8220;But you&#8217;re going to go from, say, 10% ownership to 1% ownership,&#8221; he says. &#8220;You can&#8217;t wash them out completely.&#8221;</p>
<p>Rivian would not comment on Space Florida&#8217;s warrant agreements or ownership stake, citing shareholder confidentiality. Space Florida did not dispute the figures in its financial statements but declined to comment on the value of its investment &#8220;pending board review of policy for these issues.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ketcham predicted that &#8220;it will still prove to have been a very nice investment for the state.&#8221;</p>
<p>Despite the large and somewhat mysterious discrepancy, Space Florida has no plans to pursue Rivian through the courts. &#8220;Our relationship with Rivian has been and remains excellent,&#8221; Ketcham said. &#8220;They did what they needed to do. And we want them to succeed as much as anything.&#8221;</p>
<p>But the disappearances don&#8217;t end there: Neither organization could tell TechCrunch what happened to the four original prototype Rivian vehicles that nearly rewrote investing history.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/space-florida-shrinking-rivian-stake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247007</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Snap paid $250 million to creators on its TikTok clone this year</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/snap-paid-250-million-to-creators-on-its-tiktok-clone-this-year/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/snap-paid-250-million-to-creators-on-its-tiktok-clone-this-year/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 17:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evan Spiegel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram Reels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snap inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story studio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web app]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2247227</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Snap announced today that it paid over $250 million to more than 12,000 creators this year on Spotlight, its TikTok clone. Unlike Snapchat&#8217;s friend-to-friend, ephemeral messaging, Spotlight allows users to reach a wide audience. Since last year when Spotlight launched, Snap says that creators are posting three times as often now. It&#8217;s no secret that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Snap <a href="https://newsroom.snap.com/spotlight-1-year-anniversary">announced</a> today that it paid over $250 million to more than 12,000 creators this year on Spotlight, its TikTok clone. Unlike Snapchat&#8217;s friend-to-friend, ephemeral messaging, Spotlight allows users to reach a wide audience. Since last year when <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/snapchat-launches-a-tiktok-like-feed-called-spotlight-kick-started-by-paying-creators/">Spotlight launched</a>, Snap says that creators are posting three times as often now.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s no secret that the race for short-form video dominance is underway. As TikTok became one of the fastest apps to reach <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/tiktok-reached-1-billion-monthly-active-users/">1 billion</a> monthly active users, competitors like Snapchat Spotlight, Instagram Reels, and YouTube Shorts rolled out creator funds to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/11/instagram-bonuses-reels-tiktok/">incentivize</a> people to make content specifically for their platform. Instagram Reels <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-reels-repost-tiktoks-best-practices-200536658.html">won&#8217;t promote uploads</a> with a TikTok watermark, while Snapchat reduced its original $1 million-per-day payouts because it was paying for too much &#8220;<a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/snapchat-spotlight-copycat-content-spiegel-1235071625/">copycat content</a>,&#8221; CEO Evan Spiegel said in September. Even platforms like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/linkedin-is-scrapping-its-stories-feature-to-work-on-short-form-video/">LinkedIn</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/spotify-tests-a-tiktok-like-vertical-video-feed-in-its-app/">Spotify</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/netflix-launches-fast-laughs-a-tiktok-like-feed-of-funny-videos/">Netflix</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/08/twitter-is-the-latest-platform-to-test-a-tiktok-copycat-feature/">Reddit</a>, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/08/twitter-is-the-latest-platform-to-test-a-tiktok-copycat-feature/">Twitter</a> are experimenting with TikTok-like feeds.</p>
<p>Now, Snap says that 65% of Spotlight submissions use a Snapchat creative tool like an augmented reality lens &#8212; in particular the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/everyone-you-know-is-a-disney-princess-which-means-ar-is-queen/">Cartoon Style 3D Lens</a>, which went viral this summer, generated 2.8 billion impressions in just its first week on the app.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2247227" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2247312" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2247312" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2247312" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Story-Studio-1.gif?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" /><p id="caption-attachment-2247312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Snapchat Story Studio</p></div></p>
<p>Snap is also catering toward creators with its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/snap-announces-story-studio-a-new-standalone-app-to-edit-stories/">Story Studio</a>, a standalone app released at the Snap Partner Summit in May. Some creators edit their videos with tools like Final Cut Pro or Adobe Premiere on their desktops, then send them to their phones &#8212; but Snap has tried to give users more flexibility. Story Studio lets creators do more intensive editing on their phone, while the Spotlight for web app allows users to upload their content without leaving their computers.</p>
<p>Creators can also profit on Spotlight through in-app <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/snapchat-revamps-creator-payouts-by-offering-chance-to-win-prizes-with-spotlight-challenges/">gifting</a> and Snap&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/snap-to-launch-a-new-creator-marketplace-this-month-initially-focused-on-lens-creators/">creator marketplace</a>, which allows brands to more easily collaborate with AR developers and influencers. Creators receive a share of the revenue from gifts, but they keep 100% of the revenue earned through the creator marketplace.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/snap-paid-250-million-to-creators-on-its-tiktok-clone-this-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2247227</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
