<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 14:32:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Peek raises $80M as its travel experiences software and marketplace business passes $2B in bookings</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/peek-raises-80m-as-its-travel-experiences-software-and-marketplace-business-passes-2b-in-bookings/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/peek-raises-80m-as-its-travel-experiences-software-and-marketplace-business-passes-2b-in-bookings/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 14:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238544</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Travel and tourism are slowly starting to move again in the wake of Covid-19 crashing over the world and sending us to shelter in place. Today a company focused on experiences &#8212; museum visits, skydiving, local cooking classes and more &#8212; is announcing a round of growth funding on the back of seeing its own [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Travel and tourism are slowly starting to move again in the wake of Covid-19 crashing over the world and sending us to shelter in place. Today a company focused on experiences &#8212; museum visits, skydiving, local cooking classes and more &#8212; is announcing a round of growth funding on the back of seeing its own business bounce back. <a href="https://www.peek.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Peek</a>, which provides both a marketplace for consumers to discover and book experiences, a platform for businesses to book team building and other internal events, and tech for tourism companies to digitize, manage and run their own experience businesses online &#8212; &#8220;like a Shopify for experiences,&#8221; CEO and co-founder Ruzwana Bashir said &#8212; has raised $80 million. It plans to use the funds to continue expanding its product, hiring more talent, and taking Peek to more places, after passing some $2 billion in bookings from some 35 million customers, mostly in North America.</p>
<p>The round, a Series C, is notable in part because of who is behind it: the funding is being led by WestCap &#8212; the investment firm founded by another major player in the business of travel, the former CFO of Airbnb, Laurence Tosi. New investor Goldman Sachs Asset Management is also in the round, along with 3L, Cathay Innovation, I2BF Global Ventures, Manta Ray and Apeiron. Other high profile past backers include Jack Dorsey, Eric Schmidt, and Kayak founder Paul English.</p>
<p>San Francisco-based Peek is not disclosing its valuation, but Bashir told us the figure &#8220;has increased substantially because we grew the business a lot and hit profitability this year.&#8221; Peek has now raised over $100 million in the last 10 years.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238544" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;Now that we are starting to invest again, we are going into investment mode,&#8221; she added. Worth pointing out, too, that this round was originally pitched to me as a $60 million investment, and then it grew by $20 million just days ago, which speaks also to the confidence investors currently have in the travel and tourism space.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s a big shift from a year ago, when travel-related companies were regrouping and trying to figure out how to continue weathering what had turned out to be a very long storm. Many of them had gone into the summer of 2020 hopeful that the pandemic (which really kicked off earlier in the year) would have subsided and led to a wave of exuberant movement in the warmer months, only to find any bounce short-lived. One of the more well-capitalized of the travel experience startups &#8212; Berlin&#8217;s GetYourGuide, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/16/getyourguide-picks-up-484m-passes-25m-tickets-sold-through-its-tourism-activity-app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">valued at over $1 billion</a> just 6 months before Covid-19 first started appearing &#8212; found itself raising first a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/getyourguide-closes-133m-convertible-note-as-travel-startups-continue-to-weather-the-covid-19-storm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">big convertible note</a>, and then a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/travel-startup-getyourguide-secures-97m-revolving-credit-facility/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">big credit facility</a>, as it shored up its business as the pandemic wore on.</p>
<p>Peek was also not immune. When Covid-19 hit, &#8220;it was pretty terrifying for us. We were growing great and then, all of the sudden, bookings crashed,&#8221; Bashir, who co-founded the company with Oskar Bruening (pictured, below) said. &#8220;We then did all the hard things.&#8221; That included Peek laying off 30% of its staff to help it get through the slump.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2238586" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/OskarBruening_RuzwanaBashir_Peek.jpeg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="496" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/OskarBruening_RuzwanaBashir_Peek.jpeg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/OskarBruening_RuzwanaBashir_Peek.jpeg?resize=150,110 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/OskarBruening_RuzwanaBashir_Peek.jpeg?resize=300,219 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/OskarBruening_RuzwanaBashir_Peek.jpeg?resize=768,561 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/OskarBruening_RuzwanaBashir_Peek.jpeg?resize=680,496 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/OskarBruening_RuzwanaBashir_Peek.jpeg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" />But Peek also took to the offensive, thinking of how it could work differently with its customers on both sides of the business. With end users, it doubled down on virtual experiences (for example, online cooking classes); and rethinking and expanding who &#8220;customers&#8221; could be by building out experiences booking for corporate and internal events. But the real key sounds like how it rethought that it worked with experience providers, where it helped them get their own emergency loans, and it equipped them with the tools to work within the &#8220;new normal&#8221; by helping them shift to focusing more on local activities for local people rather than tourists; and providing them with more software and functionality to run those businesses.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We are the operating system for those merchants,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>It turned out to be the right move: it meant that as those businesses picked up in activity, so did Peek, which found itself turning profitable in the midst of the pandemic. Software currently accounts for &#8220;the majority&#8221; of Peek&#8217;s business, she said, although that could well change over the next year as consumer travel starts to rebound and that brings more activity to Peek&#8217;s own marketplace.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is a lot of opportunity, $1 trillion in gross merchandise value, and still a lot of businesses haven’t made the leap online,&#8221; he said. Many of the experiences customers were previously using pen, paper, phone calls, and managing through spreadsheets, she said, &#8220;but [now] you can’t connect with customers now before you connect.&#8221;</p>
<p>Activities that Peek covers range from wine tours and watersports to skydiving and art classes, while Peek Pro, as the B2B2C product is called, offers tech to enable online booking, point-of-sale services, and &#8220;hundreds&#8221; of automations covering things like inventory management, dynamic pricing, waivers, and marketing analytics. Peek says that it has &#8216;thousands&#8217; customers, including businesses like the Museum of Ice Cream, Color Factory, Artechouse (the experiential art venues) and Pennekamp State Park.</p>
<p>Some of those businesses, without a doubt, target younger adults and thus were already pretty digitally savvy to begin with, but more generally Bashir believes that Peek&#8217;s success in building B2B2C tech for experiences companies is part of the bigger trend in the world of business software specifically for offline businesses.</p>
<p>&#8220;People underestimate what happened in offline. There was a leap forward in e-commerce,&#8221; she said of the story that&#8217;s often told about the impact Covid-19 had on businesses that were already online. But offline businesses were faced with needing to suddenly make what she calls &#8220;a ten-year leap&#8221; to catch up. Peek is part of the battalion of tech companies have rushed to fill that void for various other use cases, such as building software for restaurants, or building logistics or curbside pickup for brick-and-mortar retailers.</p>
<p>“We have been early adopters and investors in travel technology companies, and have been following Peek.com for years,” said Tosi of WestCap, in a statement. “Ruzwana Bashir is a dynamic leader and Peek.com’s unique approach has allowed them to serve millions of people. This is a transformative solution that will allow a wider audience of travelers and locals to have meaningful experiences, and for activity operators to grow their businesses.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/peek-raises-80m-as-its-travel-experiences-software-and-marketplace-business-passes-2b-in-bookings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238544</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blue Origin sets six-person tourist trip to space for Michael Strahan,  Laura Shepard Churchley and first parent-child duo</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/blue-origin-sets-six-person-tourist-trip-to-space-for-michael-strahan-laura-shepard-churchley-and-first-parent-child-duo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/blue-origin-sets-six-person-tourist-trip-to-space-for-michael-strahan-laura-shepard-churchley-and-first-parent-child-duo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 14:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238567</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Blue Origin has announced its next human spaceflight: A six-person launch set for December 9. This is the first time that Blue Origin is flying a full complement of six passengers on its New Shepard reusable rocket and capsule, and the group going on this trip includes Good Morning America co-host Michael Strahan; rocket namesake [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Blue Origin has announced its next human spaceflight: A six-person launch set for December 9. This is the first time that Blue Origin is flying a full complement of six passengers on its New Shepard reusable rocket and capsule, and the group going on this trip includes Good Morning America co-host Michael Strahan; rocket namesake Alan Shepard&#8217;s daughter Laura Shepard Churchley; Voyager Space CEO Dylan Taylor; Dick Holdings managing member Evan Dick; and mother and child pair Lane Bess and Cameron Bess.</p>
<p>In keeping with Blue Origin&#8217;s penchant for notching historic firsts with its human spaceflight missions, this will be the first time a parent and child make the trip to space together. Lane Bess, the Principal and Fonder of Bess Ventures, will be accompanied by Cameron Bess, a content creator and software developer.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2238570" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ns19-crew-collage.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238570" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2238570" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ns19-crew-collage.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="785" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ns19-crew-collage.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ns19-crew-collage.jpg?resize=150,115 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ns19-crew-collage.jpg?resize=300,230 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ns19-crew-collage.jpg?resize=768,589 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ns19-crew-collage.jpg?resize=680,521 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ns19-crew-collage.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2238570" class="wp-caption-text">Upper L to R: Lane Bess, Cameron Bess, Evan Dick; Lower L to R: Dylan Taylor, Laura Shepard Churchley, Michael Strahan</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238567" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>This will be Blue Origin&#8217;s third human spaceflight ever, and also the third this year. New Shepard previously flew two crews of four people each, first with a manifest that included Blue Origin and Amazon founder Jeff Bezos, and then just in October it<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-launches-4-person-crew-including-william-shatner-to-space/"> sent up William Shatner,</a> along with Blue Origin&#8217;s Audrey Powers, DCVC partner Chris Boshuizen, and Medidata co-founder Glen de Vries, who tragically passed away in an airplane accident just weeks later.</p>
<p>The pace that Blue Origin is hitting with these launches is impressive, especially given the likely price tags for each ticket. With six person flights, the company is likely improving its margins which may lead to slightly more affordable seats for those going up, but it&#8217;s still bound to be an extreme luxury.</p>
<p>Blue Origin&#8217;s New Shepard flies its passengers to the edge of space, staying sub-orbital but providing them with a few minutes of weightlessness and unparalleled views of Earth, before the capsule returns slowed by parachutes to a landing in the West Texas desert.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/blue-origin-sets-six-person-tourist-trip-to-space-for-michael-strahan-laura-shepard-churchley-and-first-parent-child-duo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238567</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitrise grabs $60M to keep companies updated with constantly changing mobile requirements</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/bitrise-mobile-requirements/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/bitrise-mobile-requirements/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 14:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barnabas Birmacher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitrise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiedler Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insight Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Zelman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matt Koran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile device management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Open Ocean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bitrise is meant to support developers who are busy running processes rather than creating new value for customers.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As more of the world shifts to doing everything from their smartphones, the ability to build better iOS and Android apps has to move with it. <a href="https://www.bitrise.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bitrise</a> aims to be the go-to company closing the gap between that mobile demand and a company’s ability to get apps out faster while also balancing all of the moving parts and complexities.</p>
<p>Today, mobile DevOps company Bitrise announced it secured $60 million in Series C funding, led by Insight Partners, with participation from existing investors Partech, Open Ocean, Lobito, Fiedler Capital and Y Combinator.</p>
<p>The remote-first company was co-founded by Barnabas Birmacher, Daniel Balla and Viktor Benei in October 2014. Between then and now, we reported on their <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/07/31/bitrise-raises-3-2m-a-led-by-openocean-to-attack-the-complexity-of-building-apps/">$3.2 million Series A</a> round back in 2017, but it also raised <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20190619005574/en/Bitrise-Raises-20M-Series-B-to-Transform-the-Way-You-Build-and-Operate-Mobile-Apps" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$20 million in Series B funding</a> in 2019. The new raise was planned and executed in a few weeks, bringing Bitrise’s total funding to nearly $100 million, CEO Birmacher told TechCrunch.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238105" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Two years ago, the company, headquartered in Budapest, went through Y Combinator’s Growth Program to scale its company, and has now tripled its headcount and opened offices in London, San Francisco, Boston and Osaka.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tz5W48c6kh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/07/31/bitrise-raises-3-2m-a-led-by-openocean-to-attack-the-complexity-of-building-apps/">Bitrise raises $3.2M A led by OpenOcean to attack the complexity of building apps</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bitrise raises $3.2M A led by OpenOcean to attack the complexity of building apps&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/07/31/bitrise-raises-3-2m-a-led-by-openocean-to-attack-the-complexity-of-building-apps/embed/#?secret=tz5W48c6kh" data-secret="tz5W48c6kh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“Mobile made two or three years of advancement in the last 12 months,” Birmacher said. “This means companies have to use mobile to stay competitive, but how they are developing mobile is getting more complex.”</p>
<p>Developers are busy running processes so they can’t concentrate fully on creating new value for customers, he added.</p>
<p>Bitrise aims to create an end-to-end platform for mobile development that automates core workflows, shortens release cycles and provides better understanding of how new pieces of code will affect live apps before their release, so companies can focus on getting out the next big release to customers.</p>
<p>To date, the company has over 100,000 developers using it from more than 6,000 mobile organizations. It is doubling its revenue year over year and plans to increase its employees to 300 across its engineering, product, sales and growth teams.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In addition to hiring, the new capital will enable Bitrise to expand its product so that developers can more easily operate in the continuous integration and delivery space and have better observability into the full DevOps lifecycle.</p>
<p>As part of the investment, Josh Zelman, vice president at Insight Partners, will join Bitrise’s board, while Matt Koran, also vice president at Insight, will act as a board observer.</p>
<p>“Bitrise has been building towards the current moment in mobile since its launch eight years ago,” Zelman said in a written statement. “Mobile has become a primary means of communication, entertainment and commerce for people around the world, and Bitrise has enabled enterprises to keep up with mobile innovation at an ever-increasing pace. Bitrise was purpose-built for mobile, and the company has become a leader in the mobile DevOps space.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3zri9DgDmf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/28/current-and-upcoming-trends-in-latin-americas-mobile-growth/">Current and upcoming trends in Latin America&#8217;s mobile growth</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Current and upcoming trends in Latin America&#8217;s mobile growth&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/28/current-and-upcoming-trends-in-latin-americas-mobile-growth/embed/#?secret=3zri9DgDmf" data-secret="3zri9DgDmf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/bitrise-mobile-requirements/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238105</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Klarna offers ‘Pay Now’ option in US, Klarna Card coming soon</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/klarna-offers-pay-now-option-in-u-s-klarna-card-coming-soon/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/klarna-offers-pay-now-option-in-u-s-klarna-card-coming-soon/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Sandstrom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspirock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klarna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online retailer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sebastian Siemiatkowski]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238362</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Klarna has doubled its customer base in the United States to over 21 million customers. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">U.S. consumers now have the choice to use Klarna’s “Pay Now” service to pay immediately and in full at any online retailer where Klarna is available.</p>
<p>This adds to the global retail bank, payments and shopping giant’s stateside offerings, where Klarna has doubled its customer base to more than 21 million customers.</p>
<p>In addition to Pay Now, Klarna will be introducing its Klarna Card to U.S. customers, which will enable them to make interest-free payments in four installments using a physical card format, either in stores or online. It works with the Klarna app and also can be added to Apple Pay and Google Pay.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238362" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>U.S. users were already able to use Klarna’s Express button for a seamless checkout, now live at Macy’s and Coach, and its subscription service, a first-of-its-kind tool for paying subscriptions and memberships in four, interest-free payments. Klarna works with over 250,000 retail partners.</p>
<p>Launching these services in the U.S. is a natural extension of what the company has already experienced in its other markets, Sebastian Siemiatkowski, Klarna’s co-founder and CEO, told TechCrunch. For Klarna, Europe’s volume of Pay Now represents 50%, he added.</p>
<p>“We are super excited to launch a card in the U.S.,” he said. “As we have seen in other markets, we want people to use Klarna everywhere. Some will occasionally use Klarna on websites and the app, but when you give them a piece of plastic, they are also highly appreciative and people love it.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Though <a href="https://www.similartech.com/compare/klarna-vs-paypal" target="_blank" rel="noopener">behind in market share</a> versus competitors like PayPal, Klarna’s approach as a way to pay online and its share of checkout is providing some competition. Merchants are telling Klarna that its share of checkout is steadily growing after being in the U.S. market for just two years, Siemiatkowski said.</p>
<p>“It feels like a good opportunity to give them a good challenge,” he added.</p>
<p>This latest offering follows a number of updates the company made recently, including <a href="https://www.klarna.com/us/blog/the-future-of-shopping-is-here/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">releasing its super app</a> earlier this month to provide one app for the entire customer journey from discovery to returns.</p>
<p>And, in October, Klarna <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/klarna-travel-inspirock-acquisition/">acquired Inspirock</a>, an online trip planner using artificial intelligence and local expertise, to add a travel agent component for Klarna’s 90 million users.</p>
<p>While discussing the Inspirock acquisition, David Sandstrom, Klarna CMO, said the super app was an opportunity to bring capabilities seen in other countries, like China, to the Western world and connect a lot of pain points for consumers.</p>
<p>“With the app, we took a look at what more problems beyond payments could we do,” Sandstrom added. “Moving into the space, the online shopping journey is typically spread out to 20 different apps, one each for processes like discovery, payment and return management. The super app is a framework to launch features at mass scale. We can now continuously launch products into the app, and will eventually open it up to third parties.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OjAhrqyWPG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/as-buy-now-pay-later-startups-keep-raising-capital-a-dive-into-klarna-afterpay-and-affirms-earnings/">As buy now, pay later startups keep raising capital, a dive into Klarna, Afterpay and Affirm&#8217;s earnings</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As buy now, pay later startups keep raising capital, a dive into Klarna, Afterpay and Affirm&#8217;s earnings&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/as-buy-now-pay-later-startups-keep-raising-capital-a-dive-into-klarna-afterpay-and-affirms-earnings/embed/#?secret=OjAhrqyWPG" data-secret="OjAhrqyWPG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/klarna-offers-pay-now-option-in-u-s-klarna-card-coming-soon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238362</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New capital gives Mosaic Foods additional runway for plant-based frozen meals</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/new-capital-gives-mosaic-foods-additional-runway-for-plant-based-frozen-meals/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/new-capital-gives-mosaic-foods-additional-runway-for-plant-based-frozen-meals/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 14:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam Slutsky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alleycorp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cooking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gather Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greycroft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matt Davis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mosaic Foods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new jersey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plant-based food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sam McIntire]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238089</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mosaic Foods is removing the "taste" excuse from trying plant-based foods by providing delicious frozen meals that come ready to eat.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.mosaicfoods.com/">Mosaic Foods</a>, a plant-based food company, announced Tuesday $6 million in seed funding as it continues to develop more products.</p>
<p>The New York-based company came onto the food scene in 2019, co-founded by Matt Davis and Sam McIntire, with its line of frozen veggie bowls that includes recipes like peanut tofu bowl and butternut squash and sage pasta.</p>
<p>Prior to Mosaic, Davis, CEO, and McIntire, CRO, worked with each other at Bain Capital Ventures. They realized that to eat better and adopt a plant-based diet, it takes some work, especially to find flavorful dishes that won’t make you miss meat.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238089" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>At the core of Mosaic Foods, the co-founders believe that we should all be eating more plants and less meat. However, the excuse they heard most often was lack of taste as a reason not to go plant-based.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2238093" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238093" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2238093" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Matt-Sam-Co-Founders.jpg" alt="Matt Davis, Sam McIntire, Mosaic Foods" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Matt-Sam-Co-Founders.jpg 5287w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Matt-Sam-Co-Founders.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Matt-Sam-Co-Founders.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Matt-Sam-Co-Founders.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Matt-Sam-Co-Founders.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Matt-Sam-Co-Founders.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Matt-Sam-Co-Founders.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Matt-Sam-Co-Founders.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2238093" class="wp-caption-text">Mosaic Foods co-founders Matt Davis and Sam McIntire. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Mosaic Foods</p></div></p>
<p>“If we take the excuse out of eating more plants and make it delicious, people will look forward to eating more plants, and it will have a huge impact,” McIntire told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>“We want to make eating plant-based as easy as ordering takeout,” Davis added. “We ended up cooking our own favorite recipes, and the first six dishes came out of our own kitchen.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Here’s how Mosaic works: choose a meal plan — eight or 12 meals, with the flexibility to skip or cancel; select from the breakfast, lunch and dinner options; you will receive the fast-frozen items to store in your freezer; and it comes with instructions for no chopping, cooking or cleanup. Meals cost, on average, $4.99 per serving.</p>
<p>Two years after launching, the company has gone from six to 50 products, grown 15 times in revenue, opened a 16,000-square-foot kitchen in New Jersey and expanded shipping to California. It has also expanded its product line to include oat bowls, soups and family meals, while also starting Mosaic+, a curated collection of meals created in partnership with top chefs and food personalities.</p>
<p>Gather Ventures led the seed round and was joined by Greycroft and Alleycorp. The latest investment brings Mosaic’s total funding to about $10 million.</p>
<p>“We knew working with Adam (Slutsky) would be going after a huge opportunity,” Davis said. “By raising capital, we would be able to affect more lives faster.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="luT1F35unk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/17/are-rivals-snacking-on-instacarts-core-grocery-delivery-market/">Are rivals snacking on Instacart&#8217;s core grocery delivery market?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Are rivals snacking on Instacart&#8217;s core grocery delivery market?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/17/are-rivals-snacking-on-instacarts-core-grocery-delivery-market/embed/#?secret=luT1F35unk" data-secret="luT1F35unk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Slutsky, co-founder of Moviefone, former CEO of Mimeo.com and former president of Tough Mudder, founded Gather in 2019 and only invests in plant-based companies.</p>
<p>The sector is a personal one for him — he was diagnosed with heart disease at 42 years old and had to change his diet. Slutsky’s investment strategy is very hands-on, so he invests in about four companies per year.</p>
<p>“I am a big believer in this as the world moved from convenience to now health, environment and other ethical issues,” he said. “If you can do it for a price point, it makes sense, and these guys are it.”</p>
<p>The company now has 30 employees and is covering approximately 50% of the country, mainly on the eastern seaboard (but most recently added California in July). It is also on track to hit 1 million meals sold by the end of the year.</p>
<p>The new funding will be used to build on the team already in place, invest in infrastructure, which involves continuing to own and operate its own kitchens, and launch new products. The co-founders expect to be selling via other channels, in addition to DTC, by this time next year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OHsZrKCT8n"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/bowery-tc1-produce/">Hacking lettuce for taste and profit</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hacking lettuce for taste and profit&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/bowery-tc1-produce/embed/#?secret=OHsZrKCT8n" data-secret="OHsZrKCT8n" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/new-capital-gives-mosaic-foods-additional-runway-for-plant-based-frozen-meals/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238089</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zenity raises $5M to help secure low-code/no-code applications</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/zenity-raises-5m-to-help-secure-low-code-no-code-applications/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/zenity-raises-5m-to-help-secure-low-code-no-code-applications/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 14:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business process automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business process management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CIO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[low-code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotic process automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[successfactors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tel Aviv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vertex Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As more companies adopt low-code/no-code tools to build their line-of-business applications, it&#8217;s maybe no surprise that we are now seeing a new crop of services in this ecosystem that focus on keeping these tools secure. These include Tel Aviv-based Zenity, which is coming out of stealth today and announcing a $5 million seed funding round. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As more companies adopt low-code/no-code tools to build their line-of-business applications, it&#8217;s maybe no surprise that we are now seeing a new crop of services in this ecosystem that focus on keeping these tools secure. These include Tel Aviv-based <a href="https://zenity.io/">Zenity</a>, which is coming out of stealth today and announcing a $5 million seed funding round. The round was led by Vertex Ventures and UpWest. A number of angel investors, including the former CISO of Google, Gerhard Eschelbeck, and the former CIO of SuccessFactors, Tom Fisher, also participated in this round.</p>
<p>Zenity argues that as employees start building their own applications and adopt tools like robotic process automation (RPA), this new class of applications also opens up new avenues for potential breaches and ransomware attacks.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2238410" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Zenity-Logo.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238410" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-2238410" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Zenity-Logo.png?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="75" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Zenity-Logo.png 1147w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Zenity-Logo.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Zenity-Logo.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Zenity-Logo.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Zenity-Logo.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Zenity-Logo.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2238410" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Zenity</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238381" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;Companies are heavily adopting Low-Code/No-Code, without realizing the risks it employs nor their part in the shared responsibility model,&#8221; said Zenity co-founder and CEO Ben Kliger. &#8220;We empower CIOs and CISOs to seamlessly govern their Low-Code/No-Code applications and prevent unintentional data leaks, disturbance to business continuity, compliance risks or malicious breaches.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Zenity platform helps businesses build a catalog of low-code/no-code apps in their organization, mitigate potential issues and set up a governance policy for their organization that can then be automatically enforced. The company argues that the methods of traditional security services don&#8217;t transfer to low-code/no-code applications, yet the need for a tool like this is only growing, especially given that most of the developers that use don&#8217;t have a security background (or maybe any software development background at all).</p>
<p>The company was founded by CEO Kliger and CTO Michael Bargury, who both previously worked on the Azure and cloud security teams at Microsoft.</p>
<p>“The challenge is mitigating the risks and security threats associated with Low-Code/No- Code solutions without disturbing the business,” said Tom Fisher, Zenity advisor and former CIO of Oracle, Qualcomm, CTO of eBay. “Zenity provides the perfect combination of governance and security tools with a pro-business approach that helps business developers build with confidence.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/zenity-raises-5m-to-help-secure-low-code-no-code-applications/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238381</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Streetlogic launches computer vision-based e-bike collision warning system, raises $2.1M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/streetlogic-launches-computer-vision-based-e-bike-collision-warning-system-raises-2-1m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/streetlogic-launches-computer-vision-based-e-bike-collision-warning-system-raises-2-1m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 14:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ADAS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computer Vision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-bike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric bike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streetlogic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238409</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Streetlogic wants to help e-bike riders have a safer experience on the road. The company announced a $2.1 million pre-seed raise, as well as the launch of its flagship product, a surround-view camera that can predict front, side and rear collisions and notify riders in order to prevent accidents. Starting Tuesday, customers in the U.S., [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Streetlogic wants to help e-bike riders have a safer experience on the road. The company announced a $2.1 million pre-seed raise, as well as the launch of its flagship product, a surround-view camera that can predict front, side and rear collisions and notify riders in order to prevent accidents.</p>
<p>Starting Tuesday, customers in the U.S., Canada and Europe can pre-order Streetlogic&#8217;s advanced driver assistance system (ADAS) for e-bikes with a down payment of $30. The final retail price will be around $300 to $400, and the first batch of mass produced systems is expected for delivery by the end of 2022, according to Jonathan Denby, CEO and founder of Streetlogic. Customers based in San Francisco, where Streetlogic is based, will be eligible to try one of the systems sooner via a limited, invite-only beta deployment program beginning early next year.</p>
<p>Streetlogic isn&#8217;t the first to come up with a micromobility ADAS system. Last year, Israeli startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/ride-vision-raises-7m-for-its-ai-based-motorcycle-safety-system/">Ride Vision introduced a similar</a> AI-based system that analyzes traffic around a rider in real time, providing forward collision alerts, blind spot monitoring and warnings for riding too close behind another vehicle. Like Streetlogic, Ride Vision&#8217;s system can also just record the ride, acting as a dashcam that saves a record of safety incidents to review later.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238409" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>More recently, c<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">omputer vision companies like Luna or Drover AI have developed similar tech for e-scooters that&#8217;s operated by the likes of shared micromobility operators Voi and Spin, respectively. The technology here is similar, but the target markets are different.  </span></p>
<p>&#8220;The difference is that we are custom tailoring the vision system to give smart safety features to the riders, whereas they&#8217;re using the vision system to get the riders of scooters to play more nicely on city streets,&#8221; Denby told TechCrunch. &#8220;Their features are sidewalk detection or parking compliance features that the scooter operators need to show that they&#8217;re keeping riders playing nice. Ours is just all about safety of the rider themselves, like if you&#8217;re riding in traffic this gives you an early warning if there&#8217;s a car on a collision path with you so you can keep yourself safe.&#8221;</p>
<p>The other major difference is that Luna and Drover can connect to the scooter&#8217;s OS and take over, causing the rider to slow to a stop if they&#8217;re riding on sidewalks or inappropriately. Streetlogic&#8217;s product is strictly a collision warning system, but that can still be a very useful tool, especially in cities.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vd6PDyf7Lx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/10/advanced-rider-assistance-systems-tech-spawned-by-the-politics-of-micromobility/">Advanced rider assistance systems: Tech spawned by the politics of micromobility</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Advanced rider assistance systems: Tech spawned by the politics of micromobility&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/10/advanced-rider-assistance-systems-tech-spawned-by-the-politics-of-micromobility/embed/#?secret=vd6PDyf7Lx" data-secret="vd6PDyf7Lx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;From a safety aspect, you don&#8217;t have eyes all around you at all times – you can&#8217;t, and when you&#8217;re going to work, it&#8217;s kind of like your retreat time, so you&#8217;re often thinking, or at least for me, I&#8217;m not thinking about safety. I&#8217;m just thinking about getting to work or all the things I have to do that day,&#8221; said Taylor, one of Streetlogic&#8217;s early beta testers who rides her e-bike to work everyday, in a <a href="https://www.streetlogic.ai/">testimonial on the company&#8217;s website</a>.</p>
<p>The number of preventable cyclist deaths in the U.S. <a href="https://injuryfacts.nsc.org/home-and-community/safety-topics/bicycle-deaths/">increased 6% in 2019 from 793 in 2010 to 1,089</a> in 2019, and of those <a href="https://www.iihs.org/topics/fatality-statistics/detail/bicyclists">843 were killed in crashes with motor vehicles</a>. Even as e-bike sales soar, cars are still a threat to the adoption of micromobility in cities, where 78% of fatal cycling accidents happen. Consumers looking to replace their cars with e-bikes may want to ensure they&#8217;re riding something that has similar safety features, like an ADAS system.</p>
<p>&#8220;I have this utopian vision where I think the world would be great if there were more e-bikes on the roads and cities than cars, in general,&#8221; Denby told TechCrunch. &#8220;You need a few cars out there, but the majority can be bikes, so I think making your e-bike a more dependable tool in your daily life as your primary way to get around is the key to making that happen.&#8221;</p>
<p>Streetlogic&#8217;s system, which is mounted to both the front and the rear of the bike, is based on computer vision done entirely on-device. It tracks the behaviors and movements of vehicles surrounding the rider, giving an early warning if the rider is on a potential collision path with a car. The processing and alerts are all done on a completely closed loop onboard system, so it doesn&#8217;t require any connectivity to the cloud and works even if the rider is in an area with no service.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2238461" style="width: 988px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/POV-Alert-I.webp"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238461" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2238461" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/POV-Alert-I.webp" alt="POV of Streetlogic computer vision product that warns e-bike riders of potential car collisions" width="978" height="554" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/POV-Alert-I.webp 978w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/POV-Alert-I.webp?resize=150,85 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/POV-Alert-I.webp?resize=300,170 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/POV-Alert-I.webp?resize=768,435 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/POV-Alert-I.webp?resize=680,385 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/POV-Alert-I.webp?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 978px) 100vw, 978px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2238461" class="wp-caption-text">POV of Streetlogic computer vision product that warns e-bike riders of potential car collisions.</p></div></p>
<p>Riders will hear an audio warning first, which comes from the hardware itself and might say something like &#8220;car back&#8221; if a car is coming up quickly behind the rider, for example. There&#8217;s an accompanying visual alert on the rider&#8217;s smartphone that simply points in the direction of the potential obstacle and only requires a quick glance, but this feature only makes sense if the rider attaches their phone to a handlebar phone mount.</p>
<p>Drover AI and Luna have systems that can already detect objects like pedestrians and lanes, but don&#8217;t actively warn e-scooter riders about potential collisions, although given the state of their tech, it&#8217;s not outside the realm of possibility.</p>
<p>Alex Nesic, CEO of Drover AI, told TechCrunch e-bike warning systems make sense as a &#8220;next level&#8221; feature in the high end market, but &#8220;they&#8217;re not likely to be low cost enough for shared applications, which is what we are currently focusing on.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s still early days for Streetlogic, but Denby says the tech has worked &#8220;surprisingly well&#8221; in alpha testing. The system only tracks cars for the moment because collisions or near-misses with cars are the most prevalent issues for cyclists, says Denby.</p>
<p>&#8220;But the nice thing about vision is then you can add more behavior to it over time,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Like it could track cyclists and pedestrians, potholes and cracks on the road, animals running out into the street. These are all things we can build into it over time. Even starting with just cars, we&#8217;ve covered the vast majority of incidents.&#8221;</p>
<p>Streetlogic will have to collect more data to train its ML models on so that it can build in those detections. That&#8217;s in large part what the funding is for. The pre-seed round, which comes from <span style="font-weight: 400;"> LDV Capital, Trucks Venture Capital and angel investors like Luc Vincent, Lyft&#8217;s former EVP of autonomous driving, will be used to scale the team, according to the company. The startup currently has six full time staffers after hiring two additional team members last week, but is hoping to expand its payroll so that it can both deliver on preorders and have the capacity to add maturity to the system.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve got an awesome team of super hard hitters from Apple and Uber on the hardware side and then Cruise on the software side,&#8221; said Denby.</p>
<p>Denby himself came from Uber where he advised on computer vision systems for the company&#8217;s Jump scooters, which were later purchased by Lime, and he also led the team that built the Rylo 360 degree action camera.</p>
<p>While Streetlogic is launching as a B2C product to get off the ground quickly, the company would like to pursue integrations with bike manufacturers in the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/streetlogic-launches-computer-vision-based-e-bike-collision-warning-system-raises-2-1m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238409</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Column Tax announces $5.1M seed round to launch mobile tax-prep products</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/column-tax-announces-5-1m-seed-round-to-launch-mobile-tax-prep-products/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/column-tax-announces-5-1m-seed-round-to-launch-mobile-tax-prep-products/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anita Ramaswamy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atomic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bain capital ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Credit Karma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric Wu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funding round]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H&R Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[income tax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internal Revenue Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seed round]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wealthfront]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238285</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mobile income tax software Column Tax announced today that it raised $5.1 million in seed funding and is launching its first commercial product, which will provide users with early access to their tax refunds.  Bain Capital Ventures led the seed round alongside South Park Commons, Core Innovation Capital, and Operator Partners. Some prominent angel investors [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mobile income tax software <a href="https://www.columntax.com/">Column Tax</a> announced today that it raised $5.1 million in seed funding and is launching its first commercial product, which will provide users with early access to their tax refunds. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bain Capital Ventures led the seed round alongside South Park Commons, Core Innovation Capital, and Operator Partners. Some prominent angel investors also participated in the round, including Opendoor founder Eric Wu and former Wealthfront CEO Adam Nash.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Column Tax’s “Tax Refund Unlock” becomes available today to 2 million users of cash advance app </span><a href="https://www.joinklover.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Klover</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, who tend to be millennial and Gen Z Americans, Klover CEO Brian Mandelbaum told TechCrunch in an email. Advance access to tax refunds serves as an interest-free loan, r</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">educing the need for users to take out expensive loans or accrue credit card debt, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mandelbaum said.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238285" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The product runs on an API from payroll provider </span><a href="https://atomic.financial/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Atomic</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, allowing users to receive their tax refund earnings in their paychecks.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2238286" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238286" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2238286" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MichaelBock_Co-Founder_GavinNachbar_co-founder_and_CEO-1.jpeg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MichaelBock_Co-Founder_GavinNachbar_co-founder_and_CEO-1.jpeg 6441w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MichaelBock_Co-Founder_GavinNachbar_co-founder_and_CEO-1.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MichaelBock_Co-Founder_GavinNachbar_co-founder_and_CEO-1.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MichaelBock_Co-Founder_GavinNachbar_co-founder_and_CEO-1.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MichaelBock_Co-Founder_GavinNachbar_co-founder_and_CEO-1.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MichaelBock_Co-Founder_GavinNachbar_co-founder_and_CEO-1.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MichaelBock_Co-Founder_GavinNachbar_co-founder_and_CEO-1.jpeg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MichaelBock_Co-Founder_GavinNachbar_co-founder_and_CEO-1.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2238286" class="wp-caption-text">Column Tax co-founders Gavin Nachbar and Michael Bock</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Column Tax’s tax prep product, “Tax Filing,” will also launch in February 2022 in time for the upcoming tax season, the company told TechCrunch. The seed round proceeds will help the company’s 8-person team grow to over 20 employees by the end of next year with the goal of expanding both products, CEO and founder Gavin Nachbar told TechCrunch in an interview.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Column Tax’s software differs from that of incumbents like TurboTax and H&amp;R Block in that it is mobile-only and will be embedded into a customer’s existing bank account, allowing for year-round integration that the company says will cut down users’ time spent on tax prep.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Wealthy Americans have access to CPAs and accountants and tax advice people watching over their finances year-round. We think we can take a lot of that, embed into software and give people access to that year-round,” Nachbar said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nachbar, who previously served as head of operations strategy and infrastructure at Waymo, said that payroll data companies have created “a whole new wave of opportunity” for fintechs looking to build tech solutions around income and payroll.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Before Atomic, it wouldn&#8217;t be possible to understand someone&#8217;s tax position mid-year without them downloading a pay stub and sending it to you via email,” Nachbar said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While Column Tax only supports federal income tax filings today, it plans to eventually add state tax offerings, starting with New York and California, Nachbar added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nachbar sees growth potential for embedded tax solutions that are integrated with other financial platforms, pointing to Cash App’s takeover of Credit Karma Tax as one notable example.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We&#8217;re entering this new era of embedded taxes,” Nachbar said. “The income tax engine is really complex. It&#8217;s a large technical problem. We&#8217;re building a large engineering team to tackle that.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/column-tax-announces-5-1m-seed-round-to-launch-mobile-tax-prep-products/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238285</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data collection isn&#8217;t the problem: It&#8217;s what companies are doing with it</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/data-collection-isnt-the-problem-its-what-companies-are-doing-with-it/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/data-collection-isnt-the-problem-its-what-companies-are-doing-with-it/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 13:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data fabric]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data warehouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decision intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online platforms]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2237802</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Collecting data based on a vague hypothetical scenario indicates a lack of intuitive understanding of what kinds of data are actually important to collect from users.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Maxim Kharchenko</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Max_Kharchenko_">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Maxim Kharchenko is the director of fintech products at <a href="https://www.viber.com/en/">Rakuten Viber</a> and is an expert in product leadership in the financial technology sector.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Data is a company’s most powerful asset. Yet, many businesses cannibalize this valuable asset by selling it to third parties when they should be using it to make their businesses stronger and more sustainable.</p>
<p>Nearly all digital businesses collect some type of data from their users, so there has been growing concern from privacy rights groups about how that data is used. Yet, data collection is not wrong in and of itself. It’s the why, how and what is done with it that matters most when it comes to building a profitable and sustainable business that simultaneously respects the privacy of its users.</p>
<p>In the majority of cases, there is no nefarious man behind the curtain collecting data for evil. Most companies rake in as much data as they can under the assumption that you never know when and how data might be useful at some point down the line.</p>
<p>Thankfully, this is starting to change, and data scientists at data-driven companies are leading the charge. Collecting data based on a vague hypothetical scenario indicates a lack of intuitive understanding of what kinds of data are actually important to have from users, but smart companies are rightly asking only for the data that is needed to provide products and services to the end users.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Invading user privacy by collecting data just to sell it is an unimaginative waste of time and business intelligence.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<h2>Making data work for you through AI and a data fabric</h2>
<p>Instead of selling user data to make money, data-driven companies have opted to analyze this data to understand how to gain the most useful insights. Know Your Customer (KYC) initiatives are dependent on data, using artificial intelligence (AI) to analyze the information to uncover preferences that users might not be talking about in online reviews.</p>
<p>Companies like <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/how-pepsico-scours-restaurant-menus-and-tweets-for-consumer-trends-2020-10">Pepsi are leading the way in using AI</a> for consumer product development purposes, and digital businesses can and should follow suit. Online platforms that want to go this route should beef up their in-house capabilities by hiring more data scientists and AI experts.</p>
<p>In addition to helping improve customer experience by enabling better personalization and customization options, AI can assist in making the onboarding process smoother and seamless for products and services.</p>
<p>As data becomes more complex, companies are trying to make more efficient use of their troves of data by implementing a data fabric — an interconnected layer of data and processes that supports composite data and analytics, as well as their various components.</p>
<p>A data fabric lets companies reuse and combine different styles of data science, enabling them to reduce integration design time by up to 30%, deployment by up to 30% and support by as much as 70%. In addition, a data fabric allows firms to use existing skills and technologies from data hubs, data lakes and data warehouses, as well as introduce new approaches and tools for the future.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/data-collection-isnt-the-problem-its-what-companies-are-doing-with-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2237802</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vercel raises $150M Series D as it looks to build an end-to-end front-end development platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/vercel-raises-150m-series-d-as-it-looks-to-build-an-end-to-end-front-end-development-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/vercel-raises-150m-series-d-as-it-looks-to-build-an-end-to-end-front-end-development-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 13:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bedrock Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geodesic capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ggv capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[glenn solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greenoaks Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HashiCorp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JAMstack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[player]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software engineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vercel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238326</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Only a few months ago, Vercel, the company behind the popular Next.js framework for front-end developers, announced a $102 million Series B funding round that took its valuation to $1.1 billion. Today, it&#8217;s announcing a $150 million Series C round that puts its valuation at $2.5 billion. The round, which brings Vercel&#8217;s total funding to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Only a few months ago, <a href="https://vercel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vercel</a>, the company behind the popular <a href="https://vercel.com/solutions/nextjs" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Next.js</a> framework for front-end developers, announced a $102 million Series B funding round that took its valuation to $1.1 billion. Today, it&#8217;s announcing a $150 million Series C round that puts its valuation at $2.5 billion. The round, which brings Vercel&#8217;s total funding to $131 million, was led by GGV Capital, with participation from existing investors Accel, Bedrock Capital, CRV, Geodesic Capital, Greenoaks Capital, GV, 8VC, Flex Capital, Latacora, Salesforce Ventures and Tiger Global, as well as new investor SV Angel.</p>
<p>Vercel sits at the nexus of a number of industry trends, but maybe most importantly, it is part of the Jamstack movement that prioritizes fast, static sites &#8212; but with just enough dynamic capabilities to enable modern, personalized experiences. It was only last week that Vercel&#8217;s fellow Jamstack player Netlify <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/17/netlify-snags-105m-series-d-to-fuel-jamstack-focused-web-development/">raised $105 million</a>, and I wouldn&#8217;t be surprised if we saw a few more of these rounds in this space in the coming months.</p>
<p>Vercel, which monetizes its open source efforts by offering a hosted serverless platform for running Next.js-based applications, saw a lot of growth in the previous months, with Next.js having grown to 2 million weekly npm installs now and traffic on its edge network growing 700% since April 2020. It now serves more than 24 billion requests on its network.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238326" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;We were already an investor. The company had set very high expectations for itself for this year &#8212; and they were blowing those expectations away from a financial plan standpoint,&#8221; GGV managing partner Glenn Solomon told me. &#8220;We could see what was happening with the Next.js community, with the Vercel business model and how it really snaps together with the Next.js community. The whole world is in love with the concept of product-led growth [&#8230;]. At GGV, we&#8217;ve had the good fortune of being involved with companies like Square, Slack, HashiCorp and others, which are companies where there really was &#8212; at least for a period of time &#8212; an underlying product-led growth dynamic that really helped catapult growth. That is what&#8217;s going on at Vercel in a major way right now.&#8221;</p>
<p>As Vercel co-founder and CEO Guillermo Rauch noted, raising a new funding round now was a &#8220;function of our ambitions.&#8221; &#8220;If we look at Vercel as becoming this end-to-end platform where all software development on the web happens, from idea to production through getting your analytics on what to improve next, to the next idea &#8212; we definitely need [the funding],&#8221; he said. &#8220;I think the alignment with GGV came from our values. We&#8217;re big fans of their motto: &#8216;go long.&#8217; They&#8217;re fans of open source as this new model of creating highly profitable companies. I think the combination was there and then the mechanics were efficient. We&#8217;re all about performance at Vercel, so it was that match made in heaven.&#8221;</p>
<p>Vercel plans to use the new funding to hire across teams, but especially to expand its go-to-market efforts. Rauch also noted that the company is looking at strategic acquisitions as it builds out its end-to-end platform. Rauch specifically noted that Vercel started building more analytics features in 2020, which helped the company to add another dimension to its platform beyond the framework and its hosting service.</p>
<p>The team is also looking at improving the overall development workflow for developers on its platform. With the launch of <a href="https://vercel.com/docs/concepts/deployments/checks" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Checks</a>, it recently started pushing more into this direction, but that&#8217;s only the start, Rauch noted. &#8220;That&#8217;s another logical area of investment for us,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We hear a lot that the framework is great, the hosting is great, but the workflow Vercel provides makes all the difference.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/vercel-raises-150m-series-d-as-it-looks-to-build-an-end-to-end-front-end-development-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238326</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Seaya Ventures, Cathay Innovation launch $125M fund for LatAm startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/seaya-ventures-cathay-innovation-launch-125m-fund-for-latam-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/seaya-ventures-cathay-innovation-launch-125m-fund-for-latam-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 13:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accion Venture Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alt.bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cathay innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colombia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LATAM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managing partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mexico city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seaya ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital Firms]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238054</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Seaya Cathay Latam Fund will invest in between 12 to 15 companies and will write check sizes of between $5 and $10 million.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Venture capital firms <a href="https://seayaventures.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Seaya Ventures</a> and <a href="https://cathayinnovation.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cathay Innovation</a> have created a joint fund aimed at startups across Latin America that are redefining their industries and society.</p>
<p>The two firms &#8212; Seaya is based in Spain, and Cathay in France &#8212; formally came together in April and have since opened an office in Mexico City, where they will manage the $125 million <a href="http://sclatam.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Seaya Cathay Latam Fund</a> that will focus on Series A and B investments, with reserves for follow-on rounds.</p>
<p>Beatriz Gonzalez, founder and managing partner of Seaya Ventures, said the connection between Spain and Latin America remains strong — her firm was started in 2013 and its second investment in Mexico was in Sin Delantal, which was <a href="https://novobrief.com/just-eat-acquires-sin-delantal-mexico/2094/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired by Just Eat</a> a year later.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238054" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“At the time, Spanish companies in industries like banking and utilities were all expanding into Latin America,” she said in an interview. “There were not many funds when we started in 2013, and today, the market is competitive. You can’t just bring funding to the table, you have to have funding, network and support. That combination is powerful because it is needed now by the ecosystem.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Leading the fund locally is Federico Gómez Romero, who previously led LatAm activities for seed fintech fund Accion Venture Lab. It targets consumer and enterprise companies developing technologies in areas like fintech, proptech, mobility, healthtech, food, agriculture and cybersecurity. The fund also incorporates Cathay’s corporate ecosystem as investors and strategic partners.</p>
<p>The team’s first investment was made in September when it went in on Chilean fintech <a href="https://medium.com/cathay-innovation/behind-the-term-sheet-how-xepelin-is-helping-latams-smes-flourish-e2ff7530a81b" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xepelin’s $230 million round.</a> As solo firms, both have been active in the region making other investments in Mexico’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/20/get-used-to-hearing-about-machine-learnings-operations-mlops-startups/">Kueski</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/17/lana-has-launched-in-latin-america-to-be-the-one-stop-shop-for-gig-workers-financial-needs/">Lana</a>, Brazil’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/16/brazilian-social-commerce-marketplace-facily-quietly-raises-366m-in-less-than-a-year-now-valued-at-850m/">Facily</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/alt-bank-brazils-latest-fintech-targeting-the-unbanked-raises-5-5m/">alt.bank</a>, and Colombia’s RobinFood and Chile’s Fracttal.</p>
<p>The Seaya Cathay Latam Fund will invest in 12 to 15 companies and will write check sizes of between $5 million and $10 million, Jacky Abitbol, managing partner of Cathay Innovation, said. Having already worked together on other investments, he said it made sense for his firm and Seaya to come together.</p>
<p>“Our intentions are to be a global player, and we saw opportunities to be part of the local ecosystem,” he said. “We share a lot of values and the same way of thinking, so we decided to partner to support bigger tickets and put to work a platform we built with an initial investment to support founders.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/seaya-ventures-cathay-innovation-launch-125m-fund-for-latam-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238054</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lee Fixel&#8217;s Addition leads $32M investment into TruePay, a Brazilian B2B &#8216;buy now, pay later&#8217; startup</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/lee-fixels-addition-leads-32m-investment-into-truepay-a-brazilian-b2b-buy-now-pay-later-startup/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/lee-fixels-addition-leads-32m-investment-into-truepay-a-brazilian-b2b-buy-now-pay-later-startup/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 13:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Addition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnpl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buy Now]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buy now pay later]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lee Fixel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pay Later]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TruePay]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2237531</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Global investors continue to be drawn to LatAm. TruePay, a one-year-old São Paulo-based &#8220;buy now, pay later&#8221; startup, announced today that it has raised $32 million in a Series A funding round led by Lee Fixel’s Addition. The investment marks Addition’s first time leading a Series A in Latin America. It comes just three months [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Global investors continue to be drawn to LatAm.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="http://truepay.com.br/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TruePay</a>, a one-year-old São Paulo-based &#8220;buy now, pay later&#8221; startup, announced today that it has raised $32 million in a Series A funding round led by Lee Fixel’s Addition.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The investment marks Addition’s first time leading a Series A in Latin America. It comes just three months after  Kaszek and Monashees co-led an $8.5 million seed round that also included participation from ONEVC and Global Founders Capital.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2237531" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TruePay’s mission is to build a B2B &#8220;buy now, pay later&#8221; network where sellers (industries) can grant credit without being exposed to default risk and where buyers (merchants) access credit to buy inventory from their suppliers seamlessly and costlessly.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Founded by former VCs Pedro Oliveira and Luis Eduardo Cascão, TruePay says it has clients in all states of Brazil, with a merchant base that is “in the thousands” after just five months of operations. Growth, its founders say, has fluctuated month-over-month from 100% to 200% in 2021. The company expects to grow between “ten-to fifteen-fold” in 2022.</span><b> </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In December 2020, Oliveira and Cascão left their jobs as venture capitalists at Kaszek and DNA Capital, respectively, to start the fintech company. TruePay differs from other other BNPL offerings, they say, in that it aims to turn retailer’s credit card receivables (also known as merchant cash advances) into purchasing power. By using such receivables as collateral, the company claims it can guarantee the payment to the supplier. By removing default risk barriers, TruePay aims to streamline the commercial relationship between merchants and their suppliers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By using TruePay, CEO Oliveira said, retailers have access to better payment terms with their suppliers, which allows them to make larger purchases with more time to pay and ultimately freeing up working capital for their operation.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Suppliers are no longer exposed to merchants’ default risk and hence are able to grant more credit and thus, increase sales,” he told TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The money will largely go toward further hiring. Presently, the company has 50 employees and has the goal of expanding to 100 by year’s end.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The strength of TruePay’s solution lies in the convergence of a real and untapped need amongst retailers to unlock credit and free up working capital, a large addressable market and a talented team,” said Fixel in a statement. “We look forward to supporting the company as it continues to develop its innovative, convenient and low-cost payment technology.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As we’re reported in the past, many startups in Latin America are building technology not just for the sake of innovation but to boost financial inclusion in the region.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Retailers in Brazil are the victims of a scenario where average receiving terms are long, while average paying terms are short &#8212; creating a gigantic working capital gap, according to Cascão.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> “These companies bear the country&#8217;s economy on their shoulders, but don’t have any source of capital at a minimally fair cost to address this gap,” he said. “Therefore, they end up resorting to other solutions such as factoring receivables at high rates with payment processing companies and seeking credit at abusive interest rates from banks. The suppliers of these retailers, in turn, often end up having to choose between not selling or extending them credit, running the risk of default, which they are usually unequipped to do &#8212; resulting in a negative credit cycle. TruePay was created precisely to break this negative spiral and transform the relationship into a flywheel.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="M78yk3Mx1E"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/why-global-investors-are-flocking-to-back-latin-american-startups/">Why global investors are flocking to back Latin American startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why global investors are flocking to back Latin American startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/why-global-investors-are-flocking-to-back-latin-american-startups/embed/#?secret=M78yk3Mx1E" data-secret="M78yk3Mx1E" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/lee-fixels-addition-leads-32m-investment-into-truepay-a-brazilian-b2b-buy-now-pay-later-startup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2237531</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turkey&#8217;s instant grocery giant Getir grabs UK&#8217;s Weezy in latest delivery consolidation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/getir-weezy-acquisition/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/getir-weezy-acquisition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 12:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brighton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bristol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DN Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goPuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gorillas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grocery store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Groupon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heartcore Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[instant grocery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kristof Van Beveren]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Liverpool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manchester]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mubadala Investment Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netherlands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[on-demand grocery apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online grocery shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portugal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Turkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weezy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238538</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well that was quick. UK-based hyper fast grocery delivery startup Weezy &#8212; which only raised a pre-seed for its 15min delivery services of supermarket fare last year, after founding the biz in 2019 &#8212; has been bagged by Turkish 10min-delivery-app Getir. It&#8217;s the latest slice of consolidation to hit Europe&#8217;s hyper competitive on-demand &#8216;quick commerce&#8217; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Well that was quick. UK-based hyper fast grocery delivery startup Weezy &#8212; which only <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/london-based-weezy-raises-seed/">raised a pre-seed </a>for its 15min delivery services of supermarket fare last year, after founding the biz in 2019 &#8212; has been bagged by Turkish 10min-delivery-app Getir.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the latest slice of consolidation to hit Europe&#8217;s hyper competitive on-demand &#8216;quick commerce&#8217; convenience shopping apps.</p>
<p>The value of the deal is not being announced but Weezy has raised over $25M per <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/weezy">Crunchbase</a>, including a $20M Series A this <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/uk-on-demand-supermarket-weezy-raises-20m-series-a-led-by-nycs-left-lane-capital/">January</a> &#8212; which was led by New York&#8217;s Left Lane Capital. Other investors include DN Capital, Heartcore Capital and angels, such as Chris Muhr, the Groupon founder, plus some former execs from the supermarket and on-demand food delivery sectors.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238538" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Getir, meanwhile, has been dialling up its attention on the UK market following its launch (in London), this January &#8212; <a href="https://getir.uk/press-releases/getir-covers-3-4-million-miles-one-bikes-and-e-mopeds/">announcing</a> last month that it planned to invest around £100M (~$134M) in the country to establish a nationwide network of local stores (which it claimed would create &#8220;up to 10,000 new and permanent jobs&#8221;).</p>
<p>Presumably its acquisition of Weezy accounts for a chunk of that planned splurge &#8212; as it&#8217;ll be picking up the latter&#8217;s dark stores, which includes micro fulfilment centers in London, Manchester, Brighton and Bristol.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9M6FMukUmb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/uk-on-demand-supermarket-weezy-raises-20m-series-a-led-by-nycs-left-lane-capital/">UK on-demand supermarket Weezy raises $20M Series A led by NYC&#8217;s Left Lane Capital</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;UK on-demand supermarket Weezy raises $20M Series A led by NYC&#8217;s Left Lane Capital&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/uk-on-demand-supermarket-weezy-raises-20m-series-a-led-by-nycs-left-lane-capital/embed/#?secret=9M6FMukUmb" data-secret="9M6FMukUmb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Back in January Weezy said it planned to open an additional 40 sites across the UK by the end of this year &#8212; in addition to two in London. While Getir&#8217;s own UK footprint <a href="https://getir.uk/press-releases/getir-covers-3-4-million-miles-one-bikes-and-e-mopeds/">prior to the acquisition</a> stood at between 9 and 15 cities and towns &#8212; including Manchester, Birmingham and Liverpool.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Turkish on-demand giant isn&#8217;t short of funds to shop for rivals. This summer it topped up its war-chest by raising a further $555M in Series D funds from investors including Tiger Global, Sequoia Capital and Mubadala Investment Company &#8212; and has pulled in close to a billion in funding this year (and tripled its valuation to $7.5BN), per <a href="https://www.retail-insight-network.com/comment/getir-grocery-delivery-expansion/">reports</a>.</p>
<p>Today, Getir said its business &#8212; which was founded back in 2015, so long before the pandemic arrived to supercharge online grocery shopping &#8212; is now worth $7.7BN.</p>
<p>Commenting on the acquisition in a statement, Turancan Salur, Getir UK general manager said: &#8220;Teaming up with Weezy, which has quickly established itself across the UK, is an exciting opportunity and one that complements our people-first belief and business approach. We look forward to welcoming Weezy’s customers, employees and partners to the enlarged group.”</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">In another supporting statement, Weezy CEO and co-founder, Kristof Van Beveren, added: “We are incredibly excited to continue our journey in disrupting the skyrocketing ultrafast grocery market. Getir has an unparalleled track-record of achievements and experience with an equally ambitious team. Our alignment in purpose and culture is a winning formula for expansion globally and we will continue to deliver an exceptional offering to consumers in minutes.<strong>”</strong></p>
<p>Germany rival Gorillas also grabbed almost $1BN in funding <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/19/gorillas-grabs-close-to-1bn-series-c-values-the-on-demand-grocery-delivery-biz-at-2-1bn/">last month</a>, announcing a Series C close. So startups which have raised relative peanuts raised are obvious targets for rapacious, better resourced and established rivals &#8212; whose goal is to beat the competition by scaling faster to win the market for instant groceries.</p>
<p>Weezy is not Getir&#8217;s first acquisition &#8212;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/instant-grocery-startup-getir-makes-its-first-acquisition-to-expand-into-spain-and-italy/"> this summer</a> it picked up a small player in Southern Europe to expand into Spain and Italy. It has also recently (this month) kicked off a service in the US where it&#8217;s squaring up to major US rivals.</p>
<p>One of which, GoPuff, has also been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/09/after-acquiring-dija-and-fancy-instant-grocery-startup-gopuff-launches-in-the-uk-en-route-to-european-expansion/">on a European acquisition spree lately</a> &#8212; starting with the UK market, where it&#8217;s been trying to muscle in on Getir&#8217;s territory, giving the latter added incentive to bulk up its own UK presence.</p>
<p>In all, Getir is now operating in nine countries (Turkey, the UK, the Netherlands, Germany, France, Spain, Italy, Portugal and the US) &#8212; offering app-based services including super speedy urban delivery of groceries from dark stores where it stocks some 2,000 &#8220;everyday items&#8221; that can be delivered day or night.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dzRvTfPOP5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/09/after-acquiring-dija-and-fancy-instant-grocery-startup-gopuff-launches-in-the-uk-en-route-to-european-expansion/">After acquiring Dija and Fancy, instant grocery startup Gopuff launches in the UK en route to European expansion</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;After acquiring Dija and Fancy, instant grocery startup Gopuff launches in the UK en route to European expansion&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/09/after-acquiring-dija-and-fancy-instant-grocery-startup-gopuff-launches-in-the-uk-en-route-to-european-expansion/embed/#?secret=dzRvTfPOP5" data-secret="dzRvTfPOP5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="COzrwukwhq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/19/gorillas-grabs-close-to-1bn-series-c-values-the-on-demand-grocery-delivery-biz-at-2-1bn/">Gorillas grabs &#8216;close to&#8217; $1BN, Series C values the on-demand grocery delivery biz at $2.1BN</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gorillas grabs &#8216;close to&#8217; $1BN, Series C values the on-demand grocery delivery biz at $2.1BN&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/19/gorillas-grabs-close-to-1bn-series-c-values-the-on-demand-grocery-delivery-biz-at-2-1bn/embed/#?secret=COzrwukwhq" data-secret="COzrwukwhq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/getir-weezy-acquisition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238538</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Polestar is bringing its electric Precept sedan to market in 2024 with a new name</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/polestar-is-bringing-its-precept-sedan-to-market-in-2024-with-a-new-name/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/polestar-is-bringing-its-precept-sedan-to-market-in-2024-with-a-new-name/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 12:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Polestar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238455</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Polestar Precept sedan — the concept vehicle turned production project — has a new name and an official launch date. The company, the electric performance brand that spun out from Volvo Car Group, has dubbed the shark-nosed sedan Polestar 5 and announced it will go into production in 2024. When Polestar first revealed the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Polestar Precept sedan — the concept vehicle turned production project — has a new name and an official launch date. The company, the electric performance brand that spun out from Volvo Car Group, has dubbed the shark-nosed sedan Polestar 5 and announced it will go into production in 2024.</p>
<p>When Polestar first revealed the Precept in early 2020 it was viewed as a mere concept car, albeit a striking one meant to signal where this new company was headed. By September that same year, Polestar announced the Precept would be headed to production. At the time, Polestar didn&#8217;t indicate when that might happen beyond a vague sometime &#8220;before 2025.&#8221;</p>
<p>Since then, Polestar has been trickling out teasers and a few details of its Precept sedan, including a couple of YouTube videos meant to give an inside look at the entire design, development and presumably the production process. Polestar&#8217;s <a href="https://youtu.be/GmVsIdWZknA">newest video</a> focuses on what inspired the exterior design.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238455" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The video spends the bulk of its near 4-minute time with Nahum Escobedo, the exterior design manager of the Precept. So what inspired the sharp exterior lines? Sharks and airplanes — at least partially, Escobedo said.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2238469" style="width: 1826px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/polestar-5-aerial.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238469" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2238469 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/polestar-5-aerial.jpg" alt="polestar 5 precept" width="1816" height="1008" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/polestar-5-aerial.jpg 1816w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/polestar-5-aerial.jpg?resize=150,83 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/polestar-5-aerial.jpg?resize=300,167 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/polestar-5-aerial.jpg?resize=768,426 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/polestar-5-aerial.jpg?resize=680,377 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/polestar-5-aerial.jpg?resize=1536,853 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/polestar-5-aerial.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1816px) 100vw, 1816px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2238469" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Polestar/screenshot</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;For this project we also wanted something that was very elegant, but also something that has a certain speed,&#8221; he says in the video. &#8220;So for me, the shark had this certain feeling.&#8221;</p>
<p>The dramatic rear end of the Polestar 5 shows the long aero blade light, another early design feature that appears to be sticking around for the production version.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2238470" style="width: 1818px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ppolestar-5-rear.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238470" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2238470 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ppolestar-5-rear.jpg" alt="polestar 5 precept" width="1808" height="1014" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ppolestar-5-rear.jpg 1808w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ppolestar-5-rear.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ppolestar-5-rear.jpg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ppolestar-5-rear.jpg?resize=768,431 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ppolestar-5-rear.jpg?resize=680,381 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ppolestar-5-rear.jpg?resize=1536,861 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ppolestar-5-rear.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1808px) 100vw, 1808px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2238470" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Polestar/screenshot</p></div></p>
<p>Polestar did not share any specs like battery range or the powertrain in this new video. We do know it will follow the Polestar 3, an all-electric SUV, is expected to go into production in 2022.</p>
<p>Polestar&#8217;s first production vehicle was the plug-inn hybrid grand tourer Polestar 1. The all-electric Polestar 2 sedan followed in 2020. No word yet on what Polestar 4 is — assuming the company will continue with the numeric nomenclature.</p>
<p>The latest insight into Polestar 5, the electric vehicle formally known as the Precept, follows two major expansion and financial moves by the company earlier this year. Polestar announced in late September it reached an agreement to go public via a merger with special purpose acquisition with Gores Guggenheim Inc. in a deal that is expected to value the combined company $20 billion. Once the merger closes, the combined company will be held by a new public company named Polestar Automotive Holding UK Limited. The company is expected to be listed on Nasdaq under the ticker symbol &#8220;PSNY.&#8221;</p>
<p>In June, the company announced it will <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/polestar-to-build-its-first-all-electric-suv-in-the-united-states/">manufacture the Polestar 3</a> in the United States. The Polestar 3 will be assembled at a plant shared with Volvo Cars at a factory in Ridgeville, South Carolina. Production of Polestar 3 is expected to begin globally in 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/polestar-is-bringing-its-precept-sedan-to-market-in-2024-with-a-new-name/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238455</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Italy fines Amazon and Apple $230M over alleged reseller collusion</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/italy-amazon-apple-reseller-collusion/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/italy-amazon-apple-reseller-collusion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 10:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antitrust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[competition law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238493</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon and Apple have been hit with almost $230 million (€203M) in total fines by Italy&#8217;s antitrust authority &#8212; following an investigation into reselling of Apple and (Apple-owned) Beats kit on Amazon&#8217;s Italian ecommerce marketplace. The authority says the alleged collusion decreased the level of discounts available to consumers buying Apple and Beats products on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Amazon and Apple have been hit with almost $230 million (€203M) in total fines by Italy&#8217;s antitrust authority &#8212; following an investigation into reselling of Apple and (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/05/28/apple-buys-beats-electronics-for-3b/">Apple-owned</a>) Beats kit on Amazon&#8217;s Italian ecommerce marketplace.</p>
<p>The authority says the alleged collusion decreased the level of discounts available to consumers buying Apple and Beats products on the Amazon Italy marketplace.</p>
<p>It has also ordered the tech giants to end the restrictions on resellers.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238493" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The <a href="https://www.agcm.it/media/comunicati-stampa/2021/11/I842-">AGCM</a> announced the sanction today, saying its probe identified a restrictive agreement between the pair to block some &#8220;legitimate&#8221; resellers of Beats products on Amazon.it.</p>
<p>The fine breaks down into €134.5M (~$151M) for Amazon &#8212; and €68.7M (~$77.3M) for Apple.</p>
<p>The agreement in question was signed between the pair back in October 2018.</p>
<p>Per the AGCM&#8217;s press release, it found the agreement contained a number of contractual clauses which prohibited official and unofficial resellers of Apple and Beats products from using Amazon.it &#8212; with the restriction limiting the sale of Apple and Beats products on Amazon.it to Amazon itself and a number of resellers the authority says were &#8220;chosen individually and in a discriminatory way&#8221; &#8212; in violation of Art. 101 of the Treaty on the Functioning of the European Union.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;[T]he investigation established the intention to introduce a purely quantitative restriction on the number of retailers, allowing only Amazon and certain subjects, identified in a discriminatory way, to operate on Amazon.it,&#8221; it writes in the release [which we&#8217;ve translated from Italian with Google Translate].</p>
<p>&#8220;The terms of the agreement also restricted cross-border sales, as retailers were discriminated against on a geographic basis. The restrictions of the agreement have affected the level of discounts offered by third parties on Amazon.it, decreasing their size.&#8221;</p>
<p>The authority notes that Amazon&#8217;s local marketplace accounts for at least 70% of purchases of consumer electronic kit in the country, of which &#8220;at least 40% are represented by retailers who use Amazon as a brokerage platform&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;It therefore appears essential that the application of competition rules ensure a <em>level playing field</em> for all retailers who use <em>marketplaces</em> as an increasingly important place for carrying out their commercial activity, especially in today&#8217;s context, avoiding the implementation of discriminatory behaviors that restrict competition,&#8221; it adds.</p>
<p>&#8220;In this perspective, the Authority&#8217;s decision recognizes, in line with the jurisprudence of the EU Court of Justice, the need for distribution systems, in order to be compatible with competition rules, to be based on qualitative criteria, not discriminatory and applied equally to all potential resellers.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Italian authority further notes that, following its investigation into the Amazon-Apple agreement, national competition authorities in Germany and Spain subsequently initiated similar proceedings.</p>
<p>Spain&#8217;s <em>Comisión National de los Mercados y la Competencia</em> <a href="https://www.cnmc.es/sites/default/files/3723177_376.pdf">announced</a> a possible disciplinary proceeding against Amazon and Apple this summer &#8212; opening its own investigation (which it said would take up to 18 months to complete).</p>
<p>While, back in 2018, Germany&#8217;s <em>Bundeskartellamt </em>initiated an <a href="https://www.bundeskartellamt.de/SharedDocs/Meldung/EN/Pressemitteilungen/2018/29_11_2018_Verfahrenseinleitung_Amazon.html?nn=3591568">abuse proceeding against Amazon</a> following complaints by sellers on its marketplace &#8212; closing the proceeding the <a href="https://www.bundeskartellamt.de/SharedDocs/Meldung/EN/AktuelleMeldungen/2019/17_07_2019_Case_Summary_Amazon.html">following year</a> after Amazon amended its general terms of business for sellers and pledged additional changes to alleviate competition concerns.</p>
<p>More recently, following a major update to German competition law regarding digital platforms, the <em>Bundeskartellamt</em> now has open proceedings examining the market power of both <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/apples-app-store-to-face-scrutiny-in-germany-as-fco-opens-market-power-proceeding/">tech</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/amazons-market-power-to-be-tested-in-germany-in-push-for-early-action-over-antitrust-risks/">giants</a> &#8212; and if it confirms their “paramount significance for competition across markets”, as the law puts it, the Federal Cartel Office will be able to apply ex ante measures to proactively impose conditions on how Amazon and Apple can operate in Germany to control the risk of market abuse.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="a51CjcRCM1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/amazons-market-power-to-be-tested-in-germany-in-push-for-early-action-over-antitrust-risks/">Amazon&#8217;s market power to be tested in Germany in push for &#8216;early action&#8217; over antitrust risks</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon&#8217;s market power to be tested in Germany in push for &#8216;early action&#8217; over antitrust risks&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/amazons-market-power-to-be-tested-in-germany-in-push-for-early-action-over-antitrust-risks/embed/#?secret=a51CjcRCM1" data-secret="a51CjcRCM1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The two tech giants were contacted for comment on the AGCM decision.</p>
<p>Amazon confirmed it will be appealing, sending the following statement, attributed to a spokesperson:</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“We strongly disagree with the decision of the Italian Competition Authority (ICA) and we intend to appeal. The proposed fine is disproportionate and unjustified.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We reject the ICA’s suggestion that Amazon benefits by excluding sellers from our store, since our business model relies on their success. As a result of the agreement, Italian customers can find the latest Apple and Beats products on our store, benefiting from a catalogue that more than doubled, with better deals and faster shipping.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Amazon also sought to claim the agreement it inked with Apple was good for consumers &#8212; leading to an increase in the volume of Apple products available for them to buy on its marketplace and highlights individual instances where discounts had been applied to some Apple products.</p>
<p>Amazon also sought to deny any kind of market dominance, saying its marketplace represents less than 1% of the global retail market and that there are larger retailers in every country in which it operates, including Italy &#8212; arguing that businesses have multiple channels to sell Apple products, both on and offline.</p>
<p>It added that third-party sellers account for circa 60% of sales on its marketplace, including around 18,000 Italian SMEs it said sell on Amazon.</p>
<p>Apple also sent a statement confirming it will appeal, writing:</p>
<blockquote>
<div>&#8220;We work hard to create the best products in the world with a great user experience. For the safety of our customers and the integrity of the products they buy, it&#8217;s important they know they’re purchasing genuine products. Non-genuine products deliver an inferior experience and can often be dangerous. To ensure our customers purchase genuine products, we work closely with our reseller partners and have dedicated teams of experts around the world who work with law enforcement, customs and merchants to ensure only genuine Apple products are being sold. We respect the Italian Competition Authority but believe we have done nothing wrong and plan to appeal.”</div>
</blockquote>
<div><em>This report was updated with Apple&#8217;s response</em></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8lCyxrFrew"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/07/big-tech-blows-a-collective-raspberry-at-the-houses-antitrust-report/">Big tech blows a collective raspberry at the House&#8217;s antitrust report</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Big tech blows a collective raspberry at the House&#8217;s antitrust report&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/07/big-tech-blows-a-collective-raspberry-at-the-houses-antitrust-report/embed/#?secret=8lCyxrFrew" data-secret="8lCyxrFrew" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fGbzUssbba"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/apples-app-store-to-face-scrutiny-in-germany-as-fco-opens-market-power-proceeding/">Apple&#8217;s App Store to face scrutiny in Germany as FCO opens &#8216;market power&#8217; proceeding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple&#8217;s App Store to face scrutiny in Germany as FCO opens &#8216;market power&#8217; proceeding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/apples-app-store-to-face-scrutiny-in-germany-as-fco-opens-market-power-proceeding/embed/#?secret=fGbzUssbba" data-secret="fGbzUssbba" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/italy-amazon-apple-reseller-collusion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238493</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Africa&#8217;s Mobiz nabs $4M to expand personalized SMS marketing into the US</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/south-africas-mobiz-nabs-4m-to-expand-personalized-sms-marketing-into-the-us/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/south-africas-mobiz-nabs-4m-to-expand-personalized-sms-marketing-into-the-us/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 10:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Engagement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[text messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238416</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mobiz, a South African startup integrating hyper-personalization into mobile marketing, has raised a pre-Series A round of $ 4 million from HAVAÍC, Futuregrowth, Launch Africa, Allan Gray E-Squared Ventures, CapaciTech and Endeavor&#8217;s Harvest Fund. The investment comes as the startup is ramping up efforts to expand into the U.S. and double down on marketing, sales and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://mobiz.co/">Mobiz</a>, a South African startup integrating hyper-personalization into mobile marketing, has raised a pre-Series A round of $ 4 million from HAVAÍC, Futuregrowth, Launch Africa, Allan Gray E-Squared Ventures, CapaciTech and Endeavor&#8217;s</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Harvest Fund.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The investment comes as the startup is ramping up efforts to expand into the U.S. and double down on marketing, sales and account management</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Part of the investment will </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be used</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to hire more staff in South Africa and support the commercial expansion to the U.S</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mobiz works as a code-free tool that helps marketers, enterprises and SMBs create and send SMS campaigns to their customers without any marketing experience. CEO <a href="https://za.linkedin.com/in/gregtlchen">Greg Chen</a> founded the company in 2014 came from his 15-year span in the mobile industry, noticing how enterprises in South Africa struggled to target and engage their customers via SMS efficiently</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238416" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;In South Africa and Africa general, there are a lot of companies using SMS marketing, but it&#8217;s not giving any value to them because they lack digital marketing skills,&#8221; he said to TechCrunch over a call. &#8220;So we came to enable businesses to deliver personalized digital content via a personal landing page that can </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be built</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">easily</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> within the Mobiz platform and deliver on the SMS channel.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Seven years in, the company works with more than 100 brands, such as MultiChoice, Experian, HomeChoice and New Balance</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Per data from Mobiz&#8217;s website, SMS messages delivered by the company </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are read</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> within three minutes with a 98% open rate</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company said that these messages range from offers and specials and loyalty programs to crisis communication and ticket sales.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having gained a significant market share in the South African SMS marketing space, Mobiz is turning its sights on providing its service to small and medium businesses. However, the target market is in the U.S. and not the African country where the company started</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. According to Chen, the company sees potential in the U.S.&#8217; small and medium business market because &#8220;its product is easy to use and suited for the big market opportunity in the U.S.&#8221; </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;How we&#8217;ve disrupted our space in South Africa, we see an opportunity over there. So we want to help many SMBs </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">easily</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> produce beautiful customer engagements that </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are personalized</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> at scale to make them clickable within 10 minutes on their platforms. That&#8217;s our thesis and we are very hopeful that we will work out.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The SMB market in the U.S. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is projected</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to reach $12.5 billion and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is expected</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to register a CAGR of 20.3% from 2019 to 2025, according to a <a href="https://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry/technology">report by Grandview Research</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chen says that part of this growth </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is buoyed by</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the ineffectiveness of email marketing in the U.S (similar to SMS marketing in Africa) where customers </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are inundated</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and spammed. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SMS marketing in the U.S., on the other hand, has more value because customers need to give marketers and businesses consent to receive regular SMS messages from them</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For these businesses, it means that customers who provide them with access actually want to engage</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;This has revolutionized the way marketers used to think about things when they used to say more is better. Now it&#8217;s talking to the people who actually want to buy from you and spending more money in acquiring them in a consent way and then engage with a very high return investment in the most direct channel and is no more direct channel than SMS,&#8221; said the CEO.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With Mobiz, small and medium businesses such as a coffee shop can </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">quickly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> know the particular type of coffee 100+ customers like because of the information gathered from templates used on the platform. This dynamic and instant customization improves conversions, results, sales, and engagement rates for these businesses. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This month, the company is going live with more than 200-plus beta users in the U.S. currently active on the platform</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As an early backer of the company, partner at HAVAÍC Grant Rock said his firm has been most impressed with Mobiz&#8217;s execution in South Africa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. But with the company going across borders, it will need to consider pricing as it faces competition with incumbents such as </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Textedly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and TextMagic. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Its subscription fees start at $29 per month and increases depending on the number of SMS businesses and marketers want to send</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chen adds that now that the company is going full tilt in the U.S. market, plans are set to raise a </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">subsequent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Series A round in the coming months</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/south-africas-mobiz-nabs-4m-to-expand-personalized-sms-marketing-into-the-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238416</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NoBroker becomes India&#8217;s first proptech unicorn with fresh $210 million funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/nobroker-becomes-first-indian-proptech-unicorn-with-fresh-210-million-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/nobroker-becomes-first-indian-proptech-unicorn-with-fresh-210-million-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 09:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[general atlantic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MyGate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nobroker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238496</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An Indian startup that is improving the way how millions of people in the nation lease or buy an apartment is the latest firm to become a unicorn in the South Asian market. Bangalore-based NoBroker has raised $210 million in its Series E financing round, its founders told TechCrunch in an interview. Tiger Global and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">An Indian startup that is improving the way how millions of people in the nation lease or buy an apartment is the latest firm to become a unicorn in the South Asian market.</p>
<p>Bangalore-based <a href="https://www.nobroker.in/">NoBroker</a> has raised $210 million in its Series E financing round, its founders told TechCrunch in an interview. Tiger Global and General Atlantic, two existing investors, and Moore Strategic Ventures co-led the eight-year-old startup’s Series E financing round.</p>
<p>The round values NoBroker, which has raised $361 million to date and counts Elevation Capital and Paytm founder Vijay Shekhar Sharma among its investors, at $1 billion, up from about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/indias-nobroker-raises-an-additional-30m-from-general-atlantic/">$350 million in April 2020</a>. There was no secondary transaction &#8212; that is, sales of shares by any existing investors including the founders &#8212; in the new funding round, the founders said.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238496" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>NoBroker helps people looking to buy or lease an apartment avoid brokers, thus avoiding brokerage fee. The startup operates in several major Indian cities including Bangalore, Delhi, Pune, and Hyderabad. The startup has over 7.5 million properties listed on its platform and over 16 million people have used its services.</p>
<p>Over the years, NoBroker has expanded to several additional categories including financial services (to offer customers help with securing the rent, for instance), and home services such as cleaning, fulfilling furniture needs and movers and packers. These services are also independently available to customers who have not rented or bought a place from NoBroker platform.</p>
<p>NoBroker now also operates a service, called NoBrokerhood, that is aimed at communities to stay connected and manage and keep track of visitors. NoBrokerhood, which also allows society residents to buy and sell items from each other, competes with some of the offerings of MyGate, which is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/16/mygate-security-gated-premises-india/">also backed by Tiger Global</a>.</p>
<p>The new funding follows months of strong growth as Indian states relaxed lockdown restrictions earlier this year and mobility resumed. The startup has grown three times since last year, said Amit Kumar Agarwal, founder and chief executive of NoBroker, in an interview.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“NoBroker’s digital-first approach to efficiently solve renting, buying, maintenance and related needs for real-estate owners, tenants, buyers, residential societies and developers is paradigm shifting, said Shantanu Rastogi, Managing Director of General Atlantic, in a statement.</p>
<p>&#8220;Focused execution with a customer-first mindset of the founders bodes well for NoBroker’s continued penetration in this market solving for the toughest problems. In the future, NoBroker’s product stack will also find relevance in several under-regulated developing markets around the world. We are excited to be part of NoBroker’s continued success.”</p>
<p>Agarwal and startup&#8217;s other founders &#8212; Akhil Gupta and Saurabh Garg &#8212; said in a joint interview that NoBroker will deploy the fresh funds to expand to 50 cities in a span of two to three years, up from six currently.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are seeing an upward trend in the property buying segment and this funding will help us deepen our investments in resale and primary sale verticals,&#8221; said Garg.</p>
<p>India has produced over three dozen unicorns this year &#8212; more than all other years put together &#8212; after several high-profile global investors including Tiger Global, SoftBank, and Falcon Edge Capital began to double down on the world&#8217;s second largest internet market earlier this year at the height of the ravaging pandemic.</p>
<p>In a letter to shareholders earlier this year, Tiger Global identified India as one of the few markets where it was planning to deploy billions of dollars. SoftBank Group chief executive Rajeev Misra said earlier this month that the Japanese firm has invested over $3 billion in India this year and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/11/softbank-has-deployed-3-billion-in-india-this-year-can-invest-up-to-10-billion-in-2022/">can invest up to $10 billion in the country</a> next year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/nobroker-becomes-first-indian-proptech-unicorn-with-fresh-210-million-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238496</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao talks regulation and platform&#8217;s activities in Africa</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/binance-ceo-changpeng-zhao-talks-regulation-and-platforms-activities-in-africa/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/binance-ceo-changpeng-zhao-talks-regulation-and-platforms-activities-in-africa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 08:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Middle East]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[p2p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the wall street journal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2233992</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Changpeng “CZ” Zhao launched Binance in 2017 and, according to some sources, the company grew into the world’s largest cryptocurrency exchange in the world in 180 days. The Wall Street Journal recently reported that Binance’s daily transactions stood at $76 billion, a volume worth more than its four nearest rivals combined. In the first half [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Changpeng “CZ” Zhao launched Binance in 2017 and, according to some sources, the company grew into the world’s largest cryptocurrency exchange in the world in 180 days</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/binance-became-the-biggest-cryptocurrency-exchange-without-licenses-or-headquarters-thats-coming-to-an-end-11636640029">Wall Street Journal</a> recently reported that Binance’s daily transactions stood at $76 billion, a volume worth more than its four nearest rivals combined.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the first half of 2021, Binance attracted 151 million clicks from Africa and the Middle East and 11 million from Nigeria, according to the WSJ. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">These numbers highlight the general activity of crypto trading in Africa, where $105.6 billion worth of cryptocurrency </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was transacted</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from July 2020 to June 2021, according to <a href="https://blog.chainalysis.com/reports/africas-grassroots-cryptocurrency-adoption">Chainalysis</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2233992" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite growing over 1,200% by value, Africa still accounts for only <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/africa-in-focus/2021/09/14/cryptocurrency-flows-in-africa/">2%</a> of the global value of crypto transacted in this period. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">With cryptocurrency, blockchain and decentralized finance gaining ground on the continent, Binance wants to be the leader in driving these activities</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, for that to happen, the company will need to consider the regulatory challenges it might face on the continent, where crypto activities have </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">been barred</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in two of the most prominent crypto-heavy countries, Nigeria and Kenya</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is already taking several hits from regulators in</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the U.S., China, the U.K., Japan, Malaysia, Thailand, and the E.U., which are now concerned about its unregulated and unstifled growth in recent years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In this interview with TechCrunch, Zhao discussed crypto usage and adoption in Africa, Binance activities and the company’s stance on regulation</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><em>(This transcript has been edited for clarity and length.)</em></p>
<p><strong>TechCrunch: Crypto is one industry several governments are trying to regulate. What’s your take? Should crypto be regulated?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Zhao: Regulation is essential for the crypto industry and will go a long way towards building trust with consumers and institutions interested in the space</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ultimately</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, it takes proper regulation to realize crypto mass adoption, and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">we believe</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in facilitating this in a healthy way through </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">proactively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> collaborating with local regulators and leading the industry to a common destination: benefit and protect users</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our view is that it’s great for the regulators to be coming </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in order to</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> get to 10%, 20%, 80%, 99% [crypto] adoption. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, it’s </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as crucial for regulation to complement instead of hinder crypto’s growth. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, effective regulations safeguard consumers while stimulating growth and innovation, while </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">poorly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> crafted regulatory policy stifles growth and protects dated, ineffective processes and institutions</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>As the largest exchange globally, why is Binance having so many regulatory issues in the U.S., Europe and China? And what steps is the company taking to address them?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I believe</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> every cryptocurrency exchange is working </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">closely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with regulators all around the world. As industry leaders, many people see the industry and see Binance. We don’t take that </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">lightly,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as we have the opportunity to lead by example and partner with regulators to move shared objectives forward.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are the largest crypto exchange because users trust us. We earned that trust through many decisions and actions that protected users. We want to share our best practices with the industry and regulators all around the world. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We believe</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> this will help shape a healthier industry.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As part of efforts to meet compliance with all local regulation guidelines, we’ve recently launched new products — such as Shyft Network’s Veriscope to support <a href="https://sanctionscanner.com/blog/financial-action-task-force-fatf-travel-rule-140#:~:text=FATF%20Travel%20Rule%2C%20officially%20accepted,border%20and%20domestic%20bank%20transfers.">FATF Travel Rule</a> Compliance and our Tax Reporting Tool API so users can </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">quickly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> meet their personal tax obligations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We have also reviewed our existing services, including updating Futures Leverage for New Accounts and restricting access to it in </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">a number of</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> markets and initiating a mandatory KYC [know your customer] </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">requirement</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> across the platform</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. We’ve also recently hired several top-tier talents with a strong background in compliance.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As an example in leadership, we recently began a push for industry players to be long-term driven, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in addition</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to the standard KYC/AML [anti-money laundering] procedures. We are pushing for longer unlocking schedules for founder tokens, from 2-4 years to 8-10 years. This is something that no regulators have asked for, but </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">we believe</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> it will help the industry become healthier. We are always looking for ways to protect users.</span></p>
<p><strong>Would you say governments are going about it correctly? And are they knowledgeable about the budding industry and how to hone its advantage?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is no absolute right or wrong here. It’s a matter of calibration and balance. Crypto and even the regulation of crypto are such new concepts, and many governments are trying to get more clarity about the space.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Regulators share the same mission with us &#8212; protecting consumers while encouraging innovation. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">As regulators work to find the most effective way to engage with the industry, we </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are committed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to 100% compliance globally, and all our teams have been working nonstop to achieve this</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The adoption and development of crypto has many parallels with that of the car. When the car was first invented, there weren’t any traffic laws, traffic lights or even safety belts. Laws and guidelines </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">were developed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> along the way as the cars were running on the road. These are frameworks and laws we take for granted today that allow this powerful technology to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be used</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">widely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">safely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Crypto is similar because it can be accessible for everyone, but frameworks </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are required</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to prevent misuse and bad actors. Clarifying and building the first set of standards is critical for the industry’s continued growth. And Binance wants to be a positive contributor.</span></p>
<p><strong>Why is Binance bullish on Africa, where crypto regulations are increasingly becoming worrying?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The African continent holds some unique opportunities for cryptocurrency adoption and development and so, we’ve always been bullish in Africa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Crypto is solving the issues of cross-border payments and remittances (sending money within Africa and beyond), currency devaluation, etc</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many African countries have suffered from high unemployment rates, and crypto and blockchain have provided innovative job opportunities for a young and brilliant continent, bringing Africans closer to financial freedom</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even from the first day when Binance launched, we had users from Africa, and they were actually </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">relatively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> active. And so, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> it was early 2018 that I visited Uganda, Togo, Nigeria at the same time — and also Ethiopia. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, I had a little tour around Africa </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to learn a little bit more about the market, and soon after that, we opened Binance Uganda, which was our first fiat gateway</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is particularly interesting about African usage is that the number of people having bank accounts is quite low due to a lack of access to traditional financial services</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> this is why crypto is so attractive.</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Yes, it is attractive, and maybe that’s why African central banks have targeted crypto users in recent months and barred banks from facilitating transactions</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">. What happens when they start coming for Binance instead, similar to the U.S., China and other countries?</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Binance welcomes regulation and takes a collaborative approach in working with regulators and governments in navigating this emerging industry, and we take our compliance obligations very </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">seriously</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. We are </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">actively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> keeping abreast of changing policies, rules and laws in this space.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dJJuONTNIq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/nigeria-follows-chinas-footsteps-in-piloting-digital-currency/">Nigeria follows China&#8217;s footsteps in piloting digital currency</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Nigeria follows China&#8217;s footsteps in piloting digital currency&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/nigeria-follows-chinas-footsteps-in-piloting-digital-currency/embed/#?secret=dJJuONTNIq" data-secret="dJJuONTNIq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As such, Binance is ready to assist regulators and find the optimal way to set a fair playing field &#8212; consumer protection is important to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">all of</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> us</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’ve grown </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">exponentially</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as an organization and there are certain processes and protocol updates that we are still working through at the request of regulators</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><b>Do you think crypto adoption and growth will slow down if Binance and other crypto platforms are subjected to government regulations worldwide?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No, I don’t. Smart regulation encourages innovation and helps keep users safe. It’s also important to understand that regulation and innovation are not mutually exclusive. Crypto users deserve safe access to emerging technologies and practices, including NFTs, stablecoins, staking, yield-farming and more.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We touched on this in our recently released 10</span><a href="https://yourcryptorights.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Fundamental Rights for Crypto Users.</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Crypto regulation is inevitable. But users have the right to share their voice on how the industry should evolve with their blockchain platform of choice.</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">What do you think is fueling crypto adoption in Africa?</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> it’s always a combination of many things. Africa is a unique continent with unique challenges. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example, several African countries </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are plagued</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with constant currency devaluation, and so users are more likely to use crypto and stablecoins as a hedge against devaluation and as a store of value</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Making payments &#8212; whether it is remittances, cross-border transfers or settlements &#8212; is also pretty difficult across country lines, and crypto simplifies this</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RSXHntdrTV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/09/crypto-remittances-are-a-lifeline-for-the-worlds-most-vulnerable/">Crypto remittances are a lifeline for the world’s most vulnerable</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Crypto remittances are a lifeline for the world’s most vulnerable&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/09/crypto-remittances-are-a-lifeline-for-the-worlds-most-vulnerable/embed/#?secret=RSXHntdrTV" data-secret="RSXHntdrTV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many Africans look to crypto for wealth creation and financial freedom. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Much like Southeast Asia and Latin America, millions of people live below the poverty line. So it’s natural that more people look for innovative, non-traditional ways to create wealth</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some reports say only 11% of the population in Africa have bank accounts. Many of the non-banked are skipping banks and coming </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">directly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to crypto, using a mobile phone as their bank.</span></p>
<p><b>Talking about numbers, a recent WSJ article said Nigeria had 11 million clicks in H1 2021 on Binance. Is that the number of Binance users on the continent?</b></p>
<p><b></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Wall Street Journal cited stats provided by a third party based on speculation, as they do not have access to our systems nor any user information. We can’t comment on speculative analysis conducted by external third parties.</span></p>
<p><strong>As more Africans use P2P more than ever before, how is Binance making sure users are safely trading cryptocurrencies in Africa on its platform?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These have been our focuses in Africa as we remain committed to ensuring that Africans are well educated and protected. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With Binance P2P in particular, user protection and safety are paramount. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">As of August, we had provided free crypto classes to over 400,000 Africans on topics ranging from user protection to building a career in blockchain</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The team recently implemented new risk management measures, including a crypto escrow service.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> We have also recently expanded our global KYC requirements to enhance user protection and</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> implement new P2P features to prevent bad actors from exploiting the system</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">What potentials do cryptocurrencies and blockchain hold that’ll be transformative for emerging economies such as Africa</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">?</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Honestly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the potential is endless, and in emerging economies, this is even more true. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">New financial infrastructure, systems and processes are being created &#8212; transforming lives and creating the potential for financial freedom</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I also </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">personally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> see huge potential in recent innovations </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">propelled</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> into the mainstream &#8212; GameFi, Sports Fan Tokens, NFTs, etc. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> these can be very transformative</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Hy89ENRUKQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/regulating-crypto-is-essential-to-ensuring-its-global-legitimacy/">Regulating crypto is essential to ensuring its global legitimacy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Regulating crypto is essential to ensuring its global legitimacy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/regulating-crypto-is-essential-to-ensuring-its-global-legitimacy/embed/#?secret=Hy89ENRUKQ" data-secret="Hy89ENRUKQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/binance-ceo-changpeng-zhao-talks-regulation-and-platforms-activities-in-africa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2233992</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>China&#8217;s AI giant SenseTime readies Hong Kong IPO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/sensetime-ipo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/sensetime-ipo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 08:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facial recognition software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Megvii]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SenseTime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank Vision Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taobao]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238426</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of China&#8217;s biggest AI solution providers SenseTime is a step closer to its initial public offering. SenseTime has received regulatory approval to list on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, according to media reports. Founded in 2014, SenseTime was christened as one of China&#8217;s four &#8220;AI Dragons&#8221; alongside Megvii, CloudWalk, and Yitu. In the second [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">One of China&#8217;s biggest AI solution providers SenseTime is a step closer to its initial public offering. SenseTime has <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-19/ai-giant-sensetime-said-to-win-approval-for-hong-kong-ipo">received regulatory approval</a> to list on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, according to media reports.</p>
<p>Founded in 2014, SenseTime was christened as one of China&#8217;s four &#8220;AI Dragons&#8221; alongside Megvii, CloudWalk, and Yitu. In the second half of the 2010s, their algorithms found much demand from businesses and governments hoping to turn real-life data into actionable insights. Cameras embedded with their AI models watch city streets 24 hours. Malls use their sensing solutions to track and predict crowds on the premises.</p>
<p>SenseTime&#8217;s three rivals have all mulled plans to sell shares either in mainland China or Hong Kong. Megvii is preparing to list on China&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/megvii-ipo-china/">Nasdaq-style STAR board</a> after its HKEX application lapsed.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238426" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The window for China&#8217;s data-rich tech firms to list overseas has narrowed. Beijing is making it harder for companies with sensitive data to go public outside China. And regulators in the West are wary of facial recognition companies that could aid mass surveillance.</p>
<p>But in the past few years, China&#8217;s AI upstarts were sought after by investors all over the world. In 2018 alone, SenseTime racked up more than <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/sensetime/company_financials">$2 billion in investment</a>. To date, the company has raised a staggering $5.2 billion in funding through 12 rounds. Its biggest outside shareholders include SoftBank Vision Fund and Alibaba&#8217;s Taobao. For its flotation in Hong Kong, SenseTime plans to raise up to $2 billion, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/sensetime-receives-go-ahead-hong-kong-ipo-sources-2021-11-19/">according to Reuters</a>.</p>
<p>SenseTime spends a large chunk of its capital on research and development, which cost it more than 5 billion yuan ($780 million) between 2018 and 2020, according to its <a href="https://www1.hkexnews.hk/app/sehk/2021/103756/documents/sehk21082702575.pdf">prospectus</a>. The company recorded net losses for the past four years, largely due to &#8220;the fair value losses of our preferred shares.&#8221; Its net losses reached 3.7 billion yuan in the first half of 2021. Total deficits neared 23 billion yuan as of June.</p>
<p>Like its peers, SenseTime relied on &#8220;smart city&#8221; projects for monetization. The business comprised 47.6% of its total revenues of 1.65 billion yuan in the six months ended June, up from a share of 27% in the same period of 2020. The number of cities using SenseTime&#8217;s software platform reached 119 by June, according to the firm&#8217;s prospectus.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The &#8220;Smart Business&#8221; line, which is tailored to commercial space, residential property, and other enterprise needs, made up about 40% of its revenues in the first half of this year. The firm derived the rest of its revenues from the &#8220;Smart Life&#8221; unit, which supplies to IoT devices, and &#8220;Smart Auto&#8221;, which applies perception intelligence to autonomous driving solutions.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2atcf7dhHz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/megvii-ipo-china/">Chinese facial recognition unicorn Megvii prepares China IPO</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chinese facial recognition unicorn Megvii prepares China IPO&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/megvii-ipo-china/embed/#?secret=2atcf7dhHz" data-secret="2atcf7dhHz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/sensetime-ipo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238426</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>French insurtech startup Leocare raises big funding round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/french-insurtech-startup-leocare-raises-big-funding-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/french-insurtech-startup-leocare-raises-big-funding-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 07:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LeoCare]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238218</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup Leocare has raised a big Series B funding round led by Eight Roads. Overall, the company has raised $116 million. It’s an equity and debt round, which means that part of this amount is a cash-for-equity transaction, while the rest is a credit line. The company is raising today’s Series B less than [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup Leocare has raised a big Series B funding round led by <a href="https://eightroads.com/en/">Eight Roads</a>. Overall, the company has raised $116 million. It’s an equity and debt round, which means that part of this amount is a cash-for-equity transaction, while the rest is a credit line.</p>
<p>The company is raising today’s Series B less than a year after raising <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/leocare-raises-18-1-million-for-its-insurance-products-designed-to-fit-in-a-mobile-app/">its Series A</a>. And some of Leocare’s existing investors are putting more money on the table with the Series B, such as Felix Capital, Ventech and Daphni.</p>
<p>Leocare wants to handle all your insurance needs under a single roof. The startup can insure your home, your car, your motorbike and your smartphone. And it believes consumers want to subscribe to new insurance product using a mobile app because it’s more convenient and it opens up new features.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238218" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>For instance, the company is working on a new feature called TakeCare. “It’s like Waze, it tells you when you’re entering a high-risk area,” co-founder and CEO Christophe Dandois told me.</p>
<p>But TakeCare doesn’t warn you about speed traps. Instead, the Leocare app tells you if people often end up in a car incident in the area. Leocare is leveraging road safety open data for that feature. Similarly, if your neighbor is using your car for the weekend, you can add a second driver in a few taps and remove them on Monday.</p>
<p>The startup also uses data to adjust pricing where it makes sense. For instance, Leocare tracks the channel you’re using to subscribe, looks at the smartphone model you’re using, checks the time of the session, etc. In other words, expect some dynamic pricing.</p>
<p>When you want your insurance to step in, once again, Leocare wants you to use the mobile app. You can still call a phone number, but most clients are already using the app.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The long-term vision is quite clear as Leocare wants to create a single contract that covers everything you own and everything you regularly do. And you should be able to tweak your insurance options whenever you need to. The company wants to add more products, such as bike insurance — as long as they are not one-off insurance products, such as travel insurance, it could potentially be covered by Leocare.</p>
<p>And it makes sense to aggregate everything as many customers end up paying twice for the same thing. For instance, home insurance usually cover against theft. That’s why a bike insurance could cover theft outside of the home as your Leocare home insurance is already taking care of theft at home.</p>
<p>The company currently acts as a managing general agent and partners with several insurance companies. It sells its insurance products under its own brand.</p>
<p>“With this funding round, we’ll still follow the same model but we’ll also add the ability to use our own risk carrier,” Dandois said. Depending on the insurance product, Leocare could end up managing the insurance product from start to finish.</p>
<p>In addition to new insurance products, the company wants to expand to new markets, starting with Southern Europe, such as Spain. Right now, Leocare has 65,000 active customers and aims to generate €100 million in revenue next year.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2238220" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238220" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Leocare-Team.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" class="size-full wp-image-2238220" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Leocare-Team.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Leocare-Team.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Leocare-Team.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Leocare-Team.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Leocare-Team.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Leocare-Team.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Leocare-Team.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Leocare-Team.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2238220" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Leocare</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/french-insurtech-startup-leocare-raises-big-funding-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238218</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
