<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 20:03:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>How my company is winning the war for engineering talent</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/how-my-company-is-winning-the-war-for-engineering-talent/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/how-my-company-is-winning-the-war-for-engineering-talent/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 20:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Future of Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hiring]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216346</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You can’t overlook the elephant in the room — money talks.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Konstantin Richter</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/konstantin11">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/konstantinrichter">Konstantin Richter</a> is the founder and CEO of <a href="https://blockdaemon.com/">Blockdaemon</a>, an independent blockchain infrastructure platform.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The engineering talent war is real. It has been for some time — but with a pandemic that pushed businesses in all industries to focus on e-commerce and virtual products and services, demand for skilled engineers skyrocketed.</p>
<p>In June, more than 365,000 tech jobs in the U.S. were <a href="https://www.latimes.com/business/story/2021-07-31/employers-bow-down-to-tech-workers-in-hottest-job-market">vacant</a>, with software developers, IT support specialists, systems engineers and architects among the most coveted workers by employers.</p>
<p>Yet, we are hiring 10 to 15 engineers a month, far above the industry average. What’s our secret?</p>
<p>First, it’s important to acknowledge that engineers — and most knowledge workers — have choice and bargaining power in today’s job market. An employer needs to not only respect that but take it as an opportunity to create a more attractive workplace — and remain agile long after the hiring tides change.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			You can’t overlook the elephant in the room — money talks. Today, you can’t just offer the standard “competitive salary” — you must do better. 					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Overall, we have learned that It is much harder to hire top-tier talent than it is to generate revenue. This is one of our guiding principles, and we remind our team of that all the time. It’s incumbent upon everyone in the company to focus their energies on helping us find — and retain — great people. With this commitment in place, we know the rest will take care of itself.</p>
<p>Granted, we are fortunate that cryptocurrency and blockchain have a certain cachet and come with unique engineering needs that will keep the most ambitious engineers challenged and rewarded in their day-to-day work. However, we still had to make concerted efforts to appeal to today’s in-demand engineers. Here are a few ways we are winning the war for engineering talent.</p>
<h2>Have a strong cash position</h2>
<p>You can’t overlook the elephant in the room — money talks. Today, you can’t just offer the standard “competitive salary” — you must do better. We make sure our offers stand out and are hard to turn down. This approach is driven by our strong cash position (yes, we recognize our good fortune).</p>
<p>Ultimately, innovation is our lifeblood, so everything we do is measured with quality and speed before considering cost.</p>
<h2>Review salaries at least every six months</h2>
<p>We don’t review salaries annually; the industry is too fast-paced and competitive for that antiquated approach. At least every six months, we review salary bands across the organization relative to employee performance and market trends and adjust employee compensation on a more flexible, ad-hoc basis.</p>
<p>This helps build a meritocratic and less bureaucratic culture and ensures our team reaps the benefits commensurate with their work product.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/how-my-company-is-winning-the-war-for-engineering-talent/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216346</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FourFront nabs funding to build an interconnected network of fictional TikTok stars</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/fourfront-nabs-funding-to-build-an-interconnected-network-of-fictional-tiktok-stars/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/fourfront-nabs-funding-to-build-an-interconnected-network-of-fictional-tiktok-stars/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 20:03:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alumni Ventures Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BAM Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BDMI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freeware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slow ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sydney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tech products]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216984</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every popular social media platform has opened up a new type of storytelling to a new generation of users, but TikTok&#8217;s impact has perhaps been the swiftest as the short-form video platform&#8217;s user base has quickly swelled past 1 billion users and transformed how social media stars are made. FourFront is a media startup that&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Every popular social media platform has opened up a new type of storytelling to a new generation of users, but TikTok&#8217;s impact has perhaps been the swiftest as the short-form video platform&#8217;s user base has quickly swelled past 1 billion users and transformed how social media stars are made.</p>
<p><a href="https://linktr.ee/FourFrontmedia">FourFront</a> is a media startup that&#8217;s looking to define a new type of storytelling on the platform, aiming to popularize a network of individual actors performing scripted short-form serialized stories that feel native to TikTok. Fictionalized storytelling in vlog form is clearly not a new development for social media, but FourFront is hoping that it can capitalize on the the discoverability opened up by TikTok&#8217;s For You Page (FYP) to steadily build new audiences.</p>
<p>The startup tells TechCrunch that they&#8217;ve raised $1.5 million in seed funding from Bam Ventures, Slow Ventures, BDMI, Alumni Ventures Group and HustleFund.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216984" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The startup has a couple dozen characters on TikTok, with a handful racking up several hundreds of thousands of followers. Not all of the characters have been hits, and FourFront&#8217;s team of writers and social media strategists have settled on nine characters who they&#8217;re looking to create an interconnected &#8220;universe&#8221; around where the actors organically cross paths with each other. While FourFront&#8217;s team plans out the character arcs, it&#8217;s on the actors to shoot the videos themselves.</p>
<p>The scripted content is often pretty soap opera-esque, but follows the format of popular videos on the platform; &#8220;watch us confront my sister&#8217;s cheating fiance LIVE&#8221; implores one video from FourFront&#8217;s most popular character &#8220;<a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@sydneyplus?">Sydney</a>&#8221; who has nearly 500k followers after debuting in June. In addition to helping catch her sister&#8217;s cheating fiance, Sydney has also discussed the stresses of her roommate breaking her lease early and the lessons she has learned working in customer support for a dating app.</p>
<p>FourFront co-founder Ilan Benjamin tells TechCrunch that his startup isn&#8217;t trying to mislead anyone into thinking that their network of characters are real, noting that their profile bios highlight the fictional nature of the stories and that each of the videos include the #fictional tag. &#8220;We don’t want to confuse audiences or trick them, we want them to be entertained,&#8221; Benjamin says.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2217091" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217091" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217091" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-12.58.55-PM.png" alt="" width="1024" height="905" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-12.58.55-PM.png 2140w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-12.58.55-PM.png?resize=150,133 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-12.58.55-PM.png?resize=300,265 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-12.58.55-PM.png?resize=768,679 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-12.58.55-PM.png?resize=680,601 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-12.58.55-PM.png?resize=1536,1358 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-12.58.55-PM.png?resize=2048,1811 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-12-at-12.58.55-PM.png?resize=50,44 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217091" class="wp-caption-text">FourFront&#8217;s character &#8220;Tia&#8221;</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Building content for TikTok means catering to the whims of the FYP which means plenty of viewers are catching characters like Sydney in the middle of their storylines, something that can create storytelling challenges when it comes to balancing the patience of existing fans while capturing the curiosity of new viewers.</p>
<p>&#8220;The plot mechanics might be repetitive,&#8221; Benjamin says. &#8220;It&#8217;s a constant balancing act, every video has to stand on its own and every single video has to be evergreen.&#8221;</p>
<p>For now, the company is largely focused on building out its network of stars and their audiences while looking to push boundaries in how audiences interact with characters using tech products like conversational AI chatbots and polls to help direct the stories themselves.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/fourfront-nabs-funding-to-build-an-interconnected-network-of-fictional-tiktok-stars/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216984</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Mixpanel got its startup groove back by focusing on its core product</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/how-mixpanel-got-its-startup-groove-back-by-focusing-on-its-core-product/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/how-mixpanel-got-its-startup-groove-back-by-focusing-on-its-core-product/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 19:12:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[founder story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mixpanel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product analytics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The startup myth goes something like this: You launch a startup in your dorm room, get into Y Combinator, find product-market fit, experience hockey-stick growth, raise some funding and expand the platform.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The startup myth goes something like this: You launch a startup in your dorm room, get into Y Combinator, find product-market fit, experience hockey-stick growth, raise some funding and expand the platform. Somehow your revenue hurtles toward $100 million and the company valuation flies to $1 billion. All&#8217;s right with the world.</p>
<p>In reality, though, it&#8217;s never that smooth. While some startups may achieve those milestones, there are usually bumps and full-blown challenges along the way. Mistakes will be made, some quite harmful, and how you react could determine the success or failure of your business.</p>
<p>One company that experienced all that and more is <a href="http://mixpanel.com">Mixpanel</a>, an analytics startup that emerged in 2009 to help product teams understand how customers were using their products. While founder Suhail Doshi was interning at a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2010/08/04/google-buys-slide-for-182-million-getting-more-serious-about-social-games/">now defunct Max Levchin startup</a> called Slide, he saw the need for product teams to measure how successful their digital tools were.</p>
<p>Doshi created Mixpanel, and between 2009 and 2017 he built a company that eventually reached revenue close to $100 million and a valuation of nearly unicorn stature, but at that point it was experiencing problems. It lacked focus, it was losing customers, and many of the customers it had weren&#8217;t terribly pleased with it.</p>
<p>The board made the move to bring in an outside CEO, and Doshi moved over to the chairman of the board role. The new CEO began a process of evaluating and eventually charting a course correction, one that would take it back to its core product.</p>
<p>We spoke to current CEO Amir Movafaghi, VP of people and strategy Amy Hsuan and VP of product and design Neil Rahilly to find out how Mixpanel developed, what caused it to lose its way and why it believes it has righted the ship and got the company back to a stable place. (We also asked for comments from founder Doshi to get his perspective, but the company did not respond to that request in a timely manner.) None of it was easy, and it certainly didn&#8217;t follow that seemingly smooth mythological startup journey.</p>
<h2>The early days</h2>
<p>Like any good startup story, this one started on a college campus at the University of Arizona in 2009 where 20-year-old Doshi was a college student. While interning at Slide, he saw a problem around collecting and analyzing product data, one that big companies had the resources to solve but was out of reach for startups like Slide. That&#8217;s always a sweet spot for a software service startup.</p>
<p>To that point, if a company was using an analytics product, it would likely have been something like Google Analytics or Omniture, which were geared toward understanding how people got to your website and what they did after they got there. People who were in charge of digital products had different needs, though. They wanted to see what features people were using, their path through the product, where they got stuck and when it didn&#8217;t work as designed. While both approaches might have had a usability component, the web analytics tools had a specific purpose that really wasn&#8217;t well suited to product teams.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/how-mixpanel-got-its-startup-groove-back-by-focusing-on-its-core-product/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211309</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter will now let you remove followers without blocking them</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/twitter-will-now-let-you-remove-followers-without-blocking-them/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/twitter-will-now-let-you-remove-followers-without-blocking-them/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 19:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[algorithms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After testing last month, Twitter is rolling out a feature to all web users that will let them remove followers without blocking them. This safety feature can be helpful if you want to avoid the repercussions of blocking someone &#8212; if a blocked user navigates to your profile after you block them, Twitter will tell [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/twitter-tests-a-safety-feature-on-web-to-remove-followers-without-blocking-them/"> testing</a> last month, Twitter is rolling out a feature to all web users that will let them remove followers without blocking them. This safety feature can be helpful if you want to avoid the repercussions of blocking someone &#8212; if a blocked user navigates to your profile after you block them, Twitter will tell them that they were blocked. But by removing a follower, users can feel more secure about who sees their tweets without blocking them altogether.</p>
<p>Sure, the blocked user might notice that they no longer follow you, but who knows! Maybe they clicked the unfollow button on accident! There&#8217;s some plausible deniability there that a hard block doesn&#8217;t offer.</p>
<p>For years, Twitter users had manufactured this &#8220;soft block&#8221; by swiftly blocking and unblocking a follower, which removes them from your follower list. But now, Twitter is making this its own feature.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216989" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">rolling out to everyone on the web today<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f447.png" alt="👇" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/Nqhhf2q2fo">https://t.co/Nqhhf2q2fo</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Twitter Safety (@TwitterSafety) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSafety/status/1447630725746987013?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 11, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>In the <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1435323978734841857">tweet</a> about the test that Twitter posted in September, the images indicated that you have to manually scroll through your follower list and find the person you want to remove before you can take them off your followers list. But now, you can also remove a follower by going to their profile, clicking the three-dot icon, and selecting the &#8220;Remove this follower&#8221; option. For particularly popular Twitter users, that makes the feature far more usable.</p>
<p>Unrelated to follower removals, Twitter also announced a test of a feature that would allow users to swipe on their timeline between two different feeds: one that&#8217;s sorted by Twitter&#8217;s algorithm, and one that&#8217;s chronological.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Top Tweets first or latest Tweets first? We’re making it easier to switch between the two timelines and know which one you’re scrolling.</p>
<p>Now testing with some of you on iOS: swipe between &quot;Home&quot; and &quot;Latest&quot; on the Home tab to choose which Tweets you see first. <a href="https://t.co/LoyAN4cONu">pic.twitter.com/LoyAN4cONu</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Twitter Support (@TwitterSupport) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1447971179185295364?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 12, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Twitter already lets users <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/17/twitter-chronological-timeline/">switch between</a> these two feeds, but the test comes at a time when content algorithms are at attention. When the Facebook whistleblower Frances Haugen <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-testifies-before-the-senate/">testified before the Senate</a> last week, she said that she believes ranking content chronologically can help limit the spread of toxicity, misinformation and violent content on Facebook, which uses an algorithm that promotes content that&#8217;s more likely to spark a reaction. Twitter co-founder and CEO Jack Dorsey has previously <a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1321456610158370817?lang=en">voiced support</a> for users&#8217; ability to choose from multiple algorithms to organize the content they see.</p>
<p>Twitter has been testing and implementing a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/twitter-intense-tweet-warning-prompt/">baffling amount</a> of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/twitter-spaces-spark-creator-program/">new features</a> lately. Not everything Twitter tests becomes a permanent fixture, but it used to be a good indication of where the company&#8217;s interests lied. But more recently, Twitter explained its strategy would include far more experimentation than in the past. That means it&#8217;s more ready to shut down projects and features that don&#8217;t work &#8212; something <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/twitter-fleets-rip/">it already did</a> with its Stories feature, called Fleets.</p>
<p>&#8220;You won’t see us stay tied to the things that aren’t working,&#8221; Twitter Head of Consumer Product Kayvon Beykpour <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/23/twitter-accelerates-again-with-bitcoin-tips-nfts-recorded-spaces-creator-fund-and-more/">said last month</a>, when announcing another large round of new additions. &#8220;We believe that if we’re not winding things down every once in a while, then we’re not taking big enough bets,” he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/twitter-will-now-let-you-remove-followers-without-blocking-them/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216989</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Waze is rolling out a new ‘Drive with Headspace’ experience to make commutes less stressful</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/waze-is-rolling-out-a-new-drive-with-headspace-experience-to-make-commutes-less-stressful/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/waze-is-rolling-out-a-new-drive-with-headspace-experience-to-make-commutes-less-stressful/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 18:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Headspace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[navigation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waze]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216957</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Waze announced today it&#8217;s partnering with meditation app Headspace to roll out a new ‘Drive with Headspace’ experience aimed at making commutes less stressful. The navigation app maker says the new integration is meant to help drivers learn how to “find more joy and meaning on the road.” The Headspace experience allows users to choose [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Waze <a href="https://medium.com/waze/welcome-a-new-era-of-happier-driving-with-headspace-90f539103d09?source=collection_home---4------0-----------------------">announced</a> today it&#8217;s partnering with meditation app Headspace to roll out a new ‘Drive with Headspace’ experience aimed at making commutes less stressful. The navigation app maker says the new integration is meant to help drivers learn how to “find more joy and meaning on the road.” The Headspace experience allows users to choose from five moods, including aware, bright, hopeful, joyful and open.</p>
<p>Drivers will also be able to listen to a <a href="https://open.spotify.com/playlist/5kzu984CXB3iTmshDvj8He">custom Spotify playlist</a> with music and content from Headspace, which is available through the Waze audio player. Users can also choose to swap out the in-app car icon for a “serene ride in a hot air balloon.” Additionally, the experience offers custom navigation prompts from Headspace’s director of meditation, Eve Lewis Prieto.</p>
<p>“Traffic is the worst. The longer you’re in it, the worse your blood pressure, sleep, back pain, and risk of depression. As more and more people get back into the rhythm of having to commute to school or work, many are finding themselves stuck in traffic again,” Waze said in a <a href="https://medium.com/waze/welcome-a-new-era-of-happier-driving-with-headspace-90f539103d09?source=collection_home---4------0-----------------------">blog post.</a> “To find a way to help combat the negative effects of traffic and encourage drivers to enjoy their drives, on the heels of World Mental Health Day, we turned to our friends at Headspace.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216957" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The Headspace experience is available starting today for a limited time in English, French, Spanish and Portuguese. Users can activate the experience by taping “My Waze” to find the new “Drive with Headspace” banner.</p>
<p>Waze has been rolling out numerous driving experiences over the past few years to make its users’ commutes more entertaining. For instance, the company recently launched <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/waze-with-paw-patrol-voices-sounds-like-a-chill-car-ride/">Paw Patrol</a>, <a href="https://medium.com/waze/drive-your-cares-away-with-fraggle-rock-4637dfa5b36b?source=collection_home---4------1-----------------------">Fraggle Rock</a> and <a href="https://medium.com/waze/boy-george-is-here-to-guide-your-ride-with-pride-9da03213c3b5?source=collection_home---4------8-----------------------">Pride-themed</a> experiences over the summer. It has also integrated with a number of subscription services, like <a href="https://www.engadget.com/waze-audible-102500904.html">Audible</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/18/waze-and-spotify-integration-arrives-on-ios/">Spotify</a>, Pandora, YouTube Music and iHeartRadio to make it easier to navigate while using your favorite apps.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/waze-is-rolling-out-a-new-drive-with-headspace-experience-to-make-commutes-less-stressful/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216957</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Doist redesigns Twist, the Slack alternative focused on async work</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/doist-redesigns-twist-the-slack-alternative-focused-on-async-work/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/doist-redesigns-twist-the-slack-alternative-focused-on-async-work/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 18:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internal communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twist]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216952</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Doist, the company behind Todoist and Twist, has revamped its internal communication product Twist. When I first covered Twist, I said it was like Slack without the annoying distractions. With today’s redesign, the company is doubling down on that idea. The result is an opinionated tool for internal conversations that should help you focus and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://doist.com">Doist</a>, the company behind <a href="https://todoist.com">Todoist</a> and <a href="https://twist.com">Twist</a>, has revamped its internal communication product Twist. When I first <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/21/twist-is-slack-without-the-annoying-distractions/">covered</a> Twist, I said it was like Slack without the annoying distractions. With today’s <a href="https://blog.doist.com/twist-async-team-messaging/">redesign</a>, the company is doubling down on that idea. The result is an opinionated tool for internal conversations that should help you focus and keep the team on track.</p>
<p>While Doist started working on Twist way before the coronavirus pandemic, it feels like Twist is more relevant than ever. Over the past couple of years, many teams started working remotely for the first time. Some companies that had a Microsoft 365 subscription started using Microsoft Teams, other companies spent <em>a lot</em> of time in Zoom meetings.</p>
<p>Doist founder Amir Salihefendic thinks those tools don’t work well. He has been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/17/doist-founder-amir-salihefendic-explains-why-his-remote-team-doesnt-try-to-do-everything-in-real-time/">promoting asynchronous communication</a> for years. Slack or Microsoft Teams interrupt you all the time with notifications and chat messages. It’s hard to keep up, especially if you don’t work in the same time zone as the rest of the team. And it’s impossible to have two conversations at the same time in the same channel.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216952" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Twist’s strongest differentiating point with Slack is still there. In Twist, every conversation is a thread. If you want to start a conversation, you click on a channel, such as #design, #ios or #support, and then you start a thread with a title and some body text. After you posted a new thread, other users can add comments, react with emojis and you can tag people.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2216967" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216967" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-2.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="628" class="size-full wp-image-2216967" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-2.jpg 2732w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-2.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-2.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-2.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-2.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-2.jpg?resize=1536,942 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-2.jpg?resize=2048,1256 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-2.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2216967" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twist</p></div></p>
<p>If you want to send quick feedback, ask a question to someone specifically or have a private conversation, Twist also lets you send direct messages to other users. But it&#8217;s the equivalent of sending a text message as those conversations are not meant to hold important work conversations.</p>
<p>The interface has been completely redesigned. The product has a cleaner look that helps you focus on what you’re looking at right now. Instead of a three-column layout with channels on the left, a list of threads in the center and the current open thread on the right, Dois has opted for a two-column layout that lets you focus on the current thread.</p>
<p>When you open a thread, it fills up most of the interface so that you can follow conversations better. You don’t get distracted with new comments in other threads as you can’t see the list of other threads.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2216968" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216968" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Mobile.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="681" class="size-full wp-image-2216968" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Mobile.jpg 2604w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Mobile.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Mobile.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Mobile.jpg?resize=768,511 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Mobile.jpg?resize=680,452 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Mobile.jpg?resize=1536,1022 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Mobile.jpg?resize=2048,1362 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Mobile.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2216968" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twist</p></div></p>
<p>The inbox view has been redesigned to help you see what you missed when you weren’t looking at Twist. From this view, you can see new content in the threads that you’re following. You can read those threads, add comments and more. Once you think you’re done interacting with a thread, you can mark it as done. Twist moves the thread from your inbox to the ‘Done’ view.</p>
<p>Other new features in today’s release include new keyboard shortcuts to help you move from one thread to another and a better search feature. The product costs $5 per user and per month if you sign up to a yearly plan. There’s a free option to try out the product but you can only see one month of comments and messages.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2216966" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216966" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-1.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="628" class="size-full wp-image-2216966" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-1.jpg 2732w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-1.jpg?resize=1536,942 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-1.jpg?resize=2048,1256 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Twist-Desktop-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2216966" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twist</p></div></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="U7Noad1oZy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/17/doist-founder-amir-salihefendic-explains-why-his-remote-team-doesnt-try-to-do-everything-in-real-time/">Doist founder Amir Salihefendic explains why his remote team doesn&#8217;t try to do everything in real time</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Doist founder Amir Salihefendic explains why his remote team doesn&#8217;t try to do everything in real time&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/17/doist-founder-amir-salihefendic-explains-why-his-remote-team-doesnt-try-to-do-everything-in-real-time/embed/#?secret=U7Noad1oZy" data-secret="U7Noad1oZy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/doist-redesigns-twist-the-slack-alternative-focused-on-async-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216952</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple Fitness+ UX teardown: 3 key takeaways on how not to interrupt the user journey</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/apple-fitness-ux-teardown-3-key-takeaways-on-how-not-to-interrupt-the-user-journey/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/apple-fitness-ux-teardown-3-key-takeaways-on-how-not-to-interrupt-the-user-journey/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 18:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Consumer Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[User Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ux]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On paper, there’s never been a better time to work out at home. But are these subscriptions actually any good? For example, what’s the experience of Apple Fitness+ actually like?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Peter Ramsey</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/PeteRamsey">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Peter Ramsey is CEO of <a href="https://builtformars.com/">Built For Mars</a>, a UX consultancy that helps customers build better product experiences.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/opensea-ux-teardown-3-key-takeaways/">OpenSea UX teardown: 3 key takeaways</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/apple-airtags-ux-teardown-the-trade-off-between-privacy-and-user-experience/">Apple AirTags UX teardown: The trade-off between privacy and user experience</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The home-workout sector is hot right now. <a href="https://builtformars.com/case-studies/using-apple-fitness">Amazon recently announced Halo Fitness</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/pelotons-ceo-john-foley-on-the-changing-face-of-connected-fitness/">Peloton have rereleased their treadmills</a> after some controversy, and Apple released Fitness+ late into 2020.</p>
<p>On paper, there’s never been a better time to work out at home. But are these subscriptions actually any good? For example, what’s the experience of Apple Fitness+ actually like?</p>
<p>That’s what I’ve been working on this month: Reviewing Apple Fitness and demonstrating where the experience fails to reach its stride.</p>
<p>This TechCrunch+ exclusive is a more detailed conversation around <a href="https://builtformars.com/case-studies/using-apple-fitness">this article</a>, which you can read on Built for Mars.</p>
<h2>1. The &#8220;jump in&#8221; fallacy</h2>
<p>“It&#8217;s wrong to assume that showing &#8216;options&#8217; quickly is always good UX — this is often under the guise that it&#8217;s allowing the user to &#8216;jump right in.&#8217; There&#8217;s a nuance that&#8217;s seldom considered: Can the user actually engage with all of this content or not? If they wanted to, could they actually use all of these options (or results)?”</p>
<p>This is something I see all the time, and it’s hugely misunderstood. Imagine if you went on Rightmove (or Zillow) and the homepage just showed you a selection of houses all over the world — it’d be useless. It’s rare that someone is looking to relocate anywhere, so instead, their first action is to apply a filter. It’d be wrong for Rightmove to think: &#8220;Well, we’ve shown houses immediately, so it only takes one click to find your dream home.&#8221;</p>
<p>This is essentially what happens with Apple Fitness+ — they show you workouts on the homepage, despite many (if not most) being unsuitable for you, and then don’t provide any obvious means to filter the options.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2216747" style="width: 1010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216747" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2216747 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image3.png" alt="" width="1000" height="860" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image3.png 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image3.png?resize=150,129 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image3.png?resize=300,258 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image3.png?resize=768,660 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image3.png?resize=680,585 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/image3.png?resize=50,43 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2216747" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Peter Ramsey</p></div></p>
<blockquote><p>Tip: It’s not always a good idea to display results immediately. You need to consider if everything you’re showing the user is useful.</p></blockquote>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/apple-fitness-ux-teardown-3-key-takeaways-on-how-not-to-interrupt-the-user-journey/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216737</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter launches Spark audio creator program to boost Spaces</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/twitter-spaces-spark-creator-program/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/twitter-spaces-spark-creator-program/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 18:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter Spaces]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216951</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter is deepening its investment in Spaces, the Clubhouse-like audio rooms the social network launched this year. The company announced the launch of a new creator program for Spaces on Tuesday. The Spark program is a three-month-long accelerator that aims to &#8220;discover and reward great Spaces on Twitter with financial, technical, and marketing support.&#8221; Twitter [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter is deepening its investment in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/twitter-expands-spaces-to-anyone-with-600-followers-details-plans-for-tickets-reminders-and-more/">Spaces</a>, the Clubhouse-like audio rooms the social network launched this year.</p>
<p>The company announced the launch of a<a href="https://media.twitter.com/en/verticals/creators/twitter-spaces-spark-program"> new creator program for Spaces on Tuesday</a>. The Spark program is a three-month-long accelerator that aims to &#8220;discover and reward great Spaces on Twitter with financial, technical, and marketing support.&#8221; Twitter says it&#8217;s open to established Spaces audio shows and untested experiments for the program, inviting creators interested in audio to apply.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">*unmutes*</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216951" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>today we’re opening the application process for the Twitter Spaces Spark Program</p>
<p>what’s that? it’s an initiative for creators who are excited about the future of social audio <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f447.png" alt="👇" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/4zay8uvao8">pic.twitter.com/4zay8uvao8</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Spaces (@TwitterSpaces) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSpaces/status/1447956725924077583?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 12, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Since launching Spaces, Twitter has signaled that its audio product isn&#8217;t likely to be just another<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/twitter-fleets-rip/"> test feature destined for an early retirement</a>. The company expanded ticketed Spaces last month, inviting hosts to monetize audio rooms by selling access to their hosted audio chats. This week, the company added a way for hosts to invite listeners via DM when firing up a Space. It also <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSpaces/status/1447647870006579204">rolled out a dedicated Spaces tab to more iOS users</a>, with plans to expand further to non-English languages and Android in the works.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">we’re working on making it easier to find and join Spaces you love. today starts the rollout of the Spaces Tab to more people in English and iOS first, with other languages and Android coming in the future!</p>
<p>if you have access, let us know what you think <a href="https://t.co/MatEDXv01F">pic.twitter.com/MatEDXv01F</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Spaces (@TwitterSpaces) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSpaces/status/1447647870006579204?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 11, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Anyone who gets accepted into the <a href="https://media.twitter.com/en/verticals/creators/twitter-spaces-spark-program">Spark program</a> is expected to run an audio room two times a week for the three month period. They&#8217;ll be compensated $2,500 a month — a flat rate not dictated by the Space&#8217;s performance — and granted monthly ad credits to boost their show. Anyone who signs on to the program will have the added benefit of getting promoted by Twitter&#8217;s accounts in tweets and discovery features.</p>
<p>&#8220;We recognize the hard work it takes to create audio content that’s compelling, engaging, and keeps people coming back,&#8221; the company wrote in the Spark program announcement. &#8220;And above all else, we believe in the potential of people’s ideas and the potential of live social audio, and we see an opportunity to help audio content Creators — like you — take off.&#8221;</p>
<p>Twitter users interested in building out a bi-weekly Twitter-backed audio project can apply with the company by October 22. Accepted applicants will get notified by in early November.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tQew1OAJew"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/twitter-expands-spaces-to-anyone-with-600-followers-details-plans-for-tickets-reminders-and-more/">Twitter expands Spaces to anyone with 600+ followers, details plans for tickets, reminders and more</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter expands Spaces to anyone with 600+ followers, details plans for tickets, reminders and more&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/twitter-expands-spaces-to-anyone-with-600-followers-details-plans-for-tickets-reminders-and-more/embed/#?secret=tQew1OAJew" data-secret="tQew1OAJew" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SSdKSKb0vv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/twitter-redesigns-its-mobile-app-to-make-spaces-the-center-tab/">Twitter redesigns its mobile app to make Spaces the center tab</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter redesigns its mobile app to make Spaces the center tab&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/twitter-redesigns-its-mobile-app-to-make-spaces-the-center-tab/embed/#?secret=SSdKSKb0vv" data-secret="SSdKSKb0vv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/twitter-spaces-spark-creator-program/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216951</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TechCrunch+ roundup: 3 flavors of BaaS, growth marketing fixes, NerdWallet IPO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/techcrunch-roundup-3-flavors-of-baas-growth-marketing-fixes-nerdwallet-ipo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/techcrunch-roundup-3-flavors-of-baas-growth-marketing-fixes-nerdwallet-ipo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 17:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banking-as-a-service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216880</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you're interested in submitting a post to TechCrunch, join a Twitter Spaces chat on Tuesday, October 19 to learn about what we're looking for.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Most of the people who poured into California during the Gold Rush have been long forgotten.</p>
<p>We remember Levi Strauss, however: Before he and Jacob Davis patented those denim jeans, he sold shovels and other supplies to fortune-seekers.</p>
<p>Today’s banking-as-a-service startups are similarly placed — instead of digging for treasure in the crowded consumer financial services marketplace, BaaS companies offer fintech companies access to APIs, compliance tools and other software needed to move money around.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216880" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In recent weeks, Ryan Lawler has been mapping the landscape of BaaS companies. For his latest report, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/10/baas-served-three-ways-a-closer-look-at-a-rapidly-evolving-market/">he studied three different strategies</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Turnkey banking as a service</li>
<li>Playing matchmaker between banks and fintechs</li>
<li>Buying a bank to get into BaaS</li>
</ul>
<p>“If you’re looking to spin up a new fintech app or want to add banking, debit cards or other financial services to your existing business, knowing how each of these competitors is positioned to work with customers and bank partners is key,” he writes.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><i>Full TechCrunch+ articles are only available to members<br />
<a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">Use discount code <strong>TCPLUSROUNDUP</strong></a> to save 20% off a one- or two-year subscription</i></p>
<hr />
<p>On Tuesday, October 19, at 3 p.m. PT/6 p.m. ET, I&#8217;m hosting a Twitter Spaces chat to discuss TechCrunch&#8217;s guest contributor program.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re interested in submitting a post to TechCrunch or TechCrunch+, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/domain-experts-wanted-submit-your-guest-articles-to-extra-crunch/">please read our guidelines</a> and join the conversation. Bring your questions!</p>
<p>For a reminder, please <a href="https://twitter.com/TechCrunch">follow @techcrunch on Twitter</a>.</p>
<p>Thanks very much for reading!</p>
<p>Walter Thompson<br />
Senior Editor, TechCrunch+<br />
<a href="https://www.twitter.com/yourprotagonist">@yourprotagonist</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Dyj0kqVqK0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/10/baas-served-three-ways-a-closer-look-at-a-rapidly-evolving-market/">BaaS served three ways: A closer look at a rapidly evolving market</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BaaS served three ways: A closer look at a rapidly evolving market&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/10/baas-served-three-ways-a-closer-look-at-a-rapidly-evolving-market/embed/#?secret=Dyj0kqVqK0" data-secret="Dyj0kqVqK0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>How I went from a college dorm brainstorm to leading edtech</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2216382" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216382" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2216382" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1340061313.jpg" alt="student dormitory room with bed, desk &amp; chair" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1340061313.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1340061313.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1340061313.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1340061313.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1340061313.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1340061313.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2216382" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Catherine+McQueen" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Catherine McQueen <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Earlier this year, note-sharing network StuDocu raised a $50 million Series B, but Marnix Broer, the company’s CEO, says he didn’t initially intend to co-found an edtech startup.</p>
<p>“It was more of a project to create a tool that we could use while studying in school,” he writes in a TechCrunch+ guest post that explains how the company scaled up from storing notes on a USB thumb drive to serving more than 15 million users.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nqQld4ey7T"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/how-i-went-from-a-college-dorm-brainstorm-to-leading-edtech/">How I went from a college dorm brainstorm to leading edtech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How I went from a college dorm brainstorm to leading edtech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/how-i-went-from-a-college-dorm-brainstorm-to-leading-edtech/embed/#?secret=nqQld4ey7T" data-secret="nqQld4ey7T" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Selling into the enterprise: How Slack and other startups get it wrong</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2029281" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2029281" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2029281" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1148108261.jpg" alt="Conceptual illustration of a bird pulling at a graph that resembles a worm depicting struggle." width="1024" height="805" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1148108261.jpg 1953w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1148108261.jpg?resize=150,118 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1148108261.jpg?resize=300,236 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1148108261.jpg?resize=768,604 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1148108261.jpg?resize=680,534 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1148108261.jpg?resize=1536,1207 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1148108261.jpg?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2029281" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Fanatic+StudioGary+WatersSCIENCE+PHOTO+LIBRARY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fanatic Studio/Gary Waters/SCIENCE PHOTO LIBRARY <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Going up against large enterprise companies may be daunting for a startup, but Scribe CEO and co-founder Jennifer Smith says you’re never too small to start.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Much to their detriment, many early-stage companies wait too long to spin up strategies for competing with industry leaders, she writes. One example: 12 years after its founding, Slack exited to Salesforce for $27.2 billion.</p>
<p>“The question is, if Slack had considered selling into the enterprise sooner, could it have survived as an independent public company?”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wN8UMHcPPN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/selling-into-the-enterprise-how-slack-and-other-startups-get-it-wrong/">Selling into the enterprise: How Slack and other startups get it wrong</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Selling into the enterprise: How Slack and other startups get it wrong&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/selling-into-the-enterprise-how-slack-and-other-startups-get-it-wrong/embed/#?secret=wN8UMHcPPN" data-secret="wN8UMHcPPN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>NerdWallet’s IPO filing reveals high-margin content business, accelerating marketing spend</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996009" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996009" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996009" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRN.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996009" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>A casual observer might assume that NerdWallet was a fintech company with a strong marketing game, but after perusing the company’s S-1, Alex Wilhelm concluded that it is “essentially a weaponized content play.”</p>
<p>In his analysis for The Exchange, he looked at how well NerdWallet has fared during the pandemic, its profitability, growing revenue, “and how the company manages to stay trustworthy, a question that we’ll address through the lens of editorial independence.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5HtzjhWSQ2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/nerdwallets-ipo-filing-reveals-high-margin-content-business-accelerating-marketing-spend/">NerdWallet&#8217;s IPO filing reveals high-margin content business, accelerating marketing spend</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;NerdWallet&#8217;s IPO filing reveals high-margin content business, accelerating marketing spend&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/nerdwallets-ipo-filing-reveals-high-margin-content-business-accelerating-marketing-spend/embed/#?secret=5HtzjhWSQ2" data-secret="5HtzjhWSQ2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Fintech founders can learn a lesson about frugality from these industry leaders</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2215583" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2215583" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2215583" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-94989168.jpg" alt="US Paper Money Flying out of Man's Hand" width="1024" height="766" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-94989168.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-94989168.jpg?resize=150,112 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-94989168.jpg?resize=300,224 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-94989168.jpg?resize=768,574 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-94989168.jpg?resize=680,509 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-94989168.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2215583" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Jeffrey+Coolidge" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jeffrey Coolidge <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Dave Mullen, a fintech-focused investor with SVB Capital, takes a look at how well leading fintech firms are allocating their mountains of cash.</p>
<p>“There are now a slew of fintech startups approaching or far surpassing $10 billion in value … so we can glean some insight into their capital allocation strategies by considering how they have spent to achieve their position in the ecosystem,” he writes.</p>
<p>In a guest column, he unpacks data from Coinbase, Robinhood, Affirm, Chime, Marqeta and others, offering suggestions to founders in the fintech space.</p>
<p>“Dollars may buy growth, but they can’t guarantee a good business.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DmnVf197rw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/08/fintech-founders-can-learn-a-lesson-about-frugality-from-these-industry-leaders/">Fintech founders can learn a lesson about frugality from these industry leaders</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fintech founders can learn a lesson about frugality from these industry leaders&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/08/fintech-founders-can-learn-a-lesson-about-frugality-from-these-industry-leaders/embed/#?secret=DmnVf197rw" data-secret="DmnVf197rw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Private equity is ready to take MSP consolidation to the next level</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2215529" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2215529" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2215529" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1174180848.jpg" alt="A combination of drinking straws in two cups" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1174180848.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1174180848.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1174180848.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1174180848.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1174180848.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1174180848.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2215529" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Richard+Drury" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Richard Drury <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Good news: Businesses of all stripes are digitizing their operations faster than ever before, creating huge advantages for companies that start the work now.</p>
<p>Bad news: Many technical workers are already looking for new jobs, and companies must compete to find the right people who can build robust, secure IT environments.</p>
<p>Managed services providers (MSPs) are filling the gap, and private equity firms are paying attention.</p>
<p>“MSPs have all the ingredients that private equity loves,” write Mike McGill and Kevin Jolley of Cowen and Company, LLC.</p>
<p>“A strong demand trend, low risk of obsolescence, a ‘sticky’ service that attracts long-term customers and high recurring revenues, strong cash flow margins and a relatively ‘asset-light’ business.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Fr3P20WA7m"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/08/private-equity-is-ready-to-take-msp-consolidation-to-the-next-level/">Private equity is ready to take MSP consolidation to the next level</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Private equity is ready to take MSP consolidation to the next level&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/08/private-equity-is-ready-to-take-msp-consolidation-to-the-next-level/embed/#?secret=Fr3P20WA7m" data-secret="Fr3P20WA7m" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>5 common growth marketing mistakes startups make</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2215229" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2215229" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2215229" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-72724308.jpg" alt="Red and blue darts in wall around red, white and blue dart board" width="1024" height="766" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-72724308.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-72724308.jpg?resize=150,112 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-72724308.jpg?resize=300,224 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-72724308.jpg?resize=768,574 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-72724308.jpg?resize=680,509 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-72724308.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2215229" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Jeffrey+Coolidge" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jeffrey Coolidge <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>We don’t run many articles that call out mistakes or describe dysfunctional processes; most of us have a fairly good handle on what’s going wrong at any given moment, so we focus on solutions.</p>
<p>With that in mind, growth marketer Jonathan Martinez shared a guest post with strategies for tackling these endemic issues:</p>
<ul>
<li>Low testing velocity</li>
<li>Reliance on incorrect measurements</li>
<li>Focusing only on top-of-funnel traffic</li>
<li>Lack of incrementality</li>
<li>Insufficient product-growth integration</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZL0vGhyEdL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/08/5-common-growth-marketing-mistakes-startups-make/">5 common growth marketing mistakes startups make</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 common growth marketing mistakes startups make&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/08/5-common-growth-marketing-mistakes-startups-make/embed/#?secret=ZL0vGhyEdL" data-secret="ZL0vGhyEdL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Venture capital is going to need a record-breaking run of IPOs to clear its own decks</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996008" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996008" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996008" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996008" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Global venture capital is flowing so freely, there are unicorn herds in more regions than ever before.</p>
<p>“Which, in turn, boosts the scale of unexited private-market value that will eventually need to exit,” writes Alex Wilhelm in this morning’s The Exchange.</p>
<p>“And with some U.S. tech giants limiting acquisitions as a way of playing defense against antitrust concerns, there is an implicit expectation that the IPO market will eventually have to make room for a stampede of unicorn debuts.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jS88DpKOcd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/venture-capital-is-going-to-need-a-record-breaking-run-of-ipos-to-clear-its-own-decks/">Venture capital is going to need a record-breaking run of IPOs to clear its own decks</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Venture capital is going to need a record-breaking run of IPOs to clear its own decks&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/venture-capital-is-going-to-need-a-record-breaking-run-of-ipos-to-clear-its-own-decks/embed/#?secret=jS88DpKOcd" data-secret="jS88DpKOcd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/techcrunch-roundup-3-flavors-of-baas-growth-marketing-fixes-nerdwallet-ipo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216880</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Watch Blue Origin launch 4-person crew, including William Shatner, to space live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/watch-blue-origin-launch-4-person-crew-including-william-shatner-to-space-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/watch-blue-origin-launch-4-person-crew-including-william-shatner-to-space-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 17:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216857</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[﻿ Barely three months after Blue Origin successfully sent its first crewed rocket to orbit, it&#8217;s poised for another launch on Wednesday, October 13. This time, instead of Blue&#8217;s founder and CEO Jeff Bezos headlining the flight, the company will be sending 90-year old William Shatner, who is set to become the oldest person to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FAcufhwjR2I" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></p>
<div class="article-content">
<p>Barely three months after Blue Origin successfully sent its first crewed rocket to orbit, it&#8217;s poised for another launch on Wednesday, October 13. This time, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/blue-origins-new-shepard-carries-jeff-bezos-and-three-crew-members-to-space-and-back/">instead of Blue&#8217;s founder and CEO Jeff Bezos headlining</a> the flight, the company will be sending 90-year old William Shatner, who is set to become the oldest person to go to space.</p>
<p>The NS-18 mission is set to take-off from Launch Site One, the company&#8217;s sprawling launch facility near Van Horn, in the western part of Texas. The crew will be flying in the company&#8217;s New Shepard rocket. The launch was originally scheduled to fly on October 12, but Blue Orign&#8217;s Mission Operations decided on Sunday to push it back by one day due to forecasted high winds.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216857" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
</div>
<p>Meet the crew of New Shepard&#8217;s NS-18 mission:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/william-shatner-to-fly-on-blue-origins-next-human-spaceflight-on-october-12/">William Shatner</a>, the actor arguably best-known for having played Captain James T. Kirk on “Star Trek.”</li>
<li>Audrey Powers, who serves as the company’s vice president of New Shepard Mission &amp; Flight Operations. She’s been with Blue since 2013, and served as its deputy general counsel before leaving the mission and flight operations team for the company’s New Shepard rocket.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/dcvc-partner-and-planet-labs-co-founder-chris-boshuizen-bound-for-space-on-blue-origins-second-human-flight/">Chris Boshuizen</a>, co-founder of Planet Labs and current partner at venture capital firm DCVC.</li>
<li>Glen de Vries, co-founder of the clinical trial software company Medidata Solutions. He’s also the vice chair of life sciences and healthcare at Dassault <span class="m_-1800835828865331381spellingerror">Systèmes, a French software company that acquired Medidata in 2019. </span></li>
</ul>
<div class="article-content">
<p>The launch livestream above is set to begin at around 5:30 AM PT (8:30 AM ET) on October 13, with the launch scheduled to take place roughly one hour after.</p>
<p>Crew member Boshuizen joined us <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/3-vcs-discuss-space-junk-and-what-else-theyre-betting-on-right-now/">last year at TC Sessions: Space</a>; the next event is coming up in December — still plenty of time to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/">grab your tickets</a>.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/watch-blue-origin-launch-4-person-crew-including-william-shatner-to-space-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216857</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coinbase is launching its own NFT platform to take on OpenSea</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/coinbase-is-launching-its-own-nft-platform-to-take-on-opensea/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/coinbase-is-launching-its-own-nft-platform-to-take-on-opensea/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 17:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OpenSea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[player]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216849</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Coinbase is readying the launch of an NFT marketplace that will compete with existing major players in the space like OpenSea, debuting a user waitlist for the desktop product that it hopes to launch by the end of the year. Coinbase has limited details to share on its upcoming platform, but notes in a blog [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Coinbase is <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/nft/announce">readying the launch</a> of an NFT marketplace that will compete with existing major players in the space like OpenSea, debuting a user <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/nft/announce">waitlist</a> for the desktop product that it hopes to launch by the end of the year.</p>
<p>Coinbase has limited details to share on its upcoming platform, but notes in a blog post that they hope to more deeply integrate social features into the platform, &#8220;<span class="il">Coinbase</span> NFT will make minting, purchasing, showcasing, and discovering NFTs easier than ever. We’re making NFTs more accessible by building intuitive interfaces that put the complexity behind the scenes. We’re adding social features that open new avenues for conversation &amp; discovery.&#8221;</p>
<p>Even as Bitcoin inches closer to the all-time-high it was flirting with when the Coinbase direct listing occurred, Coinbase&#8217;s stock has still failed to keep pace with the rebounding growth of some of the most popular coins in the space, now down some 27% since its direct listing in April. The exchange simultaneously has regulators breathing down their neck, with the SEC recently threatening to sue the company over their Lend yields product, which they later canceled the launch of. Coinbase is also dealing with a crowding competitive landscape stateside for buying and selling crypto as exchanges like Robinhood build out deeper support for crypto.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216849" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2216908" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216908" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2216908" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/coinbasenft3.png" alt="" width="1024" height="633" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/coinbasenft3.png 5216w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/coinbasenft3.png?resize=150,93 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/coinbasenft3.png?resize=300,186 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/coinbasenft3.png?resize=768,475 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/coinbasenft3.png?resize=680,421 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/coinbasenft3.png?resize=1536,950 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/coinbasenft3.png?resize=2048,1267 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/coinbasenft3.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2216908" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image credit</strong>: Coinbase</p></div></p>
<p>Coinbase NFT could open up a major revenue source to the now-public company, assuming that NFTs continue to court investor interest from those looking for high-priced digital collectibles and art. After spiking earlier this year and again in August, the NFT market is showing more resiliency than many expected but is still seeing even much broader swings than already-volatile cryptocurrency prices. OpenSea saw a record $3.4 billion in transaction volume in August.</p>
<p>The company is launching with support for the Ethereum blockchain, which isn&#8217;t a very surprising place to start an NFT rollout, but Coinbase notably won&#8217;t be integrating with any Layer-2 scaling networks at launch, meaning Coinbase NFT users will still potentially be paying hefty gas fees and dealing with many of the scalability issues of mainnet Ethereum at launch. Coinbase says in a blog post that it will eventually offer &#8220;multi-chain&#8221; support on Coinbase NFT, but is launching with support for ERC-721 and ERC-1155 Ethereum standards. Competitor OpenSea recently launched support for significantly lower-priced transactions leveraging the Polygon network.</p>
<p>OpenSea is the dominant power in the space, but is far from the only player that Coinbase will have to compete with. Rivals like Binance and FTX have also announced recent entries into the NFT marketplace ecosystem. While many crypto investors see NFTs as just scratching the surface of their potential, Coinbase is launching much later than some of its soon-to-be competitors. Nevertheless, given Coinbase&#8217;s name recognition in the consumer crypto world, this is likely going to be a big launch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="emvPf25fcZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/20/following-sec-lawsuit-threat-coinbase-cancels-launch-of-lend-product/">Following SEC lawsuit threat, Coinbase cancels launch of &#8216;Lend&#8217; product</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Following SEC lawsuit threat, Coinbase cancels launch of &#8216;Lend&#8217; product&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/20/following-sec-lawsuit-threat-coinbase-cancels-launch-of-lend-product/embed/#?secret=emvPf25fcZ" data-secret="emvPf25fcZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/coinbase-is-launching-its-own-nft-platform-to-take-on-opensea/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216849</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Airbyte launches a hosted version of its integration platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/airbyte-launches-a-hosted-version-of-its-integration-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/airbyte-launches-a-hosted-version-of-its-integration-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 16:35:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[access management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbyte]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer products]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[database]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Looker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pricing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Airbyte, the well-funded open source data integration startup, always made it easy for data teams to set up their ELT (extract, load and transform) pipelines, but until now, that meant self-hosting and managing the service, with all the complications that come with that. Today, the company announced the official launch of Airbyte Cloud, a hosted [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://airbyte.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Airbyte</a>, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/airbyte-announces-26m-series-a-for-open-source-data-connector-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">well-funded</a> open source data integration startup, always made it easy for data teams to set up their ELT (extract, load and transform) pipelines, but until now, that meant self-hosting and managing the service, with all the complications that come with that. Today, the company announced the official launch of Airbyte Cloud, a hosted service that takes all of the features of the open source version and adds hosting and management, on top of a number of additional support options and enterprise features like access management for teams (though single sign-on support is currently still listed as &#8220;coming soon&#8221;).</p>
<p>Currently, more than 6,000 companies use Airbyte in some form or another. That&#8217;s up from only 250 at the end of January. Over the course of the year, the company has also taken on a seed and Series A round, for a total of just over $31 million in funding. The fact that there were only two months between the seed and Series A round is a pretty good indication of how hot this space is.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2216843" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/airbyte-ui-for-your-integration-pipelines.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216843" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2216843" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/airbyte-ui-for-your-integration-pipelines.png" alt="" width="1024" height="644" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/airbyte-ui-for-your-integration-pipelines.png 1230w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/airbyte-ui-for-your-integration-pipelines.png?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/airbyte-ui-for-your-integration-pipelines.png?resize=300,189 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/airbyte-ui-for-your-integration-pipelines.png?resize=768,483 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/airbyte-ui-for-your-integration-pipelines.png?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/airbyte-ui-for-your-integration-pipelines.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2216843" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Airbyte</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216779" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>And talking about money, Airbyte also decided to mix up its pricing model a bit with Airbyte Cloud. Instead of volume-based pricing, which used to be somewhat of the norm of these kinds of services, the team decided to opt for charging for the compute time these jobs take.</p>
<p>Ideally, this takes away at least some of the friction that is often associated with these kinds of workloads. Traditionally, the Airbyte team argues, enterprises use multiple systems like Fivetran to connect to the most common API sources and internally developed scripts the data engineering teams build for their one-off use cases &#8212; and then a system for database replication on top of that.</p>
<p>&#8220;We wanted to really commoditize and solve the data integration problem,&#8221; Airbyte COO and co-founder John Lafleur told me when I asked about the pricing model. &#8220;The only way to do that is really through an infrastructure-type pricing model, like Snowflake: buy credits, consume these credits based on the hours of compute. At that point, because your database replication throughput is very high, it makes it possible. That&#8217;s why we went with compute.&#8221;</p>
<p>As Airbyte CEO and co-founder Michel Tricot added, this also means that businesses can now think about pricing for virtually all of their data services in the same compute-centric way.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Currently, Airbyte features about <a href="https://docs.airbyte.io/integrations">130 connectors</a> to services that range from consumer products like Instagram to BI systems like Google&#8217;s Looker and virtually every major database system. As the team noted, a lot of customers also use Airbyte&#8217;s open source code to build their own custom connectors. In addition, there are now also vendors who build connectors for their own customers and the team is looking at how it can incentivize its community to maintain connectors over time through the use of some form of revenue share.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kWGln2hTDO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/airbyte-announces-26m-series-a-for-open-source-data-connector-platform/">Airbyte announces $26M Series A for open-source data connector platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Airbyte announces $26M Series A for open-source data connector platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/airbyte-announces-26m-series-a-for-open-source-data-connector-platform/embed/#?secret=kWGln2hTDO" data-secret="kWGln2hTDO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/airbyte-launches-a-hosted-version-of-its-integration-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216779</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Astra completes investigation into August launch failure, aims for next attempt in October</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/astra-completes-investigation-into-august-launch-failure-aims-for-next-attempt-in-october/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/astra-completes-investigation-into-august-launch-failure-aims-for-next-attempt-in-october/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 16:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Astra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chris kemp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial launch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216842</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rocket launch startup Astra provided more details into its rather remarkable mission failure in August, during which the small launch vehicle hovered and drifted in the air before managing a brief vertical ascension. Even as it recounted the debacle, the company is ready to try again, opening the launch window for its next attempt on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Rocket launch startup Astra provided more details into its rather remarkable mission failure in August, during which the small launch vehicle hovered and drifted in the air before managing a brief vertical ascension. Even as it recounted the debacle, the company is ready to try again, opening the launch window for its next attempt on October 27.</p>
<p>This will be the fifth launch attempt for the company, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/rocket-startup-astra-is-going-public-vis-spac/">which recently went public</a> via a SPAC merger that injected it with around $500 million in cash. The rocket, dubbed “LV0007,” will carry a test payload for the U.S. Space Force.</p>
<p>This most recent flight on August 28 failed due to a propellant leakage, which caused the shutdown of one of the rocket’s engines, Astra chief Engineer Benjamin Lyon explained in a blog post. The rocket did manage to ascend as high as around thirty miles before the launch was terminated around 148 seconds after take-off. The company, along with the Federal Aviation Administration, conducted an investigation into the cause of the failure.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216842" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ROg7X99f85"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/30/astras-first-commercial-launch-fails-to-reach-orbit/">Astra&#8217;s first commercial launch fails to reach orbit</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Astra&#8217;s first commercial launch fails to reach orbit&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/30/astras-first-commercial-launch-fails-to-reach-orbit/embed/#?secret=ROg7X99f85" data-secret="ROg7X99f85" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“The issue we encountered was something we hadn’t seen before,” Lyon said. After it leaked, it seems that the first stage propellant distribution system became trapped between the rocket and the launcher. Exhaust from the other engines caused that trapped propellant to ignite, severing the electronic connections to the fuel pump and shutting down the engine less than one second after takeoff.</p>
<p>Lyon says the company has taken steps to ensure these issues do not recur on the next test flight, including tweaking the rocket-to-launcher design to ensure that even if leaks do occur, the two propellants will not mix. Astra also modified the propellant supply mechanism and improved other verification processes, he said. “Together, we believe these changes significantly reduce the likelihood of seeing a similar event in the future.”</p>
<p>LV0007 will take off from the company’s launch site in Kodiak, Alaska, with the launch window opening on October 27 through October 31. There is an additional backup window from November 5 to November 12.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Data from the two-and-a-half-minute flight provided valuable insights that we have incorporated into LV0007 and future launch vehicles,” Astra CEO Chris Kemp said. “Our team is looking forward to returning to flight and learning more about our launch system – consistent with our launch and learn philosophy.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/astra-completes-investigation-into-august-launch-failure-aims-for-next-attempt-in-october/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216842</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple is going &#8216;Unleashed&#8217; for an October 18 event</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/apple-is-going-unleashed-for-an-october-18-event/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/apple-is-going-unleashed-for-an-october-18-event/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 16:16:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216834</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hardware season isn&#8217;t over over yet. A day before Google&#8217;s big Pixel event, Apple&#8217;s getting one more (probably) swing at things with an &#8220;Unleashed&#8221; event on Monday, October 18. The company sent out invites for the announcement, which will once again be livestreamed from the company&#8217;s Cupertino headquarters. The event, which kicks off at 10AM [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hardware season isn&#8217;t over over yet. A day before Google&#8217;s big Pixel event, Apple&#8217;s getting one more (probably) swing at things with an &#8220;Unleashed&#8221; event on Monday, October 18. The company sent out invites for the announcement, which will once again be livestreamed from the company&#8217;s Cupertino headquarters.</p>
<p>The event, which kicks off at 10AM PT, comes just a smidge over a month after Apple&#8217;s last big event which brought a brand new iPhone and Apple Watch, among others. So, what does that leave? New Macs were the biggest question mark after the last event. The company is still in the midst of a two-year plan to upgrade all of its desktops and laptops to its in-house silicon. Perhaps we&#8217;ll be seeing that new MacBook Pro, with an upgraded version of last year&#8217;s M1 chip. A larger version of last year&#8217;s Arm-based iMac has been rumored, as well, along with a new Mac Mini.</p>
<p>Accessories like brand new AirPods also look like a reasonable possibility. So, what, precisely, constitutes &#8220;unleashed&#8221; in all of this? If the graphic is any indication, Apple&#8217;s invented some sort of warp speed space travel. Stay tuned.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216834" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/apple-is-going-unleashed-for-an-october-18-event/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216834</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Instagram is testing an in-app feature that will notify users of service outages</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/instagram-is-testing-an-in-app-feature-that-will-notify-users-of-service-outages/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/instagram-is-testing-an-in-app-feature-that-will-notify-users-of-service-outages/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 16:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mesenger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216806</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Instagram is testing a new feature that will notify users when the platform is experiencing an outage or technical issue. The notification will appear directly in users’ activity feeds. Instagram notes that it won’t send a notification every single time there is an outage, but if it sees that users “are confused and looking for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Instagram is testing a new feature that will notify users when the platform is experiencing an outage or technical issue. The notification will appear directly in users’ activity feeds. Instagram notes that it won’t send a notification every single time there is an outage, but if it sees that users “are confused and looking for answers,” it will determine if a notification would make things clearer.</p>
<p>The announcement comes as Facebook and its properties were hit with a lengthy outage <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-messenger-instagram-whatsapp-are-all-down/">last week on Monday</a> and again briefly <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/08/facebook-and-instagram-went-down-again-this-afternoon/">on Friday</a>. The company explained that both outages were caused by configuration changes but were unrelated.</p>
<p>“Through conversations with our community and extensive research, we know how confusing it can be when temporary issues happen on Instagram. When they impact engagement or distribution, we also know that it can lead people to think that the problems are unique to them, based on what they post. That lack of clarity can be frustrating, which is why we want it to be easier to understand what&#8217;s going on, directly from us,” Instagram said in a <a href="https://about.instagram.com/blog/announcements/instagram-outages-and-account-status">blog post.</a></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216806" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The new feature is a welcome addition to the app, as users will no longer have to wonder if the app isn’t loading because of an error on their end. Instagram is running the new test in the U.S. for the next few months. The company says it wants to start small with the feature and then expand it to more users if it makes sense to do so.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2216810" style="width: 571px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216810" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2216810" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-technical-issue-notification.jpeg" alt="" width="561" height="519" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-technical-issue-notification.jpeg 2474w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-technical-issue-notification.jpeg?resize=150,139 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-technical-issue-notification.jpeg?resize=300,277 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-technical-issue-notification.jpeg?resize=768,710 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-technical-issue-notification.jpeg?resize=680,629 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-technical-issue-notification.jpeg?resize=1536,1421 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-technical-issue-notification.jpeg?resize=2048,1894 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-technical-issue-notification.jpeg?resize=50,46 50w" sizes="(max-width: 561px) 100vw, 561px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2216810" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Instagram</p></div></p>
<p>Instagram also announced that it’s launching a new feature called ‘Account Status’ that will make it easier for people to know whether their account is at risk of being disabled. Instagram says the new tool will be a “one-stop shop to see what’s going with your account.” If users think Instagram has made a mistake with a post of theirs that was removed, they can appeal by selecting the “Request a Review” option directly within the tool.</p>
<p>The company plans to add more information to this tool to give users a better sense of how their content is being distributed and recommended across different parts of the app. Instagram says it will share more information about these two new features over time.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/instagram-is-testing-an-in-app-feature-that-will-notify-users-of-service-outages/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216806</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Atomic aims to give consumers more control over their income with payroll-connecting APIs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/atomic-aims-to-give-consumers-more-control-over-their-income-with-payroll-connecting-apis/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/atomic-aims-to-give-consumers-more-control-over-their-income-with-payroll-connecting-apis/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 16:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atomic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neobanks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plaid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Series A]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216403</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fintech startup Atomic announced this morning that it has closed a $22 million Series A. Core Innovation Capital led the round, which saw participation from preceding investors. The company has raised just under $39 million to date. The company&#8217;s API-delivered product, which focuses on payroll data, helps power a number of fintech startups that we [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Fintech startup <a href="https://atomic.financial/">Atomic</a> announced this morning that it has closed a $22 million Series A. <a href="http://corevc.com/">Core Innovation Capital</a> led the round, which saw participation from preceding investors. The company has raised just under $39 million to date.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s API-delivered product, which focuses on payroll data, helps power a number of fintech startups that we track &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/30/upstart-banking-company-dave-is-now-worth-1-billion-as-norwest-puts-in-50-million/">Dave</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/who-needs-a-baas-partner-anyway/">Bond</a>, among others &#8212; making it an interesting company to dig into.</p>
<p>Atomic&#8217;s APIs allow consumers to connect their income to different services, helping them set up direct deposit at a neobank, for example. Other use cases include income and employment verification that is simpler for workers.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216403" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company&#8217;s head of markets, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lindsay-crusan-davis/">Lindsay Davis,</a> told TechCrunch in an interview that her company wants to &#8220;unlock the power of the paycheck.&#8221;</p>
<p>Notably, the company does not currently compete with Plaid, perhaps the best-known provider of financial APIs, according to Davis.</p>
<p>Plaid&#8217;s products are used for linking consumer banking accounts to financial services and products. In contrast, Atomic focuses on income streams, allowing them to be partially or completely diverted to new financial buckets, or simply made observable to other parties with user permission for verification purposes.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Atomic charges corporate customers for income and employment verification services on a usage basis, and for its direct deposit product in a more SaaS-like manner. Davis added that some customers bundle the two services together, underscoring that Atomic&#8217;s business model is a blend of both on-demand and subscription pricing.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RqwQHyRr9I"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/10/baas-served-three-ways-a-closer-look-at-a-rapidly-evolving-market/">BaaS served three ways: A closer look at a rapidly evolving market</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BaaS served three ways: A closer look at a rapidly evolving market&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/10/baas-served-three-ways-a-closer-look-at-a-rapidly-evolving-market/embed/#?secret=RqwQHyRr9I" data-secret="RqwQHyRr9I" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Thinking broadly, a cohort of fintech startups are building business products that may provide consumers with more control over their money. Businesses are willing to pay for their services as they can lessen friction to bring new funds onto their own platforms. That neobanks and other financial services that compete with traditional banking companies are paying up to help end-users make provider choices is not a surprise. The result of that work is fintech making &#8212; to a degree &#8212; the financial world a bit more amenable to consumer control.</p>
<h2>Money</h2>
<p>TechCrunch asked the company why it decided to raise its Series A now &#8212; a question that we&#8217;ve added to our regular arsenal thanks to increased round pre-emption by investors; gone are the days when startups were expected to reach a certain revenue threshold to raise one round type or another.</p>
<p>Davis said that, in her view, companies are ready to raise a Series A when they have both have a product in market and customer traction, so it made sense for Atomic to raise this particular round now.</p>
<p>She added that her company was offered more capital last year, but that it wasn&#8217;t ready to take on the funds. But with market demand demonstrated for Atomic&#8217;s direct deposit product, she explained, and a few preemptive term sheets, the startup decided that now was the right time.</p>
<p>Atomic has around 55 staffers today, a figure that it is looking to rapidly expand. The company has 20 open roles, Davis noted.</p>
<p>The company has lots of white space around its current business to expand into. With income verification, TechCrunch will be curious to see whether Atomic eventually digs into the credit scoring market. Credit scores in the United States <a href="https://medium.com/commonfuture/why-credit-scores-are-racist-da109fcfb300">are a mess</a>, to be polite. And we&#8217;re looking for the startup that will take on the traditional agencies in charge of deciding how worthy you are of loans and other financial products.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s see if that winds up being Atomic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/atomic-aims-to-give-consumers-more-control-over-their-income-with-payroll-connecting-apis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216403</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google files a counterclaim in Epic Games lawsuit, saying it&#8217;s owed financial relief</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/google-files-a-counterclaim-in-epic-games-lawsuit-saying-its-owed-financial-relief/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/google-files-a-counterclaim-in-epic-games-lawsuit-saying-its-owed-financial-relief/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 15:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Epic Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fortnite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216771</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the Apple v. Epic Games lawsuit goes under appeal, Google on Monday afternoon filed an answer and counterclaim in the Epic Games&#8217; antitrust litigation against the company. The tech giant and Android maker denies Epic&#8217;s allegations of antitrust behavior and instead says that it&#8217;s owed relief, as Epic Games breached the Google Play Developer [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As the Apple v. Epic Games <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/epic-games-appeals-last-weeks-ruling-in-antitrust-battle-with-apple/">lawsuit</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/apple-appeals-the-epic-games-ruling-and-asks-to-put-ordered-app-store-changes-on-hold/">goes under appeal,</a> Google on Monday afternoon filed an answer and counterclaim in the Epic Games&#8217; antitrust litigation against the company. The tech giant and Android maker denies Epic&#8217;s allegations of antitrust behavior and instead says that it&#8217;s owed relief, as Epic Games breached the Google Play Developer Distribution Agreement (DDA) by allowing Fortnite players who download the app through Google Play to use Epic&#8217;s own payment processing technology.</p>
<p>This situation is similar to what took place on the App Store, where Epic Games updated its app to workaround App Store policies, and then facilitated payments through its own payments system, in violation of its legal contract with Apple. The court&#8217;s decision in Apple&#8217;s case was that Epic owed financial relief to Apple, to the tune <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/09/13/epic-games-pays-apple-6-million/">of $6 million dollars</a>.</p>
<p>Epic Games did much of the same thing on Google Play, the counterclaim alleges. Last year, Epic submitted a build of Fortnite to Google Play which used Epic&#8217;s own direct payments system and not Google Play Billing. This submission was immediately rejected for failing to comply with Google&#8217;s policies. Epic then submitted a compliant version in April 2020, which Google now describes as &#8220;an act of deception designed to provoke litigation.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216771" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The new version had concealed Epic&#8217;s payment system in an update that was sent to both Apple and Google&#8217;s app stores. This would allow Epic to switch over to its own payment system by applying a server-side configuration change, or &#8220;hotfix,&#8221; without Google&#8217;s knowledge.</p>
<p>That switched was flipped on August 13, 2020. It allowed Fortnite users to choose between Google Play Billing and Epic&#8217;s own direct payments system. This move was meant to trigger the game&#8217;s rejection from the app stores, paying the way for Epic to pursue its planned litigation. Google said it notified Epic Games on the same day the hotfix was applied that it was in violation of the DDA, Google&#8217;s Malicious Behavior Policy, and the Google Play Billing Policy, and removed Fortnite from Google Play. However, it did not disable Epic&#8217;s account so the game maker could resubmit a compliant version.</p>
<p>However, Android users who had downloaded the game from Google Play could still use Epic&#8217;s own payments system even after the app was pulled down, allowing Epic to evade its contractually obligated service fee to Google, the counterclaim states. Google is asking the court to award restitution of this loss of feeds, in addition to other damages, attorney&#8217;s fees, interest, and any other relief the court deems necessary.</p>
<p>&#8220;Epic, a multibillion-dollar company backed by two of the world’s largest video game developers, has profited immensely from the safe, secure platform provided by Google Play, a platform for which it pays a fee equivalent or less than that charged by other major platform providers,&#8221; the counterclaim states. &#8220;Not satisfied with those immense profits, it entered into a legal agreement with Google with which it never intended to comply, deceiving Google and concealing its true intentions to provoke a legal and public relations confrontation that continues to this day. Its actions have put its own users at risk, have harmed Google, and are deserving of relief from this Court,&#8221; it says.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Epic Games has no further comment on the new filing.</p>
<p>However, Epic&#8217;s position has been that Apple and Google&#8217;s requirement to use their own in-app payment systems exclusively is a monopolistic practice that disadvantages developers. In Apple&#8217;s case, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/10/apple-prohibited-from-blocking-outside-payment-in-epic-ruling/">the court agreed</a> that Apple should not block developers from sharing a link to other payment methods inside their own app or communicating to customers. It did not declare Apple a monopoly.</p>
<p>But Google&#8217;s situation is a bit different as Android already allows for sideloading apps &#8212; that means there&#8217;s another method of reaching Android users outside Google Play, making an antitrust claim more difficult.</p>
<p>Google has also filed its answer with the state&#8217;s attorney general, developer, and consumer cases.</p>
<p style="margin: 12px auto 6px auto; font-family: Helvetica,Arial,Sans-serif; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; font-size: 14px; line-height: normal; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; -x-system-font: none; display: block;"><a style="text-decoration: underline;" title="View 2021.10.11 (000183.03) Redacted Version of Defendants' Answers, Defenses, And Counterclaims to Ep on Scribd" href="https://www.scribd.com/document/531886292/2021-10-11-000183-03-Redacted-Version-of-Defendants-Answers-Defenses-And-Counterclaims-to-Ep#from_embed">2021.10.11 (000183.03) Redacted Version of Defendants&#8217; Answers, Defenses, And Counterclaims to Ep</a> by <a style="text-decoration: underline;" title="View TechCrunch's profile on Scribd" href="https://www.scribd.com/publisher/17551504/TechCrunch#from_embed">TechCrunch</a> on Scribd</p>
<p><iframe id="doc_10239" class="scribd_iframe_embed" title="2021.10.11 (000183.03) Redacted Version of Defendants' Answers, Defenses, And Counterclaims to Ep" src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/531886292/content?start_page=1&amp;view_mode=scroll&amp;access_key=key-8f6e4VjLzR1JhBEhC4U4" width="100%" height="600" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" data-auto-height="false" data-aspect-ratio="0.7729220222793488"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/google-files-a-counterclaim-in-epic-games-lawsuit-saying-its-owed-financial-relief/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216771</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>VanMoof teases new high-speed electric bike</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/vanmoof-teases-new-high-speed-electric-bike/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/vanmoof-teases-new-high-speed-electric-bike/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 15:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-bike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric bike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VanMoof]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VanMoof V]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[E-bike manufacturer VanMoof recently raised a $128 million funding round. And the company is already using some of that cash to develop a brand new product — the VanMoof V. This is a new product in the VanMoof lineup, a high-speed bike. The VanMoof V isn’t available just yet. Instead, the company teased the new [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">E-bike manufacturer <a href="https://www.vanmoof.com">VanMoof</a> recently raised a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/vanmoof-raises-128-million-to-become-the-worlds-leading-e-bike-brand/">$128 million funding round</a>. And the company is already using some of that cash to develop a brand new product — the <a href="https://www.vanmoof.com/en-FR/vanmoof-v">VanMoof V</a>. This is a new product in the VanMoof lineup, a high-speed bike.</p>
<p>The VanMoof V isn’t available just yet. Instead, the company teased the new bike in a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a7ymwpXFxtg">live YouTube video</a>. The company plans to release the VanMoof V by the end of 2022. It should cost approximately <a href="https://www.vanmoof.com/en-US/vanmoof-v">$3,598</a>, <a href="https://www.vanmoof.com/en-FR/vanmoof-v">€3,498</a> or <a href="https://www.vanmoof.com/en-GB/vanmoof-v">£2,998</a> according to the landing pages on VanMoof’s website.</p>
<p>What you get for that price is an electric bike with two motors — one in the front wheel and one in the rear wheel. There are two suspension systems at the front and at the back of the vehicle to help you with uneven streets. The VanMoof V also features thick tires for increased safety.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216791" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2216797" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216797" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-2.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" class="size-full wp-image-2216797" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-2.jpg 3128w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-2.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-2.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-2.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-2.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-2.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-2.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-2.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2216797" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> VanMoof</p></div></p>
<p>According to the YouTube video, the bike can reach a top speed of 60 km/h (37 mph). But if you have an e-bike already, you know that there are regulations when it comes to motor assistance for bikes. In Europe, an e-bike cannot travel faster than 25 km/h (15.5 mph). In the U.S., that limitation depends on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electric_bicycle_laws">each state</a> but is still lower than the VanMoof V top speed.</p>
<p>It doesn’t mean that you can’t ride faster than that. It means that the motor will stop assisting you if you reach the top speed of your jurisdiction. The company is already saying that the VanMoof V won’t help you break the law.</p>
<p>“When we first started imagining what the V could become, we very soon agreed it’s about a whole new approach to how we use the roads. The VanMoof V will have integrated speed settings to match your country’s regulations. However, this bike has the technology and capacity to hit speeds up to 60 kilometers per hour or 37 miles per hour. As it stands, local regulations across the world cap the top speed of this category. But in the long term, we need much bigger thinking,” VanMoof co-founder and CEO Ties Carlier said during the announcement.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“In our vision, current policy is limiting the adoption of this type of transportation. We’re calling for policies designed for people instead of cars. That’s why we will work with city governments to explore geofencing and push for modernized speed regulations,” he added.</p>
<p>In other words, the VanMoof V should be considered as a concept bike to share VanMoof’s vision, as well as a lobbying vehicle for policymakers around the world. The company had to share its plans in advance because you don’t need a two-wheel drive to reach 25 km/h.</p>
<p>Having said that, VanMoof is sending invitations to a group of VanMoof customers and crowdfunders. These invitations let you reserve a VanMoof V with a $20 reservation deposit. Reservations start today with a potential release date of late 2022.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2216798" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2216798" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-3.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" class="size-full wp-image-2216798" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-3.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-3.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-3.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-3.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-3.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-3.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-3.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/VanMoof-V-3.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2216798" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> VanMoof</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/vanmoof-teases-new-high-speed-electric-bike/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216791</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Olympus confirms US cyberattack, weeks after BlackMatter ransomware hit EMEA systems</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/olympus-confirms-us-cyberattack-weeks-after-blackmatter-ransomware-hit-emea-systems/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/olympus-confirms-us-cyberattack-weeks-after-blackmatter-ransomware-hit-emea-systems/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 15:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crimes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberattacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyberwarfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[olympus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[olympus corporation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216777</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Japanese technology giant Olympus has confirmed it was hit by a cyberattack over the weekend that forced it to shut down its IT systems in the U.S., Canada and Latin America. In a statement on its website, Olympus said it is “investigating a potential cybersecurity incident detected October 10” and is “currently working with the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Japanese technology giant <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/12/technology-giant-olympus-hit-by-blackmatter-ransomware/">Olympus</a> has confirmed it was hit by a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/cyberattack/">cyberattack</a> over the weekend that forced it to shut down its IT systems in the U.S., Canada and Latin America.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.olympus-global.com/news/2021/nr02217.html">a statement on its website</a>, Olympus said it is “investigating a potential cybersecurity incident detected October 10” and is “currently working with the highest priority to resolve this issue.”</p>
<p>“As part of the investigation and containment, we have suspended affected systems and have informed the relevant external partners. The current results of our investigation indicate the incident was contained to the Americas with no known impact to other regions.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216777" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“We are working with appropriate third parties on this situation and will continue to take all necessary measures to serve our customers and business partners in a secure way. Protecting our customers and partners and maintaining their trust in us is our highest priority. Our investigation is ongoing and we are committed to transparent disclosure and will continue to provide updates as new information becomes available.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s near-identical to a statement put out by Olympus last month following a cyberattack <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/12/technology-giant-olympus-hit-by-blackmatter-ransomware/">on its European, Middle East and Africa network</a>.</p>
<p>At the time of the attack, Olympus also said it was “investigating a potential cybersecurity incident.&#8221; A person with knowledge of the incident told TechCrunch that Olympus was recovering from a ransomware attack. A ransom note left behind on infected systems was also linked to the BlackMatter ransomware-as-a-service group.</p>
<p>Brett Callow, a ransomware expert and threat analyst at Emsisoft, told TechCrunch that given this latest incident occurred at the weekend — often when gangs often deploy ransomware, including holidays — increases the likelihood of a repeat attack. &#8220;And if it is ransomware, whether it’s BlackMatter again is impossible to say. It certainly could be, or the affiliate responsible for the attack on the EMEA operations could have chosen to deploy different ransomware this time,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>When reached, Olympus spokesperson Susan Scerbo did not have any immediate comment. We&#8217;ll update as we learn more about Olympus&#8217; security incident.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="H9pjsQZF4Z"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/12/technology-giant-olympus-hit-by-blackmatter-ransomware/">Technology giant Olympus hit by BlackMatter ransomware</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Technology giant Olympus hit by BlackMatter ransomware&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/12/technology-giant-olympus-hit-by-blackmatter-ransomware/embed/#?secret=H9pjsQZF4Z" data-secret="H9pjsQZF4Z" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/olympus-confirms-us-cyberattack-weeks-after-blackmatter-ransomware-hit-emea-systems/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216777</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>1Password&#8217;s new feature lets you safely share passwords using just a link</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/1passwords-new-feature-lets-you-safely-share-passwords-using-just-a-link/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/1passwords-new-feature-lets-you-safely-share-passwords-using-just-a-link/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 15:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1password]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2216769</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Password sharing in the workplace and at home is a common practice, but doing so securely can be tricky. 1Password aims to address that with this new login sharing feature.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Mariella Moon</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Mariella Moon is an associate editor at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/alphabets-wing-tests-drone-deliveries-from-shopping-center-rooftops-in-australia/">Alphabet&#8217;s Wing tests drone deliveries from shopping center rooftops in Australia</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/amazon-opens-its-first-4-star-store-outside-the-us/">Amazon opens its first 4-star store outside the US</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Password sharing in the workplace and at home is a common practice, but doing so securely can be tricky. <a href="https://www.engadget.com/1-password-8-mac-early-access-120012791.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="16" data-v9y="1">1Password</a> aims to address that with its new feature that gives you a way to share log-in credentials in a secure way even with people who don&#8217;t have an account with the service. It&#8217;s called <a href="https://blog.1password.com/psst-item-sharing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="17" data-v9y="1">Psst!</a>, which is short for Password Secure Sharing Tool, and it&#8217;s apparently one of the company&#8217;s most requested features.</p>
<p>Based on a <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/report-mismanaging-secrets-costs-companies-1-2m-annually-301317447.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="18" data-v9y="1">research</a> the company conducted, most workers reuse corporate credentials. Of those people, 36 percent admitted to sharing log-ins with other workers and clients via insecure channels, including emails, chat apps, spreadsheets, documents and texts. In another <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/report-40-of-parents-give-preschoolers-a-head-start-in-password-education-301194976.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1">survey</a>, 1Password found that most families share passwords between members and also use insecure methods, such as writing them down and messaging them to each other.</p>
<p>Psst! allows you to share credentials with anybody by generating a link with the information that other people can access, even if they don&#8217;t have a 1Password account. You can choose how long the link remains valid, from an hour to 30 days, after which it will automatically expire. You can also choose to share the credentials with anybody who has the link or with specific people only. If you choose the latter, the service will require the recipient to confirm their identity by verifying their email addresses before giving them access.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2216769" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The service has launched this new feature alongside its announcement that it now has over 100,000 business customers and that it&#8217;s growing its employee headcount to 500. Jeff Shiner, CEO of 1Password, said in a statement:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Having the ability to share passwords and other credentials outside of a business or family has been one of our most highly-requested features, and I’m very excited by today’s launch of Psst! as it helps keep everyone, not just 1Password customers, safe online. Crossing the 100,000 business customers mark is a clear indication that businesses understand the need to safeguard their passwords and other sensitive information online.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<figure>
<p><div style="width: 685px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fs.yimg.com%2Fos%2Fcreatr-uploaded-images%2F2021-10%2F8cf2eed0-2b4d-11ec-baf3-e764d13ffb03&amp;thumbnail=675%2C&amp;client=49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo&amp;signature=79144c4e9aefe53fdf52a5ed5635cc1d03b6ef90" alt="1Password" width="675" height="440" data-uuid="ccf4aac0-1aed-30cb-a6c6-90136d68a500" /><p class="wp-caption-text">1Password</p></div></figure>
<div><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/1-passwords-new-feature-will-let-you-securely-share-logins-with-anyone-130044719.html">Engadget</a>.</em></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/1passwords-new-feature-lets-you-safely-share-passwords-using-just-a-link/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2216769</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
