<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:59:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>BukuKas gets $50M from investors including DoorDash&#8217;s Gokul Rajaram and TransferWise founder Taavet Hinrikus</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/bukukas-gets-50m-from-investors-including-doordashs-gokul-rajaram-and-transferwise-co-founder-taavet-hinrikus/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/bukukas-gets-50m-from-investors-including-doordashs-gokul-rajaram-and-transferwise-co-founder-taavet-hinrikus/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 03:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BukuKas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital bookkeeping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MSMEs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMEs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2152782</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BukuKas, a startup focused on digitizing Indonesia’s small businesses, has raised $50 million in Series B funding. The round included participation from Gokul Rajaram, the DoorDash executive, and Taavet Hinrikus, co-founder and chief executive officer of TransferWise. This news comes just four months after BukuKas announced a $10 million Series A led by Sequoia Capital India. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2152786" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Photo-4-Krishnan-Lorenzo-and-BukuKas-Merchant.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2152786" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2152786" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Photo-4-Krishnan-Lorenzo-and-BukuKas-Merchant.png" alt="BukuKas co-founders Krishnan Menon (left) and Lorenzo Peracchione (right) with a BukuKas user" width="1024" height="574" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Photo-4-Krishnan-Lorenzo-and-BukuKas-Merchant.png 1075w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Photo-4-Krishnan-Lorenzo-and-BukuKas-Merchant.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Photo-4-Krishnan-Lorenzo-and-BukuKas-Merchant.png?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Photo-4-Krishnan-Lorenzo-and-BukuKas-Merchant.png?resize=768,431 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Photo-4-Krishnan-Lorenzo-and-BukuKas-Merchant.png?resize=680,381 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Photo-4-Krishnan-Lorenzo-and-BukuKas-Merchant.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2152786" class="wp-caption-text">BukuKas co-founders Krishnan Menon (left) and Lorenzo Peracchione (right) with a BukuKas user</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://bukukas.co.id/">BukuKas</a>, a startup focused on digitizing Indonesia’s small businesses, has raised $50 million in Series B funding. The round included participation from<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/27/pinterest-adds-doordash-exec-and-caviar-lead-gokul-rajaram-to-its-board/"> Gokul Rajaram,</a> the DoorDash executive, and Taavet Hinrikus, co-founder and chief executive officer of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/28/transferwise-five-unicorns/">TransferWise</a>.</p>
<p>This news comes just four months after BukuKas announced a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/bukukas-raises-10-million-led-by-sequoia-capital-india-to-build-a-end-to-end-software-stack-for-indonesian-smes/">$10 million Series A led by Sequoia Capital India</a>. BukuKas will use its Series B to hire for its engineering and product teams in Jakarta and Bangalore, and launch new services for merchants.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“We’ve been growing really fast and there was a lot of interest from some very good people,” chief executive officer Krishnan Menon told TechCrunch. “This is not a capital-need based raise, but more of a tactical raise and having the right people back us long term.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="snw7U8uUDt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/bukukas-raises-10-million-led-by-sequoia-capital-india-to-build-a-end-to-end-software-stack-for-indonesian-smes/">BukuKas raises $10 million led by Sequoia Capital India to build an &#8216;end-to-end software stack&#8217; for Indonesian SMEs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BukuKas raises $10 million led by Sequoia Capital India to build an &#8216;end-to-end software stack&#8217; for Indonesian SMEs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/bukukas-raises-10-million-led-by-sequoia-capital-india-to-build-a-end-to-end-software-stack-for-indonesian-smes/embed/#?secret=snw7U8uUDt" data-secret="snw7U8uUDt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>BukuKas was founded by Menon and chief operating officer Lorenzo Peracchione, who met while working at Lazada Indonesia. Since its launch as as a digital bookkeeping app in December 2019, BukuKas has added new features, including online payments and an e-commerce platform. The app has onboarded about 6.3 million businesses so far and now has a total of 3 million monthly active users. It claims its annualized bookkeeping transaction volume is $25.9 billion USD, or the equivalent of about 2.2% of Indonesia’s <a href="https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/NY.GDP.MKTP.KD.ZG?locations=ID">gross domestic product</a>.</p>
<p>According to Bank Indonesia, the country’s central bank, there are about <a href="https://jakartaglobe.id/context/govt-push-sme-to-use-online-marketplace-to-pave-way-into-international-market">60 million SMEs</a>, though Menon says that number may range from 55 million to 65 million. The majority still operate mostly offline, but the push to digitization began even before the COVID-19 pandemic. For example, the Indonesian government <a href="https://jakartaglobe.id/context/govt-push-sme-to-use-online-marketplace-to-pave-way-into-international-market/">launched a program two years ago with marketplace Blibi</a> to encourage more businesses to sell online, with the goal of helping more SMEs go global.</p>
<p>This means there is a growing roster of startups and services focused on helping small businesses go online. These include Y Combinator-backed <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/28/indonesian-fintech-startup-bukuwarung-gets-new-funding-to-add-financial-services-for-small-merchants/">BukuWarung</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/21/warung-pintar-raises-27-5m/">WarungPintar</a>, Grab’s Mitra GrabKios and wholesaler-focused <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/credibook-gets-1-5-million-to-help-indonesian-retail-wholesalers-digitize-their-finances/">CrediBook</a>. India-based Khatabook, another Sequoia Capital India portfolio company, l<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/indias-khatabook-raises-60-million-to-help-merchants-digitize-bookkeeping-and-accept-payments-online/">aunched BukuUang in Indonesia</a>, but has since pulled out of the market.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SyaRyIIuwd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/28/indonesian-fintech-startup-bukuwarung-gets-new-funding-to-add-financial-services-for-small-merchants/">Indonesian fintech startup BukuWarung gets new funding to add financial services for small merchants</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Indonesian fintech startup BukuWarung gets new funding to add financial services for small merchants&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/28/indonesian-fintech-startup-bukuwarung-gets-new-funding-to-add-financial-services-for-small-merchants/embed/#?secret=SyaRyIIuwd" data-secret="SyaRyIIuwd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“There’s obviously a macro shift that’s happening in the market right now. People are rushing to get digitized and people are coming out of a rough year. They started to realize ‘I need to upgrade,’ so there’s a rush to get digitized, to manage their money better, a movement to digital payments,” said Menon.</p>
<p>BukuKas’ goal is to become an end-to-end software stack for micro, small and medium enterprises and serve 20 million MSMEs by the end of 2022, with inventory management, invoicing, payment-related analytics and other tools. The company recently took several steps toward that goal. In April, it launched BukuKasPay for business owners to pay suppliers online or accept digital payments, including virtual bank accounts and e-wallets like OVO, Dana, GoPay, LinkAja and ShopeePay from customers. In September 2020, it acquired a digital ledger app called Catatan Keuangan Harian to expand its market share before launching an e-commerce platform called Tokko that enables MSMEs to set up online shops. About 1.3 million merchants have created shops using Tokko in the six months since its release.</p>
<p>Tokko focuses on merchants who find big marketplaces, like Tokopedia, too complicated, and want an alternative way to set up an online brand.</p>
<p>BukuKas’ users include warungs (small stores), fashion retailers, electronics stores, social commerce sellers and service providers. On average, its users make several thousand U.S. dollars per month in revenue, but some earn as high as tens of thousands of dollars.</p>
<p>The app is designed to work as a layer on top of WhatsApp. For example, many merchants allow customers to buy on credit, so they can use BukuKas to send automatic reminders through WhatsApp with a payment link. Businesses can also send invoices or take Tokko orders through WhatsApp. Menon said since many Indonesian merchants already relied on WhatsApp to communicate with suppliers and customers, this helps it onboard more users because they don’t have to make major changes to their operational routines. It also creates viral loops, as other businesses get payment reminders or invoices sent through BukuKas, and decide to try the app, too.</p>
<p>“Our thesis is very similar to what Square or Shopify did in the U.S. We keep merchants as the center of the universe, and we keep building solutions for them,” Menon said. “That can be software-related solutions like BukuKas’ early version and Tokko moving further into commerce. We’re moving further into banking solutions, so payments come first, and then actually building out the full banking suite. The end goal is if a merchant five years from now looks back and says, thanks to BukuKas I was able to adapt to the digital era, and sticks with us.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="r8wgwcp0Ht"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/credibook-gets-1-5-million-to-help-indonesian-retail-wholesalers-digitize-their-finances/">CrediBook gets $1.5 million to help Indonesian retail wholesalers digitize their finances</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;CrediBook gets $1.5 million to help Indonesian retail wholesalers digitize their finances&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/credibook-gets-1-5-million-to-help-indonesian-retail-wholesalers-digitize-their-finances/embed/#?secret=r8wgwcp0Ht" data-secret="r8wgwcp0Ht" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/bukukas-gets-50m-from-investors-including-doordashs-gokul-rajaram-and-transferwise-co-founder-taavet-hinrikus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2152782</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dott, Lime and Tier selected for London e-scooter trial</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/dott-lime-and-tier-selected-for-london-e-scooter-trial/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/dott-lime-and-tier-selected-for-london-e-scooter-trial/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 23:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[micromobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tier Mobility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153320</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Transport for London and London Councils have announced Dott, Lime and Tier Mobility as the winners of its prized e-scooter pilot, confirming last month’s suspicions based on job postings by the companies.  Last year, the government legalized e-scooter rental trials by local authorities, although private e-scooter riding is still illegal. This legislation spurred the launch of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Transport for London and London Councils have announced Dott, Lime and Tier Mobility as the winners of its prized e-scooter pilot, confirming </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/09/job-postings-hint-at-winners-of-nyc-and-london-e-scooter-pilots/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">last month’s suspicions based on job postings by the companies.</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p>Last year, <a class="c-link" href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/30/e-scooter-firms-get-the-green-light-to-start-trials-of-up-to-one-year-on-uk-streets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/30/e-scooter-firms-get-the-green-light-to-start-trials-of-up-to-one-year-on-uk-streets/" data-sk="tooltip_parent">the government legalized e-scooter rental trials</a> by local authorities, although private e-scooter riding is still illegal. This legislation spurred the launch of TfL and London Council’s open and competitive procurement process for viable operators. <span style="font-weight: 400;">The pilot, which will run for up to 12 months, will begin June 7 in some of London’s boroughs, including Canary Wharf and the City of London. More neighborhoods are expected to join as the year progresses, according to TfL. Lambeth and Southwark are also seeking participation. </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2153369" style="width: 588px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2153369" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2153369" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/london-borough-map-Mod.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="578" height="462" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/london-borough-map-Mod.jpg 1425w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/london-borough-map-Mod.jpg?resize=150,120 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/london-borough-map-Mod.jpg?resize=300,240 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/london-borough-map-Mod.jpg?resize=768,614 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/london-borough-map-Mod.jpg?resize=680,544 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/london-borough-map-Mod.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 578px) 100vw, 578px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2153369" class="wp-caption-text">Map of London outlining areas for the e-scooter pilot.</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rides can only begin and end in participating neighborhoods, which will designate parking bays for the scooters that are enforced by operators’ geofencing capabilities. However, riders will be able to move freely across these boroughs and &#8220;ride-through areas,&#8221; which thus far only appears to be Tower Hamlets. Between 60 and 150 e-scooters will be available to rent in each participating borough. TfL will gradually let operators that demonstrate strong compliance add scooters. Those that don&#8217;t comply could have their scooter numbers reduced. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Safety and data sharing are core requirements for the participating scooter companies. TfL hopes to be able to use data shared by the operators to help London and the United Kingdom shape future policy on e-scooters and investigate them as a viable option for London’s sustainable recovery from the pandemic. </span><a href="http://london.gov.uk/what-we-do/environment/climate-change/zero-carbon-london"><span style="font-weight: 400;">London’s mayor has set a goal of being a zero-carbon city by 2030</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, so green forms of mobility that decrease reliance on ICE vehicles is essential. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re doing all we can to support London’s safe and sustainable recovery from the coronavirus pandemic and it’s clear that e-scooters could act as an innovative, greener alternative to car trips,” said Helen Sharp, TfL’s e-scooter trial lead in a statement. “This new trial will provide the data and insights we need to determine the longer-term role e-scooters could play in our strategy for a greener and healthier future for London.”  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TfL outlined the following safety requirements for scooters: </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A lower maximum speed of 12.5 mph; </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lights at the front and rear of the vehicles that are always on throughout any rental;  </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Audible warning systems that can be used without adjusting the rider’s grip of the handlebar;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;First-ride policies&#8221; requiring new users to take an e-learning safety course;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rules against riding on sidewalks. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As with all governing city bodies, street clutter is of particular importance to London. Aside from strict geofencing regulations, there will also be a mandatory response time for operators in cases where vehicles have been improperly parked, are damaged or are causing an obstruction, according to TfL. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The safety of those using e-scooters, as well as other road users and pedestrians, is absolutely paramount, so it’s important that they are trialled in this rigorous way to ensure high standards,” said Will Norman, London’s walking and cycling commissioner, in a statement. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dott, Lime and Tier will set their own rental pricing, but they’ll need to be mindful of the needs of essential workers and those with lower incomes by offering appropriate discounts. Lime already offers its Lime Access Program in operating cities, which provides 50% off rides to those on public assistance and workers who have been most affected by the pandemic. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ly66Yre3Jc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/bird-lime-and-veoride-selected-for-nyc-e-scooter-pilot/">Bird, Lime and Veo selected for NYC e-scooter pilot</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bird, Lime and Veo selected for NYC e-scooter pilot&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/bird-lime-and-veoride-selected-for-nyc-e-scooter-pilot/embed/#?secret=Ly66Yre3Jc" data-secret="Ly66Yre3Jc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/bird-lime-and-veoride-selected-for-nyc-e-scooter-pilot/">After Lime’s recent win of New York</a> and Paris, the company, which can be found slinging rides for electric scooters, bikes and mopeds in more than 130 cities across Europe, the Middle East, the United States, Korea, Australia and New Zealand, is merely cementing its big-city dominance. With its ongoing e-bike operations in London, the company was a shoe-in. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Berlin-based Tier Mobility, which also operates in Paris, is the second heaviest hitter. Its recent expansion into Kraków, Poland marked its 100th city, and the company plans to extend coverage in Europe, the Middle East and new markets, as well as add e-bikes to its fleet. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to e-scooters, Tier will be bringing its rider-swappable battery business to London, allowing riders to exchange batteries at charging stations hosted in local businesses across London. This would allow riders to earn free trips in the process while bringing increased footfall for businesses trying to recover from the pandemic. Additionally, having this crowdsourced approach has the potential to reduce congestion associated with collection and transporting e-scooters to a warehouse for charging. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As seems to be the case with these metropolitan scooter deals, there’s always one promising underdog. In the case of London, that&#8217;s Amsterdam-based Dott, </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/european-e-scooter-and-micromobility-startup-dott-raises-85-million/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">which recently raised $85 million in a Series B</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and operates in about 20 cities in Europe. London will be Dott’s first city in the U.K. </span></p>
<p><em>This article has been updated to include other countries in which Lime operates. </em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Xh5zgvmIjk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/bird-rides-spac-filing-shows-scooter-nomics-just-doesnt-fly/">Bird&#8217;s SPAC filing shows scooter-nomics just don&#8217;t fly</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bird&#8217;s SPAC filing shows scooter-nomics just don&#8217;t fly&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/bird-rides-spac-filing-shows-scooter-nomics-just-doesnt-fly/embed/#?secret=Xh5zgvmIjk" data-secret="Xh5zgvmIjk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/dott-lime-and-tier-selected-for-london-e-scooter-trial/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153320</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canoo is being investigated by the SEC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/canoo-is-being-investigated-by-the-sec/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/canoo-is-being-investigated-by-the-sec/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 22:47:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyundai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153271</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Canoo, the Los Angeles-based electric vehicle startup that debuted on the Nasdaq public exchange earlier this year, is being investigated by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, just months after its merger with special purpose acquisition company Hennessy Capital Acquisition Corp. The investigation is broad, covering the Hennessy&#8217;s initial public offering and merger with Canoo, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Canoo, the Los Angeles-based electric vehicle startup that debuted on the Nasdaq public exchange earlier this year, is being investigated by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, just months after its merger with special purpose acquisition company Hennessy Capital Acquisition Corp.</p>
<p>The investigation is broad, covering the Hennessy&#8217;s initial public offering and merger with Canoo, the company&#8217;s operations, business model, revenues, revenue strategy, customer agreements, earnings and other related topics, along with the recent departures of certain of the company’s officers, according to a quarterly earnings report posted Monday. Canoo learned of the investigation on April 29. Canoo&#8217;s share price fell more than 3% in after-hours trading following the release of its first-quarter earnings.</p>
<p>&#8220;The SEC has also informed the Company that the investigation does not mean that it has concluded that anyone has violated the law, and does not mean that it has a negative opinion of any person, entity or security. We intend to provide the requested information and cooperate fully with the SEC investigation,&#8221; Canoo noted in the regulatory filing. Canoo added that it does not consider the investigation or other lawsuits it is facing to be material to its business.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The SEC investigation follows a string of executive departures, a change to some of the core pieces of its business model, the loss of a key automotive partnership and at least one lawsuit brought by shareholders. And that&#8217;s just the activity since the first of the year.</p>
<p>Canoo started as Evelozcity in 2017, founded by former Faraday Future executives Stefan Krause and Ulrich Kranz. The company rebranded as Canoo in spring 2019 and debuted its first vehicle several months later. It was this first vehicle, as well as Canoo&#8217;s plan to offer it only as a subscription, that captured the attention of investors, companies and the media. Last year, Hyundai announced a <a href="https://www.hyundainews.com/en-us/releases/2982">partnership with Canoo</a> to co-develop EVs, but that deal fell apart in early 2021 after the company changed its business model and decided to not offer engineering services to other automakers, according to comments made by the company&#8217;s chairman and now CEO Tony Aquila in a March investors&#8217; call.</p>
<p>Canoo has sustained numerous executive departures, including co-founder and CEO Kranz, general counsel Andrew Wolstan, CFO Paul Balciunas and its head of powertrain development. Krause, who was the company&#8217;s first CEO, stepped down in August 2019. Last month, Canoo was also named as a defendant in two class-action complaints filed by shareholders.</p>
<p>Amid the executive exits and business pivots, the company has managed to narrow its quarterly losses despite an increase in R&amp;D expenditures and no revenue. The company reported Monday a net loss of $15.2 million, or 7 cents a share, in the first quarter, compared to a loss of $30.9 million, or 37 cents a share, in the same period last year. The company said it ended the quarter with $641.9 million in cash and equivalents.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ckRXX85rwO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/20/the-debut-of-electric-pickups-signals-a-new-ev-era/">The debut of electric pickups signals a new EV era</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The debut of electric pickups signals a new EV era&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/20/the-debut-of-electric-pickups-signals-a-new-ev-era/embed/#?secret=ckRXX85rwO" data-secret="ckRXX85rwO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/canoo-is-being-investigated-by-the-sec/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153271</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bosta raises $6.7M to expand e-commerce delivery business across Africa and MENA</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/bosta-raises-6-7m-to-expand-e-commerce-delivery-business-across-africa-and-mena/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/bosta-raises-6-7m-to-expand-e-commerce-delivery-business-across-africa-and-mena/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 22:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bosta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cairo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Last mile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silicon Badia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153256</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Per a recent report by Bain &#38; Co., e-commerce is expected to grow to $28.5 billion in MENA by 2022 from a 2019 value of $8.3 billion. Egypt, one of the most active e-commerce countries in the region, is anticipated to grow 33% annually to reach $3 billion by 2022. But for any e-commerce business [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Per a recent <a href="https://www.bain.com/insights/ecommerce-in-MENA-opportunity-beyond-the-hype/">report</a> by Bain &amp; Co., e-commerce </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is expected</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to grow to $28.5 billion in MENA by 2022 from a 2019 value of $8.3 billion. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Egypt, one of the most active e-commerce countries in the region, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is anticipated</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to grow 33% </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">annually</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to reach $3 billion by 2022</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But for any e-commerce business to thrive, its last-mile delivery arm has to be well figured out. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="http://bosta.co/">Bosta</a> is one such company in Egypt helping small businesses with logistics and last-mile delivery</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Today, the company is announcing it has closed a Series A investment of $6.7 million. U.S. and Middle East VC firm Silicon Badia led the round</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, with participation from 4DX Ventures, Plug and Play Ventures, Wealth Well VC, Khwarizmi VC, as well as other regional and global investors</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This investment comes a year after the company raised a $2.5 million round, which takes its total investment raised to $9.2 million</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bosta </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was launched</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2017 by <a href="https://eg.linkedin.com/in/mohamed-ezzat-67aba7a4">Mohamed Ezzat</a> and <a href="https://eg.linkedin.com/in/ahmedgaber20">Ahmed Gaber</a>. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company offers next-day delivery to customers and handles exchange shipments, customer returns and cash collection</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p>The idea for Bosta came during Ezzat&#8217;s time at Lynks, his previous consumer goods startup. Lynks, the first YC-backed company from Egypt, allows people in Egypt to buy brands from the U.S., China and the U.K.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As co-founder and COO at Lynks, Ezzat was responsible for logistics, international clearance and last-mile delivery</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2016, Egypt experienced an economic downturn coupled with the Egyptian pound devaluation and government restriction on imports</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Lynks it meant slow growth, but Ezzat </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was concerned</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> about fixing the last-mile delivery bit, which, according to him, was a huge pain point</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;My nightmare was always the last mile. And at that time, you know that e-commerce is still very, very small. So it&#8217;s only 1% of the whole retail value,&#8221; he told TechCrunch. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;So I was always thinking, how come if we want the e-commerce to grow, and we don&#8217;t have any strong company when it comes to last-mile because, in the end, every transaction on an e-commerce platform is a transaction on a courier platform</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">E-commerce is a fragmented sector where 80% of transactions come from small businesses selling on Facebook, Instagram and social media in general</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most of these businesses lack a strong delivery experience, and Ezzat left Lynks the following year to start Bosta</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Being in the parcel delivery industry, Bosta wants to help these companies to grow </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">profitably</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It also tries to simplify logistics and allow its customers to have full control over the delivery process</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;You can use Bosta to get anything to your doorstep. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">You buy in our local currency, and we buy everything, handle the shipping, customs, clearance and bring it to your doorstep,&#8221; the CEO added</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CycuOe9dmi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/flextock-is-a-yc-backed-e-commerce-fulfillment-provider-for-africa-and-the-middle-east/">Flextock is a YC-backed e-commerce fulfillment provider for Africa and the Middle East</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Flextock is a YC-backed e-commerce fulfillment provider for Africa and the Middle East&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/flextock-is-a-yc-backed-e-commerce-fulfillment-provider-for-africa-and-the-middle-east/embed/#?secret=CycuOe9dmi" data-secret="CycuOe9dmi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company doesn&#8217;t own fleets of vehicles to carry out operations. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instead, it operates an Uber-like model where drivers sign up, are made contractors and make money when a delivery </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is completed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since 2017, the company has delivered more than 4 million packages to businesses, more than half since the pandemic outbreak last year</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bosta completes more than 300,000 deliveries per month, which is a 3.5x increase from when it raised its previous round, Ezzat stated</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">He also claims that more than 2,200 businesses use its platform daily and achieve a 95% delivery success rate</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Asides from small businesses, Bosta works with major e-commerce platforms like Souq (an Amazon company) and Jumia</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Depending on the volume of goods transported, Bosta charges small businesses about 35-40 Egyptian pounds, while the big players </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are charged</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> less, at 20-25 Egyptian pounds</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Speaking on the investment, Fawaz H Zu&#8217;bi said in a statement: “E-commerce has always had amazing potential in our region but was always </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">being held</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> back by something whether payments, logistics, market fragmentation, or customer adoption</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are excited</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to finally see companies like Bosta emerge to tackle some of these issues and help e-commerce realize its full promise and potential in a region that has now ‘turned on’ </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">digitally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the next two years, Bosta plans to deliver more than 15 million parcels in Egypt and serve over 20,000 businesses. The funds will </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be used</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for those causes, as well as expanding operations across Africa, MENA and the GCC.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;The investment is to dominate Egypt,&#8221; said Ezzat. &#8220;We want to make sure that we deliver the next day across Egypt, not </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in Cairo, where we currently do. And to be a market leader when it comes to e-commerce on the continent and be profitable. This is the main target for us now and also to start operations in Saudi Arabia.&#8221;</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LsA1KqtXkm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/rising-african-venture-investment-powers-fintech-cleantech-bets-in-2020/">Rising African venture investment powers fintech, clean tech bets in 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Rising African venture investment powers fintech, clean tech bets in 2020&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/rising-african-venture-investment-powers-fintech-cleantech-bets-in-2020/embed/#?secret=LsA1KqtXkm" data-secret="LsA1KqtXkm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/bosta-raises-6-7m-to-expand-e-commerce-delivery-business-across-africa-and-mena/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153256</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Should startups build or buy telehealth infrastructure?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/should-startups-build-or-buy-telehealth-infrastructure/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/should-startups-build-or-buy-telehealth-infrastructure/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 22:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deena Shakir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Healthtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expressable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HealthTech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2152116</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Turnkey solutions might be tempting to healthcare startups looking to take advantage of the current market tailwinds, but startups still have to decide what to outsource and what to build.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Digital health in the U.S. got a huge boost from COVID-19 as more people started consulting physicians and urgent care providers remotely in the midst of lockdowns. So much so that <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/healthcare-systems-and-services/our-insights/telehealth-a-quarter-trillion-dollar-post-covid-19-reality">McKinsey estimates</a> that up to $250 billion of the current healthcare expenditure in the U.S. has the potential to be spent virtually. The prominence of digital health is undoubtedly here to stay, but how it looks and feels from provider to provider is still a debate among sector startups.</p>
<p>But for providers who want to deliver care virtually across the country, it&#8217;s not as simple as adding a Zoom invite to an annual check-up. The process requires intention every step of the way — right from the clinicians delivering remote care to the choice of payment processor.</p>
<p>Providers and healthcare startups <em>can</em> choose white-label solutions such as publicly-listed Teladoc and Truepill, which have been around for a long time, and have powered the operations of unicorns like Hims and Hers, Nurx, and GoodRx as they look to scale in a compliant but efficient manner.</p>
<p>Turnkey solutions might be tempting to companies looking to take advantage of this opportunity, but startups still have to decide what to outsource and what to build. Should you rely on others for staffing your practice? Do you build your own payment processing service in-house? Do you integrate with Zoom or build your own video-conferencing software? These questions are crucial to think about early on to prepare for future scale regardless of whether a startup is B2B or B2C.</p>
<h2>More than just Zoom</h2>
<p>SteadyMD, which in March <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210330005641/en/SteadyMD-Raises-25-Million-to-Power-Telehealth-Infrastructure-for-Digital-Health-Companies-and-Employers-in-All-50-States">raised</a> a $25 million Series B led by Lux Capital, wants to be the infrastructure layer that makes it easier for other companies to offer telehealth services. It is hoping to address a pain point it ran into years earlier: The complexity of launching compliant telehealth services in all 50 states.</p>
<p>The company launched in 2016 with the intent to provide high-quality, virtual primary care for brick-and-mortar shops. Through that process, SteadyMD built a suite of tools to make it work with EMR integrations, doctor-patient communication channels, digital recruiting and forecasting software, and prescription referrals and operations. The burdensome process struck a chord with the co-founders and they pivoted the company to where it is today: an &#8220;AWS for healthcare&#8221;.</p>
<p>SteadyMD offers a suite of services to its customers, the least of which, says co-founder <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/guyfriedman/">Guy Friedman</a>, is its video-conferencing platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s not about the technology capacities,&#8221; Friedman says. &#8220;The very large companies that have a lot of resources are using us to help them increase their capacity as workforce.&#8221;</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/should-startups-build-or-buy-telehealth-infrastructure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2152116</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: AT&#038;T&#8217;s $43B WarnerMedia spinoff will create a new content colossus</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/2153202/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/2153202/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 22:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153202</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Welcome to Daily Crunch for Monday, May 17. We have a <em>lot</em> to get to, so we’ll keep our introduction incredibly curt and simply note that early-stage founders can still apply to the upcoming TechCrunch Battlefield event for another week or so. <a href="https://twitter.com/neeshatambe?lang=en">Neesha</a> has the details <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/14/deadline-extended-apply-to-startup-battlefield-at-tc-disrupt-2021/">here</a>. &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<h2>TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<p>Today the biggest stories concern the never-ending flow of cash to insurtech, the ability of software companies to post accelerating revenue growth, and the market leverage of major tech platforms:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/ai-powered-jerry-raises-28m-to-help-you-save-money-on-car-insurance/"><strong>Jerry raises $28M</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Adding another name to the list of startups working on building insurance marketplaces, Jerry has a twist on the model and a huge new infusion of cash. The startup wants to help consumers do more than just find insurance, pursuing the superapp concept, but in a new direction. For more on insurtech marketplaces and their growth, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/insurtech-startups-are-leveraging-rapid-growth-to-raise-big-money/">head here</a>. (Insurtech is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/as-next-insurance-makes-its-first-acquisition-insurtech-looks-energetic/">super hot in aggregate</a>, it’s worth remembering.)</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/fast-growth-pushes-an-unprofitable-no-code-startup-into-the-public-markets-inside-monday-coms-ipo-filing/"><strong>Monday.com is going public</strong></a><strong>: </strong>We’ve long known that corporate communications and planning startup Monday.com was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/25/monday-com-surpassed-130m-arr-before-the-remote-work-boom/">north of $100 million in annual recurring revenue</a>. Now, at last, it has filed to go public. So we ripped into the numbers, which show accelerating revenue adds. More importantly than the raw math, however, was the implicit point from the news that the IPO markets remain open, and for more than just <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/industrial-automation-startup-bright-machines-hauls-in-435m-by-going-public-via-spac/">the latest SPAC deals</a>. That’s good news for late-stage startups everywhere.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/apple-to-add-lossless-audio-at-no-additional-cost/"><strong>Apple adds lossless for no cost</strong></a><strong>:</strong> Spotify <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/22/spotify-to-launch-a-new-high-end-subscription-spotify-hifi/">wants to charge</a> for higher-quality streaming. Apple has decided not to. And that’s not great news for the smaller company because it needs to boost its revenue per user over time. Apple, which has infinite money, does not. The Spotify-Apple war is a notable one to watch because it pits an incumbent <em>upstart</em> against an upstart <em>incumbent</em> in the music streaming space. Let’s see how Spotify fires back.</p>
<h2>Startups and VC</h2>
<p>It appears that every startup in the world just raised more money, so here’s a rundown of the latest deals in quick-fire fashion, ordered by size:</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/fave-with-2-2-million-seed-looks-to-connect-creators-with-their-fandoms/"><strong>Fave raises $2.2M to connect fans and creators</strong></a><strong>:</strong> Founder Jacquelle Amankonah Horton wants to close the space between fans and the creators they love. Given the general market focus in recent quarters on creators, the company makes sense.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/merge-raises-4-5m-to-help-b2b-companies-build-customer-facing-integrations/"><strong>Merge raises $4.5M for its HR and finance API</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Merge offers a single API to connect products to all sorts of finance and HR products. It’s akin to a super API. And with what we presume is a developer-led sales motion and <a href="https://www.merge.dev/pricing">on-demand pricing</a>, it’s right in the middle of the current startup <em>business model</em> zeitgeist.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/sequoia-leads-5m-pre-seed-in-egypts-1-month-old-digital-bank-telda/"><strong>Telda raises $5M for Egyptian neobanking</strong></a><strong>:</strong> The Telda round is cool not only because we don’t cover Egyptian tech enough, but also because there’s Sequoia money in it. American VCs are looking farther and farther afield for their next deal.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/fresh-out-of-yc-houm-raises-8m-to-improve-the-home-rental-and-sales-market-in-latam/"><strong>Houm raises $8M for LatAm home sales</strong></a><strong>:</strong> TechCrunch described Houm as “an all-in-one platform that helps homeowners rent and sell their properties in” Latin America. The recent Y Combinator grad took part in the accelerator’s winter 2021 batch.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/with-21m-in-funding-code-ocean-aims-to-help-researchers-replicate-data-heavy-science/"><strong>Code Ocean raises $21M for collaborative data science</strong></a><strong>:</strong> In short, Code Ocean provides data jockeys with a “small-scale container platform that lets you wrap up all the necessary components of your data and analysis in an easily shared format,” Devin Coldewey reports. And now it has a lot more money to chase that vision.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/ankorstore-raises-another-102-million-for-its-wholesale-marketplace/"><strong>Ankorstore raises $102M to supply indie stores</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Hailing from France, Ankorstore provides wholesale items to smaller retailers. And Tiger just poured capital into the company, meaning that the startup has some of the most intriguing financial backing out there today.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/industrial-automation-startup-bright-machines-hauls-in-435m-by-going-public-via-spac/"><strong>One more hardware SPAC</strong></a><strong>:</strong> Bright Machines is going public via a SPAC. Our own <a href="https://twitter.com/ron_miller">Ron Miller</a> helped us dig into the company and its accounting results.</p>
<h2>The battle for voice recognition inside vehicles is heating up</h2>
<p>Until recently, integrating affordable voice-recognition software into an automobile was something from science fiction.</p>
<p>But last year, the percentage of vehicles offering in-car connected services reached 45%. By 2024, analysts predict cars with voice recognition will comprise 60% of the market.</p>
<p>Considering how much time many of us spend behind the wheel, there&#8217;s an infinite number of applications for the technology. For our latest Extra Crunch market map, we sized up the general market opportunity before creating a roster of major players and reaching out to investors to see where they&#8217;re placing bets.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sIT2pG244x"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/the-battle-for-voice-recognition-inside-vehicles-is-heating-up/">The battle for voice recognition inside vehicles is heating up</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The battle for voice recognition inside vehicles is heating up&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/the-battle-for-voice-recognition-inside-vehicles-is-heating-up/embed/#?secret=sIT2pG244x" data-secret="sIT2pG244x" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> <em>You can sign up here</em></a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>Akin to the startup market, Big Tech was incredibly busy in the last few days, so here’s your run-through:</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/jd-logistics-ipo/"><strong>JD.com’s logistics subsidiary is going public</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Good news from the Chinese startup market has been somewhat rare lately. Here’s some, which not only helps change the narrative a bit about the country’s tech scene, but also underscores how bonkers the global e-commerce market is.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/spacex-launched-52-more-starlink-satellites-to-orbit-on-saturday/"><strong>SpaceX sent out 52 more Starlink satellites</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Bring on rural, high-speed internet. So we can all move to Montana. (Please.)</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/16/gojek-and-tokopedia-merge-to-form-goto-group/"><strong>GoJek and Tokopedia are GoTo Group</strong></a><strong>: </strong>The expected combination of “Indonesia’s two biggest startups” is done, TechCrunch reports. GoJek, of course, is in the ride-hailing business, while Tokopedia is a marketplace. Now it’s a single, massive entity.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439924/microsoft-teams-personal-version-launch-available-download?scrolla=5eb6d68b7fedc32c19ef33b4"><strong>Microsoft makes Teams better for your parents</strong></a><strong>:</strong> What happens when your Discord deal dies? Well, you make your current chat-video-groups service better for regular folks, it turns out. Aside from gaming, Teams may be Microsoft’s best shot at a consumer play that works out for some time.</p>
<p>Finally, BigTelco companies <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/att-confirms-deal-to-combine-its-warnermedia-subsidiary-with-discovery-inc-in-pure-play-43b-deal/">ditching media assets</a> to de-lever ahead of higher infrastructure spend? Say no more, AT&amp;T, we’re <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/private-equity-firm-apollo-agrees-to-buy-verizon-media-assets-for-5-billion/">already hip to it</a>. (Or they could just limit some shareholder return programs for a bit. You know?)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/2153202/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153202</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Want to double your rate of return? Seek counsel from experienced executives</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/want-to-double-your-rate-of-return-seek-counsel-from-experienced-executives/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/want-to-double-your-rate-of-return-seek-counsel-from-experienced-executives/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 20:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2152866</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Years of data from hundreds of successful startups show the impact of relevant executive expertise is even greater than anticipated — it doubles the rate of return on a venture investment.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Rob Olson</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/M13Company">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		
Rob Olson is a partner and head of data strategy at <a href="https://m13.co/">M13</a>, a venture engine focused on investing in the core technologies that are going to drive and change consumer behavior over the next decade.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Does it really take an average of seven to eight years for a successful startup to exit? What can early-stage founders do to accelerate outcomes?</p>
<p>We wanted to know if founding teams can execute faster with a higher degree of success if they’re able to take advantage of relevant executive expertise. After all, that’s the thesis we built our venture model around &#8212; we purposefully designed M13 so that early-stage founders get access to experienced executives they wouldn’t otherwise have the money to hire or the time to vet, onboard and manage.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Even if companies are doing everything right, they still reduce time to exit when they have multiple founders with prior relevant experience as a senior leader or operator.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>We looked at years of data from hundreds of successful startups. As it turns out, the impact of relevant executive expertise is even greater than we had anticipated &#8212; to the tune of doubling the rate of return on a venture investment.</p>
<p>When it comes to measuring leadership experience, information about an individual executive’s experience — for example, how long they’ve been an exec — is publicly available. Unfortunately, there isn’t readily available structured data around a founding team’s seniority and how early the founders bring on people with more experience as an operator or leader.</p>
<p>To find out if leadership experience significantly impacts startups’ success, we analyzed nearly 800 executives at more than 200 companies that reached a sizable exit (greater than or equal to a $500 million valuation) via an IPO on a U.S. exchange or an exit via M&amp;A from 2004-2019. About 70% of the companies in our dataset exited between 2016-2019, including notable IPOs like Spotify, Zoom, Uber and Peloton. We decided to exclude companies in the biotech/life sciences space because these companies follow a different growth trajectory than consumer tech and B2B tech and traditionally exit via IPO or M&amp;A at a much earlier stage.</p>
<p>Here’s what our analysis of startups with successful exits revealed.</p>
<h2>Of successful exits, the average actually is 7-8 years</h2>
<p>While there are other intangible variables for startup success, the basic equation is the time and capital required to achieve an exit and the size of that exit.</p>
<p>Our dataset validates the widely accepted statement that successful exits take about seven to eight years:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2153061" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2153061" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2153061" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/m13-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="661" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/m13-1.png 1760w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/m13-1.png?resize=150,97 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/m13-1.png?resize=300,194 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/m13-1.png?resize=768,496 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/m13-1.png?resize=680,439 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/m13-1.png?resize=1536,991 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/m13-1.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2153061" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> M13</p></div></p>
<p>But could a variable like relevant leadership experience actually accelerate the time to exit? We wondered: Beyond time and capital, are there any factors — like experience as a leader or operator — that can have an exponential impact on the exit outcome? And when is the right time for those human capital resources to be introduced to make that impact?</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/want-to-double-your-rate-of-return-seek-counsel-from-experienced-executives/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2152866</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hardware hacker brings online multiplayer to the original Game Boy</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/hardware-hacker-brings-online-multiplayer-to-the-original-game-boy/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/hardware-hacker-brings-online-multiplayer-to-the-original-game-boy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 20:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stacksmashing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153209</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Move over, Xbox and PlayStation. A new foe has appeared in the world of online multiplayer gaming! It&#8217;s the&#8230; uh, Game Boy. As in that unbreakable, gray, 4.19Mhz tank from 1989. While the Game Boy has had a handful of locally multiplayer games since the beginning, using it meant physically connecting your Game Boy to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Move over, Xbox and PlayStation. A new foe has appeared in the world of online multiplayer gaming! It&#8217;s the&#8230; uh, Game Boy. As in that unbreakable, gray, 4.19Mhz tank from 1989.</p>
<p>While the Game Boy has had a handful of locally multiplayer games since the beginning, using it meant physically connecting your Game Boy to another Game Boy via an accessory called the link cable. If you wanted to play some Nintendo with someone further than a few feet away&#8230; well, you&#8217;d just have to wait a few decades.</p>
<p>In a wildly impressive display of skill, hardware hacker <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/stacksmashing/featured">stacksmashing</a> has managed to reverse-engineer the Game Boy&#8217;s link cable protocol and effectively trick it into working across the internet. The Game Boy connects through the link cable hooked into a Raspberry Pi to a custom desktop client, which in turn pings an online game server that acts as the bridge between you and your opponent(s). The Game Boy thinks it&#8217;s talking to any other ol&#8217; Game Boy, unaware of the fact that it&#8217;s actually communicating with a server that could be halfway around the world.</p>
<p>The first game they&#8217;ve got working? Tetris!</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/KtHu693wE9o?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Getting any given game to work (imagine trading a Pokémon you caught in 1998 with someone across the internet!) will require that game&#8217;s unique communication protocols to be reverse-engineered, so it&#8217;s only Tetris for now. Fortunately, stacksmashing has opened up the source code for all the various components that have been built so far, so there&#8217;s something of a foundation to build upon. And because the whole thing is no fun without anyone to play with, there&#8217;s also a Discord channel just for finding others who&#8217;ve gone down this rabbit hole. There&#8217;s even a custom PCB in the works ($15, with preorders expected to ship by June) that&#8217;ll handle the connection between the link cable and the Raspberry Pi, removing the need for you to shred a link cable to expose its wires and make this work.</p>
<p>Stacksmashing also recently made headlines by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_E0PWQvW-14">cracking open and modifying Apple&#8217;s AirTags</a>, as well as turning the Game Boy into a (hilariously underpowered) <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4ckjr9x214c">Bitcoin miner</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WHKpfnoP8y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/vcs-discuss-gamings-biggest-infrastructure-investment-opportunities-in-2021/">VCs discuss gaming&#8217;s biggest infrastructure investment opportunities in 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;VCs discuss gaming&#8217;s biggest infrastructure investment opportunities in 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/vcs-discuss-gamings-biggest-infrastructure-investment-opportunities-in-2021/embed/#?secret=WHKpfnoP8y" data-secret="WHKpfnoP8y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/hardware-hacker-brings-online-multiplayer-to-the-original-game-boy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153209</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amount raises $99M at a $1B+ valuation to help banks better compete with fintechs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/amount-raises-99m-at-a-1b-valuation-to-help-banks-better-compete-with-fintechs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/amount-raises-99m-at-a-1b-valuation-to-help-banks-better-compete-with-fintechs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 20:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbnb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amount]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barclays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blackstone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hanaco Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hsbc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ing group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Invus Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laurence Tosi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Market Leader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Westcap]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amount, a company that provides technology to banks and financial institutions, has raised $99 million in a Series D funding round at a valuation of just over $1 billion. WestCap, a growth equity firm founded by ex-Airbnb and Blackstone CFO Laurence Tosi, led the round. Hanaco Ventures, Goldman Sachs, Invus Opportunities and Barclays Principal Investments [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.amount.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Amount</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a company that provides technology to banks and financial institutions, has raised $99 million in a Series D funding round at a valuation of just over $1 billion.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://westcap.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">WestCap</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a growth equity firm founded by ex-Airbnb and Blackstone CFO Laurence Tosi, led the round. Hanaco Ventures, Goldman Sachs, Invus Opportunities and Barclays Principal Investments also participated.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Notably, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/helping-big-banks-out-affirm-affirm-and-out-chime-chime-gives-amount-a-681-million-valuation/">investment comes just over five months after Amount raised $86 million</a> in a Series C round led by Goldman Sachs Growth at a valuation of $686 million. (The original raise was $81 million, but Barclays</span> Principal Investments invested $5 million as part of a second close of the Series C round). <span style="font-weight: 400;">And </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">that </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">round came just three months after the Chicago-based </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">startup quietly raised $58 million in a Series B round in March. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The latest funding brings Amount’s total capital raised to $243 million since it spun off from </span><a href="https://www.avant.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Avant</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8212; an online lender that has raised over $600 million in equity &#8212; in January of 2020.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, what kind of technology does Amount provide? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In simple terms, Amount’s mission is to help financial institutions “go digital in months — not years&#8221; and thus, better compete with fintech rivals. The company formed just before the pandemic hit. But as we have all seen, demand for the type of technology Amount has developed has only increased exponentially this year and last.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CEO Adam Hughes says Amount was spun out of Avant to provide enterprise software built specifically for the banking industry. It </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">partners with banks and financial institutions to “rapidly digitize their financial infrastructure and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">compete in the retail lending and buy now, pay later sectors</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">,” Hughes told TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Specifically, the 400-person company has built what it describes as “battle-tested” retail banking and point-of-sale technology that it claims accelerates digital transformation for financial institutions. The goal is to give those institutions a way to offer “a secure and seamless digital customer and merchant experience” that leverages Amount’s verification and analytics capabilities. </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2153151" style="width: 588px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2153151" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2153151" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Image-from-iOS-2.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="578" height="389" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Image-from-iOS-2.jpg 3644w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Image-from-iOS-2.jpg?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Image-from-iOS-2.jpg?resize=300,202 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Image-from-iOS-2.jpg?resize=768,518 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Image-from-iOS-2.jpg?resize=680,459 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Image-from-iOS-2.jpg?resize=1536,1036 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Image-from-iOS-2.jpg?resize=2048,1381 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Image-from-iOS-2.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 578px) 100vw, 578px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2153151" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Amount</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">HSBC, TD Bank, Regions, Banco Popular and Avant (of course) are among the 10 banks that use Amount’s technology in an effort to simplify their transition to digital financial services. Recently, </span><a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/barclays-us-consumer-bank-expands-point-of-sale-financing-suite-to-include-installment-options-powered-by-amount-301277216.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Barclays US Consumer Bank</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> became one of the first major banks to offer installment point-of-sale options, giving merchants the ability to “white label” POS payments under their own brand (using Amount’s technology).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pandemic dramatically accelerated banks&#8217; interest in further digitizing the retail lending experience and offering additional buy now, pay later financing options with the rise of e-commerce,” Hughes, former president and COO at Avant, told TechCrunch. “Banks are facing significant disruption risk from fintech competitors, so an Amount partnership can deliver a world-class digital experience with significant go-to-market advantages.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, he points out, consumers’ digital expectations have changed as a result of the forced digital adoption during the pandemic, with bank branches and stores closing and more banking done and more goods and services being purchased online.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Y1KYiLt4Tv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/avant-doubles-down-on-digital-banking-with-acquisition-of-zero-financial-and-its-neobank/">Avant doubles down on digital banking with Zero Financial acquisition</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Avant doubles down on digital banking with Zero Financial acquisition&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/avant-doubles-down-on-digital-banking-with-acquisition-of-zero-financial-and-its-neobank/embed/#?secret=Y1KYiLt4Tv" data-secret="Y1KYiLt4Tv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Amount delivers retail banking experiences via a variety of channels and a point-of-sale financing product suite, as well as features such as fraud prevention, verification, decisioning engines and account management.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall, Amount clients include financial institutions collectively managing nearly $2 trillion in U.S. assets and servicing more than 50 million U.S. customers, according to the company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hughes declined to provide any details regarding the company’s financials, saying only that Amount “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">performed well” as a standalone company in 2020 and that the company is expecting “significant” year-over-year revenue growth in 2021.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Amount plans to use its new capital to further accelerate R&amp;D by investing in its technology and products. It also will be eyeing some acquisitions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We see a lot of interesting technology we could layer onto our platform to unlock new asset classes, and acquisition opportunities that would allow us to bring additional features to our platform,” Hughes told TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Avant itself made its first acquisition earlier this year when it picked up Zero Financial, news that TechCrunch covered </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/avant-doubles-down-on-digital-banking-with-acquisition-of-zero-financial-and-its-neobank/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kevin</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Marcus, partner</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">at WestCap, said his firm invested in Amount based on the belief </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">that banks and other financial institutions have “a point-in-time opportunity to democratize access to traditional financial products by accelerating modernization efforts.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Amount is the market leader in powering that change,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">” he said. “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Through its best-in-class products, Amount enables financial institutions to enhance and elevate the banking experience for their end customers and maintain a key competitive advantage in the marketplace.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fKOwmkjsqY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/02/which-neobanks-will-rise-or-fall/">Which neobanks will rise or fall?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Which neobanks will rise or fall?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/02/which-neobanks-will-rise-or-fall/embed/#?secret=fKOwmkjsqY" data-secret="fKOwmkjsqY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/amount-raises-99m-at-a-1b-valuation-to-help-banks-better-compete-with-fintechs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153140</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Volocopter debuts a bigger eVTOL aimed at the city-suburban commute</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/volocopter-debuts-a-bigger-evtol-aimed-at-the-city-suburban-commute/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/volocopter-debuts-a-bigger-evtol-aimed-at-the-city-suburban-commute/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 19:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archer Aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eVTOL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joby Aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban air mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volocopter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153168</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Germany electric aviation startup Volocopter revealed Monday a new electric vertical take-off and landing aircraft targeting the suburban-to-city commuter. The four-seater VoloConnect is designed to have a range of 62 miles, making it well-suited for trips between the suburbs and the city, the company said. The aircraft design is a significant departure from the VoloCity, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Germany electric aviation startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/volocopter/">Volocopter</a> revealed Monday a new electric vertical take-off and landing aircraft targeting the suburban-to-city commuter.</p>
<p>The four-seater VoloConnect is designed to have a range of 62 miles, making it well-suited for trips between the suburbs and the city, the company said. The aircraft design is a significant departure from the VoloCity, the company&#8217;s first passenger eVTOL that is designed for shorter urban trips. The two-seat VoloCity, which has to be certified, has a 22-mile range.</p>
<p>VoloConnect’s longer range indicates that the company has its sights set on markets outside of major city centers, and that it is looking to more directly compete with rival eVTOL startups. VoloConnect&#8217;s aircraft specs are in line with that of competitors Archer Aviation and Wisk Aero, which each have eVTOL designs with an anticipated range of around 60 miles.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>VoloConnect has a hybrid lift-and-push design, combining aspects of what one might typically see in a helicopter with a small aircraft. The vertical lift is facilitated by six propellers that sit parallel to the aircraft body and are connected by two wings. The push comes from two large fans on each side of the craft. Three wheels can retract into and out of the plane’s belly during take-off and landing.</p>
<p>The German-based startup said the new craft can reach a cruising speed of 112 mph (180 km/h) and a top speed of around 155 mph (250 km/h). It aims to achieve certification by 2026.</p>
<p>Electric aviation startups are all competing to be the first company to bring an aircraft to market. Even as Volocopter released this new design, the company is primarily focused on launching its air taxi service, which would use the smaller VoloCity aircraft, in Singapore by 2023. But before Volocopter&#8217;s aircraft can take to the skies, it will first need to achieve type certification with the European Union Aviation Safety Administration, and, in the case of Singapore, the relevant aviation authority there.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OdzprAdlfJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/can-solid-state-batteries-power-up-for-the-next-generation-of-evs/">Can solid state batteries power up for the next generation of EVs?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Can solid state batteries power up for the next generation of EVs?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/can-solid-state-batteries-power-up-for-the-next-generation-of-evs/embed/#?secret=OdzprAdlfJ" data-secret="OdzprAdlfJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/volocopter-debuts-a-bigger-evtol-aimed-at-the-city-suburban-commute/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153168</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Industrial automation startup Bright Machines hauls in $435M by going public via SPAC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/industrial-automation-startup-bright-machines-hauls-in-435m-by-going-public-via-spac/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/industrial-automation-startup-bright-machines-hauls-in-435m-by-going-public-via-spac/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 19:15:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bright Machines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC News Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[industrial automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPACs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2152948</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After the transaction is consummated, the startup will sport an anticipated equity valuation of $1.6 billion.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.brightmachines.com/">Bright Machines</a> is going public via a SPAC-led combination, it <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210517005272/en/Bright-Machines-a-Leader-in-Intelligent-Software-Defined-Manufacturing-to-Become-a-Public-Company-via-Merger-with-SCVX">announced</a> this morning. The transaction will see the 3-year-old company merge with SCVX, raising gross cash proceeds of $435 million in the process.</p>
<p>After the transaction is consummated, the startup will sport an anticipated equity valuation of $1.6 billion.</p>
<p>The Bright Machines news indicates that the great SPAC chill was not a deep freeze. And the transaction itself, in conjunction with the previously announced Desktop Metal blank-check deal, implies that there is space in the market for hardware startup liquidity via SPACs. Perhaps that will unlock more late-stage capital for hardware-focused upstarts.</p>
<p>Today we&#8217;re first looking at what Bright Machines does, and then the financial details that it shared as part of its news.</p>
<h2>What&#8217;s Bright Machines?</h2>
<p>Bright Machines is trying to solve a hard problem related to industrial automation by creating microfactories. This involves a complex mix of hardware, software and artificial intelligence. While robotics has been around in one form or another since the 1970s, for the most part, it has lacked real intelligence. Bright Machines wants to change that.</p>
<p>The company emerged in 2018 with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/23/bright-machines-lands-179m-to-bring-smarter-robotics-to-manufacturing/">a $179 million Series A</a>, a hefty amount of cash for a young startup, but the company has a bold vision and such a vision takes extensive funding. What it’s trying to do is completely transform manufacturing using machine learning.</p>
<p>At the time of that funding, the company brought in former Autodesk co-CEO Amar Hanspal as CEO and former Autodesk founder and CEO Carl Bass to sit on the company board of directors. AutoDesk itself has been trying to transform design and manufacturing in recent years, so it was logical to bring these two experienced leaders into the fold.</p>
<p>The startup’s thesis is that instead of having what are essentially “unintelligent” robots, it wants to add computer vision and a heavy dose of sensors to bring a data-driven automation approach to the factory floor.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/industrial-automation-startup-bright-machines-hauls-in-435m-by-going-public-via-spac/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2152948</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ankorstore raises another $102 million for its wholesale marketplace</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/ankorstore-raises-another-102-million-for-its-wholesale-marketplace/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/ankorstore-raises-another-102-million-for-its-wholesale-marketplace/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 18:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ankorstore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bain capital ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wholesale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wholesale marketplace]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153121</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup Ankorstore has raised a $102 million Series B funding round (€84 million). Tiger Global and Bain Capital Ventures are leading today’s funding round with existing investors Index Ventures, GFC, Alven and Aglaé also participating. This is a significant funding round, as it comes just a few months after the company raised €25 million. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://www.ankorstore.com">Ankorstore</a> has raised a $102 million Series B funding round (€84 million). Tiger Global and Bain Capital Ventures are leading today’s funding round with existing investors Index Ventures, GFC, Alven and Aglaé also participating. This is a significant funding round, as it comes just a few months after the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/ankorstore-raises-29-9-million-for-its-wholesale-marketplace/">raised</a> €25 million.</p>
<p>If you’re not familiar with Ankorstore, the company is building a wholesale marketplace for independent shop owners. You may have noticed some highly Instagrammable shops with a selection of random items, such as household supplies, maple syrup, candles, headbands, bath salts and stationery items.</p>
<p>Essentially, Ankorstore helps you source those items for shop owners. It lets you buy a ton of cutesy stuff and act as a curator for your customers. Even if you’re already working with brands directly, the startup offers some advantageous terms. In addition to buying from several brands at once, Ankorstore withdraws the money from your bank account 60 days after placing an order.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xr7YAjIV1E"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/ankorstore-raises-29-9-million-for-its-wholesale-marketplace/">Ankorstore raises $29.9 million for its wholesale marketplace</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ankorstore raises $29.9 million for its wholesale marketplace&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/ankorstore-raises-29-9-million-for-its-wholesale-marketplace/embed/#?secret=xr7YAjIV1E" data-secret="xr7YAjIV1E" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>On the other side of the marketplace, brands get paid upon delivery. Even if you’re just getting started, the minimum first order is €100 per brand.</p>
<p>And metrics have been going up and to the right. There are now 5,000 brands on Ankorstore, and 50,000 shops are buying stuff through the platform. And the best is likely ahead, as stores begin to re-open across Europe and tourism picks up again.</p>
<p>Ankorstore is now live across 14 different markets. The majority of the company’s revenue comes from international markets — not its home market France. The company’s co-founder Nicolas Cohen mentions the U.K., Germany, the Netherlands and Sweden as growth markets.</p>
<p>The total addressable market is huge, as the company has identified 800,000 independent shops across Europe that could potentially work with Ankorstore. And the success of other wholesale marketplaces, such as <a href="https://www.faire.com">Faire</a>, proves that this relatively new market is still largely untapped.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dOZa7wbA8b"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/embedded-procurement-will-make-every-company-its-own-marketplace/">Embedded procurement will make every company its own marketplace</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Embedded procurement will make every company its own marketplace&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/embedded-procurement-will-make-every-company-its-own-marketplace/embed/#?secret=dOZa7wbA8b" data-secret="dOZa7wbA8b" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/ankorstore-raises-another-102-million-for-its-wholesale-marketplace/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153121</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rocket Lab recovered the first stage from its failed May 15 launch, a silver lining for its reusability program</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/rocket-lab-recovered-the-first-stage-from-its-failed-may-15-launch-a-silver-lining-for-its-reusability-program/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/rocket-lab-recovered-the-first-stage-from-its-failed-may-15-launch-a-silver-lining-for-its-reusability-program/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 18:21:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Electron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Lab]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rocket Lab may have experienced mission failure and total payload loss during the company’s 20th planned mission on May 15, but it wasn&#8217;t all bad news, the company said in an update Monday. Importantly, the Electron rocket’s first stage &#8212; which contains nine Rutherford engines &#8212; performed as designed and did not contribute to the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Rocket Lab may have experienced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/15/rocket-labs-20th-electron-launch-ends-in-failure-with-the-loss-of-its-payload/">mission failure and total payload loss</a> during the company’s 20th planned mission on May 15, but it wasn&#8217;t all bad news, the company said in an update Monday.</p>
<p>Importantly, the Electron rocket’s first stage &#8212; which contains nine Rutherford engines &#8212; performed as designed and did not contribute to the flight failure. Rocket Lab further said the first stage completed a successful ocean splashdown using a parachute and that the company was able to retrieve it and bring it back to its production complex.</p>
<p>Rocket Lab was also testing on this mission a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/rocket-lab-prepares-to-recover-second-booster-at-sea-after-may-15-launch/">redesigned heat shield</a> made out of stainless steel, rather than aluminum, and that also seemed to function well. Testing these reusability system elements was a secondary objective here, as the primary goal is always to deliver the payloads of paying customers, but ultimately reusability could be absolutely crucial to the company&#8217;s long-term business.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“The new heat shield debuted in this flight protected the stage from the intense heat and forces experienced while re-entering Earth’s atmosphere and the program took yet another major advancement towards reusability of the rocket,” the company said Monday.</p>
<p>This is great news for Rocket Lab’s reusability program, as the first stage and engines can be examined and evaluated for further reflight trials on future missions. The company still intends to conduct its third recovery mission later this year. Rocket Lab said it was leading flight review of the May 15 mission failure with the support of the Federal Aviation Administration and anticipates the full review to be complete in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>Rocket Lab last experienced mission failure <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/04/rocket-lab-launch-fails-during-rockets-second-stage-burn-causing-a-loss-of-vehicle-and-payloads/">on July 4 last year</a>, with a total loss of the launch vehicle and payload. The company told TechCrunch there are &#8220;no indications at this point that the root cause is the same&#8221; as experienced during the July mission.</p>
<p><em>The story has been updated to include Rocket Lab&#8217;s comments.</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wIwUrOH4n5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/15/rocket-labs-20th-electron-launch-ends-in-failure-with-the-loss-of-its-payload/">Rocket Lab&#8217;s 20th Electron launch ends in failure with the loss of its payload</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Rocket Lab&#8217;s 20th Electron launch ends in failure with the loss of its payload&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/15/rocket-labs-20th-electron-launch-ends-in-failure-with-the-loss-of-its-payload/embed/#?secret=wIwUrOH4n5" data-secret="wIwUrOH4n5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LMMgkfRKyj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/23/from-launch-to-launch-peter-beck-on-building-an-orbital-business-from-scratch/">From launch to launch: Peter Beck on building Rocket Lab&#8217;s orbital business</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;From launch to launch: Peter Beck on building Rocket Lab&#8217;s orbital business&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/23/from-launch-to-launch-peter-beck-on-building-an-orbital-business-from-scratch/embed/#?secret=LMMgkfRKyj" data-secret="LMMgkfRKyj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/rocket-lab-recovered-the-first-stage-from-its-failed-may-15-launch-a-silver-lining-for-its-reusability-program/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153105</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>With $21M in funding, Code Ocean aims to help researchers replicate data-heavy science</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/with-21m-in-funding-code-ocean-aims-to-help-researchers-replicate-data-heavy-science/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/with-21m-in-funding-code-ocean-aims-to-help-researchers-replicate-data-heavy-science/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 18:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[code ocean]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2152327</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every branch of science is increasingly reliant on big data sets and analysis, which means a growing confusion of formats and platforms — more than inconvenient, this can hinder the process of peer review and replication of research. Code Ocean hopes to make it easier for scientists to collaborate by making a flexible, shareable format [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Every branch of science is increasingly reliant on big data sets and analysis, which means a growing confusion of formats and platforms — more than inconvenient, this can hinder the process of peer review and replication of research. <a href="https://codeocean.com/">Code Ocean</a> hopes to make it easier for scientists to collaborate by making a flexible, shareable format and platform for any and all data sets and methods, and it has raised a total of $21 million to build it out.</p>
<p>Certainly there&#8217;s an air of &#8220;Too many options? Try this one!&#8221; to this (and here&#8217;s the requisite <a href="https://xkcd.com/927/">relevant XKCD</a>). But Code Ocean isn&#8217;t creating a competitor to successful tools like Jupyter or GitLab or Docker — it&#8217;s more of a small-scale container platform that lets you wrap up all the necessary components of your data and analysis in an easily shared format, whatever platform they live on natively.</p>
<p>The trouble appears when you need to share what you&#8217;re doing with another researcher, whether they&#8217;re on the bench next to you or at a university across the country. It&#8217;s important for replication purposes that data analysis — just like any other scientific technique — be done exactly the same way. But there&#8217;s no guarantee that your colleague will use the same structures, formats, notation, labels and so on.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That doesn&#8217;t mean it&#8217;s <em>impossible</em> to share your work, but it does add a lot of extra steps as would-be replicators or iterators check and double check that all the methods are the same, that the same versions of the same tools are being used in the same order, with the same settings, and so on. A tiny inconsistency can have major repercussions down the road.</p>
<p>Turns out this problem is similar in a way to how many cloud services are spun up. Software deployments can be as finicky as scientific experiments, and one solution to this is containers, which like tiny virtual machines include everything needed to accomplish a computing task, in a portable format compatible with many different setups. The idea is a natural one to transfer to the research world, where you can tie up all in one tidy package the data, the software used and the specific techniques and processes used to reach a given result. That, at least, is the pitch Code Ocean offers for its platform and &#8220;Compute Capsules.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2153059" style="width: 928px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/capsule-shape.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2153059" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2153059 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/capsule-shape.png" alt="Diagram showing how a &quot;compute capsule&quot; includes code, environment, and data." width="918" height="656" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/capsule-shape.png 918w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/capsule-shape.png?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/capsule-shape.png?resize=300,214 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/capsule-shape.png?resize=768,549 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/capsule-shape.png?resize=680,486 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/capsule-shape.png?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 918px) 100vw, 918px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2153059" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Code Ocean</p></div></p>
<p>Say you&#8217;re a microbiologist looking at the effectiveness of a promising compound on certain muscle cells. You&#8217;re working in R, writing in RStudio on an Ubuntu machine, and your data are such and such collected during an in vitro observation. While you would naturally declare all this when you publish, there&#8217;s no guarantee anyone has an Ubuntu laptop with a working RStudio setup around, so even if you provide all the code, it might be for nothing.</p>
<p><a href="https://codeocean.com/resources/blog/rna-seq-capsule/">If, however, you put it on Code Ocean, like this</a>, it makes all the relevant code available, and capable of being inspected and run unmodified with a click, or being fiddled with if a colleague is wondering about a certain piece. It works through a single link and web app, cross platform, and can even be embedded on a webpage like a document or video. (I&#8217;m going to try to do that below, but our backend is a little finicky. The capsule itself is <a href="https://codeocean.com/capsule/2520679/tree/v1">here</a>.)</p>
<p><script src="https://codeocean.com/widget.js?slug=2520679" async></script></p>
<p>More than that, though, the Compute Capsule can be repurposed by others with new data and modifications. Maybe the technique you put online is a general purpose RNA sequence analysis tool that works as long as you feed it properly formatted data, and that&#8217;s something others would have had to code from scratch in order to take advantage of some platforms.</p>
<p>Well, they can just clone your capsule, run it with their own data and get their own results in addition to verifying your own. This can be done via the Code Ocean website or just by downloading a zip file of the whole thing and getting it running on their own computer, if they happen to have a compatible setup. A few more example capsules can be found <a href="https://codeocean.com/resources/blog/category/compute-capsules/">here</a>.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2153063" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Code-Ocean-WorkBench-Screen-Shot.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2153063" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2153063" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Code-Ocean-WorkBench-Screen-Shot.png" alt="Screenshot of the Code Ocean workbench environment." width="1024" height="544" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Code-Ocean-WorkBench-Screen-Shot.png 3584w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Code-Ocean-WorkBench-Screen-Shot.png?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Code-Ocean-WorkBench-Screen-Shot.png?resize=300,159 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Code-Ocean-WorkBench-Screen-Shot.png?resize=768,408 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Code-Ocean-WorkBench-Screen-Shot.png?resize=680,361 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Code-Ocean-WorkBench-Screen-Shot.png?resize=1536,816 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Code-Ocean-WorkBench-Screen-Shot.png?resize=2048,1088 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Code-Ocean-WorkBench-Screen-Shot.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2153063" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Code Ocean</p></div></p>
<p>This sort of cross-pollination of research techniques is as old as science, but modern data-heavy experimentation often ends up siloed because it can&#8217;t easily be shared and verified even though the code is technically available. That means other researchers move on, build their own thing and further reinforce the silo system.</p>
<p>Right now there are about 2,000 public compute capsules on Code Ocean, most of which are associated with a published paper. Most have also been used by others, either to replicate or try something new, and some, like ultra-specific open source code libraries, have been used by thousands.</p>
<p>Naturally there are security concerns when working with proprietary or medically sensitive data, and the enterprise product allows the whole system to run on a private cloud platform. That way it would be more of an internal tool, and at major research institutions that in itself could be quite useful.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Lm5drNuMLx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/data-is-the-worlds-most-valuable-and-vulnerable-resource/">Data is the world&#8217;s most valuable (and vulnerable) resource</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Data is the world&#8217;s most valuable (and vulnerable) resource&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/data-is-the-worlds-most-valuable-and-vulnerable-resource/embed/#?secret=Lm5drNuMLx" data-secret="Lm5drNuMLx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Code Ocean hopes that by being as inclusive as possible in terms of codebases, platforms, compute services and so on will make for a more collaborative environment at the cutting edge.</p>
<p>Clearly that ambition is shared by others, as the the company has raised $21 million so far, $6 million of which was in previously undisclosed investments and $15 million in an A round announced today. The A round was led by Battery Ventures, with Digitalis Ventures, EBSCO and Vaal Partners participating as well as numerous others.</p>
<p>The money will allow the company to further develop, scale and promote its platform. With luck they&#8217;ll soon find themselves among the rarefied air often breathed by this sort of savvy SaaS — necessary, deeply integrated and profitable.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/with-21m-in-funding-code-ocean-aims-to-help-researchers-replicate-data-heavy-science/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2152327</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canoo&#8217;s electric microbus will start under $35,000 when it comes to market next year</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/canoos-electric-microbus-will-start-under-35000-when-it-comes-to-market-next-year/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/canoos-electric-microbus-will-start-under-35000-when-it-comes-to-market-next-year/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 17:47:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric pickup truck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rivian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153016</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Los Angeles-based electric vehicle startup Canoo is bringing its first vehicle to market next year. The company said Monday its electric microbus-slash-van will be available to buy in 2022 at a base price of $34,750 before tax incentives or add-ons. It’s now taking preorders in the United States for the “lifestyle” vehicle, as well as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Los Angeles-based electric vehicle startup Canoo is bringing its first vehicle to market next year. The company said Monday its electric microbus-slash-van will be available to buy in 2022 at a base price of $34,750 before tax incentives or add-ons. It’s now taking preorders in the United States for the “lifestyle” vehicle, as well as for its round-top pickup truck and multi-purpose delivery van.</p>
<p>While Canoo did not release pricing for the other two vehicles, it said that deliveries for the pickup and production for the delivery van are slated to start as early as 2023. Customers can reserve a model by placing a $100 deposit per vehicle with the company.</p>
<p>The lifestyle van will come in four trims, including base, premium, adventure and so-called Lifestyle Vehicle Delivery. The adventure variant, which is the top trim and comes with more ground clearance and beefier profile, does not yet have a price. The base, delivery (not to be confused with the bigger multipurpose delivery van) and premium models will be priced up to $49,950, the company said. The company said the lifestyle van is expected to be able to produce 300 hp and 332 pound-feet of torque with 250 miles of battery range.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Canoo is taking a different route than many other electric vehicle manufacturers. The company&#8217;s trio of vehicles all have the same proprietary “skateboard” platform architecture that houses the batteries and electric drivetrain in a chassis that sits under the vehicle’s cabin. This contributes to a similar design language between the vehicles, which all have the same wide front windshield and relatively low profile.</p>
<p>The company is especially deviating from competitors with its electric pickup, which is scheduled to go into production in early 2023. As opposed to rivals Ford and Rivian, which are emphasizing size and power in their respective F-150 Lighting and R1T pickup trucks, Canoo’s is smaller and more playful-looking. The Rivian R1T clocks in at 218 inches long, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/canoo-combines-work-and-play-in-its-new-electric-pickup-truck/">while the Canoo truck will be 184 inches</a>. Canoo is also claiming a battery range of 200+ miles, far less than the 300+ boasted by other EV truck manufacturers. None of these companies have posted what the range will be when towing.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="t063DJuB1b"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/20/the-debut-of-electric-pickups-signals-a-new-ev-era/">The debut of electric pickups signals a new EV era</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The debut of electric pickups signals a new EV era&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/20/the-debut-of-electric-pickups-signals-a-new-ev-era/embed/#?secret=t063DJuB1b" data-secret="t063DJuB1b" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Canoo has undergone many transformations since its founding as Evelozcity in 2017. It was rebranded as Canoo in 2019 and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/18/electric-vehicle-startup-canoo-to-go-public-via-spac/">merged with special purpose acquisition company</a> Hennessy Capital Acquisition Corp. last December with a market valuation of $2.4 billion.</p>
<p>This year has been a bit bumpier for the company. The news on Monday comes less than a month after the company announced the resignations of its co-founder and CEO Ulrich Kranz and its general counsel Andrew Wolstan. Earlier this year, the company also lost its chief financial officer, Paul Balciunas, and its head of powertrain development.</p>
<p>Canoo’s skateboard architecture caught the eye of automaker Hyundai Motor Group, which last February said it would jointly develop an EV with Canoo based on the skateboard design. But during an investor call in March, Tony Aquila, who took over as company CEO following Kranz’s departure, said the deal was all but dead.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="umlETkiYYR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/canoo-combines-work-and-play-in-its-new-electric-pickup-truck/">Canoo combines work and play in its new electric pickup truck</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Canoo combines work and play in its new electric pickup truck&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/canoo-combines-work-and-play-in-its-new-electric-pickup-truck/embed/#?secret=umlETkiYYR" data-secret="umlETkiYYR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/canoos-electric-microbus-will-start-under-35000-when-it-comes-to-market-next-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153016</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The battle for voice recognition inside vehicles is heating up</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/the-battle-for-voice-recognition-inside-vehicles-is-heating-up/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/the-battle-for-voice-recognition-inside-vehicles-is-heating-up/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Halpert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 17:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazon alexa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[connected car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Market Map]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Mobility Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Assistant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Speech Recognition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual assistant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voice assistant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voice recognition]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2152193</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Once a feature only for luxury vehicles, voice recognition has moved into the mainstream as manufacturers promise a seamless connection between vehicles, homes and personal devices.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Once a fringe feature found only in luxury vehicles, voice recognition has moved into the mainstream as more automakers promise a seamless connection between your car, home and all the devices in between. The opportunity to reach consumers in their vehicles — and collect all that data — has automakers, tech giants like Amazon and Google, as well as investors scrambling for a share of the connected cars market.</p>
<p>But this is just the beginning. Voice recognition is expected to be an essential feature in future autonomous vehicles, which will see drivers ultimately surrendering the ability to control the car mechanically. Other applications for voice recognition are also emerging, including automated drones, two-wheelers and even air taxis.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Voice recognition is expected to be an essential feature in future autonomous vehicles, which will see drivers ultimately surrendering the ability to control the car mechanically.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>The upshot? A market with significant growth potential and opportunities for investors and companies of all sizes.</p>
<h2>The opportunity</h2>
<p>The share of cars featuring in-car connected services, which voice recognition requires, grew to 45% in 2020 from 30% in 2018, and is expected to reach 60% by 2024, according to IHS Markit. Automakers keen to improve the consumer experience are driving that growth, said Kyle Davis, IHS Markit&#8217;s senior analyst for vehicle experience and connected car, noting that &#8220;one of the biggest aspects of the user experience is voice.&#8221;<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/the-battle-for-voice-recognition-inside-vehicles-is-heating-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2152193</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Discuss the future of connected fitness with Mirror’s Brynn Putnam at Disrupt 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/discuss-the-future-of-connected-fitness-with-mirrors-brynn-putnam-at-disrupt-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/discuss-the-future-of-connected-fitness-with-mirrors-brynn-putnam-at-disrupt-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 17:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brynn Putnam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mirror]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2152647</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The global pandemic made some industries and utterly decimated others. The world of connected fitness falls firmly into the former. Along with top names like Peloton, Mirror had a banner year, including, most notably, sportwear company Lululemon’s acquisition of the brand for $500 million in June. It’s an impressive number for the five-year-old company, which [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The global pandemic made some industries and utterly decimated others. The world of connected fitness falls firmly into the former. Along with top names like Peloton, Mirror had a banner year, including, most notably, sportwear company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/29/lululemon-set-to-acquire-home-fitness-startup-mirror-for-500m/">Lululemon’s acquisition of the brand</a> for $500 million in June.</p>
<p>It’s an impressive number for the five-year-old company, which came out of stealth at TechCrunch Disrupt in 2018. Three years later, CEO Brynn Putnam will <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021?promo=mirrorpost">return to the Disrupt stage on September 21-23</a> to chart how the company grew from a small-scale startup to one of the leading names in a home fitness industry that saw a massive surge over the past year and a half.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="66V06FXhlX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/mirror-founder-brynn-putnam-on-life-with-lululemon-and-whether-or-not-she-sold-too-soon/">Mirror founder Brynn Putnam on life with Lululemon &#8212; and whether or not she sold too soon</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Mirror founder Brynn Putnam on life with Lululemon &#8212; and whether or not she sold too soon&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/mirror-founder-brynn-putnam-on-life-with-lululemon-and-whether-or-not-she-sold-too-soon/embed/#?secret=66V06FXhlX" data-secret="66V06FXhlX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>A former ballerina and founder of New York fitness chain Refine Method, Putnam’s career has been a fascinating one &#8212; up to and including her time at Mirror. We’ll discuss how the company embraced a boom in connected fitness, why the time was right for acquisition and what the landscape for the industry will look like going forward.</p>
<p>Stay at home orders have had a profound impact on the way we get fit, leading many frequent gym goers to embrace high-tech, at-home methods. Is this the beginning of a sea change for the way the world works out? Or will a return to normal lead buyers to dust off their gym memberships? Find out at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021?promo=mirrorpost&amp;display=true">TC Disrupt his September</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021?promo=mirrorpost&amp;display=true">grab your tickets for under $99</a> for a limited time!</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			width="99%"
			height="1300"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/discuss-the-future-of-connected-fitness-with-mirrors-brynn-putnam-at-disrupt-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2152647</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sequoia&#8217;s Shaun Maguire and Vise&#8217;s Samir Vasavada will talk success in fintech on Extra Crunch Live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/sequoias-shaun-maguire-and-vises-samir-vasavada-will-talk-success-in-fintech-on-extra-crunch-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/sequoias-shaun-maguire-and-vises-samir-vasavada-will-talk-success-in-fintech-on-extra-crunch-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 16:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ECL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch live announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samir Vasavada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shaun Maguire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vise]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144992</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the past few weeks, we&#8217;ve heard Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand discuss the biggest opportunities in prop tech, heard why Scale AI&#8217;s Alex Wang and Accel&#8217;s Dan Levine think that unconventional VC deals can be the best option and taken a stroll through the Poshmark Series A deck with CEO Manish [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In the past few weeks, we&#8217;ve heard <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/fifth-walls-brendan-wallace-and-hippos-assaf-wand-discuss-proptechs-biggest-opportunities/">Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand discuss the biggest opportunities in prop tech</a>, heard why <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/09/scale-ceo-alex-wang-and-accels-dan-levine-explain-why-sometimes-unconventional-vc-deals-are-best/">Scale AI&#8217;s Alex Wang and Accel&#8217;s Dan Levine think that unconventional VC deals can be the best option</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/27/ceo-manish-chandra-and-investor-navin-chaddha-explain-why-poshmarks-series-a-deck-sings/">taken a stroll through the Poshmark Series A deck with CEO Manish Chandra and Mayfield&#8217;s Navin Chaddha</a>.</p>
<p>This is the particular flavor of content, rich in key insights and tactical advice for founders, that goes down on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">Extra Crunch Live</a>.</p>
<p>In an upcoming episode on Wednesday, May 19, we&#8217;ll sit down with Sequoia&#8217;s Shaun Maguire and Vise CEO and co-founder Samir Vasavada.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Maguire focuses on enterprise, fintech and frontier technology for Sequoia. His portfolio companies include AMP Robotics, Knowde, Physna and Vise. He joined Sequoia in 2019, before which he was a partner at GV, where he led investments in Stripe, Opendoor, IonQ, SpinLaunch, Lambda School, Dandelion Energy, Clutter and Mode and sourced the firm&#8217;s investment in Segment.</p>
<p>Maguire has also been an entrepreneur in his own right, co-founding Expanse (a cybersecurity company), which was ultimately acquired by Palo Alto Networks for more than $800 million.</p>
<p>If that weren&#8217;t enough, Maguire also spent two years working at DARPA, and was deployed to Afghanistan, participating on a team that earned a Joint Meritorious Unit Award from the U.S. Secretary of Defense.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qxlRjkZOHq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/28/justworks-series-b-pitch-deck-may-be-the-most-wonderfully-simple-deck-ive-ever-seen/">Justworks&#8217; Series B pitch deck may be the most wonderfully simple deck I&#8217;ve ever seen</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Justworks&#8217; Series B pitch deck may be the most wonderfully simple deck I&#8217;ve ever seen&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/28/justworks-series-b-pitch-deck-may-be-the-most-wonderfully-simple-deck-ive-ever-seen/embed/#?secret=qxlRjkZOHq" data-secret="qxlRjkZOHq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Samir Vasavada co-founded Vise in 2016. Vise is an AI-powered investment management platform that aims to give independent financial advisors access to technology and tools to build and manage personalized portfolios for their clients, ultimately giving those advisors more time and energy to spend on the relationships.</p>
<p>Vise has raised upwards of $60 million.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll talk to Maguire and Vasavada about what brought them together, key tips for fundraising and how to be successful in the fintech space, and ask about the next great opportunity in fintech.</p>
<p>On the second half of the episode, Maguire and Vasavada will put on their feedback hats and listen to live elevator pitches from the audience as part of the ECL Pitch-off. Folks attending the event will be able to raise their hand and pitch their startup to the VC/founder duo, and then answer their questions and get their feedback.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Gf6Lh32w8b"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/join-ecl-on-wednesday-to-pitch-your-startup-to-fifth-walls-brendan-wallace-and-hippos-assaf-wand/">Join ECL on Wednesday to pitch your startup to Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Join ECL on Wednesday to pitch your startup to Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/join-ecl-on-wednesday-to-pitch-your-startup-to-fifth-walls-brendan-wallace-and-hippos-assaf-wand/embed/#?secret=Gf6Lh32w8b" data-secret="Gf6Lh32w8b" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But the only way you can pitch is to show up. This episode of Extra Crunch Live goes down on Wednesday, May 19 at 3pm ET/12pm PT. Anyone can attend as long as they register here, but on-demand access to the content is reserved strictly for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe">Extra Crunch members</a>, who also have access to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">complete library of Extra Crunch Live content, among many, many other awesome articles and perks. </a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/sequoias-shaun-maguire-and-vises-samir-vasavada-will-talk-success-in-fintech-on-extra-crunch-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144992</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SpaceX launched 52 more Starlink satellites to orbit on Saturday</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/spacex-launched-52-more-starlink-satellites-to-orbit-on-saturday/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/spacex-launched-52-more-starlink-satellites-to-orbit-on-saturday/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 16:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Falcon 9]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satellites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starlink]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2152971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SpaceX successfully launched another 52 Starlink internet broadband satellites into orbit on Saturday, less than one week after it sent up the last batch. A small satellite from startup Capella Space and a Tyvak observation satellite also hitched a ride on the launch, which took off from Kennedy Space Center in Florida on Saturday evening. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">SpaceX successfully launched another 52 Starlink internet broadband satellites into orbit on Saturday, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/09/spacex-launches-and-lands-a-falcon-9-rocket-booster-a-record-10th-time/">less than one week</a> after it sent up the last batch. A small satellite from startup Capella Space and a Tyvak observation satellite also hitched a ride on the launch, which took off from Kennedy Space Center in Florida on Saturday evening.</p>
<p>The launch used a veteran Falcon 9 booster that’s seen seven previous launch and landings, including during three Starlink missions. It departed from its launch pad at 6:56 PM ET (3:56 PM PT) and returned to Earth approximately nine minutes later. The rocket landed vertically on SpaceX’s autonomous drone ship “Of Course I Still Love You” in the Atlantic Ocean.</p>
<p>The launch company has now sent more than 530 Starlink satellites to space since March, and all of them on reused rockets. Reusability is a key factor toward making the launches as cost-effective as possible, a factor that is especially important as SpaceX is both the launch provider and customer of the Starlink service. As a consequence, SpaceX has been able to rapidly accelerate its Starlink launch program, with 28 launches under its belt so far. At least one additional launch is likely in the works for later this month.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company said earlier this month that it had received <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/spacex-launches-60-more-starlink-satellites-claims-over-500000-service-pre-orders-so-far/">“over half a million”</a> pre-order reservations for Starlink broadband service so far. Starlink is available in beta to customers in six countries: Australia, New Zealand, the U.S., the United Kingdom, Mexico and Canada. SpaceX CEO Elon Musk has said the company aims to have its low Earth orbit broadband internet network operational across nearly the entire globe as early as the end of 2021.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ngkuG9iphP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/spacex-launches-60-more-starlink-satellites-claims-over-500000-service-pre-orders-so-far/">SpaceX launches 60 more Starlink satellites, claims over 500,000 service pre-orders so far</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SpaceX launches 60 more Starlink satellites, claims over 500,000 service pre-orders so far&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/spacex-launches-60-more-starlink-satellites-claims-over-500000-service-pre-orders-so-far/embed/#?secret=ngkuG9iphP" data-secret="ngkuG9iphP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BzB6szLcKo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/20/spacexs-spin-out-startups-are-helping-build-las-startup-ecosystem/">SpaceX alumni are helping build LA&#8217;s startup ecosystem</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SpaceX alumni are helping build LA&#8217;s startup ecosystem&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/20/spacexs-spin-out-startups-are-helping-build-las-startup-ecosystem/embed/#?secret=BzB6szLcKo" data-secret="BzB6szLcKo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/spacex-launched-52-more-starlink-satellites-to-orbit-on-saturday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2152971</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Power up your networking with CrunchMatch at TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/powerup-your-networking-with-crunchmatch-at-tc-sessions-mobility-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/powerup-your-networking-with-crunchmatch-at-tc-sessions-mobility-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 16:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CrunchMatch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FlashParking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions: Mobility 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151069</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When thousands of mobility mavens from around the world gather at TC Sessions: Mobility 2021 on June 9, you’re going to need an efficient, organized way to tap all that opportunity. Meeting folks is easy. Meeting the people who align with your goals and can help move your business forward — that’s even better. We’ve [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When thousands of mobility mavens from around the world gather at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=crunchmatch&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=crunchmatch&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</a> on June 9, you’re going to need an efficient, organized way to tap all that opportunity. Meeting folks is easy. Meeting the people who align with your goals and can help move your business forward — that’s even better. We’ve got just the tool to help you do that.</p>
<p>But first, a not-so-subtle reminder from the home office: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=crunchmatch&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=crunchmatch&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Buy your pass to TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</a>.</p>
<p>Now then, about that networking tool. We’re talking about CrunchMatch, our AI-powered networking platform. Simply register for Mobility 2021, answer a few quick questions about your business preferences, and within minutes you’re automatically registered for CrunchMatch. Keep your eyes peeled for an email telling you how and when to access the platform.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>CrunchMatch goes to work searching for suitable matches based on the info you provided. The algorithm it uses makes fast, precise recommendations, and it gets smarter the more you use it.</p>
<p>So, who’s on your dream networking list — investors, founders, engineers, R&amp;D teams, manufacturers, supply-chain experts? CrunchMatch helps you connect and schedule private 1:1 video meetings. Pitch those investors, demo products to potential clients, interview prospective employees. It’s a targeted, fast and efficient way to boost your brand and build your business.</p>
<blockquote><p>The networking at TC Sessions: Mobility is terrific. Our company’s building momentum in the U.S. market, and the opportunity to meet and talk with all the players is very important. The CrunchMatch platform made it easy to connect and schedule meetings. — Melika Jahangiri, vice president at Wunder Mobility.</p></blockquote>
<p>And if you’re wondering whether anything concrete comes out of networking at TC Sessions: Mobility, here’s how Karin Maake, senior director of communications at FlashParking, described her experience:</p>
<blockquote><p>TC Sessions: Mobility isn&#8217;t just an educational opportunity, it&#8217;s a real networking opportunity. Everyone was passionate and open to creating pilot programs or other partnerships. That was the most exciting part. And now — thanks to a conference connection — we’re talking with Goodyear&#8217;s Innovation Lab.</p></blockquote>
<p>Check out our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/#c861bf5b-e0a9-4806-a40d-c1c4c86d8ea5">roster of speakers</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/#878941bf-c22c-4ec4-ab2f-d8c0c15cb8ae">the event agenda</a> and start strategizing about which mobility experts you want to include on your networking wish-list.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=crunchmatch&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=crunchmatch&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</a> takes place on June 9. This day-long conference will be packed to the gills with attendees from around the globe. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=crunchmatch&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=crunchmatch&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Buy your pass today</a>, and power up your networking with CrunchMatch.</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at TC Sessions: Mobility 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html?_ga=2.147735806.874617471.1572269011-985484541.1566312242">filling out this form</a><em>.</em></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-71a70eba569f6ab0fb6c9a63fc276b30"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/71a70eba569f6ab0fb6c9a63fc276b30"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-71a70eba569f6ab0fb6c9a63fc276b30')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-71a70eba569f6ab0fb6c9a63fc276b30'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/powerup-your-networking-with-crunchmatch-at-tc-sessions-mobility-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151069</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
