<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 21:33:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Grab&#8217;s SPAC splat caps off a bad week for blank-check combinations</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/grabs-spac-splat-caps-off-a-bad-week-for-blank-check-combinations/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/grabs-spac-splat-caps-off-a-bad-week-for-blank-check-combinations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 21:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2242418</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What goes up must come down. And what goes SPAC must go splat? We&#8217;ll keep workshopping that. Regardless, shares of super app Grab took a pounding today after its SPAC combination was approved last night and began to trade this morning. Grab&#8217;s stock initially rose, before falling sharply as the day went on. By the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">What goes up must come down. And what goes SPAC must go splat? We&#8217;ll keep workshopping that.</p>
<p>Regardless, shares of super app Grab took a pounding today after its SPAC combination was approved last night and began to trade this morning. Grab&#8217;s stock initially rose, before falling sharply as the day went on.</p>
<p>By the close of trading, Grab was worth $8.75 per share, or down 20.53%, per Yahoo Finance&#8217;s <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/GRAB?p=GRAB">count</a>. Shares fell another 1.7% as of the time of writing.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2242418" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>But Grab&#8217;s lackluster performance was only one from SPAC-led debuts today. Buzzfeed also ran into a <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/buzzfeed-suffers-wave-of-spac-investor-withdrawals-before-going-public-11638472756">redemption buzzsaw</a> while trying to get its SPAC deal done, while its staff was in <a href="https://twitter.com/bfnewsunion">open revolt</a> and its leadership tried to bring them into line by threatening to dock their pay &#8212; that will fix it, surely.</p>
<p>And there was more. MetroMile, the neoinsurance company that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/pay-per-mile-auto-insurer-metromile-is-heading-to-public-markets-via-spac/">went public via a SPAC</a>, hit a new 52-week low today of $2.27 per share before recovering. Given that the company&#8217;s 52-week <em>high</em> was just over $20 per share, its declines are this side of legendary.</p>
<p>There are other splashes of SPAC blood on the public-market walls. Shares of Desktop Metal are under the $6 mark after shooting as high as $34.94 in the last year. That&#8217;s another SPAC combo that has largely deflated post-consummation. Who else? Lordstown: Today it&#8217;s worth $4.14 per share, despite being worth as much as $31.56 in the last year.</p>
<p>The list goes on. There will be some SPAC winners. SoFi is still above the $10 per share mark by a good margin, for example, but <em>woof</em>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>What about Grab, though?</h2>
<p>When we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/super-app-grab-starts-trading-on-supersized-spac-combination/">were parsing Grab&#8217;s third-quarter results this morning</a>, we noted its falling revenues and rising losses. Those key performance metrics were pointing in the wrong direction.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fFQ9vtzxHJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/super-app-grab-starts-trading-on-supersized-spac-combination/">Super app Grab starts trading on supersized SPAC combination</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Super app Grab starts trading on supersized SPAC combination&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/super-app-grab-starts-trading-on-supersized-spac-combination/embed/#?secret=fFQ9vtzxHJ" data-secret="fFQ9vtzxHJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Still, with redemptions at effectively zero, and the <a href="https://www.axios.com/grab-trading-spac-merger-nasdaq-d4452495-01b0-46b7-9d6a-d6ef94746cef.html">SPAC backer holding for three years</a>, I presumed that there was something in Grab that I was missing. There was not, as it turned out.</p>
<p>The growth method of avoiding investor discontent is to post lots of revenue expansion, thus making even <em>rising</em> losses appear smaller, at least in percentage-of-revenue terms. Flat losses are better. And falling losses best, of course. But if revenue is in decline <em>while</em> losses are going up, then things are <em>bad</em>.</p>
<p>Not that Grab won&#8217;t pull it all together in time. It might! But going public with falling top line and rising red ink was never going to be easy. Perhaps we should be less surprised that Grab has managed little other than underperformance thus far as a public company.</p>
<p>Not a great week for SPACs.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/grabs-spac-splat-caps-off-a-bad-week-for-blank-check-combinations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2242418</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gillmor Gang: Get Better Back</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/gillmor-gang-get-better-back/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/gillmor-gang-get-better-back/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 21:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brent Leary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denis Pombriant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frank radice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keith Teare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Markman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2241959</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a discussion about culture versus history on this edition of the Gang, Denis Pombriant invokes the Beatles as examples of agents of change that used rock and roll to alter the arc of history. &#8220;Just understand that four kids from Liverpool changed the entire culture of the world. Not immediately, but over time.&#8221; With [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QuG2DAO7CrI?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>In a discussion about culture versus history on this edition of the Gang, Denis Pombriant invokes the Beatles as examples of agents of change that used rock and roll to alter the arc of history. &#8220;Just understand that four kids from Liverpool changed the entire culture of the world. Not immediately, but over time.&#8221; With the release of almost 8 hours of footage documented the beginning of the group&#8217;s last year of existence, those of us who revere the output and impact that ended some 50 years ago have perhaps now reached our limit. As I endured the 3-part saga each night of the Thanksgiving holiday weekend, I kept thinking that enough was finally enough.</p>
<p>Maybe Jack Dorsey thought the same thing as he quit his CEO job at Twitter. Conventional wisdom says he either was asked to leave by a board larded with corporate raiders and unhappy investors, or just plain was done. I think he did a pretty good job with a social network invented by him and loved by its embedded fans. Recent social software like newsletters and Clubhouse clones has brought the company to an interesting place in the road where it can serve the role of a postwar Hollywood studio managing the transition to a new era of subscription media.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2241959" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Saturday morning I&#8217;m some two hours away from the end of the Beatles&#8217; Get Back, and it&#8217;s been much more than I&#8217;d imagined. For days I&#8217;ve been joking that this is finally the end of the story, but it&#8217;s nothing like that. The thing that was created may be over, but the group is really just now forming its place in the history of the world. Each day grows closer to the moment when Lennon hopes they&#8217;ve passed the audition, but we already know the answer from the earliest moments. Yes it is, it&#8217;s true.</p>
<p>Harrison is the deepest into the essence of what they&#8217;ve created, with his anger fueling the project. The three song writers are done listening to each other on a pragmatic level, struggling with their fame but not willing to give any of it up just yet. Harrison and Ringo decrypt Octopus&#8217;s Garden, but the kernel in the scene is George&#8217;s command of the full Beatle envelope. As he sketches out the chord structure of Ringo&#8217;s tune, he foreshadows the second part of the project, the Abbey Road return to Beatle studio magic. As each chord resonates, the shimmer of the Beatle process appears, glows, and then is replaced by the next chord and process.</p>
<p>Lennon and McCartney exist more in relation to each other, each somewhat frozen in fatigue from grappling with the other. Harrison is more than willing to blow things up, but his ongoing narrative commentary is both accurate and positive in its optimism. He&#8217;s been living in this fishbowl long enough to know he is the only one of the group to prod it forward. When he injects Billy Preston into the sessions, everyone else can see what is obvious to Harrison. When McCartney runs down Let It Be, Preston disappears into the mix. Lennon thirsts for the live feel Preston summons, but McCartney won&#8217;t surrender his apparent control of the project by endorsing a new group member.</p>
<p>A different hierarchy emerges in the film: Without Lennon (asleep or anesthetized at home) the three default to McCartney but function only when Harrison is engaged. When McCartney senses the Frankenstein he’s enabled in Harrison, he retreats to the relative safety of Lennon’s call-and-response wit. Ringo’s eyes widen as he waits for his opening, a coiled cheshire cat. Harrison lays trap after trap for those who appear unobservant only to comment later on what was going down. George Martin is a third straight project deep into unraveling this slow motion meltdown, but appears surprisingly ineffective at adding punch to the rope-a-dope circulating in the room. Watch Harrison’s eyes as he glancingly acknowledges the camera for only the frames necessary to raise a smile. He is the director, screenwriter, and auteur of this thing.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Several remaining questions: what went on the day the group forbade the cameras at Saville Row? Before the pause and palpably after, the music tightens up as the band does some of its magic to the material. Harrison&#8217;s Get Back lead guitar switches places with Lennon&#8217;s rhythm guitar. The presumed wisdom is that the Quiet Beatle is laying out post-quitting the Twickenham sessions, but the results suggest otherwise. McCartney&#8217;s chops on the roof are transformational on all the tracks, a sign of the songs having locked into a pocket to be mined in the studio a few weeks later on Abbey Road tracks I Want You (She&#8217;s So Heavy), Something, and Come Together.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t believe the conventional wisdom. Now that we&#8217;ve all been in the room, who&#8217;s kidding who? Not McCartney, who talked divorce well before the project ran aground in the drafty Twickenham studio. Not Lennon, who months earlier knew the group was in trouble when their manager died. The Magical Mystery Tour debacle should have convinced them they couldn&#8217;t just wing a TV show, but they tried it again anyway. George Martin wasn&#8217;t their producer; he was their mentor. Ringo actually married a Bond girl. They spoke a secret language to each other. There was no Fifth Beatle.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><strong><em>the latest <a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang/archive/888815">Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center">__________________</p>
<p>The Gillmor Gang — Frank Radice, Michael Markman, Keith Teare, Denis Pombriant, Brent Leary and Steve Gillmor. Recorded live Friday, November 19, 2021.</p>
<p>Produced and directed by Tina Chase Gillmor @tinagillmor</p>
<p>@fradice, @mickeleh, @denispombriant, @kteare, @brentleary, @stevegillmor, @gillmorgang</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang">Subscribe to the new Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></strong> and join the backchannel <a href="https://t.me/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> on Telegram.</p>
<p><a href="http://facebook.com/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Gillmor Gang on Facebook</a> … and here’s our sister show <a href="http://facebook.com/g3show" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">G3 on Facebook</a>.<img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2012361" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2012361" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/gillmor-gang-get-better-back/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2241959</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NASA awards Blue Origin, Nanoracks, Northrop Grumman over $400M in contracts to avoid space station gap</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/nasa-awards-blue-origin-nanoracks-northrop-grumman-over-400m-in-contracts-to-avoid-space-station-gap/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/nasa-awards-blue-origin-nanoracks-northrop-grumman-over-400m-in-contracts-to-avoid-space-station-gap/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 21:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Axiom Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boeing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial leo destinations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial space stations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nanoracks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[northrop grumman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private space stations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voyager space]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2242445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just two days after officially (and quietly) confirming that it intends to replace the International Space Station with a commercial station by 2030, NASA has awarded over $400 million in agreements to three companies to further develop private station plans. The three companies, which received the awards under the agency’s Commercial low Earth orbit (LEO) [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Just two days after officially (and quietly) confirming that it intends to replace the International Space Station with a commercial station by 2030, NASA has awarded over $400 million in agreements to three companies to further develop private station plans.</p>
<p>The three companies, which received the awards under the agency’s Commercial low Earth orbit (LEO) Destinations program, are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Nanoracks for $160 million</li>
<li>Blue Origin for $130 million</li>
<li>Northrop Grumman for $125.6 million</li>
</ul>
<p>The three companies have already released a handful of details about their proposals. Blue Origin is calling its station concept <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/blue-origin-boeing-and-others-join-sierra-space-to-build-commercial-space-station/">“Orbital Reef,”</a> and it is designing it with Boeing, Sierra Space and others. The team said it wants to launch the station in 2027. Meanwhile, Nanoracks is calling its station, which is being developed with its parent company Voyager Space and aerospace prime Lockheed Martin, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/voyager-nanoracks-and-lockheeds-starlab-is-the-latest-sign-that-the-low-earth-orbit-economy-is-coming/">“Starlab.”</a> While Northrop didn’t give its station proposal a flashy name, it’s working with Dynetics to deliver a modular design based around its Cygnus spacecraft.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2242445" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>These substantial awards mark the first phase of a two-phase process as NASA seeks to ensure that there will be no gap between the retirement of the ISS and the introduction of a new station. NASA has repeatedly stressed, both to Congress and more recently in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/30/nasa-details-intent-to-replace-the-international-space-station-with-a-commercial-space-station-by-2030/">a report by the Office of Inspector General</a>, that the overall success of the development of a thriving economy in LEO is dependent upon avoiding this gap.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2223413" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223413" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2223413" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Orbital-Reef-Underneath.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Orbital-Reef-Underneath.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Orbital-Reef-Underneath.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Orbital-Reef-Underneath.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Orbital-Reef-Underneath.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Orbital-Reef-Underneath.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Orbital-Reef-Underneath.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Orbital-Reef-Underneath.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Orbital-Reef-Underneath.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2223413" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://www.blueorigin.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blue Origin <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>“If there is no habitable commercial destination in low Earth orbit after the ISS is decommissioned, NASA will be unable to conduct microgravity health research and technology demonstrations needed for long-duration human exploration missions to the Moon and Mars, significantly increasing the risk of—or delaying—those missions,” the agency said in the report.</p>
<p>To dodge this potential scenario, NASA has proposed for one or more commercial LEO “destinations” (as it sometimes calls stations) to be operational by 2028 – giving a two-year overlap before the ISS is retired by the end of the decade. This first set of awards will help the companies develop their designs, work that is expected to continue through 2025.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In the second phase of the program, NASA intends to certify for human use one or more stations – from this group of companies or other entrants – and ultimately become one of many customers purchasing in-orbit services and use of the stations. NASA said in a statement that this will allow it to focus on its Artemis program, which aims to return humans to the Moon, and eventually human spaceflight to Mars.</p>
<p>Notably absent is Axiom Space, which won a separate award to send up modules to attach to the ISS before separating and self-orbiting as its own station, but the company clarified that it did not bid on CLD.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/nasa-awards-blue-origin-nanoracks-northrop-grumman-over-400m-in-contracts-to-avoid-space-station-gap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2242445</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here&#8217;s a first look at the new Polestar SUV and how it fits in the automaker&#8217;s three-year plan</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/heres-a-first-look-at-the-new-polestar-suv-and-how-it-fits-in-the-automakers-three-year-plan/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/heres-a-first-look-at-the-new-polestar-suv-and-how-it-fits-in-the-automakers-three-year-plan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 21:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Polestar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Polestar 3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Polestar Precept]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Polestar SUV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volvo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2242429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From its motorsport beginnings to today, Swedish electric automaker Polestar has come a long way. According to CEO Thomas Ingenlath, the Volvo spin off is just getting started. Ingenlath, along with members of the automaker&#8217;s leadership team, laid out a three-year plan for Polestar during a presentation in New York on Thursday that included an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">From its motorsport beginnings to today, Swedish electric automaker Polestar has come a long way. According to CEO Thomas Ingenlath, the Volvo spin off is just getting started.</p>
<p>Ingenlath, along with members of the automaker&#8217;s leadership team, laid out a three-year plan for Polestar during a presentation in New York on Thursday that included an ambitious sales goal and a peek at its next electric vehicle.</p>
<p>&#8220;Cars are a very highly emotional affair,&#8221; Ingenlath said as he kicked off his pitch to media.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2242429" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2242434" style="width: 8619px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Polestar_3.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2242434" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2242434 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Polestar_3.jpg" alt="Polestar 3 electric vehicle" width="8609" height="6456" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Polestar_3.jpg 8609w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Polestar_3.jpg?resize=150,112 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Polestar_3.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Polestar_3.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Polestar_3.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Polestar_3.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Polestar_3.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Polestar_3.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 8609px) 100vw, 8609px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2242434" class="wp-caption-text">Polestar 3 electric vehicle teased at an event in December 2021. <strong>Image credit</strong>: Polestar</p></div></p>
<p>At its core, the plan is to launch three new vehicles by 2024, expand the number of vehicles sold to about 290,000 units, and do so in new markets across Europe and Asia Pacific. The foundations for this expansion are the company&#8217;s own core values of design, sustainability, innovation and customer engagement.</p>
<p>Sustainability in particular was emphasized during the event, with Polestar reaffirming its mission to produce a carbon neutral car by 2030. This will be dependent on a number of sustainable practices big and small, from using recycled materials to changing how Polestar does business on the supply chain level.</p>
<p>We know very little about the upcoming Polestars 3 and 4, though Ingenlath insisted the ball was rolling on production of both, even offering a teaser image of the 3 to whet the EV aficionados&#8217; appetites. The all-electric SUV will be <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/polestar-to-build-its-first-all-electric-suv-in-the-united-states/">built in the United States</a>, specifically in Charleston, South Carolina.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Along with being produced in a climate-responsible manner, the Polestar 3 will also be equipped with hardware from lidar developer Luminar and Nvidia-sourced processors to make its advanced driver assistance system capable of automated driving on highways, though it seems this feature won&#8217;t be available at launch.</p>
<p>Little beyond that is known of the 3 and even less of the Polestar 4, though it&#8217;s billed as a premium sport SUV &#8220;Coupe,&#8221; with a more rakish fastback profile, according to the teaser graphics displayed during the presentation. Polestar has also used the Porsche Cayenne and Macan as price-point benchmarks for the 3 and 4 respectively, so we can infer that these competitors also set the bar for the level of luxury and performance both cars intend to challenge.</p>
<p>Interestingly, the car we know the most about is the furthest one away: the Polestar 5.</p>
<p>It was recently announced that the Precept Concept will indeed go into <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/polestar-is-bringing-its-precept-sedan-to-market-in-2024-with-a-new-name/">full production as the 5th Polestar</a>, a four-door luxury sport GT. As it stands, the Precept is in a way a physical declaration of Polestar&#8217;s future and will inform the upcoming SUVs as well.</p>
<p>The jump from 29,000 units sold to 290,000 in three years sounds daunting, as well as increasing Polestar&#8217;s presence, but Ingenlath isn&#8217;t worried. &#8220;From here on in, Polestar is all about growth.&#8221;</p>
<p>With its production already underway, we&#8217;ll likely hear more about the Polestar 3 sooner than later.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/heres-a-first-look-at-the-new-polestar-suv-and-how-it-fits-in-the-automakers-three-year-plan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2242429</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GM delays production of new Chevy Bolt EVs until end of January</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/gm-delays-production-of-new-chevy-bolt-evs-until-end-of-january/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/gm-delays-production-of-new-chevy-bolt-evs-until-end-of-january/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 20:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chevy bolt recall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2242355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[General Motors will continue to delay production of new Chevrolet Bolt EVs at the company&#8217;s Orion assembly plant in Michigan &#8220;through the week of Jan. 24, 2022,&#8221; the company said in a statement emailed to TechCrunch on Thursday. The automaker said it would instead &#8220;continue to focus on battery module replacements&#8221; for tens of thousands [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">General Motors will continue to delay production of new Chevrolet Bolt EVs at the company&#8217;s Orion assembly plant in Michigan &#8220;through the week of Jan. 24, 2022,&#8221; the company said in a statement emailed to TechCrunch on Thursday. The automaker said it would instead &#8220;continue to focus on battery module replacements&#8221; for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/23/gm-recalls-bolt-evs-once-again-over-fire-risks/">tens of thousands of Chevy Bolts</a> that were recalled earlier this year due to potential fire risks within the batteries.</p>
<p>The plant has been shut down since August 23, and GM has repeatedly pushed back production dates for new Bolt vehicles.</p>
<p>In October, GM started shipping dealers replacement battery modules for the recalled Chevrolet Bolt electric vehicles. A GM spokesperson said the company was not publicly disclosing any specifics on the number of modules that had been shipped or replaced.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2242355" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;We continue to ramp up repairs and are focused on completing the repairs as quickly as possible,&#8221; the company spokesperson said in an email. &#8220;In fact, we notified employees at our Orion assembly plant (the assembly plant for the BOLT EV) that we are keeping the plant down through January to continue to prioritize recall repairs.&#8221;</p>
<p>In May, the company planned to add new software that would prevent fires to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/nhtsa-urges-some-chevy-bolt-owners-to-park-their-car-away-from-home-citing-fire-risk/">2017 to 2019 Bolts</a> that were originally recalled after a few fires were reported. When the software wasn&#8217;t effective, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/23/gm-recalls-bolt-evs-once-again-over-fire-risks/">Chevy issued a recall in July</a>. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/20/general-motors-issues-third-recall-for-chevrolet-bolt-evs-citing-rare-battery-defects/">The automaker recalled all Bolt EVs in August</a> after a newer model year Bolt caught fire.</p>
<p>LG Chem, the manufacturers of Chevy&#8217;s Bolt batteries, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/lg-will-cover-nearly-the-entire-cost-of-gms-chevy-bolt-ev-recall/">has since agreed to pay the nearly $2 billion cost of the recall</a>.</p>
<p>During <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/gm-says-it-will-double-revenue-by-2030-take-ev-market-share-from-tesla/">GM&#8217;s investor day in October</a>, the company said it would double its revenues by the end of the decade and take over EV market share from Tesla. The company previously pledged to release 30 new EVs by 2025, but so far, all GM has announced schedules for are its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/gmc-will-begin-hummer-ev-deliveries-in-december/">GMC Hummer EV pickup</a>, which is scheduled for delivery by the end of 2021, the Hummer EV SUV, which is scheduled for 2023, and the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/cadillacs-all-electric-lyriq-flagship-to-start-just-below-60000/">Cadillac Lyric</a>, which should come to market by early next year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/gm-delays-production-of-new-chevy-bolt-evs-until-end-of-january/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2242355</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: What are the latest rules for H-1B visas?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/dear-sophie-what-are-the-latest-rules-for-h-1b-visas/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/dear-sophie-what-are-the-latest-rules-for-h-1b-visas/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 20:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B visa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Labor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2241502</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have been applying for positions in the U.S., and one company says that if they hire me and get me an H-1B visa, the filing fees and cost will be taken out of my paycheck. Is that allowed?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/dear-sophie-how-long-does-international-entrepreneur-parole-take/">Dear Sophie: How long does International Entrepreneur Parole take?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/17/dear-sophie-any-advice-on-visa-issues-for-new-hires/">Dear Sophie: Any advice on visa issues for new hires?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">​​Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>TechCrunch+ members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2241502" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<hr />
<p><strong>Dear Sophie,</strong></p>
<p><strong>I’ve always wanted to live and work in the United States. I have been applying for software engineering positions in the United States, and one company says that if they hire me and get me an H-1B visa, the filing fees and cost will be taken out of my paycheck. Is that allowed? </strong></p>
<p><strong>Also, is it permissible to have more than one company put me into the H-1B lottery so I have a better chance of being selected? Will the companies find out?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Motivated in Morocco</strong></p>
<p>Dear Motivated,</p>
<p>I appreciate you reaching out with your questions! Now is an ideal time to look for job opportunities with companies that are willing to sponsor prospective hires for an <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/what-we-do/h-1b_speciality_occupations/">H-1B</a>. Most companies have started — or will soon start — the process of identifying H-1B candidates. I recently dove into a few of your questions and more dos and don’ts in a recent <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/099-h-1b-planning-for-fy2023/">podcast about the H-1B lottery process</a>, which will begin in March.</p>
<p>As many startups are dealing with the Great Resignation by hiring talented professionals, such as software engineers, remotely using various global professional employer organizations (PEOs), your questions are common heading into the next lottery season.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For a startup, putting a candidate in the H-1B lottery can be a great way to support your talented team member because the number of H-1B registrants rises each year. Startups often eagerly support their team members through H-1B sponsorship to enable them to have a better life in the U.S. and increase loyalty, as well as to bring them into a more synchronous time zone to enable fluid collaboration.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100312" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100312" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2100312" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg" alt="A composite image of immigration law attorney Sophie Alcorn in front of a background with a TechCrunch logo." width="1024" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=1536,1013 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Joanna Buniak / <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sophie Alcorn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<h2>Who pays H-1B fees and costs?</h2>
<p>According to federal regulations, an employer cannot collect H-1B-related fees and costs for the “employer’s business expenses” from the beneficiary of the H-1B visa.</p>
<p>That means the employer must pay the $10 registration fee to enter employees or prospective employees into the lottery, attorney fees and costs connected with the H-1B program, and the cost of preparing and filing an H-1B petition, including the Labor Condition Application that is filed to the U.S. Department of Labor. Other costs that an employer cannot pass along to an H-1B holder include expenses for tools and equipment, transportation costs necessary to employment and living expenses when the employee is traveling on company business.</p>
<p>However, some costs and fees may be paid by the employee, or employers are allowed to pass along some fees and costs to an employee. Examples of what employees are able to pay for generally include translations of personal documents, family members’ visas and fees related to a collective bargaining agreement, but this is definitely something to talk to your attorney about.</p>
<p>Keep in mind that a shortage of tech talent in the United States is prompting many companies to do all they can to attract and retain talent. Forward-thinking companies are offering up immigration as a benefit, paying the immigration-related costs and fees that they are not required to cover and agreeing to sponsor new hires for a green card after a year or two of employment.</p>
<p>Make sure your H-1B-sponsoring employer cares both about legal compliance as well as creating a hospitable work environment.</p>
<h2>H-1B lottery registration</h2>
<p>A company can only register an individual once for the H-1B lottery each year. If an individual is registered more than once for a lottery by the same company, that individual will be removed from the lottery.</p>
<p>However, it is technically possible for you to have multiple companies register you for the H-1B lottery each year. I understand your desire to increase your odds of being chosen in the H-1B lottery. Keep in mind that you are legally allowed to have a job offer from more than one company, but this may raise a red flag with U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS), which will want to make sure the job offers are legitimate.</p>
<p>Even though each company that registers you for the lottery may not find out about the other prospective employers, I recommend you approach the situation with integrity and transparency by communicating your approach with those prospective employers as you take your reputation with you in Silicon Valley.</p>
<p>In some limited situations, an employer may receive limited damages from an H-1B recipient who leaves the employer before an agreed-upon date depending on the damages and state law. If you find yourself in this situation, I recommend consulting with an immigration attorney.</p>
<h2>Alternatives to the H-1B</h2>
<p>If you don’t get selected in the lottery, there are several backup options available, such as a <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/066-cap-exempt-h-1bs-with-danielle-goldman/">cap-exempt H-1B</a>, an <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/what-we-do/o-visas/">O-1A visa</a> or even an <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/016-e-2-visa-for-founders-and-employees/">E-2 visa</a> if you have the desire and the means to start your own company in the U.S. I discuss these and other options in my podcast episode, “<a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/065-selected-or-not-selected-in-the-h-1b-lottery-now-what/">Selected or Not Selected in the H-1B Lottery, Now What?</a>”</p>
<p>Best wishes to you on your journey to the U.S.!</p>
<p>— Sophie</p>
<hr />
<p>Have a question for Sophie? <a href="https://webforms.pipedrive.com/f/1FRtXDHbec94FLVsSrWoOE362FDjgK7JkmZmK9g2IiOhbJLDMHtEAapwnHIfqC89l">Ask it here</a>. We reserve the right to edit your submission for clarity and/or space.</p>
<p>The information provided in “Dear Sophie” is general information and not legal advice. For more information on the limitations of “Dear Sophie,” please view <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/attorney-advertising/">our full disclaimer</a>. You can contact Sophie directly at <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a>.</p>
<p>Sophie’s podcast, <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/">Immigration Law for Tech Startups</a>, is available on all major platforms. If you’d like to be a guest, she’s accepting applications!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/dear-sophie-what-are-the-latest-rules-for-h-1b-visas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2241502</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Actuator is go!</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/actuator-robots-for-bathrooms-agtech-food-and-architecture/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/actuator-robots-for-bathrooms-agtech-food-and-architecture/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 19:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Actuator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miso Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics roundup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2241795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today’s the big day! After months of toiling away in roundups, Actuator is finally graduating to your inbox as the latest addition to the TechCrunch newsletter family. I’ve written 40 of these things since our quiet, pre-name test launch back in February (we called ourselves “Robotics Roundup” for a few unfortunate months there). You can [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today’s the big day! After months of toiling away in roundups, Actuator is finally graduating to your inbox as the latest addition to the TechCrunch newsletter family. I’ve written 40 of these things since our quiet, pre-name test launch back in February (we called ourselves “Robotics Roundup” for a few unfortunate months there). You can check out <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/actuator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the full backlog here</a>, and if you’re still reading this through TechCrunch.com, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters" target="_blank" rel="noopener">be sure to sign up here</a>.</p>
<p>Seeing as how we’re nearing the end of another very weird year, I plan to spend the next couple of weeks exploring 2021’s biggest robotics trends. Think about it like Spotify Wrapped, only instead of an embarrassing number of Steely Dan songs (<a href="https://twitter.com/bheater/status/1466067473577431042" target="_blank" rel="noopener">definitely not talking about myself here</a>), we’ll take a look at the trends in automation, AI, research and investment that defined the last 12 months. And in doing so, we should get a better picture of the world we&#8217;re heading into.</p>
<p>I’ve been threatening to launch a robotics newsletter at TC for a number of years now &#8212; probably dating back nearly as far as our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/sessions-robotics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">first big robotics event in Boston, way back in 2017</a>. It’s been a rich vein for some time, but honestly, I don’t think we could have picked a better moment to launch this thing than right now.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2241795" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>As we stare down the two-year anniversary of a global pandemic, it’s clear that for many of us there may not be a “normal” to return to &#8212; for better or worse. For those in the robotics industry, this is the first glimpse into something big, bold and exciting. Maybe it&#8217;s overly optimistic to imply that we might emerge from this to something better (and believe me, the last 21 or so months have sucked deeply on a personal level), but it&#8217;s undeniably time to rethink the way we do just about everything. Logistics, healthcare, restaurants, agriculture, retail &#8212; all of these categories are set to be fundamentally transformed by COVID-19. And robotics has an important role in that transformation.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s been nearly two years, and countless industries are still under tremendous strain to fill positions. Those who have previously considered full automation a distant pipe dream are looking far more aggressively into these solutions, and as a result, we’ve seen a tremendous uptick in investments across a broad range of categories. Concepts that VCs would have traditionally balked at as too far afield have found their way to the tops of term sheets across the world.</p>
<p>I’ve been writing about technology professionally for a long time now, and for the first time, I’m hearing people talk seriously about robotic ubiquity in the present tense. Just before Thanksgiving, I <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/11/cmus-new-robotics-institute-director-on-the-future-of-robot-research/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">spoke with Matthew Johnson-Roberson</a>, who had just been appointed the head of Carnegie Mellon’s Robotics Institute. He told me:</p>
<blockquote><p>We’re really at this inflection point when it comes to big, deployed robotic field systems out there in the world. One day, I want it to be that you look out your window, wherever you are in the U.S. and the world, and you see a robot doing something useful.</p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>We’re not quite there yet, obviously. But I do fundamentally believe that we’re a lot closer to that goal than we were in, say, January 2020. Part of our job here going forward is discussing how we get there. We should also be taking the opportunity to discuss the consequences of getting there. What all of this means for things like jobs, quality of life and the environment, for example. And, not to put too fine a point on it, how to ensure that robotics continues to serve us and not the other way around.</p>
<p>Committing to an indefinitely weekly newsletter is something that felt a bit daunting at first blush. But having done it every week for a while now, one thing’s for certain: We won’t be running out of things to discuss any time soon.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2240221" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2240221" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2240221" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/product-page-diagram_AWS-IoT-RoboRunner-2x.dae616d7c802e5df460275ad86cfa485eecf31aa.png" alt="" width="1024" height="312" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/product-page-diagram_AWS-IoT-RoboRunner-2x.dae616d7c802e5df460275ad86cfa485eecf31aa.png 2360w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/product-page-diagram_AWS-IoT-RoboRunner-2x.dae616d7c802e5df460275ad86cfa485eecf31aa.png?resize=150,46 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/product-page-diagram_AWS-IoT-RoboRunner-2x.dae616d7c802e5df460275ad86cfa485eecf31aa.png?resize=300,92 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/product-page-diagram_AWS-IoT-RoboRunner-2x.dae616d7c802e5df460275ad86cfa485eecf31aa.png?resize=768,234 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/product-page-diagram_AWS-IoT-RoboRunner-2x.dae616d7c802e5df460275ad86cfa485eecf31aa.png?resize=680,207 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/product-page-diagram_AWS-IoT-RoboRunner-2x.dae616d7c802e5df460275ad86cfa485eecf31aa.png?resize=1536,469 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/product-page-diagram_AWS-IoT-RoboRunner-2x.dae616d7c802e5df460275ad86cfa485eecf31aa.png?resize=2048,625 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/product-page-diagram_AWS-IoT-RoboRunner-2x.dae616d7c802e5df460275ad86cfa485eecf31aa.png?resize=50,15 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2240221" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> AWS</p></div></p>
<p>Heck, I may have taken the week off (happy belated Thanksgiving to those who celebrate), but robotics didn’t. My buddy Frederic is in beautiful Las Vegas, Nevada this week for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/aws-reinvent/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AWS’s re:Invent conference</a>. Amazon kicked off the show with the launch of a robotics fleet management program. The problem <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/29/aws-launches-new-robotics-programs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RoboRunner is attempting</a> to solve is one we’ve seen various startups take on. Specifically, how do companies get different brands of robotics systems to play nicely together?</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s AWS CTO Werner Vogels:</p>
<blockquote><p>Today, there are only a few successful commercial robotics companies, and there are a few big reasons for this. First, finding a fit in the robotics product market is difficult because real-world environments are dynamic and unpredictable, so pairing the right niche with the right capabilities can be a challenge. Second, building robots with a high degree of autonomy and intelligence requires multidisciplinary skills that are hard to find and recruit for. Third, robotics is capital intensive and requires large up-front investment in sensors, actuators, and mechanical hardware even when they’re already commercially available.</p></blockquote>
<p>Can Amazon gobble up industrial robotics fleet management the way it has…well, everything else, basically? The company certainly has the infrastructure and resources to take the disjointed category on. It also now has a foot in the world of early-stage robotics startups, courtesy of <a href="https://www.massrobotics.org/project/awsroboticsaccelerator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a new partnership with MassRobotics</a>. Amazon is teaming up with the Boston-based tech hub to launch a new robotics accelerator specifically focused on AWS applications.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2195465" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2195465" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2195465" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-Vegas_Announce-5.jpg" alt="Nuro-Las Vegas fundraising round" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-Vegas_Announce-5.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-Vegas_Announce-5.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-Vegas_Announce-5.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-Vegas_Announce-5.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-Vegas_Announce-5.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-Vegas_Announce-5.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-Vegas_Announce-5.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2195465" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nuro</p></div></p>
<p>Autonomous delivery company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/nuro-lands-investment-from-google-tiger-global-in-new-600-million-round/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nuro just announced another massive raise</a>. This latest $600 million round was led by Tiger Global Management (because, of course). It brings the company’s valuation to a whopping $8.6 billion. As for where that funding is going, co-founder Dave Ferguson told TechCrunch, &#8220;With the boost of this new funding, we’re turning our focus to commercializing and scaling the production of our third-generation vehicle at our new facility in Southern Nevada.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2241797" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2241797" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2241797" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P06_16Bits-Blur.png" alt="" width="1024" height="575" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P06_16Bits-Blur.png 1390w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P06_16Bits-Blur.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P06_16Bits-Blur.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P06_16Bits-Blur.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P06_16Bits-Blur.png?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P06_16Bits-Blur.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2241797" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Somatic</p></div></p>
<p>When we talk about the dirty jobs that automation could one day replace, cleaning public toilets is no doubt near the top of the list. Michael Levy, the CEO of Somatic, dropped me a line to note that the company’s robot has reached a new milestone in automatous bathroom scrubbing, as evidenced by the below video:</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/z96Qe8xTCZQ?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>The company, which effectively came out of stealth at our robotics event last year, has designed a system capable of riding in an elevator, opening doors and scrubbing down bathrooms.</p>
<p>As Levy told me last year, “The reason bathrooms are such a good application is because everything is bolted down to the floor. Things move in a predictable way. All commercial bathrooms built after 1994 are ADA compliant. What’s good for robotics is that lays a specific design.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2239956" style="width: 833px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2239956" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2239956" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/2421637834861_.pic_hd-e1638163752386.jpg" alt="" width="823" height="438" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/2421637834861_.pic_hd-e1638163752386.jpg 823w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/2421637834861_.pic_hd-e1638163752386.jpg?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/2421637834861_.pic_hd-e1638163752386.jpg?resize=300,160 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/2421637834861_.pic_hd-e1638163752386.jpg?resize=768,409 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/2421637834861_.pic_hd-e1638163752386.jpg?resize=680,362 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/2421637834861_.pic_hd-e1638163752386.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 823px) 100vw, 823px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2239956" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits: </strong>FJDynamics</p></div></p>
<p>Some more big funding for a robotics agtech firm &#8212; this time in China. Founded by former DJI chief scientist Wu Di, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/28/fj-dynamics-70-million-funding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FJDynamics</a> just announced that it has closed a $70 million Series B for its robotic harvester. Rita had a frank conversation with Wu, who noted, “You can have the most advanced AI algorithms. But if the technology doesn’t work on the production line or the farm, because you don’t have any industry experience, then how does your technology benefit people?”</p>
<p>Fair enough.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2016211" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2016211" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2016211" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_4228.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_4228.jpg 4032w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_4228.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_4228.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_4228.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_4228.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_4228.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_4228.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_4228.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2016211" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credit:</strong> Miso Robotics</p></div></p>
<p>On the note of broader trends to look out for, anecdotally, it seems there’s raring to be an uptick in crowded capital rounds. Miso Robotics, which produces the hamburger cooking robot, Flippy, <a href="https://invest.misorobotics.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">just announced a sizable $35 million crowdfunded Series B</a> spread out over 8,200 investors (a list that includes both new and returning names).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Our Series D round ended last night, it was a historic success!</p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b2.png" alt="💲" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />$35+ million raised<br /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f91d.png" alt="🤝" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> 8,200+ investors new &amp; returning</p>
<p>Thx again for your support &amp; being part of our story! We&#39;ve got many exciting updates, partnerships &amp; pilots around the corner, so stay tuned! <a href="https://t.co/RBnne1u1aJ">pic.twitter.com/RBnne1u1aJ</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Miso Robotics (@misorobotics) <a href="https://twitter.com/misorobotics/status/1461825373503635457?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>It’s a big round, as far as crowdfunding goes &#8212; and a trend worth keeping an eye on. Certainly there’s something to be said for widescale consumer buy-in, but one wonders what going this route means for investor confidence, among other things.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2241802" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2241802" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2241802" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/stellar.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/stellar.jpeg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/stellar.jpeg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/stellar.jpeg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/stellar.jpeg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/stellar.jpeg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/stellar.jpeg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/stellar.jpeg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2241802" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Stellar</p></div></p>
<p>Earlier this week, <a href="https://www.eatstellarpizza.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stellar Pizza announced</a> plans to launch its robotic pizza cooking truck in Los Angeles at some point next spring. Formed by a trio of SpaceX expats, the company says its trucks are capable of cooking a pizza from scratch in less than five minutes and producing a pizza every 45 seconds at max capacity.</p>
<p>Per its press material:</p>
<blockquote><p>With a revolutionary new pizza machine, Stellar Pizza transforms raw pizza dough and fresh toppings into a fully baked pizza in under five minutes. With the maximum capability to produce a pizza every 45 seconds, the food truck can deliver a larger quantity of fresh, gourmet pizzas more consistently than its brick-and-mortar counterparts. The robotic pizza-making process starts with a freshly prepared ball of raw pizza dough, which gets pressed and shaped into a round pizza crust. Then, house-made sauce and fresh toppings are added. Lastly, the raw pizza is inserted into one of four high-temperature custom-designed ovens to bake to perfection.</p></blockquote>
<p>Hopefully the robotic pizza truck business proves a smoother ride for Stellar <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/13/zume-buys-packaging-company-with-eyes-on-plant-based-plastic-alternative/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">than it did for Zume,</a> which has since undergone one of the weirdest pivots in recent memory and is now <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/17/zume-kills-plastics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">producing sustainable packaging with help from ABB</a>.<img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2242177 alignleft" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Figure-5c-22.jpeg" alt="" width="480" height="260" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Figure-5c-22.jpeg 480w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Figure-5c-22.jpeg?resize=150,81 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Figure-5c-22.jpeg?resize=300,163 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Figure-5c-22.jpeg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 100vw, 480px" /></p>
<p><strong>Image Credits:</strong> UC RiversideNeusbot <a href="https://news.ucr.edu/articles/2021/12/02/light-powered-soft-robots-could-suck-oil-spills" target="_blank" rel="noopener">comes to us from UC Riverside this week</a>. The soft robot moves as iron oxide and copper nanorods convert light into heat. A team at the school believes the technology could be used to help clean oil spills in the future. “Normally, people send ships to the scene of an oil spill to clean by hand,&#8221; researcher Zhiwei Li says in a release tied to the news. &#8220;Neusbot could do this work like a robot vacuum, but on the water’s surface.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2239519" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2239519" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2239519" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg" alt="Computer rendering of what the final Semiramis hanging garden structure will look like." width="1024" height="689" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg?resize=300,202 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg?resize=768,517 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg?resize=680,458 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg?resize=1536,1033 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg?resize=2048,1378 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2239519" class="wp-caption-text">Computer rendering of what the final Semiramis hanging garden structure will look like. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Gramazio Kohler Research</p></div></p>
<p>A fun one from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/robots-and-ai-assist-in-designing-and-building-swiss-universitys-hanging-gardens/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ETH Zurich to close us out</a>. The school is using construction robots to blur the lines between architecture and art with the creation of an homage to the hanging gardens of Babylon &#8212; one of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World. An aside from the piece by Devin that is simultaneously surprising and completely on-brand:</p>
<blockquote><p>The project is a sort of huge sculptural planter, “hanging gardens” inspired by the legendary structures in the ancient city of Babylon. (Incidentally, it was my ancestor, Robert Koldewey, who excavated/looted the famous Ishtar Gate to the place.)</p></blockquote>
<p>Learn something new about one of your co-workers every day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/actuator-robots-for-bathrooms-agtech-food-and-architecture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2241795</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rocket Lab reimagines rocket design with its Neutron launch vehicle</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/rocket-lab-reimagines-rocket-design-with-its-neutron-launch-vehicle/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/rocket-lab-reimagines-rocket-design-with-its-neutron-launch-vehicle/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 19:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Electron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neutron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peter beck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Lab]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2242328</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rocket Lab finally pulled the cover off its Neutron rocket, a medium-lift vehicle that CEO Peter Beck calls “a rocket of 2050,” as the company looks to take a greater share of the launch market currently dominated by SpaceX. This is the first major update on the project from the company since Neutron was announced [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Rocket Lab finally pulled the cover off its Neutron rocket, a medium-lift vehicle that CEO Peter Beck calls “a rocket of 2050,” as the company looks to take a greater share of the launch market currently dominated by SpaceX.</p>
<p>This is the first major update on the project from the company since Neutron was announced in March. Since then, Rocket Lab’s been busy, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/peter-beck-on-rocket-labs-public-listing-debut-space-spacs-and-the-neutron-rocket/">going public via a merger</a> with a blank-check firm, continuing to develop its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/17/rocket-labs-electron-booster-splashes-down-in-the-pacific-ocean/">Electron reusability program</a> and expanding its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/rocket-lab-acquires-planetary-systems-corporation-in-cash-and-stock-deal/">space services division</a>. All the while, the company has managed to stay mum about Neutron &#8212; until now.</p>
<h2>Carbon composites</h2>
<p>Neutron features a number of surprising innovations that depart from other rockets of its class in both operation and development. The first is materials: The 131-foot rocket will be made out of a special carbon composite, much like its sibling rocket, Electron.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2242328" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>It’s an interesting choice, particularly as SpaceX famously decided to ditch carbon composites for its Starship system in favor of stainless steel. But this is not Rocket Lab’s first rodeo with carbon composites; not only do they make up the bulk of the Electron rocket, Beck has been working with advanced composites and materials since the start of his career at a New Zealand government research facility.</p>
<p>“If you&#8217;re someone who is used to working in metallics, actually moving into composites is really challenging,” Beck told TechCrunch. “But if you&#8217;ve always been in composites and your experience is there, then actually, they&#8217;re pretty simple.”</p>
<p>Metallic structures are heavy and low-performance; while that can be made up for with high-performance engines, this doesn’t lead to high margins or high reliability for reuse, he added. Lighter structures avoid what he called “the rocket spiral of doom”: a never-ending arms race between heavier structures requiring more propellant, which then requires a larger propellant tank, which increases the weight and requires even more propellant — ad infinitum.</p>
<p>“This is the first time in my career ever where the spiral of doom is inversed. The spiral of doom is inversed because of the lightweight structures, and it&#8217;s not just important from a launch perspective, it&#8217;s actually really important from a reentry perspective,&#8221; he said. Why? According to Beck, Neutron’s large diameter at 23 feet and light weight gives it a large ballistic coefficient, a measure of an object’s ability to resist air drag. So the focus on structure means using less propellant on reentry, less air drag (and less heat as a consequence), and a simpler engine.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Neutron will also be finished in a new type of graphite composite for added thermal protection, a new addition that will be coming to future Electron rockets as well.</p>
<h2>The &#8216;Hungry Hippo&#8217;</h2>
<p>Another major departure from conventional rocket design are Neutron’s fairings, a piece of equipment that traditionally sits at the top of the rocket like a nose cone, protecting the payload inside. Historically, fairings separate and fall back to Earth and are generally considered expendable, though SpaceX retrieves them from the ocean for refurbishment and reuse.</p>
<p>Rocket Lab has instead attached the four fairings to the first stage, where they will mechanically open (imagine a strange, robotic flower). This is yet another design decision that has been driven by the use of composite materials, Beck said.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2242334" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2242334" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2242334" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Neutron-Stage-2-deploying.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Neutron-Stage-2-deploying.jpg 5692w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Neutron-Stage-2-deploying.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Neutron-Stage-2-deploying.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Neutron-Stage-2-deploying.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Neutron-Stage-2-deploying.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Neutron-Stage-2-deploying.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Neutron-Stage-2-deploying.jpg?resize=2048,1151 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Neutron-Stage-2-deploying.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2242334" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://rocketlabusa.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rocket Lab <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>“Normally you don&#8217;t have the mass margins to be able to hold onto fairings and do things like that. You have to get rid of the fairings as quick as you can, because you can&#8217;t afford that parasitic mass. But when the parasitic mass is really low, then it allows you to be able to do these kinds of things.”</p>
<p>Neutron will be capable of carrying a maximum of 15,000 kilograms of payload to low Earth orbit, putting it right in competition with SpaceX&#8217;s Falcon 9 and Relativity Space&#8217;s in-development Terran R rocket.</p>
<h2>But what about the second stage?</h2>
<p>Not only is there no nose cone payload fairing, Rocket Lab also decided to overhaul the second stage as well. Conventional rocket design integrates the second stage by sandwiching it between the first stage and the payload. But with Neutron, the second stage will hang inside the first stage. When the rocket needs to deploy the payload, the &#8220;Hungry Hippo&#8221; fairing design will open and release both the second stage and payload to orbit.</p>
<p>Rocket Lab intends to use Neutron for different types of missions, including human spaceflight. In the case of a crewed launch, Beck said they could simply remove the fairings and the capsule holding the crew would go on top.</p>
<p>The second stage is designed to be expendable. While other rocket companies are working on full reusability, Beck said the jury was still out on whether second stage reusability makes sense, particularly considering the increased mass requirements of reusability and the associated operational costs of recovery.</p>
<h2>Returning to Earth</h2>
<p>Once the second stage is deployed, the first stage will return to Earth to land right back on its launch pad. That means no touchdown on an ocean barge, another choice that will save on operational costs, Beck said.</p>
<p>Neutron will get to orbit and back using seven new engines Rocket Lab has developed, which it calls Archimedes. These low-pressure engines will run on liquid oxygen (LOX) and methane, rather than LOX and kerosene. Just like the decision to return the first stage to the launch site, the propellant choice was designed to minimize turnaround time between missions.</p>
<p>“Engines have typically in the past required a lot of refurbishment. And they require a lot of refurbishment because the propellants chosen have been LOX and kerosene. Kerosene creates a lot of sooting, a lot of coking,” he said. “So that&#8217;s what drove the decision to use methane, is that you can run an engine on methane and it&#8217;s perfectly clean and still shiny after you&#8217;ve finished burning it.”</p>
<p>Neutron will eventually take off from somewhere in the United States, and Rocket Lab is in the middle of a competitive process to choose a launch and manufacturing site. Much has been made of the auspicious absence of any specific launch date for Neutron &#8212; Rocket Lab had previously said 2024, which was not mentioned in this morning’s update &#8212; but Beck said that omission wasn’t intentional.</p>
<p>“We’re aiming to get one on the pad in ’24 and get a commercial customer up in the sky in ’25,” he confirmed. “But we also acknowledge it&#8217;s a rocket program. So it’s a lot of work to do but we&#8217;re working hard and that&#8217;s the plan.”</p>
<p>Rewatch the company&#8217;s Neutron update in here:</p>
<p><iframe title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7kwAPr5G6WA" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/rocket-lab-reimagines-rocket-design-with-its-neutron-launch-vehicle/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2242328</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>After being pushed out of Google, Timnit Gebru forms her own AI research institute: DAIR</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/google-timnit-gebru-ai-research-dair/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/google-timnit-gebru-ai-research-dair/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 19:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethical AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raesetje Sefala]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Safiya Noble]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Timnit Gebru]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2242318</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Almost exactly one year ago, Timnit Gebru, one of the leaders of Google&#8217;s ethics in AI team and one of the foremost experts in that topic, was fired after sending an email of concern to her team. Now she has set up shop herself with a brand new research institute, DAIR, focused on the topics [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Almost exactly one year ago, Timnit Gebru, one of the leaders of Google&#8217;s ethics in AI team and one of the foremost experts in that topic, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/googles-co-lead-of-ethical-ai-team-says-she-was-fired-for-sending-an-email/">was fired after sending an email of concern to her team</a>. Now she has set up shop herself with a brand new research institute, DAIR, focused on the topics she felt were being sidelined at Google.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.dair-institute.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Distributed Artificial Intelligence Research Institute</a> is &#8220;an independent, community rooted institute set to counter Big Tech’s pervasive influence on the research, development and deployment of AI,&#8221; according to its <a href="https://www.dair-institute.org/press-release" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announcement press release</a>.</p>
<p>Built from the start to include and emphasize diverse perspectives and question the processes used at companies like Google, Amazon and Facebook/Meta, DAIR will be independently funded. The focus will be on publishing papers in the academic realm but without either the relentless pressure of traditional academia or the paternalistic interference of a global corporation hanging over the researchers.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2242318" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;ve been frustrated for a long time about the incentive structures that we have in place and how none of them seem to be appropriate for the kind of work I want to do,&#8221; Gebru <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/12/02/timnit-gebru-dair/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told The Washington Post</a>.</p>
<p>So far the institute has raised $3.7 million, from the Ford Foundation, the MacArthur Foundation, the Kapor Center and the Open Society Foundation. That ought to be enough to get started — and pay its researchers well, ensuring that this type of work is a realistic alternative to working at one of the deep-pocketed corporations that frequently fund AI research.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve asked Gebru, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/video/will-ai-diversify-human-thinking-or-replace-it-with-chris-ategeka-ucot-timnit-gebru-google-ai-and-ken-goldberg-uc-berkeley/">whom we have had on stage to talk about these very topics</a>, for further information on DAIR&#8217;s methods and directions for future research and will update this post if I hear back. But two personnel give an idea of what we can expect.</p>
<p>Safiya Noble, author of &#8220;Algorithms of Oppression&#8221; and Macarthur Genius Grant recipient, will be on DAIR&#8217;s advisory committee; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/10/tackling-deep-seated-bias-in-tech-with-haben-girma-mutale-nkonde-and-safiya-noble/">we recently hosted her for a panel at TC Sessions: Justice</a> where she spoke about the danger of considering technologies neutral or valuable as they become widely used and &#8220;banal,&#8221; when in fact that is exactly the time they should be under greater scrutiny.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wHdxQvbDA6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/10/tackling-deep-seated-bias-in-tech-with-haben-girma-mutale-nkonde-and-safiya-noble/">Tackling deep-seated bias in tech with Haben Girma, Mutale Nkonde and Safiya Noble</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tackling deep-seated bias in tech with Haben Girma, Mutale Nkonde and Safiya Noble&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/10/tackling-deep-seated-bias-in-tech-with-haben-girma-mutale-nkonde-and-safiya-noble/embed/#?secret=wHdxQvbDA6" data-secret="wHdxQvbDA6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>And Raesetje Sefala is DAIR&#8217;s first research fellow; Sefala&#8217;s recent research focuses on <a href="https://openreview.net/forum?id=WV0waZz9dTF" target="_blank" rel="noopener">geographical and economic segregation</a> in South Africa, quantified by satellite imagery.</p>
<p>&#8220;AI needs to be brought back down to earth. It has been elevated to a superhuman level that leads us to believe it is both inevitable and beyond our control,&#8221; said Gebru in the announcement. &#8220;When AI research, development and deployment is rooted in people and communities from the start, we can get in front of these harms and create a future that values equity and humanity.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/google-timnit-gebru-ai-research-dair/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2242318</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nowhere to hide: The emissions threat facing corporate America</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/nowhere-to-hide-the-emissions-threat-facing-corporate-america/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/nowhere-to-hide-the-emissions-threat-facing-corporate-america/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 18:50:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bpifrance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon footprint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2241720</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Businesses across industries and throughout the world are facing an existential threat that can no longer be ignored.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Rachel Delacour</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Rachel_Delacour">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Rachel is the CEO and co-founder of <a href="https://www.sweep.net/">Sweep</a>. Previously, she co-founded BIME Analytics, which was acquired by Zendesk. She invests in mainly women-founded businesses, and her achievements have been recognized by La Tribune Women’s award, the French State’s Young Innovative Enterprise Award, and she was named as one of <a href="https://france.inspiringfifty.org/rachel-delacour">France’s Inspiring 50</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Pia d’Iribarne</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/piadiri">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Pia is a co-founder and managing partner at <a href="https://www.newwave.vc/">New Wave</a>, a pan-European seed fund co-founded and backed by a small group of successful entrepreneurs and investors. She started her career at McKinsey and Accel. She is half French and half Dutch and lives between London and Paris.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Each degree Celsius of warming will erase 1.2% of the United States GDP, <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/theres-no-cheap-way-to-deal-with-the-climate-crisis">according to Solomon Hsiang</a>, a climate scientist and economist at the University of California, Berkeley, and the co-director of the research group Climate Impact Lab. If U.S. companies do not act now to halt climate emissions, Hsiang predicts a loss of up to 10.5% of annual GDP, which equates to approximately $2.2 trillion per year.</p>
<p>Most organizations do not understand the gravity of the need to address emissions now. Businesses across industries and throughout the world are facing an existential threat that can no longer be ignored. It’s time to address the impact of rapidly accelerating climate change in the corporate sector. The effect of harmful emissions on the bottom line can’t be overstated.</p>
<p>Customers are choosing to purchase products from carbon-conscious companies and investors such as <a href="https://www.blackrock.com/us/individual/about-us/road-to-net-zero">BlackRock</a>, <a href="https://www.balderton.com/sustainable-future-goals/">Balderton Capital</a> and <a href="https://www.alantecapital.com/">Alante Capital</a> are considering sustainability in their investment processes. The market has moved beyond good intentions. To ensure an organization is successful in its efforts to measure and reduce emissions, it is imperative that they have a plan and tools in place to take on every component of the company ecosystem.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2241720" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h2>How do companies get started?</h2>
<p>The first and most important step is to admit you have a problem and are emitting more than you think. Acknowledge your carbon footprint. Communicate a desire to learn and do better. Begin education at a strategic level first, then distill it throughout the organization to key stakeholders consistently over time.</p>
<p>In the absence of a universal standard, the C-suite must be knowledgeable about and capable of quantifying sustainability risks threatening their business &#8212; and the practices being put into place to ameliorate them.</p>
<p>Assemble a dedicated team and bring in a third-party consultant or software vendor to assess the company’s emissions and make recommendations. Typically, the sustainability team drives the effort. Include the CFO and CTO for data collection and the evaluation of cost and revenue implications. Ensure that your general counsel is also included in the conversation for compliance purposes. Representatives from operations, community relations, HR and communications should take part.</p>
<p>Next, conduct an assessment that provides a deep analysis of the company’s carbon emissions and overall sustainability practices. The assessment should include factors generating direct and indirect emissions, such as vehicle fleets and purchased energy including electricity, heating and cooling.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Host a series of regular meetings between executives, sustainability teams and consultants to discuss the results of the assessment, which actions will be taken, and the timeline for implementation. This will help to enlist missionaries in the efforts, from the top-down and bottom-up.</p>
<p>Once they are organized in their efforts, companies must also look at how they generate carbon emissions beyond their four walls. Start a dialogue with your value chain &#8212; this is where enterprise-grade SaaS emission platforms come in.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.epa.gov/climateleadership/scope-3-inventory-guidance">Scope 3 emissions</a> resulting from assets not owned or controlled by an organization, but that impact their value chain, most often represent the biggest part of a company’s footprint. If you aren’t measuring and reducing scope 3 emissions, then your carbon reduction plan is not credible, even if you have reduced or eliminated scopes 1 and 2. The more you engage your stakeholders, the closer you get to the emissions, the quicker you reduce such emissions.</p>
<h2>How might approaches vary?</h2>
<p>Whether a small startup or a large enterprise, the approach to reduction is the same: Begin with measurement. Set <a href="https://sciencebasedtargets.org/">science-based reduction targets</a> and monitor your footprint on a consistent basis. Leverage fintech-inspired tools to make on-target, granular goals and a climate-positive impact. Map your business by department, brand, business units and geography, while also including the company’s value chain and suppliers.</p>
<p>Data plays an essential role in setting a company’s baseline. Without accurate information that is granular, you cannot determine if the actions you are taking are working, nor whether those you plan to execute in the future will work. In addition to a precise baseline, it’s imperative to be precise with approval workflow to prevent “garbage-in, garbage-out” data. There needs to be a massive amount of trackable and actionable data points &#8212; internally and externally &#8212; through the value chain.</p>
<p>Next, assign actions and establish deadlines to meet the goals. Ensure that your numbers are precise and utilize sustainability management software and carbon consultants to kick off your reduction journey before shifting to automation.</p>
<p>When it comes to reduction, choose your first battle by identifying where your highest emissions are coming from. Typically, <a href="https://www.epa.gov/ghgemissions/sources-greenhouse-gas-emissions">these emissions</a> stem from company transportation &#8212; burning fossil fuel for our cars and buses traveling to and from the office, or jetting to other parts of the world for a business meeting. Though they might seem small at the time, they add up to what truly matters.</p>
<p>Investigate each and every component of inside operations and your supply chain and select sustainable partners. You can’t blame your accounting department for not using recycled paper if your company is still doing strategic business with the most important Brazilian soy importer.</p>
<p>Continuously evolve and evaluate your climate progress on a weekly or even daily basis. Ideate, iterate and try again when you stumble. Stay accountable to your company’s emission reduction goals and remain open and transparent with regulators, employees, customers and investors.</p>
<h2>What happens if companies don&#8217;t follow through?</h2>
<p>Companies should begin implementing long-term changes to accommodate eventual green policy. While there may be incentives that companies may benefit from, the cost of energy and fossil fuels has been steadily skyrocketing in recent years.</p>
<p>This, in conjunction with the desire to leave the planet in a better place, should be reason enough to take action. Your company’s low-carbon efforts will pay in the end regardless of how long the wait for subsidies is.</p>
<p>Millennials and Gen Zs evaluate a company’s sustainability practice as part of the decision to accept a job offer. Companies of any size that are driven by climate action goals and efforts and share those transparently and publicly are more likely to attract fresh, intelligent workers who share the same personal philosophies.</p>
<p>Employees that work for organizations focused on net-zero emissions become a company’s biggest ambassadors and advocates in both internal and external conversations, not only helping to attract new hires, but also to maintain longer tenure in the workplace. Companies in industries such as oil and gas are struggling to adapt and having difficulty attracting talent.</p>
<h2>What organizations are demonstrating early success?</h2>
<p>Companies that are transparent and committed to their journey are recognized winners. They’re willing to acknowledge their carbon impact and have invested resources to tackle their emissions. Microsoft, HP, Orange, Beyond Meat and Bpifrance are succeeding in their climate action goals. When transparency is at the forefront, not only can organizations highlight their areas of improvement, but they can also publicly celebrate their successes.</p>
<p>Existing groups such as <a href="https://sustainability.aboutamazon.com/about/the-climate-pledge">Amazon’s Climate Pledge</a>, <a href="https://unfccc.int/climate-action/climate-neutral-now">UNFCCC’s Climate Neutral Now</a>, and <a href="https://www.theclimategroup.org/about-ep100">The Climate Group’s EP100</a> allow companies to pledge their climate actions among others in their industry. These established groups allow your executive team to connect with other leaders who share the same climate philosophies as you do. Better yet, companies can form their own climate coalitions to explore emissions measurement solutions and tools with like-minded leaders. Share your progress, including trials and tribulations, regularly and transparently.</p>
<p>After COP26, it’s clear that companies have <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/b044fe94-ae00-4363-9362-3906a9b92cf8">a big role to play</a> in our journey to tackle climate change. From financing the green transition to supporting other businesses in their reduction efforts, corporations will have a massive impact on getting us closer to our 1.5-degree C target. And who knows, they might even be responsible for <a href="https://www.sweep.net/academy/161-cop26-businesses-can-tip-the-carbon-balance">tipping the carbon balance</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/nowhere-to-hide-the-emissions-threat-facing-corporate-america/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2241720</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Glorify, an ambitious app for Christians, just landed $40 million in Series A funding led by a16z</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/glorify-an-ambitious-app-for-christians-just-landed-40-million-in-series-a-funding-led-by-a16z/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/glorify-an-ambitious-app-for-christians-just-landed-40-million-in-series-a-funding-led-by-a16z/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 18:46:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glorify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michael ovitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Latin America Fund]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2242213</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Religion-based apps, tools and communities aren&#8217;t brand new, including to investors. Pray.com, for example, an LA-based app for daily prayer and bedtime Bible stories that was founded in 2016, has raised at least $34 million from investors, including Kleiner Perkins. Ministry Brands, a nine-year-old, Knoxville, Tennessee-based outfit that now includes dozens of software and payments [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Religion-based apps, tools and communities aren&#8217;t brand new, including to investors. Pray.com, for example, an LA-based app for daily prayer and bedtime Bible stories that was founded in 2016, has raised at least <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/pray/company_financials" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$34 million</a> from investors, including Kleiner Perkins. Ministry Brands, a nine-year-old, Knoxville, Tennessee-based outfit that now includes dozens of software and payments brands tailored to faith-based organizations, was acquired by Insight Partners in 2016 for $1.4 billion (which is reportedly now looking to <a href="https://www.pehub.com/insight-partners-explores-sale-of-ministry-brands/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">flip it</a>).</p>
<p>Still, fueled by a pandemic that drove churches to close, faith-based apps and communities are growing faster than ever &#8212; the most popular, <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/bible/id282935706" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bible app</a>, is now on more than 400 million devices worldwide &#8212; and getting more notice as a result.</p>
<p>The newest of these is<a href="https://glorify-app.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Glorify</a>, a two-year-old, 60-person, subscription-based &#8220;well-being&#8221; app that offers users guided meditation, along with audio bible passages and Christian music. The London-based outfit just raised $40 million in Series A funding led by Andreessen Horowitz, with participation from SoftBank Latin America Fund, K5 Global and a long string of famous individuals, including Kris Jenner, Corey Gamble, Michael Ovitz, Jason Derulo and Michael Bublé.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2242213" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>We talked yesterday with its 22-year-old co-founder and co-CEO, Ed Beccle, who says he spends up to a third of his time in São Paulo, and who <a href="https://amazingworkplaces.co/hintsa-performance-acquires-grasp-hr/">recently sold</a> his previous company for what he describes as a “multimillion-dollar” exit. Indeed, he says he dropped out of high school at age 16 to work on his startups.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Perhaps unsurprisingly, during our conversation, he laid out a vision that extends well beyond meditation and Bible readings. He also offered a peek into how wealthy celebrities and startup entrepreneurs are being brought together. Excerpts of that chat follow, edited lightly for length.</span></p>
<p><strong>TC: You say this is your third or fourth startup. With Glorify, did you see an opportunity or are you a religious person or is it a combination of both things?</strong></p>
<p>EB: I think definitely a combination of both. It&#8217;s hard not to get a little bit philosophical when you&#8217;re young, and you&#8217;re doing exciting things, maybe you make more money than regular people your own age. For me, at least, I stopped and thought, &#8216;Well, I can afford all the Ubers and Uber Eats in the world, and I don&#8217;t really spend any other money. I don&#8217;t have a mortgage or dependents. What would I do if I could do anything?&#8217;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>[The answer] has always been working on tech that changes the way people think and feel. That&#8217;s what I&#8217;m kind of obsessed with. . . Now I&#8217;ve never been more proud of anything in my life than this company because it is so much more than just a business. I&#8217;ve come at it from from a lot of different angles and one is very much on an emotional level and my own beliefs around faith. Then the other is: It&#8217;s the most incredible commercial opportunity. It&#8217;s going to be, I think, far bigger than people realize.</p>
<p><strong>TC: You have a pretty interesting syndicate of investors. How did that come together?</strong></p>
<p>EB: I think it came together a bit like everything that I&#8217;ve done, which is just, you know, by my continually trying and chatting to as many people as I can and putting myself in a lot of awkward situations sometimes to get in front of the right people. In terms of the celebrity elements, I have to say that that was a shock. [Former Hollywood agent] Michael Kives has been a complete hero on this front; he sent me a message that said, &#8216;Are you free&#8217; on whatever the date was. &#8216;I want you to come to dinner with me and the Kardashians&#8217; and there were probably 25 people on the guest list that he sent over, and I&#8217;m not sure there was a single person aside from myself and one other who wasn&#8217;t an A-lister. Like, it was crazy. I walk through the door, and there was Michael [Bublé] and Jason Derulo, and, I mean, what you see on the press release is literally the tip of the iceberg. We&#8217;ve only released some of the names.</p>
<p>It comes down to: Why have we done it? Why have I tried so hard to get a lot of these people involved? It&#8217;s because we&#8217;re trying to create a cultural movement around faith and making believing in God and something greater, something that&#8217;s more than just okay [and into] something that can really change your life. My goal with all of these people is to get them to make Glorify the medium that they talk about their faith through.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Can you talk about some of the business metrics that made these people decide to commit to the venture?</strong></p>
<p>EB: We&#8217;re averaging at least 250,000 people daily and we&#8217;ve had now 2.5 million downloads over the last year or so. I think things have really kicked off in the last six months to be honest, and what&#8217;s so exciting is that a lot of this growth has been semi organic. It&#8217;s not from viral <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/K-factor_(marketing)" target="_blank" rel="noopener">K factor</a> that exists within the app. We always thought it was too early to start introducing stuff like that.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Is the plan to evolve this into a full-fledged social network?</strong></p>
<p>EB: When we talk about it being a social network, 100%. It&#8217;s just that trying to look at social very differently. We want to optimize for very different things. I want to be building tight-knit engaged communities that are really meaningful and purpose-led, rather than things that are mass, superficially engaged, which is really the trap of social today. We don&#8217;t monetize through ads; the user really isn&#8217;t the product. We want to bring people closer together and not necessarily in huge groups but through amazing micro interactions that can exist and bring you closer to a small group of people who you really care about.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Are you close to break-even at this point?</strong></p>
<p>EB: Definitely not, but it&#8217;s very intentional. We&#8217;ve proven paid conversion, which we&#8217;re really happy about . . .  I believe the engaged audience that we will have will probably have a higher propensity to pay for all sorts of other products that we release. That cool daily worship product will [continue to] be in the Glorify app, although far improved, even in over the next few months, but [we think we can] take that audience and direct them to other products that we&#8217;ve created, where they&#8217;ll have high propensity to pay.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Are you talking about virtual tithing? Bible study?</strong></p>
<p>EB: An example would be in in Christian dating. It&#8217;s an amazing, huge space, but anyone who really tries to build within it has to become kind of a Christian Tinder, using visuals to be the primary way you match people. I don&#8217;t know if that&#8217;s really the right way to go about it. Instead, you know, if you&#8217;re a user of Glorify, we&#8217;ll be able to match you with people based on shared beliefs [and] your engagement with the Bible [and] all sorts of things where we have almost a competitive advantage over anyone else because of the product that we&#8217;ve begun with.</p>
<p><em>Pictured above: From left to right, Henry Costa and Ed Beccle, co-CEOs of Glorify. The best friends met at a co-working space when Costa was doing angel investing in London. According to Beccle, they instantly hit it off and he asked Costa if he would be his co-founder at Grasp. They later co-founded Glorify. </em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/glorify-an-ambitious-app-for-christians-just-landed-40-million-in-series-a-funding-led-by-a16z/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2242213</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AWS launches re:Post, a new community-driven Q&#038;A service</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/aws-launches-repost-a-new-community-driven-qa-service/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/aws-launches-repost-a-new-community-driven-qa-service/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 18:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Web Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS re:Invent 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2242299</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At its annual re:Invent conference, AWS announced re:Post, a new community-driven question and answer service designed to help AWS customers remove technical roadblocks. The new service is part of the AWS Free Tier. AWS says re:Post is driven by the community of AWS customers, partners and employees. &#8220;AWS re:Post is an AWS-managed Q&#38;A service offering crowd-sourced, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At its annual re:Invent conference, AWS <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/aws-repost-a-reimagined-qa-experience-for-the-aws-community/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> re:Post, a new community-driven question and answer service designed to help AWS customers remove technical roadblocks. The new service is part of the <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/free/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AWS Free Tier.</a> AWS says re:Post is driven by the community of AWS customers, partners and employees.</p>
<p>&#8220;AWS re:Post is an AWS-managed Q&amp;A service offering crowd-sourced, expert-reviewed answers to your technical questions about AWS that replaces the original AWS Forums,&#8221; the company explained in a <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/aws-repost-a-reimagined-qa-experience-for-the-aws-community/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blog post</a> about the announcement. &#8220;Community members can earn reputation points to build up their community expert status by providing accepted answers and reviewing answers from other users, helping to continually expand the availability of public knowledge across all AWS services.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2242308" style="width: 926px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2242308" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2242308" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/aws-re-post.png" alt="" width="916" height="567" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/aws-re-post.png 916w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/aws-re-post.png?resize=150,93 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/aws-re-post.png?resize=300,186 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/aws-re-post.png?resize=768,475 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/aws-re-post.png?resize=680,421 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/aws-re-post.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 916px) 100vw, 916px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2242308" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits: </strong>AWS</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2242299" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company says customers will find re:Post to be an ideal resource when they are building an application using AWS and have a technical question about an AWS service or best practices. It could also be helpful when customers are learning about AWS or are preparing for an AWS certification. In addition, AWS says re:Post could be useful when customers&#8217; teams are debating issues related to design or operations on AWS. Lastly, the service could be used to share your AWS expertise with the community and also build a reputation as a community expert.</p>
<p>Users don&#8217;t have to sign in to re:Post to browse the content available. Those who do choose to sign in will have the opportunity to create a profile, post questions and answers and interact with others. Creating a profile will allow users to link their AWS certifications through Credly and to indicate interests in specific AWS technology and services. AWS re:Post automatically shares new questions with community experts based on their areas of expertise.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/aws-reinvent-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/aws-reinvent-2021-banner.png" alt="read more about AWS re:Invent 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/aws-launches-repost-a-new-community-driven-qa-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2242299</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meta&#8217;s NPE team takes a global focus with seed-stage investments, offices in emerging markets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/metas-npe-team-takes-a-global-focus-with-seed-stage-investments-offices-in-emerging-markets/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/metas-npe-team-takes-a-global-focus-with-seed-stage-investments-offices-in-emerging-markets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 18:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[east africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lagos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Menlo Park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silicon Valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2242100</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Meta&#8217;s (formerly, Facebook&#8217;s) experimental app division, the NPE team, is shifting gears. The group, which first launched in mid-2019, has been focused on building consumer-facing apps that would allow the company to test out new social features and gauge people&#8217;s reactions. Over the years, the largely Menlo Park-based team launched and retired a number of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Meta&#8217;s (formerly, Facebook&#8217;s) experimental app division, the NPE team, is shifting gears. The group, which first <a href="https://tech.fb.com/npe-team-from-facebook/">launched</a> in mid-2019, has been focused on building consumer-facing apps that would allow the company to test out new social features and gauge people&#8217;s reactions.</p>
<p>Over the years, the largely Menlo Park-based team launched and retired a number of experiments, ranging from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/facebook-tests-video-speed-dating-events-with-sparked/">dating</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/26/facebook-launches-catchup-an-audio-only-group-calling-app-that-shows-whos-ready-to-chat-now/">calling apps</a> to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/facebook-launches-e-gg-an-experimental-collage-making-app/">meme-makers</a> to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/facebook-launches-bars-a-tiktok-like-app-for-creating-and-sharing-raps/">TikTok</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/29/facebook-takes-on-twitter-with-venue-a-second-screen-companion-for-live-events/">Twitter</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/facebook-tests-hotline-a-qa-product-thats-a-mashup-of-clubhouse-and-instagram-live/">Clubhouse rivals</a> to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/07/facebook-ships-an-experimental-app-for-couples/">apps for couples</a> and more. Now, NPE will begin testing out a new thesis: that the next big idea may come from a market outside the U.S.</p>
<p>To capitalize on that potential, the organization <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/facebook-to-target-nigerian-learners-with-educational-app-sabee-created-by-its-rd-team/">recently</a> set up an office in Lagos, Nigeria, and it will soon open another in Asia. It&#8217;s also adjusting its strategy to include making seed-stage investments in small, entrepreneurial teams.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2242100" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>One such check has already been written. Meta&#8217;s <a href="https://fortune.com/2021/11/08/who-would-take-venture-dollars-from-facebook-right-now/">recent investment</a> in an A.I.-powered developer platform for building virtual characters, <a href="https://www.inworld.ai/">Inworld AI</a>, was directed by NPE. But future checks may go to non-metaverse companies to include those with more near-term potential &#8212; like startups taking advantage of the mobile internet in new ways.</p>
<p>Meta, of course, understands that many of today&#8217;s universal experiences first emerged from niche communities. WhatsApp, for example, grew in popularity in regions where SMS text messaging wasn&#8217;t free before it was adopted globally. Some mobile money innovations, meanwhile, grew out of the lack of legacy payment systems in East Africa.</p>
<p>To ensure it&#8217;s not missing out on future opportunities like this, Meta&#8217;s NPE team is looking outside Silicon Valley.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2242255" style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2242255" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2242255" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ime-Archibong.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="390" height="312" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ime-Archibong.jpg 6000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ime-Archibong.jpg?resize=150,120 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ime-Archibong.jpg?resize=300,240 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ime-Archibong.jpg?resize=768,614 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ime-Archibong.jpg?resize=680,544 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ime-Archibong.jpg?resize=1536,1229 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ime-Archibong.jpg?resize=2048,1638 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ime-Archibong.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 390px) 100vw, 390px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2242255" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Meta&#8217;s Ime Archibong</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This new direction is being led by Ime Archibong, head of Meta&#8217;s New Product Experimentation (NPE), an 11-year Meta employee, whose experience prior to NPE included working on Facebook&#8217;s developer platform. That role saw him bouncing around the world to connect with entrepreneurs from both smaller startups and larger companies. After joining NPE two years ago, Archibong is taking the group in a similar direction.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s a bit like what I was doing for the prior 10 years, which is going and attracting a bunch of entrepreneurial talent and small teams, and getting them access to the resources &#8212; which is talent, time and technology to build out their ideas,&#8221; he explained. &#8220;And of course, the objective is that some of the seeds of the ideas that we&#8217;re able to build, at some point, could be very big.&#8221;</p>
<p>The team will focus on markets in Asia, Africa and Latin America as it pursues this new direction, though it isn&#8217;t entirely giving up on U.S.-based projects. However, some of those may look different than they have in the past. Instead of launching and quickly shuttering new social apps that don&#8217;t gain traction, NPE&#8217;s current set of experiments include a project that&#8217;s helping citizens in the U.S. re-enter society after being incarcerated and another aimed at helping LGBTQ families on the journey to becoming parents. These are obviously a bit meatier than just another TikTok clone.</p>
<p>But the expanded focus to include the global stage will see NPE often looking for ideas that may start off small &#8212; perhaps even addressing underserved markets &#8212; but have the potential to scale.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think that the future is going to be built in some of these regions around the world that have been historically overlooked and undervalued,&#8221; Archibong noted. &#8220;I have a firm belief that the problems, solutions, the opportunities and the new experiences that are going to be built by people who are most proximate to the communities that they&#8217;re trying to serve.&#8221; And these solutions will be &#8220;more durable, more sustainable, and more viable&#8221; in the long run, he said.</p>
<p>This thesis itself sounds solid enough &#8212; after all, history has already proved it right. However, the question remains as to whether the global entrepreneurship community will welcome checks written by Meta, given its history of &#8220;borrowing&#8221; ideas from smaller companies.</p>
<p>Meta is widely known to have copied Snapchat&#8217;s Stories and grown it into a much<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/13/instagram-stories-bigger-than-snapchat/"> larger product</a>. It <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/07/facebook-avatars/">launched</a> its own version of Snap&#8217;s Bitmoji. It&#8217;s currently expanding its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/facebook-officially-launches-live-audio-rooms-and-podcasts-in-the-u-s/">Clubhouse</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/facebook-reels-exits-beta-in-the-u-s-with-offers-to-pay-creators-for-well-performing-videos/">TikTok</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/21/facebook-is-working-on-neighborhoods-a-nextdoor-clone-based-on-local-groups/">Nextdoor</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/facebooks-newsletter-platform-bulletin-is-now-live/">Substack</a> clones. A <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/phhhoto-sues-meta-facebook-antitrust/">startup called Phhhoto is even suing Meta</a> for first promising it a partnership opportunity, then ultimately deciding to just build its own version of Phhhoto&#8217;s technology (which became Boomerang from Instagram). What Meta didn&#8217;t copy, it acquired &#8212; whether that was a future rival like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/04/09/facebook-to-acquire-instagram-for-1-billion/">Instagram</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/02/19/crazy-like-a-facebook-fox/">WhatsApp</a> or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/15/facebook-to-acquire-giphy-in-a-deal-reportedly-worth-400-million/">Giphy</a>, or an up-and-comer like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/16/facebook-acquires-anonymous-teen-compliment-app-tbh-will-let-it-run/">tbh</a> or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/04/24/facebook-acquires-activity-tracking-app-moves/">Moves</a>.</p>
<p>While Inworld AI may have felt comfortable working with Meta, given how tightly aligned their missions were in VR, other seed-stage startups may not feel the same. But Archibong believes there will be enough out there who will take the chance.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think that there are going to be more opportunities like that [with Inworld AI]. People who see working with us, a mission-aligned organization with what they&#8217;re trying to do &#8212; an organization that&#8217;s probably pretty excited about similar technology trends, or emergent platforms or user behavior,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The company hasn&#8217;t said how much capital it plans to deploy over what period of time, but the checks &#8212; like the teams themselves &#8212; will be &#8220;really, really small,&#8221; Archibong said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/metas-npe-team-takes-a-global-focus-with-seed-stage-investments-offices-in-emerging-markets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2242100</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beat the price hike and fire up CrunchMatch for TC Sessions: Space 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/beat-the-price-hike-and-fire-up-crunchmatch-for-tc-sessions-space-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/beat-the-price-hike-and-fire-up-crunchmatch-for-tc-sessions-space-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marquise Foster]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 17:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CrunchMatch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions Space 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2240710</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Heads up folks, as we shift metaphors (ever-so-briefly) from space to sports. We’ve got a news double-header for TC Sessions: Space 2021, which takes flight (we said it was brief) on December 14-15. Ready? Here goes part one: If you’re part of the community determined to shape the burgeoning space economy, and you still don’t [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Heads up folks, as we shift metaphors (ever-so-briefly) from space to sports. We’ve got a news double-header for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/">TC Sessions: Space 2021</a>, which takes flight (we said it was brief) on December 14-15.</p>
<p>Ready? Here goes part one: If you’re part of the community determined to shape the burgeoning space economy, and you still don’t have your pass, the time is Now O’clock. Prices go up in just two days. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/#tickets">Buy your pass</a> <strong>before</strong> <strong>December 4</strong>, and you’ll keep $55 in your wallet.</p>
<p>Here’s part two — and even more incentive to get your pass ASAP. CrunchMatch is now open, which means you have 12 full days — before the conference even begins — to search the attendees list and schedule meetings with the people who align with your business goals.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2240710" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>If you’re not familiar with CrunchMatch, it’s our AI-powered platform that replaces frustrating and unreliable needle-in-a-haystack networking with an efficient, highly effective process.</p>
<p>When you register(ed) for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?utm_medium=email &amp;utm_campaign=space2021&amp;utm_content=generaladmission&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=pricesincrease&amp;display=">TC Sessions: Space</a>, you answer a few quick questions about your business preferences, and within minutes you’re automatically registered for CrunchMatch. It’s open as of today, so check your inbox for an email telling you how to access the platform.</p>
<p>CrunchMatch searches for suitable matches based on the info you provided. The algorithm it uses makes fast, precise recommendations, and it gets smarter the more you use it. Check out what other TechCrunch event attendees say about networking the TC way:</p>
<blockquote><p>CrunchMatch made it easy to set up short networking sessions, and I used it to meet with founders in adjacent areas like climate or B2B SaaS. I met interesting people I wouldn&#8217;t necessarily have connected with otherwise. — Ashley Barrington, founder, MarketPearl.</p>
<p>The CrunchMatch networking platform is such a smart, useful tool. It lets you see who’s there, find the right people and reach out for a meeting. I scheduled five or six appointments in one day. The meetings were small, intimate and very informative. — Felicia Jackson, inventor and founder of CPRWrap.</p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Here’s a quick calculation: Save $55 + CrunchMatch = more opportunity for less money. That’s one doozy of a double-header and a formula for success.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?utm_medium=email &amp;utm_campaign=space2021&amp;utm_content=generaladmission&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=pricesincrease&amp;display=">TC Sessions: Space 2021</a> takes place December 14-15, but the price of admission goes up in just two days. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/#tickets">Buy your pass</a> <strong>before December 4</strong>, save $55, fire up CrunchMatch and start connecting to the people who can move your business forward.</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at TC Sessions: Space 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-054de807d08247a54a95307c1ca7ea3f"
			width="99%"
			height="1000"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/054de807d08247a54a95307c1ca7ea3f"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="bizzabo"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-054de807d08247a54a95307c1ca7ea3f')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-054de807d08247a54a95307c1ca7ea3f'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/beat-the-price-hike-and-fire-up-crunchmatch-for-tc-sessions-space-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2240710</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AWS launches Amplify Studio, a new low-code app development tool</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/aws-launches-amplify-studio-a-new-low-code-app-development-tool/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/aws-launches-amplify-studio-a-new-low-code-app-development-tool/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 17:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Web Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amplify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS re:Invent 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Figma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Werner Vogels]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2242217</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At its re:Invent conference, AWS today announced Amplify Studio, a new Figma-connected no-code/low-code service that is meant to help developers quickly build cloud-connected apps. Amplify Studio is an extension of the existing AWS Amplify service, which already focused on building web and mobile apps, but without the easy to use drag-and-drop interface of Amplify Studio. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At its re:Invent conference, AWS today <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/mobile/aws-amplify-studio-figma-to-fullstack-react-app-with-minimal-programming/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/amplify/studio/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amplify Studio</a>, a new Figma-connected no-code/low-code service that is meant to help developers quickly build cloud-connected apps. Amplify Studio is an extension of the existing AWS Amplify service, which already focused on building web and mobile apps, but without the easy to use drag-and-drop interface of Amplify Studio.</p>
<p>AWS has made an interesting move here by connecting Studio to the popular Figma user interface design tool. Through this, designers can build the interface in Figma and then the developers can connect this to their backend data and build the application logic in Studio. It also frees AWS from having to build its own design tool, of course. Amplify Studio does this by translating Figma designs into React UI component code.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2242243" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ezgif-3-b98b50e3f6a6.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2242243" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2242243" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ezgif-3-b98b50e3f6a6.gif" alt="" width="600" height="375" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2242243" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits: </strong>AWS</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2242217" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;With Studio’s new &#8216;UI Library (Preview),&#8217; you can sync components from Figma to Amplify Studio,&#8221; AWS&#8217;s Rene Brandel writes in today&#8217;s announcement. &#8220;Amplify also provides you a handy Figma file to get started faster. The Amplify Figma file includes both UI primitives and pre-built components. Studio can also sync any new components created in Figma as well!&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2242268" style="width: 786px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/front-to-back.224f6f3948fdd43ab4614ffe1a527f5a436fb85d-1.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2242268" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2242268 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/front-to-back.224f6f3948fdd43ab4614ffe1a527f5a436fb85d-1.png" alt="" width="776" height="416" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/front-to-back.224f6f3948fdd43ab4614ffe1a527f5a436fb85d-1.png 776w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/front-to-back.224f6f3948fdd43ab4614ffe1a527f5a436fb85d-1.png?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/front-to-back.224f6f3948fdd43ab4614ffe1a527f5a436fb85d-1.png?resize=300,161 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/front-to-back.224f6f3948fdd43ab4614ffe1a527f5a436fb85d-1.png?resize=768,412 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/front-to-back.224f6f3948fdd43ab4614ffe1a527f5a436fb85d-1.png?resize=680,365 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/front-to-back.224f6f3948fdd43ab4614ffe1a527f5a436fb85d-1.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 776px) 100vw, 776px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2242268" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> AWS</p></div></p>
<p>As Amazon CTO Werner Vogels noted, the company still considers this a developer-first service, mostly for front-end engineers. That means there&#8217;s still some code to write here and there, and developers can easily export their apps into their existing DevOps pipeline.</p>
<p>If necessary, developers will also be able to override some of the pre-built components in Amplify Studio, using the AWS Cloud Development Kit. With this, AWS argues, developers won&#8217;t hit a wall, where they won&#8217;t be able to scale their apps as they &#8212; and their needs &#8212; grow.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/aws-reinvent-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/aws-reinvent-2021-banner.png" alt="read more about AWS re:Invent 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/aws-launches-amplify-studio-a-new-low-code-app-development-tool/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2242217</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AWS Cloud WAN aims to connect geographically complex environments to cloud</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/amazon-announces-aws-cloud-wan-to-connect-geographically-complex-environments-to-cloud/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/amazon-announces-aws-cloud-wan-to-connect-geographically-complex-environments-to-cloud/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 17:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS re:Invent 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Werner Vogels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wide area networking]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2242221</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Companies face all kinds of challenges moving to the cloud. The more complex and spread out you are geographically, the more difficult it becomes to manage your network. In an effort to solve this issue, Amazon announced AWS Cloud WAN today to bring software-defined wide area networking to AWS. Amazon chief technology officer Werner Vogels [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Companies face all kinds of challenges moving to the cloud. The more complex and spread out you are geographically, the more difficult it becomes to manage your network. In an effort to solve this issue, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/networking-and-content-delivery/introducing-aws-cloud-wan-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon announced AWS Cloud WAN</a> today to bring software-defined wide area networking to AWS.</p>
<p>Amazon chief technology officer Werner Vogels explained the complexities around managing a worldwide network have grown as the company&#8217;s offerings have grown. &#8220;Now, even with all of these components, building a global network, connecting maybe hundreds of your offices to the cloud, is still a big challenge,&#8221; Vogels explained to the AWS re:Invent audience in Las Vegas this morning.</p>
<p>Vogels says that the company began looking at how it could solve this for AWS customers. &#8220;So we started to think about how can we help these customers really overcome all the heavy lifting that you have to do if you have a very widespread network that you need to connect to the cloud. So today, I&#8217;m happy to announce AWS Cloud WAN, which gives you the ability to build, manage and monitor global traffic across a wide area network using AWS.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2242221" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>You can select the regions you want to use, then select the offices and facilities you want to connect. &#8220;Then automatically once you actually define this, all the remote users and sites and data centers will connect to the geographically closest location using a VPN or direct connect, and actually builds it for you in minutes using the big AWS backbone for you to give you a highly reliable and highly available software-defined, wide area network running over the AWS infrastructure,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>This new capability is available in preview starting today across multiple regions around the world.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/aws-reinvent-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/aws-reinvent-2021-banner.png" alt="read more about AWS re:Invent 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/amazon-announces-aws-cloud-wan-to-connect-geographically-complex-environments-to-cloud/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2242221</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AWS to launch over 30 new Local Zones internationally starting in 2022</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/aws-to-launch-over-30-new-local-zones-starting-in-2022/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/aws-to-launch-over-30-new-local-zones-starting-in-2022/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 17:12:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Web Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS re:Invent 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[local zones]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2242212</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At its annual re:Invent conference, AWS announced that it will be launching over 30 new AWS Local Zones in major cities around the world. These new AWS Local Zones will be made available starting in 2022 in more than 21 countries, including Argentina, Australia, Austria, Belgium, Brazil, Canada, Chile, Colombia, Czech Republic, Denmark, Finland, Germany, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At its annual re:Invent conference, AWS <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/localzones/locations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that it will be launching over 30 new AWS Local Zones in major cities around the world. These new AWS Local Zones will be made available starting in 2022 in more than 21 countries, including Argentina, Australia, Austria, Belgium, Brazil, Canada, Chile, Colombia, Czech Republic, Denmark, Finland, Germany, Greece, India, Kenya, Netherlands, Norway, Philippines, Poland, Portugal and South Africa.</p>
<p>For context, AWS Local Zones are a type of AWS infrastructure deployment that places compute, storage and other select services closer to customers, giving them the ability to run applications on AWS that require single-digit millisecond latencies to their end-users or on-premise installations.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2242215" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2242215" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2242215" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/aws-local-zones.png" alt="" width="1024" height="500" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/aws-local-zones.png 2364w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/aws-local-zones.png?resize=150,73 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/aws-local-zones.png?resize=300,146 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/aws-local-zones.png?resize=768,375 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/aws-local-zones.png?resize=680,332 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/aws-local-zones.png?resize=1536,750 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/aws-local-zones.png?resize=2048,1000 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/aws-local-zones.png?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2242215" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> AWS</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2242212" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">&#8220;I&#8217;m very</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">excited</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">to</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">announce</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">that</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">we</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">will</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">be</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">expanding</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">the</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">local</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">zones</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">internationally</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">across</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">the</span> <span class="transcript-snippet__content__body__word ng-star-inserted">world in Europe, South America, Africa, Asia and Australia,&#8221; Amazon CTO Werner Vogels said during the event. &#8220;And of course we will have one in my home city of Amsterdam.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>AWS notes that these new locations join 16 Local Zones across the United States, and will help customers serve end-users around the world with even lower latency. The current Local Zones are located in Boston, Chicago, Dallas, Denver, Houston, Kansas City, Las Vegas, Los Angeles, Miami, Minneapolis, New York City, Philadelphia and Portland.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/aws-reinvent-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/aws-reinvent-2021-banner.png" alt="read more about AWS re:Invent 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/aws-to-launch-over-30-new-local-zones-starting-in-2022/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2242212</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>EU warns adtech giants over &#8216;legal tricks&#8217; as it moots changes to centralize privacy oversight</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/gdpr-centralized-enforcement/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/gdpr-centralized-enforcement/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 16:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andrea Jelinek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[belgium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CJEU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Protection Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EDPB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Data Protection Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kent Walker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Max Schrems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[noyb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vera Jourova]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wojciech Wiewiórowski]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2242073</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The European Commission has given its clearest signal yet that it&#8217;s prepared to intervene over weak enforcement of the EU&#8217;s data protection rules against big tech. Today the bloc&#8217;s executive also had a warning for adtech giants Google and Facebook &#8212; accusing them of choosing &#8220;legal tricks&#8221; over true compliance with the EU&#8217;s standard of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The European Commission has given its clearest signal yet that it&#8217;s prepared to intervene over weak enforcement of the EU&#8217;s data protection rules against big tech.</p>
<p>Today the bloc&#8217;s executive also had a warning for adtech giants Google and Facebook &#8212; accusing them of choosing &#8220;legal tricks&#8221; over true compliance with the EU&#8217;s standard of &#8220;privacy by design&#8221; &#8212; and emphasizing the imperative for them to take data protection &#8220;seriously&#8221;.</p>
<p>Speaking at a privacy conference this morning, Vera Jourová, the EU&#8217;s commissioner for values and transparency, said enforcement of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) at a national level must buck up &#8212; and become &#8220;effective&#8221; &#8212; or else it &#8220;will have to change&#8221;, warning specifying that any &#8220;potential changes&#8221; will move toward centralized enforcement.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2242073" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p class="m_9153046325992127683Briefinglist1"><span lang="EN-GB">&#8220;When I was looking at existing enforcement decisions and pending cases, I also came to another conclusion,&#8221; she also said.  &#8220;<u></u><u></u></span><u></u><span lang="EN-GB">So, we have penalties or decisions against <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/19/french-court-slaps-down-googles-appeal-against-57m-gdpr-fine/">Google</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/irelands-draft-gdpr-decision-against-facebook-branded-a-joke/">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/whatsapp-faces-267m-fine-for-breaching-europes-gdpr/">WhatsApp</a>.</span></p>
<p class="m_9153046325992127683Briefinglist1"><u></u><u></u><u></u><span lang="EN-GB">&#8220;To me this means that clearly there is a problem with compliance culture among those companies that live off our personal data. D<u></u><u></u></span><u></u><span lang="EN-GB">espite the fact that they have the best legal teams, presence in Brussels and spent countless hours discussing with us the GDPR. <u></u><u></u></span><u></u><span lang="EN-GB">Sadly, I fear this is not privacy by design.<u></u><u></u></span></p>
<p><u></u><span lang="EN-GB">&#8220;</span><u></u><span lang="EN-GB">I think it is high time for those companies to take protection of personal data seriously. I want to see full compliance, not legal tricks. It’s time not to hide behind small print, but tackle the challenges head on.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>In parallel, an influential advisor to the bloc&#8217;s top court has <a href="https://curia.europa.eu/jcms/upload/docs/application/pdf/2021-12/cp210216en.pdf">today</a> published an opinion which states that EU law does not preclude consumer protection agencies from bringing representative actions at a national level &#8212; following a referral by a German court in a case against Facebook Ireland &#8212; which, if the CJEU&#8217;s judges agree, could open up a fresh wave of challenges to tech giants&#8217; misuse of people&#8217;s data without the need to funnel complaints through the single point of failure of gatekeeper regulators like Ireland&#8217;s Data Protection Commission (DPC).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ga438rGsSB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/facebooks-lead-eu-privacy-supervisor-hit-with-corruption-complaint/">Facebook&#8217;s lead EU privacy supervisor hit with corruption complaint</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook&#8217;s lead EU privacy supervisor hit with corruption complaint&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/facebooks-lead-eu-privacy-supervisor-hit-with-corruption-complaint/embed/#?secret=Ga438rGsSB" data-secret="Ga438rGsSB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Towards centralized privacy oversight?</h2>
<p>On paper, EU law provides people in the region with a suite of rights and protections attached to their data. And while the regulation has attracted huge international attention, as other regions grapple with how to protect people in an age of data-mining giants, the problem for many GDPR critics, as it stands, is that the law decentralizes oversight of these rules and rights to a patchwork of supervisory agencies at the EU Member State level.</p>
<p>While this can work well for cases involving locally bounded services, major problems arise where complaints span borders within the EU &#8212; as is always the case with tech giants&#8217; (global) services. This is because a one-stop-shop (OSS) mechanism kicks in, ostensibly to reduce the administrative burden for businesses.</p>
<p>But it also enables a huge get-out clause for tech giants, allowing them to forum shop for a &#8216;friendly&#8217; regulator through their choice of where to locate their regional HQ. And working from a local EU base, corporate giants can use investment and job creation in that Member State as a lever to work against and erode national political will to press for vigorous oversight of their European business at the local authority level.</p>
<p>&#8220;In my view, it does take too long to address the key questions around processing of personal data for big tech,&#8221; said Jourová giving a keynote speech to the Forum Europe data protection &amp; privacy conference. &#8220;Yes, I understand the lack of resources. I understand there is no pan-European procedural law to help the cross-border cases. I understand that the first cases need to be rock-solid because they will be challenged in court.</p>
<p>&#8220;But I want to be honest &#8212; we are in the crunch time now. Either we will all collectively show that GDPR enforcement is effective or it will have to change. And there is no way back to decentralised model that was there before the GDPR. Any potential changes will go towards more centralisation, bigger role of the EDPB [European Data Protection Board] or Commission.&#8221;</p>
<p>Jourová added that the &#8220;pressure&#8221; to make enforcement effective &#8220;is already here&#8221; &#8212; pointing to debate around incoming legislation that will update the EU&#8217;s rules around ecommerce, and emphasizing that, on the Digital Services Act, Member States have been advocating for enforcement change &#8212; and &#8220;want to see more central role of the European Commission&#8221;.</p>
<p>Point being that if there&#8217;s political will for structural changes to centralize EU enforcement among Member States, the Commission has the powers to propose the necessary amendments &#8212; and will hardly turn its nose up at being asked to take on more responsibility itself.</p>
<p>Jourová&#8217;s remarks are a notable step up on her approach to the thorny issue of GDPR enforcement back in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/">summer 2020</a> &#8212; when, at the two year review mark of the regulation entering into application, she was still talking about the need to properly resource DPAs &#8212; in order that they could &#8220;step up their work&#8221; and deliver &#8220;vigorous but uniform enforcement&#8221;, as she put it then.</p>
<p>Now, in the dying days of 2021 &#8212; with a still massive backlog of decisions yet to be issued around cross-border cases, some of which are highly strategic, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/25/facebook-google-face-first-gdpr-complaints-over-forced-consent/">targeting adtech platforms&#8217; core surveillance business model</a> (Jourová&#8217;s speech, for example, noted that 809 procedures related to the OSS have been triggered but only 290 Final Decisions have been issued) &#8212; the Commission appears to be signalling that it&#8217;s finally running out of patience on enforcement.</p>
<p>And that it is already eyeing a Plan B to make the GDPR truly effective.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tlg1RBmPlH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/irelands-draft-gdpr-decision-against-facebook-branded-a-joke/">Ireland&#8217;s draft GDPR decision against Facebook branded a joke</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ireland&#8217;s draft GDPR decision against Facebook branded a joke&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/13/irelands-draft-gdpr-decision-against-facebook-branded-a-joke/embed/#?secret=tlg1RBmPlH" data-secret="tlg1RBmPlH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Criticism of weak enforcement against tech giants has been a rising chorus in Europe for years. Most recently frustration with regulatory inaction led privacy campaigner Max Schrems&#8217; not-for-profit, noyb, to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/facebooks-lead-eu-privacy-supervisor-hit-with-corruption-complaint/">file a complaint of criminal corruption</a> against the GDPR&#8217;s most infamous bottleneck: Ireland&#8217;s DPC, accusing the regulator of engaging in &#8220;procedural blackmail&#8221; which it suggested would help Facebook by keeping key developments out of the public eye, among other eye-raising charges.</p>
<p>The Irish regulator has faced the strongest criticism of all the EU DPAs over its role in hampering effective GDPR enforcement.</p>
<p>Although it&#8217;s not the only authority to be accused of creating a bottleneck by letting major complaints pile up on its desk and taking a painstaking ice-age to investigate complaints and issue decisions (assuming it opens an investigation at all).</p>
<p>The UK&#8217;s ICO &#8212; when the country was still in the EU &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/17/privacy-experts-slam-uks-disastrous-failure-to-tackle-unlawful-adtech/">did nothing</a> about complaints against real-time-bidding&#8217;s abuse of people&#8217;s data, for example, despite <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/20/behavioural-advertising-is-out-of-control-warns-uk-watchdog/">sounding a public warning over behavioral ads&#8217; unlawfulness as early as 2019</a>. While Belgium&#8217;s DPA has been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/16/iab-europes-ad-tracking-consent-framework-found-to-fail-gdpr-standard/">taking a painstaking amount of time</a> to issue a final decision on the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/iab-europe-tcf-gdpr-breach-belgium/">IAB Europe&#8217;s TCF&#8217;s failure to comply with the GDPR</a>. <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">But Ireland&#8217;s central role in regulating most of big tech means it attracts the most flak. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="O3CeWN3oNv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/iab-europe-tcf-gdpr-breach-belgium/">IAB Europe says it&#8217;s expecting to be found in breach of GDPR</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;IAB Europe says it&#8217;s expecting to be found in breach of GDPR&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/iab-europe-tcf-gdpr-breach-belgium/embed/#?secret=O3CeWN3oNv" data-secret="O3CeWN3oNv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The sheer number of tech giants that have converged on Ireland &#8212; wooed by low corporate tax rates (likely with the added cherry of business-friendly data oversight) &#8212; gives it an outsized role in overseeing what&#8217;s done with European&#8217;s data.</p>
<p>Hence Ireland has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/22/googles-lead-eu-regulator-opens-formal-privacy-probe-of-its-adtech/">open investigations</a> into Apple, Google, Facebook and many others &#8212; yet has only issued two final decisions on cross-border cases so far (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/twitter-fined-550k-over-a-data-breach-in-irelands-first-major-gdpr-decision/">Twitter</a> last year; and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/whatsapp-faces-267m-fine-for-breaching-europes-gdpr/">WhatsApp</a> this year).</p>
<p>Both of those decisions went through a dispute mechanism that&#8217;s also baked into the GDPR &#8212; which kicks in when other EU DPAs don&#8217;t agree with a draft decision by the lead authority.</p>
<p>That mechanism further slowed down the DPC&#8217;s enforcement in those cases &#8212; but substantially cranked up the intervention the two companies ultimately faced. Ireland had wanted to be a lot more lenient vs the collective verdict once all of the bloc&#8217;s oversight bodies had had their say.</p>
<p>That too, critics say, demonstrates the DPC&#8217;s regulatory capture by platform power.</p>
<p>An opinion piece in yesterday&#8217;s <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/irelands-the-wrong-privacy-watchdog-for-europe/2021/12/01/6a8d7b64-5274-11ec-83d2-d9dab0e23b7e_story.html">Washington Post</a> skewered the DPC as &#8220;the wrong privacy watchdog for Europe&#8221; &#8212; citing a study by the Irish Council for Civil Liberties that found it had only published decisions on about 2% of the 164 cross border cases it has taken on.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The number of complaints the DPC has chosen to entirely ignore &#8212; i.e. by not opening a formal investigation &#8212; or else to quietly shutter (&#8220;resolve&#8221;) without issuing a decision or taking any enforcement action is likely considerably higher. </span></p>
<p>The agency is shielded by a very narrow application of Freedom of Information law, which applies only in relation to DPC records pertaining to the &#8220;general administration&#8221; of its office. So when TechCrunch asked the DPC, last December, how many times it had used GDPR powers such as the ability to order a ban on processing it declined to respond to our FOIs &#8212; arguing the information did not fall under Ireland&#8217;s implementation of the law.</p>
<p>Silence and stonewalling only go so far, though.</p>
<p>Calls for root and branch reform of the DPC specifically, and enforcement of the GDPR more generally, can now be heard from Ireland&#8217;s own parliament all the way up to the European Commission. And big tech&#8217;s game of tying EU regulators in knots looks as if it&#8217;s &#8212; gradually, gradually &#8212; getting toward the end of its rope.</p>
<p>What comes next is an interesting question. Last month the European Data Protection Superviso (EDPS) <a href="https://edps.europa.eu/data-protection/our-work/publications/brochures/future-data-protection-effective-enforcement_en">announced</a> a conference on the future of &#8220;effective&#8221; digital enforcement &#8212; which will take place in June 2022 &#8212; and which he said would discuss best practice and also &#8220;explore alternative models of enforcement for the digital future&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are ambitious,&#8221; said Wojciech Wiewiorowski as he announced the conference. &#8220;There is much scope for discussion and much potential improvement on the way current governance models are implemented in practice. We envisage a dialogue across different fields of regulation &#8212; from data protection to competition, digital markets and services, and artificial intelligence as well &#8212; both in the EU, and Europe as a continent, but also on the global level.&#8221;</p>
<p>Discussion of &#8220;different&#8221; and &#8220;alternative&#8221; models of enforcement will be a focus of the event, per Wiewiorowski &#8212; who further specified that this will include discussion of &#8220;a more centralized approach&#8221;. So the EDPS and the Commission appear to be singing a similar tune on reforming GDPR enforcement.</p>
<p>As well as the Commission itself (potentially) taking on an enforcement role in the future &#8212; perhaps specifically on major, cross border cases related to big tech, in order to beef up GDPR&#8217;s application against the most powerful offenders (as is already proposed in the case of the DSA and enforcing those rules against &#8216;very large online platforms&#8217;; aka vLOPs) &#8212; the GDPR steering and advisory body, the EDPB, also looks set to play an increasingly strategic and important role.</p>
<p>Indeed, it already has a &#8216;last resort&#8217; decision making power to resolve disputes over cross border GDPR enforcement &#8212; and Ireland&#8217;s intransigence has led to it exercising this power for the first time.</p>
<p>In the future, the Board&#8217;s role could expand further if EU lawmakers decide that more centralization is the only way to deliver effective enforcement against tech giants that have become experts in exhausting regulators with bad faith arguments and whack-a-mole procedures, in order to delay, defer and deny compliance with European law.</p>
<p>The EDPB&#8217;s chair, Andrea Jelinek, was also speaking at the Forum Europe conference today. Asked for her thoughts on how GDPR enforcement could improve, including problematic elements like the OSS, she cautioned that change will be a &#8220;long term project&#8221;, while simultaneously agreeing there are notable &#8220;challenges&#8221; at the point where national oversight intersects with the needs of cross border enforcement.</p>
<p>&#8220;Enforcing at a national level and at the same time resolving cross border cases is time and resource intensive,&#8221; she said. &#8220;Supervisory authorities need to carry out investigations, observe procedural rules, coordinate and share information with other supervisory authorities. For the current system to work properly it is of vital important that supervisory authorities have enough resources and staff.</p>
<p>&#8220;The differences in national administrative procedures and the fact that in some Member States no deadlines are foreseen for handling a case also creates an obstacle to the efficient functioning of the OSS.&#8221;</p>
<p>Jelinek made a point of emphasizing that EDPB has been taking action to try to remedy some of issues identified &#8212; implementing what she described as &#8220;a series of practical solutions&#8221; to tackle problems around enforcement.</p>
<p>She said this has included developing (last year) a co-ordinated enforcement framework to facilitate joint actions (&#8220;in a flexible and coordinated manner&#8221;) &#8212; such as launching enforcement sweeps and joint investigations.</p>
<p>The EPBD is also establishing a pilot project to provide a pool of experts to support investigations and enforcement activities &#8220;of significant common interest&#8221;, she noted, predicting: &#8220;This will enhance the cooperation and solidarity between all the supervisory authorities by addressing their operational needs.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Finally we should not forget that the GDPR is a long term project and so is strengthening cooperation between supervisory authorities,&#8221; she added. &#8220;Any transformation of the GDPR will take years. I think the best solution is therefore to deploy the GDPR fully &#8212; it is likely that most of the issues identified by Member States and stakeholders will benefit from more experience in the application of the regulation in the coming years.&#8221;</p>
<p>However it is already well over three years since GDPR came into application. So many EU citizens may query the logic of waiting <em>years</em> <em>more</em> for regulators to figure out how to jointly work together to get the job of upholding people&#8217;s rights done. Not least because this enforcement impasse leaves data-mining tech giants free to direct their vast data-enabled wealth and engineering resource at developing new &#8216;innovations&#8217; &#8212; to better evade legal restrictions on what they can do with people&#8217;s data.</p>
<p>One thing is clear: The next wave of big tech regulatory evasion will come dressed up in claims of privacy &#8220;innovation&#8221; from the get-go.</p>
<p>Indeed, that is already how adtech giants like Google are trying to re-channel regulators&#8217; attention from enforcing against their core attention-manipulation, surveillance-based business model.</p>
<p>Google SVP Kent Walker also took to the (virtual) conference stage this morning for a keynote slot in which he argued that the novel ad targeting technologies Google is developing under its &#8220;Privacy Sandbox&#8221; badge (such as FloCs; aka <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/google-isnt-testing-flocs-in-europe-yet/">federated learning of cohorts</a>) will provide the answer to what big (ad)tech likes to claim is an inherent tension between European fundamental rights like privacy and economic growth.</p>
<p>The truth, as ever, is a lot more nuanced than that. For one thing, there are plenty of ways to target ads that don&#8217;t require processing people&#8217;s data. But as most of Europe&#8217;s regulators remain bogged down in a mire of corporate capture, under-resourcing, culture cowardice/risk aversion, internecine squabbles and, at times, a sheer lack of national political will to enforce the law against the world&#8217;s wealthiest companies, the adtech duopoly is sounding cockily confident that it will be allowed to carry on and reset the terms of the game in its own interests once again.</p>
<p>(The added irony here is that Google is currently working under the oversight of the UK&#8217;s Competition and Markets Authority and ICO on shaping behavioral remedies attached to its Sandbox proposals &#8212; and has said that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/26/cma-google-privacy-sandbox-revisions/">these commitments will be applied globally</a> if the UK is minded to accept them; which does risk tarnishing the GDPR&#8217;s geopolitical shine, given the UK is no longer a member of the EU&#8230; )</p>
<p>For EU citizens, it could well mean that &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/16/europes-top-court-strikes-down-flagship-eu-us-data-transfer-mechanism/">once again</a> &#8212; it&#8217;s up to the CJEU to come to the rescue of their fundamental rights &#8212; assuming the court ends up concurring with advocate general Richard de la Tour&#8217;s opinion today that the GDPR:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8221; &#8230; does not preclude national legislation which allows consumer protection associations to bring legal proceedings against the person alleged to be responsible for an infringement of the protection of personal data, on the basis of the prohibition of unfair commercial practices, the infringement of a law relating to consumer protection or the prohibition of the use of invalid general terms and conditions, provided that the objective of the representative action in question is to ensure observance of the rights which the persons affected by the contested processing derive directly from that regulation.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Consumer protection agencies being able to pursue representative legal actions to defend fundamental rights against tech giants&#8217; self interest &#8212; at the Member State level, and therefore, all across the EU &#8212; could actually unblock GDPR enforcement via a genuinely decentralized wave of enforcement that&#8217;s able to route around the damage of captured gatekeepers and call out big adtech&#8217;s manipulative tricks in court.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hycXxVsfnx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/26/cma-google-privacy-sandbox-revisions/">Google agrees with UK&#8217;s CMA to deeper oversight of Privacy Sandbox</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google agrees with UK&#8217;s CMA to deeper oversight of Privacy Sandbox&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/26/cma-google-privacy-sandbox-revisions/embed/#?secret=hycXxVsfnx" data-secret="hycXxVsfnx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tuVTcUk8zR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/">GDPR&#8217;s two-year review flags lack of &#8216;vigorous&#8217; enforcement</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GDPR&#8217;s two-year review flags lack of &#8216;vigorous&#8217; enforcement&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/embed/#?secret=tuVTcUk8zR" data-secret="tuVTcUk8zR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/gdpr-centralized-enforcement/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2242073</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AWS brings M1 Mac minis to its cloud</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/aws-brings-m1-mac-minis-to-its-cloud/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/aws-brings-m1-mac-minis-to-its-cloud/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 16:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Web Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS re:Invent 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ec2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eucalyptus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mac mini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mac os]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macintosh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oregon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Werner Vogels]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2242200</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At today&#8217;s AWS re:Invent keynote, Amazon CTO Werner Vogels announced that AWS will now offer M1 Mac minis as part of its EC2 compute service. It was only last year that AWS first brought Mac minis to its cloud. Using the Thunderbolt port, these minis connect to the AWS Nitro System, which helps make them [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At today&#8217;s AWS re:Invent keynote, Amazon CTO Werner Vogels <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/use-amazon-ec2-m1-mac-instances-to-build-test-macos-ios-ipados-tvos-and-watchos-apps/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that AWS will now offer M1 Mac minis as part of its EC2 compute service.</p>
<p>It was only last year that AWS first <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/aws-brings-the-mac-mini-to-its-cloud/">brought Mac minis to its cloud</a>. Using the Thunderbolt port, these minis connect to the AWS Nitro System, which helps make them available in the EC2 cloud, just like any other instance. The minis used here are the standard M1 8 core machines with 16 GiB of memory.</p>
<p>The new instances will be available in two regions (US West &#8211; Oregon and US East &#8211; North Virginia) for $0.6498 per hour, with support for discounts through AWS&#8217; Savings Plans, too. AWS promises that these new machines offer a &#8220;60% better price performance over the x86-based EC2 Mac instances for iPhone and Mac app build workloads.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2242200" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2242211" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mac2-GUI-via-VNC-1024x761-1.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2242211" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2242211" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mac2-GUI-via-VNC-1024x761-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="761" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mac2-GUI-via-VNC-1024x761-1.png 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mac2-GUI-via-VNC-1024x761-1.png?resize=150,111 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mac2-GUI-via-VNC-1024x761-1.png?resize=300,223 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mac2-GUI-via-VNC-1024x761-1.png?resize=768,571 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mac2-GUI-via-VNC-1024x761-1.png?resize=680,505 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mac2-GUI-via-VNC-1024x761-1.png?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2242211" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> AWS</p></div></p>
<p>The use case for these machines hasn&#8217;t changed with this launch. Just like with the original Mac instances, the idea here is to provide developers with the hardware to build and test their applications for Mac OS and iOS apps.</p>
<p>This launch is probably no surprise to most, given that the M1 Mac minis were already rolling out when the first Mac instances launched. At the time, AWS said M1 machines will arrive &#8220;early next year.&#8221; It looks like it took a bit longer to roll these out.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mmelIvOiRI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/aws-brings-the-mac-mini-to-its-cloud/">AWS brings the Mac mini to its cloud</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;AWS brings the Mac mini to its cloud&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/aws-brings-the-mac-mini-to-its-cloud/embed/#?secret=mmelIvOiRI" data-secret="mmelIvOiRI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/aws-reinvent-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/aws-reinvent-2021-banner.png" alt="read more about AWS re:Invent 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/aws-brings-m1-mac-minis-to-its-cloud/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2242200</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mexico&#8217;s Mendel secures $35M to tackle LatAm&#8217;s corporate spend management problem</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/mexicos-mendel-secures-35m-to-tackle-corporate-spend-management-in-latam/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/mexicos-mendel-secures-35m-to-tackle-corporate-spend-management-in-latam/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 16:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ALLVP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[infinity ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mendel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2242159</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mendel, a corporate spend management solution for enterprises in Latin America, announced today that it has secured $35 million in debt and equity.  The Mexico-based startup closed the $15 million Series A round and $20 million debt financing after participating in Y Combinator’s Winter 2021 cohort. ALLVP and Infinity Ventures, a firm founded by a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://mendel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mendel</a>, a corporate spend management solution for enterprises in Latin America, announced today that it has secured $35 million in debt and equity. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Mexico-based startup closed the $15 million Series A round and $20 million debt financing after participating in Y Combinator’s Winter 2021 cohort. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ALLVP and </span><a href="https://www.infinityvc.capital/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Infinity</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Ventures, a firm founded by a trio of ex-PayPal execs, co-led the equity raise. A number of angel investors also participated including Airbase Founder and CEO Thejo Kote, Auth0 co-founder and CTO Matias Woloski, Mercado Libre CFO Pedro Arnt, Kavak COO  and Bain Capital’s Keri Gohman, among others.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Better Tomorrow Ventures, Broadhaven and Magma Partners are also backers of the company.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2242159" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mendel’s mission is straightforward: to reinvent corporate spend management by automating most of the operations for an enterprise CFO that are currently done manually. Or put even more simply, it wants to be a one-stop shop for all B2B spend. Alan Karpovsky &amp; Alejandro Zecler (who both previously founded and sold other startups) started the company late last year and Helena Polyblank (CPO) and Gonzalo Castiglione (CTO) later joined as co-founders.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you look at all the different areas of any enterprise company in LatAm, the CFO function is clearly the one that has had the least innovation,” said </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Karpovsky. “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unlike CMOs who have all sorts of media optimization platforms, content creation tools and social listening software, and CTOs who have countless frameworks, repositories, CI and code-enhancement collaboration tools, CFOs still rely mostly on spreadsheets and ERPs &#8211; and in some companies even fax machines.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/as-corporate-cards-are-subsumed-into-software-airbase-posts-rapid-growth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">corporate spend space</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is an increasingly crowded one. Ramp and Brex have both raised large rounds this year, and TripActions pivoted last year beyond travel to general expense management. Divvy got acquired by Bill.com. Mendel, however, likens its model to being more similar to that of Airbase, a U.S.-based corporate spend startup that in June closed </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/airbase-raises-60m-as-the-corporate-spend-market-segments-matures/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a $60 million Series B</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> led by Menlo Ventures and whose CEO is an investor.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our current solution is like ‘Ramp for Latin America for enterprises,’ ” Karpovsky told TechCrunch. “In the U.S., all these companies are targeting the startups/SMB sector. We are deeply focused on providing enterprise solutions for big companies where the CFO doesn&#8217;t wake up every morning thinking ‘How can I get more cash back’?” </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KKwBSRjArJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/as-corporate-cards-are-subsumed-into-software-airbase-posts-rapid-growth/">As corporate cards are subsumed into software, Airbase posts rapid growth</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As corporate cards are subsumed into software, Airbase posts rapid growth&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/as-corporate-cards-are-subsumed-into-software-airbase-posts-rapid-growth/embed/#?secret=KKwBSRjArJ" data-secret="KKwBSRjArJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mendel says its software gives finance teams a way to manage card transactions in real time, set</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> granular spend rules and track spending from a central dashboard. Its roadmap will go beyond expense management to include accounts payable automation, employee cash advance and factoring.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Part of Mendel’s strategy is to attract customers with high payment volume and low credit risk, while at the same time charging a SaaS fee for the usage of their platform. The startup, which is focused on the Mexican market for now, has started strong &#8212; onboarding more than 150 clients (such as </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mercado Libre, PetCo and Telcel) </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in the first months since it launched earlier this year. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mendel says its payment volume (GTV) </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">has increased by 100x in the last three months. Currently, its  payment volume is growing 2x week over week, according to Karpovsky. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The B2B payment market in Mexico is a massive opportunity, the company believes, especially considering how few payments are made by cards. In fact, Karpovsky said that traditional banks and American Express have not been growing market share in the country “for years.”</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2242170" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2242170" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2242170 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mendel-Platform-Mobile-App-and-Card.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="403" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mendel-Platform-Mobile-App-and-Card.jpg 5218w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mendel-Platform-Mobile-App-and-Card.jpg?resize=150,89 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mendel-Platform-Mobile-App-and-Card.jpg?resize=300,178 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mendel-Platform-Mobile-App-and-Card.jpg?resize=768,456 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mendel-Platform-Mobile-App-and-Card.jpg?resize=680,403 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mendel-Platform-Mobile-App-and-Card.jpg?resize=1536,911 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mendel-Platform-Mobile-App-and-Card.jpg?resize=2048,1215 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mendel-Platform-Mobile-App-and-Card.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2242170" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Mendel</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Presently, Mendel </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">has 70 employees and it expects to end 2022 with 200. It also plans to use its new capital to “invest heavily” in product development, including expansion into broader B2B payments, as well as toward marketing and awareness. Money will also go toward developing new business verticals and partnerships.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Its investors are naturally bullish on the company’s potential.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">ALLVP’s Federico Antoni said his firm has been looking at the corporate spend and financial services space for years, viewing it as a “huge opportunity” in LatAm.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it came across Mendel, he was impressed by the team’s vision to “build the next Nubank for corporates.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The mission and vision for Mendel resonated with us immediately,” he told TechCrunch. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Infinity&#8217;s Mario Ruiz agrees.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“In Latin America, larger enterprises are underserved by incumbents, and Mendel is democratizing access to best-in-class software and payments,&#8221; he wrote via email. &#8220;As we have seen with the success of other corporate card and expense management startups globally, we believe that Mendel has the team, technology, and tenacity to become the leader in Latin America.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Better Tomorrow Ventures’ Sheel Mohnot said his firm was drawn to invest in Mendel because its “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">product really needs to exist” in LatAm where “no one else is going after” the problem.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’ve seen a lot of success with this model in the states and there is more of a need in LatAm &#8212; companies don’t just give cards to everyone, the spend controls are important,” he said. “These guys have previously built a successful business in a similar business and had already signed on Mercado Libre as a customer before we led the seed round.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0bqnYXHDBB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/why-global-investors-are-flocking-to-back-latin-american-startups/">Why global investors are flocking to back Latin American startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why global investors are flocking to back Latin American startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/why-global-investors-are-flocking-to-back-latin-american-startups/embed/#?secret=0bqnYXHDBB" data-secret="0bqnYXHDBB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/mexicos-mendel-secures-35m-to-tackle-corporate-spend-management-in-latam/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2242159</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
