<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 10:39:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Ava expands its AI captioning to desktop and web apps, and raises $4.5M to scale</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/ava-expands-its-ai-captioning-to-desktop-and-web-apps-and-raises-4-5m-to-scale/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/ava-expands-its-ai-captioning-to-desktop-and-web-apps-and-raises-4-5m-to-scale/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 11:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accessibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ava]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[captioning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[captions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transcription]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085048</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The worldwide shift to virtual workplaces has been a blessing and a curse to people with hearing impairments. Having office chatter occur in text rather than speech is more accessible, but virtual meetings are no easier to follow than in-person ones — which is why real-time captioning startup Ava has seen a huge increase in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The worldwide shift to virtual workplaces has been a blessing and a curse to people with hearing impairments. Having office chatter occur in text rather than speech is more accessible, but virtual meetings are no easier to follow than in-person ones — which is why <a href="https://www.ava.me/">real-time captioning startup Ava</a> has seen a huge increase in users. Riding the wave, the company just announced two new products and a $4.5 million seed round.</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/ava-3" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="ava-3">Ava <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/11/21/ava-gives-the-hearing-impaired-a-more-present-voice-in-group-conversations/">previously made its name</a> in the deaf community as a useful live transcription tool for real-life conversations. Start the app up and it would instantly hear and transcribe speech around you, color-coded to each speaker (and named if they activate a QR code). Extremely useful, of course, but when meetings stopped being in rooms and started being in Zooms, things got a bit more difficult.</p>
<p>&#8220;Use cases have shifted dramatically, and people are discovering the fact that most of these tools are not accessible,&#8221; co-founder and CEO Thibault Duchemin told TechCrunch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>And while some tools may have limited captioning built in (for example Skype and Google Meet), it may or may not be saved, editable, accurate, or convenient to review. For instance Meet&#8217;s ephemeral captions, while useful, only last a moment before disappearing, and are not specific to the speaker, making them of limited use for a deaf or hard of hearing person trying to follow a multi-person call. And the languages they are available in are limited as well.</p>
<p>As Duchemin explained, it began to seem much more practical to have a separate transcription layer that is not specific to any one service.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2085271" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-header.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2085271" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2085271" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-header.jpg" alt="Illustration of a laptop and phone transcribing audio." width="1024" height="560" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-header.jpg 1163w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-header.jpg?resize=150,82 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-header.jpg?resize=300,164 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-header.jpg?resize=768,420 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-header.jpg?resize=680,372 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-header.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2085271" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Ava</p></div></p>
<p>Thus Ava&#8217;s new product, a desktop and web app called Closed Captioning, which works with all major meeting services and online content, captioning it with the same on-screen display and making the content accessible via the same account. That includes things like YouTube videos without subtitles, live web broadcasts, and even audio-only content like podcasts, in more than 15 languages.</p>
<p>Individual speakers are labeled, automatically if an app supports it, like Zoom, or by having people in the meeting click a link that attaches their identity to the sound of their voice. (There are questions of privacy and confidentiality here, but they will differ case by case and are secondary to the fundamental capability of a person to participate.)</p>
<p>The transcripts all go to the person&#8217;s Ava app, letting them check through at their leisure or share with the rest of the meeting. That in itself is a hard service to find, Duchemin pointed out.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s actually really complicated,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Today if you have a meeting with four people, Ava is the only technology where you can have accurate labeling of who said what, and that&#8217;s extremely valuable when you think about enterprise.&#8221; Otherwise, he said, unless someone is taking detailed notes — unlikely, expensive, and time-consuming — meetings tend to end up black boxes.</p>
<p>For such high quality transcription, speech-to-text AI isn&#8217;t good enough, he admitted. It&#8217;s enough to follow a conversation, but &#8220;we&#8217;re talking about professionals and students who are deaf or hard of hearing,&#8221; Duchemin said. &#8220;They need solutions for meetings and classes and in-person, and they aren&#8217;t ready to go full AI. They need someone to clean up the transcript, so we provide that service.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2085272" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-app-all.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2085272" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2085272" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-app-all.png" alt="Features of the Ava app." width="1024" height="317" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-app-all.png 8694w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-app-all.png?resize=150,46 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-app-all.png?resize=300,93 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-app-all.png?resize=768,237 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-app-all.png?resize=680,210 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-app-all.png?resize=1536,475 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-app-all.png?resize=2048,633 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ava-app-all.png?resize=50,15 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2085272" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Ava</p></div></p>
<p>Ava Scribe quickly brings in a human trained not in direct transcription but in the correction of the product of speech-to-text algorithms. That way a deaf person attending a meeting or class can follow along live, but also be confident that when they check the transcript an hour later it will be exact, not approximate.</p>
<p>Right now transcription tools are being used as value-adds to existing products and suites, he said — ways to attract or retain customers. They aren&#8217;t beginning with the community of deaf and hard of hearing professionals and designing around their needs, which is what Ava has striven to do.</p>
<p>The explosion in popularity and obvious utility of their platform has led to this $4.5M seed round, as well, led by Initialized Capital and Khosla Ventures.</p>
<p>Duchemin said they expected to double the size of their team with the money, and start really marketing and finding big customers. &#8220;We&#8217;re very specialized, so we need a strong business model to grow,&#8221; he said. A strong, unique product is a good place to start, though.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/ava-expands-its-ai-captioning-to-desktop-and-web-apps-and-raises-4-5m-to-scale/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085048</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Papercup, the UK startup using AI for realistic-sounding voice translation, raises £8M funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/papercup/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/papercup/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 09:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Localglobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Papercup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sands Capital Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2084894</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Papercup, the U.K.-based AI startup that has developed speech technology that translates people’s voices into other languages and is already being used in the video and television industry, has raised £8 million in funding. The round was led by LocalGlobe and Sands Capital Ventures, alongside Sky, GMG Ventures, Entrepreneur First (EF) and BDMI. Papercup says [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.papercup.com/">Papercup</a>, the U.K.-based AI startup that has developed speech technology that translates people’s voices into other languages and is already being used in the video and television industry, has raised £8 million in funding.</p>
<p>The round was led by <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/localglobe" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="localglobe">LocalGlobe <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Sands Capital Ventures, alongside Sky, GMG Ventures, Entrepreneur First (EF) and BDMI. <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/papercup-ai" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="papercup-ai">Papercup <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> says the new capital will be used to invest further into machine learning research and to expand its &#8220;human-in-the-loop&#8221; quality control functionality, which is used to improve and customise the quality of its AI-translated videos.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Papercup’s existing angel investors include William Tunstall-Pedoe, the founder of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/04/17/sources-say-amazon-acquired-siri-like-evi-app-for-26m-is-a-smartphone-coming/">Evi Technologies</a> &#8212; the company acquired by Amazon to create Alexa &#8212; and Zoubin Ghahramani, former chief scientist and VP of AI at Uber and now part of the Google Brain leadership team.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Founded in 2017 by Jesse Shemen and Jiameng Gao while going through EF’s company builder program, Papercup is building out an AI and machine learning-based system that it says is capable of translating a person’s voice and expressiveness into other languages. Unlike a lot of text-to-speech, the startup claims the resulting voice translation is “indistinguishable” from human speech, and, perhaps uniquely, it attempts to retain the characteristics of the original speaker&#8217;s voice.</p>
<p>Initially, the tech is being targeted at video producers, including already being used by Sky News, Discovery and YouTube stars Yoga with Adriene, along with DIY content creators. It is pitched as a much more scalable and therefore lower-cost alternative to pure human dubbing.</p>
<p>“Most of the world’s video and audio content is shackled to a single language,” says Papercup co-founder and CEO Shemen. “That includes billions of hours of videos on YouTube, millions of podcast episodes, tens of thousands of classes on Skillshare and Coursera, and thousands of hours of content on Netflix. Almost every content owner is scrambling to go international, but there is yet no simple and cost-effective way to translate content beyond subtitling”.</p>
<p>For “deep pocketed studios,” there is of course the option to employ high-end dubbing via a professional dubbing studio and voice actors, but this is far too expensive for most content owners. And even wealthy studios are often constrained in terms of how many languages they can accommodate.</p>
<p>“That leaves the mid and long tail of content owners &#8212; literally 99% of all content &#8212; stranded and incapable of reaching international audiences beyond subtitling,” says Shemen, which, of course, is where Papercup comes into play. “Our aim is to generate translated voices that sound as close to the original speaker as possible”.</p>
<p>To do that, he says that Papercup will need to tackle four things. First up is creating “natural sounding” voices, i.e. how clear and human-like the synthetic voices sound. The second challenge is retaining emotion and pacing to reflect how the original speaker expressed themselves (think: happy, sad, angry etc.). Third is capturing the uniqueness of someone’s voice (e.g. Morgan Freeman, but in German). Lastly, the resulting translation needs the correct alignment of the audio to the video itself.</p>
<p>Explains Shemen: “We started off by making our voices as human-like and natural sounding as possible, where we’ve made quite a significant leap in terms of quality by honing our technology to the task, and today we have one of the best Spanish speech synthesis systems in production.</p>
<p>“We’re now focusing on better retainment and transfer of the original emotion and expressiveness in the original speaker across languages, and meanwhile figuring out what it is exactly that makes for quality dubbing”.</p>
<p>The next challenge and arguably the toughest nut to crack is “speaker adaptation,” described as capturing the uniqueness of someone’s voice. “This is the last layer of adaptation,” notes the Papercup CEO, “but it was also one of our first breakthroughs in our research. While we have models that can accomplish this, we’re focusing more of our time on emotion and expressiveness”.</p>
<p>That’s not to say Papercup is entirely machine-powered, even if it might be one day. The company also employs a “human-in-the-loop” process to make corrections and adjustments to the translated audio track. This includes correcting for any speech recognition or machine translation errors that come up, making adjustments to the timings of the audio, as well as enforcing emotions (e.g. happy, sad) and changing the speed of the generated voice.</p>
<p>How much human-in-the-loop is required depends on the type of content and priorities of the content owners, i.e. how realistic or perfect they need the resulting video to be. In other words, it isn’t a zero-sum game, as good enough will be more than enough for a swathe of content owners at scale.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ksvpnHDFvo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/22/meet-the-startups-that-pitched-at-efs-9th-demo-day-in-london/">Meet the startups that pitched at EF’s 9th Demo Day in London</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Meet the startups that pitched at EF’s 9th Demo Day in London&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/22/meet-the-startups-that-pitched-at-efs-9th-demo-day-in-london/embed/#?secret=ksvpnHDFvo" data-secret="ksvpnHDFvo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Asked about the technology’s beginnings, Shemen says Papercup started with research conducted by co-founder and CTO Jiameng Gao “who is incredibly smart and oddly obsessed with speech processing”. Gao completed two Masters at University of Cambridge (in machine learning and speech language technology) and wrote a thesis on speaker adaptive speech processing. It was at Cambridge that he realised that something like Papercup was possible.</p>
<p>“When we started working together at Entrepreneur First at the end of 2017, we built our initial prototype systems that showed that this technology was even possible despite there being no precedent for it,” says Shemen. “Based on early conversations, the demand was clearly overwhelming for what we were building &#8212; it was just a function of actually building something that could be used in a production environment”.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/papercup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2084894</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google and IAB adtech targeted with more RTB privacy complaints</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/google-and-iab-adtech-targeted-in-latest-batch-of-rtb-privacy-complaints/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/google-and-iab-adtech-targeted-in-latest-batch-of-rtb-privacy-complaints/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 09:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[behavioral ads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IAB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rtb]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2084464</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Another batch of complaints has been filed with European Union data protection agencies urging enforcement action against the adtech industry’s abuse of Internet users’ information to target ads. The complaints argue that behavioural ads are both harmful and unlawful. Earlier complaints over the same Real-Time Bidding (RTB) programmatic advertising issue were filed across the EU [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Another batch of complaints has been filed with European Union data protection agencies urging enforcement action against the adtech industry’s abuse of Internet users’ information to target ads.</p>
<p>The complaints argue that behavioural ads are both harmful and unlawful.</p>
<p>Earlier <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/20/gdpr-adtech-complaints-keep-stacking-up-in-europe/">complaints</a> over the same Real-Time Bidding (RTB) programmatic advertising issue were filed across the EU in 2018 and 2019 but have yet to result in any substantive regulatory action.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Ireland did open a probe into <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/google" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="google">Google&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> ad exchange <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/22/googles-lead-eu-regulator-opens-formal-privacy-probe-of-its-adtech/">last year</a>. While <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Belgium&#8217;s DPA has been progressing an investigation into a flagship industry tool that&#8217;s used for gathering consents to ad targeting &#8212; making a preliminary finding of non-compliance in </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/16/iab-europes-ad-tracking-consent-framework-found-to-fail-gdpr-standard/">October</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">. But litigation to reach a final verdict on the IAB Europe&#8217;s &#8216;Transparency and Consent&#8217; (TCF) framework won&#8217;t take place until next year.</span></p>
<p>(Related: The UK’s data protection agency is facing a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/uks-ico-faces-legal-action-after-closing-adtech-complaint-with-nothing-to-show-for-it/">legal challenge over its failure to act on RTB complaints</a>, despite repeatedly <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/20/behavioural-advertising-is-out-of-control-warns-uk-watchdog/">expressing concern</a> about the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/20/adtech-told-to-keep-calm-and-fix-its-lawfulness-problem/">industry’s lawfulness problem</a>.)</p>
<p>Both Google and the IAB continue to deny any problems with their adtech. Last year Google said authorised buyers that use its systems are subject to &#8220;stringent policies and standards&#8221;. While the IAB Europe rejected the Belgium DPA&#8217;s findings &#8212; <a href="https://iabeurope.eu/blog/iab-europe-submits-response-to-preliminary-report-of-the-belgian-data-protection-authority/">saying</a> its preliminary report &#8220;fundamental misunderstand[s]&#8221; the TCF tech.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7aw1QklEJ6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/21/irelands-data-watchdog-slammed-for-letting-adtech-carry-on-biggest-breach-of-all-time/">Ireland&#8217;s data watchdog slammed for letting adtech carry on &#8216;biggest breach of all time&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ireland&#8217;s data watchdog slammed for letting adtech carry on &#8216;biggest breach of all time&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/21/irelands-data-watchdog-slammed-for-letting-adtech-carry-on-biggest-breach-of-all-time/embed/#?secret=7aw1QklEJ6" data-secret="7aw1QklEJ6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The latest <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/gdpr" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="gdpr">GDPR <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> complaints target how the <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/rtb-electric-solutions" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="rtb-electric-solutions">RTB <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> component of programmatic advertising broadcasts Internet users’ personal data to scores of entities involved in these high speed eyeball auctions &#8212; arguing it runs counter to core security requirements in the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), as well as being horrible for people&#8217;s privacy.</p>
<p>A key principle of the GDPR is security by design and default — with the regulation placing legal requirements on personal data handlers to make sure people’s information is properly secured.</p>
<p>The complaints, which target Google and the IAB in their capacity as RTB standard setters, <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">have been filed by civil society groups in six European countries &#8212; namely: </span><a href="https://www.apti.ro">Asociatia pentru Tehnologie si Internet</a> (ApTi), Romania; <a href="https://direitosdigitais.pt">D3 &#8211; Defesa dos Direitos Digitais</a>, Portugal; <a href="https://www.gong.hr/en/">GONG</a>, Croatia; <a href="http://ghdfoundation.com">Global Human Dignity Foundation</a>, Malta; <a href="https://www.homodigitalis.gr/en">Homo Digitalis</a>, Greece; and the <a href="https://www.cyi.ac.cy">Institute of Information Cyprus</a>.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">They&#8217;re being coordinated by a consortium led by the </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.liberties.eu/en">Civil Liberties Union for Europe</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> (Liberties), the </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.openrightsgroup.org">ORG</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> (Open Rights Group) and the </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://en.panoptykon.org">Panoptykon Foundation</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">. </span></p>
<p>“Real-time bidding, which is the bedrock of the online advertising industry, is an abuse of people’s right to privacy,&#8221; said Dr Orsolya Reich, senior advocacy officer at Liberties, in a supporting statement. &#8220;The GDPR has been in place since 2018 and it is there precisely to give people a greater say about what happens to their data online.</p>
<p>&#8220;Today, more civil society groups are saying enough with this invasive advertising model and are asking data protection authorities to stand up against the harmful and unlawful practices they use.”</p>
<p>The consortium is asking for a joint investigation by their respective national DPAs — and for regulators to join with ongoing adtech investigations in Ireland (into Google’s adtech) and Belgium (into the IAB Europe’s TCF framework).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5Q4NFXiHEd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/16/iab-europes-ad-tracking-consent-framework-found-to-fail-gdpr-standard/">IAB Europe&#8217;s ad tracking consent framework found to fail GDPR standard</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;IAB Europe&#8217;s ad tracking consent framework found to fail GDPR standard&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/16/iab-europes-ad-tracking-consent-framework-found-to-fail-gdpr-standard/embed/#?secret=5Q4NFXiHEd" data-secret="5Q4NFXiHEd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>It’s not clear how far the Irish DPC’s investigation of Google has progressed — but it continues to face criticism for the lack of decisions on cross-border GDPR cases, some 2.5 years after the regulation technically begun being applied.</p>
<p>A mechanism in the GDPR means cross-border cases (basically anything related to mainstream consumer tech) get passed to a lead agency to investigate. However other agencies also remain involved, as interested parties, and must agree with any final decision made.</p>
<p>The system has led to a bottleneck of cases in certain EU locations, such as Ireland, where many tech giants base their European HQ. So the concern is this one-stop-shop mechanism is adding an unworkable level of friction to GDPR investigations &#8212; delaying decisions and enforcement action so much it risks the entire framework.</p>
<p>The Commission has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/europe-to-put-forward-rules-for-political-ads-transparency-and-beef-up-its-disinformation-code-next-year/">acknowledged weakness in GDPR enforcement</a>. Most obviously because it&#8217;s working on a massive package of new digital regulations. Though its strategy for fixing the enforcement problem is less clear as EU Member States look set to remain responsible for the bulk of this additional oversight, just as they&#8217;re responsible for resourcing their own DPAs now. (And <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/27/brave-accuses-european-governments-of-gdpr-resourcing-failure/">yet more complaints</a> have been filed this year accusing European governments of a GDPR resourcing failure.)</p>
<p>Ireland&#8217;s DPC is slated to issue its first cross-border GDPR decision in a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/twitter-could-face-its-first-gdpr-penalty-within-days/">case that relates to a Twitter security breach</a> very shortly. But last year its commissioner, Helen Dixon, suggested it would come with its first such decisions early in 2020 &#8212; so the gap between GDPR expectation and reality is running almost 12 months late at this point.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OQCcwDaOhw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/gdpr-enforcement-must-level-up-to-catch-big-tech-report-warns/">GDPR enforcement must level up to catch big tech, report warns</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GDPR enforcement must level up to catch big tech, report warns&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/gdpr-enforcement-must-level-up-to-catch-big-tech-report-warns/embed/#?secret=OQCcwDaOhw" data-secret="OQCcwDaOhw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The consortium filing the latest RTB complaints writes in a press release that while some of the earlier adtech complaints were referred to lead authorities it has no knowledge of “any meaningful cooperation or joint operations between national authorities and the lead authorities”.</p>
<p>“This suggests that cooperation and consistency mechanisms as envisioned in the GDPR are yet to be implemented fully,” the group adds, calling for a joint investigation into the RTB issue because the technology functions in the same way across borders &#8212; and “produces the same negative effects in all EU member states”, as they put it.</p>
<p>However it&#8217;s not clear how extra joint working &#8212; if indeed that&#8217;s really what&#8217;s being called for &#8212; would help to speed up GDPR enforcement. Nor how referring additional complaints to Ireland and Belgium would work to speed up their current investigations.</p>
<p>Most likely, the intent is to keep up pressure on the regulators to act.</p>
<p>Asked about the call for joint working, a Liberties spokesman told us: &#8220;The problem is that Google and IAB are big players, standard-setters in the market, and they affect all Internet users. Given the geographical scope of the issues raised in the complaints, we think it&#8217;s better for supervisory authorities to act in unison, not to be working alone in their corner.  This is why national partners are inviting their national DPAs to refer this complaint to the lead supervisory authorities who are already investigating Google&#8217;s and IAB&#8217;s compliance with the GDPR.&#8221;</p>
<p>Commenting in another supporting statement, Mariano delli Santi, legal and policy officer at the ORG, added: “These new complaints show that the GDPR is working. Individuals are increasingly aware of their rights, and they demand change. Now, it is up to the authorities to support this process, and make sure these laws are properly and consistently enforced against the widespread abuses of the adtech industry.”</p>
<p>At the time of writing, the only extant example of enforcement against a tech giant under the updated regulation was a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/21/french-data-protection-watchdog-fines-google-57-million-under-the-gdpr/">January 2019</a> decision to fine Google $57M by France&#8217;s CNIL. That investigation was limited to having a national scope, though, rather than being treated as a cross-border case.</p>
<p>Since then Google has shifted its legal base in Europe to Ireland &#8212; so now falls under the lead jurisdiction of the DPC.</p>
<p>This arrangement appears to suit big tech, enabling it to avoid the risk of speedier investigations conducted by single Member State agencies acting faster alone. (So it&#8217;s very interesting to see TikTok <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/06/tiktok-announces-first-data-center-in-europe/">ramping up its business infrastructure </a>and <a href="https://www.rte.ie/news/business/2020/1111/1177365-tiktok-ireland-jobs/">headcount in Ireland</a> &#8212; as it&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/tiktok-is-being-investigated-by-frances-data-watchdog/">also now on CNIL&#8217;s radar</a>&#8230; )</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Mlnm3QaVeu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/tiktok-is-being-investigated-by-frances-data-watchdog/">TikTok is being investigated by France&#8217;s data watchdog</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok is being investigated by France&#8217;s data watchdog&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/tiktok-is-being-investigated-by-frances-data-watchdog/embed/#?secret=Mlnm3QaVeu" data-secret="Mlnm3QaVeu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>As noted earlier, EU lawmakers have conceded GDPR enforcement has been a weakness thus far.</p>
<p>In a review of the two year old regulation <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/">this summer</a> the Commission highlighted a lack of universally vigorous enforcement.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/europe-to-put-forward-rules-for-political-ads-transparency-and-beef-up-its-disinformation-code-next-year/">Last week</a> the values and transparency commissioner, Vera Jourouv, also raised the problem as she set out the bloc&#8217;s plan to bolster democratic values against a range of online risks, such as algorithmically amplified or microtargeted disinformation and election interference &#8212; acknowledging GDPR alone isn&#8217;t enough to fix myriad intersecting tech-fuelled problems.</p>
<p>“[After the Cambridge Analytica scandal] we said that we are relieved that after GDPR came into force we are protected against this kind of practice — that people have to give consent and be aware of that — but we see that it might be a weak measure only to rely on consent or leave it for the citizens to give consent,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>“Enforcement of privacy rules is not sufficient &#8212; that’s why we are coming in the European Democracy Action Plan with the vision for the next year to come with the rules for political advertising, where we are seriously considering to limit the microtargeting as a method which is used for the promotion of political powers, political parties or political individuals.”</p>
<p>The European Commission is in the progress of drafting an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/29/europe-to-limit-how-big-tech-can-push-its-own-services-and-use-third-party-data/">ambitious and interlocking package of digital regulations</a>, that it wants to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/europe-sets-out-the-rules-of-the-road-for-its-data-reuse-plan/">fuel a regional data economy</a> and set <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/europe-eyeing-limits-on-how-big-tech-can-use-data-and-bundle-apps-reports/">firm online rules to engender the necessary trust</a> &#8212; and has said it wants this major digital policymaking effort to serve Europe for decades.</p>
<p>But without effective enforcement of its Internet rulebook it’s not clear how the bloc&#8217;s digital strategy will deliver as intended.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CKqLm7NXug"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/europes-data-strategy-aims-to-tip-the-scales-away-from-big-tech/">Europe&#8217;s data strategy aims to tip the scales away from big tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe&#8217;s data strategy aims to tip the scales away from big tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/europes-data-strategy-aims-to-tip-the-scales-away-from-big-tech/embed/#?secret=CKqLm7NXug" data-secret="CKqLm7NXug" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/google-and-iab-adtech-targeted-in-latest-batch-of-rtb-privacy-complaints/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2084464</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>France fines Google $120M and Amazon $42M for dropping tracking cookies without consent</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/france-fines-google-120m-and-amazon-42m-for-dropping-tracking-cookies-without-consent/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/france-fines-google-120m-and-amazon-42m-for-dropping-tracking-cookies-without-consent/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 08:55:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cnil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cookies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085374</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[France&#8217;s data protection agency, the CNIL, has slapped Google and Amazon with fines for dropping tracking cookies without consent. Google has been hit with a total of €100 million ($120M) for dropping cookies on Google.fr and Amazon €35M (~42M) for doing so on the Amazon .fr domain under the penalty notices issued today. The regulator [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">France&#8217;s data protection agency, the <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/cnil" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="cnil">CNIL, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has slapped Google and Amazon with fines for dropping tracking cookies without consent.</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/google" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="google">Google <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has been hit with a total of €100 million ($120M) for dropping cookies on Google.fr and Amazon €35M (~42M) for doing so on the <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/amazon" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="amazon">Amazon <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>.fr domain under the penalty notices issued today.</p>
<p>The regulator carried out investigations of the websites over the past year and found tracking cookies were automatically dropped when a user visited the domains in breach of the country&#8217;s Data Protection Act.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In Google&#8217;s case the CNIL has found three consent violations related to dropping non-essential cookies.</p>
<p>&#8220;As this type of cookies cannot be deposited without the user having expressed his consent, the restricted committee considered that the companies had not complied with the requirement provided for by article 82 of the Data Protection Act and the prior collection of the consent before the deposit of non-essential cookies,&#8221; it writes in the <a href="https://www.cnil.fr/fr/cookies-sanction-de-60-millions-deuros-lencontre-de-google-llc-et-de-40-millions-deuros-lencontre-de">penalty notice</a> [which we&#8217;ve translated from French].</p>
<p>Amazon was found to have made two violations, per the CNIL <a href="https://www.cnil.fr/fr/cookies-sanction-de-35-millions-deuros-lencontre-damazon-europe-core">penalty notice</a>.</p>
<p>CNIL also found that the information about the cookies provided to site visitors was inadequate &#8212; noting that a banner displayed by Google did not provide specific information about the tracking cookies the Google.fr site had already dropped.</p>
<p>Under local French (and European) law, site users should have been clearly informed before the cookies were dropped and asked for their consent.</p>
<p>In Amazon&#8217;s case its French site displayed a banner informing arriving visitors that they agreed to its use of cookies. CNIL said this did not comply with transparency or consent requirements &#8212; since it was not clear to users that the tech giant was using cookies for ad tracking. Nor were users given the opportunity to consent.</p>
<p>The law on tracking cookie consent has been clear in Europe for years. But in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/01/europes-top-court-says-active-consent-is-needed-for-tracking-cookies/">October 2019</a> a CJEU ruling further clarified that consent must be obtained prior to storing or accessing non-essential cookies. As we reported at the time sites that failed to ask for consent to track were risking a big fine under EU privacy laws.</p>
<p>Google and Amazon are now finding that out to their cost, it seems.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cEx9bxn4bG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/01/europes-top-court-says-active-consent-is-needed-for-tracking-cookies/">Europe&#8217;s top court says active consent is needed for tracking cookies</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe&#8217;s top court says active consent is needed for tracking cookies&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/01/europes-top-court-says-active-consent-is-needed-for-tracking-cookies/embed/#?secret=cEx9bxn4bG" data-secret="cEx9bxn4bG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>We&#8217;ve reached out to Amazon and Google for comment on the CNIL&#8217;s action.</p>
<p><strong>Update: </strong>Google sent this statement, attributed to a spokesperson:</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr">People who use Google expect us to respect their privacy, whether they have a Google account or not. We stand by our record of providing upfront information and clear controls, strong internal data governance, secure infrastructure, and above all, helpful products. Today&#8217;s decision under French ePrivacy laws overlooks these efforts and doesn’t account for the fact that French rules and regulatory guidance are uncertain and constantly evolving. We will continue to engage with the CNIL as we make ongoing improvements to better understand its concerns.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In Google&#8217;s case the CNIL also found that when a user selected to deactivate personalized advertising &#8212; via an option that Google&#8217;s cookie notice presented them with &#8212; the mechanism only partially worked, as one advertising cookie remained stored on their machine and continued to process data in clear violation of the consent law.</p>
<p>The CNIL&#8217;s penalty for Google breaks down into a fine of €60M for Google LLC and €40M for Google Ireland Ltd.</p>
<p>It says the size of the fines is justified because of the seriousness of the triple breach of article 82 of the Data Protection Act.</p>
<p>Other factors involved in determining the size of the fine included the reach of Google&#8217;s search engine in France and the fact that its corporate practices affect almost 50M people, as well as the sizeable profits it derives from advertising which are linked to data generated by its tracking cookies.</p>
<p>Per the CNIL&#8217;s investigation, Google stopped automatically dropping the ad cookies on the Google.fr domain after an update in September 2020. However it said a new cookie notice that&#8217;s presenting to arriving users still does not provide adequate information about what the cookies are used for nor inform users they can refuse these non-essential cookies.</p>
<p>Because of this the CNIL has also hit Google with an injunction &#8212; giving it three months to correct the cookie notices so they provide the required information to users or Google is risking further fines of €100,000 per day until the violation stops.</p>
<p>The regulator&#8217;s investigation of Google.fr took place in March 2020, while its checks on Amazon.fr took place between mid December, 2019 and mid May, 2020.</p>
<p>Amazon also updated its local site in September 2020 &#8212; to stop automatically dropping the tracking cookies.</p>
<p>However the CNIL is similarly unhappy with the information it provides to users, finding it does not clearly explain the tracking cookies nor make it plain users can refuse this &#8216;personalized&#8217; advertising, so the ecommerce giant has also been issued with an injunction to make good on the consent notices within three months or face further fines of €100,000 per day.</p>
<p>The top-line penalties are some of the largest tech giants have faced in Europe to date related to the bloc&#8217;s privacy rules. Albeit, the size of the fines still pales in comparison the billions the tech giants rake in globally each year.</p>
<p>The CNIL previously fined Google $57M, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/21/french-data-protection-watchdog-fines-google-57-million-under-the-gdpr/">back in 2019</a> &#8212; also for failing transparency requirements. Though that case was related to complaints filed under the EU&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).</p>
<p>In this instance (for both Google and Amazon) the CNIL points out that cookie consent falls under the EU&#8217;s ePrivacy Directive, which means the GDPR&#8217;s one-stop-shop mechanism does not kick in. Which means the French watchdog has legal competence to investigate, rather than needing to refer concerns to a lead EU DPA where each of the companies have their regional legal base.</p>
<p>In Google&#8217;s case that would be Ireland (while Amazon has its European legal base in Luxembourg).</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that Ireland&#8217;s DPC still hasn&#8217;t issued a single GDPR decision in any of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/lack-of-big-tech-gdpr-decisions-looms-large-in-eu-watchdogs-annual-report/">scores of open cases relayed to big tech</a> (including into <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/22/googles-lead-eu-regulator-opens-formal-privacy-probe-of-its-adtech/">various aspects</a> of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/04/googles-location-tracking-finally-under-formal-probe-in-europe/">Google&#8217;s business</a>), more than 2.5 years since the GDPR came into application.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the speed of French investigations and decisions continue to impress.</p>
<p>So today&#8217;s cookie fines will likely provide more succour to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/gdpr-enforcement-must-level-up-to-catch-big-tech-report-warns/">critics of GDPR enforcement</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PHdDXPX4zX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/gdpr-enforcement-must-level-up-to-catch-big-tech-report-warns/">GDPR enforcement must level up to catch big tech, report warns</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GDPR enforcement must level up to catch big tech, report warns&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/gdpr-enforcement-must-level-up-to-catch-big-tech-report-warns/embed/#?secret=PHdDXPX4zX" data-secret="PHdDXPX4zX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Although it&#8217;s not a like-for-like comparison as the CNIL&#8217;s investigations in these case have been limited in scope (i.e. national), bypassing the administrative complexity attached to GDPR cross-border cases &#8212; which involves some joint working and ultimate agreement between multiple DPAs across the EU.</p>
<p>However, if an older EU directive is shown to be delivering speedy enforcement &#8212; when the &#8216;shiny&#8217;, newer regulation can&#8217;t &#8212; that does raise some major questions for regional lawmakers who have conceded in recent months that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/">GDPR enforcement is a weakness</a> of their flagship framework.</p>
<p>Forum shopping, via the GDPR&#8217;s one-stop-shop mechanism, is looking like the biggest blocker to EU citizens being able to uphold their much trumpeted fundamental rights.</p>
<p>Returning to the cookie consent issue, the CNIL has made investigating cookie compliance a particular focus &#8212; publishing <a href="https://www.cnil.fr/fr/cookies-et-autres-traceurs-la-cnil-publie-des-lignes-directrices-modificatives-et-sa-recommandation">updated guidance</a> for using the tracking tech in October, when it said it would offer a grace period of up to six months to come into compliance.</p>
<p>However the regulator warned it would continue to fully monitor wider compliance issues around cookies and could take action to protect the privacy of Internet users if necessary.</p>
<p>Hence it&#8217;s stepped in with penalties and injunctions for Google and Amazon now.</p>
<p>Ireland&#8217;s DPC also published updated <a href="https://www.dataprotection.ie/sites/default/files/uploads/2020-04/Guidance%20note%20on%20cookies%20and%20other%20tracking%20technologies.pdf">cookie guidance this year</a>, back in April, saying too that it would give a grace period &#8212; until October &#8212; before it begun taking any enforcement action. But, so far, it hasn&#8217;t made public any such action.</p>
<p>While its first ever GDPR decision in a cross-border case &#8212; against Twitter &#8212; is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/twitter-could-face-its-first-gdpr-penalty-within-days/">expected to land finally this month</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="snTKlLt3kM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/07/cookie-consent-still-a-compliance-trash-fire-in-latest-watchdog-peek/">Cookie consent still a compliance trash fire in latest watchdog peek</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cookie consent still a compliance trash fire in latest watchdog peek&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/07/cookie-consent-still-a-compliance-trash-fire-in-latest-watchdog-peek/embed/#?secret=snTKlLt3kM" data-secret="snTKlLt3kM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/france-fines-google-120m-and-amazon-42m-for-dropping-tracking-cookies-without-consent/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085374</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Improving sound for hardware giants, Sweden&#8217;s Dirac finds its niche in China</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/dirac-profile/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/dirac-profile/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 08:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dirac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Huawei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oppo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Speaker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transsion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Xiaomi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2084025</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The rise of U.S.-China tensions has accelerated the bifurcation of global technology, with the two superpowers each working on their own tech systems. While the rift might be discouraging cross-border investment and business expansion between the rivals, the countries that are in-between &#8212; like those in Southeast Asia and Europe &#8212; are still finding opportunities. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The rise of U.S.-China tensions has accelerated the bifurcation of global technology, with the two superpowers each working on their own tech systems. While the rift might be discouraging cross-border investment and business expansion between the rivals, the countries that are in-between &#8212; like those in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/east-ventures-melisa-irene-on-southeast-asia/">Southeast Asia</a> and Europe &#8212; are still finding opportunities.</p>
<p>Sweden&#8217;s <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/dirac" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="dirac">Dirac <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is such an example. The 15-year-old firm has been licensing sound optimization technology to mobile, home entertainment, AR/VR, automotive, and other businesses where sounds are critical. The geopolitical complications &#8220;have not impacted&#8221; the company at all, its founder and chief executive Mathias Johansson told TechCrunch in an interview.</p>
<p>Based in the university city Uppsala of Sweden, Dirac has deep ties to China, offering solutions to the country&#8217;s smartphone leaders from Huawei, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/oppo" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="oppo">Oppo, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/xiaomi" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="xiaomi">Xiaomi, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> to Africa-focused Transsion. More than 50% of its revenue come from China today.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Dirac&#8217;s interest in China stems in part from the founder&#8217;s early fascination with the country. When Johansson visited China for the first time through his PhD program two decades ago, he was impressed by the &#8220;rapid evolution&#8221; in the tech industry there.</p>
<p>&#8220;The audio industry put a lot of manufacturing in China first, but then more and more on development and design. We realized this is a market that&#8217;s absolutely key for the entire consumer electronics ecosystem,&#8221; Johansson said.</p>
<p>The entrepreneur had since been traveling to Asia, especially Japan and China where electronics were flourishing. In 2010, he hired Dirac&#8217;s first China manager Tony Ye, who previously worked for Swedish software firm IAR Systems in Shanghai. At the time, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/07/25/apples-iphone-4-drives-global-growth-heres-what-it-means-for-a-new-low-cost-iphone-model/">revolutionary iPhone 4</a> was making waves across the world, but Johansson and his team were also bullish about China.</p>
<p>&#8220;We thought that China is going to be the leader in smartphones eventually. We thought that with Android and with Arm processors [China] is going to be a very different market. So we really went in there and focused on the market. And we thought that [Chinese] would be more hungry, more interested in trying out new things, simply because they were newcomers just like we were pioneers,&#8221; the founder said.</p>
<p>&#8220;It turned out to be the right bet.&#8221;</p>
<p>Though the Chinese government has been advocating for technological autonomy, the national efforts are prioritizing strategic areas like 5G and AI. In smaller and less politically charged fields, imported technologies are still seeing demand. These solutions are often cutting-edge and built upon years of research and development, but they are too niched for big corporations to invest the money and time. That is true for certain video enhancement solutions (see TechCrunch&#8217;s profile of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/26/imint-vidhance-profile/">Imint</a>, also an Uppsala-based company), or advanced sound optimization in the case of Dirac.</p>
<p>Johansson began researching the audio technology behind Dirac some 20 years ago during university, which made it harder for latecomers to catch up, the founder asserted. Dirac fixes audio like how glasses correct vision. Its team would first send out a test signal through the target speaker system, records it with a microphone, generates a digital fingerprint of audio, and measures the acoustic information. It then makes an exact &#8220;mirror universe&#8221; of the distortions created by the system, sends pre-distorted audio back to the speakers and the users will eventually get the distortion-free version of the sound.</p>
<p>The research and development cycle at Dirac is long, but working with Chinese companies has forced the Swedish firm to adapt.</p>
<p>&#8220;It challenged us to come up with new, more efficient ways of doing the same thing and to keep that innovation pace ahead of the competitor, whether it&#8217;s domestic Chinese, or the U.S., or wherever,&#8221; the founder admitted.</p>
<p>Dirac maintains its cashflow by licensing its intellectual property to clients and charges royalty fees per unit of device shipped. It also operates a B2B2C model, whereby the end-user can upgrade the sound system of a device, say, a speaker, by paying a fee, which is then divided between Dirac and its client, i.e. the device maker. Its latest big-name customer is the Chinese electric carmaker BYD, a deal that the company sees as an important step in furthering its automotive ambitions.</p>
<p>&#8220;Traditional carmakers are being challenged and the whole ecosystem is changing,&#8221; Johansson observed. &#8220;With software upgrades, cars are becoming something very different. They&#8217;re becoming much more like mobile phones and much more software-centric. The whole entertainment aspect and the audio experience in cars are becoming almost the most important part of the car because the noise is so low, the car is so quiet and you&#8217;re maybe driving a self-driving car. The audio experience you will get from cars will be outstanding in a couple of years.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/dirac-profile/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2084025</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Infra.Market raises $20 million for its B2B marketplace in India</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/infra-market-raises-20-million-for-its-b2b-marketplace-in-india/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/infra-market-raises-20-million-for-its-b2b-marketplace-in-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 07:43:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evolvence India Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085349</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A startup that is improving the way construction and real estate companies in India procure materials and handle logistics for their projects has received the backing of three new investors. Mumbai-headquartered Infra.Market said on Thursday it has raised $20 million in a Series B financing round. The round was led by Evolvence India Fund, Sistema [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A startup that is improving the way construction and real estate companies in India procure materials and handle logistics for their projects has received the backing of three new investors.</p>
<p>Mumbai-headquartered Infra.Market said on Thursday it has raised $20 million in a Series B financing round. The round was led by <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/evolvence-india-fund" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="evolvence-india-fund">Evolvence India Fund, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Sistema Asia Fund, and Foundamental, while existing investors Accel, Tiger Global, and Nexus also participated in it. The four-year-old startup has raised about $50 million to date.</p>
<p><a href="http://infra.market/">Infra.Market</a> helps small businesses such as manufacturers of paints and cements improve the quality of their production and meet various compliances. The startup adds its load cells to the manufacturing facilities of these small businesses to ensure there is no lapse in quality, and also helps them work with other businesses that can provide them with better raw material and provide guidance on pricing. It also works closely with businesses to ensure that their deliveries are made on time.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>These improvements, explained co-founder Souvik Sengupta, help small manufacturers land larger clients that have higher expectations from the businesses with which they engage.</p>
<p>“We are bringing a service layer to these small manufacturers, enabling them to grow their business. We don’t own the asset and are creating private label brands,” he said in an interview with TechCrunch. Infra.Market today works with over 170 small manufacturers and counts the vast majority of major construction and real estate companies such as giants Larsen &amp; Toubro, Tata Projects and Ashoka Buildcon as its clients. Sengupta said the startup sells to over 400 large clients and 3,000 small retailers.</p>
<p>Sengupta said the startup was on track to hit the ARR (annual recurring revenue) of $100 million before the pandemic, which for at least two months nearly cut its business in half. But the startup has picked up pace again, and is now on track to hit the ARR of $180 million. The startup aims to grow this figure to $300 million by March next year.</p>
<p>Infra.Market is also enabling small manufacturers reach customers outside of India. Some of its clients are in Bangladesh, Malaysia, Singapore, and Dubai. Sengupta said Infra.Market will deploy the fresh funds to expand to more markets as well as deepen its penetration in smaller Indian cities and towns. International markets today account for 10% of the revenue Infra.Market clocks.</p>
<p>&#8220;As an enabler to this sector, Infra.Market has emerged as one of the most disruptive companies through pioneering technological innovation in the procurement and distribution of building materials catering to the infrastructure and construction industry by improving logistics, financing, procurement and project management of large scale projects in key markets across India. The company has very quickly demonstrated remarkable growth backed by a solid business model and deep sector domain knowledge of its founders and management team,&#8221; said Rohit Batra, Partner at Evolvence India, in a statement.</p>
<p>The startup, which today runs about half a dozen private label brands, also plans to expand to more categories such as electrical items, Sengupta said.</p>
<p>Sumit Jain, Senior Partner at Sistema Asia Fund, said Infra.Market is increasingly serving as an important institution in the context of India&#8217;s bounce-back in the post-Covid world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/infra-market-raises-20-million-for-its-b2b-marketplace-in-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085349</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Seoul-based payment tech startup CHAI gets $60 million from Hanhwa, SoftBank Ventures Asia</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/seoul-based-payment-tech-startup-chai-gets-60-million-from-hanhwa-softbank-ventures-asia/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/seoul-based-payment-tech-startup-chai-gets-60-million-from-hanhwa-softbank-ventures-asia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CHAI Card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hanhwa Investment & Securities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Ventures Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2084731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Demand for contactless payments and e-commerce has grown in South Korea during the COVID-19 pandemic. This is good news for payment service operators, but the market is very fragmented, so adding payment options is a time-consuming process for many merchants. CHAI wants to fix this with an API that enables companies to accept over 20 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Demand for contactless payments and e-commerce has grown in South Korea during the COVID-19 pandemic. This is good news for payment service operators, but the market is very fragmented, so adding payment options is a time-consuming process for many merchants. CHAI wants to fix this with an API that enables companies to accept over 20 payment systems. The Seoul-based startup announced today it has raised a $60 million Series B.</p>
<p>The round was led by Hanhwa Investment &amp; Securities, with participation from SoftBank Ventures Asia (the early-stage venture capital arm of SoftBank Group), SK Networks, Aarden Partners and other strategic partners. It brings CHAI’s total funding to $75 million, including a $15 million Series A in February.</p>
<p>Last month, the Bank of Korea, South Korea’s central bank, <a href="http://www.koreaherald.com/view.php?ud=20201103000771">released a report </a>showing that contactless payments increased 17% year-over-year since the start of COVID-19.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>CHAI serves e-commerce companies with an API called I’mport, that allows them to accept payments from over 20 options, including debit and credit cards through local payment gateways, digital wallets, wire transfers, carrier billings and PayPal. It is now used by 2,200 merchants, including Nike Korea and Philip Morris Korea.</p>
<p>CHAI chief executive officer Daniel Shin told TechCrunch that businesses would usually have to integrate each kind of online payment type separately, so I’mport saves its clients a lot of time.</p>
<p>The company also offers its own digital wallet and debit card called the CHAI Card, which launched in June 2019 and now has 2.5 million users, a small number compared with South Korea’s leading digital wallets, which include Samsung Pay, Naver Pay, Kakao Pay and Toss.</p>
<p>&#8220;CHAI is a late comer to Korea’s digital payments market, but we saw a unique opportunity to offer value,&#8221; said Shin. The CHAI Card offers merchants a lower transaction fee than other cards and users typically check its app about 20 times to see new cashback offers and other rewards based on how often they pay with their cards or digital wallet.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’ve digitized the plastic card experience, and this is the first step towards creating a robust online rewards platform,&#8221; Shin added.</p>
<p>In press statement, Hanhwa Investment &amp; Securities director SeungYoung Oh director said, &#8220;I’mport has reduced what once took e-commerce businesses weeks to complete into a simple copy-and-paste task, radically reducing costs. It is a first-of-its-kind business model in Korea, and I have no doubt that CHAI will continue to grow this service into an essential infrastructure of the global fintech landscape.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/seoul-based-payment-tech-startup-chai-gets-60-million-from-hanhwa-softbank-ventures-asia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2084731</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LabCorp COVID-19 test kit has just been approved for sale over-the-counter</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/labcorp-covid-19-test-kit-has-just-been-approved-for-sale-over-the-counter/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/labcorp-covid-19-test-kit-has-just-been-approved-for-sale-over-the-counter/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 23:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food and Drug Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labcorp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life Sciences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2084846</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[LabCorp has now become the first company to receive approval to sell its COVID-19 test kit over-the-counter without a prescription, according to a statement from the company. One of the largest diagnostics testing companies in the U.S., LabCorp could be a significant competitor to companies like EverlyWell, which received approvals for its at-home testing kits [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/laboratory-corporation-of-america" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="laboratory-corporation-of-america">LabCorp <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has now become the first company to receive approval to sell its COVID-19 test kit over-the-counter without a prescription, according to a statement from the company.</p>
<p>One of the largest diagnostics testing companies in the U.S., LabCorp could be a significant competitor to companies like EverlyWell, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/16/everylwell-gains-first-fda-authorization-for-a-standalone-at-home-covid-19-test-sample-collection-kit/">which received approvals for its at-home testing kits in May</a>; MyLab Box, <a href="https://medcitynews.com/2020/12/walmart-partners-with-startup-to-sell-at-home-covid-19-tests/?rf=1">which announced a partnership with Walmart earlier this week to sell COVID-19 test kits with the giant retailer</a>; or LetsGetChecked, which has its own at-home test.</p>
<p>LabCorp was actually the first company to receive approval from the FDA for its test kit, and now the company can sell the product through retail channels without a prescription.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GbNyIqxxyC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/21/labcorps-at-home-covid-19-test-kit-is-the-first-to-be-authorized-by-the-fda/">LabCorp&#8217;s at-home COVID-19 test kit is the first to be authorized by the FDA</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;LabCorp&#8217;s at-home COVID-19 test kit is the first to be authorized by the FDA&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/21/labcorps-at-home-covid-19-test-kit-is-the-first-to-be-authorized-by-the-fda/embed/#?secret=GbNyIqxxyC" data-secret="GbNyIqxxyC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“With the first over-the-counter at-home collection kit ever authorized by the FDA for COVID-19, we are empowering people to learn about their health and make confident decisions,” said Dr. Brian Caveney, chief medical officer and president of LabCorp Diagnostics, in a statement. “With this authorization, we can help more people get tested, reduce the spread of the virus and improve the health of our communities.”</p>
<p>It&#8217;s pretty inarguable that anything that reduces the friction consumers face in getting tested for SARS-CoV-2, the virus that causes COVID-19, is a good thing. It&#8217;s also in line with a broader push to increase healthcare access for consumers in an effort to reduce costs.</p>
<p>When customers purchase the COVID-19 test kit, they register the kit on the company&#8217;s website and then follow the instructions given there. Tests results are delivered through a corporate portal and a healthcare provider is available to assist customers who test positive on how to proceed with a course of treatment.</p>
<p>The company said its kit should not be viewed as a substitute for visits to a healthcare professional and is intended for use by adults 18 or older.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s important to note that the LabCorp PCR test has not been cleared or approved by the FDA and is being authorized under an emergency use authorization.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YBNClktuZh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/16/everylwell-gains-first-fda-authorization-for-a-standalone-at-home-covid-19-test-sample-collection-kit/">Everlywell gains first FDA authorization for a standalone, at-home, COVID-19 test sample collection kit</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Everlywell gains first FDA authorization for a standalone, at-home, COVID-19 test sample collection kit&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/16/everylwell-gains-first-fda-authorization-for-a-standalone-at-home-covid-19-test-sample-collection-kit/embed/#?secret=YBNClktuZh" data-secret="YBNClktuZh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/labcorp-covid-19-test-kit-has-just-been-approved-for-sale-over-the-counter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2084846</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Airbnb said to price IPO between $67 and $68</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/airbnb-said-to-price-ipo-between-67-and-68/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/airbnb-said-to-price-ipo-between-67-and-68/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 23:33:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbnb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[initial public offering]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The WSJ is reporting that Airbnb is expected to price its IPO at either $67 or $68 per share. The American hospitality unicorn raised its IPO price target earlier this week, from $44 to $50 to $56 to $60. While we&#8217;re still waiting for official pricing, Airbnb is worth $41 billion at its IPO price, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/airbnb-expected-to-price-ipo-above-56-to-60-a-share-range-11607527468">The WSJ</a> is reporting that Airbnb is expected to price its IPO at either $67 or $68 per share. The American hospitality unicorn <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/the-ipo-market-looks-hot-as-airbnb-and-c3-ai-raise-price-targets/">raised its IPO price target earlier this week</a>, from $44 to $50 to $56 to $60.</p>
<p>While we&#8217;re still waiting for official pricing, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/airbnb" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="airbnb">Airbnb <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is worth $41 billion at its IPO price, using the upper pricing estimate and the company&#8217;s share count of 602,448,251 from its most recent S-1/A filing. That figure rises sharply if we included more than 50 million shares that could be added to the mix upon the exercise of vested employee options. The company&#8217;s fully diluted valuation at its IPO price was calculated to be $47 billion.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.axios.com/airbnb-valued-at-47-billion-in-ipo-8f5e3d0f-1c2b-4459-bd65-22a6a6a0007d.html">Axios reports</a> that Airbnb raised $3.5 billion at its fully diluted valuation.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rOosaKnCxq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/the-ipo-market-looks-hot-as-airbnb-and-c3-ai-raise-price-targets/">The IPO market looks hot as Airbnb and C3.ai raise price targets</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The IPO market looks hot as Airbnb and C3.ai raise price targets&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/the-ipo-market-looks-hot-as-airbnb-and-c3-ai-raise-price-targets/embed/#?secret=rOosaKnCxq" data-secret="rOosaKnCxq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Regardless of how you prefer to value the company, its worth has risen sharply from an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/15/airbnb-ups-its-debt-by-1bn-amid-the-coronavirus-travel-crunch/">early pandemic nadir of $18 billion</a>. After COVID-19 ravaged the company&#8217;s business, it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/05/citing-revenue-declines-airbnb-cuts-1900-jobs-or-around-25-of-its-global-workforce/">laid off staff</a> and took on external capital.</p>
<p>Since the end of Q1 and the first months of Q2, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/understanding-airbnbs-summer-recovery/">Airbnb has recovered</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/airbnb-files-to-go-public/">allowing it to file to go public</a> and earn its highest valuation to date.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s pricing comes after both DoorDash and C3.ai each <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/how-doordash-and-c3-ai-can-defend-their-red-hot-ipo-valuatons/">priced above their own raised ranges</a>, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/doordash-c3-ai-skyrocket-in-public-market-debuts/">saw their shares skyrocket in the first day&#8217;s trading</a>. Some exuberance was therefore not unexpected.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="skCTdhv1Bm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/doordash-c3-ai-skyrocket-in-public-market-debuts/">DoorDash, C3.ai skyrocket in public market debuts</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;DoorDash, C3.ai skyrocket in public market debuts&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/doordash-c3-ai-skyrocket-in-public-market-debuts/embed/#?secret=skCTdhv1Bm" data-secret="skCTdhv1Bm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Airbnb starts trading tomorrow morning. More then.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/airbnb-said-to-price-ipo-between-67-and-68/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085191</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: FTC and 48 state AGs sue Facebook</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/daily-crunch-ftc-sues-facebook/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/daily-crunch-ftc-sues-facebook/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 23:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085218</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook faces big antitrust lawsuits, DoorDash and C3.ai go public and YouTube announces new election misinformation policies. This is your Daily Crunch for December 9, 2020. The big story: FTC and 48 state AGs sue Facebook The Federal Trade Commission filed an antitrust lawsuit against Facebook today, as did 48 attorneys general representing 46 states. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="facebook">Facebook <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> faces big antitrust lawsuits, DoorDash and C3.ai go public and YouTube announces new election misinformation policies. This is your Daily Crunch for December 9, 2020.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: FTC and 48 state AGs sue Facebook</strong></p>
<p>The Federal Trade Commission <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/ftc-seeks-to-break-up-facebook-alleging-illegal-monopoly/">filed an antitrust lawsuit against Facebook</a> today, as did <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/facebook-antitrust-state-attorneys-general/">48 attorneys general representing 46 states</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>They&#8217;re separate suits, although the two groups coordinated their investigations. Both suits claim that Facebook has behaved illegally when it acquired Instagram and WhatsApp, and that it used its monopoly power to suppress competition. The FTC suit also calls for Instagram and WhatsApp to be split off from the company.</p>
<p>In response, Facebook <a href="https://twitter.com/fbnewsroom/status/1336764387818950656">tweeted</a>, &#8220;Years after the FTC cleared our acquisitions, the government now wants a do-over with no regard for the impact that precedent would have on the broader business community or the people who choose our products every day.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/doordash-c3-ai-skyrocket-in-public-market-debuts/">DoorDash, C3.ai skyrocket in public market debuts</a> — Two American tech unicorns saw their values climb after they began trading today.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/youtube-declares-war-on-us-election-misinformation-a-month-late/">YouTube declares war on US election misinformation… a month late</a> — YouTube waited until the “safe harbor” deadline, when audits and recounts must be wrapped up at the state level, to enforce a set of rules against election misinformation.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/google-ceo-says-company-will-review-events-leading-up-to-dr-timnit-gebrus-departure/">Google CEO says company will review events leading up to Dr. Timnit Gebru’s departure</a> — In CEO Sundar Pichai’s memo, he said the company needs to “accept responsibility for the fact that a prominent Black, female leader with immense talent left Google unhappily.”</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/squire-series-c/">Squire, a barbershop tech startup, triples its valuation to $250M in latest round</a> — Squire raised $59 million in a round led by Iconiq Capital.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/career-karma-series-a/">Career Karma raises $10M to connect students to coding bootcamps</a> — The startup is bringing a pick-and-shovel strategy to the coding bootcamp world.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/ada-ventures-closes-first-fund-at-50m-investing-in-diverse-founders-tacking-societys-problems/">Ada Ventures closes first fund at $50M, investing in diverse founders tackling society’s problems</a> — A year ago this week, Ada Ventures launched on stage at TechCrunch Disrupt.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/coinbases-backstory-and-future-with-kings-of-crypto-author-jeff-john-roberts/">Coinbase’s backstory and future with ‘Kings of Crypto’ author Jeff John Roberts</a> — &#8220;Kings of Crypto&#8221; tells the story of Coinbase, Brian Armstrong and the dream of a crypto economy.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/as-several-marketplace-unicorns-prepare-ipos-a-vc-digs-into-the-data/">As several marketplace unicorns prepare IPOs, a VC digs into the data</a> — &#8220;Growth trumps all,&#8221; says Menlo Ventures partner Venky Ganesan.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/how-doordash-and-c3-ai-can-defend-their-red-hot-ipo-valuatons/">How DoorDash and C3.ai can defend their red-hot IPO valuations</a> — An excited market brings big valuations, stacks of cash and high expectations.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which aims to democratize information about startups. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/gift-guide-the-best-books-for-2020-as-recommended-by-vcs-and-techcrunch-writers-part-2/">Gift Guide: The best books for 2020 as recommended by VCs and TechCrunch writers (Part 2)</a> — Here are nine more books (plus one bonus) recommended by VCs and TechCrunch writers.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/streamers-including-netflix-and-cbs-all-access-roll-out-new-family-friendly-features/">Streamers, including Netflix and CBS All Access, roll out new family-friendly features</a> — Netflix announced the rollout of the Kids Activity Report and Family Profiles, while CBS All Access added a Kids Mode.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/tc-sessions-space-2020-launches-next-week/">TC Sessions: Space 2020 launches next week</a> — We&#8217;ll be (virtually) hosting out-of-this-world experts, innovative agencies and bold, boundary-breaking startups.</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/daily-crunch-ftc-sues-facebook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085218</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK electric vehicle startup Arrival picks Charlotte for its North American headquarters</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/uk-electric-vehicle-startup-arrival-picks-charlotte-for-its-north-american-headquarters/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/uk-electric-vehicle-startup-arrival-picks-charlotte-for-its-north-american-headquarters/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 22:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085239</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Arrival, the U.K. electric vehicle startup that plans to become a publicly traded company through a merger with special purpose acquisition company CIIG Merger Corp., has picked Charlotte for its North American headquarters. The company said it will add 150 new employees to support the headquarters and invest about $3 million in office space in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://arrival.com/">Arrival</a>, the U.K. electric vehicle startup that plans to become a publicly traded company through a merger with special purpose acquisition company CIIG Merger Corp., has picked Charlotte for its North American headquarters.</p>
<p>The company said it will add 150 new employees to support the headquarters and invest about $3 million in office space in the South End neighborhood of Charlotte. Arrival said it will be hiring for a variety of corporate positions, including human resources, marketing, finance and administrative professionals.</p>
<p>Arrival was a secretive electric vehicle startup for nearly five years until January when it announced a $110 million investment from Hyundai and Kia. Over the past year, the company has shared more of its plans and partners, all culminating in its announcement last month to<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/arrival-becomes-latest-electric-vehicle-startup-to-test-the-public-markets-with-a-spac/"> merge with a SPAC</a>, or shell company, to become a publicly traded company. The SPAC merger is expected to close in the first quarter of 2021.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Li6Dntba2B"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/arrival-becomes-latest-electric-vehicle-startup-to-test-the-public-markets-with-a-spac/">Arrival becomes latest electric vehicle startup to test the public markets with a SPAC</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Arrival becomes latest electric vehicle startup to test the public markets with a SPAC&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/arrival-becomes-latest-electric-vehicle-startup-to-test-the-public-markets-with-a-spac/embed/#?secret=Li6Dntba2B" data-secret="Li6Dntba2B" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Arrival’s aim is to produce electric vehicles that are competitive in price with traditional fossil fuel-powered vehicles and lower cost of ownership than other comparable EVs. Arrival says its modular electric “skateboard” platform, which can be used on a range of different vehicle types, along with its use of microfactories set up near major cities are how it will achieve its mission.</p>
<p>Arrival plans to produce commercial electric vehicles, beginning with van and bus models. The plan is to have four vehicles in the market by 2023, Arrival Automotive CEO Mike Ableson has previously said.</p>
<p>Arrival&#8217;s North American headquarters will be located less than 30 miles away from its first U.S. microfactory in Rock Hill, South Carolina. The company employs more than 1,200 people and has five engineering facilities and two microfactories globally.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/uk-electric-vehicle-startup-arrival-picks-charlotte-for-its-north-american-headquarters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085239</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SpaceX flies its Starship rocket to 40,000 feet, just misses the landing in explosive finale</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/spacex-flies-its-starship-rocket-to-40000-feet-just-misses-the-landing-in-explosive-finale/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/spacex-flies-its-starship-rocket-to-40000-feet-just-misses-the-landing-in-explosive-finale/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 22:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyperloop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rocket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2084505</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SpaceX is one step closer to replacing its Falcon line of active duty spacecraft: Its Starship prototype &#8220;SN8&#8221; achieved a major milestone in the ongoing spacecraft&#8217;s development program, flying to a height of around 40,000 feet at SpaceX&#8217;s development facility in southern Texas. One of the Starship&#8217;s three Raptor engines cut off around two minutes [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/space-exploration-technologies" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="space-exploration-technologies">SpaceX <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is one step closer to replacing its Falcon line of active duty spacecraft: Its Starship prototype &#8220;SN8&#8221; achieved a major milestone in the ongoing spacecraft&#8217;s development program, flying to a height of around 40,000 feet at SpaceX&#8217;s development facility in southern Texas.</p>
<p>One of the Starship&#8217;s three Raptor engines cut off around two minutes into flight, but the prototype rocket continued its ascent. Then at around three minutes, another extinguished, leaving just one lit and firing. The rocket continued to climb, oriented upward, but it was hard to tell from the feed exactly how high it reached. The third flared out at around 4:30 into the mission, and the Starship oriented into a horizontal position, angling back toward Earth but effectively flat on its belly, gliding.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xf8iDvSpmC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/04/spacex-successfully-flies-its-starship-prototype-to-a-height-of-around-500-feet/">SpaceX successfully flies its Starship prototype to a height of around 500 feet</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SpaceX successfully flies its Starship prototype to a height of around 500 feet&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/04/spacex-successfully-flies-its-starship-prototype-to-a-height-of-around-500-feet/embed/#?secret=xf8iDvSpmC" data-secret="xf8iDvSpmC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The Starship&#8217;s engines re-ignited as the rocket approached the ground, flipping the rocket into a vertical orientation once again and slowing its descent. It landed a bit harder than expected, however, resulting in an explosion that engulfed the rocket. That&#8217;s still a successful test, and went better than SpaceX or most observers likely expected it would. SpaceX&#8217;s flight controller could be heard on the stream congratulating the team on a job well done.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2085249" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/landing-explosion-starship.gif" alt="" width="1000" height="556" /></p>
<p>While a flight that ends with an explosion and total loss of the spacecraft may not seem like a win, when you&#8217;re designing and testing an entirely new spaceship it most definitely is. SpaceX expected that this test flight likely wouldn&#8217;t achieve all of its objectives, and CEO Elon Musk said on Twitter earlier this week that he likely anticipated it might achieve its target flight height but not do much else. It seems to have done that, and managed its &#8220;belly flop&#8221; maneuver, as well as correctly re-oriented itself for landing, but with a bit too much speed coming in for the touchdown.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Successful ascent, switchover to header tanks &amp; precise flap control to landing point! <a href="https://t.co/IIraiESg5M">https://t.co/IIraiESg5M</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1336808486022258688?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 9, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The team has no doubt gathered a ton of valuable data from this test, and will now be taking those lessons back to help improve its next attempts. SpaceX already has two more prototypes, SN9 and SN10, effectively ready to go for follow-up tests. Those already carry improvements compared to SN8 which flew today, and the team will be quick to implement additional tweaks based on this flight and the data they obtained during the test.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Y6sTMtUtmZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/spacex-completes-another-successful-short-test-flight-of-its-starship-spacecraft-prototype/">SpaceX completes another successful short test flight of its Starship spacecraft prototype</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SpaceX completes another successful short test flight of its Starship spacecraft prototype&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/spacex-completes-another-successful-short-test-flight-of-its-starship-spacecraft-prototype/embed/#?secret=Y6sTMtUtmZ" data-secret="Y6sTMtUtmZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/spacex-flies-its-starship-rocket-to-40000-feet-just-misses-the-landing-in-explosive-finale/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2084505</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tiny water-based robot is powered by light and can walk, move cargo and even dance</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/tiny-water-based-robot-is-powered-by-light-and-can-walk-move-cargo-and-even-dance/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/tiny-water-based-robot-is-powered-by-light-and-can-walk-move-cargo-and-even-dance/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 21:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magnet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[northwestern university]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new robot created by researchers at Northwestern University looks and behaves like a tiny aquatic animal, and could serve a variety of functions, including moving things place to place, catalyzing chemical reactions, delivering therapeutics and much more. This new soft robot honestly looks a heck of a lot like a lemon peel, but it&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A new robot created by <a href="https://news.northwestern.edu/stories/2020/12/aquatic-soft-robot-inspired-by-sea-creatures-walks-rolls-transports-cargo/">researchers at Northwestern University</a> looks and behaves like a tiny aquatic animal, and could serve a variety of functions, including moving things place to place, catalyzing chemical reactions, delivering therapeutics and much more. This new soft robot honestly looks a heck of a lot like a lemon peel, but it&#8217;s actually a material made up of 90% water for the soft exterior, with a nickel skeleton inside that can change its shape in response to outside magnetic fields.</p>
<p>These robots are very small &#8212; only around the size of a dime &#8212; but they&#8217;re able to perform a range of tasks, including walking at the same speed as an average human, and picking up and carrying things. They work by either taking in or expelling water through their soft components, and can respond to light and magnetic fields thanks to their precise molecular design. Essentially, their molecular structure is crafted such that when they&#8217;re hit by light, the molecules that make them up expel water, causing the robot&#8217;s &#8220;legs&#8221; to stiffen like muscles.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2085195" style="width: 1010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2085195" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2085195" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nwu-dancing-lemon-robot.gif" alt="" width="1000" height="511" /><p id="caption-attachment-2085195" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Northwestern</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/magnet" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="magnet">Magnetic <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> fields can then be applied to make the legs move, thanks to the embedded nickel skeleton, which is ferromagnetic. Use of light and magnetic fields together, along with highly accurate computation, can produce very precise movement along desired paths.</p>
<p>The researchers behind this little bot envision future versions that are even smaller &#8212; small enough to operate on a microscopic level, perhaps for applications including targeted drug delivery within a patient. They could also theoretically be programmed to work together in a &#8220;swarm&#8221;-like arrangement, which would allow them to scale up to handle larger tasks, such as potentially acting as an on-demand suture in case of injury.</p>
<p>A lot of research and work will be required to get to that kind of application, but the existence of the bots even at this stage is a remarkable achievement and a hint at what&#8217;s to come from soft robotics and intelligent materials that don&#8217;t require the kind of heavy and bulky compute associated with today&#8217;s production robots.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/tiny-water-based-robot-is-powered-by-light-and-can-walk-move-cargo-and-even-dance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085167</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google CEO says company will review events leading up to Dr. Timnit Gebru&#8217;s departure</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/google-ceo-says-company-will-review-events-leading-up-to-dr-timnit-gebrus-departure/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/google-ceo-says-company-will-review-events-leading-up-to-dr-timnit-gebrus-departure/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Megan Rose Dickey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 21:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Include]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Timnit Gebru]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085138</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In light of artificial intelligence researcher Dr. Timnit Gebru&#8217;s exit from Google last week, Google CEO Sundar Pichai sent a memo to staffers, obtained by Axios, saying the company would investigate &#8220;the circumstances that led up to Dr. Gebru&#8217;s departure, examining where we could have improved and led a more respectful process.&#8221; Last week, Gebru [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In light of artificial intelligence researcher Dr. <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/timnit-gebru" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="timnit-gebru">Timnit Gebru&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> exit from <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/google" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="google">Google <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> last week, Google CEO Sundar Pichai sent a memo to staffers, <a href="https://www.axios.com/sundar-pichai-memo-timnit-gebru-exit-18b0efb0-5bc3-41e6-ac28-2956732ed78b.html">obtained by Axios</a>, saying the company would investigate &#8220;the circumstances that led up to Dr. Gebru&#8217;s departure, examining where we could have improved and led a more respectful process.&#8221;</p>
<p>Last week, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/googles-co-lead-of-ethical-ai-team-says-she-was-fired-for-sending-an-email/">Gebru said she was fired from the company</a> after sending an email to her direct reports discussing how she was disappointed in her organization&#8217;s approach to DEI as well as the approval process around her research paper. Gebru sent that email after Google did not grant her permission to attach her and her colleagues names to an <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/12/04/1013294/google-ai-ethics-research-paper-forced-out-timnit-gebru/">AI ethics paper about language models</a>. Gebru had previously sent her superiors an email, detailing that if they would not meet her specific conditions she would prepare to leave. Google proceeded to tell her it accepted her resignation and cut off her access to her work email.</p>
<p>In Pichai&#8217;s memo, he said the company needs to &#8220;accept responsibility for the fact that a prominent Black, female leader with immense talent left Google unhappily.&#8221; He also noted how it&#8217;s had a &#8220;ripple effect&#8221; through underrepresented communities at Google.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PnSK0FC1vI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/googles-co-lead-of-ethical-ai-team-says-she-was-fired-for-sending-an-email/">Google&#8217;s co-lead of Ethical AI team says she was fired for sending an email</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google&#8217;s co-lead of Ethical AI team says she was fired for sending an email&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/googles-co-lead-of-ethical-ai-team-says-she-was-fired-for-sending-an-email/embed/#?secret=PnSK0FC1vI" data-secret="PnSK0FC1vI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Google declined to comment but confirmed the memo is authentic. You can read the <a href="https://www.axios.com/sundar-pichai-memo-timnit-gebru-exit-18b0efb0-5bc3-41e6-ac28-2956732ed78b.html">full memo over on Axios</a>.</p>
<p>Pichai&#8217;s memo comes a couple of days after more than 2,000 Googlers and thousands of other supporters signed a letter standing with Gebru.</p>
<p>&#8220;Instead of being embraced by Google as an exceptionally talented and prolific contributor, Dr. Gebru has faced defensiveness, racism, gaslighting, research censorship, and now a retaliatory firing,&#8221; they wrote. &#8220;In an <a class="cu kc" href="https://twitter.com/timnitGebru/status/1334364732480958467" rel="noopener nofollow">email</a> to Dr. Gebru’s team on the evening of December 2, 2020, Google executives claimed that she had chosen to resign. This is false. In their direct correspondence with Dr. Gebru, these executives <a class="cu kc" href="https://twitter.com/timnitGebru/status/1334341991795142667" rel="noopener nofollow">informed</a> her that her termination was immediate, and pointed to an <a class="cu kc" href="https://www.platformer.news/p/the-withering-email-that-got-an-ethical" rel="noopener nofollow">email</a> she sent to a Google Brain diversity and inclusion mailing list as pretext.&#8221;</p>
<p>They went on to demand those who were involved in deciding how to treat Dr. Gebru&#8217;s paper meet with the Ethical AI team to explain what happened. They also demanded greater transparency around the decision-making, as well as a commitment from Google Research to research integrity and academic freedom.</p>
<p>
		<div class="embed breakout" id="vidible_div_0" data-pid="56faf851e4b0d3dcac2e081a" data-bcid="564f313b67b6231408bc51ee" data-video="5bac337dbf4885293903f4f0"></div>
		<span><script type="text/javascript" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/themes/techcrunch-2017/features/shortcodes/vidible-callback-js.php?id=0"></script></span>
		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/google-ceo-says-company-will-review-events-leading-up-to-dr-timnit-gebrus-departure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085138</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Watch live as SpaceX tries again to fly its Starship to great heights for the first time</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/watch-live-as-spacex-tries-again-to-fly-its-starship-to-great-heights-for-the-first-time/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/watch-live-as-spacex-tries-again-to-fly-its-starship-to-great-heights-for-the-first-time/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 20:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyperloop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085149</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SpaceX&#8217;s Starship prototype is set to take it&#8217;s first high-altitude flight — to around 40,000 feet or so — sometime this afternoon. This is the second time that it&#8217;s been poised to make this giant leap, after a try yesterday was aborted in the final seconds due to one of the Raptor engines automatically shutting [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/ap-BkkrRg-o?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/space-exploration-technologies" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="space-exploration-technologies">SpaceX&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Starship prototype is set to take it&#8217;s first high-altitude flight — to around 40,000 feet or so — sometime this afternoon. This is the second time that it&#8217;s been poised to make this giant leap, after a try yesterday was aborted in the final seconds due to one of the Raptor engines automatically shutting down to potentially prevent an even worse ending to the test.</p>
<p>The spacecraft is one of the latest prototypes of Starship that <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/space-exploration-technologies" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="space-exploration-technologies">SpaceX <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has built, and the first that will try for this high-flying demonstration. Other prototypes have climbed to a maximum of around 500 feet, after which they completed a controlled landing, too. This one will try that as well, provided it gets that far, but SpaceX CEO <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/elon-musk" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="elon-musk">Elon Musk <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has said that it&#8217;s very likely something will go wrong with this test – which is fully within expectations at this stage in the spacecraft&#8217;s development.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The rocket is launching from <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/space-ecb7" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="space-ecb7">SpaceX&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> development facility in Texas, and will fly to its apogee height of 40,000 feet before executing (again, hopefully) what is essentially a belly flop maneuver to turn around and then fall back to Earth, before ultimately performing a controlled landing to come to rest vertically. All theoretical, but that&#8217;s how it would go if everything went perfectly.</p>
<p>We could get a spectacularly different result, which would still help SpaceX immensely in their development of Starship by providing valuable data. The exact timing of the test flight isn&#8217;t yet known, so stay tuned above — the window officially closes at 6 p.m. EST today, so it&#8217;ll have to happen before then if it&#8217;s going to happen.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GSmnKSA12g"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/spacex-snags-885m-from-fcc-to-serve-rural-areas-with-starlink/">SpaceX snags $885M from FCC to serve rural areas with Starlink</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SpaceX snags $885M from FCC to serve rural areas with Starlink&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/spacex-snags-885m-from-fcc-to-serve-rural-areas-with-starlink/embed/#?secret=GSmnKSA12g" data-secret="GSmnKSA12g" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/watch-live-as-spacex-tries-again-to-fly-its-starship-to-great-heights-for-the-first-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085149</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FTC seeks to break up Facebook, alleging illegal monopoly</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/ftc-seeks-to-break-up-facebook-alleging-illegal-monopoly/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/ftc-seeks-to-break-up-facebook-alleging-illegal-monopoly/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 20:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antitrust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FTC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085120</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Federal Trade Commission today announced a new antitrust lawsuit against Facebook, alleging that the social network has used monopoly power &#8220;with the aim of suppressing, neutralizing and deterring serious competitive threats,&#8221; and must be broken up. The suit is separate from, but was investigated in coordination with, one from 48 attorneys general also announced [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Federal Trade Commission today announced a new antitrust lawsuit against <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="facebook">Facebook, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> alleging that the social network has used monopoly power &#8220;with the aim of suppressing, neutralizing and deterring serious competitive threats,&#8221; and must be broken up. The suit is separate from, but was investigated in coordination with, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/facebook-antitrust-state-attorneys-general/">one from 48 attorneys general also announced today</a>.</p>
<p>Both suits allege that Facebook has engaged in illegal patterns of behavior, which the states and federal investigators worked together to characterize. But the state lawsuit is concerned with violations at the state law level, while the <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/federal-trade-commission" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="federal-trade-commission">FTC <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> alleges violation of federal law. Therefore the two lawsuits, while objecting to the same actions by Facebook, will be pursued and adjudicated separately.</p>
<p>The allegations of both are similar: That Facebook&#8217;s acquisitions of WhatsApp and Instagram both constituted illegal shutdowns of nascent competitors by a monopoly, and that Facebook has used access to its platform as leverage to prevent other competitors from emerging.</p>
<p>The FTC and state lawsuits both call for the acquisitions of Instagram and WhatsApp, perhaps among others, to be retroactively judged to be illegal, and for those companies to be split off from the main Facebook company.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pkZeYAqyQP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/facebook-antitrust-state-attorneys-general/">Facebook hit with massive antitrust lawsuit from 46 states</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook hit with massive antitrust lawsuit from 46 states&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/facebook-antitrust-state-attorneys-general/embed/#?secret=pkZeYAqyQP" data-secret="pkZeYAqyQP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In addition to this divestiture, Facebook would need to seek prior notice and approval for all future mergers and acquisitions, from both the FTC and state authorities; various behaviors would also be prohibited, such as tying API access to not offering competing features.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/fbnewsroom/status/1336764387818950656">Facebook, in a Tweet</a>, said it is looking into the lawsuits, but disparaged them, saying, &#8220;T<span class="css-901oao css-16my406 r-1qd0xha r-ad9z0x r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0">he government now wants a do-over with no regard for the impact that precedent would have on the broader business community.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Indeed it is a natural question: How can the government approve the purchases of Instagram and WhatsApp, then retroactively disapprove them, without calling into question the entire oversight mechanism of the FTC and other regulatory agencies?</p>
<p>As the FTC notes in <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/facebook-q-a">its Q&amp;A on the lawsuit</a>, this is not actually unprecedented or even unexpected. The process of approving the purchase of one company by another may present no obvious illegal qualities at the time, but behind the scenes it may involve many. An approved and consummate merger might be unwound if, for example, it was found to have been executed on false pretenses after the fact — or, as in this case, if it is found later to be part of a pattern of illegal practices.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our enforcement action challenges more than just the acquisitions,&#8221; explains the FTC. &#8220;We are challenging a multiyear course of conduct that constituted monopolization of the personal social networking market … the FTC can — and often does — challenge consummated transactions when they violate the law. In fact, identifying anti-competitive consummated transactions has been a key part of the mandate of the Technology Enforcement Division since its formation in February 2019 as the Technology Task Force.&#8221;</p>
<p>These filings are only the very first part of what will almost certainly prove to be a multiyear process — and one spanning two administrations at that, which will only slow proceedings. The next step will likely be a PR push from Facebook explaining its innocence.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/ftc-seeks-to-break-up-facebook-alleging-illegal-monopoly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085120</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>As several marketplace unicorns prepare IPOs, a VC digs into the data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/as-several-marketplace-unicorns-prepare-ipos-a-vc-digs-into-the-data/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/as-several-marketplace-unicorns-prepare-ipos-a-vc-digs-into-the-data/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 20:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbnb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[initial public offering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[menlo ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2084359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Naturally, the economic model is important. Profitability is important. TAM is important. But right now, the markets are hot. Growth trumps all.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Venky Ganesan</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/venkyganesan">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="http://www.menlovc.com/team/venky-ganesan">Venky Ganesan</a> is a partner at <a href="http://www.menlovc.com/">Menlo Ventures</a>, which has invested in several marketplace companies including Uber, Poshmark and Rover.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/gallery/10-laws-of-successful-marketplaces/">10 Laws of Successful Marketplaces</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The end of 2020 will be marked by a series of high-profile consumer technology IPOs. Among the companies on file are several marketplace businesses including home rental giant <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/airbnb" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="airbnb">Airbnb, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> food delivery service DoorDash, grocery delivery company Instacart and the online shopping platform Wish.</p>
<p><a href="https://poshmark.com/">Poshmark</a>, a social commerce platform in which Menlo Ventures invested early, has also filed to go public. While the public market will soon assign value to these marketplace businesses, the dominance of these businesses underscores the strength of the marketplace business model. It’s interesting then, to dig into the numbers to understand the state of marketplace businesses today.</p>
<h2>What to make of 2020?</h2>
<p>Typically, we’d spend most of our time analyzing the most recent data. But, it will surprise no one that 2020 is an outlier. Thankfully, we don’t need to throw the data out. There are some interesting insights. The pandemic impacted businesses broadly, some boomed while others went bust. How the marketplace category fared varied from business to business, depending on the category.</p>
<p>The large public marketplaces continued to perform. If we look at the top 20 publicly traded marketplaces, we see that their combined market cap increased ~63% in 2020. This growth rate is lower than the ~99% growth of the 20 public SaaS leaders.</p>
<p>Not surprisingly companies like the video meeting platform Zoom and Shopify, a commerce platform that allows anyone to set up an online store and sell their products, benefitted from new dynamics introduced by the pandemic.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			If we look at the top 20 publicly traded marketplaces, we see that their combined market cap increased ~63% in 2020.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Similarly, some of the largest public marketplaces, like Amazon, Etsy and Delivery Hero were boosted by changes in consumer behavior including spikes in online shopping and delivery.</p>
<p>Acquisition efficiencies increased with increased demand from consumers and merchants that resulted in favorable growth plus EBITDA pairing.</p>
<p>Take Etsy as an example: In the last quarter, it grew at a whopping 128% YoY compared to 32% the year before with EBITDA margin of 30% versus 15% from the year before.</p>
<p>But where some marketplace categories were propelled by COVID-19 tailwinds, categories like travel and fitness struggled against the headwinds created by the pandemic. This is where we saw some exciting innovation from startups &#8212; which tend to be more nimble than their public counterparts &#8212; adapted to the new normal. Take Classpass, which was originally conceived as a platform to connect gym goers with the right studio/fitness classes.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/as-several-marketplace-unicorns-prepare-ipos-a-vc-digs-into-the-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2084359</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TiVo will offer personalized Match Scores to help you find your next streaming service</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/tivo-match-scores/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/tivo-match-scores/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 20:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tivo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085071</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;re gazing longingly at new streaming services but can&#8217;t actually afford all of them, TiVo says it can help you choose. In recent years, the company has been trying to evolve beyond the DVR business by creating products that make it easier for consumers to navigate the increasingly fragmented TV landscape. Earlier this year, it [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If you&#8217;re gazing longingly at new streaming services but can&#8217;t actually afford all of them, <a href="http://www.tivo.com">TiVo</a> says it can help you choose.</p>
<p>In recent years, the company has been trying to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/16/tivos-ceo-explains-how-the-company-fully-embraces-streaming/">evolve beyond the DVR business</a> by creating products that make it easier for consumers to navigate the increasingly fragmented TV landscape. Earlier this year, it launched <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/06/tivo-enters-the-streaming-market-with-a-50-android-tv-powered-device-tivo-stream-4k/">the TiVo Stream 4K</a>, a $50 Android TV dongle.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://blog.tivo.com/tivo-for-consumer/tivo-stream-4k/tivo-match-scores-helping-you-choose-the-best-streaming-services-for-you/">a blog post</a>, TiVo said that its goal is to help you answer questions like, &#8220;Do I need a live TV lineup? If so, what&#8217;s the optimal service and line-up for me? Which streaming services best fit my taste and consumption profile?&#8221; The <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/tivo" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="tivo">TiVo <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Stream 4K was the first step in that strategy, and today&#8217;s launch of TiVo Match Scores is the second.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The idea is pretty simple: When you browse different streaming services in the My Services section of the TiVo Stream interface, you&#8217;ll start seeing personalized scores between 1 and 100. The higher the score, the more likely that the service is a good fit for you.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2085098" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2085098" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2085098" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/unnamed-7.jpg?w=680" alt="TiVo Match Scores" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/unnamed-7.jpg 1440w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/unnamed-7.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/unnamed-7.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/unnamed-7.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/unnamed-7.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/unnamed-7.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2085098" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TiVo</p></div></p>
<p>Vice president of Product Chris Thun told me via email that with streaming services becoming increasingly protective of their viewership data, TiVo draws on a variety of data sources to calculate the scores for each viewer — the same data it uses to recommend movies and shows throughout the TiVo Stream experience.</p>
<p>&#8220;With TiVo Stream, we’re utilizing engagement-based personalization alongside the more traditional viewership data (in cases where views are made available to us) to tune our recommendations,&#8221; Thun said. &#8220;Ingredient signals driving engagement-based personalization include titles within TiVo Stream that you engage with, add to your watchlist or make a partner app selection (strongly implying viewership).&#8221;</p>
<p>Thun said every streaming service that&#8217;s <a href="https://explore.tivo.com/how-to/stream-4k/streaming-apps">integrated with TiVo Stream </a>will be scored. The company plans to roll out Match Scores over the next few days, with full deployment by the end of the week.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tP31YF4u5v"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/16/tivos-ceo-explains-how-the-company-fully-embraces-streaming/">Tivo&#8217;s CEO explains how the company &#8216;fully embraces&#8217; streaming</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tivo&#8217;s CEO explains how the company &#8216;fully embraces&#8217; streaming&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/16/tivos-ceo-explains-how-the-company-fully-embraces-streaming/embed/#?secret=tP31YF4u5v" data-secret="tP31YF4u5v" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/tivo-match-scores/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085071</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook hit with massive antitrust lawsuit from 46 states</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/facebook-antitrust-state-attorneys-general/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/facebook-antitrust-state-attorneys-general/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 19:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antitrust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2084427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A huge collection of states filed an antitrust lawsuit Wednesday accusing Facebook of suppressing its competition through monopolistic business practices. Forty-eight attorneys general across 46 states, the territory of Guam and the District of Columbia are behind the lawsuit, with only South Dakota, South Carolina, Alabama and Georgia declining to join. The lawsuit, which looks [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A huge collection of states filed an antitrust lawsuit Wednesday accusing <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="facebook">Facebook <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> of suppressing its competition through monopolistic business practices. Forty-eight attorneys general across 46 states, the territory of Guam and the District of Columbia are behind the lawsuit, with only South Dakota, South Carolina, Alabama and Georgia declining to join.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://ag.ny.gov/sites/default/files/facebook_complaint_12.9.2020.pdf">lawsuit</a>, which looks at Facebook&#8217;s actions throughout the company&#8217;s history, alleges that the company bought competitors &#8220;illegally&#8221; and in a &#8220;predatory manner&#8221; in order to grow and preserve its market power. The suit cites Facebook&#8217;s acquisitions of Instagram and WhatsApp as prominent examples.</p>
<p>The collection of states asks the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia to &#8220;restrain Facebook from making further acquisitions valued at or in excess of $10 million&#8221; without notifying the plaintiff states in advance. The lawsuit also asks the court for &#8220;any additional relief it determines is appropriate, including the divestiture or restructuring of illegally acquired companies, or current Facebook assets or business lines.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The suit was led by a committee of attorneys general from California, Colorado, Florida, Iowa, Nebraska, North Carolina, Ohio, Tennessee and the District of Columbia, with New York Attorney General Letitia James spearheading the effort.</p>
<p>&#8220;Almost every state in this nation has joined this bipartisan lawsuit because Facebook’s efforts to dominate the market were as illegal as they were harmful,&#8221; James said. &#8220;Today’s suit should send a clear message to Facebook and every other company that any efforts to stifle competition, reduce innovation, or cut privacy protections will be met with the full force of our offices.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="25okuO0yAY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/ftc-seeks-to-break-up-facebook-alleging-illegal-monopoly/">FTC seeks to break up Facebook, alleging illegal monopoly</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;FTC seeks to break up Facebook, alleging illegal monopoly&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/ftc-seeks-to-break-up-facebook-alleging-illegal-monopoly/embed/#?secret=25okuO0yAY" data-secret="25okuO0yAY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The state antitrust action against Facebook materialized the same week that the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/ftc-seeks-to-break-up-facebook-alleging-illegal-monopoly/">FTC voted to pursue its own antitrust suit</a> against the social media giant. That vote tied a bow on a <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2020/11/06/ftc-sue-facebook-antitrust-violations-434810">20-month investigation</a> into Facebook&#8217;s business, including its acquisitions of WhatsApp and Instagram — two formerly independent apps that were folded into the social giant&#8217;s business. The FTC is now calling for those companies to be spun out independently.</p>
<p>Facebook has been regularly criticized for its outsized influence and repeatedly called to testify before Congress on related issues, but the coordinated antitrust effort at the federal and state level marks a challenging new chapter for the company.</p>
<p><iframe class="scribd_iframe_embed" src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/487543304/content?start_page=1&view_mode&access_key=key-1AuRuCi2CKccpHIMIipf"  data-auto-height="true" scrolling="no" id="scribd_487543304" width="100%" height="500" frameborder="0"></iframe>
		<div style="font-size:10px;text-align:center;width:100%"><a href="https://www.scribd.com/doc/487543304" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">View this document on Scribd</a></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/facebook-antitrust-state-attorneys-general/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2084427</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gift Guide: The best books for 2020 as recommended by VCs and TechCrunch writers (Part 2)</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/gift-guide-the-best-books-for-2020-as-recommended-by-vcs-and-techcrunch-writers-part-2/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/gift-guide-the-best-books-for-2020-as-recommended-by-vcs-and-techcrunch-writers-part-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 19:50:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gift Guide 2020]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2083969</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We published the TechCrunch list of the best books of 2020 last week, which included such titles as Barton Gellman’s Dark Mirror as recommended by our cybersecurity editor Zack Whittaker and Shoe Dog by Phil Knight, recommended by Lightspeed’s Nicole Quinn. In all, we selected nine books from our writers and VCs in the community that helped us get through 2020.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome to TechCrunch&#8217;s 2020 Holiday Gift Guide! Need help with gift ideas? We&#8217;re here to help! We&#8217;ll be rolling out gift guides from now through the end of December. </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2020/"><em>You can find our other guides right here.</em></a></p>
<p>We published the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/gift-guide-the-best-books-for-2020-recommended-by-vcs-and-techcrunch-writers-part-1/">TechCrunch list of the best books of 2020</a> last week, which included such titles as Barton Gellman’s &#8220;<i>Dark Mirror&#8221;</i> as recommended by our cybersecurity editor Zack Whittaker and &#8220;Shoe Dog&#8221; by Phil Knight, recommended by Lightspeed’s Nicole Quinn. In all, we selected nine books from our writers and VCs in the community that helped us get through 2020.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vm1amqkLCD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/gift-guide-the-best-books-for-2020-recommended-by-vcs-and-techcrunch-writers-part-1/">Gift Guide: The best books for 2020 recommended by VCs and TechCrunch writers (Part 1)</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gift Guide: The best books for 2020 recommended by VCs and TechCrunch writers (Part 1)&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/gift-guide-the-best-books-for-2020-recommended-by-vcs-and-techcrunch-writers-part-1/embed/#?secret=vm1amqkLCD" data-secret="vm1amqkLCD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But maybe you are a straggler when it comes to reading, and you’re just catching up on your holiday book shopping. Or maybe you reviewed a book, and decided to take my deadline(s) for turning in said review liberally. With all the time we have indoors, nine books doesn’t really feel like enough these days, does it? So here are nine more books (plus one bonus) recommended by VCs and TechCrunch writers for 2020.</p>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic">This article contains links to affiliate partners where available. When you buy through these links, TechCrunch may earn an affiliate commission.</i></p>
<h2 id="No Filter: The Inside Story of Instagram by Sarah Frier">No Filter: The Inside Story of Instagram by Sarah Frier</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.simonandschuster.com/books/No-Filter/Sarah-Frier/9781982126803">Simon &amp; Schuster</a>, 2020, 352 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Alexia Bonatsos, founder and general partner at Dream Machine and former editor of TechCrunch</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2083972" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/50772888.jpg?w=450" alt="" width="450" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/50772888.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/50772888.jpg?resize=99,150 99w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/50772888.jpg?resize=199,300 199w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/50772888.jpg?resize=768,1160 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/50772888.jpg?resize=450,680 450w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/50772888.jpg?resize=1017,1536 1017w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/50772888.jpg?resize=1356,2048 1356w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/50772888.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></p>
<p>Most of the canonical “tech books” (&#8220;Super Pumped,&#8221; &#8220;Hatching Twitter,&#8221; &#8220;Bad Blood&#8221;) are written by men. In &#8220;No Filter,&#8221; Sarah Frier finally puts the female gaze on a tech platform, an achievement that mirrors that of my favorite movie of 2020, &#8220;Portrait of a Lady on Fire.&#8221; From now-famous street food vendors in São Paulo to a North Korean expat ‘gramming his meals in Pyongyang, Instagram has transformed our lives the same way it transformed our poorly lit iPhone photos.</p>
<p>The book chronicles this transformation, taking us from the Florence study abroad trip where Filippo Brunelleschi’s shift to linear perspective inspired Kevin Systrom to change how the world communicates to the Calabasas mansion where Kylie Jenner first posted about her ‘Kylie’ lip kits.</p>
<p>It takes us through the Great Authentication Wars of 2012: Twitter shutting off its contacts to Instagram, Instagram shutting off its photo integration with Twitter, and reminds you that before they were behemoths testifying in front of Congress, social networks could be Greek God-level dramatic with the smallest feature update. To quote Zuck (or Ozymandias), “If we don’t create the thing that kills Facebook, someone else will. The Internet is not a friendly place. Things that don’t stay relevant don’t even get the luxury of leaving ruins. They disappear.”</p>
<p>It also leaves us in the present. In &#8220;No Filter,&#8221; Instagram head Adam Mosseri states during a Q&amp;A that the most important question Instagram faces is, “Are we good for people?” What do you think? Whether you believe in techno determinism or social determinism, this tome about how over one billion people found themselves living, working and playing on a photosharing app is a masterpiece filled with rich detail, Instagram in stark relief.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$25 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1982126809/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1982126809&amp;linkId=2467ff40eb61bf3fcc28d24803007a86">on Amazon</a></p>
<h2 id="Radical Abundance: How a Revolution in Nanotechnology Will Change Civilization by K. Eric Drexler">Radical Abundance: How a Revolution in Nanotechnology Will Change Civilization by K. Eric Drexler</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.publicaffairsbooks.com/titles/k-eric-drexler/radical-abundance/9781610391146/">PublicAffairs</a>, 2013, 368 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Matt Ocko, co-managing partner and co-founder of DCVC</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2083973" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/8126siLiu1L.jpg?w=466" alt="" width="466" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/8126siLiu1L.jpg 1392w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/8126siLiu1L.jpg?resize=103,150 103w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/8126siLiu1L.jpg?resize=206,300 206w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/8126siLiu1L.jpg?resize=768,1120 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/8126siLiu1L.jpg?resize=466,680 466w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/8126siLiu1L.jpg?resize=1053,1536 1053w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/8126siLiu1L.jpg?resize=34,50 34w" sizes="(max-width: 466px) 100vw, 466px" /></p>
<p>I like to re-examine how fragile the history of scientific progress is, and how easily humanity has been both derailed (sometimes for centuries) or leapt ahead. Alternatively, sometimes a scientific revolution happens quietly and slowly over a few decades even when it was seemingly derailed — even more interestingly, evolving very differently than its original, ardent proponents imagined.</p>
<p>An example of this case is nanotech, which is why I’ve been re-reading Dr. Eric Drexler’s &#8220;Radical Abundance&#8221; – the title is a goal my partners and I hope humanity achieves – and his more technical &#8220;Nanosystems.&#8221; Together, these books lay out the case for a nanotech-driven economy without most of today’s economic limits, but from a very “atoms-and-bits”-centric perspective. A well-realized possible outcome of this vision was depicted by Neal Stephenson, the sci-fi writer, in &#8220;The Diamond Age.&#8221; I’m not re-reading that now, but I heartily recommend it as part of a “nanotech book triptych”</p>
<p>The reason Drexler’s books merited re-reading this year for me is that many of his prerequisites for a nanotech economy of abundance are being achieved, but through computational and synthetic biology and related life-science breakthroughs. These platforms are getting living cells to do amazing things for humanity’s benefit. Ironically, it’s still his vision of robots following complex instructions in emergent systems, and even robots made of carbon — but not at all what he expected. A good lesson for everyone betting on radical innovation.</p>
<p>There’s still massive promise in “traditional” nanotech, and Deep Tech companies are doing everything from producing flawless slabs of diamond to transform computers and medical devices, to similar atomic-scale breakthroughs in quantum computing and sensor technology. In the end, who knows? Maybe we get both a fully-realized “diamond age” and the apotheosis of the “DNA age” we’re in right now. Humanity wins either way.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $29<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1610391136/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1610391136&amp;linkId=03dd714ed110b9661772fe41319ff842"> from Amazon</a></p>
<h2 id="Convenience Store Woman by Sayaka Murata">Convenience Store Woman by Sayaka Murata</h2>
<p><a href="https://groveatlantic.com/book/convenience-store-woman/">Grove Atlantic</a>, 2019, 192 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Ingrid Lunden, TechCrunch’s news editor</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2083975" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81SsLYe8ZRL.jpg?w=502" alt="" width="502" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81SsLYe8ZRL.jpg 1607w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81SsLYe8ZRL.jpg?resize=111,150 111w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81SsLYe8ZRL.jpg?resize=222,300 222w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81SsLYe8ZRL.jpg?resize=768,1039 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81SsLYe8ZRL.jpg?resize=502,680 502w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81SsLYe8ZRL.jpg?resize=1135,1536 1135w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81SsLYe8ZRL.jpg?resize=1513,2048 1513w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81SsLYe8ZRL.jpg?resize=37,50 37w" sizes="(max-width: 502px) 100vw, 502px" /></p>
<p>Chain convenience stores can feel as expendable and as predictable as the products they sell. Bright lights, pre-packaged food, headache medicine, cold drinks, and coffee — all arranged in the same places, all sold with the same smile. All pretty soulless.</p>
<p>But is it? One person’s banality is another person’s lifeline in this short, quiet, and surreal novel about a woman who works in a convenience store in Tokyo.</p>
<p>Keiko Furukura is both your most ordinary and extraordinary convenience store worker. As precise, practical and methodical as the Japanese aesthetic embodied by the convenience store where she works, Keiko has been in the job for years. And she is disconcertingly content with it, devoid of any of the ambitions or boredoms, or elations or sadness, shared by her friends and family, and likely you and me. Her particular outlook becomes the norm for how we start to see her world.</p>
<p>Like the store, and Keiko herself, Murata’s writing brings a stylized, calm cadence to the world she depicts. Dark comedy is there, but even if you don’t see it, the world goes on. And, because of that cadence, when Keiko’s life takes a turn, the effect is especially jarring — tense, even.</p>
<p>The novel is a fascinating peep into a slice of Tokyo life. And its brief length means you can consume it in one long sitting or over a few days — not a bad thing in a year when so many people have complained that they’ve been unable to read books.</p>
<p>Indeed, in this pandemic period, when our own lives have been reduced down to a small set of routines, &#8220;Convenience Store Woman&#8221; is a welcome escape, even as it resonates strongly.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$13 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0802128254/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0802128254&amp;linkId=6ceaa81431ccb4440f95d406f7ca6899">from Amazon</a></p>
<h2 id="The Price of Peace: Money, Democracy and the life of John Maynard Keynes by Zachary D. Carter">The Price of Peace: Money, Democracy and the life of John Maynard Keynes by Zachary D. Carter</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/563378/the-price-of-peace-by-zachary-d-carter/">Random House</a>, 2020, 656 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Sarah Cannon, partner at Index Ventures</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2083976" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81cyA4UXkEL.jpg?w=450" alt="" width="450" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81cyA4UXkEL.jpg 1695w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81cyA4UXkEL.jpg?resize=99,150 99w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81cyA4UXkEL.jpg?resize=199,300 199w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81cyA4UXkEL.jpg?resize=768,1160 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81cyA4UXkEL.jpg?resize=450,680 450w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81cyA4UXkEL.jpg?resize=1017,1536 1017w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81cyA4UXkEL.jpg?resize=1356,2048 1356w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/81cyA4UXkEL.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></p>
<p>To start, I must reveal my bias which is that Keynes is my favorite economist. Regardless of whether one shares my admiration for Keynes himself or his economic philosophy, &#8220;The Price of Peace&#8221; provides an economic history of his ideas and policy experiences which are inextricably linked to the major economic crises of the twentieth century.</p>
<p>Keynes is credited as the intellectual architect of fiscal stimulus which felt particularly relevant in 2020 as we are experimenting with stimulus packages of unprecedented scale in the face of the pandemic.</p>
<p>In addition to being a fascinating history of ideas, the book presents a picture of Keynes’s life and relationship with his close circle of friends, the Bloomsbury Group, which included the likes of Bertrand Russell and Virginia Woolf. In American culture, I think we often obsess over individual genius but throughout history there are many groups of artists, writers and intellectuals who profoundly impacted one another’s works. Hoping to stumble on some such interdisciplinary salons in San Francisco when we open up again…</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $25<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0525509038/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0525509038&amp;linkId=2acfec5d18284a9f0864a1f4357aebd6"> from Amazon</a></p>
<h2 id="Jump-Starting America: How Breakthrough Science Can Revive Economic Growth and the American Dream by Jonathan Gruber and Simon Johnson">Jump-Starting America: How Breakthrough Science Can Revive Economic Growth and the American Dream by Jonathan Gruber and Simon Johnson</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.publicaffairsbooks.com/titles/jonathan-gruber/jump-starting-america/9781541762503/">PublicAffairs</a>, 2019, 368 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Roy Bahat, head of Bloomberg Beta</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2083977" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/51ys0n9HSeL.jpg?w=439" alt="" width="439" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/51ys0n9HSeL.jpg 646w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/51ys0n9HSeL.jpg?resize=97,150 97w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/51ys0n9HSeL.jpg?resize=194,300 194w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/51ys0n9HSeL.jpg?resize=439,680 439w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/51ys0n9HSeL.jpg?resize=32,50 32w" sizes="(max-width: 439px) 100vw, 439px" /></p>
<p>While we’re all thinking about the future of work, the only reason we have all the work we do <i>today</i> is because of government. All of tech exists, in part, because government-funded scientific research and business picked up the mantle. Today, as we’re struggling with how to get many places in America back to work, the best hope for &#8220;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/11/placing-bets-beyond-the-venture-hubs-of-new-york-and-silicon-valley/">comeback cities</a>&#8221; might be getting the band back together: government funding the science that business turns into the innovations of our daily lives.</p>
<p>&#8220;Jump-Starting America&#8221; presents a plan to get places around America growing again — by boosting public funding in scientific research and development.</p>
<p>Gruber and Johnson argue we should place new research and technology hubs in places with the need for growth. They point to dozens of cities in the U.S. that have the preconditions for success: a large pool of educated workers, high-quality universities, and a low cost of living. All those places lack is the scientific infrastructure to become new centers of innovation, and the private sector ignores them. &#8220;What these places need is a jump start.&#8221;</p>
<p>This book <a href="https://www.jump-startingamerica.com/102-places-for-jumpstarting-america">ranks cities across the country</a> to identify those most ready for this scientific boost — see their <a href="https://www.jump-startingamerica.com/technology-hub-map">map</a> to explore places you care about.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $13<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1541762487/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1541762487&amp;linkId=d7d6167909fb4d936f0ad7dfe2597e34"> from Amazon</a></p>
<h2 id="You Again by Debra Jo Immergut">You Again by Debra Jo Immergut</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.harpercollins.com/products/you-again-debra-jo-immergut?variant=32123657650210">Ecco</a> (HarperCollins), 2020, 288 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Ron Miller, TechCrunch enterprise reporter</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2083978" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71jYS6IXHcL.jpg?w=448" alt="" width="448" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71jYS6IXHcL.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71jYS6IXHcL.jpg?resize=99,150 99w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71jYS6IXHcL.jpg?resize=198,300 198w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71jYS6IXHcL.jpg?resize=768,1166 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71jYS6IXHcL.jpg?resize=448,680 448w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71jYS6IXHcL.jpg?resize=1012,1536 1012w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71jYS6IXHcL.jpg?resize=1349,2048 1349w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71jYS6IXHcL.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 448px) 100vw, 448px" /></p>
<p>Imagine 40-something you sitting in the back of a New York City cab and seeing your 20-something self walking down the street. That’s the way &#8220;You Again,&#8221; a novel by Debra Jo Immergut opens. Abigail Ward is a woman in her mid-40s with a comfortable job, a seemingly good marriage, two teen sons and a house in Brooklyn, but something is missing in her life and it begins to manifest itself in her visions of her younger self.</p>
<p>Whether these visions are real or not is beside the point. Ward, who was a talented young artist in her 20s, has skeletons long locked away in her mind’s closet and she begins behaving in odd ways. While her son becomes involved in antifa, she starts down a path of increasingly risky behaviors putting her ideal suburban life at considerable risk.</p>
<p>While we search with the author for reasons for this increasingly odd behavior, Immergut slowly reveals more information about why Ward appears to be unraveling.</p>
<p>It is safe to reveal that the protagonist was a promising artist, that she was admired by her teachers and her classmates for her budding talent, and that she had a gift for color. Her early paintings, completed at around the age she starts seeing herself, were getting noticed in the New York art community.</p>
<p>We learn that she let all of that slip away for the comforts and mundane realities of suburban living — having children, paying bills, buying groceries and living her life. She spends her days in a cubicle designing ad campaigns for a pharmaceutical company. It’s a considerable step down from the artistic vision she had of who she was and where she would end up at 45.</p>
<p>The story catapults along, a mystery wrapped in this woman’s behavioral enigma as these meetings reveal more information. While the book brings together a compelling plot line involving lost dreams of youth, personified by these visits with her younger self, I’m not sure it completely succeeds in carrying it through to a satisfying conclusion.</p>
<p>You will have to read it to reveal the details and the reason behind all of this, but I was left wondering, even when Ward’s motives are ultimately revealed, if I believed that this woman, this character as defined in these pages, would have behaved this way. I still admit to being riveted, to wanting to find the answers to these questions, I’m just not sure I was satisfied with the answers.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$19 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0062747584/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0062747584&amp;linkId=5f304ce65d260f4122f594cfa9d669fc">from Amazon</a></p>
<h2 id="Principles by Ray Dalio">Principles by Ray Dalio</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.principles.com">Simon &amp; Schuster</a>, 2017, 592 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Aaron Holiday, co-founder and managing partner at 645 Ventures</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2083979" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71FDkx5WllL.jpg?w=453" alt="" width="453" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71FDkx5WllL.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71FDkx5WllL.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71FDkx5WllL.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71FDkx5WllL.jpg?resize=768,1152 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71FDkx5WllL.jpg?resize=453,680 453w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71FDkx5WllL.jpg?resize=1024,1536 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71FDkx5WllL.jpg?resize=1365,2048 1365w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71FDkx5WllL.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 453px) 100vw, 453px" /></p>
<p>In a year of radical change and uncertainty at almost every turn, reading &#8220;Principles&#8221; kept me grounded through the turbulence of 2020. In his book, author Ray Dalio, the founder of Bridgewater Associates, shares insights on life, investing, and much more.</p>
<p>Bridgewater, the world’s largest hedge fund with $130 billion in assets under management, was built upon a set of principles that serve as a cornerstone of the firm’s success. Those principles and decision-making frameworks, articulated in the book, have been profoundly impactful on our own leadership team at 645 Ventures. They have been especially valuable as we closed our largest fund to date and seek to build the firm through and beyond the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>In the early days of building our fund, we’ve seen first-hand how important it is to distinguish luck from success, especially as it relates to intrinsic performance. Dalio emphasizes that the optimal frame of mind for great leaders is to be humble and open-minded in order to develop the strong mental maps that guide decision-making. This principle stands the test of time and repeatedly drives success, as do several others that Dailio introduces, such as “The who is more important than the what” in hiring, and the importance of self-reflection and owning your “ego and blind spots.”</p>
<p>The wisdom of &#8220;Principles&#8221; is universal enough to serve a range of purposes and people, and it is an especially important reference guide for this generation of founders daring to build iconic businesses. We aspire to live these principles in our own firm, and we often see them in the founding teams of our most successful portfolio companies.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $17 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1501124021/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1501124021&amp;linkId=c38d7e85fe4e51df5876472413215159">from Amazon</a></p>
<h2 id="Love and Other Thought Experiments by Sophie Ward">Love and Other Thought Experiments by Sophie Ward</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.hachette.co.uk/titles/sophie-ward/love-and-other-thought-experiments/9781472154583/">Corsair</a> (Hachette), 2020, 256 pages<br />
<strong>Recommended by Catherine Shu, TechCrunch writer</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2083980" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71-A72XAjRL.jpg?w=423" alt="" width="423" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71-A72XAjRL.jpg 1591w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71-A72XAjRL.jpg?resize=93,150 93w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71-A72XAjRL.jpg?resize=186,300 186w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71-A72XAjRL.jpg?resize=768,1236 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71-A72XAjRL.jpg?resize=423,680 423w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71-A72XAjRL.jpg?resize=955,1536 955w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71-A72XAjRL.jpg?resize=1273,2048 1273w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/71-A72XAjRL.jpg?resize=31,50 31w" sizes="(max-width: 423px) 100vw, 423px" /></p>
<p>I have to admit that the main reason I picked up Sophie Ward’s debut novel, &#8220;Love and Other Thought Experiments,&#8221; is because she was one of my favorite actors when I was a kid. If you grew up in the 1980s, you might remember Ward from movies like &#8220;Young Sherlock Holmes&#8221; and &#8220;Return to Oz.&#8221;</p>
<p>While continuing to act, Ward launched a writing career, too, publishing essays, short stories and the 2014 book “A Marriage Proposal; the importance of equal marriage and what it means for all of us.” She also somehow found time to complete a PhD at Goldsmiths, University of London, that focused on the use of narrative in philosophy of the mind.</p>
<p>All those paths converge in &#8220;Love and Other Thought Experiments,&#8221; which was long-listed for this year’s Booker Prize. The novel centers around Rachel and Eliza, a couple whose bond becomes fraught when Rachel is convinced an ant has crawled in her eye and started living in her head. Eliza, a scientist, quietly struggles to understand and sympathize with Rachel, even as the two embark on parenthood.</p>
<p>Each chapter of the book is based on a well-known thought experiment (theoretical scenarios that help people understand philosophical principles), and told from the perspective of different characters as they find their way, and each other, through alternative timelines.</p>
<p>Honestly, the book is hard to describe. You might assume that a book based on philosophical thought experiments would make for onerous reading, but Ward’s genre-crossing narrative is so deft and engaging that it was a surprise to realize I had reached the last few pages.</p>
<p>2020 has often felt surreal. I know I’m not the only person who has started experiencing time differently — days, weeks and months feel like an interminable slough, yet there is too much happening at once for our brains to fully comprehend. &#8220;Love and Other Thought Experiments&#8221; was comforting, reminding me that when almost everything feels unmoored, there are always fundamental truths to find and hold onto, in our beliefs and our relationships.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $15 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1472154606/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1472154606&amp;linkId=d735033b311a3f086dd1bc33fc2e399e">from Amazon</a></p>
<h2 id="The Dark Forest and Death’s End by Cixin Liu">The Dark Forest and Death’s End by Cixin Liu</h2>
<p><a href="https://us.macmillan.com/books/9780765397485">Tor Books</a> (Macmillan), 2015/2016, 512 pages / 608 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Alex Wilhelm, TechCrunch senior editor</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2083981" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Deaths-End.jpg?w=452" alt="" width="452" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Deaths-End.jpg 1020w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Deaths-End.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Deaths-End.jpg?resize=199,300 199w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Deaths-End.jpg?resize=768,1155 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Deaths-End.jpg?resize=452,680 452w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Deaths-End.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 452px) 100vw, 452px" /></p>
<p>By now many of us have read &#8220;The Three Body Problem,&#8221; an incredible work of science-fiction and human imagination. Until this year, however, I hadn’t thought of reading the second and third books in the trilogy.</p>
<p>I was robbing myself of joy and didn’t know it.</p>
<p>Over the summer, during a week off, I powered through the sequel to T&#8221;he Three Body Problem,&#8221; &#8220;The Dark Forest&#8221; and found it incredibly interesting. To avoid spoilers, I’ll just say that it made me rethink my lifelong desire to get off the planet and go somewhere else, and for humans to keep our outward push not only to the edges of our backyard — the Solar System — but also into the further reaches of our celestial neighborhood.</p>
<p>And then I read the next book, &#8220;Death’s End.&#8221; It’s long. There were a few moments when I was a little tired. But I cannot recall reading any other book in my life that was as consistently inventive and brilliant. It was so good, so surprising, so deep, so long and vivid, and so fundamentally human, that I even wound up reading a follow-up by a different author that started life as fanfic that was later made crypto-cannon. That was a first.</p>
<p>&#8220;Death’s End &#8221; is the book I want you to read, but you can’t read it alone. You need prior context to fully juice it. But as you deserve the adventure, the expanse, the ring of hope and loss, and the contemplation of our species that it will bring you, the work required will be entirely worth it.</p>
<p>The book is imperfect. Anyone who has read Cixin Liu knows that he has weaknesses. These are perfectly illustrated in a prequel of sorts to &#8220;The Three Body Problem&#8221; trilogy, &#8220;Ball Lightning,&#8221; that I recently finished. He’s not great at writing female characters. And his protagonists can, at times, seem to have overlapping personality traits and origin stories.</p>
<p>But those mistakes are merely human, while the distances that &#8220;Death’s End&#8221; took me too were much more; they were cosmic. I want to tell you more but spoiling even a page would be a damned waste, so go re-read &#8220;The Three Body Problem&#8221; — which I did not do before digging into The Dark Forest, and it was an error — and then move through the trilogy. Please.</p>
<p>(And if those two books do ring your bell, &#8220;Anathem,&#8221; &#8220;The Mote In God’s Eye&#8221; and &#8220;Fire Upon the Deep&#8221; should be on your list as well.)</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/076537708X/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=076537708X&amp;linkId=8fdd081311442c8cb3ca27a51d041a34">The Dark Forest, $21 from Amazon</a> |  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0765377101/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0765377101&amp;linkId=289d2199319b6a823cac79a3503b47fe">Death&#8217;s End, $21 from Amazon</a></p>
<h3 id="One more thing…">One more thing…</h3>
<h2 id="Traction: Get a Grip on Your Business by Gino Wickman">Traction: Get a Grip on Your Business by Gino Wickman</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.benbellabooks.com/shop/traction/">BenBella Books</a>, 2007 (updated 2012), 275 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Garry Tan, founder and managing partner, Initialized Capital</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2083982" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/519hpdx2J8L.jpg?w=333" alt="" width="333" height="500" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/519hpdx2J8L.jpg 333w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/519hpdx2J8L.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/519hpdx2J8L.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/519hpdx2J8L.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 333px) 100vw, 333px" /></p>
<p>Actionable advice for business owners of all kinds, not just startup founders. A great reminder that not every business is a startup, but it is definitely true that every great startup must learn to be a great business if they are to truly reach their ultimate potential.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$15 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1936661837/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1936661837&amp;linkId=6ac8d5d8d624940625f082d124901832">from Amazon</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vm1amqkLCD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/gift-guide-the-best-books-for-2020-recommended-by-vcs-and-techcrunch-writers-part-1/">Gift Guide: The best books for 2020 recommended by VCs and TechCrunch writers (Part 1)</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gift Guide: The best books for 2020 recommended by VCs and TechCrunch writers (Part 1)&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/gift-guide-the-best-books-for-2020-recommended-by-vcs-and-techcrunch-writers-part-1/embed/#?secret=vm1amqkLCD" data-secret="vm1amqkLCD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2020/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/gift-guide-2020-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/gift-guide-the-best-books-for-2020-as-recommended-by-vcs-and-techcrunch-writers-part-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2083969</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
