<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 04:45:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Cabify launches &#8216;Cabify Go!&#8217;, a multi-modal subscription service</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/cabify-launches-cabify-go-a-multi-modal-subscription-service/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/cabify-launches-cabify-go-a-multi-modal-subscription-service/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 08:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscription services]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2161921</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cabify wants to own the way people in cities move. The Spanish-born ride-hailing company is rolling out a pilot multi-modal subscription model to 40,000 users in Madrid this week, with plans to expand to its other markets throughout Spain and Latin America. The &#8220;Cabify Go!&#8221; subscription service appears to have something for everyone. All of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cabify wants to own the way people in cities move. The Spanish-born ride-hailing company is rolling out a pilot multi-modal subscription model to 40,000 users in Madrid this week, with plans to expand to its other markets throughout Spain and Latin America.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The &#8220;Cabify Go!&#8221; subscription service appears to have something for everyone. All of Cabify’s different mobility offerings &#8212; ride-hailing service, </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/10/movo-grabs-22-5m-to-get-more-cities-in-latam-scooting/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">electric micromobility subsidiary MOVO</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, bike subscription service Bive and courier service &#8212; are already available under one app, but now customers will also be able to select one of three plans that reflect the mobility needs of different users. Select users will now see a &#8220;Go!&#8221; button on the top-right corner of the screen. This is a step toward making the Cabify name ubiquitous among city dwellers planning a trip, whether they’re taking an old-fashioned taxi ride to the airport or are riding a scooter to work. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The subscription scheme ‘Cabify Go!’ is born to make our app their recurring platform, with diverse available services,” </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Leonor Barrueco, Cabify&#8217;s VP of growth,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> told TechCrunch. “This approach is strongly aligned with our goal of becoming the leading multi-mobility platform. At this stage there&#8217;s an opportunity to get closer to our users&#8217; multiple and varying needs. We want to offer our users convenient, diverse and sustainable ways to move around the city at an affordable monthly fee.”</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The main subscription offering, &#8220;Cabify Go! Todo en uno&#8221; or &#8220;Everything in one&#8221; plan, costs €6.95 per month and gives users a blanket 10% discount on all their Cabify trips, as well as 30% off Cabify Envíos, its courier service. Subscribers also get two free cancellations each month and are exempt from the additional fee incurred from high demand. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cabify is also offering the &#8220;A dos ruedas&#8221; or &#8220;On two wheels&#8221; plan, which costs €19.95 per month and includes 10 free MOVO rides of up to €6 without any additional cost. The mobility company expects subscriptions to help bring on new users. Currently, the rate of new users in Cabify&#8217;s moped segment is nearly 1.5 times higher than the ride-hailing services&#8217; rate, according to Barrueco. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;Given the convergence of the platform space where customers can demand a variety of booming multi-mobility services, some users might be new to alternative options whilst some are new to the whole multi-mobility ecosystem,&#8221; said Barrueco.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jS9MbrsarT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/17/unagi-expands-e-scooter-subscriptions-with-10-5m-in-new-funding/">Unagi expands e-scooter subscriptions with $10.5M in new funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Unagi expands e-scooter subscriptions with $10.5M in new funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/17/unagi-expands-e-scooter-subscriptions-with-10-5m-in-new-funding/embed/#?secret=jS9MbrsarT" data-secret="jS9MbrsarT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Finally, its &#8220;Pedelea&#8221; or &#8220;Pedal&#8221; plan includes the Bive long-term rental service for electric or mechanical bikes, with a competitive monthly price of €49.95 and €28.95, respectively. Servicing and maintenance is included, as well as a 10% discount on ride-hailing trips. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bive, which Cabify introduced about a year ago, has already spread from Madrid to Valencia, Sevilla and Barcelona. By integrating the service into Cabify’s subscription offerings, the company hopes to promote the Bive service through another outlet, an idea borne out by internal insights. Barrueca says that 50% of Bive’s user base are new users to the Cabify platform. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are no sign-up or cancellation fees for any of the services, and users can cancel at any time, according to Barrueco. But that&#8217;s par for the course when it comes to mobility subscriptions, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">which seem to be on the rise as the subscription business model grows to answer shifting consumption habits. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to monetization tech developer <a href="https://www.telecoming.com/blog/subscronomics-the-subscription-economy-will-surpass-228-billion-during-2021/">Telecoming&#8217;s 2021 Subscronomics Report</a>, in the European market, &#8220;with a base of 353 million households and more than 2,100 connected devices (22% of the total worldwide), 560 million subscriptions will be purchased this year (25% of the worldwide total).&#8221; This is expected to contribute to a global subscriptions industry of almost $228 billion, which is 31% higher than in 2020, with an average YOY growth of 23% from now until 2025. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other companies that have jumped on the monthly rental train early include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/17/unagi-expands-e-scooter-subscriptions-with-10-5m-in-new-funding/">Unagi</a> with its e-scooters, Swapfiets with bikes and e-bikes and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/10/ev-subscription-service-onto-partners-with-shell-to-expand-access-to-charging/">Onto with electric vehicles</a>.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="S7CaWds4Tt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/10/ev-subscription-service-onto-partners-with-shell-to-expand-access-to-charging/">EV subscription service Onto partners with Shell to expand access to charging</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;EV subscription service Onto partners with Shell to expand access to charging&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/10/ev-subscription-service-onto-partners-with-shell-to-expand-access-to-charging/embed/#?secret=S7CaWds4Tt" data-secret="S7CaWds4Tt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Barrueco says one of Cabify&#8217;s goals in increasing its own business is to contribute to the transformation of cities to be more people-centric and environmentally friendly by making shared modes of transport more accessible.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;One of the company’s top priorities is to ramp up and consolidate our multimobility service proposition which provides our users with diverse sustainable alternatives and aims to replace the dominance of the private car,&#8221; said Barrueco.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the global share of EVs over Cabify&#8217;s entire fleet is only about 1%, with hybrid vehicles accounting for 3%, Cabify is targeting 2025 for full electrification for collaborating fleets in Spain, and 2030 in Latin America. The company is collaborating with a number of stakeholders, including IDB Invest, the Ministry of Energy in Chile and car brands to test suitable EV models.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;This common journey to the general adoption of EVs entails tackling a number of urban and sector-wide challenges such as the scarcity of EV models that are autonomy-wise compatible with ride-hailing services, battery life spans, legal certainty in access to credit or the characteristics and availability of charging points,&#8221; said Barrueco.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uMSWzwEuX9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/will-ride-hailing-profits-ever-come/">Will ride-hailing profits ever come?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Will ride-hailing profits ever come?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/12/will-ride-hailing-profits-ever-come/embed/#?secret=uMSWzwEuX9" data-secret="uMSWzwEuX9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/cabify-launches-cabify-go-a-multi-modal-subscription-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2161921</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chinese lidar maker Hesai lands $300M led by Hillhouse, Xiaomi, Meituan</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/china-lidar-hesai-300-million-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/china-lidar-hesai-300-million-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 04:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baidu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bosch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hillhouse Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lidar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lightspeed Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meituan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qiming Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shanghai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temasek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Xiaomi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162808</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The rush to back lidar companies continues as more automakers and robotaxi startups include the remote sensing method in their vehicles. Latest to the investment boom is Hesai, a Shanghai-based lidar maker founded in 2014 with an office in Palo Alto. The company just raised over $300 million in a Series D funding round led [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The rush to back lidar companies continues as more automakers and robotaxi startups include the remote sensing method in their vehicles.</p>
<p>Latest to the investment boom is Hesai, a Shanghai-based lidar maker founded in 2014 with an office in Palo Alto. The company just raised over $300 million in a Series D funding round led by GL Ventures, the venture capital arm of storied private equity firm Hillhouse Capital, smartphone maker Xiaomi, on-demand services giant Meituan and CPE, the private equity platform of Citic.</p>
<p>Hesai <a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/SIj9Hh7X2qzFauVX9mnFEA">said</a> the new proceeds will be spent on mass-producing its hybrid solid-state lidar for its OEM customers, the construction of its smart manufacturing center, and research and development on automotive-grade lidar chips. The company said it has accumulated &#8220;several hundred million dollars&#8221; in funding to date.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Other participants in the round included Huatai Securities, Lightspeed China Partners and Lightspeed Venture Capital, as well as Qiming Venture Partners. Bosch, Baidu, and ON Semiconductor are also among its shareholders.</p>
<p>Another Chinese lidar startup Innovusion, a major supplier to electric vehicle startup Nio, raised a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/innovusion-64-millions-series-b/">$64 million round led by Temasek</a> in May. Livox is another emerging lidar maker that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/innovusion-64-millions-series-b/">was an offshoot of DJI</a>.</p>
<p>Lidar isn&#8217;t limited to powering robotaxis and passenger EVs, and that&#8217;s why Hesai got Xiaomi and Meituan onboard. Xiaomi makes hundreds of different connected devices through its manufacturing suppliers that could easily benefit from industrial automation, to which sensing technology is critical. But the phone maker also unveiled plans this year to<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/xiaomi-ev-subsidiary/"> make electric cars</a>.</p>
<p>Meituan, delivering food to hundreds of millions of consumers in China, could similarly benefit from replacing human riders with<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/meituan-jd-com-and-neolix-begin-autonomous-deliveries-in-beijing/"> lidar-enabled unmanned vans and drones</a>.</p>
<p>Hesai, with a staff of over 500 employees, says its clients span 70 cities across 23 countries. The company touts Nuro, Bosch, Lyft, Navya, and Chinese robotaxi operators Baidu, WeRide and AutoX among its customers. <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Last year, it kickstarted a </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/22/scale-ai-releases-free-lidar-dataset-to-power-self-driving-car-development/">partnership with Scale AI</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, a data labeling company, to launch an open-source data set for training autonomous driving algorithms, with data collected using Hesai&#8217;s lidar in California. </span></p>
<p>Last July, Hesai and lidar technology pioneer Velodyne <a href="https://www.hesaitech.com/en/media/46">entered a long-term licensing agreement</a> as the two dismissed legal proceedings in the U.S., Germany and China.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="N16XuxZR75"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/innovusion-64-millions-series-b/">Lidar startup Innovusion closes $64M round led by Temasek</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lidar startup Innovusion closes $64M round led by Temasek&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/innovusion-64-millions-series-b/embed/#?secret=N16XuxZR75" data-secret="N16XuxZR75" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/china-lidar-hesai-300-million-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162808</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple&#8217;s new encrypted browsing feature won&#8217;t be available in China, Saudi Arabia and more: report</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-private-relay-unavailable-in-china/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-private-relay-unavailable-in-china/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 02:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[belarus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colombia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Craig Federighi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firewall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[great firewall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet censorship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[isp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kazakhstan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philippines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vpn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple announced a handful of privacy-focused updates at its annual software developer conference on Monday. One called Private Relay particularly piques the interest of Chinese users living under the country&#8217;s censorship system, for it encrypts all browsing history so nobody can track or intercept the data. As my colleague Roman Dillet explains: When Private Relay [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple announced a handful of privacy-focused updates at its annual software developer conference on Monday. One called Private Relay particularly piques the interest of Chinese users living under the country&#8217;s censorship system, for it encrypts all browsing history so nobody can track or intercept the data.</p>
<p>As my colleague Roman Dillet <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-announces-icloud-with-privacy-focused-features/">explains</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>When Private Relay is turned on, nobody can track your browsing history — not your internet service provider, anyone standing in the middle of your request between your device and the server you’re requesting information from. We’ll have to wait a bit to learn more about how it works exactly.</p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The excitement didn&#8217;t last long. Apple <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/apple-privacy/apples-new-private-relay-feature-will-not-be-available-in-china-idUSL2N2NP2UK">told Reuters</a> that Private Relay won&#8217;t be available in China alongside Belarus, Colombia, Egypt, Kazakhstan, Saudi Arabia, South Africa, Turkmenistan, Uganda and the Philippines.</p>
<p>Apple couldn&#8217;t be immediately reached by TechCrunch for comment.</p>
<p>Virtual private networks or VPNs are popular tools for users in China to bypass the &#8220;great firewall&#8221; censorship apparatus, accessing web services that are otherwise blocked or slowed down. But VPNs <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/free-vpn-bad-for-privacy/">don&#8217;t necessarily protect users&#8217; privacy</a> because they simply funnel all the traffic through VPN providers&#8217; servers instead of users&#8217; internet providers, so users are essentially entrusting VPN firms with protecting their identities. Private Relay, on the other hand, doesn&#8217;t even allow Apple to see one&#8217;s browsing activity.</p>
<p>In an <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90643627/apple-privacy-wwdc-private-relay-vpn-icloud-plus-macos-monterey">interview</a> with Fast Company, Craig Federighi, Apple&#8217;s senior vice president of software engineering, explained why the new feature may be superior to VPNs:</p>
<p>&#8220;We hope users believe in Apple as a trustworthy intermediary, but we didn’t even want you to have to trust us [because] we don’t have this ability to simultaneously source your IP and the destination where you’re going to–and that’s unlike VPNs. And so we wanted to provide many of the benefits that people are seeking when in the past they’ve decided to use a VPN, but not force that difficult and conceivably perilous privacy trade-off in terms of trusting it a single intermediary.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s unclear whether Private Relay will simply be excluded from system upgrades for users in China and the other countries where it&#8217;s restricted, or it will be blocked by internet providers in those regions. It also remains to be seen whether the feature will be available to Apple users in Hong Kong, which has seen an <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-hong-kong-security-censorship-idUSKBN29K0ZM">increase in online censorship</a> in the past year.</p>
<p>Like all Western tech firms operating in China, Apple is trapped between antagonizing Beijing and flouting the values it espouses at home. Apple has a history of caving in to Beijing&#8217;s censorship pressure, from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/tesla-china-user-data-storage/">migrating all user data in China </a>to a state-run cloud center, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/07/29/apple-removes-vpn-apps-from-the-app-store-in-china/">cracking down on independent VPN apps</a> in China, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/04/apple-restricts-chinese-podcasts/">limiting free speech in Chinese podcasts</a>, to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/apple-removes-two-rss-feed-readers-from-china-app-store/">removing RSS feed readers from the China App Store</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="J5xCN4EYrU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/free-vpn-bad-for-privacy/">Free VPNs are bad for your privacy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Free VPNs are bad for your privacy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/free-vpn-bad-for-privacy/embed/#?secret=J5xCN4EYrU" data-secret="J5xCN4EYrU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-private-relay-unavailable-in-china/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162797</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 career options for ex-founders seeking their next adventure</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/6-career-options-for-ex-founders-seeking-their-next-adventure/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/6-career-options-for-ex-founders-seeking-their-next-adventure/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 23:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[angel investing tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Becoming an Angel Investor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consulting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consulting networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expert networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[founder advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scout programs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162624</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As someone with "founder" on your resume, you face a greater challenge when trying to get a salaried job. You’ve already shown that you really want to lead a company and not just rise up the ladder.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">David Teten</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/dteten">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		David Teten is founder of <a href="https://versatilevc.com/">Versatile VC</a> and writes periodically at <a href="https://teten.com/">teten.com</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/dteten">@dteten</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/how-to-win-consulting-board-and-deal-roles-with-pe-and-vc-funds/">How to win consulting, board and deal roles with PE and VC funds</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/5-innovative-fundraising-methods-for-emerging-vcs-and-pes/">5 innovative fundraising methods for emerging VCs and PEs</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Hey, founders between gigs: What now?</p>
<p>If you exited your last company for airplane money and are now independently wealthy, congratulations! If you want to build another company, just self-fund. If you want outside capital, VCs will chase after you to invest.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, most founders are not in that position: <a href="https://www.failory.com/blog/startup-failure-rate">nine out of 10 startups fail</a>. Even if you achieve a high valuation, you might end up like <a href="https://www.legalsportsreport.com/21742/fanduel-founders-common-shareholders-get-nothing-in-ppb-deal/">FanDuel</a>’s founders: Their investors got the benefit of a $465 million exit; the founders got zero.</p>
<p>As someone with &#8220;founder&#8221; on your resume, you face a greater challenge when trying to get a traditional salaried job. You’ve already shown that you really want to lead a company and not just rise up the ladder, which means some employers are <a href="https://twitter.com/jstrauss/status/1388909396034408452?s=11">less likely</a> to hire you. One research <a href="https://journals.aom.org/doi/abs/10.5465/AMBPP.2020.90">paper</a> found:</p>
<blockquote><p>[F]ormer founders receive fewer callbacks than non-founders; however, all founders are not disadvantaged similarly. Former founders of successful ventures receive <strong>even fewer </strong>[emphasis added] callbacks than former founders of failed ventures. Through 20 interviews with technical recruiters, we highlight the mechanisms driving this founder-experience discount: concerns related to the applicant&#8217;s capability and ability to fit into and remain committed to the wage employment and the hiring firm.</p></blockquote>
<p>At my prior firm, ff Venture Capital, we invested in a company co-founded by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nathan-jenkins-1a09b2172/">Nate Jenkins</a>, who had a successful exit, but not quite enough to buy a private plane. He’s now researching his next opportunity and interviewing for some jobs. At the end of a recent interview, the interviewer summarized, &#8220;I&#8217;ll hire you, but is this what you really want to do?&#8221;</p>
<p>That said, Samuel Sabin, CEO of <a href="https://www.hireblue.co/">HireBlue</a>, observed, “Some founders who work better with more resources at their disposal may be tapped for intrapreneurship roles. Also, some companies value a self-starter mentality.”</p>
<p>So what should you do? Especially if your life partner and/or bank account are burnt out on the income volatility of startups?</p>
<p>I’ve been in this situation myself when I shut down one startup and exited two others. I think you have six main options:</p>
<h3>Full-time initiatives</h3>
<ol>
<li>Launch a new company.</li>
<li>Get a job.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Part-time activities</h3>
<ol>
<li>Angel investing, venture capital and mentoring.</li>
<li>Consulting.</li>
<li>Sell information products.</li>
<li>Education and self-improvement.</li>
</ol>
<p>At <a href="http://versatilevc.com">Versatile VC</a>, our new VC fund, we’re creating an online community just for founders who are in transition, <a href="https://versatilevc.com/fnm">Founders’ Next Move</a>. We hope you will join us!</p>
<h2>Full-time initiatives</h2>
<h3>Launch a new company</h3>
<p>If you want to work on your startup idea, the bar for starting a company should always be very high. VCs have a diversified portfolio and most of their investments die. You don’t have a diverse portfolio and so you’re taking far more risk than the VCs. For free resources to help research your ideas, see <a href="http://teten.com/mr">What startup will you build? Identifying market white space</a>.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/6-career-options-for-ex-founders-seeking-their-next-adventure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162624</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple finally launches a Screen Time API for app developers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-finally-launches-a-screen-time-api-for-app-developers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-finally-launches-a-screen-time-api-for-app-developers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 23:07:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile device]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile device management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[screen time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tim Cook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web traffic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WWDC 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162746</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just after the release of iOS 12 in 2018, Apple introduced its own built-in screen time tracking tools and controls. It then began cracking down on third-party apps that had implemented their own screen time systems, saying they had done so through technologies that risked user privacy. What wasn&#8217;t available at the time? A Screen [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Just after the release of iOS 12 in 2018, Apple <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/17/ios-12-is-now-available-to-download/">introduced</a> its own built-in screen time tracking tools and controls. It then began <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/05/apple-puts-third-party-screen-time-apps-on-notice/">cracking down</a> on third-party apps that had implemented their own screen time systems, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/28/apple-defends-its-takedown-of-some-apps-monitoring-screen-time/">saying they had done so</a> through technologies that risked user privacy. What wasn&#8217;t available at the time? A Screen Time API that would have allowed developers to tap into Apple&#8217;s own Screen Time system and build their own experiences that augmented its capabilities. That&#8217;s now changed.</p>
<p>At Apple&#8217;s Worldwide Developers Conference on Monday, it <a href="https://www.apple.com/ios/ios-15-preview/features/">introduced</a> a new Screen Time API that offers developer access to frameworks that will allow a parental control experience that also maintains user privacy.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Oh there’s a Screen Time API, nice <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WWDC21?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WWDC21</a> <a href="https://t.co/Et6lfs6g7X">pic.twitter.com/Et6lfs6g7X</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&mdash; Guilherme Rambo (@_inside) <a href="https://twitter.com/_inside/status/1401986759198658560?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 7, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The company added three new Swift <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/ManagedSettings?changes=latest_minor">frameworks</a> to the iOS SDK that will allow developers to create apps that help parents manage what a child can do across their devices and ensure those restrictions stay in place.</p>
<p>The apps that use this API will be able to set restrictions like locking accounts in place, preventing password changes, filtering web traffic and limiting access to applications. These sorts of changes are already available through Apple&#8217;s Screen Time system, but developers can now build their own experiences where these features are offered under their own branding and where they can then expand on the functionality provided by Apple&#8217;s system.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">ScreenTime API looks great, I sincerely hope someone provides me a way to bulk change stuff for my kids. If I had known I would have to tweak each kids ScreenTime individually like I do today, I might have had less children. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WWDC21?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WWDC21</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Stan Lemon (@stanlemon) <a href="https://twitter.com/stanlemon/status/1402023431487606789?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 7, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Developers&#8217; apps that take advantage of the API can also be locked in place so it can only be removed from the device with a parent&#8217;s approval.</p>
<p>The apps can authenticate the parents and ensure the device they&#8217;re managing belongs to a child in the family. Plus, Apple said the way the system will work lets parents choose the apps and websites they want to limit without compromising user privacy. (The system returns only opaque tokens instead of <a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/mdm/bundle-ids-for-native-ios-and-ipados-apps-mdm90f60c1ce/web">identifiers for the apps</a> and website URLs, Apple told developers, so the third-parties aren&#8217;t gaining access to private user data like app usage and web browsing details. This would prevent a shady company from building a Screen Time app only to collect troves of user data about app usage, for instance.)</p>
<p>The third-party apps can also create unique time windows for different apps or types of activities, and warn the child when time is nearly up. When it registers the time&#8217;s up, the apps lock down access to websites and apps and perhaps remind the child it&#8217;s time to do their homework &#8212; or whatever other experience the developer has in mind.</p>
<p>And on the flip side, the apps could create incentives for the child to gain screen time access after they complete some other task, like doing homework, reading or chores, or anything else.</p>
<p>Developers could use these features to design new experiences that Apple&#8217;s own Screen Time system doesn&#8217;t allow for today, by layering their own ideas on top of Apple&#8217;s basic set of controls. Parents would likely fork over their cash to make using Screen Time controls easier and more customized to their needs.</p>
<p>Other apps could tie into Screen Time too, outside of the &#8220;family&#8221; context &#8212; like those aimed at mental health and well-being, for example.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Oooh &#8211; an API for Screen Time! Definitely want to build support for this into Streaks, if possible.<a href="https://t.co/keuaJ6WFvo">https://t.co/keuaJ6WFvo</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/wwdc21?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#wwdc21</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Quentin Zervaas (@qzervaas) <a href="https://twitter.com/qzervaas/status/1401985372733665282?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 7, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Of course, developers have been asking for a Screen Time API since the launch of Screen Time itself, but Apple didn&#8217;t seem to prioritize its development until the matter of Apple&#8217;s removal of rival screen time apps was brought up in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/29/apple-ceo-tim-cook-questioned-over-app-stores-removal-of-rival-screen-time-apps-in-antitrust-hearing/">an antitrust hearing last year</a>. At the time, Apple CEO Tim Cook defended the company&#8217;s decision by explaining that apps had been using MDM (mobile device management) technology, which was designed for managing employee devices in the enterprise, not home use. This, he said, was a privacy risk.</p>
<p>Apple has a session during WWDC that will detail how the new API works, so we expect we&#8217;ll learn more soon as the developer info becomes more public.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/WWDC-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/wwdc-2021-banner.jpg" alt="read more about Apple's WWDC 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-finally-launches-a-screen-time-api-for-app-developers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162746</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: At Apple&#8217;s WWDC 2021 keynote, everything old is new again</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/daily-crunch-15/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/daily-crunch-15/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 22:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Today was the kickoff of Apple’s developer conference, WWDC, meaning that the TechCrunch crew was super busy all day and that we have an ocean of news from Cupertino for you to enjoy. But the startup market was just as busy, thankfully, with some fascinating funding rounds, acquisitions and more to parse through. Today we have something for everyone! &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<p>P.S. Including all of you interested in finance. Here’s a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/this-spac-is-betting-that-a-british-healthcare-company-can-shake-up-the-us-market/">teardown of the Babylon Health SPAC deal</a>. Enjoy!</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/live-from-apples-wwdc-2021-keynote/">Apple’s keynote lucre</a>:</strong> Apple’s keynote today was the usual affair of animation, on-screen text, musicals, and lots and lots of news. More below <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-unveils-ios-15-with-new-features-for-facetime-and-better-notifications/">but iOS 15</a></strong>, <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-introduces-shareplay-for-co-watching-streaming-and-screen-sharing-over-facetime/">SharePlay</a></strong> and <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-announces-icloud-with-privacy-focused-features/">iCloud+</a></strong> are obvious standouts.</li>
<li><strong>The global chip shortage: </strong>The global chip shortage won’t lift until <strong><a href="https://t.co/7N8zkc7TBE">late next year</a></strong>, meaning that we’re likely going to see investment in new chip-fab capacity. Like the news today that <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/bosch-opens-1-2-billion-chip-plant-in-germany/">Bosch opened a $1.2 billion chip manufacturing facility in Germany</a></strong>. Much like the AI market is cleaving along geopolitical fault lines, in time, more countries are going to want to have domestic chip-fab capabilities as a form of self-reliance.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/paytm-ipo-shareholders/">Paytm is going public</a>: </strong>Noida, India-based Paytm, the most valuable startup in the country, will go public, it told employees recently. That’s good news for the company, we suppose, but also potentially big news for India’s larger startup and venture capital scene.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups and VC</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/astra-to-acquire-electric-in-space-propulsion-company-apollo-fusion/"><strong>Astra buys Apollo Fusion</strong></a><strong>:</strong> This is a fun one. Astra, a space launch upstart that is pursuing a SPAC-led IPO, is buying Apollo Fusion, which is focused on what TechCrunch described as “electric propulsion.” So not fusion, sadly, but electric propulsion is a key space technology that allows satellites, for example, to move around while in orbit. It can also be fuel-sipping to a degree, making it a tech that could help satellites and other heavenly bodies enjoy long service lives.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/tiger-global-leads-30m-investment-into-briq-a-fintech-for-the-construction-industry/"><strong>Briq raises its construction-focused fintech service</strong></a><strong>:</strong> The recent implosion of construction-unicorn Katerra is not stopping venture investment in its market. Today Briq, a startup that provides fintech solutions to construction companies, announced that Tiger Global has led a $30 million round into its business. Normally a $30 million check would give us a good feel for how big Briq’s revenue base is today. But with market scuttlebutt indicating that Tiger is content to pour capital into companies with diminutive revenues, it’s hard to say. Briq told TechCrunch that its annual recurring revenue grew by 200% in the last year.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/mendel-raises-18m-to-tease-out-data-structure-from-medicines-disparate-document-trove/">Mendel raises $18M to structure unstructured medical data</a>:</strong> Every industry creates lots of data these days, but the medical industry sweats data like a first-time Peloton user. And, as you can imagine, most of the data that off-gases from the medical world is unstructured and generally a mess. Enter Mendel, which wants to organize, share and exchange medical data after it ingests and cleans it up. I dig it.</li>
<li>Finally today, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/lightspeed-buys-ecwid-for-500m-nuorder-for-425m-in-ongoing-e-commerce-consolidation-play/"><strong>Lightspeed has acquired</strong></a> “e-commerce platform Ecwid for $500 million, and NuOrder, a B2B ordering platform servicing wholesales, brands and retailers, for $425 million.” The Canadian point-of-sale provider has been busy buying startups in recent years, part of a larger roll-up strategy that it expects will accrete into an enticing package of services. Or, as the company put it, the deals will help Lightspeed become “the common thread uniting merchants, suppliers and consumers.” That’s pretty heavy on the corporate-speak, but does speak to Lightspeed’s ambitions. I raise this particular set of deals because Lightspeed is not as well known as its scale might have you think.</li>
</ul>
<h2>The hidden benefits of adding a CTO to your board</h2>
<p>Conventional wisdom says startup boards should include a few CEOs who are able to offer informed advice, but having a technical leader in the mix creates real upside, according to Abby Kearns, chief technology officer at Puppet.</p>
<p>Beyond their engineering experience, CTOs can help founders set realistic timelines, identify pain points and bring what Kearns calls &#8220;pragmatic empathy&#8221; to high-pressure situations.</p>
<p>&#8220;A CTO understands the nuts and bolts,&#8221; says Kearns.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Qc3I9YQObA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/the-hidden-benefits-of-adding-a-cto-to-your-board/">The hidden benefits of adding a CTO to your board</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The hidden benefits of adding a CTO to your board&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/the-hidden-benefits-of-adding-a-cto-to-your-board/embed/#?secret=Qc3I9YQObA" data-secret="Qc3I9YQObA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> <em>You can sign up here</em></a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>As noted above, there’s a lot of Apple news to dig through, but we also have notes from Microsoft and Pinterest to parse. So let’s get done with WWDC and then dive into the rest.</p>
<p>Today’s Apple event generated oodles of coverage. Here’s what you need to know (products bolded to help you find what you need):</p>
<ul>
<li>TechCrunch’s liveblog of the event <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/live-from-apples-wwdc-2021-keynote/">can be found here</a>. It’s, as always, fun and fast and funny.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-unveils-ios-15-with-new-features-for-facetime-and-better-notifications/">Apple unveils <strong>iOS 15</strong> with new features for FaceTime and better notifications</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-refines-ios-15-notifications-with-focus-summary-features/">Apple refines <strong>iOS 15</strong> notifications with Focus, Summary features</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-introduces-shareplay-for-co-watching-streaming-and-screen-sharing-over-facetime/">Apple introduces <strong>SharePlay</strong> for co-watching, streaming and screen sharing over FaceTime</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-announces-facetime-updates-at-wwdc-2021/">Apple announces <strong>FaceTime</strong> updates</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apples-live-text-lets-you-interact-with-text-in-your-photos/">Apple’s <strong>Live Text</strong> lets you interact with text in your photos</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-maps-upgrade-brings-more-detailed-maps-transit-features-ar-view-and-more/"><strong>Apple Maps</strong> upgrade brings more detailed maps, transit features, AR view and more</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-finally-updates-its-weather-app-with-dynamic-backgrounds-maps-and-way-more-data/">Apple (finally) updates its <strong>weather app</strong> with dynamic backgrounds, maps and way more data</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/ipados-15-announced-at-wwdc-features-improved-multitasking-and-improved-swift-playgrounds-support/"><strong>iPadOS 15</strong> announced at WWDC, features improved multitasking and surprising Swift Playgrounds features</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-announces-icloud-with-privacy-focused-features/">Apple announces <strong>iCloud+</strong> with privacy-focused features</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/watchos-8-brings-new-mindfulness-features-and-respiratory-tracking/"><strong>watchOS 8</strong> brings new mindfulness features and respiratory tracking</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-unveils-macos-12-monterey/">Apple unveils <strong>macOS 12 Monterey</strong></a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-wwdc-2021-privacy-security/">Apple unveils new <strong>iOS 15 privacy features</strong> at WWDC</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-is-bringing-shortcuts-to-the-mac-and-starts-transition-from-automator/">Apple is bringing <strong>Shortcuts</strong> to the Mac and starts transition from <strong>Automator</strong></a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-tv-to-support-using-homepod-mini-as-speakers-among-other-updates/"><strong>Apple TV</strong> to support using HomePod Mini as speakers, among other updates</a></li>
</ul>
<p>And there’s more to come. So, if that’s not enough from the Apple news column for you, keep your eyes on the site.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/WWDC-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/wwdc-2021-banner.jpg" alt="read more about Apple's WWDC 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
<h2>Elsewhere in BigTechLandia</h2>
<p>Pinterest is finally <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/pinterest-adds-a-shopping-list-feature-to-round-up-your-saved-products/"><strong>rolling out the ability</strong></a> to save items into a shopping list. The general argument for the long-term value of Pinterest has been that, sure, it has ads, but it’s also essentially an e-commerce sleeping giant. Perhaps Big Pin wants to awaken a bit faster than we had expected.</p>
<p>To close, Microsoft is <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/microsofts-windows-virtual-desktop-is-now-azure-virtual-desktop/">renaming Windows Virtual Desktop to Azure Virtual Desktop</a></strong>. Why the change? Because, loosely, there’s lots more demand for the product in a post-pandemic world than the one that came before it, and thus the ability to “set up a full virtual desktop environment from the Azure portal” using only “a few clicks,” as Frederic reported, could be a big deal.</p>
<h2>Community</h2>
<p>What were you looking forward to the most at WWDC? <a href="https://twitter.com/TechCrunch/status/1401923333638270978">You told us iOS updates</a>. And <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-the-wwdc-2021-keynote/">there are a bunch</a>. Come <a href="https://discord.gg/c69vr5QT">chat on the Discord server</a> about what Apple did (and didn’t) announce.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/">TechCrunch Sessions: Mobility</a> is happening this Wednesday, and there’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/#tickets">still time to buy tickets</a>. On the fence? Come <a href="https://twitter.com/i/spaces/1MYxNmkVBpPJw">hang out with us tomorrow on Twitter Spaces at 4 p.m. PDT/7 p.m. EDT</a> to get a taste of what you’ll experience at the event.</p>
<p>Speaking of events, keep an eye on <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com">the site</a> for some Pittsburgh Spotlight-related news tomorrow.</p>
<h2>TC Eventful</h2>
<p>Whether you’re into artificial intelligence, autonomous and/or electric vehicles, robotics or hunting the next transportation unicorn, you’ll want to make sure you’re at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021?promo=dailycrunch50&amp;display=true">TechCrunch’s Sessions: Mobility</a> event this Wednesday, June 9. Bring your questions and join the conversation with CEOs and founders from Scale AI, Ford, Joby Aviation and Hyundai and discover 30 of the hottest early-stage mobility startups poised to become the next big thing. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021?promo=dailycrunch50&amp;display=true">Register today</a> and get a free expo ticket with promo code <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021?promo=dailyexpo&amp;display=true">DAILYEXPO</a>. Or save 50% for access to the entire event with promo code <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021?promo=dailycrunch50&amp;display=true">DAILYCRUNCH50</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/daily-crunch-15/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162623</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter restricts accounts in India to comply with government legal request</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/twitter-restricts-accounts-in-india-to-comply-with-government-legal-request/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/twitter-restricts-accounts-in-india-to-comply-with-government-legal-request/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 21:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162702</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter disclosed on Monday that it blocked four accounts in India to comply with a new legal request from the Indian government. The American social network disclosed on Lumen Database, a Harvard University project, that it took action on four accounts &#8212; including those of hip-hop artist L-Fresh the Lion and singer and song-writer Jazzy [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter disclosed on Monday that it blocked four accounts in India to comply with a new legal request from the Indian government.</p>
<p>The American social network <a href="https://www.lumendatabase.org/notices/24019321">disclosed</a> on Lumen Database, a Harvard University project, that it took action on four accounts &#8212; including those of hip-hop artist L-Fresh the Lion and singer and song-writer Jazzy B &#8212; to comply with a legal request from the Indian government it received over the weekend. The accounts are geo-restricted within India but accessible from outside of the South Asian nation. (As part of their transparency efforts, some companies including Twitter and Google make requests and orders they receive from governments and other entities public on Lumen Database.)</p>
<p>All four accounts, like several others that the Indian government ordered to be <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/twitter-restricts-over-a-dozen-high-profile-accounts-in-india-following-legal-demand/">blocked in the country earlier this year</a>, had protested New Delhi’s agriculture reforms and some had posted other tweets that criticized Prime Minister Narendra Modi’s seven years of governance in India, an analysis by TechCrunch found.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A Twitter spokesperson told TechCrunch that when the company receives a valid legal request, it reviews it under both its own rules and local laws.</p>
<p>“If the content violates Twitter’s Rules, the content will be removed from the service. If it is determined to be illegal in a particular jurisdiction, but not in violation of the Twitter Rules, we may withhold access to the content in India only. In all cases, we notify the account holder directly so they’re aware that we’ve received a legal order pertaining to the account,” the spokesperson added.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2162748 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/jazzb-twitter-india-block.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="367" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/jazzb-twitter-india-block.jpg 1546w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/jazzb-twitter-india-block.jpg?resize=150,81 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/jazzb-twitter-india-block.jpg?resize=300,162 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/jazzb-twitter-india-block.jpg?resize=768,414 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/jazzb-twitter-india-block.jpg?resize=680,367 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/jazzb-twitter-india-block.jpg?resize=1536,829 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/jazzb-twitter-india-block.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>The new legal request, which hasn&#8217;t been previously reported, comes at a time when Twitter is making efforts to comply with the Indian government’s new IT rules, new guidelines that several of its peers including Facebook and Google have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/28/facebook-whatsapp-google-and-other-internet-giants-comply-with-indias-it-rules/">already complied with</a>.</p>
<p>On Saturday, India’s Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology had given a “final notice” to Twitter to comply with its new rules, which it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/india-announces-sweeping-guidelines-for-social-media-on-demand-streaming-firms-and-digital-news-outlets/">unveiled in February this year</a>. The new rules require significant social media firms to appoint and share contact details of representatives tasked with compliance, nodal point of reference and grievance redressals to address on-ground concerns.</p>
<p>Tension has been brewing between Twitter and the government of India of late. Last month, police in Delhi visited Twitter offices to “serve a notice” about an investigation into its intel on classifying Indian politicians’ tweets as misleading. Twitter called the move <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/twitter-says-concerned-with-india-intimidation-requests-3-more-months-to-comply-with-new-it-rules/">a form of intimidation</a>, and expressed concerns for its employees and requested the government respect citizens’ rights to free speech.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wzlnphi8JX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/twitter-says-concerned-with-india-intimidation-requests-3-more-months-to-comply-with-new-it-rules/">Twitter says it&#8217;s concerned with India intimidation, requests 3 more months to comply with new IT rules</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter says it&#8217;s concerned with India intimidation, requests 3 more months to comply with new IT rules&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/twitter-says-concerned-with-india-intimidation-requests-3-more-months-to-comply-with-new-it-rules/embed/#?secret=wzlnphi8JX" data-secret="wzlnphi8JX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Late last month, Twitter had requested New Delhi to extend the deadline for compliance with the new rules by at least three months.</p>
<p>The Jack Dorsey-led company has grappled with several tough situations in India, one of its biggest market by users, this year. After briefly complying with a New Delhi order early this year, the company faced heat from the government for restoring accounts that had posted <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/twitter-takes-actions-on-over-500-accounts-in-india-amid-government-warning/">tweets critical of the Indian government’s policy</a> or Prime Minister Narendra Modi.</p>
<p>The two faced off again publicly in April after New Delhi ordered Twitter and Facebook to take down posts that were <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/24/india-orders-twitter-to-take-down-tweets-critical-of-its-coronavirus-handling/">critical of the government’s handling of the coronavirus pandemic</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HZqOY4ecE3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/24/india-orders-twitter-to-take-down-tweets-critical-of-its-coronavirus-handling/">India orders Twitter and Facebook to take down posts critical of its coronavirus handling</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;India orders Twitter and Facebook to take down posts critical of its coronavirus handling&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/24/india-orders-twitter-to-take-down-tweets-critical-of-its-coronavirus-handling/embed/#?secret=HZqOY4ecE3" data-secret="HZqOY4ecE3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/twitter-restricts-accounts-in-india-to-comply-with-government-legal-request/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162702</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tesla&#8217;s head of heavy duty trucking has left the company</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/the-executive-in-charge-of-the-tesla-semi-has-left-the-company/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/the-executive-in-charge-of-the-tesla-semi-has-left-the-company/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 21:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jerome Guillen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tesla electric truck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162680</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jerome Guillen, a critical executive at Tesla who was working on the development and eventual production of the Tesla Semi, has left the company, the automaker said Monday in a filing to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. Guillen&#8217;s departure comes just three months after he was moved from the president of automotive position, which [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Jerome Guillen, a critical executive at Tesla who was working on the development and eventual production of the Tesla Semi, has left the company, the automaker said Monday in a <a href="https://sec.report/Document/0001564590-21-031976/">filing to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission</a>.</p>
<p>Guillen&#8217;s departure comes just three months after he was moved from the president of automotive position, which included oversight of the Tesla Semi, to a role with less responsibility as head of heavy duty trucking. Guillen had led Tesla&#8217;s entire automotive business from September 2018 until March 2021.</p>
<p>Guillen had a decade-long career at Tesla and held numerous roles at the company. He started at Tesla in 2010 and reported directly to CEO Elon Musk as the program director of the Model S and soon was given more responsibility, including as VP of vehicle engineering. He was later appointed president of automotive before becoming president of heavy duty trucking in March 2021. Guillen is a former Daimler executive who was responsible for the development of the company&#8217;s new generation of Class 8 trucks.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Tesla Semi, a battery electric semi-truck, is still in development. The company first revealed the Tesla Semi in November 2017. It had been slated to go into production by 2019, but it has continued to be pushed back. It&#8217;s unclear if Guillen&#8217;s departure will further delay the Semi.</p>
<p>In January, Tesla CEO Elon Musk said during the company&#8217;s 2020 Q4 earnings call that all engineering work on the semi had been completed and that it expected to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/elon-musk-says-tesla-semi-is-ready-for-production-but-limited-by-battery-cell-output/">begin deliveries in 2021</a>. The availability of battery cells was the only issue limiting the vehicle&#8217;s production, Musk said at the time. Three months later, Tesla didn&#8217;t provide much of a progress report except to say the semi was in development.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="k4BNZ7zqIh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/elon-musk-says-tesla-semi-is-ready-for-production-but-limited-by-battery-cell-output/">Elon Musk says Tesla Semi is ready for production, but limited by battery cell output</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Elon Musk says Tesla Semi is ready for production, but limited by battery cell output&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/elon-musk-says-tesla-semi-is-ready-for-production-but-limited-by-battery-cell-output/embed/#?secret=k4BNZ7zqIh" data-secret="k4BNZ7zqIh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Earlier this month, the company announced that the first Tesla Semi Megacharger would be installed at Frito-Lay’s Modesto, California delivery center. The Megacharger charging stations will be capable of serving up to 100 Tesla Semi trucks.</p>
<p>It was <a href="https://electrek.co/2021/03/30/tesla-semi-production-line-new-nevada-building-electric-trucks-per-week/">reported</a> earlier this year that Tesla is building a new production line for its Semi model near its Nevada Gigafactory location, with the aim of producing five semi-trucks per week.</p>
<p><em>Developing &#8230;</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/the-executive-in-charge-of-the-tesla-semi-has-left-the-company/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162680</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Announcing the Early Stage Pitch-Off judges</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/announcing-the-early-stage-pitch-off-judges-2/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/announcing-the-early-stage-pitch-off-judges-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neesha A. Tambe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 21:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ben Sun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[early stage pitch-off]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leah Solivan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shardul Shah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Early Stage 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162230</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TechCrunch Early Stage Part Two is set to take place July 8th and 9th. You can still shoot your shot to pitch to an amazing panel of judges and thousands of TC viewers. TechCrunch editors will select 10 founders from around the world to pitch on stage July 9th. Apply here. Startups will have five [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/">TechCrunch Early Stage</a> Part Two is set to take place July 8th and 9th. You can still <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/N4qcpnuC">shoot your shot</a> to pitch to an amazing panel of judges and thousands of TC viewers. TechCrunch editors will select 10 founders from around the world to pitch on stage July 9th. <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/N4qcpnuC"><strong>Apply here</strong></a>.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary">Startups will have five minutes to pitch their companies, business models and innovative ideas &#8212; followed by a Q&amp;A with our superb panel of judges. The winner will get a feature article on TechCrunch.com, one-year free subscription to Extra Crunch and a complimentary Founder Pass to TechCrunch Disrupt this fall.</p>
<p>TechCrunch Early Stage Part Two is set to be a game-changer for founders looking to take their startups to the next level. At this two-day virtual event, early-stage founders can take part in highly interactive group sessions with top investors and ecosystem experts, in fields ranging from fundraising and marketplace positioning, to growth marketing and content development.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Without further ado, here are your judges for the Early Stage Pitch-Off:</p>
<p><strong>Ben Sun, Primary Venture Partners</strong></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2162676" style="width: 150px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162676" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2162676" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ben-Sun.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="140" height="140" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ben-Sun.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ben-Sun.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ben-Sun.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ben-Sun.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ben-Sun.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ben-Sun.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ben-Sun.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ben-Sun.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ben-Sun.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ben-Sun.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Ben-Sun.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 140px) 100vw, 140px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162676" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Primary Venture Partners</p></div></p>
<p>Ben is a co-founder and general partner at Primary Venture Partners. He has been a serial entrepreneur and investor as a co-founder of LaunchTime, an incubator and investor in early-stage tech startups and as a co-founder of Community Connect, which was one of the first social networking companies. Ben focuses his investing activities on primarily consumer-facing companies. His previous investments include Coupang, Jet.com, MakeSpace, Ollie, Mirror, Slice, Bounce Exchange, Selfmade, Shoptalk and Penrose Hill. Ben has been active in the NYC tech community for almost 20 years. Prior to working as an entrepreneur and investor, Ben worked at Merrill Lynch in the Technology Investment Banking Group. He graduated from the University of Michigan with a degree in Economics.</p>
<p><strong>Leah Solivan, Fuel Capital</strong></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2162675" style="width: 150px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162675" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2162675" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Leah-Solivan-1.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="140" height="140" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Leah-Solivan-1.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Leah-Solivan-1.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Leah-Solivan-1.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Leah-Solivan-1.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Leah-Solivan-1.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Leah-Solivan-1.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Leah-Solivan-1.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Leah-Solivan-1.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Leah-Solivan-1.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Leah-Solivan-1.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Leah-Solivan-1.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 140px) 100vw, 140px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162675" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits: </strong>Leah Solivan</p></div></p>
<p>Leah Solivan is general partner at Fuel Capital, where she invests in early-stage companies across consumer technology, hardware, marketplaces and retail. She’s passionate about supporting teams who are taking on world-changing ideas. Leah relates so well to founders because she is one herself. She created one of the most widely recognized consumer brands of the past decade with TaskRabbit. As TaskRabbit’s CEO for eight years, Leah scaled the company to 44 cities and raised more than $50 million. In 2016, Leah transitioned into the role of executive chairwoman and in 2017, TaskRabbit was acquired by IKEA.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Shardul Shah, Index Ventures</strong></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2162674" style="width: 151px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162674" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2162674" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Shardul-Shah.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="141" height="141" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Shardul-Shah.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Shardul-Shah.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Shardul-Shah.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Shardul-Shah.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Shardul-Shah.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Shardul-Shah.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Shardul-Shah.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Shardul-Shah.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Shardul-Shah.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Shardul-Shah.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Shardul-Shah.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 141px) 100vw, 141px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162674" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Index Ventures</p></div></p>
<p>Shardul joined Index in 2008. He focuses on security, cloud infrastructure and enterprise software investments. He is a director of Attack IQ, Brightback, Castle Intelligence, Datadog (Nasdaq:DDOG), Expel, Gatsby and Wiz.io. Shardul was previously a director of Adallom (Microsoft), SourceClear (CA Technologies), Koality (Docker), Lacoon (Check Point), Base (Zendesk) and an investor in Duo Security (Cisco). After graduating from the University of Chicago, Shardul worked with Summit Partners where he focused on healthcare and internet technologies.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/announcing-the-early-stage-pitch-off-judges-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162230</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>After contentious debate, FDA approves first Alzheimer&#8217;s drug since 2003</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/after-contentious-debate-fda-approves-first-alzheimers-drug-since-2003/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/after-contentious-debate-fda-approves-first-alzheimers-drug-since-2003/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Betuel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 21:04:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alzheimer's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drug discovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life Sciences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pharmaceuticals]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162591</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Monday, the US Food and Drug Administration granted approval to a keenly-watched Alzheimer’s drug, aducanumab, developed by the drugmaker Biogen. The decision to approve the drug, which was once abandoned as a failure, has been the subject of debate within the scientific and regulatory community for months. Aducanumab, which will be marketed as Aduhelm, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Monday, the US Food and Drug Administration granted approval to a keenly-watched Alzheimer’s drug, aducanumab, developed by the drugmaker Biogen. The decision to approve the drug, which was once abandoned as a failure, has been the subject of debate within the scientific and regulatory community for months.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aducanumab, which will be marketed as Aduhelm, is the first novel Alzheimer’s treatment to be approved since 2003, the FDA noted in a press release. Aducanumab is also the first novel treatment designed to address </span><a href="https://www.nia.nih.gov/health/what-happens-brain-alzheimers-disease"><span style="font-weight: 400;">one of several</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> proposed underlying causes of Alzheimer’s: the buildup of beta-amyloid plaques in the brain that disrupt the communication of neurons. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Critically, the drug received a conditional form of FDA approval called the ‘<a href="https://www.fda.gov/drugs/information-health-care-professionals-drugs/accelerated-approval-program">Accelerated Approval Program.’</a> The accelerated approval pathway is designed to provide early access to drugs for serious conditions if they address markers of disease – even when the FDA has misgivings about the overall results of clinical trials. Because of this, Biogen will still have to conduct a post-approval confirmatory trial of aducanumab. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the drug does not work as intended, we can take steps to remove it from the market. But hopefully, we will see further evidence of benefit in the clinical trial and as greater numbers of people receive Aduhelm,” the FDA statement </span><a href="https://www.fda.gov/drugs/news-events-human-drugs/fdas-decision-approve-new-treatment-alzheimers-disease"><span style="font-weight: 400;">reads. </span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TechCrunch has contacted Biogen for comment on the upcoming confirmatory trial, and will update this story with Biogen’s response. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The use of the accelerated approval pathway is clearly intended to address lingering controversies that have plagued aducanumab in the months leading up to the FDA’s ruling. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In early-stage trials, there were promising signs that aducanumab might slow cognitive decline, a major Alzheimer’s symptom. In a 2016 </span><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nature19323"><span style="font-weight: 400;">trial</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> published in the journal </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nature</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, 125 patients with mild or moderate Alzheimer’s who received monthly infusions of the drug saw levels of plaques decrease, as did symptoms of cognitive decline. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The decline of the plaques in the brain were </span><a href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/laneur/article/PIIS1474-4422(19)30480-6/fulltext"><span style="font-weight: 400;">“robust and unquestionable”</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as one </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lancet Neurology </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">paper puts it, but the clinical findings were more modest – it wasn’t clear exactly how much people’s cognitive ability benefitted from the treatment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These early trials eventually led the FDA to allow the drug to skip phase 2 clinical trials, which are designed to identify dosages of the drug, and proceed directly to phase 3 clinical trials. This move was </span><a href="https://www.statnews.com/2021/05/30/if-the-fda-approves-biogens-alzheimers-treatment-i-wont-prescribe-it/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">criticized</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by some physicians. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Those phase 3 clinical trials, called </span><a href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT02477800"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ENGAGE</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT02484547"><span style="font-weight: 400;">EMERGE</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, have become the center of tension. Both trials tested monthly intravenous injections of the drug on about 1600 patients with early Alzheimer’s. In 2019, both trials were </span><a href="https://www.alzforum.org/news/research-news/biogeneisai-halt-phase-3-aducanumab-trials"><span style="font-weight: 400;">halted</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> because the drug didn’t appear to be slowing cognitive decline, the primary endpoint of the trials. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additional data analyzed in late 2019 from the EMERGE trial suggested that the drug was linked with a </span><a href="https://investors.biogen.com/static-files/5a31a1e3-4fbb-4165-921a-f0ccb1d64b65"><span style="font-weight: 400;">23 percent less</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> cognitive decline, compared to a placebo. There were side effects: namely swelling and inflammation of the brain. This was seen in about</span><a href="https://investors.biogen.com/static-files/8e58afa4-ba37-4250-9a78-2ecfb63b1dcb#page=17"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 40 percent</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of Phase 3 trial participants, though most were symptomatic and most of those with symptoms (headache, nausea, visual disturbances) resolved after 4-16 weeks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still, even the new data wasn’t enough to convince an independent FDA advisory committee, who, in November 2020 </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/06/health/aducanumab-alzheimers-drug-fda-panel.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">did not endorse</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> approval of the drug. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Monday, The FDA, </span><a href="https://www.fda.gov/drugs/news-events-human-drugs/fdas-decision-approve-new-treatment-alzheimers-disease"><span style="font-weight: 400;">argued</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that the drug’s effects on </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">beta-amyloid plaques</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> were strong enough to suggest that benefit outweighed the risk. Critically, the FDA did not comment on the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">strength of clinical outcomes</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> – in short, the agency </span><a href="https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2021/761178s000lbl.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">is basing this approval</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on the drug’s ability to address beta-amyloid plaques, not how well each patient cognitive function responds to the drug. The followup study will need to address that outcome directly. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still, about </span><a href="https://www.fda.gov/drugs/news-events-human-drugs/fdas-decision-approve-new-treatment-alzheimers-disease"><span style="font-weight: 400;">6 million people</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> have Alzheimer’s in the US, and patient organizations have rallied in response to this drug. </span><a href="https://twitter.com/alzassociation/status/1401922061816287236?s=10"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Alzheimer’s Association</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has hailed the drug as a “victory for people living with Alzheimer’s.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ahead of the FDA’s decision on Monday, it was clear that, should aducanumab be approved, it would soon become a “blockbuster drug.” The financial picture around the drug seems to support that idea. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Trading of Biogen shares were initially halted, but have since</span><a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=biogen+shares&amp;oq=biogen+shares&amp;aqs=chrome..69i57l2j69i59j0i271l2j69i60l3.1179j0j4&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> jumped</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 40 percent today, following the announcement. Shares of Eisai Co. Ltd, a Japanese company working with Biogen </span><a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=eisai+shares&amp;oq=eisai+shares&amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j0i67j35i39j0i20i131i263i433j0i67j46i175i199i433j69i60l2.1317j0j4&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8"><span style="font-weight: 400;">jumped over 46 percent</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the first three hours following the FDA’s approval. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Certainly, Biogen was banking on this approval as a long-term strategy. In an April 2021, </span><a href="https://investors.biogen.com/static-files/a957e5ba-325f-4a37-bfc8-43cecfc64620"><span style="font-weight: 400;">earnings presentation</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the company estimated that there were 600 sites ready to launch the treatment post-approval. Biogen has also submitted marketing authorization applications for aducanumab in Brazil, Canada, Switzerland and Australia. On June 7, the company announced that a year’s supply of the drug would </span><a href="https://investors.biogen.com/news-releases/news-release-details/biogen-and-eisai-launch-multiple-initiatives-help-patients"><span style="font-weight: 400;">cost $56,000</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the wider world of Alzheimer’s drugs, it’s possible other companies may see this approval as proof-of-concept for other drugs targeting beta amyloid plaques. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In an </span><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/537036a"><span style="font-weight: 400;">editorial</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that accompanied the 2016 </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nature </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">paper on aducanumab, Eric Reiman, executive director of Banner Alzheimer’s Institute, argued that scientific confirmation that beta-amyloid-targeted treatment slows cognitive decline would be a “game changer.&#8221; The aducanumab trials have been likened to a test of this idea. Speaking to </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Financial Times, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Howard Filit, founding executive director of the Alzheimer’s Drug Discovery Foundation, </span><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/972b44c8-76dc-4f13-9195-f93d467e646c?desktop=true&amp;segmentId=d8d3e364-5197-20eb-17cf-2437841d178a#myft:notification:instant-email:content"><span style="font-weight: 400;">called </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">aducanumab “the first rigorous test of the beta-amyloid hypothesis.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In that sense, conditional approval may indicate that the FDA is sympathetic to this form of Alzheimer’s treatment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There’s </span><a href="https://www.clinicaltrialsarena.com/analysis/alzheimers-biogen-eli-lilly-amyloid-targeting-therapy-fda-approval/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">at least one</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> more beta-amyloid targeted drug from a major drugmaker (Eli Lilly) clinical trials. We may see some more of them emerge soon, provided that Biogen’s confirmatory study of aducanumab doesn&#8217;t prompt the FDA to withdraw approval. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/after-contentious-debate-fda-approves-first-alzheimers-drug-since-2003/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162591</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple&#8217;s new App Store Guidelines aim to crack down on fraud and scams</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apples-new-app-store-guidelines-aim-to-crack-down-on-fraud-and-scams/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apples-new-app-store-guidelines-aim-to-crack-down-on-fraud-and-scams/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 20:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Epic Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Georgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iTunes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kosta Eleftheriou]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vpn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WWDC 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162090</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple today is releasing a new version of its App Store Review Guidelines, its lengthy document that dictates the rules that apps must abide by in order to be published to its App Store. Among the more notable changes rolling out today are several sections that will see Apple taking a harder stance on App [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple today is releasing a new version of its <a href="https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/">App Store Review Guidelines</a>, its lengthy document that dictates the rules that apps must abide by in order to be published to its App Store. Among the more notable changes rolling out today are several sections that will see Apple taking a harder stance on App Store fraud, scams and developer misconduct, including a new process that aims to empower other developers to hold bad actors accountable.</p>
<p>One of the key updates on this front involves a change to Apple&#8217;s Developer Code of Conduct (Sections 5.6 and 5.6.1-5.6.4 of the Review Guidelines).</p>
<p>This section has been significantly expanded to include guidance stating that repeated manipulative or misleading behavior or other fraudulent conduct will lead to the developer&#8217;s removal from the Apple Developer Program. This is something Apple has done for repeated violations, it claims, but wanted to now ensure it was clearly spelled out in the guidelines.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In an entirely new third paragraph in this section, Apple says that if a developer engages in activities or actions that are not in accordance with the developer code of conduct, they will have their Apple Developer account terminated.</p>
<p>It also details what, specifically, must be done to restore the account, which includes providing Apple with a written statement detailing the improvements they&#8217;ve made, which will have to be approved by Apple. If Apple is able to confirm the changes have been made, it may then restore the developer&#8217;s account.</p>
<p>Apple explained in a press briefing that this change was meant to prevent a sort of catch and release scenario where a developer gets caught by Apple, but then later reverts their changes to continue their bad behavior.</p>
<p>As part of this update, Apple added a new section about developer identity (5.6.2). This is meant to ensure the contact information for developers provided to Apple and customers is accurate and functional, and that the developer isn&#8217;t impersonating other, legitimate developers on the App Store. This was a particular issue in a high-profile incident of App Store fraud which involved a <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/03/30/trezor-scam-bitcoin-1-million/">crypto wallet app that scammed</a> a user out of his life&#8217;s savings (~$600,000) in Bitcoin. The scam victim had been deceived because the app was using the same name and icon as a different company that made a hardware crypto device, and because the scam app was rated five stars. (Illegitimately, that is.)</p>
<p>Related to this, Apple clarified the language around App Store discovery fraud (5.6.3) to more specifically call out any type of manipulations of App Store charts, search, reviews and referrals. The former would mean to crack down on the clearly booming industry of fake App Store ratings and reviews, which can send a scam app higher in charts and search.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the referral crackdown would address consumers being shown incorrect pricing outside the App Store in an effort to boost installs.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">There are hundreds of these. And then, there&#39;s hundreds of *real* ones too: <br /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br />&quot;SCAM. What shady business. Downloaded this app on concept. It doesn’t even work. There is no free version AT ALL. You are tricked into downloading and then asked to pay $7.99 per FREAKING WEEK. Wow.&quot;</p>
<p>&mdash; Kosta Eleftheriou (@keleftheriou) <a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1356011094070841348?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 31, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Another section (5.6.4) addresses issues that come up after an app is published, including negative customer reports and concerns and excessive refund rates, for example. If Apple notices this behavior, it will investigate the app for violations, it says.</p>
<p>Of course, the question here is: Will Apple actually notice the potential scammers? In recent months, a growing number of developers believe Apple is allowing far too many scammers to fall through the cracks of App Review.</p>
<p>One particular thorn in Apple&#8217;s side <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/apple-urged-to-root-out-rating-scams-as-developer-highlights-ugly-cost-of-enforcement-failure/">has been</a> Fleksy keyboard app founder Kosta Eleftheriou, who is not only suing Apple for the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/fleksy-co-founder-is-suing-apple-over-lost-revenue-resulting-from-app-store-scammers/">revenue he&#8217;s personally lost to scammers</a>, but also formed a sort of one-man bunco squad to expose some of the more egregious scams to date. This has included the above-mentioned crypto scam; a kids game that actually <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/04/15/app-store-scam-is-a-kids-game-with-a-hidden-online-casino/">contained a hidden online casino</a>; and a VPN app <a href="https://www.phonearena.com/news/another-ios-vpn-app-scam-is-uncovered_id131487">scamming users out of $5 million</a> per year, among many others.</p>
<p>The rampant fraud taking place on the App Store was also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/apple-downplays-complaints-about-app-store-scams-in-antitrust-hearing/">brought up during Apple&#8217;s antitrust hearing</a>, when Georgia’s Senator Jon Ossoff asked Apple’s Chief Compliance Officer Kyle Andeer why Apple was not able to locate scams, given they&#8217;re &#8220;trivially easy&#8221; to identify.</p>
<p>Apple downplayed the concerns then, and continues to do so through <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/05/app-store-stopped-over-1-5-billion-in-suspect-transactions-in-2020/">press releases like this one, which noted</a> how the App Store stopped over $1.5 billion in fraudulent transactions in 2020.</p>
<p>But a new update to these guidelines seems to be an admission that Apple may need a little help on this front. It says developers can now directly report possible violations they find in other developers&#8217; apps. Through a new form that standardizes this sort of complaint, developers can point to guideline violations and any other trust and safety issues they discover. Often, developers notice the scammers whose apps are impacting their own business and revenue, so they&#8217;ll likely turn to this form now as a first step in getting the scammer dealt with.</p>
<p>Another change will allow developers to appeal a rejection if they think there was unfair treatment of any kind, including political bias. Previously, Apple <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/31/21406112/apple-app-store-appeals-process-live-guidelines-challenge-antitrust-fortnite">had allowed developers</a> to appeal App Store decisions and suggest changes to guidelines.</p>
<p>Apple told us it has 500 app reviewers covering 81 languages who see new scenarios daily that have to be accounted for in updated guidelines and policies. Apple says it takes what it learns from these individual issues it encounters to invest in its systems, algorithms and training so it can prevent similar issues in the future. The company believes the new Code of Conduct rules, in particular, will give it the tools needed to better crack down on App Store fraud.</p>
<p>The rules about scams are only a handful of the many changes rolling out with today&#8217;s updated App Store Review Guidelines.</p>
<p>There are a few others, however, also worth highlighting:</p>
<ul>
<li>Apple clarified rules around &#8220;hookup&#8221; apps to ensure developers understand porn and prostitution are not allowed on the App Store &#8212; often an issue with the fly-by-night hookup apps, which bait and switch users.</li>
<li>Creator content apps are instructed that they must follow rules for user-generated content, when applicable, meaning they must have content blocking, reporting and robust moderation.</li>
<li>Apple added the ability for licensed pharmacies and licensed cannabis dispensaries to facilitate purchasing, provided they&#8217;re legal and geogated.</li>
<li>Apps that report criminal activity require the developers to work with local law enforcement. (Citizen is a recent example of an app gone awry <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447446/citizen-app-internal-slack-palisades-fire-arson-bounty-manhunt-los-angeles">when users hunted down the wrong person</a>. That level of carelessness may be coming to an end now.)</li>
<li>Bait-and-switch marketing and ads about app pricing isn&#8217;t allowed.</li>
<li>Cellular carrier apps can now include other kinds of subscription apps besides music and video services.</li>
<li>Apple clarifies that developers can communicate on email with anyone, but says they can&#8217;t target customers acquired through the App Store with messages about how to make purchases outside of the App Store.</li>
<li>Apple has enough drinking game apps. Stop sending them in.</li>
<li>Apps that offer account creation also have to offer account deletion.</li>
<li>Other clarity was added around in-app purchases for gift cards, app metadata, bug fix submissions and more. But these were not major changes.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/WWDC-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/wwdc-2021-banner.jpg" alt="read more about Apple's WWDC 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apples-new-app-store-guidelines-aim-to-crack-down-on-fraud-and-scams/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162090</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple releases torrent of updates, and Wall Street yawns</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-releases-torrent-of-updates-and-wall-street-yawns/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-releases-torrent-of-updates-and-wall-street-yawns/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 19:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LOL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stock market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wall street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WWDC 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162600</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today&#8217;s WWDC keynote from Apple covered a huge range of updates. From a new macOS to a refreshed watchOS to a new iOS, better privacy controls, FaceTime updates, and even iCloud+, there was something for everyone in the laundry list of new code. Apple&#8217;s keynote was essentially what happens when the big tech companies get [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today&#8217;s WWDC keynote from Apple <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-the-wwdc-2021-keynote/">covered a huge range of updates</a>. From <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-unveils-macos-12-monterey/">a new macOS</a> to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/watchos-8-brings-new-mindfulness-features-and-respiratory-tracking/">a refreshed watchOS</a> to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-unveils-ios-15-with-new-features-for-facetime-and-better-notifications/">a new iOS</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-wwdc-2021-privacy-security/">better privacy controls</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-announces-facetime-updates-at-wwdc-2021/">FaceTime updates</a>, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-announces-icloud-with-privacy-focused-features/">even iCloud+</a>, there was something for everyone in the laundry list of new code.</p>
<p>Apple&#8217;s keynote was essentially what happens when the big tech companies get huge; they have so many projects that they can&#8217;t just detail a few items. They have to run down their entire parade of platforms, dropping packets of news concerning each.</p>
<p>But despite the obvious indication that Apple has been hard at work on the critical software side of its business, especially its services-side (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-announces-icloud-with-privacy-focused-features/">more here</a>), Wall Street gave a firm, emphatic shrug.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/apple-event-fails-to-save-the-companys-stock-from-broader-market-sell-off/">is standard</a> but always slightly confusing.</p>
<p>Investors care about future cash flows, at least in theory. Those future cash flows come from anticipated revenues, which are born from product updates, driving growth in sales of services, software, and hardware. Which, apart from the hardware portion of the equation, is precisely what Apple detailed today.</p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #000000;">And lo, Wall Street looked upon the drivers of its future earnings estimates, and did sayeth &#8220;<em>lol, who really cares.&#8221;</em></span></strong></p>
<p>Shares of Apple were down a fraction for most of the day, picking up as time passed not thanks to the company&#8217;s news dump, but because the Nasdaq largely rose as trading raced to a close.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the Apple chart, <a href="http://ycharts.com">via YCharts</a>:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2162612 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AAPL_chart-3.png" alt="" width="850" height="503" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AAPL_chart-3.png 850w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AAPL_chart-3.png?resize=150,89 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AAPL_chart-3.png?resize=300,178 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AAPL_chart-3.png?resize=768,454 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AAPL_chart-3.png?resize=680,402 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AAPL_chart-3.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></p>
<p>And here&#8217;s the Nasdaq:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2162610" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/^IXIC_chart.png" alt="" width="850" height="523" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/^IXIC_chart.png 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/^IXIC_chart.png?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/^IXIC_chart.png?resize=300,185 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/^IXIC_chart.png?resize=768,473 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/^IXIC_chart.png?resize=680,419 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/^IXIC_chart.png?resize=1536,945 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/^IXIC_chart.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></p>
<p>Presuming that you are not a ChartMaster<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />, those might not mean much to you. Don&#8217;t worry. The charts say very little all-around so you are missing little. Apple was down a bit, and the Nasdaq up a bit. Then the Nasdaq went up more, and Apple&#8217;s stock generally followed. Which is good to be clear, but somewhat immaterial.</p>
<p>So after yet another major Apple event that will help determine the health and popularity of every Apple platform &#8212; key drivers of lucrative hardware sales! &#8212; the markets are betting that all their prior work estimating the True and Correct value of Apple was dead-on and that there is no need for any sort of up-or-down change.</p>
<p>That, or Apple is so big now that investors are simply betting it will grow in keeping with GDP. Which would be a funny diss. Regardless, more from the Apple event <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-the-wwdc-2021-keynote/">here</a> in case you are behind.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/WWDC-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/wwdc-2021-banner.jpg" alt="read more about Apple's WWDC 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-releases-torrent-of-updates-and-wall-street-yawns/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162600</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The hidden benefits of adding a CTO to your board</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/the-hidden-benefits-of-adding-a-cto-to-your-board/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/the-hidden-benefits-of-adding-a-cto-to-your-board/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 19:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agile software development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[board of directors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief technology officer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate governance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CTO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lightbend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[puppet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software engineering]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162210</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Not only do CTOs understand the ever-changing tech landscape, they also provide insights to help organizations to go beyond traditional IT conversations and leverage technology to scale businesses.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Abby Kearns</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/ab415">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/abbykearns/">Abby Kearns</a>, chief technology officer at <a href="http://puppet.com/">Puppet</a>, has more than 20 years of experience scaling growth for numerous Fortune 500 and startup companies.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The pandemic forced companies around the world to adjust to a &#8220;new normal,&#8221; which caused many leaders to pivot their business strategies and adopt new technologies to continue operations. In a time of chaos and change, there is no senior leader that can navigate this sort of change better than a CTO.</p>
<p>Not only do CTOs understand the ever-changing tech landscape, they also provide invaluable insights to help organizations go beyond traditional IT conversations and leverage technology to successfully scale businesses.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Boards are facing pressure to be strategic and thoughtful on how to evolve in the rapidly iterating world of technology, and a CTO is uniquely positioned to address specific challenges.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>There are now more reasons than ever to consider adding a CTO to your board. As a CTO myself, I know how important and impactful it can be to have technical-minded leaders on a company’s board of directors. At a time when companies are accelerating their digital transformation, it’s critical to have diverse technical perspectives and people from varying backgrounds, as transformations are a mix of people, process and technology.</p>
<p>Drawing on my experience on Lightbend’s board of directors, here are five hidden benefits of making space at the table for a CTO.</p>
<h2>A unique mind (and skill) set</h2>
<p>Currently, most boards of directors are composed of former CEOs, CFOs and investors. While such executives bring vast experience, they have very specific expertise, and that frequently does not include technical proficiency. In order for a company to be successful, your board needs to have people with different backgrounds and expertise.</p>
<p>Inviting different perspectives forces companies out of the groupthink mentality and find new, creative solutions to their problems. Diverse perspectives aren&#8217;t just about the title –– racial ethnicity and gender diversity are clearly a play here as well.</p>
<h2>Deep understanding of tech</h2>
<p>For a product-led company, having a CTO who has been close to product development and innovation can bring deep insights and understanding to the boardroom. Boards are facing pressure to be strategic and thoughtful on how to evolve in the rapidly iterating world of technology, and a CTO is uniquely positioned to address specific challenges.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/the-hidden-benefits-of-adding-a-cto-to-your-board/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162210</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here&#8217;s everything Apple announced at the WWDC 2021 keynote</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-the-wwdc-2021-keynote/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-the-wwdc-2021-keynote/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 19:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WWDC 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162558</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s that time again! This morning Apple kicked off its annual Worldwide Developer Conference the same way it does each year: a keynote jammed to the brim with all the new stuff coming to its various devices. Didn&#8217;t have time to tune in to the liveblog or watch the stream? We get it. That&#8217;s why [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s that time again! This morning Apple kicked off its annual <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/WWDC-2021/">Worldwide Developer Conference</a> the same way it does each year: a keynote jammed to the brim with all the new stuff coming to its various devices.</p>
<p>Didn&#8217;t have time to tune in to the liveblog or watch the stream? We get it. That&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve boiled down all of the biggest news to the bullet points below. Skim at your leisure!</p>
<h2>iOS 15</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2162349" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-maps-ios-overview.jpg" alt="WWDC iOS overview screen" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-maps-ios-overview.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-maps-ios-overview.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-maps-ios-overview.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-maps-ios-overview.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-maps-ios-overview.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-maps-ios-overview.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-maps-ios-overview.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-maps-ios-overview.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Craig Federighi started things off with details <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-unveils-ios-15-with-new-features-for-facetime-and-better-notifications/">on the latest major update to iOS</a>, noting that this release focuses on four points: staying connected, finding focus, using intelligence and exploring the world. He noted iOS 15 will roll into public beta in July, with a full release &#8220;this fall.&#8221;</p>
<h2>FaceTime updates</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Spatial audio: </strong>When using a compatible audio setup, spatial audio will make it seem more like your friends&#8217; voices are coming from their on-screen position.</li>
<li><strong>Voice isolation: </strong>Better (and toggle-able) voice isolation for when you&#8217;re FaceTiming from a loud environment.</li>
<li><strong>Portrait mode: </strong>The portrait mode from the camera app is coming to FaceTime — in other words, pretty background blurring.</li>
<li><strong>FaceTime links: </strong>You&#8217;ll now be able to generate shareable FaceTime links to let others (including desktop and Android users via the browser!) join FaceTime calls.</li>
<li><strong>SharePlay: </strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-introduces-shareplay-for-co-watching-streaming-and-screen-sharing-over-facetime/">Shared audio/video streams</a> to allow you to listen to music, watch video (select video partners initially, including Disney+, Hulu, HBO Max and TikTok), and control apps in sync with friends. You can pushed the shared videos to your AppleTV, keeping it all synced up between devices and households.</li>
</ul>
<h2>&#8220;Focus&#8221; mode<img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2162283" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications-focus.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications-focus.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications-focus.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications-focus.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications-focus.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications-focus.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications-focus.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications-focus.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications-focus.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></h2>
<ul>
<li>You&#8217;ll be able to shift your phone into different, customizable modes — like &#8220;work,&#8221; where only your work-related apps will show up, or &#8220;personal&#8221; which could tuck all those work apps and widgets to the background. Vacation mode, activate!</li>
<li><strong>Notifications batching:</strong> You can now tell iOS to batch less important notifications together, delivering them all at a specific time (like after you&#8217;ve woken up, rather than letting them trickle in throughout the night).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Live Text</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2162299" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-12.22.31-PM.jpg" alt="WWDC 2021 - Photos - Live Text" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-12.22.31-PM.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-12.22.31-PM.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-12.22.31-PM.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-12.22.31-PM.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-12.22.31-PM.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-12.22.31-PM.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-12.22.31-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-12.22.31-PM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>The camera <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apples-live-text-lets-you-interact-with-text-in-your-photos/">can now recognize text in photos</a> (handwritten or printed) and make it selectable, searchable, copy/pastable, etc. It can recognize things beyond text, as well, including animal breeds, landmarks, etc.</p>
<h2>Apple Wallet</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2162316" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ID-driver.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ID-driver.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ID-driver.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ID-driver.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ID-driver.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ID-driver.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ID-driver.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ID-driver.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ID-driver.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>Apple is incorporating home, office and hotel keys into Apple Wallet, allowing you to unlock compatible doors in those places with your phone. You&#8217;ll be able to check into select hotels, for example, and have your room key show up on your phone as soon as your room is ready.</p>
<p>They&#8217;re also working with the TSA (in select states, at first) to put an encrypted copy of your state driver&#8217;s license (!) in Wallet that will be accepted at security screenings.</p>
<h2>Apple Maps</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2162338" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162338" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2162338" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.33.03-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="573" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.33.03-PM.jpg 1528w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.33.03-PM.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.33.03-PM.jpg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.33.03-PM.jpg?resize=768,430 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.33.03-PM.jpg?resize=680,380 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.33.03-PM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162338" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>Maps is getting a details-focused overhaul, with the addition of 3D elevation maps, 3D rendered landmarks, crosswalks, bike lanes, etc.</p>
<p>Apple Maps is also taking some cues from Google Maps, including a mode that has you use the camera to scan nearby buildings to more precisely orient the phone and help you figure out which direction you&#8217;re supposed to go at the beginning of a walk.</p>
<h2>AirPods updates</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2162358" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-airpods-find-map.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-airpods-find-map.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-airpods-find-map.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-airpods-find-map.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-airpods-find-map.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-airpods-find-map.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-airpods-find-map.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-airpods-find-map.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-airpods-find-map.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Conversation mode:</strong> AirPods Pro will now allow you to boost the volume of voices (and control the volume of ambient noise) of those around you when you&#8217;re having a face-to-face conversation in a noisy environment.</li>
<li><strong>Find My:</strong> AirPods will now work with the Find My app even when they&#8217;re in the case, and will be able to alert you if you leave them behind.</li>
<li>Spatial audio is coming to tvOS and M1-powered Macs.</li>
</ul>
<h2>iPadOS</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2162400" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.49.02-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="573" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.49.02-PM.jpg 1528w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.49.02-PM.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.49.02-PM.jpg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.49.02-PM.jpg?resize=768,430 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.49.02-PM.jpg?resize=680,380 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.49.02-PM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<ul>
<li>iPadOS will get home screen widgets. They&#8217;re pretty similar to the ones you&#8217;ve seen on iOS, with the addition of a much bigger widget option because, well, bigger screen.</li>
<li>The &#8220;App Library&#8221; concept is making its way from iOS to iPadOS, as well.</li>
<li>A new <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/ipados-15-announced-at-wwdc-features-improved-multitasking-and-improved-swift-playgrounds-support/">multitasking menu</a> will (hopefully) simplify the way you handle multitasking on iPadOS, moving the system away from the easily forgotten gestures currently required.</li>
<li>The Notes app will now let you @ mention someone in a shared note to get their attention on a change, and highlight changes when you come back to a shared doc. &#8220;Quick Notes,&#8221; meanwhile, will let you create a note from anywhere by swiping up from the bottom right corner of the screen.</li>
<li><strong>Translate:</strong> iPadOS will get a system-wide text translation option, along with an app for translating in-person conversations in real time.</li>
<li>Swift Playgrounds will now let you build apps on the iPad and <em>submit them to the App Store</em>.</li>
<li>Public beta in July, full release &#8220;this fall.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<h2>Security updates</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2162404" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.49.31-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="573" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.49.31-PM.jpg 1528w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.49.31-PM.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.49.31-PM.jpg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.49.31-PM.jpg?resize=768,430 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.49.31-PM.jpg?resize=680,380 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.49.31-PM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Mail app will now automatically obscure your IP address/location from those invisible tracking pixels marketers love to tuck into emails.</li>
<li>An &#8220;App Privacy Report&#8221; option in settings will now summarize how often any given app accesses your location, photos, etc. to hopefully flag any unexpected behaviors.</li>
<li>Siri&#8217;s speech recognition will now happen on-device, keeping the audio recordings off of Apple&#8217;s servers and allowing for Siri commands without an internet connection.</li>
<li>You&#8217;ll be able to add recovery contacts to your iCloud account, allowing you to select friends who can help you get back into your iCloud account if you get locked out. You&#8217;ll also be able to pick &#8220;Legacy&#8221; contacts who can request access to your iCloud data should you pass away.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Health updates</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2162433" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-labs-highlights.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-labs-highlights.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-labs-highlights.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-labs-highlights.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-labs-highlights.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-labs-highlights.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-labs-highlights.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-labs-highlights.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-labs-highlights.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Your iPhone can now analyze your gait, step timing, etc. to analyze your &#8220;walking steadiness&#8221; to hopefully flag if your fall risk is increasing over time.</li>
<li>A &#8220;Trends&#8221; summary in the health app will highlight patterns in your step counts, heart rate, etc.</li>
<li>New &#8220;Health sharing&#8221; options will let you securely share health data with people you care about — like that of your parents, or your kids.</li>
</ul>
<h2>watchOS</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2162455" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-watchos-respiratory-rate.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-watchos-respiratory-rate.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-watchos-respiratory-rate.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-watchos-respiratory-rate.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-watchos-respiratory-rate.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-watchos-respiratory-rate.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-watchos-respiratory-rate.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-watchos-respiratory-rate.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-watchos-respiratory-rate.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/watchos-8-brings-new-mindfulness-features-and-respiratory-tracking/">watchOS will now be able to help track your respiratory rate</a> (how many breaths you take per minute), and note how you might breathe differently throughout the day (like when you&#8217;re sleeping). They&#8217;re also adding new workout modes to the activity tracking engine, including Tai Chi and Pilates.</li>
<li>A new &#8220;Portraits&#8221; watchface will use your portrait-mode photos to create a neat, layered-looking clock layout.</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2162577" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Portraits.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="548" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Portraits.jpg 1060w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Portraits.jpg?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Portraits.jpg?resize=300,160 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Portraits.jpg?resize=768,411 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Portraits.jpg?resize=680,364 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Portraits.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Text input is getting a subtle overhaul on watchOS, with the &#8220;Scribble&#8221; handwriting recognition being incorporated right into the text view. You use the crown to place the text cursor, then draw the letters/symbols you want right on top of your text.</li>
<li>Public beta in July, full release &#8220;this fall.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<h2>Siri goes to third-party devices</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2162482" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-homekit-siri-third-party.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-homekit-siri-third-party.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-homekit-siri-third-party.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-homekit-siri-third-party.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-homekit-siri-third-party.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-homekit-siri-third-party.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-homekit-siri-third-party.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-homekit-siri-third-party.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-homekit-siri-third-party.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>Apple says it&#8217;s opening up Siri to third-party manufacturers and their devices, allowing Siri to live on things like ecobee thermostats beginning later this year.</p>
<h2>macOS</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2162490" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-monterey.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-monterey.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-monterey.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-monterey.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-monterey.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-monterey.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-monterey.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-monterey.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-monterey.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<ul>
<li>The next major release of macOS <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-unveils-macos-12-monterey/">will be called macOS Monterey</a>.</li>
<li>All of the aforementioned SharePlay stuff — which allows you to watch video and listen to music in sync with friends over FaceTime — is coming to macOS.</li>
<li>&#8220;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/macos-12-monterey-upgrades-continuity-with-universal-control/">Universal control</a>&#8221; will let you use one keyboard/mouse setup to control multiple macs and iPads, automatically recognizing when a new compatible device is placed nearby. Put an iPad next to your MacBook, and bam — it automatically extends, turning the two devices into one big canvas.</li>
<li>Macs are getting AirPlay, allowing you to send AirPlay content to your Mac&#8217;s display like you might an AppleTV.</li>
<li>The &#8220;Shortcuts&#8221; automation system from iOS<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-is-bringing-shortcuts-to-the-mac-and-starts-transition-from-automator/"> is coming to macOS</a>, allowing you to quickly drag-and-drop together scripts to do the things you find yourself doing often. (If you&#8217;re already using macOS&#8217; automator system, it&#8217;ll still be supported for now.)</li>
<li>Safari is getting a UI overhaul; tabs are being made smaller, and they&#8217;re introducing a &#8220;tab groups&#8221; system to keep things organized. Tab groups will automatically sync between iCloud devices.</li>
<li>Public beta in July, full release &#8220;this fall.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<h2>Dev stuff</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2162545" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-xcode-cloud-4.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" /></p>
<p>Though its called the Worldwide Developers Conference, Apple tends to keep the keynote focused largely on the consumer-facing stuff and save the most technical bits for the week&#8217;s many breakout sessions. They did touch on a few developer highlights, though, including:</p>
<ul>
<li>New APIs to hook into things like SharePlay, Focus, etc.</li>
<li>iOS is getting a built-in 3D object scanning system that developers can tie into their apps, allowing them to integrate 3D scanning-style functionality without having to reinvent that wheel.</li>
<li>Devs will now be able to build multiple App Store product pages for the same app — with different icons, screenshots, etc. — to see which one resonates best.</li>
<li>TestFlight — the service for privately distributing pre-release/beta apps on Apple&#8217;s phone/tablet/watch operating systems — is coming to macOS.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/WWDC-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/wwdc-2021-banner.jpg" alt="read more about Apple's WWDC 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-the-wwdc-2021-keynote/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162558</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple to introduce A/B testing and in-app events to the App Store</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-to-introduce-a-b-testing-and-in-app-events-to-the-app-store/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-to-introduce-a-b-testing-and-in-app-events-to-the-app-store/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 18:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iTunes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WWDC 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162537</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple today announced a number of coming changes and improvements to the App Store that will help developers better target their apps to users, get their apps discovered by more people and even highlight what sort of events are taking place inside their apps to entice new users to download the app and encourage existing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple today announced a number of coming changes and improvements to the App Store that will help developers better target their apps to users, get their apps discovered by more people and even highlight what sort of events are taking place inside their apps to entice new users to download the app and encourage existing users to return.</p>
<p>The company said its App Store today sees 600 million weekly users across 175 countries, and has paid out more than $230 billion to developers since the App Store launched, highlighting the business opportunity for app developers.</p>
<p>However, as the App Store has grown, it&#8217;s become harder for app developers to market their apps to new users or get their apps found. The new features aim to address that.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2162568" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162568" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2162568" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.41.07-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="382" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.41.07-PM.jpg 2720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.41.07-PM.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.41.07-PM.jpg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.41.07-PM.jpg?resize=768,431 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.41.07-PM.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.41.07-PM.jpg?resize=1536,862 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.41.07-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1149 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.41.07-PM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162568" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>One change involves the app&#8217;s product page. Starting this year, app developers will be able to create multiple custom product pages to showcase different features of their app for different users. For instance, they&#8217;ll be able to try out things like different screenshots, videos, and even different app icons to A/B test what users like the most.</p>
<p>They&#8217;ll also be able to advertise the dynamic things that are taking place inside their apps on an ongoing basis. Apple explained that apps and games are constantly rolling out new content and limited time events like film premieres on streaming services, events like Pokémon GO fests, or Nike fitness challenges. But these events were often only discoverable by those who already had the app installed and then opted in to push notifications.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2162563" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162563" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2162563" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.42.38-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="373" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.42.38-PM.jpg 2714w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.42.38-PM.jpg?resize=150,82 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.42.38-PM.jpg?resize=300,165 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.42.38-PM.jpg?resize=768,422 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.42.38-PM.jpg?resize=680,373 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.42.38-PM.jpg?resize=1536,843 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.42.38-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1124 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-07-at-2.42.38-PM.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162563" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>Apple will now allow developers to better advertise these events, with the launch of in-app events &#8220;front and center on the App Store.&#8221; The events can be showcased on the app&#8217;s product page. Users can learn more about the events, sign up to be notified or quickly join the event, if it&#8217;s happening now. They can also discover events with personalized recommendations and through App Store search.</p>
<p>App Store editors will curate the best events and the new App Store widget will feature upcoming events right on users&#8217; home screens, too.</p>
<p>Apple says the feature will be open to all developers, including those who already run events and those who are just getting started.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/WWDC-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/wwdc-2021-banner.jpg" alt="read more about Apple's WWDC 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-to-introduce-a-b-testing-and-in-app-events-to-the-app-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162537</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>macOS 12 Monterey upgrades Continuity with Universal Control</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/macos-12-monterey-upgrades-continuity-with-universal-control/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/macos-12-monterey-upgrades-continuity-with-universal-control/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 18:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mac OS X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macintosh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sidecar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tablet computers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WWDC 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162498</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During the WWDC conference today, Apple unveiled the new macOS 12 Monterey. A major feature in the macOS update is Universal Control, which builds upon the Continuity features first introduced in OS X Yosemite. For years it&#8217;s been possible to open a news article on your iPhone and keep reading it on your MacBook, or [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">During the WWDC conference today, Apple unveiled the new <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-unveils-macos-12-monterey/">macOS 12 Monterey</a>. A major feature in the macOS update is Universal Control, which builds upon the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/07/23/apple-os-x-yosemite-beta/">Continuity features</a> first introduced in OS X Yosemite. For years it&#8217;s been possible to open a news article on your iPhone and keep reading it on your MacBook, or to copy and paste a link from your iPad to your iMac. But Universal Control takes these features further.</p>
<p>With Universal Control, you can use a single mouse and keyboard to navigate across multiple Apple devices at once. This functionality works across more than two devices &#8212; in the demo video, the feature is used to seamlessly move across an iPad, MacBook and iMac. Users can drag and drop files across multiple devices at once, making it possible, for example, to use a multi-screen setup while editing video on Final Cut Pro.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s possible in Universal Control isn&#8217;t necessarily new &#8212; this has been made possible before through third-party apps. Plus, in 2019, Apple debuted <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/28/apples-sidecar-just-really-gets-me-you-know/">Sidecar</a>, which allowed users to connect their iPad as a second monitor for their MacBook or iMac. But, Universal Control improves upon Sidecar &#8212; and maybe renders it obsolete &#8212; by allowing users to link any Apple devices together, even if it&#8217;s not an iPad. Though this update may not be groundbreaking, it&#8217;s a useful upgrade to existing features.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/WWDC-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/wwdc-2021-banner.jpg" alt="read more about Apple's WWDC 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/macos-12-monterey-upgrades-continuity-with-universal-control/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162498</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple TV to support using HomePod Mini as speakers, among other updates</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-tv-to-support-using-homepod-mini-as-speakers-among-other-updates/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-tv-to-support-using-homepod-mini-as-speakers-among-other-updates/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 18:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple tv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FaceTime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HomeKit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HomePod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart speakers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Jobs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tablet computers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WWDC 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162493</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple didn&#8217;t announce that rumored combined Apple TV device that would combine the set-top box with a HomePod speaker during its WWDC keynote, but it did announce a few features that will improve the Apple TV experience &#8212; including one that involves a HomePod Mini. Starting this fall, Apple said you&#8217;ll be able to select [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple didn&#8217;t announce that <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-04-12/apple-working-on-combined-tv-box-speaker-to-revive-home-efforts?sref=gni836kR">rumored</a> combined Apple TV device that would combine the set-top box with a HomePod speaker during its WWDC keynote, but it did announce a few features that will improve the Apple TV experience &#8212; including one that involves a HomePod Mini. Starting this fall, Apple said you&#8217;ll be able to select the HomePod Mini as the speaker for your Apple TV 4K. It also introduced a handful of software updates for Apple TV users, including a new way to see shows everyone in the family will like, and support for co-watching shows through FaceTime.</p>
<p>The co-watching feature is actually a part of a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-announces-facetime-updates-at-wwdc-2021/">larger FaceTime update</a>, which will let users stream music, TV, and screen share through their FaceTime calls. The Apple TV app is one of those that&#8217;s supported through this new system,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-introduces-shareplay-for-co-watching-streaming-and-screen-sharing-over-facetime/"> called SharePlay</a>. It will now include a new &#8220;Shared with You&#8221; row that highlights the shows and movies your friends are sharing, as well.</p>
<p>Another feature called &#8220;For All of You&#8221; will display a collection of shows and movies based on everyone&#8217;s interests within Apple TV&#8217;s interface. This is ideal you&#8217;re planning to watch something as a family &#8212; like for movie night, for example. And you can fine tune the suggestions based on who&#8217;s watching.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A new Apple TV widget is also being made available, which now includes iPad support.</p>
<p>And the new support for HomePod Mini will help deliver &#8220;rich, balanced sound&#8221; and &#8220;crystal clear dialog,&#8221; when you&#8217;re watching Apple TV with the Mii set up as your speakers, Apple said.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/WWDC-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/wwdc-2021-banner.jpg" alt="read more about Apple's WWDC 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-tv-to-support-using-homepod-mini-as-speakers-among-other-updates/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162493</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple is bringing Shortcuts to the Mac and starts transition from Automator</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-is-bringing-shortcuts-to-the-mac-and-starts-transition-from-automator/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-is-bringing-shortcuts-to-the-mac-and-starts-transition-from-automator/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 18:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shortcuts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162527</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple has announced the next major version of macOS at WWDC 2021 —&#160;macOS Monterey. Among other features, Apple is going to release Shortcuts on macOS. It’s going to look and work a lot like Shortcuts on iOS and iPadOS. “The Mac has a long history of automation with command line, shell scripts, Apple scripts and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple has announced the next major version of macOS at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/wwdc-2021/">WWDC 2021</a> —&nbsp;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-unveils-macos-12-monterey/">macOS Monterey</a>. Among other features, Apple is going to release Shortcuts on macOS. It’s going to look and work a lot like Shortcuts on iOS and iPadOS.</p>
<p>“The Mac has a long history of automation with command line, shell scripts, Apple scripts and Automator. And on iOS, we&#39;ve made automation even easier with Shortcuts,” SVP of Software Engineering Craig Federighi said. “And this year we&#39;re bringing Shortcuts to the Mac.”</p>
<p>In the new Shortcuts app, you can see a gallery of popular shortcuts. It’s going to be interesting to see what exactly you can trigger with shortcuts, but you can expect to be able to launch apps, create GIFs, send a message, create an email, launch a website, etc.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>After that, you can trigger your shortcuts in the right column of the Finder, in the menubar and in Spotlight. You can also trigger them with Siri.</p>
<p>With this announcement, Apple is also setting the stage for the end of Automator. “This is just the start of a multi-year transition Automator will continue to be supported, and you can import Automator workflows into beginning one with shortcuts,” Federighi said.</p>
<p>If you read between the lines, it sounds like Apple doesn’t plan to add new features to Automator. Shortcuts is the future of automation on macOS, iOS and iPadOS.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uVy2rWlKUA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-unveils-macos-12-monterey/">Apple unveils macOS 12 Monterey</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple unveils macOS 12 Monterey&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-unveils-macos-12-monterey/embed/#?secret=uVy2rWlKUA" data-secret="uVy2rWlKUA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2162507" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/WWDC-2021/"><img alt="read more about Apple's WWDC 2021 on TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/wwdc-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-is-bringing-shortcuts-to-the-mac-and-starts-transition-from-automator/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162527</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple unveils new iOS 15 privacy features at WWDC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-wwdc-2021-privacy-security/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-wwdc-2021-privacy-security/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 18:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WWDC 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162186</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple kicked off its global annual developer conference, WWDC, with a ton of new features and technologies. TechCrunch has all the coverage here from the keynote. As with previous years, Apple has dropped a number of new security and privacy features. New privacy dashboard keeps tabs on app tracking requests Apple is bringing a new [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple kicked off its global annual developer conference, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/WWDC-2021/">WWDC</a>, with a ton of new features and technologies. TechCrunch has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/WWDC-2021/">all the coverage here</a> from the keynote. As with previous years, Apple has dropped a number of new security and privacy features.</p>
<h3>New privacy dashboard keeps tabs on app tracking requests</h3>
<p>Apple is bringing a new privacy dashboard to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-unveils-ios-15-with-new-features-for-facetime-and-better-notifications/">iOS 15</a> to make it easier to see which apps are collecting your data and when. It&#8217;s a continuation of Apple&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/apples-app-tracking-transparency-feature-has-arrived-heres-what-you-need-to-know/">App Tracking Transparency feature</a> that it rolled out earlier this year to block apps from siphoning off and selling your data to advertisers and data brokers. In iOS 15, you will be able to see which apps you have given permission to access your data — such as your location, microphone, contacts and photos — and how often it&#8217;s accessed.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2162495" style="width: 1010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162495" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2162495" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/privacy-dashboard.jpg" alt="" width="1000" height="728" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/privacy-dashboard.jpg 2203w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/privacy-dashboard.jpg?resize=150,109 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/privacy-dashboard.jpg?resize=300,218 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/privacy-dashboard.jpg?resize=768,559 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/privacy-dashboard.jpg?resize=680,495 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/privacy-dashboard.jpg?resize=1536,1118 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/privacy-dashboard.jpg?resize=2048,1490 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/privacy-dashboard.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162495" class="wp-caption-text">(Image: TechCrunch / screenshot)</p></div></p>
<h3>Mail will block invisible email trackers</h3>
<p>Emails are not as private as you might think. Most marketing emails contain hidden pixel-sized images that know when you&#8217;ve opened an email. These trackers also collect information about you, including your IP address, which can be used to infer your location. Some browser extensions <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/10/these-6-browser-extensions-will-immediately-improve-your-privacy-online/">already block</a> these invisible email trackers. But Apple said it&#8217;s bringing privacy features to the Mail app, which will make it more difficult for emails — and ad trackers — from knowing which emails you&#8217;ve opened.</p>
<h3>Siri will process speech on the device</h3>
<p>Siri, Apple&#8217;s voice assistant, requires the internet to work, but will soon work offline. Apple said Siri will soon process speech on the device so that audio never leaves the device. Apple said this will help prevent unwanted audio recording, but will also help make Siri respond to requests faster.</p>
<ul>
<li>Apple also has a few new security and privacy features baked into its new iCloud+ premium service, including private relay, which encrypts your Safari internet traffic. As part of its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-announces-icloud-with-privacy-focused-features/">new premium iCloud+ service</a>, Apple is also rolling out private relay browsing, which encrypts your Safari traffic and routes it so that it&#8217;s more difficult to track which websites you visit. TechCrunch&#8217;s Romain Dillet has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-announces-icloud-with-privacy-focused-features/">more</a>.</li>
<li>There are plenty of authenticator apps, like Authy and Duo, which let you generate stronger two-factor codes for your online accounts than codes sent by text message &#8212; iOS 15 also <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/06/07/ios-15-built-in-password-authenticator/">bakes in</a> its own authenticator for the first time.</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nS6isAB7db"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-announces-icloud-with-privacy-focused-features/">Apple announces iCloud+ with privacy-focused features</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple announces iCloud+ with privacy-focused features&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-announces-icloud-with-privacy-focused-features/embed/#?secret=nS6isAB7db" data-secret="nS6isAB7db" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/WWDC-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/wwdc-2021-banner.jpg" alt="read more about Apple's WWDC 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-wwdc-2021-privacy-security/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162186</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple unveils macOS 12 Monterey</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-unveils-macos-12-monterey/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-unveils-macos-12-monterey/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 18:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WWDC 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2161737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The past year has seen some of the most dramatic updates to Macs in recent memory. At last year’s WWDC, Apple announced its long-awaited move from Intel chip’s to its own first party silicon. By the end of the year, the company launched the first three M1 Macs, along with Big Sur, one of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The past year has seen some of the most dramatic updates to Macs in recent memory. At last year’s WWDC, Apple announced its long-awaited move from Intel chip’s to its own first party silicon. By the end of the year, the company launched the first three M1 Macs, along with Big Sur, one of the biggest updates to macOS.</p>
<p>At this morning’s kickoff to WWDC, the company unveiled macOS 12 &#8212; named, you guessed it, Monterey. Universal Control is the top line new feature here, which further bridges the gap between desktop and tablet. Sticking the iPad next to a Mac, you can move the cursor between devices using the same trackpad and keyboard. The feature works on up to three devices at once.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2162507" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-shortcuts-automator.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>AirPlay to Mac also let&#8217;s you cast content directly to your big desktop screen &#8212; that&#8217;s nice for weirdos like me who don&#8217;t have a TV. Shortcuts are also now available on macOS, allowing for simpler automation that the existing Automator. Users will be able to import Automator workflows directly to the desktop version of the popular mobile app. It will be a multi-year transition, but rip Automator &#8212; you will be missed (kind of). Shortcuts will be coming to Siri, Spotlight, the menu bar and Finder to start.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2162516" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-safari-url.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-safari-url.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-safari-url.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-safari-url.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-safari-url.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-safari-url.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-safari-url.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-safari-url.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-macOS-safari-url.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>Safari is getting some updates, of course. The biggest piece of news on the browser front is the arrival of Tab Groups &#8212; which is more or less as it sounds. Users can group tabs into bundles, which can be shared with other users. That&#8217;s a lot of content and will probably require a rethink of many users workflows. But at least the tab bar itself is getting cleaner and more streamlined.</p>
<p>Also new are desktop extensions that can now be with iOS and iPadOS. Desktops also now support Spatial Audio on the AirPods Pro, LaunchPad now features a games folder to get that content all in one place and Memojis can be displayed on the login screen.</p>
<p>Some nice additions, but as expect, Monterey doesn&#8217;t represent as big an update as Big Sur. There are some nice new features here, but it seems likely that much of the big news is happening under the hood, as the company continues to refine the Apple Silicon experience across its new systems.</p>
<p>Public beta will go live next month. Monterey will be available for all users this fall.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/WWDC-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/wwdc-2021-banner.jpg" alt="read more about Apple's WWDC 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-unveils-macos-12-monterey/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2161737</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
