<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 15:25:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Are early-stage funding rounds out of control?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/are-early-stage-funding-rounds-out-of-control/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/are-early-stage-funding-rounds-out-of-control/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 15:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Angel Investor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2254397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Despite the twofold growth in dollars invested, the number of companies receiving funding has grown by less than 30% compared with Q3 2020.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Curtis Townshend</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/openviewventure">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/curtis-townshend-88b544a9">Curtis Townshend</a> is senior director of growth at <a href="https://openviewpartners.com/">OpenView</a>. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Software businesses are setting new heights for fundraising nearly every day. Transmit Security <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/525-million-a-round-transmit-security-passwords-insight-2021-6">broke records</a> last summer with their $543 million Series A, and in Q3 2021, <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/q3-2021-na-startup-funding-report/">$26.4 billion was invested in North American</a> early stage startups, compared with $12.1 billion a year earlier. There have been warnings that these landmark fundraises are driven by too much capital available and a highly competitive venture market.</p>
<p>However, despite the twofold growth in dollars invested, the number of companies receiving funding has grown by less than 30% compared with Q3 2020. Simply put, 2021 has seen startups raise the bar for what a good company looks like and investors have been willing to pay a high price for a piece of the pie.</p>
<h2>Key takeaways</h2>
<p>Recent benchmark data shows that qualifying for the top quartiles in key SaaS Metrics was harder in 2021 than ever before, particularly when you consider the growth and net dollar retention metrics.</p>
<ul>
<li>From 2018-2020, growing at 140% would put business in the top quartile as a Series A company.</li>
<li>Beyond growth, formerly impressive metrics like 110% net dollar retention no longer make the cut.</li>
</ul>
<p>Taking a closer look at each of these early rounds highlights that investors might not be going crazy with their recent investments as startups redefine what &#8220;good&#8221; looks like.</p>
<h2>Seed/angel</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2254429" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2254429" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2254429" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/image1-1.png" alt="Growth expectations at the Seed stage are much higher than they have been in the past." width="1024" height="276" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/image1-1.png 1143w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/image1-1.png?resize=150,40 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/image1-1.png?resize=300,81 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/image1-1.png?resize=768,207 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/image1-1.png?resize=680,183 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/image1-1.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2254429" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> OpenView Venture Partners</p></div></p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/are-early-stage-funding-rounds-out-of-control/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2254397</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Emotional wellness app Mine&#8217;d raises $3.5M led by Listen Ventures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/emotional-wellness-app-mined-raises-3-5m-led-by-listen-ventures/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/emotional-wellness-app-mined-raises-3-5m-led-by-listen-ventures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 14:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seed funding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2253946</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mine&#8217;d, a digital platform and wellness network that connects consumers with emotional health experts and community, has raised a $3.5 million seed round led by Listen Ventures. The round was also funded by WNDRCO and Able Partners, Joyance Partners, Route 66 Ventures as well as angel investors Ed Baker, the former vice president of growth [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Mine&#8217;d, a <a href="https://www.doyoumined.com/">digital platform</a> and wellness network that connects consumers with emotional health experts and community, has raised a $3.5 million seed round led by Listen Ventures. The round was also funded by WNDRCO and Able Partners, Joyance Partners, Route 66 Ventures as well as angel investors Ed Baker, the former vice president of growth at Facebook and Uber, and Jillionaire from Major Lazer. Mine&#8217;d features interactive and short-form live and on-demand classes to users based on a wide range of topics, including dating, breakups, career and purpose. Since launching six months ago, Mine&#8217;d has built a community of over 100,000 users and one million videos.</p>
<p>The platform was co-founded by wellness-tech entrepreneur Aaron Albert and emotional wellness content creator <a href="http://www.instagram.com/createthelove">Mark Groves</a>. Albert, who is now the company&#8217;s CEO, says the idea for Mine&#8217;d was prompted by his experience with trying to find support after a breakup. He says he found traditional therapy to be expensive and time-consuming, while modern solutions like teletherapy lacked in their quality of care. <span style="font-weight: 400;">A friend of his who knew he was having a hard time sent him one of Mark Groves&#8217; wellness videos. Albert says he was immediately taken with Groves&#8217; content and reached out to him, after which the pair began working together. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;I started to explain all of the challenges I faced as a consumer wanted to get emotional support and he expressed to me all of the challenges he faced as a creator of emotional wellness content, not feeling like there was a safe space for his peers amidst the creator economy explosion,&#8221; Albert told TechCrunch. &#8220;It was very clear there was a real opportunity here, and so Mine’d was born.&#8221;</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2253946" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Once users join Mine&#8217;d, <span style="font-weight: 400;">they&#8217;re asked to select the areas they want to improve on. Users are then shown a selection of experts where they can see what areas they specialize in and browse content before choosing who to follow. Users are able to join live sessions where they can ask experts questions and get or give support to the community.</span></p>
<p>In terms of the new funding, Albert says Mine&#8217;d plans to use it to bring on an additional 100-200 experts to the platform. Mine&#8217;d currently has 20 wellness experts, including marriage and family therapist Vienna Pharaon, marriage, family and relationship expert Dr. Alexandra Solomon and sex therapist Shadeen Francis. The company also plans to launch creator tools that will allow its experts to offer more support to their community. Mine&#8217;d also aims to focus on email marketing and content production. Lastly, the company plans to use the funding to launch exclusive Mine&#8217;d courses within the app.</p>
<p>When asked what sets Mine&#8217;d apart from other wellness apps, Groves said other platforms are focused on how to scale one-on-one therapy, coaching and group therapy. Although Mine&#8217;d believe in those methods, Groves believes that by the time someone goes to therapy, it&#8217;s very late in their personal growth journey.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We wanted to meet people, with curated and incredible content, at step one, the frictionless space where people are beginning to search for answers to their problems, challenges and making sense of their feelings,&#8221; Groves stated. &#8220;W</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">e wanted to create a space where they could be themselves, be curious, be vulnerable, and decide on the depth of intimacy that they are comfortable with given their familiarity with personal growth, therapy, and consuming content that is sometimes challenging and emotional.&#8221;</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Regarding the future, the company plans to continue developing Mine&#8217;d in a way that still feels personal and vulnerable. Groves outlined that Mine&#8217;d will help its experts<span style="font-weight: 400;"> reach the people who need support while allowing them the ability to get paid for their expertise. In addition, Albert said the company also plans to expand its offerings. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We are looking to become the unifier in the emotional wellness space,&#8221; Albert said. &#8220;We want to give our community the chance to not only get help through our many content offerings, but ultimately be able to book 1:1 and small group coaching. We are planning to launch a Mine’d Coaching Certification, allowing people to step into their calling and become coaches themselves.&#8221;</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/emotional-wellness-app-mined-raises-3-5m-led-by-listen-ventures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2253946</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Verb Data puts $3M to work so companies can build better in-product dashboards</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/verb-data-puts-3m-to-work-so-companies-can-build-better-in-product-dashboards/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/verb-data-puts-3m-to-work-so-companies-can-build-better-in-product-dashboards/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 14:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dashboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data warehouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data warehousing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dave Hurt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[El Cap Holdings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Notion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oleg Fridman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software as a service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verb Data]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2254176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Verb’s customer-facing analytics tools are built specifically to live inside multi-tenant SaaS applications.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Nine months after its public launch, <a href="https://www.verbdata.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Verb Data</a>, a customer-facing analytics company, took in $3 million in funding to continue developing technology so that SaaS companies can build better in-product dashboards for their customers.</p>
<p>Founders Dave Hurt and Oleg Fridman started the Boston-based company in January 2020 and started its private beta program with five customers in August 2020, then launched to the public in April 2021.</p>
<p>Verb’s customer-facing analytics tools are built specifically to live inside multi-tenant SaaS applications, CEO Hurt told TechCrunch via email. What makes it different from competitors is the way it makes simpler the process of building and maintaining customer-facing dashboards by non-technical team members by reporting and automating the data infrastructure that supports those data experiences.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2254176" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“For example, every chart that is built and embedded into a customer’s application is backed by a data warehouse that is specifically optimized for that chart without requiring any developer effort,” he added. “This allows software teams to focus on their core product while also providing their end-users with high-performing analytics dashboards.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The funding round was led by El Cap Holdings and lead investors Stew Bradley and Kunal Tandon. Individual investors also participating include Stan Garber, Alex Yakubovich, Matt MacInnis, Steve Garrity and Packy McCormick.</p>
<p>The company counts dozens of companies as customers, including Encamp, BidOps, SwipeBy and ReviveMedia. Hurt attributes Verb’s flexibility for enabling customers to use the tools in a way that is unique to their needs.</p>
<p>Some are using it for embedded product dashboards, some are using it inside of Notion as a client analytics portal and others use Verb for customer success management or as a sales tool.</p>
<p>“Verb has allowed us to supercharge our efforts around both internal and customer reporting,” Ben Leiken, CTO at Bid Ops, a predictive sourcing software company, said via email. “Thanks to their powerful features, we’re able to instantly deploy changes and test new features with customers — all without needing to wait for our next release.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xINGyYi8zY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/27/how-to-be-one-of-the-haves-of-saas/">How to be one of the &#8216;haves&#8217; of SaaS</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to be one of the &#8216;haves&#8217; of SaaS&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/27/how-to-be-one-of-the-haves-of-saas/embed/#?secret=xINGyYi8zY" data-secret="xINGyYi8zY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Prior to this new funding, Verb Data raised an undisclosed pre-seed round in 2020 that helped it complete its private beta and get to the public launch, Hurt said. He plans to invest in building out the company’s engineering team and on product development. Verb has 15 employees, up from seven at this time last year.</p>
<p>Some of the features coming down the pipeline in the first quarter include map data and charts for greater flexibility and use with Verb’s modularized drag-and-drop editor. Users will also be able to visualize their data on maps on existing dashboards to allow for better reporting.</p>
<p>In addition, Verb is working on additional data source integrations from existing partners, an updated design styles library and Slack integration for quicker and easier communication when a dashboard is created, Hurt said.</p>
<p>Hurt said the company was focused on customer growth over revenue, so he did not have year over year metrics to share, but did say that over the past six months, Verb had 65 new signups with an overall conversion rate of 20%. In July that rate increased to 30%. The company intends to raise another round of funding in the third quarter of 2023 and expects to have 100 paying customers by the end of 2023.</p>
<p>“The SaaS market is becoming more vertical-specific, which means that companies are competing on core functionality in their respective niche,” Hurt said. “While this generally means that end-customers are benefiting from software that more closely aligns with their needs, it also means that product teams have to focus on their core functionality to keep up with competition, making the analytics dashboard an even more difficult feature to prioritize on the roadmap.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="W0he8H35vE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/how-to-ensure-quality-in-the-era-of-big-data/">How to ensure data quality in the era of big data</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to ensure data quality in the era of big data&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/how-to-ensure-quality-in-the-era-of-big-data/embed/#?secret=W0he8H35vE" data-secret="W0he8H35vE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/verb-data-puts-3m-to-work-so-companies-can-build-better-in-product-dashboards/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2254176</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Steering innovation toward the public good</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/steering-innovation-toward-the-public-good/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/steering-innovation-toward-the-public-good/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-scooters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Georgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indiana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north carolina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oregon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2253276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When it comes to transportation innovation, perhaps the hardest thing to predict is the timing of how and when these developments will impact our everyday lives]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Pete Buttigieg</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/SecretaryPete">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Pete Buttigieg currently serves as the 19th Secretary of Transportation, having been sworn in on February 3, 2021.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Millennia ago, some unnamed innovator created humanity’s most famous early invention: the wheel. And ever since, the story of transportation has been one of human creativity, innovation, and technology. From e-scooters to spacecraft, technology shapes most human journeys, whether it’s a historic spaceflight or a daily cross-town commute.</p>
<p>At the U.S. Department of Transportation, my colleagues and I think every day about how transportation technologies are evolving, and we use our policy tools to support these innovations and make sure they deliver convenience, safety, and economic opportunity for the American people.</p>
<p>At any time in history, and certainly in ours, innovation shapes and reshapes how people and goods move to where they need to be. But in recent years, “innovation” has become such a buzzword that it risks losing its meaning—and policymakers risk losing our focus as we contend with the constantly shifting and rapidly developing world of transportation technology.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2253276" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>As policymakers, we must prioritize. We need to assess which important innovations will develop on their own, and which require federal support for basic research. We must consider when a technology should be given as much room as possible to develop experimentally, and when it raises concerns that require regulation to keep people safe.</p>
<p>The current decade is especially full of challenges and opportunities from developments in transportation technology. We are witnessing the rise of electric and autonomous vehicles, the widespread adoption of recreational and commercial drones, renewed attention to cybersecurity vulnerabilities in our infrastructure, increasingly routine commercial space travel, and, perhaps most urgently, the high-stakes race to dramatically reduce transportation’s impact on our climate before it’s too late.</p>
<p>Amid these changes, the role of public policy is not always obvious, but it’s always important. To inform our work, today our department is establishing a set of six guiding principles for our work on innovation in transportation.</p>
<p>Innovation is not an end in itself, but a chance to improve. Our innovation efforts should serve our most important public policy goals, like creating economic opportunity, advancing equitable access to transportation, and helping to confront the climate crisis.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Innovation should be shaped in ways that help America win the 21st century, with transportation systems and infrastructure that make communities more competitive, adaptable, and resilient.</p>
<p>Our innovation strategy must support workers, knowing that our choices will help to define whether any given technological development meets its potential to create economic benefits for all.</p>
<p>A good innovation strategy allows for experimentation and learns from setbacks, because these are indispensable parts of the scientific method that underpin all invention and discovery.</p>
<p>Our approach to innovation should center on opportunities to collaborate, recognizing the distinct but related roles of the public, private, and academic sectors.</p>
<p>And finally, our policies should be flexible and adapt as technology changes, because we can’t prepare for an evolving future with policy that only makes sense under present or past conditions.</p>
<p>These principles will help us to ensure that the enormous potential of U.S. transportation innovation benefits our nation and its people. To some, “government” and “innovation” are not words that go together naturally. But in reality, the public sector has always played a vital role in unlocking the innovative capacity of the American people.</p>
<p>Consider the smartphone, an invention that transformed the way we live in a matter of just a few years. Smartphones could only be the result of private-sector inventions and marketing—the natural role of private companies, not government departments. But the technologies on which smartphones depend—like microprocessors, lithium batteries, touchscreens, GPS, and indeed the internet itself—were all supported or invented by government researchers.</p>
<p>Some of our largest tech companies—including Google, Apple, and Tesla—benefited from government subsidies, loan guarantees, or other public support early in their growth.</p>
<p>And while government is far from the source of all invention, it does have a responsibility to help ensure that all inventions are safe and practical for the public.</p>
<p>Government didn’t invent planes, trains, or automobiles, but it did build airports, lay tracks, and construct highways. It enacted laws requiring seat belts and air bags, and created an air traffic control system so that people could travel safely.</p>
<p>As secretary of Transportation, I’ve had the privilege of seeing firsthand the latest frontiers of transportation innovation in our country.</p>
<p>In Georgia last year, I saw the nation’s first-ever solar roadway, which provides clean power for nearby electric vehicle (EV) chargers. In Oregon, I test-drove one of the electric buses that cities around the country are embracing as cleaner and quieter alternatives to outdated diesel vehicles. And in North Carolina, I visited an advanced research lab working on an extremely important, if unglamorous, subject: the future of pavement, including more durable asphalt and even materials that can recycle carbon dioxide.</p>
<p>American companies and scientists are at work every day pushing the boundaries of what is possible in transportation. And our department is at work every day supporting basic research and maintaining the guardrails that ensure those technologies unfold in ways that are safe, equitable, and clean. In the years ahead, these core principles will guide that work—and thanks to President Biden’s historic Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, we have new resources to support those efforts.</p>
<p>These investments will help more Americans adopt electric vehicles and save money on fuel. They will help more children take the bus to school without being exposed to toxic fumes. And they will put more people to work creating the infrastructure of the future.</p>
<p>When it comes to transportation innovation, perhaps the hardest thing to predict is the timing of how and when these developments will impact our everyday lives. Less than 60 years passed between the first flight at Kitty Hawk and the first crewed American spaceflight. Less than 10 years after the first smartphones hit the market, ride-sharing was overtaking taxi use in many American cities. Electric vehicles were in commercial production in 1902 at Studebaker factories in my hometown of South Bend, Indiana—only to all but disappear for most of the 20th century, then re-emerge as a dominant force in the 21st.</p>
<p>It’s not the job of policymakers to guess or dictate how and when these advancements will unfold. But our role in supporting, fostering, and safeguarding the work of transportation innovation is vital, and it comes at an exceptionally important time in the story of American transportation. The decade ahead will bring countless transformative changes in how people and goods move around the country and the world. And the Department of Transportation will be here to help support those innovations and ensure they benefit us all.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/steering-innovation-toward-the-public-good/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2253276</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canada&#8217;s Assent Compliance lands $350M from Vista Equity for supply chain data management</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/canadas-assent-compliance-lands-350m-from-vista-equity-for-supply-chain-data-management/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/canadas-assent-compliance-lands-350m-from-vista-equity-for-supply-chain-data-management/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Assent Compliance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vista equity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2254258</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Never before has the importance of a smooth-flowing supply chain been as clear as it has been in the COVID-19 pandemic era. For manufacturers in particular, managing intricate supply chains can be particularly challenging. Enter Assent Compliance &#8212; a Canadian company focused on supply chain sustainability management. Put more simply, Ottawa-based Assent aims to help [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Never before has the importance of a smooth-flowing supply chain been as clear as it has been in the COVID-19 pandemic era. For manufacturers in particular, managing intricate supply chains can be particularly challenging.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Enter </span><a href="https://www.assentcompliance.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Assent Compliance</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8212; a Canadian company focused on supply chain sustainability management. Put more simply, Ottawa-based Assent aims to help manufacturers make smarter decisions regarding “who they do business with and how their products are sourced,” notes CEO Andrew Waitman.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And today, the company is announcing it has raised $350 million at a valuation of more than $1 billion in a funding round led by Vista Equity Partners. The financing follows a $131 million Series C raise led by Warburg Pincus, which remains the company’s largest shareholder.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2254258" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Interestingly, Assent was bootstrapped for the first five years of its life &#8212; from 2010 to 2015. In the subsequent years, after Waitman came on as CEO, the company has raised over $500 million and grew its headcount from about 20 to 820 today (45% of which identify as female). While half a billion dollars raised in the U.S. is not uncommon, it’s a bit more rare in the Canadian tech scene.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Assent’s trajectory continues to grow and Waitman projects the SaaS company will cross $100 million in annual recurring revenue (ARR) this year after growing ARR by over 50% in the past 12 months. Its customers include the likes of </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">GE Appliances, Polaris, Stryker and Escatec.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company delivers enterprise-wide supply chain sustainability solutions across product compliance, trade compliance and ESG &#8212; better known as</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Environmental, Social and (Corporate) Governance</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Assent has made a name for itself by being exclusively focused on complex manufacturing. Doubling down on that niche has allowed it to build what it claims is “the industry&#8217;s largest network of supplier intelligence.” Specifically, it works to help complex manufacturers proactively identify and manage risk, accelerate market access and growth and promote brand reputation.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Assent’s compliance platform provides centralized access to supply chain data for use by teams across a given company. It automates data collection and validation and provides &#8220;configurable&#8221; reporting so that its customers “can stay ahead” of their data requirements.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The increasing complexity and scale of regulations and varying requirements globally, combined with a heightened focus on ESG, presents challenges for companies across industries, particularly for manufacturers,” Waitman said. “Assent enables deep insight and rapid transparency to help ensure products are made with environmental and human rights standards necessary to compete — and win — in markets of the future.&#8221;</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EXf5zqEoLh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/canadas-startup-market-booms-alongside-hot-global-vc-investment/">Canada’s startup market booms alongside hot global VC investment</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Canada’s startup market booms alongside hot global VC investment&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/canadas-startup-market-booms-alongside-hot-global-vc-investment/embed/#?secret=EXf5zqEoLh" data-secret="EXf5zqEoLh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company plans to use its new capital mostly to continue expanding in Europe, eventually enter the Asian market and grow its headcount by 40% across its sales, services, engineering, customer success and marketing teams.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Manufacturing represents 20% of GDP,” Waitman told TechCrunch. “It’s an enormous market.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vista’s Foundation Fund, which invests in middle-market companies seeking to scale and accelerate their growth trajectory, led the investment. Vista’s Patrick Severson, co-head of the Vista Foundation Fund, and Jake Hodgman, managing director of the Foundation Fund, will join the Assent board of directors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Companies globally are facing increased demand to ensure they source their components and raw materials in an ethical and responsible manner, either from government regulators who oversee them or from customers and partners whose expectations hold them to higher standards, noted Severson. Assent is “ahead of the curve” when it comes to solving enterprise supply chain challenges through technology.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Assent’s solution empowers companies to mitigate their brand and reputation risk and become better corporate citizens,” </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Severson added. “The scrutiny being placed on complex manufacturers in how they manage their supply chains is only increasing. Assent is uniquely positioned to be a clear leader in a future focused on manufacturers adopting supply chain sustainability best practices.” </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/canadas-assent-compliance-lands-350m-from-vista-equity-for-supply-chain-data-management/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2254258</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Illegal movie streaming service Popcorn Time shuts down</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/illegal-movie-streaming-service-popcorn-time-shuts-down/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/illegal-movie-streaming-service-popcorn-time-shuts-down/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[popcorn time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2254401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Popcorn Time, the app that was once popular for making pirating movies as easy as watching Netflix, has shut down. Its original developers abandoned it in 2014 but it has survived as open source.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Mariella Moon</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Mariella Moon is an associate editor at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/whatsapp-begins-offering-novi-money-transfers-to-some-users-in-the-us/">WhatsApp begins offering Novi money transfers to some users in the US</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/spacex-launches-a-nasa-telescope-that-will-observe-black-holes/">SpaceX launches a NASA telescope that will observe black holes</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Popcorn Time, the app that was once popular for making pirating movies as easy as watching Netflix, has <a href="https://popcorn-time.tw/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="14" data-v9y="1">shut down</a>. Its original developers <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2014-03-15-torrent-front-end-popcorn-time-made-streaming-movies-free-and-ea.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="15" data-v9y="1">took the service down</a> and abandoned the project merely a few days after it launched in 2014. But since the project was open source, other developers were able pick up where they left off, and it&#8217;s been killed and revived a few more times ever since. It remains to be seen whether Popcorn Time is now gone for good, but it looks like the biggest contributor to its most recent demise is the dwindling interest in the app.</p>
<p>On its website, the developers posted a graph of &#8220;popcorn time&#8221; searches over the past seven years. While the app enjoyed a ton of searches in the months after its launch in 2015, the graph shows a sharp decline in interest by 2016. Its popularity continued to wane, and it never really recovered after that, at least based on Google Trends.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-01-04/popcorn-time-alternative-is-hard-to-find-as-app-shuts-down?sref=10lNAhZ9" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="16" data-v9y="1"><em>Bloomberg</em></a>, the group behind Popcorn Time announced its closure in an email. While they didn&#8217;t say whether law enforcement action was a factor behind their decision to shut down the app this time around, Popcorn Time has had brushes with the law in the past. The original version may have closed after authorities got involved, and Hollywood studios even <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2015-09-02-popcorn-time-hollywood-lawsuit.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="17" data-v9y="1">sued individual users</a> who allegedly downloaded and shared copies of movies illegally.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2254401" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Developers associated with Popcorn Time previously <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2015-03-20-popcorn-time-p2p.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="18" data-v9y="1">talked about</a> how they&#8217;re not responsible for piracy themselves, because the service doesn&#8217;t actually host any content. Instead, it relied on a peer-to-peer sharing system and only provided a way for users to access content hosted on other people&#8217;s computers.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/movie-piracy-app-popcorn-time-shuts-down-115523694.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/illegal-movie-streaming-service-popcorn-time-shuts-down/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2254401</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>iProov snaps up $70M for its facial verification technology, already in use by Homeland Security, the NHS and others</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/iproov-snaps-up-70m-for-its-facial-verification-technology-already-in-use-by-homeland-security-the-nhs-and-others/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/iproov-snaps-up-70m-for-its-facial-verification-technology-already-in-use-by-homeland-security-the-nhs-and-others/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:23:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Access Control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authentication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biometrics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[english channel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[executive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[face id]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facial recognition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[identity management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managing partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mBlox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NHS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rabobank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silver lake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surveillance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2254345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biometrics, and specifically facial recognition, have seen a surge of usage in the last several years, first as a tool to help organizations verify identities digitally against rising waves of fraud and cybercrime; and second as a way to help enable that process even further in our socially-distanced, pandemic-punctuated times. Today, a startup called iProov, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Biometrics, and specifically facial recognition, have seen a surge of usage in the last several years, first as a tool to help organizations verify identities digitally against rising waves of fraud and cybercrime; and second as a way to help enable that process even further in our socially-distanced, pandemic-punctuated times. Today, a startup called <a href="https://www.iproov.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">iProov</a>, which provides face authentication and verification technology to a number of governments and other big organizations &#8212; attracting some controversy in the process &#8212; is announcing $70 million in funding to keep up its growth momentum.</p>
<p>The funding is coming from a single investor, Sumeru Equity Partners out of the Bay Area, which originally started life as a part of Silver Lake before spinning off as an independent operation in 2014. Valuation is not being disclosed, nor is the total raised by the company to date.</p>
<p>London-based iProov has seen a lot of business traction so far in its home market of the U.K., and now it plans to use capital specifically to continue building out its present in the U.S. and other international markets where it&#8217;s already started to get a foothold. iProov works at the large enterprise level and its customer base currently includes U.S. Department of Homeland Security, the U.K.&#8217;s Home Office and National Health Services (NHS), the Australian Taxation Office, GovTech Singapore and banks Rabobank and ING. iProov said 2021 was a bumper year for the company: it tripled its revenues over the year before (although it&#8217;s not disclosing how much that works out to in actual terms).</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2254345" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>As a measure of how much, and how, iProov is getting used, the NHS says that as of <a href="https://www.nhsx.nhs.uk/news/milestone-hit-with-over-16-million-nhs-app-users/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">September 2021</a>, usage of its NHS app &#8212; &#8212; which uses iProov to power the facial verification that is used to register for the app, which then lets you check and show your vaccination status; book doctor appointments; re-order prescriptions; view your medical records; get advice; and more &#8212; ballooned to 16 million users, from just 4 million in May 2021 (now it&#8217;s January and there are likely more).</p>
<p>To be clear, this isn&#8217;t facial recognition &#8212; which founder and CEO Andrew Bud describes as a mere &#8220;commodity&#8221; these days &#8212; but technology, sold as <a href="https://www.iproov.com/iproov-system/technology/genuine-presence-assurance">Genuine Presence Assurance</a> and <a href="https://www.iproov.com/iproov-system/technology/liveness-assurance">Liveness Assurance</a> by iProov &#8212; that lets an organization capture an image of an individual, verify that it&#8217;s real against another piece of ID and not a deepfake or other counterfeit image, and proceed with whatever transaction is going on, all by way of cloud-based remote, virtual mobile technology.</p>
<p>Its peak usage last year last year typically would see iProov getting pinged for more than 1 million facial verifications per day.</p>
<p>But that growth has not come without scrutiny and other controversial attention.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Critics have <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/sep/24/undisclosed-private-companies-analysing-facial-data-from-nhs-app" target="_blank" rel="noopener">slammed</a> iProov and the UK government for a lack of transparency over how user data is handled in process of capturing and authenticating images for biometric verification, particularly given that iProov is a private company working for a public organization; related to that there have been other ethical questions raised between the <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/sep/15/nhs-app-storing-facial-verification-data-via-contract-with-firm-linked-to-tory-donors" target="_blank" rel="noopener">links</a> between some of the startup&#8217;s earliest backers and the Tory Party (which is currently in power in the UK).</p>
<p>And as of this week (timed to coincide with the funding news?) iProov has also been the <a href="https://findbiometrics.com/facetec-sues-iproov-over-alleged-biometric-technology-patent-infringement-501051/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">subject of a patent lawsuit</a> from a U.S. rival called FaceTec, which claims that iProov has copied parts of its technology and is demanding an injunction (something that could be tricky as iProov increases its focus on the U.S.).</p>
<p>Meanwhile, iProov has also been involved in early work to see how and if its facial authentication technology might be applied in other use cases, such <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/apr/03/boris-johnson-to-give-go-ahead-for-trials-of-covid-passports" target="_blank" rel="noopener">these trials</a> to speed up Covid vaccination certification, another potential avenue for scrutiny.</p>
<p>In an interview, Bud was quick to counter the controversial currents that have swirled around his company and the technology that it&#8217;s built.</p>
<p>On the issue of privacy and security, Bud is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewbud/?originalSubdomain=uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">longtime veteran</a> of the telecoms and mobile worlds, initially as an engineer and then an executive, who said that his interest in biometrics was sparked after being burned at his previous company, mBlox, where malicious hackers exploited the company&#8217;s SMS infrastructure and stole millions of dollars from customers.</p>
<p>The experience made him realize how critical security needed to be both at the end of the provider, but as something that was easy for consumers to engage with too. &#8220;It needed to be ultra-inclusive and simple,&#8221; Bud said. &#8220;How can we ensure something like that would never happen again? I had to solve that problem.&#8221; That, he said, was what spurred him to start looking at biometrics, which he believes is the best answer to that question. And from that he built his next company, which became iProov.</p>
<p>&#8220;These are fair questions,&#8221; he said in response to me raising the issue of privacy and data protection at iProov and its work with public and private institutions. &#8220;Privacy is extremely important to iProov and our systems are built to protect users.&#8221; Everything is compliant with GDPR or other government-mandated data protection rules, related to data and how it may or may not be used, he added, and the methods that iProov uses to process user data are built to keep customers and their identities safe from being compromised. He also confirmed that none of the data that passes through its system is used for commercial purposes. iProov runs a policy of not knowing the identities or other personal information realted to any photos, but it does store imagery, specifically to help track and block malicious actors and to track anomalies.</p>
<p>On the subject of the patent infringement lawsuit from FaceTec, Bud dismissed it as &#8220;completely unfounded,&#8221; with a spokesperson sending me a more complete statement after my interview (as well as asking we keep this part out of the story altogether&#8230;):</p>
<p>&#8220;All of our products have been developed in-house and are covered by granted patents. Accusations that we have used [FaceTec] technology in our products are completely unfounded, and iProov will take all appropriate actions to defend itself and its customers.&#8221;</p>
<p>And as for future applications, although the UK government hasn&#8217;t yet shown a willingness to mandate so-called &#8220;Covid passports&#8221; widely &#8212; where people have to provide quick verification of their vaccination status to gain entry to events, public venues, workplaces and more &#8212; the basics of that technology are already there and being used by a number of other customers, Bud said. These include a recent launch from Eurostar (which runs the train under the English Channel between London and cities on the European continent) for passengers to authenticate their various credentials at home, to reduce the amount of dwell time at check in, where they then can walk through simply by showing their faces to a screen.</p>
<p>Facial-related biometrics, Bud said, are likely to remain the mainstay of what iProov and others will develop going forward for these and similar use cases, although the company also offers a palm-based identification method, too. Primarily, however, iProov and others will have to follow the lead of the organizations they work for: their tech will only be as useful as whatn ever biometric information the original organization collects. (And these days, government-issued IDs, with photos, remain the main source of that data.)</p>
<p>As we move ever more processes to digital and cloud-based platforms, finding ever more watertight methods of verifying identities of users, while evading the increasingly sophisticated approaches of fraudsters and malicious hackers, will continue to be a huge priority. Investors seem willing to place bets on iProov being one of the strong players in keeping those services working as they should.</p>
<p class="m_-6092298163636487534gmail-m5006224922490917439msolistparagraph">&#8220;We see iProov as becoming the industry standard to establish the genuine presence of anything (a person, a document etc),&#8221; said Kyle Ryland, a managing partner at Sumeru, in a statement to TechCrunch. &#8220;We hope that iProov will be used not only to accelerate digital onboarding and verification for both online and physical experiences, but also to replace the use of insecure passwords for frictionless authentication and much more. We have a platform that is constantly learning and allows us to remain at the forefront of emerging technologies and new security threats.&#8221;<u></u><u></u></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/iproov-snaps-up-70m-for-its-facial-verification-technology-already-in-use-by-homeland-security-the-nhs-and-others/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2254345</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;How can you understand life if you don&#8217;t look at it live?&#8221; — Eikon Therapeutics rakes in $518M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/how-can-you-understand-life-if-you-dont-look-at-it-live-eikon-therapeutics-rakes-in-518m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/how-can-you-understand-life-if-you-dont-look-at-it-live-eikon-therapeutics-rakes-in-518m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Betuel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drug development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drug discovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2254132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Adam Goulburn, a partner at Lux Capital, was first struck by Eikon Therapeutics’ pitch to use super microscopes to develop drugs when founder Eric Betzig posed a simple question: How can you understand life if you don’t look at it live?  “It was such a simple statement, but it was kind of eye opening to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Adam Goulburn, a partner at Lux Capital, was first struck by <a href="https://www.eikontx.com/">Eikon Therapeutics’</a> pitch to use super microscopes to develop drugs when founder Eric Betzig posed a simple question: </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">How can you understand life if you don’t look at it live? </span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It was such a simple statement, but it was kind of eye opening to me,” Goulburn tells TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The environment within our cells is in perpetual motion: proteins twist, turn and shift in place. But this environment has, even under most microscopes, remained invisible. </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2254132" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That is, until scientists Eric Betzig</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stefan W. Hell</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">William E. Moerner, developed techniques allowing us to </span><a href="https://www.nobelprize.org/prizes/chemistry/2014/press-release/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">“peer into the nanorealm” inside living cells</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> – a feat that earned the team a Nobel Prize in Chemistry in 2014.  Betzig, specifically, was the first to develop super-resolution fluorescence microscopy, which allowed the movement of single molecules to be seen in detail. </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2254158" style="width: 1568px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2254158" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2254158 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/368042-U2OS-0002_WellD02_Point00_ChSPT_10fps_v2-1.gif" alt="" width="1558" height="923" /><p id="caption-attachment-2254158" class="wp-caption-text">The movement of proteins within live cells.</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That innovation has formed the basis of a startup that’s been raking in funding since its founding in 2019. Eikon Therapeutics, co-founded by Betzig, is a biopharmaceutical company with plans to use super-resolution fluorescence microscopy, the data collected by these high powered microscopes, and a host of other tools to develop new drugs. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Thursday, the company announced s $517.8 million Series B round. This follows a $148 million Series A announced in May 2021, and brings the company’s total funding to over $668 million. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">New investors in the Series B round include include funds and accounts advised by T. Rowe </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Price Associates, Canada Pension Plan Investment Board (CPP Investments), EcoR1 Capital, UC Investments (Office of the Chief Investment Officer of the Regents of the University of California), a wholly owned subsidiary of the Abu Dhabi Investment Authority (ADIA), Stepstone Group, Soros Capital, Schroders Capital, Harel Insurance, General Catalyst, E15 VC, Hartford HealthCare Endowment, and AME Cloud Ventures.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Column Group, Foresite Capital, Innovation Endeavors, Horizons Ventures, and Lux Capital, all investors in the company’s Series A round, are returning for the Series B. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“A lot of people throw around the world proprietary technology, but what Eikon, has, in my view, is truly proprietary,” Goulburn said. “We certainly see its ability to give us a unique advantage in finding new biology.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There’s little doubt that super-resolution microscopy contains vast biological potential, but how does it apply to drug development? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One way to think about it is to recall that proteins do most of the work within our cells: they help send signals, carry out chemical reactions, or transport smaller molecules throughout the body, for instance. When we take a drug, we’re introducing another component into that busy workforce with the hope that it will bind to a certain target, and change what’s already going on inside the body (which, presumably, is causing an issue). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tools like super-resolution microscopy allow scientists to see exactly what’s happening when a drug is introduced into a living cell, rather than inferring what’s happening through other types of experiments. And, perhaps, it could also reveal new targets that haven’t been visible before. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We have these super resolution, single particle tracking microscopes that could look into cells,” explains Goulburn. “Then if you add millions of cells in a well, and then add millions of wells, and add millions of drug-like compounds to that well you can really start to explore drug discovery, in the live sense of the word, at scale.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That said, Eikon has been focusing on the “industrialization” of their drug discovery platform – i.e. Developing a process and tools that allow this detailed protein data to be used to make new drugs, or better understand the ones that currently exist. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This process is being overseen by some of the best in the business: namely Roger Perlmutter, former president of Merck Research Laboratories, who </span><a href="https://www.biospace.com/article/merck-s-perlmutter-to-retire-effective-january-1-2021/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">announced his retirement</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from the Merck in 2020. But with this most recent funding round, the company has landed six more C-suite hires. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Daniel Anderson, former VP of biology at Recursion Pharmaceuticals, will join as Chief Scientific Officer. Russ Berman, formerly VP of Engineering at Pacific Biosciences will join as Chief Technical Officer. Alfred Freddie Bowie, Jr., former VP of corporate and business development at Veracyte will join as Chief Financial Officer. Barbara Howes, formerly Chief Human Resources officer at Pliant Therapeutics will join as Chief People Officer and Executive Vice President. Ashish Kheterpal, former Chief Information Officer of PACT Pharma will join as Chief Information Officer, and Ben Thorner formerly Senior Vice President and Head of BD&amp;L at Merck Research Laboratories will join as General Counsel and Chief Business Officer. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Goulburn argues that the Eikon’s technology is ready for industry right now. In a press release, John Hall, an investment analyst at T. Rowe Price also noted that Eikon’s research was already “generating significant volumes of quantitative information about the dynamic behavior of proteins.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> “It’s, in my view, industrialized right now,” Goulburn says. “We’re running drug screens 24/7. It’s the biofactory of the future in my mind.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company is pursuing four unnamed target programs and has one undisclosed partner, but Goulburn did not provide specifics on how those programs are proceeding. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With this most current round of funding, the company will look to grow its 100-person team (ideally, doubling in size, says Goulburn), to accelerate the development of its platform, and advance the discovery programs already in motion.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/how-can-you-understand-life-if-you-dont-look-at-it-live-eikon-therapeutics-rakes-in-518m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2254132</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>HealthLeap raises $1.1M pre-seed to reduce malnutrition in hospitals with clinical AI assistant</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/healthleap-raises-1-1m-pre-seed-to-reduce-malnutrition-in-hospitals-with-clinical-ai-assistant/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/healthleap-raises-1-1m-pre-seed-to-reduce-malnutrition-in-hospitals-with-clinical-ai-assistant/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 11:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fifty years]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HealthLeap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pharmacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seth Bannon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2254236</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Malnutrition is very common among hospitalized patients in the U.S., and its coded prevalence is increasing. Amid this problem lies an opportunity to optimize the overall quality of patient care, improve clinical outcomes and reduce costs. That’s the drive for South Africa-based health tech startup HealthLeap, which focuses on a global healthcare market starting from [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Malnutrition is very common among hospitalized patients in the U.S., and its coded prevalence is increasing. Amid this problem lies an opportunity to optimize the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">overall</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> quality of patient care, improve clinical outcomes and reduce costs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That’s the drive for South Africa-based health tech startup <a href="https://www.healthleap.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">HealthLeap</a>, which focuses on a global healthcare market starting from the U.S. The startup provides a clinical assistant for dietitians working in hospitals. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s emerging from stealth to announce its $1.1 million pre-seed round led by deep tech investor Fifty Years</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Malnutrition happens when there’s a deficiency, excess or imbalance of nutrients in people’s bodies</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This can cause significant adverse effects on people’s physiology and clinical outcomes.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2254236" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">People with diseases can develop malnutrition when they cannot consume adequate quantities or quality of food, or their diet does not reach the proper levels of nutrients to compensate for the specific nutritional needs created by the disease.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">HealthLeap </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">says it is building AI-assisted tools for healthcare professionals to better address hospital malnutrition.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“As a clinical dietitian, I saw many patients suffer due to malnutrition being </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">insufficiently</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> addressed in hospitals, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">partially</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> because clinical dietitians </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are understaffed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and other clinicians are not </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">adequately</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> trained in clinical nutrition,” </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">clinical dietitian and chief research officer</span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jemimameyer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Jemima Meyer</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> told TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I wanted to help dietitians with the complex clinical calculations that they </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">constantly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> tailor to each patient case and their changing medical condition.”</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meyer hacked the first version of a research-backed productivity tool to help her colleagues perform calculations, make decisions using the latest clinical research and treat more patients in less time. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With her brother and CEO</span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/josiah-meyer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Josiah Meyer</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and CTO</span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/raybotha/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Ray Botha</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, they standardized the process, and that was how HealthLeap was launched in April 2021</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company’s AI-based clinical assistant product </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is called</span><a href="https://www.healthleap.io/nutrileap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">NutriLeap</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Its mobile app, which is HIPAA-compliant, helps hospital dietitians (and soon the other healthcare providers they collaborate with) with automated clinical calculations and research-backed suggestions. With this, they can determine precise, personalized nutritional needs </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">significantly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> faster for patients. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We are predicting optimal treatment steps to ensure patients receive adequate nutrition,” said CTO Botha. “The decisions clinicians make inside our app combined with data from other sources, including an EHR integration, will further improve our predictions.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The app is used by 50 dietitians in a private beta program. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company said it has a <a href="https://www.healthleap.io/nutrileap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">waitlist</a> nearing 1,000 dietitians, pharmacists and physicians</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2254386" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2254386" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2254386" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/HealthLeap-founders-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="510" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/HealthLeap-founders-1.jpg 4176w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/HealthLeap-founders-1.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/HealthLeap-founders-1.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/HealthLeap-founders-1.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/HealthLeap-founders-1.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/HealthLeap-founders-1.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/HealthLeap-founders-1.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/HealthLeap-founders-1.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2254386" class="wp-caption-text">HealthLeap founders: Ray Botha, CTO: Josiah Meyer, CEO; Jemima Meyer, CRO</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Malnutrition in hospitals </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is associated</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with</span><a href="https://aspenjournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/ncp.10771"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">3</span></a><a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24247093/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">-5x mortality</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> during a hospital stay. It</span><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2212267213006412" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">affects 30-50%</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of patients, but only</span><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S2212267216315544" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">5%</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">are diagnosed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. HealthLeap says it wants to eradicate hospital malnutrition globally. But for now, it </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is focused</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on the U.S. because of the possibilities the new United States Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) standards unlock. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We believe</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in a future where nutrition is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">uniquely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> optimized for the health of every person. We want to help make nutrition data-driven for everyone, and we’re starting with the people that need it most </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">urgently</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">: hospital patients,” said the chief executive Josiah Meyer. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">“One important data source that got unlocked is Electronic Health Record data due to the USCDI standards</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The USCDI standards, approved in July last year, allow health tech organizations to access </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">previously</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> unavailable health data sources. And with the pandemic </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">massively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> accelerating healthcare professionals’ adoption rates of digital tools, HealthLeap </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is poised</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to capture a significant market share with its software.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to helping clinical dietitians and other healthcare providers (hospital pharmacists, physicians, nurses) identify patients at risk of malnutrition, HealthLeap also prescribes daily quantities of oral, tube, and IV feeding to the patient’s ever-changing needs. The company said it plans to help dietitians to treat patients even after discharge.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">HealthLeap is still very much in the pre-revenue stage. But it won’t stay that way much longer. According to preliminary pricing research carried out by the company, 97% of its target users are willing to pay a monthly subscription fee out of pocket for access to NutriLeap.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Figuring out revenue is good news for startups and the investors backing them. For</span><a href="https://fiftyyears.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Fifty Years</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, HealthLeap’s lead investor that recently</span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/fifty-years-a-deep-tech-investor-has-raised-90-million-from-tens-of-unicorn-founders/#"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> raised $90 million </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">for its third and newest fund, investing in “the next generation of founders that will change the world for the better” is paramount as well. That’s why the firm, which is made up of 44 unicorn founders, backed HealthLeap.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It’s a tragedy that so many die </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">needlessly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> because they don’t get the nutrition they need while in the hospital,” said Fifty Years founding partner Seth Bannon in a statement. “By addressing hospital malnutrition in a scalable way using machine learning, HealthLeap will save dietitians time, save healthcare providers money, and most </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">importantly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> save patients’ lives. That’s easy to get excited about.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">HealthLeap says it will use this pre-seed capital to hire software engineers and data scientists to continue creating smart tools to help clinicians prevent and treat hospital malnutrition.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/healthleap-raises-1-1m-pre-seed-to-reduce-malnutrition-in-hospitals-with-clinical-ai-assistant/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2254236</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reliance Retail backs Dunzo in $240 million funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/reliance-retail-backs-dunzo-in-240-million-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/reliance-retail-backs-dunzo-in-240-million-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 11:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dunzo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reliance Retail]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2254366</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reliance Retail has led a $240 million funding round in Google-backed hyperlocal delivery startup Dunzo as the largest Indian retail chain expands to the instant commerce space, a category that has made inroads in the South Asian market in recent quarters. Reliance Retail is investing $200 million in the round for a 25.8% stake in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Reliance Retail has led a $240 million funding round in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/google-backs-indias-dunzo-in-40-million-funding-round/">Google-backed hyperlocal delivery startup Dunzo</a> as the largest Indian retail chain expands to the instant commerce space, a category that has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/20/zepto-a-10-minute-grocery-delivery-app-in-india-raises-100-million/">made inroads</a> in the South Asian market in recent quarters.</p>
<p>Reliance Retail is investing $200 million in the round for a 25.8% stake in the six-year-old startup, which operates an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/04/dunzo-hyperlocal-ecommerce-delivery/">eponymous hyper-local delivery service</a> in seven cities in India. The new round, a name for which was not disclosed, values the Bengaluru-based startup at $775 million. Existing investors Lightbox, Lightrock, 3L Capital and Alteria Capital also participated in the round.</p>
<p>“We are seeing a shift in consumption patterns online and have been highly impressed with how Dunzo has disrupted the space. Dunzo is the pioneer of Quick commerce in India and we want to support them in furthering their ambitions of becoming a prominent local commerce enabler in the country,” said Isha Ambani, Director of Reliance Retail Ventures Limited, in a statement.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2254366" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“Our merchants will get access to the hyperlocal delivery network of Dunzo to support their growth as they move their business online through Jio Mart,” she added.</p>
<p>Dunzo allows its customers to buy a wide range of items across several categories, from grocery, perishables, pet supplies and medicines to dinner from their neighborhood stores and restaurants. They can also use Dunzo to move their own items &#8212; such laptops, chargers, medicines, and lunch &#8212; around the city.</p>
<p>Last year, it entered the instant delivery space in Bengaluru, offering customers delivery within 15 to 20 minutes. The startup said it is seeing over 20% week-on-week growth without disclosing any figures.</p>
<p>Dunzo said Thursday that it plans to expand to more geographies &#8212; an additional eight cities &#8212; and broaden its quick commerce play with the fresh funds.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>E-commerce accounts for less than 3% of all retail sales in India, according to industry estimates. Mom and pop stores and other neighborhood outlets that dot tens of thousands of cities, towns, villages and slums across the country drive most of the sales in the nation.</p>
<p>Dunzo, which counts Blume Ventures among its investors, is attempting to reimagine how e-commerce and delivery is done in India, thereby posing a challenge to Amazon and Walmart-owned Flipkart, as well as local food and grocery delivery startups such as Swiggy, Zomato, and new comer Zepto.</p>
<p>Kabeer Biswas, cofounder and chief executive of Dunzo, said in Reliance Retail &#8212; which is run by India&#8217;s richest man, Mukesh Ambani &#8212; the startup has found a &#8220;long-term partner with whom we can accelerate growth and redefine how Indians shop for their daily and weekly essentials.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We’re excited by the traction and velocity that Dunzo Daily has achieved and over the next 3 years, we aim to establish ourselves as one of the most reliable quick commerce providers in the country.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/reliance-retail-backs-dunzo-in-240-million-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2254366</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>France spanks Google $170M, Facebook $68M over cookie consent dark patterns</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/cnil-facebook-google-cookie-consent-eprivacy-breaches/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/cnil-facebook-google-cookie-consent-eprivacy-breaches/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 11:03:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cnil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cookie consent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ePrivacy Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Data Protection Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vera Jourova]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2254341</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chalk another one up for decentralized enforcement: France&#8217;s data protection watchdog has slapped headline-grabbing fines on Facebook and Google for failing to respect local (and pan-EU) cookie consent rules. Today, the CNIL said it&#8217;s fined Google €150M (~$170M) and Facebook €60M (~$68M) for breaching French law, following investigations of how they present tracking choices to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Chalk another one up for decentralized enforcement: France&#8217;s data protection watchdog has slapped headline-grabbing fines on Facebook and Google for failing to respect local (and pan-EU) cookie consent rules.</p>
<p>Today, the CNIL <a href="https://www.cnil.fr/en/cookies-cnil-fines-google-total-150-million-euros-and-facebook-60-million-euros-non-compliance">said</a> it&#8217;s fined Google €150M (~$170M) and Facebook €60M (~$68M) for breaching French law, following investigations of how they present tracking choices to users of google.fr, youtube.com and facebook.com.</p>
<p>The regulator said it was acting after receiving a number of complaints.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2254341" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In a clear breach of EU and French law, it found the pair do not offer an option for users to reject non-essential cookies as easily as the option they offer for them to accept all tracking.</p>
<p>So, in short, the tech giants were using manipulative dark patterns to try to force consent.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s an illustrative snippet from the CNIL&#8217;s <a href="https://www.cnil.fr/en/cookies-facebook-ireland-limited-fined-60-million-euros">press release</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8221; &#8230; the information given by the company is not clear since, in order to refuse the deposit of cookies, Internet users must click on a button entitled &#8220;Accept cookies&#8221;, displayed in the second window. It considered that such a title necessarily generates confusion and that the user may have the feeling that it is not possible to refuse the deposit of cookies and that they have no way to manage it.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The restricted committee judged that the methods of collecting consent proposed to users, as well as the lack of clarity of information provided to them, constitute violations of Article 82 of the French Data Protection Act.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Under EU law, if consent is the legal basis being claimed for processing people&#8217;s data there are strict standards that must be adhered to &#8212; consent must be informed, specific and freely given in order for it to be obtained legally.</p>
<p>Long running complaints against Facebook and Google over similarly problematic consent issues continue to languish on the desk of the Irish Data Protection Commission (DPC), meanwhile &#8212; which under the EU&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)&#8217;s one-stop-shop (OSS) mechanism is a quasi centralized enforcer for most of big tech.</p>
<p>The DPC has been accused of dragging its feet on GDPR oversight of tech giants and creating a bottleneck for effective enforcement of the regulation, as the OSS encourages forum shopping &#8212; and Ireland&#8217;s low corporate tax economy appears only too happy to oblige client corporates with low resolution regulatory oversight too.</p>
<p>Notably, the CNIL is taking action against Facebook and Google under an earlier piece of EU legislation &#8212; the ePrivacy Directive &#8212; which gives competence to national agencies in their own territories. So the French continue to find creative ways to apply GDPR data protection standards nationally, despite the OSS and Irish GDPR blockage.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s a particular irony here, in that Google and Facebook involved themselves in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/digging-into-googles-push-to-freeze-eprivacy/">regional lobbying efforts to delay a planned update to the ePrivacy Directive</a> &#8212; which would have replaced it with a regulation, as we&#8217;ve reported before.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eIRrojVabg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/digging-into-googles-push-to-freeze-eprivacy/">Digging into Google&#8217;s push to freeze ePrivacy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Digging into Google&#8217;s push to freeze ePrivacy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/digging-into-googles-push-to-freeze-eprivacy/embed/#?secret=eIRrojVabg" data-secret="eIRrojVabg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/07/eprivacy-an-overview-of-europes-other-big-privacy-rule-change/">ePrivacy Regulation</a> still hasn&#8217;t been adopted &#8212; despite being proposed back in 2017! Which creates inconsistencies between EU law. But does also leaves Member State-level regulators such as CNIL free to enforce ePrivacy rules within their own jurisdictions, retaining decentralized power to sanction big tech on its home turf under the ePrivacy Directive. So, er, oopsy! That&#8217;s turned into a fairly expensive mistake for Facebook and Google in France at least.</p>
<p>France&#8217;s regulator has been especially busy on this front &#8212; fining Google €100M back in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/france-fines-google-120m-and-amazon-42m-for-dropping-tracking-cookies-without-consent/">December 2020</a> for dropping tracking cookies without consent. At the same time it also stung Amazon €35M over the same issue.</p>
<p>Earlier, the CNIL even managed to get an early GDPR fine in against Google &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/21/french-data-protection-watchdog-fines-google-57-million-under-the-gdpr/">all the way back in 2019</a> &#8212; before the company realized its legal exposure and switched the legal entity handling EU users&#8217; data from the US to Ireland so that its regional business would fall under the DPC&#8217;s &#8216;less muscular&#8217; oversight.</p>
<p>To date, Google has not faced a single sanction under GDPR out of Ireland &#8212; despite a number of very substantial and very long running complaints filed against it, including over <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/25/facebook-google-face-first-gdpr-complaints-over-forced-consent/">forced consent</a>; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/04/googles-location-tracking-finally-under-formal-probe-in-europe/">its handling of location data</a>; and its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/22/googles-lead-eu-regulator-opens-formal-privacy-probe-of-its-adtech/">adtech</a>.</p>
<p>Complaints are not only continuing to stack up against tech giants over systemic breaches of EU data protection law and against the DPC for its embarrassingly thin record on enforcement &#8212; and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/facebooks-lead-eu-privacy-supervisor-hit-with-corruption-complaint/">even for alleged corruption, in a more recent charge against Ireland</a> &#8212; but also against the European Commission itself which <a href="https://twitter.com/johnnyryan/status/1478683243193024512">stands accused</a> of failing in its duty to monitor GDPR enforcement at a Member State level.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">My reply to Didier Reynders, European Justice Commissioner, on 14 December is now public. The Commission must act to uphold data protection law. <br />His recent letter to MEPs, covered by <a href="https://twitter.com/vmanancourt?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@vmanancourt</a>, is perplexing. <a href="https://t.co/kt2nkfV8Se">https://t.co/kt2nkfV8Se</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Johnny Ryan (@johnnyryan) <a href="https://twitter.com/johnnyryan/status/1478683243193024512?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 5, 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The Commission did intervene verbally <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/gdpr-centralized-enforcement/">late last year</a> &#8212; with a direct warning to data protection agencies that GPDR enforcement must become &#8220;effective&#8221; fast or else it suggested DPAs would face having such power taken out of their hands &#8212; in favor of centralized enforcement by the EU executive.</p>
<p>At the same time, Google and Facebook were also blasted by the Commission which accused adtech giants of choosing legal tricks over genuine compliance with the bloc&#8217;s privacy standards, with commissioner Vera Jourová warning: &#8220;I<span lang="EN-GB">t is high time for those companies to take protection of personal data seriously. I want to see full compliance, not legal tricks. It’s time not to hide behind small print, but tackle the challenges head on.”</span></p>
<p>But despite firing a few pot-shots, the Commission appears reluctant to actually step in and sanction Ireland, though. So it&#8217;s been left to Member States like France to make the point in another way &#8212; i.e. by having its agencies illustrate that enforcement is not only possible but happening.</p>
<p>(See also: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/google-fined-592m-in-france-for-breaching-antitrust-order-to-negotiate-news-copyright-fees/">France&#8217;s competition watchdog taking tough action against Google</a>, for example.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kJ3g0o5UB9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/google-fined-592m-in-france-for-breaching-antitrust-order-to-negotiate-news-copyright-fees/">Google fined $592M in France for breaching antitrust order to negotiate copyright fees for news snippets</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google fined $592M in France for breaching antitrust order to negotiate copyright fees for news snippets&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/google-fined-592m-in-france-for-breaching-antitrust-order-to-negotiate-news-copyright-fees/embed/#?secret=kJ3g0o5UB9" data-secret="kJ3g0o5UB9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In addition to today&#8217;s headline-grabbing fines, the CNIL has ordered Facebook and Google to change how they present cookie choices to users in France &#8212; giving the pair three months to provide local users with a means of refusing cookies that&#8217;s as simple as the existing means of accepting them &#8212; &#8220;in order to guarantee their freedom of consent&#8221;.</p>
<p>Failure to comply with the order will mean the companies face further penalties &#8212; of €100,000 per day of delay.</p>
<p>The CNIL has been focusing its oversight on cookie consents for some time.</p>
<p>The regulator set a deadline of March 31, 2021 for websites to comply with <a href="https://www.cnil.fr/fr/cookies-et-autres-traceurs-la-cnil-publie-des-lignes-directrices-modificatives-et-sa-recommandation">updated cookie guidance</a> which it published back in October 2020. And, since the end of March, says it has adopted nearly 100 &#8220;corrective measures&#8221; (aka, orders and sanctions) related to non-compliance with the legislation on cookies.</p>
<p>Ireland also published <a href="https://www.dataprotection.ie/sites/default/files/uploads/2020-04/Guidance%20note%20on%20cookies%20and%20other%20tracking%20technologies.pdf">updated cookie guidance</a>, back in April 2020 &#8212; when it said it would give websites and data controllers six months to come into compliance before taking any enforcement action.</p>
<p>However the DPC has once again shown itself to be all mouth and no trousers: Failing to issue any public sanctions in relation to cookie consent violations against commercial entities (and certainly nothing against Facebook or Google on this front).</p>
<p>A DPC decision against Facebook-owned WhatsApp that was issued late <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/whatsapp-faces-267m-fine-for-breaching-europes-gdpr/">last year</a> focused on transparency breaches.</p>
<p>The size of that eventual penalty for WhatsApp &#8212; $267M &#8212; was also substantially inflated after interventions by other EU DPAs and the European Data Protection Board; Ireland&#8217;s draft decision had only suggested a fine of up to €50M. Facebook, meanwhile, is seeking to evade the sanction by appealing against it.)</p>
<p>Reached for comment on the CNIL&#8217;s spank for disingenuous cookie consents, a Meta/Facebook spokesperson said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;​​We are reviewing the authority&#8217;s decision and remain committed to working with relevant authorities. Our cookie consent controls provide people with greater control over their data, including a new settings menu on Facebook and Instagram where people can revisit and manage their decisions at any time, and we continue to develop and improve these controls.”</p></blockquote>
<p>The tech giant also pointed to an <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/09/updating-our-cookie-controls-in-europe/">announcement </a>it made in September last year about an update to its local &#8220;cookie controls&#8221; &#8212; when it said it would be giving people in Europe &#8220;a more granular level of control over their cookie choices and more information on what we use different kinds of cookies for, including what information we receive from other apps and websites&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;This work is part of our ongoing efforts to give people greater control over their privacy and align with evolving privacy requirements, such as the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR) and the ePrivacy Directive (ePD),&#8221; it added at the time.</p>
<p>Whatever the specific fiddles Facebook made back then the changes don&#8217;t seem to have impressed the French.</p>
<p>At the time of writing Google had not responded to a request for comment on CNIL&#8217;s sanction but we&#8217;ll update this report if we get one.</p>
<p><strong>Update: </strong>A Google spokesperson said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;People trust us to respect their right to privacy and keep them safe. We understand our responsibility to protect that trust and are committing to further changes and active work with the <span class="il">CNIL</span> in light of this decision under the ePrivacy Directive.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cNaHzeUG5s"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/30/europes-cookie-consent-reckoning-is-coming/">Europe&#8217;s cookie consent reckoning is coming</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe&#8217;s cookie consent reckoning is coming&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/30/europes-cookie-consent-reckoning-is-coming/embed/#?secret=cNaHzeUG5s" data-secret="cNaHzeUG5s" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dZUhFwVZGV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/gdpr-centralized-enforcement/">EU warns adtech giants over &#8216;legal tricks&#8217; as it moots changes to centralize privacy oversight</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;EU warns adtech giants over &#8216;legal tricks&#8217; as it moots changes to centralize privacy oversight&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/gdpr-centralized-enforcement/embed/#?secret=dZUhFwVZGV" data-secret="dZUhFwVZGV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fdivli954y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/facebooks-lead-eu-privacy-supervisor-hit-with-corruption-complaint/">Facebook&#8217;s lead EU privacy supervisor hit with corruption complaint</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook&#8217;s lead EU privacy supervisor hit with corruption complaint&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/facebooks-lead-eu-privacy-supervisor-hit-with-corruption-complaint/embed/#?secret=fdivli954y" data-secret="fdivli954y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/cnil-facebook-google-cookie-consent-eprivacy-breaches/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2254341</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>YC-backed Namibian startup JABU gets $3.2M for its B2B e-commerce and retail play</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/yc-backed-namibian-startup-jabu-gets-3-2m-for-its-b2b-e-commerce-and-retail-play/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/yc-backed-namibian-startup-jabu-gets-3-2m-for-its-b2b-e-commerce-and-retail-play/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 08:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Afore Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cameroon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FJ Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment banker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lagos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meesho]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[morocco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PWC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southern Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zambia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2253794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Namibian business-to-business e-commerce startup JABU confirmed to TechCrunch that it has raised a $3.2 million financing round. The seed round, which was closed last year, welcomed investors such as Afore Capital, Y Combinator, FJ Labs, Quiet Capital, Kli Capital, Pareto Capital and unnamed angels. As a last-mile distribution e-commerce company, JABU joins a list of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Namibian business-to-business e-commerce startup <a href="https://www.gojabu.com/">JABU</a> confirmed to TechCrunch that it has raised a $3.2 million financing round.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The seed round, which was closed last year, welcomed investors such as Afore Capital, Y Combinator, FJ Labs, Quiet Capital, Kli Capital, Pareto Capital and unnamed angels.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a last-mile distribution e-commerce company, JABU joins a list of startups across the continent that help small retailers order and stock their products and, at the same time, provide data-driven services to suppliers and manufacturers.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2253794" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CEO <a href="https://na.linkedin.com/in/davidakinin">David Akinin</a> founded JABU in mid-2020 to fix Namibia’s inefficient and almost nonexistent supply chain and distribution.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Its platform connects over 6,000 retailers to local and multinational suppliers — such as Namibia Breweries Limited, ABInBev, Bokomo, Coca-Cola, Namibmills — and digitizes orders, payments and logistics.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Namibian startup has its fleet of vehicles along with eight distribution centers</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Suppliers using the platform have dashboards to see where their products are being delivered, check key performance indicators and book merchandising. They can also make advertising and marketing campaigns at shops, perform product giveaways and tap</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> into merchandising revenue.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">JABU operated in stealth mode for much of last year. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It got into Y Combinator during the accelerator’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/here-are-all-the-companies-from-y-combinators-summer-2021-demo-day-part-1/">summer batch</a> in 2021, the first time for a Namibian startup</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup doesn’t appear in our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/this-yc-summer-batch-features-the-largest-group-of-african-startups-yet/">curated list</a> because it deferred its Demo Day until this year’s winter batch, where up to 15 African startups </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">have </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">been selected by</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Y Combinator, according to some sources.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last year saw venture capital firms and institutional investors scramble to back newly formed and existing business-to-business e-commerce retail startups. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the earliest in the space, Nigerian B2B e-commerce platform <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/06/tradedepot-raises-110m-from-ifc-novastar-to-extend-bnpl-service-to-merchants-across-africa/">TradeDepot</a>, raised a combined $110 million in debt and equity</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Startups from other parts of Africa that raised investments include Morocco’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/chari-a-moroccan-startup-digitizing-mom-and-pop-stores-raises-5m-at-70m-valuation/">Chari,</a> Egypt’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/egyptian-startup-capiter-raises-33m-to-expand-b2b-e-commerce-platform-across-mena/">Capiter</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/05/maxab-the-egyptian-b2b-food-and-grocery-delivery-startup-raises-40m-for-expansion/">MaxAB</a>, and Kenya’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/kenyas-twiga-raises-50m-to-scale-affordable-food-solutions-across-africa/">Twiga</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/kenyas-marketforce-raises-2m-plans-to-focus-on-its-b2b-retail-marketplace-rejareja/">MarketForce</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">JABU shines a light on the Southern Africa region. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company operates in three cities in Namibia and recently expanded into two Zambian cities</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Its monthly GMV has grown 25x and the average growth of delivered SKUs stands at </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">nearly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 53% monthly since March. The company said that revenue has also seen a 35x growth within the same time frame.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As with most African countries, Namibia is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">heavily</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> reliant on cash. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">And JABU — profiting from owning its supply chain — is making efforts to digitize its physical cash collection processes via wallets</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When the money from retailers arrives at JABU distribution centers, it </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">typically</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> takes 48 hours to settle into the banks</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Instead of going through this mundane process, JABU’s wallets will allow merchants to deposit and withdraw money immediately in sync with these centers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our volumes growth grew so much and we’ve picked up so much money in physical currency, the banks and others have sat down and said, ‘How can we fix this</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">?’ I mean, we went from having a couple R100,000 (rands) a week to having millions of Namibian dollars. And we realized there’s something better and bigger than we originally tapped into,” Akinin said about why the company is creating wallets for its merchants.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Akinin said the next stage of JABU’s wallet system would see merchants offering other services to consumers on top of their digitized cash. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The only way to do that is by partnering with the merchants, and they go through a [know your customer] process, we make sure the merchants have the right space and the right account </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">to</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> back their float. And then they transact with their customers. So we’re entering the B2B2C space through the merchants that we work with,” he said.</span></p>
<p>JABU’s revenue largely comes from distribution it carries out itself or via third-party fleets<span style="font-weight: 400;">. Merchandising and targeted marketing and advertising also bring in bucks for the company. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It will take commissions from transactions performed on merchants’ wallets in the future</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2254329" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2254329" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2254329" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/PhotoPictureResizer_220106_090055066_crop_2515x2285.jpg?w=680" alt="Jabu" width="680" height="618" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/PhotoPictureResizer_220106_090055066_crop_2515x2285.jpg 2515w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/PhotoPictureResizer_220106_090055066_crop_2515x2285.jpg?resize=150,136 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/PhotoPictureResizer_220106_090055066_crop_2515x2285.jpg?resize=300,273 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/PhotoPictureResizer_220106_090055066_crop_2515x2285.jpg?resize=768,698 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/PhotoPictureResizer_220106_090055066_crop_2515x2285.jpg?resize=680,618 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/PhotoPictureResizer_220106_090055066_crop_2515x2285.jpg?resize=1536,1396 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/PhotoPictureResizer_220106_090055066_crop_2515x2285.jpg?resize=2048,1861 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/PhotoPictureResizer_220106_090055066_crop_2515x2285.jpg?resize=50,45 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2254329" class="wp-caption-text">David Akinin (Co-founder and CEO, JABU)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Akinin, who had a stint at Google as a sales and goods analyst, also spent parts of his professional career as an investment banker at Credit Suisse</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. He would later make a series of visits to top African cities like Johannesburg, Lagos and Addis Ababa, but it was in Windhoek that he found the spark to try something new.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Namibia had huge housing demand at the time. Akinin launched a startup to offer digital mortgages but pivoted to a construction company with a presence in Namibia, Zambia and Cameroon.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Due to the pandemic, Akinin’s construction company embarked on a COVID relief program to donate food supplies in Namibia</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Then, he stumbled on the country’s B2B e-commerce retail opportunity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We went into the informal sector and realized that the city had shut down every single informal retailer</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. And when they did that, we had this software we had developed to like digitize housing demand,” he said, describing how JABU started. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">hired 40 people from the community and in about one or two weeks, we registered 1,000 shops that had </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">been affected by</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> this shutdown. We realized that there’s a huge opportunity here to not only help them reopen but understand something very key here that they have no supply chain and also no way of sourcing their products at an affordable rate.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Informal retail is still king in Africa. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">A<a href="https://www.pwc.co.za/en/press-room/retail-in-africa.html"> study by PwC</a> reported that informal channels such as kiosks and mom-and-pop stores account for 90% of sales in Africa’s major economies</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The opportunity is so large that some startups, such as Nigerian B2B retail platform Sabi (a Rensource spinoff), said it was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/25/rensource-spinoff-sabi-closes-6m-bridge-round-expands-b2b-retail-platform-outside-nigeria/">processing almost $12 million monthly GMV,</a> TechCrunch learned in an interview with its founders in November.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">JABU, with more than 200 employees, is gearing for a Series A fundraising this quarter, Akinin told TechCrunch. The startup will use the seed round and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">subsequent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> growth round </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">to expand into Botswana and South Africa, grow its tech and operations team, and train its field agents.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/06/yc-backed-namibian-startup-jabu-gets-3-2m-for-its-b2b-e-commerce-and-retail-play/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2253794</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Payroll startup PayFit is France’s latest unicorn as it raises $289 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/payroll-startup-payfit-is-frances-latest-unicorn-as-it-raises-289-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/payroll-startup-payfit-is-frances-latest-unicorn-as-it-raises-289-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 06:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payfit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payroll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2253954</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup PayFit just announced that it closed a new $289 million Series E round (€254 million) before the holidays. Following this round, the startup has reached a post-money valuation of $2.1 billion (€1.82 billion). The company has been building a payroll and HR software-as-a-service platform for small and medium companies. It is operating in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://payfit.com/en/">PayFit</a> just announced that it closed a new $289 million Series E round (€254 million) before the holidays. Following this round, the startup has reached a post-money valuation of $2.1 billion (€1.82 billion).</p>
<p>The company has been building a payroll and HR software-as-a-service platform for small and medium companies. It is operating in a handful of European countries — around 150,000 people currently get paid through PayFit.</p>
<p>General Atlantic is leading the round, while some of PayFit’s existing investors are participating once again, such as Eurazeo, Bpifrance&#8217;s Large Venture fund and Accel.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2253954" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The startup has been on a roll as it raised a Series D round <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/17/payfit-raises-107-million-for-its-payroll-and-hr-platform/">in March 2021</a>. I asked about PayFit’s valuation and how it has changed since the Series D.</p>
<p>“It’s true that we had never communicated about our valuation before. We only shared the size of our funding rounds,” co-founder and CEO Firmin Zocchetto told me. “I can only tell you that our valuation has greatly increased.”</p>
<p>He listed two reasons why PayFit has had little issues raising at a higher valuation. First, the company is doing well when it comes to revenue. The startup’s annual recurring revenue has increased by 70% in 2021.</p>
<p>Second, there’s a lot of money floating around for the best performing tech companies. He said that the current climate is “extremely favorable.” And I bet a lot of people would recommend taking advantage of the situation.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>The market opportunity</h2>
<p>But let’s try to dissect PayFit’s business a bit more to find out how the company ended up here. PayFit lets you manage your payroll from a web browser and automate as many steps as possible.</p>
<p>PayFit has a product advantage compared to other solutions as you don’t need to be an expert and work for an accounting firm to generate payroll. The startup makes sure you remain compliant and hides the complexity. For instance, if there are regulatory changes, PayFit will update the logic of its application.</p>
<p>The company also has a big market opportunity. Every company needs a payroll solution <em>and</em> it’s incredibly hard to switch from one solution to another — it’s the perfect Venn diagram for a software-as-a-service product.</p>
<p>There are currently 6,000 companies using PayFit. Around 80% of them are based in France. Other customers are located in Spain, Germany or the U.K. Most importantly, when someone creates a company from scratch, many of them choose PayFit and stick with it.</p>
<p>When you think about it, 150,000 employees getting paid through PayFit is not that much. There are tens of millions of employees in France, the U.K., Spain and Germany. Before opening a branch in new countries, PayFit wants to capture more market share in these four markets.</p>
<p>Labor laws vary from one country to another, which means that there could be different geographical leaders as there’s a natural barrier to entry. For instance, <a href="https://gusto.com">Gusto</a> and <a href="https://justworks.com">Justworks</a> are doing well in the U.S. but they don’t operate in other markets. It&#8217;s going to be important to see if PayFit has what it takes to become the clear market leader in France, the U.K., Germany and Spain.</p>
<p>Finally, once PayFit owns the relationship with the HR or admin specialist in the client company, it can provide additional services. “We started with payroll, but what we really care about is the employer-employee relationship,” Zocchetto said.</p>
<p>PayFit offers different tools to manage vacation, facilitate onboarding, manage time sheets and track employee expenses. Soon, the company will also offer a way to handle annual performance reviews in PayFit.</p>
<p>Essentially, PayFit is part of a cohort of startups that are reinventing the admin stack. PayFit’s founder names Qonto and Alan as two companies that are also working on overhauling back-end tools. <a href="https://qonto.com/en">Qonto</a> offers bank accounts for SMBs while <a href="https://alan.com">Alan</a> offers health insurance products for companies.</p>
<p>With 700 employees in Paris, Berlin, Barcelona and London, PayFit now wants to diversify its product offering, integrate with more third-party products and improve its customer service. The company wants to “offer small companies the same perks that you would get by working for big companies,” Zocchetto said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/payroll-startup-payfit-is-frances-latest-unicorn-as-it-raises-289-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2253954</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AARP Innovation Labs takes a holistic approach to age-tech at CES</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/aarp-innovation-labs-takes-a-holistic-approach-to-age-tech-at-ces/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/aarp-innovation-labs-takes-a-holistic-approach-to-age-tech-at-ces/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 05:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AARP Innovation Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Age tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beeyonder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Camino Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ces 2022]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Consumer Electronics Show]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Embleema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Folia Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gameboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Genivity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goalsetter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JoyLux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kinoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mighty health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MindMics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NexStride]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ompractice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tellus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tembo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trust and Will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zibrio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2254309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When young (or youngish) people think of age-tech, they may picture mostly clinical solutions—telemedicine platforms, for instance. Growing older, however, doesn’t just have a physical component. Isolation, for example, is a serious issue for elderly people, especially during the pandemic. And older people still have to manage their day-to-day routines and finances, not just plan [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When young (or youngish) people think of age-tech, they may picture mostly clinical solutions—telemedicine platforms, for instance. Growing older, however, doesn’t just have a physical component. Isolation, for example, is a serious issue for elderly people, especially during the pandemic. And older people still have to manage their day-to-day routines and finances, not just plan estates and wills.</p>
<p>AARP Innovation Labs, the incubator program, highlights the many facets of aging <a href="https://aarpinnovationlabs.org/ces/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in its CES’ virtual presentation</a> with a roster of startups that were divided into five groups: community, clinic, wellness, financial services and housing.</p>
<p>The program included fintech startups because of the pandemic’s economic impact, focusing on three companies that “are helping aging populations better manage finances and budgets, and effectively plan for the future.” Originally created to teach kids and teenagers financial literacy, <a href="https://www.goalsetter.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Goalsetter</a> is expanding its reach to more people with savings and investment management tools. <a href="https://www.genivity.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Genivity</a> creates customized financial projections based on users’ health and lifestyle habits, medical conditions and retirement goals, showing them how many years they might need to work before retiring and and what point they may need extended care. <a href="https://trustandwill.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Trust &amp; Will</a>, meanwhile, makes it easy for families to create guardianship plans, wills and trusts.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2254309" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8NsxlPqLls"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/01/goalsetter-raises-15-million-to-go-b2b-with-childrens-financial-literacy-app/">Goalsetter raises $15 million to go B2B with children&#8217;s financial literacy app</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Goalsetter raises $15 million to go B2B with children&#8217;s financial literacy app&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/01/goalsetter-raises-15-million-to-go-b2b-with-childrens-financial-literacy-app/embed/#?secret=8NsxlPqLls" data-secret="8NsxlPqLls" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Isolation was a serious problem for older adults even before COVID-19 and the pandemic has made loneliness worse. AARP Innovation addresses that problem with its selection of &#8220;community&#8221; startups. While many people already rely on other video chat apps, <a href="https://kinoo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kinoo</a> wants to tailor the experience for families with elderly relatives living away from them. It IoT toys for kids that let them play games and do projects with their grandparents and other family members through Kinoo’s app.</p>
<p>A tabletop console gaming system, <a href="https://lastgameboard.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gameboard</a>, also lets family members enjoy fun time, instead of just chat time, with one another. It hosts hundreds of games, including role-playing games. <a href="https://beeyonder.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Beeyonder</a> is a marketplace for live virtual expert-led tours around the world, and can help alleviate the boredom of staying at home while the pandemic drags on.</p>
<p>Many of the startups in AARP’s incubator focus on aging in place, or helping older people stay in their homes instead of moving into a care facility. Its “Housing” section included three companies focused on personal mobility. <a href="https://www.meetcamino.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Camino Robotics</a> is creating “e-rollators,” or smart walkers with features that help people walk over slopes and uneven surfaces, brake automatically when going downhill and folds into “compact mode” for navigating tight spaces. <a href="https://brazemobility.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Braze Mobility </a>says it can turn any wheelchair into a smart wheelchair with patent-pending blind spot sensors that warn about obstacles through lights, sounds and vibrations. Meanwhile, De Oro Devices’ <a href="https://www.getnexstride.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NexStride</a>, created for people with Parkinson’s, is a small device that can be attached to canes and walkers and uses audio and visual cues to help users overcome freezing episodes and go on longer walks.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Meanwhile, <a href="https://tellusyoucare.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tellus</a> is a startup that helps people live on their own with small wall-mounted sensors that can track biometric data, including heart rate, breathing, sleep and falls, from up to five meters away, and sends alerts to caregivers and family members through an app.</p>
<p>In its wellness category, AARP Innovation presented three startups focused on overall health and well-being. These included Zibrio, which was also part of AARP’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/startups-at-ces-showed-how-tech-can-help-elderly-people-and-their-caregivers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CES line-up last year</a>. <a href="https://www.zibrio.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zibrio</a> is a scale that not only measures weight, but also gauges a person’s balance and fall risk. The company says Zibrio’s balance scale can predict if you are at risk of falling within the next 12 months, and its app then gives personalized care recommendations. While many people track their nutrition and exercise with apps like MyFitnessPal or Noom, <a href="https://mightyhealth.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mighty Health</a> was developed specifically for people over 50 years old. It connects users with a health coach and features nutrition and workout plans created for older adults.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GuDiStzto2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/13/mighty-health-created-a-wellness-app-with-older-adults-top-of-mind/">Mighty Health created a wellness app with older adults top of mind</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Mighty Health created a wellness app with older adults top of mind&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/13/mighty-health-created-a-wellness-app-with-older-adults-top-of-mind/embed/#?secret=GuDiStzto2" data-secret="GuDiStzto2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Mental wellbeing is also incredibly important. <a href="https://www.ompractice.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ompractice</a> was started to help people who “experience geographic, economic and inclusivity barriers” get access to health, wellness and mindfulness features by partnering with fitness studios and working with large organizations, including health systems, to make their services accessible to users.</p>
<p>Of course, improving healthcare and the delivery of health services for older adults is extremely important, especially in the United States with its fragmented healthcare system. Included under AARP Innovation’s “clinic” section, <a href="https://www.foliahealth.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Folia Health</a> is a health “individual operating system” that lets patients answer multiple choice questions each day, when are then reviewed by their providers to help with diagnostic and care plans. It can be used to manage several conditions and communicate with multiple care providers. Telemedicine startup <a href="https://tembo.health/ Tembo Health" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tembo</a>, on the other hand, partners with senior care communities, enabling them to provide remote medical services to their residents or clients. <a href="https://www.embleema.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Embleema</a> was created to make pharmaceutical studies easier by making the evidence generation and regulatory review processes faster.</p>
<p>For individuals, the clinic section included two startups. <a href="https://www.mindmics.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MindMics</a> are smart earbuds that analyze biometrics, including heartrate, and send them to an app. <a href="https://joylux.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">JoyLux</a> specifically addresses menopause with a roster of products, including devices for pelvic floor exercises, lubricants, supplements and cooling pads.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aUc5lw41WQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/hormonal-health-is-a-massive-opportunity-where-are-the-unicorns/">Hormonal health is a massive opportunity: Where are the unicorns?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hormonal health is a massive opportunity: Where are the unicorns?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/hormonal-health-is-a-massive-opportunity-where-are-the-unicorns/embed/#?secret=aUc5lw41WQ" data-secret="aUc5lw41WQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ces-2022/?utm_source=internal&amp;utm_medium=footer-banner"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ces-2022-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about CES 2022 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/aarp-innovation-labs-takes-a-holistic-approach-to-age-tech-at-ces/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2254309</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Korean car-sharing startup SOCAR has filed for an IPO   </title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/korean-car-sharing-startup-socar-has-filed-for-an-ipo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/korean-car-sharing-startup-socar-has-filed-for-an-ipo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 02:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car sharing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car sharing startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[socar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2254273</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SOCAR, a south Korean car-sharing startup, has filed for an initial public offering, announced on Wednesday by Korea Exchange. The details &#8211; the number of shares to be offered in the IPO and the price range &#8211; have not yet been determined, said a spokesperson at SOCAR.  SOCAR has reached approximately $834 billion (1 trillion [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><a href="https://www.socar.kr/">SOCAR</a>, a south Korean car-sharing startup, has filed for an initial public offering, <a href="https://kind.krx.co.kr/listinvstg/listinvstgcom.do?method=searchListInvstgCorpDetail&amp;bizProcNo=20211130000101">announced</a> on Wednesday by <a href="http://open.krx.co.kr/contents/OPN/05/05000000/OPN05000000.jsp#fe3647848b826aa1ddee224c4b5526f4=1&amp;view=25522">Korea Exchange</a>. The details &#8211; the number of shares to be offered in the IPO and the price range &#8211; have not yet been determined, said a spokesperson at SOCAR. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">SOCAR has reached approximately $834 billion (1 trillion won) valuation after raising $50.7 million (60 billion won) in October 2020. The company has raised a total of about $275 million since its inception in 2011, the company spokesperson confirmed.  According to media reports, SOCAR’s estimated valuation is to be $2.5 billion (3 trillion won) after the listing in the first half of this year. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Its previous investors include <a href="https://www.sk-inc.com/en/">SK Holdings</a>, Bain Capital, Premier Partners, SoftBank Ventures Asia, Altos Ventures, KB Investment, Stonebridge Ventures, LB Private Equity, SG Private Equity, and more.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2254273" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The company plans to launch a transportation super app this year that will provide all-in-one mobility services like car-sharing, electric bike-sharing, parking lot search, car-hailing, train reservation and more, Jaewook Park, CEO of SOCAR, said in early December at the company&#8217;s press conference. Park also said SOCAR would replace a fleet of its vehicles with zero-emission, including electric or hydrogen-powered cars, by 2030 and strengthen its autonomous cars business. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">SOCAR will accelerate to make additional acquisitions and advance its technology with the IPO proceeds, Park said. The company already completed two acquisitions last month &#8211; South Korean online parking platform </span><a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://www.moduparking.com/?NaPm=ct%3Dkxgw9k21%7Cci%3Dcheckout%7Ctr%3Dds%7Ctrx%3D%7Chk%3D8d59cd5d1e333d91b3a1bf5d49794f02cf9bbdd9" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Modu Company</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> and electric bike rental platform </span><a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://elecle.bike/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Elecle</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true">. SOCAR also invested in autonomous driving startup <a href="https://www.rideflux.com/">RideFlux</a> in 2018. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The 11-year-old firm started the car-sharing service with 100 rental cars in Jeju in 2011 and launched its mobile app in 2012. SOCAR acquired VCNC, a Korean mobile messaging app platform, in 2018 to operate a van-hailing service Tada. (The startup, however, had to cease its van-hailing service in 2020 because of South Korea’s revised law that restricts ride-hailing to only licensed taxis and limits rental car services from offering drivers, with the exception of vans with 11 to 15 seats.) Last October, SOCAR has <a href="https://en.yna.co.kr/view/AEN20211008005100320">sold</a> a 60% stake in the ride-hailing arm to Viva Republica, the Seoul-based fintech company behind Toss. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">In 2018, SOCAR set up a Malaysia-based subsidiary SOCAR Malaysia, which has raised a total of <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/socar-malaysia/company_financials">$73.2 million</a> so far. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The competition of the mobility platform industry in South Korea has intensified as local car-hailing companies such as <a href="https://www.kakaomobility.com/">Kakao Mobility</a> and <a href="https://www.tmapmobility.com/">TMAP Mobility</a> actively expand their business in the country with ambitions to become the mobility super app. In October, <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/uber-revives-push-south-korea-210000315.html">Uber Technologies</a> also joined the race by forming a joint venture company with TMAP Mobility, owned by Korean telco giant SK Telecom, to offer ride-hailing service in South Korea. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Kakao Mobility reportedly plans to go public in two years while TMAP Mobility aims to list by 2025. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The company spokesperson noted that its car-sharing peers also include Zipcar, Turo, and getaround. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KBvn3LoP9Y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/10/24/socar-koreas-answer-to-zipcar-raises-18-million-but-isnt-looking-overseas-just-yet/">Socar, Korea&#8217;s Answer To Zipcar, Raises $18 Million But Isn&#8217;t Looking Overseas Just Yet</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Socar, Korea&#8217;s Answer To Zipcar, Raises $18 Million But Isn&#8217;t Looking Overseas Just Yet&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2014/10/24/socar-koreas-answer-to-zipcar-raises-18-million-but-isnt-looking-overseas-just-yet/embed/#?secret=KBvn3LoP9Y" data-secret="KBvn3LoP9Y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7VpmsnPw2H"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/01/kakao-mobility-picks-up-additional-55m-funding-at-over-4-2b-valuation/">Kakao Mobility picks up additional $55M funding at over $4.2B valuation </a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Kakao Mobility picks up additional $55M funding at over $4.2B valuation &#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/01/kakao-mobility-picks-up-additional-55m-funding-at-over-4-2b-valuation/embed/#?secret=7VpmsnPw2H" data-secret="7VpmsnPw2H" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HUAWZ59OFh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/car-sharing-startup-turo-has-filed-confidentially-for-an-ipo/">Car-sharing startup Turo has filed confidentially for an IPO</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Car-sharing startup Turo has filed confidentially for an IPO&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/car-sharing-startup-turo-has-filed-confidentially-for-an-ipo/embed/#?secret=HUAWZ59OFh" data-secret="HUAWZ59OFh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="caPnYeOgqG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/20/getaround-raises-45m-from-toyota-and-others-to-build-more-partnerships/">Getaround raises $45M from Toyota and others to build more partnerships</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Getaround raises $45M from Toyota and others to build more partnerships&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/20/getaround-raises-45m-from-toyota-and-others-to-build-more-partnerships/embed/#?secret=caPnYeOgqG" data-secret="caPnYeOgqG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/korean-car-sharing-startup-socar-has-filed-for-an-ipo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2254273</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Your kids can get lost in Disney with these storytelling headphones</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/once-upon-a-time/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/once-upon-a-time/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 02:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ces 2022]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oranoff]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2251003</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Some of my favorite childhood memories include being read to, and learning to read myself to get lost in a book. If you&#8217;ll forgive me the oldmanyellsatcloud.gif moment: It&#8217;s a grievous loss that many children are so comprehensively surrounded by screens that it&#8217;s hard to experience this. I was delighted, then, to see Oranoff launch [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Some of my favorite childhood memories include being read to, and learning to read myself to get lost in a book. If you&#8217;ll forgive me the <em>oldmanyellsatcloud.gif</em> moment: It&#8217;s a grievous loss that many children are so comprehensively surrounded by screens that it&#8217;s hard to experience this. I was delighted, then, to see <a href="https://www.onanoff.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Oranoff</a> launch its StoryPhones product at CES this year. The headphones can, independently of any other devices you connect to them for audio playback store a bunch of audio content within the headphones themselves. Perfect for getting lost in the magic of fairy tales and magic.</p>
<p>The company announced it even snagged a content collaboration with Disney for its launch, with a collection of stories for children, bringing to their ears characters kids are likely to know from the big and small screen. The headphones will ship with stories including some of the best-known characters and stories in the Disney line-up, including Mickey and Minnie Mouse, The Little Mermaid, Frozen, The Lion King, Toy Story, The Incredibles, Monsters Inc. and more. The company claims it has a library of carefully curated content suitable for kiddos aged 3 and up.</p>
<p>In addition to pre-recorded content, the headphones support something the company calls &#8220;PlayShield,&#8221; where parents can record their own stories on a mobile app, and load them onto the headphones for playback later. The company suggests that it is a way to connect with grandparents and far-flung families, bringing them all closer through storytelling.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2251003" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Finally, the product has a feature called ZenShield, which &#8220;contains relaxing audio profiles to help overstimulated kids calm down, relax and even sleep.&#8221; You can think of it as a pause button for the rowdy tykes, I suppose. The sounds include piano music, ocean waves, raindrops and more.</p>
<p>The headphones have a SafeAudio feature built in to keep the volume down to prevent hearing damage to sensitive little children&#8217;s ears, and as a result, it picked up a couple of CES 2022 innovation awards, in the &#8220;Headphones &amp; Personal Audio&#8221; and &#8220;Health &amp; Wellness&#8221; categories.</p>
<p>The headphones can store around 90 minutes of content on its pitiful 64MB of storage &#8211; in a world where a 4GB SD card can be procured for $4, I&#8217;m baffled why the company would only include so little user-accessible storage; perhaps they&#8217;ll re-think that choice in a future version of the headphones.</p>
<p>At first, the headphones are launching across Europe, in Italy, Spain, Austria, Switzerland, Germany, the U.K., and France, in five languages &#8212; Italian, Spanish, German, French and English. The recommended retail price in Europe is £84.99 (around US$115). for the US, The StoryPhones bundle which includes a headphone and either a Mickey or Minnie StoryShield costs $99.90. The StoryShields can be bought individually too and range from $7.99 to $14.99.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ces-2022/?utm_source=internal&amp;utm_medium=footer-banner"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ces-2022-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about CES 2022 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/once-upon-a-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2251003</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>As CES goes hybrid, connected fitness companies have another big year</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/as-ces-goes-hybrid-connected-fitness-companies-have-another-big-year/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/as-ces-goes-hybrid-connected-fitness-companies-have-another-big-year/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 01:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ces 2022]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[connected fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[echelon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2254247</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[CES hasn’t traditionally been the healthiest week for me. Aside from some unintentional intermittent fasting, TechCrunch really has the habit of doing it up with our team dinners at the show, to say nothing of Matt’s near religious devotion to a Mexican place named Tacos &#38; Beer. In my defense, I will say that there’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">CES hasn’t traditionally been the healthiest week for me. Aside from some unintentional intermittent fasting, TechCrunch really has the habit of doing it up with our team dinners at the show, to say nothing of Matt’s near religious devotion to a Mexican place named Tacos &amp; Beer.</p>
<p>In my defense, I will say that there’s never been a year that I haven’t blown through my step count several times over every day of the show. Wandering the hall of the Las Vegas Convention Center will do that to a tech journalist. This year, of course, my steps have been suffering, as TechCrunch opted to attend the show virtually, amid omicron-related concerns.</p>
<p>If I’m being honest, those same concerns left me wondering whether I should be back at the gym, too. I’m sure I’m not alone in that, either. While it’s true that companies like Peloton saw regression as gyms and the like saw re-openings late last year, this pandemic is far from over. And the idea of being in a confined room with a bunch of other heavy breathers seems less than ideal, even as it’s currently too cold to do much working out outside in many parts of the country.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2254247" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="h1Qm30CbpQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/companies-rush-to-replace-the-gym-at-ces/">Companies rush to replace the gym at CES</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Companies rush to replace the gym at CES&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/companies-rush-to-replace-the-gym-at-ces/embed/#?secret=h1Qm30CbpQ" data-secret="h1Qm30CbpQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>It’s always hard to project the longevity of these sorts of trends, but it’s pretty safe to say that the last few years will have proven a sea change for the world of home fitness. I’ve personally spoken with many people who don’t plan to go back to the gym after all of this is over (well, assuming all of this is ever actually over, I guess). That’s not entirely a symptom of the pandemic, of course &#8212; companies like Peloton and Mirror were gaining plenty of traction before many of us knew what a novel coronavirus was.</p>
<p>Of course, when it rains its pours with this stuff. My inbox has been bombarded with home fitness services for the past couple of years. It’s clear that as many companies as possible are looking to capitalize on this moment, and between Peloton’s earnings and transactions like Lululemon’s acquisition of Mirror, how can blame them? We certainly saw an uptick at last year’s all-virtual CES, but in 2022, they’re impossible to avoid.</p>
<p>Like any ultra-hot tech category, only a few will survive. Peloton was set to loom large over the event in more ways than one, including a keynote by CEO John Foley &#8212; though earlier this week, the fitness brand joined a long list of companies opting out of attendance. In spite of such concerns, however, there were plenty of products more than willing to fill that void.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2254252" style="width: 685px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2254252" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2254252" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/dims.jpeg" alt="" width="675" height="506" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/dims.jpeg 675w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/dims.jpeg?resize=150,112 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/dims.jpeg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/dims.jpeg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 675px) 100vw, 675px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2254252" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> LG</p></div></p>
<p>LG’s offering in the category was far more conceptual than practical. If anything, the company’s stationary bike was designed to show off how its curved monitor technology could be incorporated into home fitness. Given the size of the product, it seemed like a pretty solid indictment of itself, given that space and price are at a premium for many looking to outfit their homes with exercise equipment.</p>
<p>I’m frankly surprised we didn’t get more attempts to jam the term “metaverse” into this year’s home fitness pitches. VR fitness app Liteboxer wins the prize there. &#8220;The dawn of the metaverse points to a demand for a deeper sense of connectivity,” co-founder and CEO Jeff Morin said in a release. “Virtual reality workouts connect people in a way that&#8217;s more meaningful than a 2D screen on a tablet, phone or computer. With just a VR headset and your will to win, anyone can now workout anywhere in the world with the best trainers, tracks and fitness technology.&#8221;</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JIHvzsUQ6qk?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>The “meta” word is mentioned four times in the aforementioned release. In this case it seems to be used fairly interchangeably with the term “VR,” as this is a title for the Quest 2 headset. Liteboxer VR arrives in the Quest Store on March 3, and will run $19 a month for a subscription.</p>
<p>Echelon showcased its EX-8s Connect Bike, designed to take on Peloton’s high-end Bike+, undercutting the product only slightly at $2,399. That’s a high price tag for a company that also makes uber-affordable products for Walmart. That price gets you, among other things, a curved 24-inch 1080p display and a customizable lightshow for the wheels. It’s set to arrive later this month.<img loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2254253" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/home_02_pc-1.png" alt="" width="768" height="500" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/home_02_pc-1.png 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/home_02_pc-1.png?resize=150,98 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/home_02_pc-1.png?resize=300,195 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/home_02_pc-1.png?resize=680,443 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/home_02_pc-1.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /></p>
<p><strong>Image Credits:</strong> WonderciseWondercise, meanwhile, is a software-first solution. The company aims to offer a platform that’s designed to connect remote exercise buffs and break through some of the isolation that comes from switching from the gym to the home. Per the company’s press material:</p>
<blockquote><p>The live leaderboard displays scores based on an individual’s technique, creating a fun atmosphere in sessions. Colorful on-screen power bars and profiles were intentionally designed to make the experience feel like a game, adding a competitive dimension to workouts. Wondercise is focused on bringing the Internet of Things to the fitness industry so everyone can get the performance analytics and data they need, wherever they work out.</p></blockquote>
<p>As crowded as the home equipment category is getting, however, it’s nothing compared to software-first solutions, and Wondercise will be competiting directly with big names, including Apple and Samsung.</p>
<p>Hydrow, meanwhile, was one of the key companies representing home rowers. It’s a category beyond the saturated world of treadmills and bikes that’s prime for some real growth. Rowers offer a fuller body workout than bikes, though generally burn fewer calories. Peloton is rumored to be getting into the rowing machine game, but for now Hydrow looms as the big name in the space.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ces-2022/?utm_source=internal&amp;utm_medium=footer-banner"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ces-2022-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about CES 2022 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/as-ces-goes-hybrid-connected-fitness-companies-have-another-big-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2254247</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: With the H-1B lottery looming, how should we approach overseas hiring?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/dear-sophie-with-the-h-1b-lottery-looming-how-should-we-approach-overseas-hiring/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/dear-sophie-with-the-h-1b-lottery-looming-how-should-we-approach-overseas-hiring/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 23:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B visa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Institute For The Future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2253326</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We’re an early-stage startup struggling to recruit. We received some applications from international talent. This is all new territory for us. What’s your advice for hiring internationally?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/dear-sophie-will-the-h-1b-lottery-be-based-on-the-highest-wages/">Dear Sophie: Will the H-1B lottery be based on the highest wages?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/22/dear-sophie-whats-allowed-between-a-k-1-visa-and-a-green-card/">Dear Sophie: What’s allowed between a K-1 visa and a green card?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">​​Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>TechCrunch+ members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2253326" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<hr />
<p><strong>Dear Sophie,</strong></p>
<p><strong>We’re an early-stage startup that — like many other companies — is facing a significant challenge when it comes to recruiting talent. We have not posted job openings internationally, but we’ve received some applications from international talent. </strong></p>
<p><strong>This is all new territory for us. What’s your advice for hiring internationally? Also, I know the H-1B lottery is fast approaching. </strong></p>
<p><strong>Can you explain a bit more about this process?</strong></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>— Eager Early-Stage Startup</strong></p>
<p>Dear Eager,</p>
<p>Yes, the <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/099-h-1b-planning-for-fy2023/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">H-1B lottery</a> is fast approaching! The period for registering H-1B candidates opens in March; there are a few steps companies need to take before then if they have never before participated in the H-1B lottery process. First, be sure to create an account with U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS), which conducts the lottery. Given this timeline, your company should determine as soon as possible whether the positions you are looking to fill and the prospective international talent you are looking to hire would qualify for an <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/what-we-do/h-1b_speciality_occupations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">H-1B specialty occupation visa</a>.</p>
<p>Check out my column in TechCrunch+ last week for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/dear-sophie-will-the-h-1b-lottery-be-based-on-the-highest-wages/">more specifics on the lottery process</a>. To bypass the H-1B lottery — or if a candidate is not selected in the lottery — your company could consider getting a <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/066-cap-exempt-h-1bs-with-danielle-goldman/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cap-exempt H-1B</a> for the candidate. Transferring an individual’s H-1B to your startup is also an option. To find out more about that process, take a look at this <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/dear-sophie-should-we-sponsor-international-hires-for-h-1b-transfers-and-green-cards/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dear Sophie column</a>.</p>
<h2>A futurist lens on international hires</h2>
<p>I recently had a <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/103-a-futurists-lens-on-immigration-future-of-work-climate-change-and-more-with-jamais-cascio/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">fascinating conversation</a> with Jamais Cascio, a futurist and distinguished fellow at the <a href="https://www.iftf.org/jamaiscascio/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Institute for the Future in Palo Alto</a>. Cascio has some wonderful insight relevant to your question.</p>
<p>The population in the U.S. is getting older and the birth rate is declining; as such, we will increasingly need to look to immigration to keep our economy going. Cascio discusses three mindsets for dealing with radical changes in this chaotic world to remain strong as a company and succeed into the future. This advice is highly applicable to companies such as yours as you embark on an effort to hire from abroad.</p>
<p>The three mindsets that Cashio said would benefit companies are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Resilience: Being able to withstand a shock to the system without breaking. For example, he said companies that have just-in-time delivery models are very brittle and prone to break down compared to those that have built-in slack into their system. Building in slack often requires additional resources and reduced efficiency and profit but offers built-in resilience.</li>
<li>Improvisation: Remain creative and nimble and be ready to embrace change.</li>
<li>Empathy: Probably the most critical of the three, this involves recognizing the humanity in others and what we do matters to others now and in the future. (I loved hearing that the role of the heart is and will be critical for business success!)</li>
</ul>
<p>Embracing these mindsets while developing an immigration strategy that offers stability for international talent will be key to attracting and retaining talent and creating a company culture that fosters innovation and endurance. Listen to my podcast, “<a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/057-11-tips-for-companies-to-support-valued-humans/\" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tips for Companies to Support Valued Humans</a>,” in which I discuss this in more detail.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100312" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100312" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2100312" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg" alt="A composite image of immigration law attorney Sophie Alcorn in front of a background with a TechCrunch logo." width="1024" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=1536,1013 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Joanna Buniak / <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sophie Alcorn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<h2>Specific visas to consider</h2>
<p>Before we dive into visa specifics, please be aware that I recommend you consult an experienced immigration attorney, who can help you devise an immigration strategy for prospective international hires, as well as provide guidance on what visas would be appropriate given the job opening and prospective candidate. Take a look at a previous <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/dear-sophie-any-advice-on-visa-issues-for-new-hires/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dear Sophie column</a> in which I offer an overview on immigration-related matters you should focus on if your startup does not yet have someone handling HR.</p>
<h2>O-1A visa</h2>
<p>If your prospective hires don’t make it through the H-1B lottery process I mentioned above, or you need to get them here more quickly than October and you can’t take the risk that they might not be selected in the H-1B lottery this year, a great option is the <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/what-we-do/o-visas/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">O-1A extraordinary ability visa</a>. More and more of our startup clients are opting to pursue it for key executives and individual contributors with niche expertise. While the bar for qualifying for the O-1A is much higher than for the H-1B, the process for getting an O-1A is much quicker. And the O-1A does not have an annual cap or lottery process to contend with.</p>
<h2>Visas for talent from specific countries</h2>
<p>Specific visas exist for talent from Australia, Canada, Chile, Mexico and Singapore.</p>
<p>If the job candidate is an Australian national, an <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/e-3-visa-australian-professionals/">E-3 visa</a> will allow that individual to work in the U.S. in a specialty occupation, just like an H-1B. E-3 visas also require the sponsoring employer to file a Labor Condition Application with the U.S. Department of Labor, as is required with H-1B petitions. A maximum of 10,500 E-3 visas is available each year.</p>
<p>Is the job candidate a Chilean or Singaporean national? If so, the candidate may qualify for an <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/what-we-do/h1-b1-visas-chileans-singaporeans/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">H-1B1</a> specialty occupation visa, which is an H-1B visa earmarked for citizens of Chile and Singapore. Thanks to special treaties the U.S. has with those two countries, professionals may qualify to receive H-1B1 visas on a fast-track basis. Each year, 1,400 H-1B1 visas are reserved for Chileans and 5,400 are reserved for Singaporeans — and rarely are those visas completely exhausted.</p>
<p>Professionals from <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/tn-treaty-national-nafta-canadians/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Canada</a> and <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/tn-treaty-national-nafta-mexicans/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mexico</a> can come to the U.S. to work under a <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/tn-visas-and-status-for-canadian-and-mexican-citizens/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TN visa</a>, which was born out of trade treaties between Canada, Mexico and the U.S. TN visas are limited to professions listed in treaty agreements, but most of these jobs overlap with H-1B specialty occupations.</p>
<p>Some good news: Through the end of 2022, consular officers can now waive the in-person interview requirement for some individuals seeking some nonimmigrant (temporary) visas, including H-1Bs and O-1s. Individuals who are applying for a visa in their country or nationality of residence may have the interview waived if any of the following apply:</p>
<ul>
<li>Previously issued any type of visa.</li>
<li>Never been refused a visa unless it was overcome or waived.</li>
<li>No ineligibility.</li>
<li>Citizens or nationals of a country that participates in the <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/visa-waiver-program-requirements" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Visa Waiver Program.</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Wishing you every success!</p>
<p>Sophie</p>
<hr />
<p>Have a question for Sophie? <a href="https://webforms.pipedrive.com/f/1FRtXDHbec94FLVsSrWoOE362FDjgK7JkmZmK9g2IiOhbJLDMHtEAapwnHIfqC89l" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ask it here</a>. We reserve the right to edit your submission for clarity and/or space.</p>
<p>The information provided in “Dear Sophie” is general information and not legal advice. For more information on the limitations of “Dear Sophie,” please view <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/attorney-advertising/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">our full disclaimer</a>. You can contact Sophie directly at <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alcorn Immigration Law</a>.</p>
<p>Sophie’s podcast, <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Immigration Law for Tech Startups</a>, is available on all major platforms. If you’d like to be a guest, she’s accepting applications!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/dear-sophie-with-the-h-1b-lottery-looming-how-should-we-approach-overseas-hiring/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2253326</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: $360M funding round values Fractal &#8216;well north of $1 billion,&#8217; says co-founder</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/daily-crunch-111/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/daily-crunch-111/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 23:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2254110</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PST, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for January 5, 2021! Today we have a great mix of news for you. Mega-rounds? Heck yes. Electric trucks from U.S. companies? Yep! Android cozying up to Windows? But of course. And some great essays on lock-up periods, LP transparency and more.</p>
<p>But before we do that, every once in a while I’m going to highlight a TechCruncher behind the scenes who deserves some love. Today it’s Henry Pickavet, one of our editors and guiding lights, someone I have known and worked with since my early 20s. He’s perfect, apart from the sports teams he follows and the fact that he likes cricket. Follow him <a href="https://twitter.com/pickavet" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on Twitter here</a> if you are so inclined! —<a href="http://twitter.com/alex" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alex</a></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2254110" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/making-sense-of-opensea-at-a-13b-valuation/#:~:text=OpenSea%2C%20the%20well%2Dknown%20NFT,how%20overheated%20things%20have%20become.">Making sense of OpenSea at $13B:</a></strong> From rumor to report to confirmation, the OpenSea funding round worth $300 million came to its conclusion quickly. Now the NFT marketplace is worth some $13 billion. So, TechCrunch did the obvious thing and asked if that number makes any darn sense. As it turns out, yes, but how much depends on your level of crypto-bullishness,</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/google-brings-android-and-some-windows-pcs-closer-together/">Android <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f91d.png" alt="🤝" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Windows:</a> </strong>While Apple has been busy defending its walls surrounding the garden that is iOS, Google and Microsoft have been busy paving roads between their Android and Windows operating systems. First, Microsoft announced that some Android apps would eventually run on Windows. And now, news that “Google is working with the likes of Intel, Acer and HP to [connect] your phone to your Windows PC.”</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/visual-collaboration-company-miro-valued-at-17-5b-following-400m-in-new-funding/"><strong>And here’s the *other* company now worth more than $10B:</strong></a><strong> </strong>It’s Miro! Yep, the online workspace company, as we put it, is now worth some $17.5 billion after raising a $400 million round. The company claims it has 30 million users. Competitor <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/mural-raises-50m-series-c-after-tripling-its-arr-in-the-last-year/">Mural is also doing well</a>, indicating that their market is fairly deep in the remote-work era.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Startups/VC</h3>
<p>A few essays to start our startup download today, I think. The first comes from our own <a href="https://twitter.com/cookie" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Connie Loizos</a> diving into the “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/the-year-of-the-disappearing-lock-up/">year of the disappearing lock-up</a>.” In short, Loizos notes that the traditional forced holding period post-IPO is being dismantled in hot public offerings. Not that this is a guarantee of future results — the opposite, it seems — but it’s worth tracking the change to what was once a key IPO rule, and, frankly, mark of confidence.</p>
<p>Speaking of IPOs, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/a-quick-check-in-on-the-neoinsurance-unicorn-public-meltdown/">the insurtech IPO wave of 2020 and 2021 is looking pretty darn threadbare today</a>. TechCrunch took a look back at the struggles of names we’ve written about for ages, the Roots and Metromiles of the world, but also Oscar Health. It hasn’t done well either, it turns out.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/abracarioca" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anna Heim</a> wrote a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/more-lp-transparency-is-overdue/">fascinating piece on LP transparency</a>. The idea that founders should care about where <em>their</em> investors get their money is not new. But what is fresh is the leverage that founders have over investors — the founder-investor power dynamic has flipped, leading more VCs to think that it might be time to open up their own books a little.</p>
<p>Now, more news!</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/meet-bankaya-a-mexican-fintech-that-is-going-offline-for-customer-acquisition/">Bankaya goes offline for customer acquisition:</a></strong> The hunt for new users is a global startup challenge, and one that leads to some interesting solutions. Mexican fintech Bankaya is taking an IRL tack to the challenge, noting that the major ad channels for its products are rife with competitors chasing the same eyeballs.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/alto-raises-40-billion-to-help-individuals-make-tax-savvy-investments-in-assets-like-crypto-and-artwork/">Tax advantaged crypto investments?</a></strong> Startup Alto just raised $40 million for what TechCrunch reports is a “self-directed IRA platform [that] provides a simpler, more affordable option for individuals to invest their retirement savings into alternatives,” at least in theory. I dig it.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/ai-startup-fractal-becomes-unicorn-with-360-million-investment-from-tpg/">Fractal goes unicorn with new $360M round:</a></strong> It turns out that this company is 21 years old, so it’s not a startup, per se. But it is a private company that just raised nine figures, so it hit our radar. The company’s analytics product does AI and analytics work for major companies.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/softbank-in-talks-to-back-india-elastic-run/">SoftBank eyes new Indian investment:</a> </strong>Pune-based ElasticRun is in talks to close a round worth $200 million or so from SoftBank Vision 2 and Goldman Sachs, Manish Singh reports for TechCrunch. The startup helps neighborhood stores “secure inventory from top brands and working capital,” we report.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/bob-the-magic-dishwasher-dragon/">Meet a very cute dishwasher named Bob:</a></strong> From the CES trenches, meet Bob. It’s a small dishwasher unit for apartment countertops that is efficient, and, dare we say it, adorable.</li>
<li>To close out our startup items, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/xage-snags-30m-series-b-to-help-secure-critical-infrastructure/"><strong>Xage has raised $30 million to help project critical infrastructure</strong></a>. Which is good, given that much of the power lines and water facilities that you depend on are fairly out of date and begging for nation-state shenanigans. (The startup’s name is pronounced <em>zage</em>, <a href="https://twitter.com/ron_miller" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ron Miller</a>.)</li>
</ul>
<h2>4 trends that will define e-commerce in 2022</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2252949" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/4-trends-that-will-define-e-commerce-in-2022/"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2252949" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2252949 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1130532283.jpg" alt="Multi Colored Note Paper on Cork Board" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1130532283.jpg 2121w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1130532283.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1130532283.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1130532283.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1130532283.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1130532283.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1130532283.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1130532283.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2252949" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=MirageC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MirageC <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Data privacy has been top of mind for online sellers and for good reason: Regulators are taking an interest, and iOS 14.5 lets users turn off data tracking, with negative consequences for &#8220;Facebook&#8217;s ad targeting.&#8221;</p>
<p>Bearing those factors and others in mind, Ben Parr, president and co-founder of e-commerce marketing platform Octane.ai, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/4-trends-that-will-define-e-commerce-in-2022/">shared his predictions for 2022</a> with TechCrunch+:</p>
<ul>
<li>Personalization and zero-party data become critical.</li>
<li>E-commerce embraces web3 and NFTs, but what will that look like?</li>
<li>Live shopping goes mainstream.</li>
<li>Slow but gradual improvement to the supply chain.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>We have a number of automotive-themed news items below, but let’s start on your phone with Instagram. The social subsidiary of the larger Meta empire is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/instagram-chronological-feed/">bringing back its chronological feed</a>. Praise be. Forcing users to endure algorithmic timelines is lame, in my view, and something that moves power away from users toward the adtech gods that run social platforms. I might even re-sign up for Instagram now that this is fixed.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/ftc-settle-mortgage-files-exposed/"><strong>Mortgage data analytics company settles with FTC over data breach:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Back in 2019, TechCrunch reported that “OpticsML, a New York-based vendor working for Ascension, left a database of highly sensitive financial data exposed to the internet without a password.” Now two years after that reporting, results!</li>
<li><strong>GM promises a plethora of electric vehicles:</strong> If <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/electric-chevrolet-equinox-chevrolet-blazer-suvs-are-coming-in-2023/">you want an electric Equinox or Blazer</a>, GM is going to hook you up in 2023. It claims. And the company is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/the-chevy-silverado-finally-goes-electric/">building an electric Silverado pickup</a>, coming a bit late to the table given how many announcements Ford has already made. But the die really is cast here regarding the future of rolling vehicles, no matter who is currently leading. They are going electric. And fast.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/gm-personal-autonomous-vehicles/">And GM wants to get self-driving cars on the road:</a> </strong>By the middle of the decade, the company said. I am a wee bit skeptical of any provided timeline for autonomous vehicles, but at some point they will work — right? — and that day will be good. Let’s hope these latest projections bear out in time.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2217068" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217068" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217068" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg" alt="dc experts" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217068" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend growth marketers who have expertise in SEO, social, content writing and more! If you’re a growth marketer, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03" target="_blank" rel="noopener">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re curious about how these surveys are shaping our coverage, check out this article on TechCrunch+ from Ben Parr: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/4-trends-that-will-define-e-commerce-in-2022/">“4 trends that will define e-commerce in 2022.”</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/daily-crunch-111/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2254110</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Doosan announces $33.7M raise, as it introduces a robotic camera system at CES</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/doosan-announces-33-7m-raise-as-it-introduces-a-robotic-camera-system-at-ces/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/doosan-announces-33-7m-raise-as-it-introduces-a-robotic-camera-system-at-ces/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 23:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ces 2022]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doosan robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Korean Investment Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Praxis Capital Partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2254204</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Doosan Robotics this week announced $33.7 million in funding, led Praxis Capital Partners and Korea Investment Partners. The fundraising news arrives as the Seoul-based company shows off its wares at CES in Las Vegas. The company says the funding will be used to increase research and development and attract new partners as it looks to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Doosan Robotics this week announced $33.7 million in funding, led Praxis Capital Partners and Korea Investment Partners. The fundraising news arrives as the Seoul-based company shows off its wares at CES in Las Vegas.</p>
<p>The company says the funding will be used to increase research and development and attract new partners as it looks to expand its global footprint. Doosan also notes in a release that its robotics systems have hit 1,000 units annually, while sales outside of Korea (primarily North America and Western Europe) now account for roughly 70% of that total figure. The company is also in the process of eyeing an IPO.</p>
<p>“We’re looking forward to expediting the growth of our business with the recent funds raised,” CEO Junghoon Ryu said in a release. “We will further enhance the competitiveness of new products and software that are mounted with our proprietary technology and strive to attain the position as number one market share holder in the global cobot market.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2254204" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Doosan is primarily known for its collaborative robots (cobots), whose use run the gamut from manufacturing and research to the coffee-making barista robot, Dr. Presso, which debuted late last year.</p>
<p>Aside from the funding news, the company also announced the NINA (&#8220;New Inspiration. New Angle”) camera system. We’d mentioned it a few weeks ago, after it collected a CES Innovation award, but this week we’re getting more information on the robotic system, which is due out in March.</p>
<p>The company refers to NINA as a “prosumer” system, which likely applies to what’s supposed to be a relatively push-button approach to grabbing potentially complicated shots. That arrives in part, due to things like object tracking, coupled with an open platform that allows users to program different shots.</p>
<p>&#8220;NINA brings in a whole new era for Doosan as we expand our offerings into the entertainment and content genre,” the company’s CEO said in a separate statement. “Our goal has been to deliver something accessible yet innovative for professional content creators across entertainment, advertising, social media, and other relevant industries, and we’re confident NINA will deliver in big ways across the board.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ces-2022/?utm_source=internal&amp;utm_medium=footer-banner"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ces-2022-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about CES 2022 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/doosan-announces-33-7m-raise-as-it-introduces-a-robotic-camera-system-at-ces/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2254204</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
