<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 19:33:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Intel inks deal with Department of Defense to support domestic chip-building ecosystem</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/intel-inks-deal-with-department-of-defense-to-support-domestic-chip-building-ecosystem/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/intel-inks-deal-with-department-of-defense-to-support-domestic-chip-building-ecosystem/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 19:11:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chip makers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[department of defense]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2192813</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Intel has signed a deal with the Department of Defense to support a domestic commercial chip-building ecosystem. The chipmaker will lead the first phase of a program called Rapid Assured Microelectronics Prototypes &#8211; Commercial (RAMP-C), which aims to bolster the domestic semiconductor supply chain. The chipmaker&#8217;s recently launched division, Intel Foundry Services, will lead the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Intel has signed a deal with the Department of Defense to support a domestic commercial chip-building ecosystem. The chipmaker will lead the first phase of a program called <a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/newsroom/news/intel-wins-us-project-develop-foundry-ecosystem.html">Rapid Assured Microelectronics Prototypes &#8211; Commercial (RAMP-C)</a>, which aims to bolster the domestic semiconductor supply chain.</p>
<p>The chipmaker&#8217;s recently launched division, Intel Foundry Services, will lead the program.</p>
<p>As part of RAMP-C, Intel will partner with IBM, Cadence, Synopsys and others to establish a domestic commercial foundry ecosystem. Intel says the program was designed to create custom integrated circuits and commercial products required by the Department of Defense’s systems.</p>
<p>“The RAMP-C program will enable both commercial foundry customers and the Department of Defense to take advantage of Intel’s significant investments in leading-edge process technologies,” said Randhir Thakur, president of Intel Foundry Services, in a statement. “Along with our customers and ecosystem partners, including IBM, Cadence, Synopsys and others, we will help bolster the domestic semiconductor supply chain and ensure the United States maintains leadership in both R&amp;D and advanced manufacturing.”</p>
<p>Intel recently announced that it plans to invest <a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/newsroom/news/idm-manufacturing-innovation-product-leadership.html#gs.92ragp">approximately $20 billion to build two new factories in Arizona</a>, as it aims to become a major provider for domestic foundry customers. The company says the factories will support expanding requirements for its products.</p>
<p>The chipmaker’s partnership with the Department of Defense comes amid the ongoing global semiconductor shortage, which is due in part to the pandemic and its impact on the global supply chain. The company is among other tech and auto giants<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/12/biden-white-house-semiconductor-summit/"> in continuous talks with the White House regarding possible solutions</a> for the shortage. Intel CEO Pat Gelsinger met with<a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/intel-ceo-pitches-pricey-chip-plants-to-officials-at-home-and-abroad-11628933400?mod=article_inline"> Biden administration officials last month</a> to discuss plans to build more chip factories and to appeal for subsidies.</p>
<p>In a new statement regarding RAMP-C, Gelsinger states that “one of the most profound lessons of the past year is the strategic importance of semiconductors, and the value to the United States of having a strong domestic semiconductor industry.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“When we launched Intel Foundry Services earlier this year, we were excited to have the opportunity to make our capabilities available to a wider range of partners, including in the U.S. government, and it is great to see that potential being fulfilled through programs like RAMP-C,” Gelsinger added.</p>
<p>Gelsinger came <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/pat-gelsinger-stepping-down-as-vmware-ceo-to-replace-bob-swan-at-intel/">on board as CEO in January</a> with the aim to turn around the chipmaker and pursue new strategies for manufacturing and selling chips. A few months ago, Intel was rumoured to be in talks to buy chip manufacturer <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/16/intel-rumored-to-be-in-talks-to-buy-chip-manufacturer-globalfoundries-for-30b/">GlobalFoundries for $30 billion</a>, but there’s been no news on that front.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="C9tUvyb6yI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/28/semiconductors-in-2021/">2021 will be a calmer year for semiconductors and chips (except for Intel)</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;2021 will be a calmer year for semiconductors and chips (except for Intel)&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/28/semiconductors-in-2021/embed/#?secret=C9tUvyb6yI" data-secret="C9tUvyb6yI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/intel-inks-deal-with-department-of-defense-to-support-domestic-chip-building-ecosystem/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2192813</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kapacity.io is using AI to drive energy and emissions savings for real estate</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/kapacity-io-is-using-ai-to-drive-energy-and-emissions-savings-for-real-estate/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/kapacity-io-is-using-ai-to-drive-energy-and-emissions-savings-for-real-estate/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 18:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decarbonization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy savings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HVAC control automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kapacity-io]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nordic Makers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2192522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Y Combinator-backed Kapacity.io is on a mission to accelerate the decarbonization of buildings by using AI-generated efficiency savings to encourage electrification of commercial real estate &#8212; wooing buildings away from reliance on fossil fuels to power their heating and cooling needs. It does this by providing incentives to building owners/occupiers to shift to clean energy [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Y Combinator-backed <a href="https://kapacity.io">Kapacity.io</a> is on a mission to accelerate the decarbonization of buildings by using AI-generated efficiency savings to encourage electrification of commercial real estate &#8212; wooing buildings away from reliance on fossil fuels to power their heating and cooling needs.</p>
<p>It does this by providing incentives to building owners/occupiers to shift to clean energy usage through a machine learning-powered software automation layer.</p>
<p>The startup&#8217;s cloud software integrates with buildings&#8217; HVAC systems and electricity meters &#8212; drawing on local energy consumption data to calculate and deploy real-time adjustments to heating/cooling systems which not only yield energy and (CO2) emissions savings but generate actual revenue for building owners/tenants &#8212; paying them to reduce consumption such as at times of peak energy demand on the grid.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are controlling electricity consumption in buildings, focusing on heating and cooling devices &#8212; using AI machine learning to optimize and find the best ways to consume electricity,&#8221; explains CEO and co-founder Jaakko Rauhala, a former consultant in energy technology. &#8220;The actual method is known as &#8216;demand response&#8217;. Basically that is a way for electricity consumers to get paid for adjusting their energy consumption, based on a utility company&#8217;s demand.</p>
<p>&#8220;For example if there is a lot of wind power production and suddenly the wind drops or the weather changes and the utility company is running power grids they need to balance that reduction &#8212; and the way to do that is either you can fire up natural gas turbines or you can reduce power consumption&#8230; Our product estimates how much can we reduce electricity consumption at any given minute. We are [targeting] heating and cooling devices because they consume a lot of electricity.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The way we see this is this is a way we can help our customers electrify their building stocks faster because it makes their investments more lucrative and in addition we can then help them use more renewable electricity because we can shift the use from fossil fuels to other areas. And in that we hope to help push for a more greener power grid,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p>Kapcity&#8217;s approach is applicable in deregulated energy markets where third parties are able to play a role offering energy saving services and fluctuations in energy demand are managed by an auction process involving the trading of surplus energy &#8212; typically overseen by a transmission system operator &#8212; to ensure energy producers have the right power balance to meet customer needs.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Demand for energy can fluctuate regardless of the type of energy production feeding the grid but renewable energy sources tend to increase the volatility of energy markets as production can be less predictable versus legacy energy generation (like nuclear or burning fossil fuels) &#8212; wind power, for example, depends on when and how strongly the wind is blowing (which both varies and isn&#8217;t perfectly predictable). So as economies around the world dial up efforts to tackle climate change and hit critical carbon emissions reduction targets there&#8217;s growing pressure to shift away from fossil fuel-based power generation toward cleaner, renewable alternatives. And the real estate sector specifically remains a major generator of CO2, so is squarely in the frame for &#8220;greening&#8221;.</p>
<p>Simultaneously, decarbonization and the green shift looks likely to drive demand for smart solutions to help energy grids manage increasing complexity and volatility in the energy supply mix.</p>
<p>&#8220;Basically more wind power &#8212; and solar, to some extent &#8212; correlates with demand for balancing power grids and this is why there is a lot of talk usually about electricity storage when it comes to renewables,&#8221; says Rauhala. &#8220;Demand response, in the way that we do it, is an alternative for electricity storage units. Basically we&#8217;re saying that we already have a lot of electricity consuming devices &#8212; and we will have more and more with electrification. We need to adjust their consumption before we invest billions of dollars into other systems.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We will need a lot of electricity storage units &#8212; but we try to push the overall system efficiency to the maximum by utilising what we already have in the grid,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p>There are of course limits to how much &#8220;adjustment&#8221; (read: switching off) can be done to a heating or cooling system by even the cleverest AI without building occupants becoming uncomfortable.</p>
<p>But Kapacity&#8217;s premise is that small adjustments &#8212; say turning off the boilers/coolers for five, 15 or 30 minutes &#8212; can go essentially unnoticed by building occupants if done right, allowing the startup to tout a range of efficiency services for its customers; such as a peak-shaving offering, which automatically reduces energy usage to avoid peaks in consumption and generate significant energy cost savings.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our goal &#8212; which is a very ambitious goal &#8212; is that the customers and occupants in the buildings wouldn&#8217;t notice the adjustments. And that they would fall into the normal range of temperature fluctuations in a building,&#8221; says Rauhala.</p>
<p>Kapacity&#8217;s algorithms are designed to understand how to make dynamic adjustments to buildings&#8217; heating/cooling without compromising &#8220;thermal comfort&#8221;, as Rauhala puts it &#8212; noting that co-founder (and COO) Sonja Salo, has both a PhD in demand response and researched thermal comfort during a stint as a visiting researcher at UC Berkley &#8212; making the area a specialist focus for the engineer-led founding team.</p>
<p>At the same time, the carrots it&#8217;s dangling at the commercial real estate to sign up for a little algorithmic HVAC tweaking look substantial: Kapacity says its system has been able to achieve a 25% reduction in electricity costs and a 10% reduction in CO2-emissions in early pilots. Although early tests have been limited to its home market for now.</p>
<p>Its other co-founder, Rami El Geneidy, researched smart algorithms for demand response involving heat pumps for his PhD dissertation &#8212; and heat pumps are another key focus for the team&#8217;s tech, per Rauhala.</p>
<p>Heat pumps are a low-carbon technology that&#8217;s fairly commonly used in the Nordics for heating buildings, but whose use is starting to spread as countries around the world look for greener alternatives to heat buildings.</p>
<p>In the U.K., for example, the government announced a plan last year to install hundreds of thousands of heat pumps per year by 2028 as it seeks to move the country away from widespread use of gas boilers to heat homes. And Rauhala names the U.K. as one of the startup&#8217;s early target markets &#8212; along with the European Union and the U.S., where they also envisage plenty of demand for their services.</p>
<p>While the initial focus is the commercial real estate sector, he says they are also interested in<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> residential buildings &#8212; noting that from a &#8220;tech core point of view we can do any type of building&#8221;. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;We have been focusing on larger buildings &#8212; multifamily buildings, larger office buildings, certain types of industrial or commercial buildings so we don&#8217;t do single-family detached homes at the moment,&#8221; he goes on, adding: &#8220;We have been looking at that and it&#8217;s an interesting avenue but our current pilots are in larger buildings.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Finnish startup was only founded last year &#8212; taking in a pre-seed round of funding from <a href="http://www.nordicmakers.vc">Nordic Makers</a> prior to getting backing from YC &#8212; where it will be presenting at the accelerator&#8217;s demo day next week. (But Rauhala won&#8217;t comment on any additional fund raising plans at this stage.)</p>
<p>He says it&#8217;s spun up five pilot projects over the last seven months involving commercial landlords, utilities, real estate developers and engineering companies (all in Finland for now), although &#8212; again &#8212; full customer details are not yet being disclosed. But Rauhala tells us they expect to move to their first full commercial deals with pilot customers this year.</p>
<p>&#8220;The reason why our customers are interested in using our products is that this is a way to make electrification cheaper because they are being paid for adjusting their consumption and that makes their operating cost lower and it makes investments more lucrative if &#8212; for example &#8212; you need to switch from natural gas boilers to heat pumps so that you can decarbonize your building,&#8221; he also tells us. &#8220;If you connect the new heat pump running on electricity &#8212; if you connect that to our service we can reduce the operating cost and that will make it more lucrative for everybody to electrify their buildings and run their systems.</p>
<p>&#8220;We can also then make their electricity consumed more sustainable because we are shifting consumption away from hours with most CO2 emissions on the grid. So we try to avoid the hours when there&#8217;s a lot of fossil fuel-based production in the grid and try to divert that into times when we have more renewable electricity.</p>
<p>&#8220;So basically the big question we are asking is how do we increase the use of renewables and the way to achieve that is asking when should we consume? Well we should consume electricity when we have more renewable in the grid. And that is the emission reduction method that we are applying here.&#8221;</p>
<p>In terms of limitations, Kapacity&#8217;s software-focused approach can&#8217;t work in every type of building &#8212; requiring that real estate customers have some ability to gather energy consumption (and potentially temperature) data from their buildings remotely, such as via IoT devices.</p>
<p>&#8220;The typical data that we need is basic information on the heating system &#8212; is it running at 100% or 50% or what&#8217;s the situation? That gets us pretty far,&#8221; says Rauhala. &#8220;Then we would like to know indoor temperatures. But that is not mandatory in the sense that we can still do some basic adjustments without that.&#8221;</p>
<p>It also of course can&#8217;t offer much in the way of savings to buildings that are running 100% on natural gas (or oil) &#8212; i.e. with electricity only used for lighting (turning lights off when people are inside buildings obviously wouldn&#8217;t fly); there must be some kind of air conditioning, cooling or heat pump systems already installed (or the use of electric hot water boilers).</p>
<p>&#8220;An old building that runs on oil or natural gas &#8212; that&#8217;s a target for decarbonization,&#8221; he continues. &#8220;That&#8217;s a target where you could consider installing heat pumps and that is where we could help some of our customers or potential customers to say OK we need to estimate how much would it cost to install a heat pump system here and that&#8217;s where our product can come in and we can say you can reduce the operating cost with demand response. So maybe we should do something together here.&#8221;</p>
<p>Rauhala also confirms that Kapacity&#8217;s approach does not require invasive levels of building occupant surveillance, telling TechCrunch: &#8220;We don&#8217;t collect information that is under GDPR [General Data Protection Regulation], I&#8217;ll put it that way. We don&#8217;t take personal data for this demand response.&#8221;</p>
<p>So any guestimates its algorithms are making about building occupants&#8217; tolerance for temperature changes are, therefore, not going to be based on specific individuals &#8212; but may, presumably, factor in aggregated information related to specific industry/commercial profiles.</p>
<p>The Helsinki-based startup is not the only one looking at applying AI to drive energy cost and emissions savings in the commercial buildings sector &#8212; another we spoke to recently is Düsseldorf-based <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/dabbel-gets-4-4m-to-cut-co2-by-automating-hvac-for-commercial-buildings/">Dabbel</a>, for example. And plenty more are likely to take an interest in the space as governments start to pump more money into accelerating decarbonization.</p>
<p>Asked about competitive differentiation, <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Rauhala points to a focus on real-time adjustments and heat pump technologies.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;One of our key things is we&#8217;re developing a system so that we can do close to real-time control &#8212; very, very short-term control. That is a valuable service to the power grid so we can then quickly adjust,&#8221; he says. &#8220;And the other one is we are focusing on heat pump technologies to get started &#8212; heat pumps here in the Nordics are a very common and extremely good way to decarbonize and understanding how we can combine these to demand response with new heat pumps that is where we see a lot of advantages to our approach.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Heat pumps are a bit more technically complex than your basic natural gas boiler so there are certain things that have to be taken it account and that is where we have been focusing our efforts,&#8221; he goes on, adding: &#8220;We see heat pumps as an excellent way to decarbonize the global building stock and we want to be there and help make that happen.&#8221;</p>
<p>Per capita, the Nordics has the most heat pump installations, according to Rauhala &#8212; including a lot of ground source heat pump installations which can replace fossil fuel consumption entirely.</p>
<p>&#8220;You can run your building with a ground source heat pump system entirely &#8212; you don&#8217;t need any supporting systems for it. And that is the area where we here in Europe are more far ahead than in the U.S.,&#8221; he says on that.</p>
<p>&#8220;The <a href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/62/environmental-audit-committee/news/138004/mps-turn-up-the-heat-on-governments-ambitions-to-install-600000-heat-pumps-every-year/">U.K. government is pushing for a lot of heat pump installations</a> and there are incentives in place for people to replace their existing natural gas systems or whatever they have. So that is very interesting from our point of view. The U.K. also has a lot of wind power coming online and there have been days when the U.K. has been running 100% with renewable electricity which is great. So that actually is a really good thing for us. But then in the longer term in the U.S. &#8212; Seattle, for example, has banned the use of fossil fuels in new buildings so I&#8217;m very confident that the market in the U.S. will open up more and quickly. There&#8217;s a lot of opportunities in that space as well.</p>
<p>&#8220;And of course from a cooling perspective air conditioning in general in the U.S. is very widespread &#8212; especially in commercial buildings so that is already an existing opportunity for us.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;My estimate on how valuable electricity use for heating and cooling is it&#8217;s tens of billions of dollars annually in the U.S. and EU,&#8221; he adds. &#8220;There&#8217;s a lot of electricity being used already for this and we expect the market to grow significantly.&#8221;</p>
<p>On the business model front, the startup&#8217;s cloud software looks set to follow a SaaS model but the plan is also to take a commission of the savings and/or generated income from customers. &#8220;We also have the option to provide the service with a fixed fee, which might be easier for some customers, but we expect the majority to be under a commission,&#8221; adds Rauhala.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, were the sought-for global shift away from fossil fuels to be wildly successful &#8212; and all commercial buildings&#8217; gas/oil boilers got replaced with 100% renewable power systems in short order &#8212; there would still be a role for Kapacity&#8217;s control software to play, generating energy cost savings for its customers, even though our (current) parallel pressing need to shrink carbon emissions would evaporate in this theoretical future.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;d be very happy,&#8221; says Rauhala. &#8220;The way we see emission reductions with demand response now is it&#8217;s based on the fact that we do still have fossil fuels power system &#8212; so if we were to have a 100% renewable power system then the electricity does nothing to reduce emissions from the electricity consumption because it&#8217;s all renewable. So, ironically, in the future we see this as a way to push for a renewable energy system and makes that transition happen even faster. But if we have a 100% renewable system then there&#8217;s nothing [in terms of CO2 emissions] we can reduce but that is a great goal to achieve.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ICL7XhenSj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/dabbel-gets-4-4m-to-cut-co2-by-automating-hvac-for-commercial-buildings/">Dabbel gets $4.4M to cut CO2 by automating HVAC control for commercial buildings</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Dabbel gets $4.4M to cut CO2 by automating HVAC control for commercial buildings&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/dabbel-gets-4-4m-to-cut-co2-by-automating-hvac-for-commercial-buildings/embed/#?secret=ICL7XhenSj" data-secret="ICL7XhenSj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NeWx4CB12g"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/9-top-real-estate-and-proptech-investors-cities-and-offices-still-have-a-future/">9 top real estate and proptech investors: Cities and offices still have a future</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;9 top real estate and proptech investors: Cities and offices still have a future&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/9-top-real-estate-and-proptech-investors-cities-and-offices-still-have-a-future/embed/#?secret=NeWx4CB12g" data-secret="NeWx4CB12g" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/kapacity-io-is-using-ai-to-drive-energy-and-emissions-savings-for-real-estate/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2192522</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Future tech exits have a lot to live up to</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/future-tech-exits-have-a-lot-to-live-up-to/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/future-tech-exits-have-a-lot-to-live-up-to/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 17:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pitchbook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup valuations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2192577</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Investors appear to be betting that the future IPO market will accelerate at attractive prices. Otherwise, none of what we are seeing regarding the rising price of startups makes sense.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Inflation may or may not prove transitory when it comes to consumer prices, but startup valuations are definitely rising &#8212; and noticeably so &#8212; in recent quarters.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s the obvious takeaway from a <a href="https://pitchbook.com/news/reports/q2-2021-us-vc-valuations-report">recent PitchBook report</a> digging into valuation data from a host of startup funding events in the United States. While the data covers the U.S. startup market, the general trends included are likely global, given that the same venture rush that has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/investors-dont-expect-the-us-startup-funding-market-to-slow-down/">pushed record capital into startups</a> in the U.S. is also occurring in markets <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/16/india-poised-for-record-vc-year-as-unicorns-head-for-decisive-ipos/">like India</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/why-latin-american-venture-capital-is-breaking-records-this-year/">Latin America</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/the-european-vc-market-is-so-hot-it-may-skip-its-summer-holiday/">Europe </a>and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/african-startups-join-global-funding-boom-as-fintech-shines/">Africa</a>.</p>
<p>The rapidly appreciating startup price chart is interesting, and we&#8217;ll unpack it. But the data also implies a high bar for future IPOs to not only preserve startup equity valuations at their point of exit, but exceed their private-market prices. A changing regulatory environment regarding antitrust could limit large future deals, leaving a host of startups with rich price tags and only one real path to liquidity.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Investors appear to be implicitly betting that the future IPO market will accelerate for a multiyear period at attractive prices.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>That situation should be familiar: It&#8217;s the unicorn traffic jam that we&#8217;ve covered for years, in which the global startup markets create far more startups worth $1 billion and up than the public markets have historically accepted across the transom.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s talk about some big numbers.</p>
<h2>Startup valuations: Up, and going upper</h2>
<p>To summarize what PitchBook published: Round sizes are going up as valuations go up, and with the latter rising faster than the former, we&#8217;re not seeing investors get more ownership despite them having to spend more for deal access.</p>
<p>In the early-stage market, deal sizes are rising as follows:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2192593" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2192593" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2192593" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.24.54-AM.png" alt="" width="750" height="331" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.24.54-AM.png 712w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.24.54-AM.png?resize=150,66 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.24.54-AM.png?resize=300,132 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.24.54-AM.png?resize=680,300 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.24.54-AM.png?resize=50,22 50w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2192593" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> PitchBook</p></div></p>
<p>Prices are going up as well, as the following chart shows:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2192591" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2192591" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2192591" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.24.49-AM.png" alt="" width="750" height="328" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.24.49-AM.png 723w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.24.49-AM.png?resize=150,66 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.24.49-AM.png?resize=300,131 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.24.49-AM.png?resize=680,297 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.24.49-AM.png?resize=50,22 50w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2192591" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits</strong>: PitchBook</p></div></p>
<p>Which leads to the following decline in equity take rates:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2192592" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2192592" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2192592" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.25.01-AM.png" alt="" width="750" height="354" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.25.01-AM.png 759w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.25.01-AM.png?resize=150,71 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.25.01-AM.png?resize=300,142 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.25.01-AM.png?resize=680,321 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-23-at-11.25.01-AM.png?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2192592" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> PitchBook</p></div></p>
<p>Those charts belie somewhat how quickly venture capital is changing. For example, in 2020, the median early-stage value created between rounds was $16 million (or a 54% relative velocity, if you prefer). In 2021 thus far, it&#8217;s $39.4 million (120% relative velocity). And that 2020 figure was a prior record. It just got smashed.</p>
<p>The PitchBook dataset has other superlatives worth noting. Enterprise-focused seed pre-money valuations hit an average of $11 million in the first half of 2021, an all-time high. Early-stage valuations for enterprise-focused startups also hit fresh records &#8212; $92.7 million on average, $43 million median &#8212; this year after rising consistently since 2011.</p>
<p>And late-stage valuations for enterprise tech startups have gone vertical (chart on the right):<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/future-tech-exits-have-a-lot-to-live-up-to/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2192577</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok is building its own AR development platform, TikTok Effect Studio</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/tiktok-is-building-its-own-ar-development-platform-tiktok-effect-studio/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/tiktok-is-building-its-own-ar-development-platform-tiktok-effect-studio/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 17:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Augmented Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[augmented reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spark AR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video hosting]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2192673</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Both Facebook and Snap offer tools that allow developers to build out augmented reality (AR) experiences and features for their own respective family of apps. Now, TikTok is looking to do the same. The company recently launched a new creative toolset called TikTok Effect Studio, currently in private beta testing, which will allow its own [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Both <a href="https://sparkar.facebook.com/ar-studio/">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://ar.snap.com/">Snap</a> offer tools that allow developers to build out augmented reality (AR) experiences and features for their own respective family of apps. Now, TikTok is looking to do the same. The company recently launched a new creative toolset called TikTok Effect Studio, currently in private beta testing, which will allow its own developer community to build AR effects for TikTok&#8217;s short-form video app.</p>
<p>On <a href="https://effecthouse.tiktok.com/">a new website titled &#8220;Effect House</a>,&#8221; TikTok asks interested developers to sign up for early access to Effect Studio.</p>
<p>On the form provided, developers fill out their name, email, TikTok account info, company and level of experience with building for AR, as well as examples of their work. The website also asks if they&#8217;re using a Mac or PC (presumably to gauge which desktop platform to prioritize), and whether they would test Effect House for work or for personal use.</p>
<p>The project was first spotted by social media consultant <a href="https://twitter.com/MattNavarra/status/1426639697829322762">Matt Navarra</a>, via a tip from <a href="https://twitter.com/Sam_Schmir">Sam Schmir</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">TikTok is launching an Effects Studio in beta </p>
<p>h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/Sam_Schmir?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Sam_Schmir</a> <a href="https://t.co/K3LS5S2Yoq">pic.twitter.com/K3LS5S2Yoq</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Matt Navarra (@MattNavarra) <a href="https://twitter.com/MattNavarra/status/1426639697829322762?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 14, 2021</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>TikTok confirmed to TechCrunch the website launched earlier in August, but the project itself is still in the early stages of testing in only a few select markets, one of which is the U.S.</p>
<p>The company couldn&#8217;t offer a time frame as to when these tools would become more broadly available. Instead, TikTok characterized Effect Studio as an early &#8220;experiment,&#8221; adding that some of its experiments don&#8217;t always make it to launch. Plus, other experiments may undergo significant changes between their early beta phases and what later becomes a public product.</p>
<p>That said, the launch of an AR toolset would make TikTok more competitive with industry rivals, who today rely on creative communities to expand their apps&#8217; feature sets with new features and experiences. Snap, for example, launched a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/snap-announces-3-5m-fund-directed-toward-ar-lens-creation/">$3.5 million fund</a> last year directed toward Snapchat AR Lens creation. Meanwhile, at Facebook&#8217;s F8 developer conference in June, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/facebooks-spark-ar-platform-expands-to-video-calling-with-multipeer-api/">the company announced</a> it had grown its Spark AR platform to over 600,000 creators across 190 countries, making it the largest mobile AR platform worldwide.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2192748" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2192748" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2192748" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-effect-house-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="467" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-effect-house-1.jpg 2354w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-effect-house-1.jpg?resize=150,103 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-effect-house-1.jpg?resize=300,206 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-effect-house-1.jpg?resize=768,527 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-effect-house-1.jpg?resize=680,467 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-effect-house-1.jpg?resize=1536,1054 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-effect-house-1.jpg?resize=2048,1406 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/tiktok-effect-house-1.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2192748" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> screenshot of TikTok website</p></div></p>
<p>TikTok, too, has been increasing its investment in developer tools over the past couple of years. However, its focus as of late has been on <a href="https://developers.tiktok.com/">toolkits</a> aimed at third-party developers who want to integrate more closely with TikTok in their own apps. Today, TikTok&#8217;s developer website provides access to tools that allow app makers to add TikTok features to their apps like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/tiktok-expands-integrations-with-third-party-apps-for-logins-sharing-sounds-and-more/">user authentication flows, sound sharing</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/04/tiktok-expands-its-influence-to-third-party-apps-with-new-developer-program/">others</a> that allow users to publish videos from a third-party editing app out to TikTok.</p>
<p>The new TikTok Effect Studio isn&#8217;t meant to be used with third-party apps, however.</p>
<p>Instead, it&#8217;s about building AR experiences (and possibly, other creative effects), that would be provided to TikTok users directly in the consumer-facing video app.</p>
<p>Though willing to confirm its broader goals for TikTok Effect Studio, the company declined to share specific details about the exact tools that may be included, citing the project&#8217;s early days.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re always thinking about new ways to bring value to our community and enrich the TikTok experience,&#8221; a TikTok spokesperson told TechCrunch. &#8220;Currently, we&#8217;re experimenting with ways to give creators additional tools to bring their creative ideas to life for the TikTok community,&#8221; they added.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="62YU4GulrJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/12/will-apple-facebook-or-microsoft-be-the-future-of-augmented-reality/">Will Apple, Facebook or Microsoft be the future of augmented reality?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Will Apple, Facebook or Microsoft be the future of augmented reality?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/12/will-apple-facebook-or-microsoft-be-the-future-of-augmented-reality/embed/#?secret=62YU4GulrJ" data-secret="62YU4GulrJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qRXuWVLiyf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/17/how-tiktok-decides-who-to-make-famous/">How TikTok decides who to make famous</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How TikTok decides who to make famous&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/17/how-tiktok-decides-who-to-make-famous/embed/#?secret=qRXuWVLiyf" data-secret="qRXuWVLiyf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/tiktok-is-building-its-own-ar-development-platform-tiktok-effect-studio/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2192673</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pry Financials raises $4.2M to make startup accounting more approachable</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/pry-financials-raises-4-2m-to-make-startup-accounting-more-approachable/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/pry-financials-raises-4-2m-to-make-startup-accounting-more-approachable/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 17:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accounting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bookkeeping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global founders capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pioneer Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pry Financials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scenario modeling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup finances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2192025</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pry Financials wants to make startup finances approachable for its entire team, not just the people in charge of its accounting spreadsheets. The Y Combinator alum announced today it has raised $4.2 million from Global Founders Capital, Pioneer Fund, NOMO VC, Liquid2 and Hyphen Capital.  Launched in March, Pry now has more than 200 customers [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p3"><a href="https://pry.co/">Pry Financials</a> wants to make startup finances approachable for its entire team, not just the people in charge of its accounting spreadsheets. The Y Combinator alum announced today it has raised $4.2 million from Global Founders Capital, Pioneer Fund, NOMO VC, Liquid2 and Hyphen Capital.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">Launched in March, Pry now has more than 200 customers and claims it has grown 35% month-over-month since YC’s Demo Day. It was founded by Alex Sailer, Tiffany Wong, Hayden Jensen and Andy Su.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">Before starting Pry, Su was co-founder of InDinero, another YC alum that started as a “Mint for small businesses” before<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2010/09/01/jessica-mahindinero"> pivoting to a full-service accounting company</a>. InDinero launched while he was still a student at UC Berkeley, and Su eventually became responsible for its financial planning.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2192029" style="width: 460px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2192029" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2192029" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Pry166.jpg" alt="A group photo of Pry Financials' team" width="450" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Pry166.jpg 5479w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Pry166.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Pry166.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Pry166.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Pry166.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Pry166.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Pry166.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Pry166.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2192029" class="wp-caption-text">Pry Financials&#8217; team. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Pry Financials</p></div></p>
<p class="p3">He told TechCrunch that most startups can’t afford accounting software like Workday Adaptive Planning. Instead, they sometimes work with outsourced CFO services, but mostly rely on spreadsheets for everything: three-way forecasts, predicting runway, hiring and contractor budgets and investor updates.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">“I was the chief technical officer and over the years, I also took on the finance function, so it was kind of a dual CTO/CFO role. This was 2010 through 2020 and as technology grew, the engineering and product teams got all sorts of new tools every six months or so, whereas the finance team was just stuck in Excel,” he said.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">Started as a side project while Su was still at InDinero, Pry starts at just $50 a month and replaces those spreadsheets with easy-to-understand dashboards for accounting, financial planning and scenario modeling. The dashboards connect to QuickBooks, Xero or bank accounts, so numbers are continuously updated.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p class="p3">Pry&#8217;s clients typically start using it after they raise seed funding, because “for most first-time founders, that’s the most amount of money you have ever received, so you need to spend more time managing it and reviewing it every month. And you’re spending a lot of time on payroll each month,” Su said. Second-time founders, meanwhile, sign up for Pry because they are sick of Excel spreadsheets.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6OPrcrxuL1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/freshbooks-secures-130-75m/">FreshBooks reaches $1B+ valuation with $130.75M for its SMB-focused accounting platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;FreshBooks reaches $1B+ valuation with $130.75M for its SMB-focused accounting platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/freshbooks-secures-130-75m/embed/#?secret=6OPrcrxuL1" data-secret="6OPrcrxuL1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p class="p3">“Reviewing a spreadsheet is mind-numbingly hard,” said Su. “If you see a number that’s off, you get this weird formula if you didn’t do it yourself. Then you basically have to write a long email to the financial analyst who wrote it and hope that they get back to you before closing time.” For founders who need to update lenders or investors every month, this means a lot of work.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">Pry makes the process more efficient by turning three-way reports — combinations of balance sheets, profit and loss statements and cashflow — into Financial Report dashboards, and then adding features like hiring plans, financial modeling and scenario planning.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">The scenario planning feature serves as a sandbox, giving startup teams and their investors a way to predict how different situations will impact finances: for example, how much runway they have if they raise a certain amount of funding or adjust product pricing.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2192032" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2192032" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2192032" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/pry_financials-fundraising-dashboard-1.jpg" alt="Fundraising dashboards created with Pry Financials" width="1024" height="589" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/pry_financials-fundraising-dashboard-1.jpg 1390w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/pry_financials-fundraising-dashboard-1.jpg?resize=150,86 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/pry_financials-fundraising-dashboard-1.jpg?resize=300,173 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/pry_financials-fundraising-dashboard-1.jpg?resize=768,442 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/pry_financials-fundraising-dashboard-1.jpg?resize=680,391 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/pry_financials-fundraising-dashboard-1.jpg?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2192032" class="wp-caption-text">Fundraising dashboards created with Pry Financials. <strong>Image credits:</strong> Pry Financials</p></div></p>
<p class="p3">“We’re improving upon and trying to make decisions about the company in a collaborative way. The analogy we have is Git branching, where you have your main plan, and want to try something like a new revenue model or acquiring a business, but don’t want to mess with your current strategy,” said Su. “What you can do is create a completely new branch with, say, a new pricing strategy. You can make all the changes you want and then switch back to your old branch without worrying about overriding or conflicting with it.”<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">Those speculative branches are also continuously updated with the company’s most recent bank account and payroll information, so founders don’t need to recreate them from scratch if they want to revisit a potential scenario later.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">Pry plans to build more complex predictive tools and also integrate industry standards, like statistic and benchmarks, into templates to help founders understand what targets they should set.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">Because Pry is easier to manage than a set of Excel spreadsheets, Su said it&#8217;s helped startups spot important things. For example, one founder was able to find a way to save $15,000 by catching a tax issue. Pry also helps everyone at a startup understand its finances’ even if they haven’t worked with accounting spreadsheets before. The platform will add roles and permissions soon, so founders can give or restrict access to different people, like leaders of specific departments.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">Su said Pry does not compete with the accounting services many startups rely on until they can hire a head of finance, but makes it easier for startups to collaborate with them since they can share their dashboards.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">“Usually early on, you can outsource to a CFO firm. That’s the norm in the business and it works pretty well for most companies. You get a part-time CFO to work really hard for a month and get your fundraising structure done,” said Su, adding “we fit into that ecosystem well.”<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fnSUOcttlJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/docyt-raises-1-5m-for-its-ml-based-accounting-automation-platform/">Docyt raises $1.5M for its ML-based accounting automation platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Docyt raises $1.5M for its ML-based accounting automation platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/docyt-raises-1-5m-for-its-ml-based-accounting-automation-platform/embed/#?secret=fnSUOcttlJ" data-secret="fnSUOcttlJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aBldMazAkA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/founders-how-well-do-you-really-understand-seed-stage-financing/">Founders: How well do you really understand seed-stage financing?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Founders: How well do you really understand seed-stage financing?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/founders-how-well-do-you-really-understand-seed-stage-financing/embed/#?secret=aBldMazAkA" data-secret="aBldMazAkA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/pry-financials-raises-4-2m-to-make-startup-accounting-more-approachable/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2192025</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How one founder aims to bring researchers and food producers together around cultured meat</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/how-one-founder-aims-to-bring-researchers-and-food-producers-together-around-cultured-meat/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/how-one-founder-aims-to-bring-researchers-and-food-producers-together-around-cultured-meat/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 16:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Found]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Animal Alternative Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clarisse Beurrier]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat substitute]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2192651</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When Clarisse Beurrier was getting her education in chemical engineering and biotechnology, she already knew she wanted to make a difference; hence her participation in Effective Altruism Cambridge, an organization dedicated to helping smart and capable people target their philanthropic urges at the problems that will have the biggest actual impact on the world. She&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When Clarisse Beurrier was getting her education in chemical engineering and biotechnology, she already knew she wanted to make a difference; hence her participation in Effective Altruism Cambridge, an organization dedicated to helping smart and capable people target their philanthropic urges at the problems that will have the biggest actual impact on the world. She&#8217;s now a co-founder at Animal Alternative Technologies, a startup aiming to expedite the commercialization of cultured — aka &#8220;lab-grown&#8221; — meat.</p>
<p>Clarisse joined us for this week&#8217;s episode of <a href="https://pod.link/found">Found</a>, our interview podcast where we speak to a different founder every week. We talk about what Clarisse learned about the cultured meat and animal protein alternative industry from her work experience at a couple of startups, including HigherSteaks, and how that dovetailed with the work she was doing at school to help her identify a crucial gap between science and industry. We get into everything from convincing big, entrenched industry heavyweights to embrace change to the challenges of being a first-time founder right out of school.</p>
<p>We loved our time chatting with Clarisse, and we hope you love yours listening to the episode. And of course, we’d love if you can subscribe to <a href="http://apple.co/found">Found in Apple Podcasts</a>, on <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/0Dqmcq2aDrZkS9v1fITOKV?si=Hfp6dAwAQKyenJnprGxnqg">Spotify</a>, on <a href="https://podcasts.google.com/feed/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5zaW1wbGVjYXN0LmNvbS9lMmI0QU5vYg?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwiYisj3nZfwAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQCQ">Google Podcasts</a> or in <a href="https://pod.link/found">your podcast app of choice</a>. Please leave us a review and let us know what you think, or send us direct feedback either on <a href="https://twitter.com/found">Twitter </a>or via email at <a href="mailto:found@techcrunch.com">found@techcrunch.com</a>, or leave us a voicemail at (510) 936-1618. And please join us again next week for our next featured founder.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/57e7d14b-dbc3-4da7-a0e1-57772971d9db?dark=false" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/how-one-founder-aims-to-bring-researchers-and-food-producers-together-around-cultured-meat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2192651</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taiwan Innovative Space will conduct a test launch of its Hapith I rocket in Australia later this year</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/taiwan-innovative-space-will-conduct-a-test-launch-of-its-hapith-i-rocket-in-australia-later-this-year/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/taiwan-innovative-space-will-conduct-a-test-launch-of-its-hapith-i-rocket-in-australia-later-this-year/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 16:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[low-earth orbit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taiwan innovative space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tispace]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2192639</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Australian regulators have given Taiwan Innovative Space, a five-year-old launch company that goes by Tispace, the green light to conduct a commercial launch at a newly licensed facility in southern Australia later this year. Tispace will conduct a test flight of its two-stage, suborbital rocket Hapith I from the Whalers Way Orbital Launch Complex in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Australian regulators have given Taiwan Innovative Space, a five-year-old launch company that goes by <a href="http://www.tispace.com/">Tispace</a>, the green light to conduct a commercial launch at a newly licensed facility in southern Australia later this year.</p>
<p>Tispace will conduct a test flight of its two-stage, suborbital rocket Hapith I from the Whalers Way Orbital Launch Complex in Southern Australia. The flight will be used to validate the vehicle’s propulsion, guidance, telemetry and structure systems, Tispace said in a news release. The launch facility, operated by space infrastructure company Southern Launch, received its license from the country’s industry ministry in March.</p>
<p>The news is potentially significant for both Australia and Taiwan’s burgeoning space industries, which have lagged behind other nations&#8217;. Australia only established a domestic space agency in 2018, and interest in how the country can get in on the new space economy has only grown since. The newly licensed launch facility will initially support a test launch campaign for up to three suborbital rockets, in order to collect data on the possible environmental impacts of the site.</p>
<p>“This [launch permit approval] is an important outcome in establishing Australia’s commercial launch capability and demonstrating what our country can offer to the international space sector,” Australia’s Minister for Industry, Science and Technology, Christian Porter, said in a statement. “Space is a significant global growth market that will support Australia’s economic future through big investment, new technologies and job growth across multiple industries.”</p>
<p>Taiwan has also been slow to develop a home-grown space industry, though the country took a major step forward when Taiwanese legislators passed the Space Development Law in May to spur the development of a domestic space program. But while the country has a handful of satellites in orbit &#8212; most recently the YUSAT and IDEASSat CubeSats, which were transported into orbit on a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket from Cape Canaveral in January &#8212; it has yet to launch a rocket or spacecraft from its soil.</p>
<p>Hapith I is Taiwan’s first domestically manufactured rocket, and Tispace its first commercial space launch company. The company had planned to test the Hapith vehicle from a launch site in Taiwan, but the site was scrapped over legal issues concerning the location. In addition to launch, Tispace may start conducting even more of its operations abroad: According to an Australian press release, it’s also considering “bringing manufacturing of complete rocket systems” to the land down under.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2Ds3MM6dZC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/lets-make-a-deal-a-crash-course-on-corporate-development/">Let’s make a deal: A crash course on corporate development</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Let’s make a deal: A crash course on corporate development&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/lets-make-a-deal-a-crash-course-on-corporate-development/embed/#?secret=2Ds3MM6dZC" data-secret="2Ds3MM6dZC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/taiwan-innovative-space-will-conduct-a-test-launch-of-its-hapith-i-rocket-in-australia-later-this-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2192639</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Netflix&#8217;s live-action &#8216;Cowboy Bebop&#8217; series arrives on November 19th</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/netflixs-live-action-cowboy-bebop-series-arrives-on-november-19th/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/netflixs-live-action-cowboy-bebop-series-arrives-on-november-19th/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 16:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cowboy Bebop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2192627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Netflix's live-action adaptation of classic anime Cowboy Bebop has been a long time coming, and the show finally has a release date. The 10-episode first season will start streaming on November 19th.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Kris Holt</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://www.twitter.com/krisholt">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Kris Holt is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com/">Engadget</a>. 	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/foxconn-plans-to-build-ev-factories-in-the-us-and-thailand-in-2022/">Foxconn plans to build EV factories in the US and Thailand in 2022</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/heatworks-opens-pre-orders-for-its-plumbing-free-countertop-dishwasher/">Heatworks opens pre-orders for its plumbing-free countertop dishwasher</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Netflix&#8217;s live-action adaptation of classic anime <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/cowboy%20bebop" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1"><em><ins>Cowboy Bebop</ins></em></a><em> </em>has been a long time coming, and the show finally has a release date. The 10-episode first season will start streaming on November 19th.</p>
<p>Although <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/netflix" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1"><ins>Netflix</ins></a> hasn&#8217;t posted a trailer just yet, it provided a first proper look at <em>Cowboy Bebop</em> in a bunch of photos. The images show John Cho (Spike Spiegel), Mustafa Shakir (Jet Black) and Daniella Pineda (Faye Valentine) <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-04-04-cowboy-bebop-netflix-john-cho-mustafa-shakir.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="22" data-v9y="1"><ins>in character</ins></a>, as well as an adorable corgi.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">See You Space Cowboy. </p>
<p>Meet Spike Spiegel (John Cho), Jet Black (Mustafa Shakir), and Faye Valentine (Daniella Pineda) in Cowboy Bebop. Premiering November 19 <a href="https://t.co/7vRtZvYjYM">pic.twitter.com/7vRtZvYjYM</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Netflix (@netflix) <a href="https://twitter.com/netflix/status/1429790537922404356?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Live-action adaptations of anime haven&#8217;t typically been well-received (here&#8217;s looking at you, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-04-08-ghost-in-the-shell-cyberpunk.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="25" data-v9y="1"><em><ins>Ghost in the Shell</ins></em></a>). There&#8217;s pressure on Netflix to get this take on <em>Cowboy Bebop</em> right, but things are looking promising. The core cast looks great in the first batch of images, while some key creatives from the 1998 anime are involved. Legendary composer Yoko Kanno <a href="https://twitter.com/NetflixGeeked/status/1429805689522753539" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="26" data-v9y="1"><ins>returns</ins></a>, while original director Shinichirō Watanabe consulted on the Netflix show.</p>
<p>Production started in 2019 but it was paused for eight months after Cho <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-18-cowboy-bebop-john-cho.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="27" data-v9y="1"><ins>sustained a knee injury</ins></a> on the set. Filming eventually <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-cowboy-bebop-092024319.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="28" data-v9y="1"><ins>wrapped in March</ins></a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<figure><img src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fs.yimg.com%2Fos%2Fcreatr-uploaded-images%2F2021-08%2F7a5223e0-0424-11ec-af57-85e8a0d94b20&amp;thumbnail=675%2C&amp;client=49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo&amp;signature=2421f504c97adbb19fedcefa4710c6f0e7f15162" alt="Cowboy Bebop" data-uuid="dc544d7e-5697-3ead-9e78-f22e09f64ac8" /></p>
<div class="photo-credit">Netflix</div>
</figure>
<div><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This post originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/netflix-cowboy-bebop-release-date-photos-152038789.html">Engadget</a>.</em></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/netflixs-live-action-cowboy-bebop-series-arrives-on-november-19th/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2192627</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zūm CEO Ritu Narayan explains why equity and accessibility works for mobility services</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/zum-ceo-ritu-narayan-explains-why-equity-and-accessibility-works-for-mobility-services/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/zum-ceo-ritu-narayan-explains-why-equity-and-accessibility-works-for-mobility-services/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 16:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Mobility Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobility as a service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ride hailing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ride-sharing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ritu Narayan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2188246</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Getting children to school safely is a challenge nearly as old as public education. But rarely have entrepreneurs tackled the problem of updating and optimizing one of our largest transit systems.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Getting children to school safely and reliably is a challenge as old as public education itself. But rarely have any entrepreneurs tackled the problem of updating and optimizing one of the nation&#8217;s largest legacy transit systems, now nearly a century old. It&#8217;s still common to find people at U.S. student transportation hubs speaking into walkie-talkies and wrangling clipboards as they sort passengers into gas-guzzling yellow buses.</p>
<p>Ritu Narayan was working as a product executive at eBay when her two children began attending school. Finding safe and reliable options for getting them to campus was sometimes so difficult that anytime those options would fall out, she would be on the verge of leaving her job.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			&#8220;We had the minimum viable product, which we expanded upon, built the entire platform, and we kept on going to better places with our solutions.&#8221;					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Bearing in mind that her mother in India had set aside a career to raise Narayan and her three siblings, she founded Zūm in 2016 with brothers Abhishek and Vivek Garg to optimize routes, create transparency and make school commutes greener; since then, Zūm has operated in several California districts (including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/zum-wins-150m-from-san-francisco-schools-to-modernize-and-electrify-student-transport/">San Francisco</a>), as well as in Seattle, Chicago and Dallas. In Oakland, Zūm has optimized routes to reduce the previous bus requirement by 29 percent, with the balance being serviced by midsized vehicles.</p>
<p>Zūm also plans to have a fleet of 10,000 electric school buses by 2025 and is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/child-transpo-startup-zum-aims-to-create-1-gigawatt-of-energy-with-electric-school-buses/">partnering with AutoGrid</a> to transform that fleet into a virtual power plant with the potential capacity to route 1 GW of energy back to the grid.</p>
<p>To get a deeper look into the startup&#8217;s plans and hear what Narayan has learned from its journey so far, we discussed the pandemic&#8217;s impacts on Zūm&#8217;s development, where she thinks the company will be a year from now, and how she convinced investors to back a business model that embraces accessibility and equity.</p>
<p><em>(Editor&#8217;s note: This interview has been edited for clarity and length.)</em></p>
<p><b>How did COVID-19 affect your business? What percentage of your business is back now?</b></p>
<p>It&#8217;s funny, because we used to say that student transportation is a recession-proof business, and no matter what, kids are still going to go to school, but the pandemic was the first time in probably the last 100 years when kids across the globe did not go to school. It was an interesting time for us, because overnight, all the rides were closed and we had to focus on what was needed immediately to support our districts and students.</p>
<p>We realized that the school is such an important physical infrastructure that&#8217;s not just for education, but students get meals there as well as physical and emotional help. So we helped the school districts with reverse logistics, taking the meals or laptops from the school districts and delivering them to homes, because our software could handle that kind of thing. That was just an interim to make sure the communities settled. Starting last year, rides started coming back around 30%, and this year starting in April, it has been 100% back in the business.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/zum-ceo-ritu-narayan-explains-why-equity-and-accessibility-works-for-mobility-services/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2188246</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>With more cash and a launch, Vannevar Labs is reconnecting Silicon Valley to its defense industry roots</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/vannevar-labs-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/vannevar-labs-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 16:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anduril]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[defense tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[department of defense]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foreign language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[natural language processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vannevar Labs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2192597</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Silicon Valley was once one of the most productive regions in the country for the defense industry, churning out chips and technologies that helped the United States overtake the Soviet Union during the Cold War. Since then, the region has been known far less for silicon and defense than for the consumer internet products of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Silicon Valley was once one of the most productive regions in the country for the defense industry, churning out chips and technologies that helped the United States overtake the Soviet Union during the Cold War. Since then, the region has been known far less for silicon and defense than for the consumer internet products of Google, Facebook and Netflix.</p>
<p>A small number of startups, though, are attempting to revitalize that important government-industry nexus as the rise of China pushes more defense planners in Washington to double down on America’s technical edge. <a href="https://www.vannevarlabs.com">Vannevar Labs</a> is one of this new crop, and it has hit some new milestones in its quest to displace traditional defense contractors with Silicon Valley entrepreneurial acumen.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/25/vannevar-labs-comes-out-of-stealth-to-bring-best-in-class-ai-tech-to-national-security-agencies/">I last chatted with the company just as it was debuting in late 2019</a>, having raised a $4.5 million seed. The company has been quiet and heads down the past two years as it developed a product and traction within the defense establishment. Now it’s ready to reveal a bit more of what all that work has culminated in.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jcXDFkYEsh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/25/vannevar-labs-comes-out-of-stealth-to-bring-best-in-class-ai-tech-to-national-security-agencies/">Vannevar Labs comes out of stealth to bring best-in-class AI tech to national security agencies</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Vannevar Labs comes out of stealth to bring best-in-class AI tech to national security agencies&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/25/vannevar-labs-comes-out-of-stealth-to-bring-best-in-class-ai-tech-to-national-security-agencies/embed/#?secret=jcXDFkYEsh" data-secret="jcXDFkYEsh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>First, the company officially launched its Vannevar Decrypt product in January of this year. It’s focused on foreign language natural language processing, organizing overseas data and resources that are collected by the intelligence community and then immediately translating and interpreting those documents for foreign policy decisionmakers. CEO and co-founder Brett Granberg said that the product “went from one deployment to a dozen adoptions.”</p>
<p>Second, the company raised a $12 million Series A investment in May from Costanoa Ventures and Point72, with General Catalyst participating. Costanoa and GC co-led the startup’s seed round.</p>
<p>Finally, the company has been on a hiring spree. The team has grown into a crew of 20 employees, and the firm last week brought on Scott Sanders to lead business development. Sanders was one of the earliest employees at Anduril, and had spent several years at the company. Vannevar also added to its board John Doyle, a long-time Palantir employee who was head of its national security business, according to Granberg. Today, the team is equally split between national security folks and technologists, and he says that the team is set to double this year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_1886228" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1886228" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-1886228" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Vannevar-Labs.png?w=680" alt="Vannevar Labs" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Vannevar-Labs.png 4608w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Vannevar-Labs.png?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Vannevar-Labs.png?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Vannevar-Labs.png?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Vannevar-Labs.png?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Vannevar-Labs.png?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Vannevar-Labs.png?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Vannevar-Labs.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1886228" class="wp-caption-text">Co-founders Nini Moorhead and Brett Granberg of Vannevar Labs. Photo via Vannevar Labs.</p></div></p>
<p>With a few years of hindsight, Granberg says that he has refined what he considers the best model for defense tech startups to break into the hardscrabble market at the Pentagon and across Northern Virginia.</p>
<p>First, there needs to be incredible focus on getting access to actual end users and learning their work. The functions that defense and intelligence personnel perform are completely different from operations in the commercial economy, and trying to translate what works at a large corporation into defense is a fool’s errand. “You need to have both the DNA of understanding new technology and the DNA of deeply understanding a lot of different use cases within DoD,” Granberg said, referencing the Department of Defense.</p>
<p>That has directly informed how Decrypt has developed over time. “We started focusing on the counter-terrorism space, and as the government moved away from counter-terrorism, we started moving to the foreign actors that were important,” he said. “Once we have our first couple of deployments, we are able to iterate very, very quickly.”</p>
<p>He also strongly eschews a popular view in defense procurement circles that there are “dual-use” technologies that can be used equally well in commercial and defense applications. “Some of the most important mission problems where the government spends the most money and has the most interest,” he explained, are also contexts where commercial off-the-shelf products (dubbed COTS in the industry parlance) are least useful. He says startups targeting defense simply cannot split their bandwidth by also trying to learn commercial use cases.</p>
<p>In fact, he went so far to predict that “you are going to see a lot of companies that have raised a lot of money that will fizzle out in the coming years” because they just can’t nail the dual-use model well.</p>
<p>Second, he argues that defense tech startups need to move beyond the model that each company should work on one platform, and instead move to an organizational model where a company offers multiple products to reach scale. Each product has the potential to reach “a couple of hundred million in revenue,” according to Granberg, but it is hard to expand a company’s size if it doesn’t parallelize product development.</p>
<p>To that end, Granberg said that he pushes Vannevar Labs to always be exploring new product lines for growth. “Decrypt is our first product [but]10% of our energy is in new product efforts,” he said. “I can imagine when we are three to four years down the line… it might be nine-10 products.” He said that the one platform approach might have worked for Palantir, which ironically, is the major winner in the defense tech space the last few years. But newer companies like Anduril and Shield AI have been designed around product line expansion.</p>
<p>Finally, noting those other companies, Granberg believes there is something of a collective benefit as each startup makes headway in the defense sector. “There is this theory in our space that we don’t view ourselves as competitors — if one of us does well, we all do well,” he said. Given the varied mission requirements of different agencies and the absolute massive scale of budgets in this field, startups actually have a lot of independent terrain to explore, even if they come up against the big legacy defense contractors on a regular basis.</p>
<p>As for Vannevar Labs, its next goal is to turn its Decrypt product into a program of record, which would guarantee it a certain level of sales and revenue for potentially years into the future. That’s a huge bar to leap, but would be a turning point in the company’s long-term trajectory.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iFkU8FfU5R"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/academy-investor-network-usaa/">Can the military academies compete with Stanford and Harvard in venture? Two veterans are raising $50M to find out</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Can the military academies compete with Stanford and Harvard in venture? Two veterans are raising $50M to find out&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/academy-investor-network-usaa/embed/#?secret=iFkU8FfU5R" data-secret="iFkU8FfU5R" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/vannevar-labs-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2192597</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Announcing the agenda for TechCrunch Sessions: SaaS</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/announcing-the-agenda-for-techcrunch-sessions-saas/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/announcing-the-agenda-for-techcrunch-sessions-saas/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Smith]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 15:45:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abby Kearns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ali ghodsi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AppDynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CapitalG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Casey Aylward]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costanoa Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daniel Dines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Databricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DataRobot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dave Wright]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firewall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greylock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jared Spataro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Javier Soltero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jay Kreps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jenn Knight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jyoti bansal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kathy Baxter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kobie Fuller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laela Sturdy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nick Mehta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sarah Guo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ServiceNow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software as a service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uipath]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191190</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TechCrunch Sessions is back! On October 27, we’re taking on the ferociously competitive field of software as a service (SaaS), and we&#8217;re thrilled to announce our packed agenda, overflowing with some of the biggest names and most exciting startups in the industry. And you’re in luck, because $75 early-bird tickets are still on sale — [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=agendapost60percent&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=agendapost60percent&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TechCrunch Sessions is back!</a></p>
<p id="speakable-summary">On October 27, we’re taking on the ferociously competitive field of software as a service (SaaS), and we&#8217;re thrilled to announce our packed agenda, overflowing with some of the biggest names and most exciting startups in the industry. And you’re in luck, because <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=agendapost60percent&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=agendapost60percent&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$75 early-bird tickets are still on sale</a> — make sure you book yours so you can enjoy all the agenda has to offer and save $100 bucks before prices go up!</p>
<p>Throughout the day, you can expect to hear from industry experts, and take part in discussions about the potential of new advances in data, open source, how to deal with the onslaught of security threats, investing in early-stage startups and plenty more.</p>
<p>We’ll be joined by some of the biggest names and the smartest and most prescient people in the industry, including <strong>Javier Soltero</strong> at Google, <b>Kathy Baxter </b>at Salesforce, <b>Jared Spataro </b>at Microsoft,<b> Jay Kreps </b>at Confluent, <b>Sarah Guo </b>at Greylock and<b> Daniel Dines</b> at UiPath.</p>
<p>You’ll be able to find and engage with people from all around the world through world-class networking on our virtual platform — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=agendapost60percent&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=agendapost60percent&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">all for $75 and under</a> for a limited time, with even deeper discounts for nonprofits and government agencies, students and up-and-coming founders!</p>
<p>Our agenda showcases some of the powerhouses in the space, but also plenty of smaller teams that are building and debunking fundamental technologies in the industry. We still have a few tricks up our sleeves and will be adding some new names to the agenda over the next month, so keep your eyes open.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="X7XLUTfQyz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/databricks-co-founder-and-ceo-ali-ghodsi-is-coming-to-tc-sessions-saas/">Databricks co-founder and CEO Ali Ghodsi is coming to TC Sessions: SaaS</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Databricks co-founder and CEO Ali Ghodsi is coming to TC Sessions: SaaS&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/databricks-co-founder-and-ceo-ali-ghodsi-is-coming-to-tc-sessions-saas/embed/#?secret=X7XLUTfQyz" data-secret="X7XLUTfQyz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In the meantime, check out these agenda highlights:</p>
<h3><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient"><strong>Survival of the Fittest: Investing in Today’s SaaS Market<br />
</strong></span>with Casey Aylward (Costanoa Ventures), Kobie Fuller (Upfront) and Sarah Guo (Greylock)</h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">The venture capital world is faster and more competitive than ever. For investors hoping to get into the hottest SaaS deal, things are even crazier. With more nontraditional money pouring into the sector, remote dealmaking now the norm and an increasingly global market for software startups, venture capitalists are being forced to shake up their own operations &#8212; and expectations. TechCrunch sits down with three leading investors to discuss how they are fighting for allocation in hot deals, what they’ve changed in their own processes, and what today’s best founders are demanding.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient"><strong>Data, Data Everywhere<br />
</strong></span>with Ali Ghodsi (Databricks)</h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">As companies struggle to manage and share increasingly large amounts of data, it&#8217;s no wonder that Databricks, whose primary product is a data lake, was valued at a whopping $28 billion for its most recent funding round. We&#8217;re going to talk to CEO Ali Ghodsi about why his startup is so hot, and what comes next.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient">SaaS Security, Today and Tomorrow</span><br />
with Edna Conway (Microsoft), Olivia Rose (Amplitude)</h3>
<ul>
<li>Enterprises face a constant stream of threats, from nation states to cybercriminals and corporate insiders. After a year where billions worked from home and the cloud reigned supreme, startups and corporations alike can&#8217;t afford to stay off the security pulse. Find out what SaaS startups need to know about security now, and in the future.</li>
</ul>
<h3><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient"><strong>Automation&#8217;s Moment Is Now</strong></span><br />
with Daniel Dines (UiPath), Laela Sturdy (CapitalG) and Dave Wright (ServiceNow)</h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">One thing we learned during the pandemic is the importance of automation, and that&#8217;s only likely to be more pronounced as we move forward. We&#8217;ll be talking to UiPath CEO Daniel Dines, Laela Sturdy, an investor at CapitalG and Dave Wright from ServiceNow about why this is automation&#8217;s moment.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient"><strong>Was the Pandemic Cloud Productivity&#8217;s Spark</strong></span><br />
with Javier Soltero (Google)</h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">One big aspect of SaaS is productivity apps like Gmail, Google Calendar and Google Drive. We&#8217;ll talk with executive Javier Soltero about the role Google Workspace plays in the Google cloud strategy.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient"><strong>The Future Is Wide Open</strong><br />
</span>with Abby Kearns (Puppet), Aghi Marietti (Kong) and Jason Warner (Redpoint)</h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many startups today have an open-source component, and it&#8217;s no wonder. It builds an audience and helps drive sales. We&#8217;ll talk with Abby Kearns from Puppet, Augusto “Aghi” Marietti from Kong and Jason Warner, an investor at Redpoint, about why open source is such a popular way to build a business.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient"><strong>How Microsoft Shifted from On-Prem to the Cloud</strong></span><br />
with Jared Spataro (Microsoft)</h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jared Spataro has been with Microsoft for over 15 years and he was a part of the shift from strictly on-prem software to that which is dominated by the cloud. Today he runs one of the most successful SaaS products out there, and we&#8217;ll talk to him about how Microsoft made that shift and what it&#8217;s meant to the company.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient"><strong>How Startups are Turning Data into Software Gold</strong></span><br />
with Jenn Knight (Agentsync), Barr Moses (Monte Carlo) and Dan Wright (DataRobot)</h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">The era of big data is behind us. Today’s leading SaaS startups are working </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">with</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> data, instead of merely fighting to help customers collect information. We’ve collected three leaders from three data-focused startups that are forging new markets to get their insight on how today’s SaaS companies are leveraging data to build new companies, attack new problems and, of course, scale like mad.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient"><strong>What Happens After Your Startup Is Acquired</strong></span><br />
with Jyoti Bansal (Harness), Nick Mehta (GainSight) a<strong>nd Jewel Burkes Solomon (Partpic)</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">We&#8217;ll speak to three founders about the emotional upheaval of being acquired and what happens after the check clears and the sale closes. Our panel includes Jyoti Bansal who founded AppDynamics, Jewel Burkes Solomon, who founded Partpic and Nick Mehta from GainSight.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient"><strong>How Confluent Rode the Open Source Wave to IPO</strong></span><br />
with Jay Kreps (Confluent)</h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Confluent, the streaming platform built on top of Apache Kafka, was born out of a project at LinkedIn, and rode that from startup to IPO. We&#8217;ll speak to co-founder and CEO Jay Kreps to learn about what that journey was like.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>We&#8217;ll have more sessions and names shortly, so stay tuned. But get excited in the meantime, we certainly are.</p>
<p><strong>Pro tip:</strong> Keep your finger on the pulse of TC Sessions: SaaS. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=agendapost60percent&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=agendapost60percent&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Get updates</a> when we announce new speakers, add events and offer ticket discounts.</p>
<p>Why should you carve a day out of your hectic schedule to attend TC Sessions: SaaS? This may be the first year we’ve focused on SaaS, but this ain’t our first rodeo. Here’s what other attendees have to say about their TC Sessions experience.</p>
<p>“TC Sessions: Mobility offers several big benefits. First, networking opportunities that result in concrete partnerships. Second, the chance to learn the latest trends and how mobility will evolve. Third, the opportunity for unknown startups to connect with other mobility companies and build brand awareness.” — Karin Maake, senior director of communications at FlashParking.</p>
<p>“People want to be around what&#8217;s interesting and learn what trends and issues they need to pay attention to. Even large companies like GM and Ford were there, because they&#8217;re starting to see the trend move toward mobility. They want to learn from the experts, and TC Sessions: Mobility has all the experts.” — Melika Jahangiri, vice president at Wunder Mobility.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=agendapost60percent&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=agendapost60percent&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TC Sessions: SaaS 2021</a> takes place on October 27. Grab your team, join your community and create opportunity. Don’t wait — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=agendapost60percent&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=agendapost60percent&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">jump on the early bird ticket sale right now</a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-1d55f0d8caafae9cbb2c5dda72b72e89"
			width="99%"
			height="1000"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/1d55f0d8caafae9cbb2c5dda72b72e89"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-1d55f0d8caafae9cbb2c5dda72b72e89')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-1d55f0d8caafae9cbb2c5dda72b72e89'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/announcing-the-agenda-for-techcrunch-sessions-saas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191190</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Givz raises $3M in seed funding to make donations a marketing tool for businesses</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/givz-raises-3m-in-seed-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/givz-raises-3m-in-seed-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 15:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accomplice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eniac ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Givz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vic Singh]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2192366</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Givz, which has developed an API-powered platform that gives brands a way to convert discounts into donations, has raised $3 million in seed funding. Eniac and Accomplice co-led the financing for the New York-based startup. Additional investors include Supernode Ventures, Claude Wasserstein of Fine Day, Phoenix Club and Dylan Whitman. Givz was founded in 2017 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://givz.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Givz</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which has developed an API-powered platform that gives brands a way to convert discounts into donations, has raised $3 million in seed funding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eniac and Accomplice co-led the financing for the New York-based startup. Additional investors include Supernode Ventures, Claude Wasserstein of Fine Day, Phoenix Club and Dylan Whitman.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Givz was founded in 2017 to make charitable giving more accessible and convenient for the masses. In March 2020, right before the COVID-19 pandemic hit, the company pivoted from B2C to B2B and used the technology rails it had built to create the e-commerce marketing platform that Givz is today.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company aims to drive “full-price purchasing behavior” by giving consumers the ability to convert the money they would be saving if getting a discount, and donating it to their favorite charities. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Prior to the funding, Givz had been working with more than 80 enterprise, mid-market and SMB retail and e-commerce clients such as H&amp;M, Tom Brady’s TB12, Seedlip and Terez, and accumulated more than 40,000 individual users. Since the shift last year, the company has helped drive more than $1 million to 1,100 charities, according to CEO and founder Andrew Forman.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It just launched on Shopify, which Forman says will give the startup access to the 1.7 million retailers that use Shopify as their e-commerce platform.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Givz operates under the premise that “donation-driven marketing” consistently outperforms discounts and costs less, “making it an attractive addition&#8221; to corporate marketing.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We are creating a new marketing category and generating the largest sustainable charitable giving platform in the process,” he told TechCrunch. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An example of a company using Givz can be found in Tervis, which offered customers </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">“For every $50 you spend, you’ll receive $15 to give to the charity of your choice.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“They used Givz technology to allow consumers to choose the charity of their choice and make a turnkey disbursement to hundreds of charities,” Forman explained. “They saw a 20% lift in website conversion and a 17% increase in average order value as a result of this offer.”</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2192368" style="width: 580px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2192368" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2192368 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Givz.jpg?w=570" alt="" width="570" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Givz.jpg 1144w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Givz.jpg?resize=126,150 126w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Givz.jpg?resize=252,300 252w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Givz.jpg?resize=768,916 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Givz.jpg?resize=570,680 570w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Givz.jpg?resize=42,50 42w" sizes="(max-width: 570px) 100vw, 570px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2192368" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Givz</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Currently, Givz has eight employees with plans to more than double that number over the next year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company plans to use the new capital toward that hiring, and to do some marketing of its own.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We also want to explore the full potential around the consumer behavior data we collect,” Forman said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the short term, Givz is focused on “Shopify growth” with direct to consumer brands.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“But we have successful use cases and huge potential with enterprise retailers and financial institutions</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">,” Forman told TechCrunch. “In the future, we have our sights set on restaurants, the gaming industry and global expansion. I believe that using personalized donations to incentivize consumer behavior has endless application across industries, verticals and continents.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eniac partner Vic Singh said that there’s been a trend of brands experimenting with different ways to target the socially conscious consumer. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We believe Givz&#8217;s donation-driven marketing platform offers brands the best way to attract the socially conscious consumer while elevating their brand, moving more inventory and driving increased order value rather than simplistic traditional discounting,” he added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Accomplice’s TJ Mahony said that both he and Singh believed SMS would emerge as a new marketing category, which led to early investments in Attentive and Postscript, respectively.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We both saw a similar opportunity with Givz,” he wrote via e-mail. “Discounting is a well worn marketing muscle, but it&#8217;s detrimental to the brand, margins and customer expectations. We believe continuous impact marketing becomes the alternative to discounting and marketers will begin to build teams and budget around thoughtful and persistent giving strategies.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5AsoCtPZCC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/klaviyo-ec1-marketing/">Marketing in 2021 is emotional and not just transactional</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Marketing in 2021 is emotional and not just transactional&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/klaviyo-ec1-marketing/embed/#?secret=5AsoCtPZCC" data-secret="5AsoCtPZCC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/givz-raises-3m-in-seed-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2192366</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lux Capital&#8217;s Deena Shakir is helping judge Startup Battlefield at this year&#8217;s Disrupt</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/lux-capitals-deena-shakir-is-helping-judge-startup-battlefield-at-this-years-disrupt/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/lux-capitals-deena-shakir-is-helping-judge-startup-battlefield-at-this-years-disrupt/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 14:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deena Shakir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lux capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup Battlefield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2159939</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Deena Shakir is a partner at Lux Capital, where she looks to invest in technologies that are streamlining analog industries while also improving lives and livelihoods. Among the companies she has backed, for example, are Shiru, which is leveraging computational design to create enhanced proteins to help feed the world; and AllStripes, which aggregates and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Deena Shakir is a partner at Lux Capital, where she looks to invest in technologies that are streamlining analog industries while also improving lives and livelihoods. Among the companies she has backed, for example, are <a href="https://www.shiru.com/">Shiru</a>, which is leveraging computational design to create enhanced proteins to help feed the world; and <a href="https://www.allstripes.com/">AllStripes</a>, which aggregates and analyzes medical records, then sells the de-identified data to pharma companies to help them develop medicines.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not a surprise that Shakir is focused on empowering people. Shakir&#8217;s father is a psychiatrist and as she <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/lux-capitals-deena-shakir-sees-space-and-frontier-tech-going-mainstream-right-now/">once told us</a>, &#8220;for a hot minute, I thought I was going to be a doctor myself.&#8221; Instead, after attending Harvard, then Georgetown’s School of Foreign Service, she wound up working for the State Department during the Obama administration, then headed to Google. She would stay for the next seven years, spending the last of them with GV, Google’s venture unit. There, her work revolved in part around some of the alternative protein companies in GV&#8217;s portfolio. Then, in 2019, she was poached by Lux.</p>
<p>Indeed, while Shakir might have once imagined working with people on an individual basis, she has become an increasingly sought-after investor in startup teams, which is why we couldn&#8217;t be more excited that she&#8217;s able to join us this year for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021?display=true">TechCrunch Disrupt</a>. Specifically, we&#8217;re thrilled that Shakir will be judging our Startup Battlefield competition, the centerpiece of Disrupt every year and oftentimes a life-changing event for the winning team &#8212; and often runners-up, too. Consider that past winners include Vurb, Dropbox, Mint and Yammer, while runner-up Cloudflare currently boasts a market cap of $38 billion.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yjmHPW6fHB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/lux-capitals-deena-shakir-sees-space-and-frontier-tech-going-mainstream-right-now/">Lux Capital&#8217;s Deena Shakir sees space and frontier tech going mainstream right now</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lux Capital&#8217;s Deena Shakir sees space and frontier tech going mainstream right now&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/lux-capitals-deena-shakir-sees-space-and-frontier-tech-going-mainstream-right-now/embed/#?secret=yjmHPW6fHB" data-secret="yjmHPW6fHB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>It&#8217;s because we take the competition &#8212; and our record to date &#8212; so seriously that we&#8217;re exceedingly thankful to savvy investors like Shakir, who ask the right questions, and make the tough decisions when it comes time to decide which teams to move along.</p>
<p>Want to watch and judge from home? With our entirely virtual event this year, you&#8217;re more than welcome to join us from the comfort of your home or office (and let us know what you think of the startups within the many networking forums you&#8217;ll find).</p>
<p>To watch this year&#8217;s 20+ startups compete for $100,000 &#8212; and to interact with more than 100 hours of content and thousands of enthusiastic startup fans &#8212; make sure to book your pass to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021?display=true">TC Disrupt, happening September 21-23</a> &#8212; all for less than $100.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021?display=true">Secure your seat today</a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			width="99%"
			height="1300"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/lux-capitals-deena-shakir-is-helping-judge-startup-battlefield-at-this-years-disrupt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2159939</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FDA fully approves Pfizer-BioNTech&#8217;s COVID-19 vaccine</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/fda-fully-approves-pfizer-biontechs-covid-19-vaccine/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/fda-fully-approves-pfizer-biontechs-covid-19-vaccine/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 14:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BioNTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pfizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2192576</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) has granted full approval to Pfizer-BioNTech&#8217;s COVID-19 vaccine, making it the first vaccine to achieve that status. The mRNA-based vaccine has been available since late last year through an Emergency Use Authorization (EUA), and will continue to be offered under that designation for those aged 12 to 15 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) has <a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-approves-first-covid-19-vaccine">granted full approval</a> to Pfizer-BioNTech&#8217;s COVID-19 vaccine, making it the first vaccine to achieve that status. The mRNA-based vaccine has been available since late last year through an Emergency Use Authorization (EUA), and will continue to be offered under that designation for those aged 12 to 15 until that separate approval process goes through, but the U.S. drug regulator now recognizes the Pfizer vaccine as fully approved and certified for adults 16 and up.</p>
<p>Part of receiving the approval means that Pfizer and BioNTech can now officially market their vaccine in the U.S., and the FDA revealed it&#8217;ll be offered under the trade dress &#8220;Comirnarty,&#8221; which doesn&#8217;t strike me as particularly catchy but at least it&#8217;s less of a mouthful than &#8220;the Pfizer-BioNTech COVID-19 vaccine.&#8221; FDA approval also means that the vaccine has met all of the administration&#8217;s standards for safety and efficacy, including preclinical and clinical trial data, as well as information about its manufacture, and data gathered from its use during the EUA period.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s hope that this new full authorization will encourage fence-sitters who have offered up &#8220;I&#8217;ll wait until it&#8217;s fully approved&#8221; as an excuse for not yet having gotten the vaccine despite its availability. At the very least, it&#8217;s going to be a lot harder for those hesitating to justify their unreasonable and irresponsible stance in the face of the ongoing pandemic.</p>
<p>Comirnarty got flagged for &#8220;Priority Review&#8221; by the FDA, which essentially means that the administration devoted its full attention to the process in order to expedite it. No word yet on a timeline for Moderna&#8217;s approval, but it&#8217;s also in the priority review queue.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll be talking to BioNTech CEO and co-founder Uğur Şahin at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=disrupt2021&amp;utm_content=ursheetpost&amp;utm_source=tcwebsite&amp;promo=ugursahinpost&amp;display=TRUE">TC Disrupt 2021</a> this year, so be sure to check out that virtual event coming up September 21-23.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9d1GtyATFL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/biontech-founder-ugur-sahin-and-mayfields-ursheet-parikh-are-coming-to-disrupt/">BioNTech founder Uğur Şahin and Mayfield&#8217;s Ursheet Parikh are coming to Disrupt</a></p></bl<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>ockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BioNTech founder Uğur Şahin and Mayfield&#8217;s Ursheet Parikh are coming to Disrupt&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/biontech-founder-ugur-sahin-and-mayfields-ursheet-parikh-are-coming-to-disrupt/embed/#?secret=9d1GtyATFL" data-secret="9d1GtyATFL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/fda-fully-approves-pfizer-biontechs-covid-19-vaccine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2192576</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why have the markets spurned public neoinsurance startups?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/why-have-the-markets-spurned-public-neoinsurance-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/why-have-the-markets-spurned-public-neoinsurance-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 14:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Swigart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MetroMile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oscar health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pie Insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[root insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2192540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The companies we're examining cover auto insurance (Root, MetroMile), home and rental insurance (Hippo, Lemonade), and health insurance (Oscar Health). All are taking a whacking by the market. Why?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We&#8217;ve spent <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/24/should-we-be-worried-about-insurtech-valuations/">quite a lot of time</a> of late wondering <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/06/a-lot-of-cash-and-little-love-an-insurtech-story/?tpcc=ECTW2020">just what the heck</a> is up with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/13/what-happens-when-wall-street-falls-out-of-love-with-your-sector/">the valuations of insurtech startups that went public</a> in the last year. Keep in mind that we&#8217;re discussing neoinsurance providers like MetroMile and Hippo, not insurtech marketplaces <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/insurify-raises-23m-series-a-to-add-new-coverage-varietals-boost-its-marketing-efforts/">like Insurify</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/the-zebra-reaches-100m-run-rate-turns-profitable-as-insurtech-booms/">or Zebra</a>.</p>
<p>There was a stream of insurtech exits in 2020 and early 2021. After <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/02/high-flying-ipos-for-lemonade-and-accolade-may-encourage-other-unicorns-to-go-public/">Lemonade&#8217;s firecracker IPO</a>, MetroMile and Hippo and Root also went public. Since those debuts, we&#8217;ve seen their valuations erode significantly.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>But Oscar Health got somewhat lost in our larger analysis of the space. An investor pointed out to The Exchange this weekend that we were a bit early in wondering just what investors were thinking when Oscar was going public &#8212; its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/oscar-healths-initial-ipo-price-is-so-high-it-makes-me-want-to-swear/">IPO price range felt incredibly high, and we said so</a>. Then, Oscar Health priced above that $32 to $34 per share interval, kicking off its life <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/oscar-health-prices-ipo-at-39-and-secures-a-9-5b-valuation/">worth $39 per share</a>.</p>
<p>Today&#8217;s it&#8217;s worth $13.58 per share.</p>
<p>We could call it another data point in our larger analysis, but it&#8217;s a bit more than that as Oscar Health expands the list of insurance <em>types</em> that startups tackled, scaled, took public and then saw fall out of investor favor. The companies that we are examining cover a number of industries, from auto insurance (Root, MetroMile), to home and rental insurance (Hippo, Lemonade), and, thanks to Oscar Health, health insurance as well. All are taking a whacking by the market.</p>
<p><em>Why?</em> Happily, I think I&#8217;ve figured it out. More precisely, a CEO of a neoinsurance company in a different niche talked The Exchange through one particular hypothesis that makes rather good sense.</p>
<h2>Show me the <del>money</del> metrics</h2>
<p>Last week, I chatted with <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/johnswigart/">Pie Insurance co-founder CEO John Swigart</a>. Pie sells SMB-focused insurance, with a focus on workers&#8217; comp coverage. In Swigart&#8217;s view, small businesses have historically been overcharged and underserved for insurance. With a bit of tech, his company can offer coverage to smaller companies than many traditional insurance providers found attractive, and at better price points to boot.</p>
<p>Pie raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/pie-insurance-raises-118m/">a $118 million Series C</a> in March, with <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/pie-insurance/company_financials">Crunchbase tallying $306 million</a> in external capital for the company thus far. We&#8217;ll talk more about Pie at a later date.</p>
<p>What matters for our needs this morning is what Swigart said when I asked him what in the flying fuck was going on with public insurtech share prices. Given that he is building a related company, I was hoping that he would be both up to speed and have a take. He did.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/why-have-the-markets-spurned-public-neoinsurance-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2192540</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Equity Monday: Stocks up, cryptos up, regulation up</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/equity-monday-stocks-up-cryptos-up-regulation-up/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/equity-monday-stocks-up-cryptos-up-regulation-up/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 14:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shelf.io]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zetwerk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2192553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. This is Equity Monday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/3fe3c48b-1973-44b3-ac25-e8b18e3d4fe9?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>This is Equity Monday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You can follow the show on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/equitypod">here</a>. I <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">also tweet</a>.</p>
<p>Today&#8217;s show was good fun to put together. Here&#8217;s what we got to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Global stocks are up to kick off the week. It&#8217;s a great way to start Monday, frankly.</li>
<li>Thinking broadly, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/21/china-roundup-bytedance-amazon/">latest regulatory news</a> from China regarding ByteDance is not super bullish for the nation&#8217;s tech industry. And what the <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/pranavdixit/big-tech-thought-it-had-a-billion-users-in-the-bag-now-its">Indian government is doing to its own technology industry is not encouraging</a>. But all of that <em>and</em> tension between the two countries is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/tencent-in-talks-to-lead-funding-in-indias-pocket-fm/">not stopping deals</a>. You can&#8217;t stop deals!</li>
<li>Facebook <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/08/21/facebook-coronavirus-vaccine/">bowed to pressure</a>, and released a content report that it had previously shelved.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/indias-zetwerk-valued-at-1-33-billion-in-new-funding/">Zetwerk raised a $150 million Series E.</a> The Indian startup scene is trucking right along, perhaps acting a bit as if its government wasn&#8217;t increasingly authoritarian.</li>
<li>Shelf.io raised a $52.5 million Series B in what we&#8217;re somewhat considering a classic Tiger-led deal.</li>
<li>And the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/virgin-orbit-to-go-public-via-3-2b-spac-deal/">SPAC boom is not over yet</a>, with yet another Virgin space company headed for the public markets.</li>
</ul>
<p>Woo! And that&#8217;s the start to the week. Hugs from here, and we&#8217;ll chat you on Wednesday!</p>
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 a.m. PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts!</i></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="V2eM7sstrR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/shelf-io-closes-huge-52-5m-series-b-after-posting-4x-arr-growth-in-the-last-year/">Shelf.io closes huge $52.5M Series B after posting 4x ARR growth in the last year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Shelf.io closes huge $52.5M Series B after posting 4x ARR growth in the last year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/shelf-io-closes-huge-52-5m-series-b-after-posting-4x-arr-growth-in-the-last-year/embed/#?secret=V2eM7sstrR" data-secret="V2eM7sstrR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/equity-monday-stocks-up-cryptos-up-regulation-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2192553</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shelf.io closes huge $52.5M Series B after posting 4x ARR growth in the last year</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/shelf-io-closes-huge-52-5m-series-b-after-posting-4x-arr-growth-in-the-last-year/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/shelf-io-closes-huge-52-5m-series-b-after-posting-4x-arr-growth-in-the-last-year/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 14:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insight Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[knowledge management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shelf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shelf.io]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2192525</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is the sort of deal that we expect to see Tiger in -- an outsized investment compared to prior rounds into a high-growth company that has lots of market room. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Covering public companies can be a bit of a drag. They grow some modest amount each year, and their constituent analysts pester them with questions about gross margin expansion and sales rep efficiency. It can be a little dull. Then there are startups, which grow much more quickly &#8212; and are more fun to talk about.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s the case with <a href="https://shelf.io/">Shelf.io</a>. The company announced an impressive set of metrics this morning, including that from July 2020 to July 2021, it grew its annual recurring revenue (ARR) 4x. Shelf also disclosed that it secured a $52.5 million Series B led by Tiger Global and Insight Partners.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s quick growth for a post-Series A startup. Crunchbase <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/shelf-io">reckons</a> that the company raised $8.2 million before its Series B, while <a href="http://pitchbook.com">PitchBook</a> pegs the number at $6.5 million. Regardless, the company was efficiently expanding from a limited capital base before its latest fundraising event.</p>
<p>What does the company&#8217;s software do? Shelf plugs into a company&#8217;s information systems, learns from the data and then helps employees respond to queries without forcing them to execute searches or otherwise hunt for information.</p>
<p>The company is starting with customer service as its target vertical. According to Shelf CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sedarius-tekara-perrotta-14658235">Sedarius Perrotta</a>, Shelf can absorb information from, say, Salesforce, SharePoint, legacy knowledge management platforms and Zendesk. Then, after training models and staff, the company&#8217;s software can begin to provide support staff with answers to customer questions as they talk to customers in real time.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s tech can also power responses to customer queries not aimed at a human agent and provide a searchable database of company knowledge to help workers more quickly solve customer issues.</p>
<p>Per Perrotta, Shelf is targeting the sales market next, with others to follow. How might Shelf fit into sales? According to the company, its software may be able to offer staff already written proposals for similar-seeming deals and other related content. The gist is that at companies that have lots of workers doing similar tasks &#8212; clicking around in Salesforce, or answering support queries, say &#8212; Shelf can learn from the activity and get smarter in helping employees with their tasks. I presume that the software&#8217;s learning ability will improve over time, as well.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Shelf, around 100 people today, hopes to double in size by the end of the year, and then double again next year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Y6rxoVm7kq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/the-tortoise-and-the-hare-story-is-playing-out-right-now-in-vc/">&#8216;The tortoise and the hare&#8217; story is playing out right now in VC</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;&#8216;The tortoise and the hare&#8217; story is playing out right now in VC&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/the-tortoise-and-the-hare-story-is-playing-out-right-now-in-vc/embed/#?secret=Y6rxoVm7kq" data-secret="Y6rxoVm7kq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That&#8217;s where the new capital comes in. Hiring folks in the worlds of machine learning and data science is very expensive. And because the company wants to scale those hires quickly, it will need a large bank balance to lean on.</p>
<p>Quick ARR growth was not the only reason Shelf was able to secure such an outsized Series B, at least when compared to how much capital it had raised before. Per Perrotta, Shelf has 130% net dollar retention and no churn to report, meaning its customers are both sticky and expand organically.</p>
<p>While Shelf is interesting today and has certainly found niches it can sell into in its current form, I am more curious about how far the company can take its machine learning system, called MerlinAI. If its tech can get sufficiently smart, its ability to prompt and help employees could reduce onboarding time and the overall cost of employee training. That would be a huge market.</p>
<p>This is the sort of deal that we expect to see Tiger in &#8212; an outsized investment (compared to prior rounds) into a high-growth company that has lots of market room. Whatever price Tiger just paid for the company&#8217;s stock, a few years of continued growth should de-risk the investment. By our read, Tiger is really just the market-leading bull on software market growth in the long term. Shelf fits into that thesis neatly.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/shelf-io-closes-huge-52-5m-series-b-after-posting-4x-arr-growth-in-the-last-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2192525</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PayPal expands the ability to buy, hold and sell cryptocurrency to the UK</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/paypal-expands-the-ability-to-buy-hold-and-sell-cryptocurrency-to-the-u-k/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/paypal-expands-the-ability-to-buy-hold-and-sell-cryptocurrency-to-the-u-k/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 13:49:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venmo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2192546</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PayPal will now allow users outside the U.S. to buy, hold and sell cryptocurrency for the first time. The company announced today the launch of a new service that will allow customers in the U.K. to select between four types of cryptocurrencies &#8212; including Bitcoin, Ethereum, Litecoin and Bitcoin Cash &#8212; which can be purchased [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">PayPal will now allow users outside the U.S. to buy, hold and sell cryptocurrency for the first time. The company announced today the launch of <a href="http://www.paypal.com/uk/crypto">a new service</a> that will allow customers in the U.K. to select between four types of cryptocurrencies &#8212; including Bitcoin, Ethereum, Litecoin and Bitcoin Cash &#8212; which can be purchased using a connected bank account or debit card.</p>
<p>The company first rolled out support for cryptocurrency in the U.S. last fall, in partnership with <a href="https://www.paxos.com/">Paxos Trust Company</a>. That service reached all U.S. customers <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/paypal-says-all-users-in-u-s-can-now-buy-hold-and-sell-cryptocurrencies/">as of mid-November.</a> PayPal-owned <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/venmo-adds-support-for-buying-holding-and-selling-cryptocurrencies/">Venmo also added support</a> for cryptocurrency last spring.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="owZUK8FsRG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/venmo-adds-support-for-buying-holding-and-selling-cryptocurrencies/">Venmo adds support for buying, holding and selling cryptocurrencies</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Venmo adds support for buying, holding and selling cryptocurrencies&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/venmo-adds-support-for-buying-holding-and-selling-cryptocurrencies/embed/#?secret=owZUK8FsRG" data-secret="owZUK8FsRG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>U.K. customers who want to purchase cryptocurrency can now do so via the PayPal website or mobile app, where they can choose from pre-determined purchase amounts or enter another amount of their own choosing. PayPal says users will be able to start buying as little as £1 of cryptocurrency, if they choose. There are, however, <a href="https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/paypal-fees?locale.x=en_GB">transaction fees</a> and currency conversion fees when buying and selling <a href="https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/paypal-fees?locale.x=en_GB">cryptocurrency</a>, the company notes. These vary based on the amount of cryptocurrency being bought or sold.</p>
<p>The new service itself is very much like PayPal&#8217;s U.S. offering, with one notable exception. PayPal told us it&#8217;s tailoring the transaction limits for its U.K. customers. At launch, the maximum amount for any single crypto purchase is £15,000. The maximum amount for purchases over a 12-month period is £35,000. In the U.S., the company had initially launched the service with a $20,000 weekly purchase limit. But it <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/paypal-increases-crypto-purchase-limits-to-100k">upped that to $100,000 in July</a> and <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/07/15/paypal-ups-weekly-crypto-purchase-limit-fivefold-to-100000-.html">dropped its annual purchase limit</a>.</p>
<p>The company also told TechCrunch the U.K. made sense as the first international expansion for its cryptocurrency service because it&#8217;s a fintech hub, as well as PayPal&#8217;s second-largest market globally, where it has a sizable base of consumer customers.</p>
<p>&#8220;We think that we&#8217;re going to be helping the cryptocurrency ecosystem develop further in the U.K. In the U.S., we knew there was high demand for this service. Yet we were surprised to see the level of customer engagement for PayPal’s in-app crypto service from day one,&#8221; a PayPal spokesperson said. &#8220;Since we’ve launched, we’ve seen incredible and sustained engagement from our users. Consumers who buy, hold and sell cryptocurrency on our platform in the U.S. log on at 2x their previous rate,&#8221; they added.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Cryptocurrency will also be a key feature in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/paypals-new-super-app-is-ready-to-launch-will-also-include-messaging/">PayPal&#8217;s forthcoming &#8220;super app</a>,&#8221; which is due to roll out over the next several months.</p>
<p>The company would not comment on if or when it would expand its other cryptocurrency services to the U.K., including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/paypals-new-feature-allows-u-s-consumers-to-check-out-using-cryptocurrency/">its more recently launched &#8220;Checkout with Crypto,</a>&#8221; which allows customers to checkout using their cryptocurrency at millions of online businesses by first converting into fiat currency the crypto needed for the transaction. Instead, PayPal said it wanted to first learn and observe how its U.K. customers adopt the new offering to buy, hold and sell cryptocurrency before rolling out more features and functionality.</p>
<p>Beyond its support for cryptocurrency in its own apps, PayPal&#8217;s venture capital arm has also made a number investments in crypto and the blockchain over the past months, including by participating in <a href="https://newsroom.paypal-corp.com/2021-06-17-TRM-Labs-Raises-14-Million-Series-A-Funding-Round">the $14 million Series A</a> for cryptocurrency risk management software TRM Labs; in <a href="https://newsroom.paypal-corp.com/2021-05-27-PayPal-Ventures-Invests-In-Talos-Series-A-Funding-Round">the $40 million Series A</a> for digital asset trading infrastructure company Talos; and in <a href="https://newsroom.paypal-corp.com/2021-03-02-PayPal-Ventures-Invests-In-TaxBits-Series-A-Funding-Round">the $100 million Series A</a> for crypto tax software company TaxBit.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="b4GYXpWxOW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/everyone-wants-to-fund-the-next-coinbase/">Everyone wants to fund the next Coinbase</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Everyone wants to fund the next Coinbase&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/everyone-wants-to-fund-the-next-coinbase/embed/#?secret=b4GYXpWxOW" data-secret="b4GYXpWxOW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;The pandemic has accelerated digital change and innovation across all aspects of our lives — including the digitization of money and greater consumer adoption of digital financial services,&#8221; Jose Fernandez da Ponte, vice president and general manager, Blockchain, Crypto and Digital Currencies at PayPal, said in a statement.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our global reach, digital payments expertise, and knowledge of consumer and businesses, combined with rigorous security and compliance controls provides us the unique opportunity, and the responsibility, to help people in the U.K. to explore cryptocurrency. We are committed to continue working closely with regulators in the U.K., and around the world, to offer our support — and meaningfully contribute to shaping the role digital currencies will play in the future of global finance and commerce,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Currently, PayPal offers support for cryptocurrency in the U.S., excluding Hawaii, and U.S. territories, in addition to the U.K., but says it&#8217;s exploring the potential for digital currencies through partnerships with licensed and regulated cryptocurrency platforms and with central banks elsewhere in the world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/paypal-expands-the-ability-to-buy-hold-and-sell-cryptocurrency-to-the-u-k/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2192546</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moesif secures $12M to provide user behavior insights on API usage</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/moesif-secures-12m-to-provide-user-behavior-insights-on-api-usage/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/moesif-secures-12m-to-provide-user-behavior-insights-on-api-usage/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 13:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arra Malekzadeh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Craft Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david sacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Derric Gilling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[merus capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moesif]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xing wang]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2192333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As more companies provide more API-first services, Moesif has developed a way for those companies to learn how their customers are utilizing them.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As more companies provide more API-first services, <a href="https://www.moesif.com/">Moesif</a> has developed a way for those companies to learn how their customers are utilizing them.</p>
<p>The San Francisco-based startup is adding to its capital raise Monday with the announcement of a $12 million Series A round led by David Sacks and Arra Malekzadeh of Craft Ventures. Existing investor Merus Capital, which led Moesif’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/04/moesif-raises-3-5m-seed-round-to-provide-insight-into-api-usage/">$3.5 million seed round</a> in 2019, also participated in the round, bringing the company’s total raise to $15.5 million, Moesif co-founder and CEO Derric Gilling told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Gilling and Xing Wang founded Moesif in 2017 and went <a href="https://techcrunch.com/gallery/our-favorite-startups-from-alchemist-accelerator-batch-15/slide/2/">through the Alchemist Accelerator</a> in 2018.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SWbz51xtVS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/04/moesif-raises-3-5m-seed-round-to-provide-insight-into-api-usage/">Moesif raises $3.5M seed round to provide insight into API usage</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Moesif raises $3.5M seed round to provide insight into API usage&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/04/moesif-raises-3-5m-seed-round-to-provide-insight-into-api-usage/embed/#?secret=SWbz51xtVS" data-secret="SWbz51xtVS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Companies seeking data around API usage and workflow traditionally had to build that capability in-house on top of a tech like Snowflake, Gilling said. One of the problems with that was if someone wanted a report, the process was ad hoc, meaning they would file a ticket and wait until a team had time to run the report. In addition, companies find it difficult to accurately bill customers on usage or manage when someone exceeds the rate limits.</p>
<p>“We started to see people build on top of our platform and pull data on APIs, and they started asking us how to directly serve customers, like making them aware if they are hitting a rate limit,” Gilling added. “We started to build new functionality and a way to customize the look and feel of the platform.”</p>
<p>Moesif provides self-service analytics that can be accessed daily and features to scale analytics in a more cost-effective manner. Customers use it to monitor features to better understand when there are issues with the API, and there are additional capabilities to understand who is using the API, how often and who may be likely to stop using a product based on how they are using it.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company is also now seeing its revenue grow over 20% month over month this year and adoption by more diverse use cases and larger companies. At the time of the seed round, the company was just getting started with analytics and user trials, Gilling said. Today, it boasts a customer list that includes UPS, Tomorrow.io, Symbl.ai and Deloitte.</p>
<p>The company has also gone from a team of two to nine employees, and Gilling expects to use the new funding to bolster that roster across engineering, sales, developer relations and customer success.</p>
<p>He is also focusing on being a thought leader in the space and is pushing go-to-market and building out a new set of features to monetize APIs and improve its dashboard to better differentiate Moesif from competitors, which he said focus more on server health versus customer usage.</p>
<p>As part of the investment, Craft Ventures’ Malekzadeh is joining Moesif’s board. She was introduced to Gilling by another portfolio company and felt Moesif fit into Crafts’ thesis on SaaS companies.</p>
<p>Malekzadeh’s particular interest is in developer tools, and while in her previous position working at a startup developing APIs, she felt firsthand the pain point of not being able to know how those APIs were being used, how much customers should be billed and “was always bugging the product and engineering teams for reports.”</p>
<p>Moesif didn’t exist at the time she worked at the startup, and instead, her company had to build it own tools that turned out to be clunky, while at the same time recruiting top engineers that didn’t want to take up their time with building something that wasn’t the company’s core product.</p>
<p>“The two founders are highly technical, but they provided great content on their website that helped me learn about them,” Malekzadeh added. “One of the interesting things about them is that even though they are technical, they speak the same language as a business user, which makes them special as a developer-first company. Just the growth in their revenue was super impressive, and their customer references were glowing.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1VoVRWR1nB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/the-most-important-api-metric-is-time-to-first-call/">The most important API metric is time to first call</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The most important API metric is time to first call&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/the-most-important-api-metric-is-time-to-first-call/embed/#?secret=1VoVRWR1nB" data-secret="1VoVRWR1nB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/moesif-secures-12m-to-provide-user-behavior-insights-on-api-usage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2192333</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>African fintech OPay valued at $2B in SoftBank Vision Fund 2-led $400M funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/african-fintech-opay-valued-at-2b-in-softbank-vision-fund-2-led-400m-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/african-fintech-opay-valued-at-2b-in-softbank-vision-fund-2-led-400m-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 12:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Group]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2192538</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chinese-backed and Africa-focused fintech company OPay raised $400 million in new financing led by SoftBank Vision Fund 2, Bloomberg reported Monday, valuing the company at $2 billion. The round, which marks the fund&#8217;s first investment in an African startup, drew participation from existing investors like Sequoia Capital China, Redpoint China, Source Code Capital and Softbank [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Chinese-backed and Africa-focused fintech company OPay raised $400 million in new financing led by SoftBank Vision Fund 2, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-08-23/softbank-bets-on-fintech-startup-opay-at-2-billion-valuation?sref=gni836kR">Bloomberg reported</a> Monday, valuing the company at $2 billion.</p>
<p>The round, which marks the fund&#8217;s first investment in an African startup, drew participation from existing investors like Sequoia Capital China, Redpoint China, Source Code Capital and Softbank Ventures Asia. Other investors, including DragonBall Capital and 3W Capital, also took part in the new financing round.</p>
<p>This news comes three months after The Information <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/african-fintech-opay-reportedly-raising-400m-at-a-1-5b-valuation/">reported</a> that the company was in talks to raise &#8220;up to $400 million at a $1.5 billion valuation&#8221; from a group of Chinese investors. The new financing also comes two years after OPay announced two funding rounds in 2019 — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/09/opera-founded-starup-opay-raises-50m-for-mobile-finance-in-nigeria/">$50 million</a> in June and a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/17/operas-africa-fintech-startup-opay-gains-120m-from-chinese-investors/">$120 million Series B</a> in November.</p>
<p>In an emailed statement, OPay CEO Yahui Zhou said OPay &#8220;wants to be the power that helps emerging markets reach a faster economic development.&#8221; The company, founded in 2018, had an exclusive presence in Nigeria before last year.</p>
<p>While the company started with providing customers with digital services in their everyday life, from mobility and logistics to e-commerce and fintech at cheap rates, those super app plans have been largely underwhelming.</p>
<p>Right now, it&#8217;s the company&#8217;s mobile money and payment arm that thrives the most. By simply allowing unbanked and underbanked users in Nigeria to send and receive money and pay bills through a network of thousands of agents, OPay has grown at an exponential rate.</p>
<p>The company plays in an extremely competitive fintech market. Nigeria is Africa’s most populous nation, and with a <a href="https://globalfindex.worldbank.org/archives/sub-saharan-africa">large share of its people underbanked and unbanked</a>, fintech is the most promising digital sector in the country. The same can be said for the continent as a whole. Mobile money services have long catered to the needs of the underbanked. Per GSMA, Africa had more than 160 million active mobile money users generating over $495 billion in transaction value last year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Parent company Opera reported that OPay’s monthly transactions grew 4.5x to over $2 billion in December last year. OPay also claims to process about 80% of bank transfers among mobile money operators in Nigeria and 20% of the country’s nonmerchant point of sales transactions. Last year, the company also said it acquired an international money transfer license with a WorldRemit partnership also in the works.</p>
<p>Per Bloomberg, the company’s monthly transaction volumes exceed $3 billion at the moment.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JnOh62rBsL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/african-fintech-opay-reportedly-raising-400m-at-a-1-5b-valuation/">African fintech OPay is reportedly raising $400M at over $1.5B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;African fintech OPay is reportedly raising $400M at over $1.5B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/african-fintech-opay-reportedly-raising-400m-at-a-1-5b-valuation/embed/#?secret=JnOh62rBsL" data-secret="JnOh62rBsL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Last year, OPay expanded to Egypt, and according to the company, that&#8217;s an entry point to the Middle East market.</p>
<p class="paywall">In a statement, Kentaro Matsui, a managing director at SoftBank Group Corp, said, “We believe our investment will help the company extend its offering to adjacent markets and replicate its successful business model in Egypt and other countries in the region.”</p>
<p>SoftBank joins a growing list of high-flying investors (Dragoneer, Sequoia and SVB Capital, among others) that have cut their first checks in African ventures this year. As the continent continues to show promise, fintech remains its poster child. This year up to half of the total investments raised have emerged from the sector; it contributed to more than 25% last year.</p>
<p>In addition, fintech has produced the most mega-rounds so far. TymeBank <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/south-african-digital-bank-tymebank-lands-109m-from-uk-and-phillippines-investors/">raised $109 million</a> in February, Flutterwave <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/african-payments-company-flutterwave-raises-170m-now-valued-at-over-1b/">bagged a $170 million</a> round in March and Chipper Cash <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/30/africa-has-another-unicorn-as-chipper-cash-raises-100m-series-c-led-by-svb-capital/">secured $100 million</a> in May.</p>
<p>OPay&#8217;s fundraise is the largest of the lot in terms of size and value, making it the second African fintech unicorn after Flutterwave and the third African unicorn after e-commerce giant Jumia. The three make up the five billion-dollar tech companies on the continent, which include Interswitch and Fawry.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/african-fintech-opay-valued-at-2b-in-softbank-vision-fund-2-led-400m-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2192538</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
