<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 20:55:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Deliveroo could leave Spanish market ahead of on-demand labor reclassification</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/deliveroo-could-leave-spanish-market-ahead-of-on-demand-labor-reclassification/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/deliveroo-could-leave-spanish-market-ahead-of-on-demand-labor-reclassification/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 20:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deliveroo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Just-Eat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber Eats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184120</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Deliveroo said it is considering leaving the Spanish market, citing limited market share and a long road of investment with 'highly uncertain long-term potential returns' on the horizon.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Deliveroo <a href="https://www.investegate.co.uk/deliveroo-plc--roo-/rns/proposal-to-end-operations-in-spain/202107300908580582H/">announced today</a> that it is considering leaving the Spanish market, citing limited market share and a long road of investment with &#8220;highly uncertain long-term potential returns&#8221; on the horizon.</p>
<p>The company, an on-demand outfit based in the U.K., <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/deliveroo-prices-its-shares-on-the-lse-at-3-90-at-the-lower-end-of-the-range-with-a-market-cap-of-7-59b/">went public earlier in 2021</a>. Its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/what-to-make-of-deliveroos-rough-ipo-debut/">shares initially sagged</a>, drawing concern about both the value of on-demand companies and tech concerns listing in London more broadly. However, shares of Deliveroo have since recovered, and the company&#8217;s <a href="https://dpd-12774-s3.s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/assets/8316/2574/2996/Deliveroo_PLC_update_Q2_2021.pdf">second-quarter earnings report</a> saw it raise its expected gross order volume growth expectations &#8220;from between 30% to 40% to between 50% to 60%.&#8221;</p>
<p>Given its rising growth expectations and improving public-market valuation, you may be surprised that Deliveroo is willing to leave any of the 12 markets in which it currently operates. In the case of Spain, it appears that Deliveroo is concerned that changes to local labor laws will make its operations more expensive in the country, which, given its modest market share, is not palatable.</p>
<p>Recall that <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/spain-adopts-landmark-law-protect-gig-delivery-workers-77620461">Spain adopted a law</a> in May &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/spain-agrees-on-labor-reform-that-will-recognize-delivery-platform-riders-as-employees/">a law generally agreed to in March</a> &#8212; requiring on-demand companies to hire their couriers. This is the sort of arrangement that on-demand companies in food delivery and ride-hailing have long fought; many on-demand companies are unprofitable <em>without</em> hiring couriers, and doing so could raise their costs. The possibility of worsened economics makes such changes to labor laws in any market a worry for startups and public companies alike that lean on freelance delivery workers.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s parse the Deliveroo statement to better understand the company&#8217;s perspective. Here&#8217;s the introductory paragraph:</p>
<blockquote><p>Deliveroo today announces that it proposes to consult on ending its operations in Spain. Deliveroo currently operates across 12 markets worldwide, with the vast majority of the Company&#8217;s gross transaction value (GTV) coming from markets where Deliveroo holds a #1 or #2 market position.</p></blockquote>
<p>Translation: We&#8217;re probably leaving Spain. Most of our order volume comes from markets where we are in a leading position (the company competes with Uber Eats, Glovo and Just Eat in different markets). We are not in a leading position in Spain.</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="ad"><span class="r">Spain represents less than 2% of Deliveroo&#8217;s GTV in H1 2021. The Company has determined that achieving and sustaining a top-tier market position in Spain would require a disproportionate level of investment with highly uncertain long-term potential returns that could impact the economic viability of the market for the Company. </span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Translation: Spain is a very small market for Deliveroo. To gain lots of market share in Spain would be very costly, and the company isn&#8217;t sure about the long-term profitability of the country&#8217;s business. This is where labor issues like this come into play &#8212; investing to gain market share in a country where your business is less profitable is hard to pencil out.</p>
<p>And <a href="https://elpais.com/economia/2021-07-30/deliveroo-se-propone-cerrar-su-division-espanola.html">according to El Pais</a>, the decision by Deliveroo comes as it was up against a deadline regarding worker reclassification. That may have contributed to the timing of the announcement.</p>
<p>From this juncture, Deliveroo spends three paragraphs discussing how it will support workers in case it does leave the Spanish market. It closes with the following:</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="ae"><span class="o">This proposal does not impact previously communicated full-year guidance on Group annual GTV growth and gross profit margin.</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fair enough.</p>
<p>On-demand companies have made arguments over the years that changes to labor laws that would push more costs onto their plates in the form of hiring couriers &#8212; or simply paying them more &#8212; would make certain markets uneconomic and drive them away. Here, Deliveroo can follow through with an exit at essentially no cost, given how small its order volume is compared to its other 11 markets.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/deliveroo-could-leave-spanish-market-ahead-of-on-demand-labor-reclassification/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184120</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>For tech firms, the risk of not preparing for leadership changes is huge</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/for-tech-firms-the-risk-of-not-preparing-for-leadership-changes-is-huge/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/for-tech-firms-the-risk-of-not-preparing-for-leadership-changes-is-huge/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 20:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resource management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership tactics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satya Nadella]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tim Cook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184018</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A change of command is one of the most delicate moments in the life cycle of any organization. If mishandled, the transition from one CEO to the next can result in massive downsides.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jason Dressel</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/historyfactory">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jason Dressel is president of<a href="https://www.historyfactory.com/"> History Factory</a>, which helps companies use their history and heritage to enhance and transform strategy, positioning, marketing and communication.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Every week over the past three and a half years, an average of three CEOs have exited tech companies in the U.S. That tally is higher — in good times and bad — than in any of the other 26 for-profit sectors tracked by executive search firm <a href="https://www.challengergray.com/blog/ceo-turnover-cools-in-may-falling-26-from-april/">Challenger, Gray &amp; Christmas</a>. You&#8217;d think tech companies should be the paradigm of how to prep for leadership transitions, since they operate in such a constant state of flux.</p>
<p>They’re far from it.</p>
<p>A change of command is one of the most delicate moments in the life cycle of any organization. If mishandled, the transition from one CEO to the next can result in a loss of market valuation, momentum and focus, as well as key personnel, customers and partners. It may even become that turning point when an organization begins to slide toward irrelevance.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>With so much at stake, 84% of tech execs agree that succession planning is more important than ever because of today’s fast-changing business environment, according to <a href="https://www.historyfactory.com/the-succession-trap/">our new survey</a> of corporate America’s leaders. Seven out of 10 survey respondents agreed that tech companies face more scrutiny than other multinationals during a transition.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			84% of tech execs agree that succession planning is more important than ever because of today’s fast-changing business environment.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Yet we found that tech execs appear just as unprepared for C-suite transitions as their peers in other sectors. Three out of five respondents said their companies don’t have a documented plan to handle a leadership change, even though, by that same ratio, they acknowledge that a documented plan is the biggest determinant in seamless transitions.</p>
<p>The findings may not be troubling if these respondents were millennial startup founders, years from leaving their companies. The executives we polled, however, hail from 160 companies that have been in business for a minimum of 15 years — 35 are tech companies, the largest industry cohort in the survey.</p>
<p>The smallest companies have at least 1,500 employees and $500 million in annual revenue, while the largest have head counts of over 500,000 and revenue upward of $100 billion. They have been around long enough to understand — and put into place — risk management and crisis planning, including what happens should their leaders fall victim to the proverbial milk truck.</p>
<p>Tech execs should be more rigorous about succession planning for one important reason: institutional memory. Tech firms generally are younger than other companies of a similar size, which partly explains why the median age of S&amp;P 500 companies plunged to 33 years in 2018 from 85 years in 2000, according to <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/Industries/Electric%20Power%20and%20Natural%20Gas/Our%20Insights/Traditional%20company%20new%20businesses%20The%20pairing%20that%20can%20ensure%20an%20incumbents%20survival/Traditional-company-new-businesses-VF.ashx">McKinsey &amp; Co</a>.</p>
<p>These enterprises clearly have accomplished a lot in their short lives, but in their haste, most have not captured their history, unlike their longer-lived peers in other sectors. Less than half of these tech firms, in fact, have formally recorded their leader’s story for posterity. That puts them at a disadvantage when, inevitably, they will be required to onboard newcomers to their C-suites.</p>
<p>It’s best to record this history well before the intense swirl of a leadership transition begins. Crucially, it will help the incoming and future generations of leadership understand critical aspects of its track record, the lessons learned, culture and identity. It also explains why the organization has evolved as it has, what binds people together and what may trigger resistance based on previous experience. It’s as much about moving forward as looking back.</p>
<p>Most execs in our poll get it, with 85% saying a company’s history can be a playbook for new executives to learn and prepare for upcoming challenges and opportunities. “History is the mother of innovation for any type of company,” one respondent said. “History,&#8221; writes another, “includes the roadmap to failures as well as successes.”</p>
<p>But this documented history cannot be a hagiography of the departing CEO. Too often, outgoing execs spend their last years in office constructing their own trophy cases. Even as they conceded their own flat-footedness on transition planning, the majority of execs said they have already taken steps to create and reinforce their personal legacies — two-thirds said they have already completed their own formal legacy planning, many with the blessing of their boards.</p>
<p>It’s ironic, then, that three out of five also said that the legacy of a CEO or founder often overshadows the skill set and experience a successor brings. Two-thirds of tech execs believed that the longer a leader has been in office, the more it complicates a transition.</p>
<p>Tech leaders can do this right and have done so. Asked which five big-name CEO transitions was most successful, respondents’ No. 1 was <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2021-02-09/this-is-how-tim-cook-transformed-apple-aapl-after-steve-jobs?sref=MSHtM8dd">Apple’s handoff</a> from Steve Jobs to Tim Cook (38%), followed by Microsoft’s page-turn from Steve Ballmer to Satya Nadella (28%). The others, at General Electric, General Motors and Goldman Sachs, each netted no more than 13% of votes.</p>
<p>Apple&#8217;s apparent predominance in this survey might contradict the advice to play down the aggrandizement of an exiting CEO and highlight the compilation and transfer of an organization’s history to the next chief executive. Jobs, after all, painstakingly managed his legacy until the end. But even as he continued to take center-stage, he also made sure to pass along Apple’s institutional knowledge and ethos to Cook over the 13 years they shared space on Apple’s executive floor.</p>
<p>Sooner or later, everyone in the C-suite today — including startup founders — will depart. For the sake of everyone they’ll leave behind, they should begin prepping for that day now.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="r0pYmZuEwa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/why-i-make-everyone-in-my-company-be-the-ceo-for-a-day/">Why I make everyone in my company be the CEO for a day</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why I make everyone in my company be the CEO for a day&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/why-i-make-everyone-in-my-company-be-the-ceo-for-a-day/embed/#?secret=r0pYmZuEwa" data-secret="r0pYmZuEwa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/for-tech-firms-the-risk-of-not-preparing-for-leadership-changes-is-huge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184018</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Extra Crunch roundup: Livestream e-commerce, growth marketing interviews, CEO for a day</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/extra-crunch-roundup-livestream-e-commerce-growth-marketing-interviews-ceo-for-a-day/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/extra-crunch-roundup-livestream-e-commerce-growth-marketing-interviews-ceo-for-a-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 20:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[duolingo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184145</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thanks very much for reading Extra Crunch this week; have a great weekend.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This year, livestream viewers in China are projected to spend more than $60 billion on digital shopping experiences that let them interact with influencers in real time.</p>
<p>Promoting everything from cosmetics to food, social media stars use Taobao, TikTok and other platforms to livestream products and take questions from the audience.</p>
<p>On Taobao&#8217;s Single’s Day Global Shopping Festival in 2020, livestreams racked up $6 billion in sales, twice as much revenue as the year prior.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Sensing a trend, Western startups are getting in on the action, with companies like Whatnot and PopShop.Live raising rounds to build out their infrastructure. Looking forward, Alanna Gregory, senior global director at Afterpay, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/livestream-e-commerce-why-companies-and-brands-need-to-tune-in/">says she foresees four major trends</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Networks</li>
<li>SaaS streaming tools</li>
<li>Host discovery and outreach tools</li>
<li>Host marketplaces and agencies</li>
</ul>
<p>&#8220;For brands, SaaS streaming tools will be the most impactful way to take advantage of livestream commerce trends,&#8221; Gregory writes in an Extra Crunch guest post. &#8220;All of this will be incredibly transformative.&#8221;</p>
<hr />
<p>To help entrepreneurs take on the most fundamental challenge facing early-stage startups, our team is speaking to growth marketers to learn more about the advice they&#8217;re offering clients these days.</p>
<p>This week, Miranda Halpern and Anna Heim interviewed experts on growth marketing:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/the-mkt1-interview-growth-marketing-in-2021-hiring-versus-outsourcing-and-more/">The MKT1 interview: Growth marketing in 2021, hiring versus outsourcing and more</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/unmuted-founder-max-van-den-ingh-on-success-beyond-the-metrics/">Unmuted founder Max van den Ingh on success beyond the metrics</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/draft-dev-ceo-karl-hughes-on-the-importance-of-using-experts-in-developer-marketing/">Draft.dev CEO Karl Hughes on the importance of using experts in developer marketing</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Growth is an existential issue, so these stories are free to read and share. If you&#8217;ve worked with an individual or an agency who helped your startup find and keep new users,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/help-techcrunch-find-the-best-growth-marketers-for-startups/"> please let us know</a>.</p>
<p>Thanks very much for reading Extra Crunch this week; have a great weekend.</p>
<p>Walter Thompson</p>
<p>Senior Editor, TechCrunch</p>
<p><a href="https://www.twitter.com/yourprotagonist">@yourprotagonist</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Iqk824tp45"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/livestream-e-commerce-why-companies-and-brands-need-to-tune-in/">Livestream e-commerce: Why companies and brands need to tune in</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Livestream e-commerce: Why companies and brands need to tune in&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/livestream-e-commerce-why-companies-and-brands-need-to-tune-in/embed/#?secret=Iqk824tp45" data-secret="Iqk824tp45" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Why Latin American venture capital is breaking records this year</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996006" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996006" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996006" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996006" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Alex Wilhelm and Anna Heim’s global exploration of Q2 venture capital data wrapped up this week with an in-depth look at Latin America.</p>
<p>One investor told them that today’s LatAm startup market “is a story about talent, not about capital.”</p>
<p>“The union of talent and money is what startup markets need to thrive,” they write. “But there are other reasons why Latin American startups are so frequently in the news today, including structural factors, such as strong digital penetration and quick e-commerce growth.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uTiYd3XywG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/why-latin-american-venture-capital-is-breaking-records-this-year/">Why Latin American venture capital is breaking records this year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why Latin American venture capital is breaking records this year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/why-latin-american-venture-capital-is-breaking-records-this-year/embed/#?secret=uTiYd3XywG" data-secret="uTiYd3XywG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Dear Sophie: Should we sponsor international hires for H-1B transfers and green cards?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2099516" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2099516" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2099516" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg" alt="lone figure at entrance to maze hedge that has an American flag at the center" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2099516" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin/TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Dear Sophie,</strong></p>
<p><strong>My startup is desperately recruiting, and we see a lot of engineering candidates on H-1Bs. </strong></p>
<p><strong>They’re looking for H-1B transfers and green cards. What should we do?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Baffled in the Bay Area</strong></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="F8Pp1LQbjg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/dear-sophie-should-we-sponsor-international-hires-for-h-1b-transfers-and-green-cards/">Dear Sophie: Should we sponsor international hires for H-1B transfers and green cards? </a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Dear Sophie: Should we sponsor international hires for H-1B transfers and green cards? &#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/dear-sophie-should-we-sponsor-international-hires-for-h-1b-transfers-and-green-cards/embed/#?secret=F8Pp1LQbjg" data-secret="F8Pp1LQbjg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Why I make everyone in my company be the CEO for a day</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2182504" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2182504" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2182504" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-889233-001.jpg" alt="Vincit runs a CEO of the Day program once a month" width="1024" height="764" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-889233-001.jpg 2005w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-889233-001.jpg?resize=150,112 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-889233-001.jpg?resize=300,224 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-889233-001.jpg?resize=768,573 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-889233-001.jpg?resize=680,507 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-889233-001.jpg?resize=1536,1145 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-889233-001.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2182504" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Blake+Little" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blake Little <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>In the reality TV series &#8220;Undercover Boss,&#8221; high-powered executives disguise themselves so they can work alongside everyday employees, ostensibly to learn from them.</p>
<p>Flipping that script, software company Vincit USA has a “CEO of the Day” program where staffers move into a metaphorical corner office for 24 hours and receive a very real unlimited budget. There&#8217;s just one requirement.</p>
<p>&#8220;The CEO must make one lasting decision that will help improve the working experience of Vincit employees,&#8221; said Ville Houttu, Vincit&#8217;s founder and CEO.</p>
<p>Since instituting the program, Vincit USA has received multiple awards for its workplace culture and sees reduced staff turnover.</p>
<p>&#8220;Though it may seem crazy, the initiative has paid off tenfold,&#8221; said Houttu.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wQMtBZdso7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/why-i-make-everyone-in-my-company-be-the-ceo-for-a-day/">Why I make everyone in my company be the CEO for a day</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why I make everyone in my company be the CEO for a day&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/why-i-make-everyone-in-my-company-be-the-ceo-for-a-day/embed/#?secret=wQMtBZdso7" data-secret="wQMtBZdso7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>What I’ve learned after 5 years of buying common stock in startups</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2182461" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2182461" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2182461" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-103000219.jpg" alt="Buying common stock can help align investor and founder incentives" width="1024" height="751" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-103000219.jpg 2022w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-103000219.jpg?resize=150,110 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-103000219.jpg?resize=300,220 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-103000219.jpg?resize=768,563 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-103000219.jpg?resize=680,498 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-103000219.jpg?resize=1536,1126 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-103000219.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2182461" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Tim+Robberts" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tim Robberts <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Instead of giving founders standard term sheets, Boston-based seed-stage venture capital firm Pillar VC offers to buy common stock.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are many terms and conditions in a preferred term sheet that can misalign investors and founders,&#8221; says founding partner Jamie Goldstein.</p>
<p>&#8220;As with any experiment, we have learned a few things that have surprised us and faced challenges we’ve had to overcome.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TkD2xxzu19"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/what-ive-learned-after-5-years-of-buying-common-stock-in-startups/">What I&#8217;ve learned after 5 years of buying common stock in startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What I&#8217;ve learned after 5 years of buying common stock in startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/what-ive-learned-after-5-years-of-buying-common-stock-in-startups/embed/#?secret=TkD2xxzu19" data-secret="TkD2xxzu19" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>China’s regulatory crackdown is good news for startups aligned with CCP goals</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996007" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996007" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996007" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996007" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Alex Wilhelm takes stock of the wall of news out of China over the past week to see if there’s a silver lining for startups in the country as the Chinese Communist Party cracks down on everything from edtech companies to streaming platforms.</p>
<p>His take?</p>
<p>“The result may be concentrated effort and capital in sectors that Beijing favors and reduced capital and focus from entrepreneurs in sectors that have been deemed fit for strict control,” he writes. “Simply: Central planning is going to tilt business more toward centrally planned goals.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="61Euw8STQJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/chinas-regulatory-crackdown-is-good-news-for-startups-aligned-with-ccp-goals/">China&#8217;s regulatory crackdown is good news for startups aligned with CCP goals</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;China&#8217;s regulatory crackdown is good news for startups aligned with CCP goals&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/chinas-regulatory-crackdown-is-good-news-for-startups-aligned-with-ccp-goals/embed/#?secret=61Euw8STQJ" data-secret="61Euw8STQJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Duolingo’s IPO pricing is great news for edtech startups</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2146337" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2146337" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2146337" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="686" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg?resize=300,201 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg?resize=768,515 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg?resize=680,456 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg?resize=1536,1029 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg?resize=2048,1372 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2146337" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>The Pittsburgh-based language-learning unicorn initially aimed for an $85 to $95 per share IPO price range, then bumped that up to $95 to $100 before it began to trade. It ultimately entered the public markets at $102 per share.</p>
<p>Alex Wilhelm notes that based on Duolingo’s expected Q2 revenues, the company has a run-rate multiple of nearly 16x. Compare that to the median multiple for public SaaS companies of 14x.</p>
<p>“Duolingo, a <em>consumer edtech company,</em> is now more valuable per revenue dollar than the median public enterprise SaaS business,” Alex writes.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aZhQLcRD3j"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/duolingos-ipo-pricing-is-great-news-for-edtech-startups/">Duolingo&#8217;s IPO pricing is great news for edtech startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Duolingo&#8217;s IPO pricing is great news for edtech startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/duolingos-ipo-pricing-is-great-news-for-edtech-startups/embed/#?secret=aZhQLcRD3j" data-secret="aZhQLcRD3j" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Financial firms should leverage machine learning to make anomaly detection easier</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2182155" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2182155" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2182155" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg" alt="Machine learning can make anolmaly detection easier" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg 2309w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2182155" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=GOCMEN" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GOCMEN <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>“Anomaly detection is one of the more difficult and underserved operational areas in the asset-servicing sector of financial institutions,” EZOPS CEO Bikram Singh writes in a guest column.</p>
<p>But it’s critical to detect these anomalies amid a sea of data. That’s where unsupervised learning can offer a solution.</p>
<p>​​”With all eyes on data, it’s crucial that financial institutions find solutions to detect anomalies upfront, thereby preventing bad data from infecting downstream processes,” Singh writes.</p>
<p>“Machine learning can be applied to detect the data anomalies as well as identify the reasons for them, effectively reducing the time spent researching and rectifying executions.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RfhvjtgA4y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/financial-firms-should-leverage-machine-learning-to-make-anomaly-detection-easier/">Financial firms should leverage machine learning to make anomaly detection easier</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Financial firms should leverage machine learning to make anomaly detection easier&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/financial-firms-should-leverage-machine-learning-to-make-anomaly-detection-easier/embed/#?secret=RfhvjtgA4y" data-secret="RfhvjtgA4y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>African startups join global funding boom as fintech shines</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996008" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996008" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996008" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996008" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Alex Wilhelm and Anna Heim continued their global tour of Q2 2021 venture capital data, this week focusing on Africa.</p>
<p>“Early data indicates that Africa is set to trounce historical records in terms of venture capital raised in the year and that the first half of 2021 saw roughly twice the funds raised by African startups as was recorded in the first half of 2020,” they write.</p>
<p>“Startups across Africa have never had more access to capital than they do right now.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PK5lu75PEt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/african-startups-join-global-funding-boom-as-fintech-shines/">African startups join global funding boom as fintech shines</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;African startups join global funding boom as fintech shines&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/african-startups-join-global-funding-boom-as-fintech-shines/embed/#?secret=PK5lu75PEt" data-secret="PK5lu75PEt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>True ‘shift left and extend right’ security requires empowered developers</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2183611" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2183611" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2183611" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg" alt="Empowered developers will change the nature of true shift left and extend right security" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg 2121w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2183611" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=kuritafsheen" target="_blank" rel="noopener">kuritafsheen <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>The intention of DevSecOps is to wedge security and compliance into DevOps. But that’s easier said than done, says Apiiro founder and CEO Idan Plotnik.</p>
<p>“Shifting left and extending right doesn’t mean that a scanning tool or security architect should detect a security risk earlier in the process — it means that a developer should have all the context to prevent the vulnerability before it even happens,” he writes.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uafTMAYn04"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/true-shift-left-and-extend-right-security-requires-empowered-developers/">True &#8216;shift left and extend right&#8217; security requires empowered developers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;True &#8216;shift left and extend right&#8217; security requires empowered developers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/true-shift-left-and-extend-right-security-requires-empowered-developers/embed/#?secret=uafTMAYn04" data-secret="uafTMAYn04" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>4 key areas SaaS startups must address to scale infrastructure for the enterprise</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2183726" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2183726" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2183726" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-83597636.jpg" alt="bonsai tree with miniature scaffolding" width="1024" height="809" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-83597636.jpg 1948w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-83597636.jpg?resize=150,119 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-83597636.jpg?resize=300,237 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-83597636.jpg?resize=768,607 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-83597636.jpg?resize=680,537 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-83597636.jpg?resize=1536,1214 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-83597636.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2183726" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Stewart+Sutton" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stewart Sutton <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Asana’s head of engineering, Prashant Pandey, rounds up four tips for SaaS startups looking to build up their infrastructure to meet customers&#8217; growing needs.</p>
<p>“Startups and SMBs are usually the first to adopt many SaaS products. But as these customers grow in size and complexity — and as you rope in larger organizations — scaling your infrastructure for the enterprise becomes critical for success,” he writes.</p>
<p>He offers four areas to focus on:</p>
<ul>
<li>Address your customers’ security and reliability needs</li>
<li>Give IT admins control over product usage</li>
<li>Build data isolation into your architecture</li>
<li>Support customers by interconnecting their data across applications</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="e3FaxxPSRU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/4-key-areas-saas-startups-must-address-to-scale-infrastructure-for-the-enterprise/">4 key areas SaaS startups must address to scale infrastructure for the enterprise</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;4 key areas SaaS startups must address to scale infrastructure for the enterprise&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/4-key-areas-saas-startups-must-address-to-scale-infrastructure-for-the-enterprise/embed/#?secret=e3FaxxPSRU" data-secret="e3FaxxPSRU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/extra-crunch-roundup-livestream-e-commerce-growth-marketing-interviews-ceo-for-a-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184145</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kodiak Robotics&#8217; founder says tight focus on autonomous trucks is working</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/kodiak-robotics-founder-says-tight-focus-on-autonomous-trucks-is-working/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/kodiak-robotics-founder-says-tight-focus-on-autonomous-trucks-is-working/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 20:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ADAS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Don Burnette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kodiak Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving truck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2181810</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["We will need to raise more money, as you pointed out, that's certainly no secret, but I think that we have multiple options to do that."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Kodiak Robotics is one of the last private autonomous vehicles companies focused on trucking that is still standing. Nearly all the rest have been wooed by the public marketplace and the capital it can provide. But co-founder and CEO Don Burnette says the three-year-old company&#8217;s strategy of staying focused and small(er) is paying off.</p>
<p>It will be able to deploy a commercial-scale operation for about $500 million in funding, he says in the interview below. To put those go-to-market costs in perspective, that&#8217;s 10% of what Waymo has raised in external fundraising and less than 25% of newly publicly traded company TuSimple&#8217;s total fundraise.</p>
<p>Kodiak&#8217;s strategy is to take a specialized, hyperfocused approach to autonomous trucking that outsources a lot of tech, like data labeling, lidar, radar and mapping, to existing companies. Burnette, who was one of four founders of the self-driving truck startup Otto that Uber acquired, thinks this is a faster, cheaper and more efficient path to commercialization versus building out your own systems and teams.</p>
<p>The company is moving freight for commercial customers, dipping its toes in the market by working with technology partners within the existing ecosystem. Burnette says Kodiak&#8217;s Driver technology has achieved a level of maturity where it can handle anything the highway throws at it. In December, the startup achieved “disengagement-free deliveries” between Dallas and Houston, meaning the autonomous system didn’t have to be switched off for safety reasons.</p>
<p><em>The following interview, part of an ongoing series with founders who are building transportation companies, has been edited for length and clarity. </em></p>
<p><strong>You previously told me that Kodiak would need about $500 million in total funding to get to commercial driverless. You also said you’ve had some undisclosed funding rounds, but publicly, you’ve only raised $40 million. Can you still execute on your vision this far off?</strong></p>
<p>Absolutely. We are always, as startups are, in fundraising mode. We&#8217;re always talking to investors. And there&#8217;s a lot of great things happening behind the scenes currently that we haven&#8217;t yet announced. We are growing, we&#8217;re hiring, if you can look to that as an indicator of the health of a company.</p>
<p>Our tech and our plan is really sound, and we are building up our commercialization efforts in a way that I think is going to be very exciting to the overall industry and to the market. We will need to raise more money, as you pointed out, that&#8217;s certainly no secret, but I think that we have multiple options to do that.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			&#8220;Kodiak is one of the only remaining serious AV trucking companies still in the private sector, and so I think that gives us some advantages in a lot of ways.&#8221;					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p><strong>How do you intend to close that gap? Are you looking at venture capital, or maybe going for an IPO or SPAC?</strong></p>
<p>We&#8217;re considering all of the above. It&#8217;s a constant conversation internally on what is the best path for Kodiak, what is the appetite of the various forms of investors and strategic relationships. Nothing is excluded.</p>
<p>The stock market is obviously very attractive and exciting. I think TuSimple has demonstrated that an IPO with the right set of metrics and the right set of momentum and partners is possible and can be successful. I think there&#8217;s also lots of opportunity within the VCs and the private markets. Kodiak is one of the only remaining serious AV trucking companies still in the private sector, and so I think that gives us some advantages in a lot of ways.</p>
<p><strong>What&#8217;s your sense of the venture funding environment right now in autonomous? Is it harder now than it was, say, four years ago?</strong></p>
<p>The appetite has changed. In particular, investors are more skeptical of timelines and promises. There is not this sense of Wild West excitement like there was four or five years ago, and that was the Golden Age of raising capital, certainly for earlier stage companies.</p>
<p>Kodiak was at the tail end of that age, and now the goalposts have changed, and the target investors have changed. It&#8217;s no longer the early-stage VCs that companies like Kodiak and others are talking to. It&#8217;s more of the growth-stage funds, and growth-stage funds look for different types of metrics. They look for commercial traction, product-market fit, users, efficiencies, etc.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/kodiak-robotics-founder-says-tight-focus-on-autonomous-trucks-is-working/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2181810</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Growth roundup: Investing in community, targeting developers, new marketer recs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/growth-roundup-investing-in-community-targeting-developers-new-marketer-recs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/growth-roundup-investing-in-community-targeting-developers-new-marketer-recs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Halpern]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 20:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183866</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;The best thing a startup can do, and I’m seeing it happen more and more, is investing in community early on,&#8221; growth marketing expert Max van den Ingh of Unmuted tells us. &#8220;When I was leading growth at MisterGreen, we created a community for the first thousand Tesla Model 3 owners in the Netherlands. Everyone [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">&#8220;The best thing a startup can do, and I’m seeing it happen more and more, is investing in community early on,&#8221; growth marketing expert Max van den Ingh of Unmuted tells us. &#8220;When I was leading growth at MisterGreen, we created a community for the first thousand Tesla Model 3 owners in the Netherlands. Everyone wanted to be a part of this founding tribe, learn from each other, get insights and so on.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;This group turned out to be our most effective marketing tool,&#8221; he explains in an interview we published this week. &#8220;Word-of-mouth went through the roof. We had all of these people talking about our community at birthday parties, in their office, you name it. This is a great example of investing in marketing you can’t really measure, but which you do strongly believe in.&#8221;</p>
<p>Elsewhere in this week’s growth marketing recap, you’ll find TechCrunch’s coverage of growth marketing, and related topics, from the past week. You’ll also find a few recommendations for growth marketers. If you’d like to recommend a great one you&#8217;ve worked with, please fill out our <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>Marketer: </strong><a href="https://scottgraham.io/">Scott Graham</a><br />
<strong>Recommended by: </strong>Heather Larrabee, CMO, <a href="https://www.form.com/">FORM</a><br />
<strong>Testimonial: </strong>“He was referred to us and blew our socks off from his initial analysis. He’s the rare growth adviser expert at strategy and execution. He’s a servant leader, a systems thinker, integrates with the team with empathy and curiosity like he’s an internal teammate, brings a wealth of cutting-edge knowledge, and a stable of incredible partners and resources. He runs with the best and the brightest, but he’s the first one on and the last one off for the day, putting in the time to make things great. He has an uncanny ability to communicate complex concepts and make them accessible for all audiences, and he’s been a foundational game changer for our business and many others.”</p>
<p><strong>Marketer: </strong><a href="https://ascendant.uk/">Ascendant </a><br />
<strong>Recommended by: </strong>Robyn Weatherley<strong>, </strong><a href="https://www.thirdfort.com/">Thirdfort Limited</a><br />
<strong>Testimonial: </strong>“Beyond their knowledge and experience (which is in abundance!), they have a deep understanding and appreciation for the unique challenges early-stage businesses have. They are in tune with the particular hurdles at various stages of growth and are able to adapt their working style dependent on those. They haven&#8217;t just helped us execute vital growth tactics, but they&#8217;ve helped us set up the framework to keep executing on those whether we are 5, 50 or 500 people. This is incredibly important as we scale and to demonstrate to future investors. They are also exceptional mentors and are able to offer real-world advice and work flexibly to suit the ever-changing nature of a high-growth early-stage business.”</p>
<p><strong>Marketer: </strong><a href="https://ferdinandgoetzen.com/">Ferdinand Goetzen</a><br />
<strong>Recommended by: </strong>Willem van Roosmalen, <a href="http://www.homerun.co">Homerun</a><br />
<strong>Testimonial: </strong>“Exceptional skills and experience in B2B SaaS, impressive track record, clear communicator, true leader, makes impact from day one, entrepreneur (actually launched his own start up, <a href="https://www.reveall.co/">Reveall</a>).”</p>
<p><strong>Marketer: </strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/adrianagrowth/">Adriana Ivascu</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/honeypotdigital/">HoneyPot Dgtl</a><br />
<strong>Recommended by: </strong>Mihaela Petre, <a href="https://www.beerproject.be/">Brussels Beer Project</a><br />
<strong>Testimonial: “</strong>Besides her solid experience in growth and digital, Adriana has a genuine interest in growing not only the company but its people. She is hands-on in digital transformation but on top of it, she is a coach who inspires and brings the best in teams. We are very happy to have benefited from a long-term strategic growth path and a skill playbook that we can pass on to our whole organization.”</p>
<p><strong>Marketer: </strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mariska-vroegindeweij/#">Mariska Vroegindeweij</a>, <a href="https://growthconfetti.nl/">Growth &amp; confetti</a><br />
<strong>Recommended by: </strong>Hugo Pereira, <a href="http://www.evbox.com">EVBox</a><br />
<strong>Testimonial: </strong>“[During our time working together] she was very young and bright. She started the Growth Marketing division on her own, built a team of developers, designers, advertisement specialists, product owners to drive conversion on the whole funnel from MQL to Opportunities. It&#8217;s hard to find a marketer that combines leadership skills with hardcore skills to drive growth. She was also very data-driven, challenged me a lot on assumptions and proved me wrong a few times by doing experiments and showcasing better ways to convert. And she was bold enough to start her own agency at a young age and doing well. Plus, she&#8217;s tons of fun.”</p>
<blockquote><p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Help TechCrunch find the best growth marketers for startups. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">this quick survey</a> and we&#8217;ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/the-mkt1-interview-growth-marketing-in-2021-hiring-versus-outsourcing-and-more/">The MKT1 interview: Growth marketing in 2021, hiring versus outsourcing and more</a>: We hosted a Twitter Spaces with strategic marketing firm MKT1 recently, following a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/mkt1-developer-marketing-is-what-startup-marketing-should-look-like/">popular interview</a> we published with them a few weeks ago. “The skill sets of growth marketers are in high demand,&#8221; co-founder Kathleen Estreich told host Danny Crichton during the event. &#8220;They always have been, but it feels pretty acute right now. Given that a lot of the companies are raising money earlier and starting to try and build that traction faster to grow into the valuations, we’re starting to see a huge need.” If you’re curious to see what skills are needed in growth marketing positions right now, take a look at the <a href="https://pallet.xyz/list/mkt1-jobs/jobs">job board</a> curated by MKT1.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/draft-dev-ceo-karl-hughes-on-the-importance-of-using-experts-in-developer-marketing/">Draft.dev CEO Karl Hughes on the importance of using experts in developer marketing</a>: Anna Heim interviewed Karl Hughes, founder of Daft.dev, which works with a large number of developer tool companies. Hughes&#8217; insights come from personal experience, “I’ve been a software developer, and then most recently was a CTO at a startup in Chicago, so I knew that there were lots of companies trying to reach developers [ … ] and that a lot of them were doing a poor job of it.” In this interview, Hughes addresses the mistakes made when targeting marketing toward developers, the steps that Draft.dev takes to mitigate them and more.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/unmuted-founder-max-van-den-ingh-on-success-beyond-the-metrics/">Unmuted founder Max van den Ingh on success beyond the metrics</a>: “At Unmuted, when we start working with a new client, we perform a series of exercises together,&#8221; he told us in the interview. &#8220;This helps us get a clear picture of where the client is now and where they could be when we’ve optimized marketing. Next, instead of fixed numbers, like a specific amount of new customers in a given period, we focus on growth levers, like month-over-month growth in certain conversion or activation areas. Focusing on growth levers makes our work more actionable.&#8221; Read the interview with him for more about Unmuted’s “modern” marketing approach, setting realistic goals and trends seen in growth marketing during the pandemic.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/dan-olsen-leads-a-product-market-fit-masterclass-for-the-startup-alley-cohort/">Dan Olsen leads a product-market fit masterclass for the Startup Alley+ cohort</a>: As part of Startup Alley+, TC Disrupt 2021 is offering a VIP experience where Dan Olsen will be holding a product-market fit masterclass. Olsen’s roster of clients includes Google, Facebook and Amazon.</p>
<p>Is there a startup growth marketing expert that you want us to know about? Let us know by filling out our <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/growth-roundup-investing-in-community-targeting-developers-new-marketer-recs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183866</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yat thinks emoji &#8216;identities&#8217; can be a thing, and it has $20M in sales to back it up</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/yat-thinks-emoji-identities-can-be-a-thing-and-it-has-20m-in-sales-to-back-it-up/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/yat-thinks-emoji-identities-can-be-a-thing-and-it-has-20m-in-sales-to-back-it-up/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 19:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emoji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ION]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysql]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[naveen jain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online identity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OpenSea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183855</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I learned about Yat in April, when a friend sent our group chat a link to a story about how the key emoji sold as an &#8220;internet identity&#8221; for $425,000. &#8220;I hate the universe,&#8221; she texted. Sure, the universe would be better if people with a spare $425,000 spent it on mutual aid or something, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">I learned about <a href="https://y.at/">Yat</a> in April, when a friend sent our group chat a link to a story about how <a href="https://thedefiant.io/emoji-based-username-project-yat-wants-to-become-universal-internet-identity-system/">the key emoji sold as an &#8220;internet identity&#8221; for $425,000</a>. &#8220;I hate the universe,&#8221; she texted.</p>
<p>Sure, the universe would be better if people with a spare $425,000 spent it on mutual aid or something, but minutes later, we were trying to figure out what this whole Yat thing was all about. And few more minutes later, I spent $5 (in U.S. dollars, not crypto) to buy <a href="https://y.at/%E2%98%95%F0%9F%91%89%F0%9F%92%A9%E2%9D%97"><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2615.png" alt="☕" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f449.png" alt="👉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4a9.png" alt="💩" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2757.png" alt="❗" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></a>, an emoji string that I think tells a moving story about my caffeine dependency and sensitive stomach. I didn&#8217;t think I would be writing about this when I made that choice.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184099" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184099" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2184099" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_7485.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="360" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_7485.jpg 750w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_7485.jpg?resize=150,79 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_7485.jpg?resize=300,159 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_7485.jpg?resize=680,360 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_7485.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184099" class="wp-caption-text">Kesha&#8217;s Yat URL on Twitter</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>On the surface, Yat is a platform that lets you buy a URL with emojis in it &#8212; even <a href="https://twitter.com/KeshaRose">Kesha</a> (y.at/<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f308.png" alt="🌈" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f680.png" alt="🚀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f47d.png" alt="👽" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />), <a href="https://twitter.com/LilTunechi">Lil Wayne</a> (y.at/<a class="css-4rbku5 css-18t94o4 css-901oao css-16my406 r-xfsgu1 r-1loqt21 r-4qtqp9 r-poiln3 r-1b7u577 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0" dir="ltr" role="link" href="https://t.co/hJ2L5cP0li?amp=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f47d.png" alt="👽" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f3b5.png" alt="🎵" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></a>), and <a href="https://twitter.com/disclosure">Disclosure</a> (y.at/<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f60e.png" alt="😎" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f3b5.png" alt="🎵" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f60e.png" alt="😎" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />) are using them in their Twitter bios. Like any URL on the internet, Yats can redirect to another website, or they can function like a more <a href="https://y.at/%F0%9F%8C%88%F0%9F%9A%80%F0%9F%91%BD">eye-catching Linktree</a>. While users could purchase their own domain name that supports emojis and use it instead of a Yat, many people don&#8217;t have the technical expertise or time to do so. Instead, they can make a one-time purchase from Yat, which owns the Y.at domain, and the company will provide you with your own y.at link for you.</p>
<p>This convenience, however, comes at a premium. Yat uses an algorithm to determine your Yat&#8217;s &#8220;rhythm score,&#8221; its metric for determining how to price your emoji combo based on its rarity. Yats with one or two emojis are so expensive that you have to contact the company directly to buy them, but you can easily find a four- or five-emoji identity that&#8217;ll only put you out $4.</p>
<p>Beyond that, CEO Naveen Jain &#8212; a Y Combinator alumnus, founder of digital marketing company Sparkart and angel investor &#8212; thinks that Yat is ultimately an internet privacy product. Jain wants people to be able to use their Yats in any way they&#8217;re able to use an online identity now, whether that&#8217;s to make payments, send messages, host a website or log in to a platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;Objectively, it&#8217;s a strange norm. You go on the internet, you register accounts with ad-supported platforms, and your username isn&#8217;t universal. You have many accounts, many usernames,&#8221; Jain said. &#8220;And you don&#8217;t control them. If an account wants to shut you down, they shut you down. How many stories are there of people trying to email some social network, and they don&#8217;t respond because they don&#8217;t have to?&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184101" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184101" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2184101" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Yat-4-copy.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="616" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Yat-4-copy.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Yat-4-copy.jpg?resize=150,136 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Yat-4-copy.jpg?resize=300,272 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Yat-4-copy.jpg?resize=768,696 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Yat-4-copy.jpg?resize=680,616 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Yat-4-copy.jpg?resize=1536,1392 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Yat-4-copy.jpg?resize=50,45 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184101" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://y.at" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Yat <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Yat doesn&#8217;t plan to fuel itself with ad money, since users pay for the product when they purchase their Yat, whether they get it for $4 or $400,000.</p>
<p>In the long run, Yat&#8217;s CEO says the company plans to use blockchain technology as a way to become self-sovereign. Yats would become assets issued on decentralized, distributed databases. Today, there are several projects working to create <a href="https://blog.nameshield.com/blog/2020/04/08/dns-on-blockchain-the-next-evolution-of-domain-names/">a decentralized alternative</a> to the current domain name system (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_Name_System">DNS</a>), which is managed by internet regulatory authority <a href="https://www.icann.org/">ICANN</a>.  DNS is how you find things on the internet, but uses a centralized, hierarchical system. A blockchain domain name system would have no central authority, and some believe this could be the foundation of a next-gen web, or &#8220;Web 3.0.&#8221;</p>
<p>Today, words like &#8220;blockchain&#8221; and &#8220;cryptocurrency&#8221; don&#8217;t appear on the Yat website. Jain doesn&#8217;t think that&#8217;s compelling to average consumers &#8212; he believes in progressive decentralization, which explains why Yats are currently purchased with dollars, not ethereum.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;Something we think is really funny about the cryptocurrency world is that anyone who&#8217;s a part of it spends a lot of time talking about databases,&#8221; Jain said. &#8220;People don&#8217;t care about databases. When&#8217;s the last time you went to a website and it said &#8216;powered by MySQL&#8217;?&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Y.at, however, was registered at a <a href="https://www.101domain.com/at.htm">traditional internet registrar</a>, not on the blockchain.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is laying the foundation &#8212; there are certain elements of the vision that are certainly more of a social contract than actual implementation at this point in time,&#8221; says Jain. &#8220;But this is the vision that we&#8217;ve set forth, and we&#8217;re working continuously towards that goal.&#8221;</p>
<p>Still, until Yat becomes more decentralized, it can&#8217;t yet give users the complete control it aspires to. At present, the <a href="https://y.at/terms">Terms &amp; Conditions</a> give Yat the authority to terminate or suspend users at its discretion, but the company claims it hasn&#8217;t yet booted anyone from the system.</p>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">As Yat becomes more decentralized, our terms and conditions won&#8217;t be important,&#8221; Jain said. &#8220;This is the nature of pursuing a progressive decentralization strategy.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>In its &#8220;generation zero&#8221; phase (an open beta), Yat claims to have sold almost $20 million worth of emoji identities. Now, as the waitlist to get a Yat ends, Yat is posting some rare emoji identities on <a href="https://opensea.io/">OpenSea</a>, the NFT marketplace that recently reached a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/nft-market-opensea-hits-1-5-billion-valuation/">valuation of $1.5 billion</a>.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184092" style="width: 526px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184092" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2184092" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?w=680" alt="" width="516" height="516" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png 720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 516px) 100vw, 516px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184092" class="wp-caption-text">A still image of a Yat visualizer creation</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;For the first time ever, we&#8217;re going to be auctioning some Yats on OpenSea, and we&#8217;re going to be launching minting of Yats on Ethereum,&#8221; Jain said. Before minting Yats as NFTs, users can create a digital art landscape for their Yats through a Visualizer. These features, as well as new emojis in the Yat emoji set, will launch this evening at a virtual event called <a href="https://yativerse.y.at/pages/yat-horizon">Yat Horizon</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">Yat Creators will now have more rights,&#8221; Jain said about the new ability to mint Yats as NFTs. &#8220;We are going to continue to pursue progressive decentralization until we achieve our ultimate goal: making Yat the best self-directed, self-sovereign identity system for all.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Consumers have a demonstrated interest in retaining greater privacy on the internet &#8212; data shows that in iOS 14.5, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/05/96-of-us-users-opt-out-of-app-tracking-in-ios-14-5-analytics-find/">96% of users</a> opted out of ad tracking. But the decentralization movement hasn&#8217;t yet been able to market its privacy advantages to the mainstream. Yat helps solve this problem because even if you don&#8217;t understand what blockchain means, you understand that having a personal string of emojis is pretty fun. But, before you spend $425,000 on a single-emoji username, keep in mind that Yat&#8217;s vision will only completely materialize with the advent of Web 3.0, and we don&#8217;t yet know when or if that will happen.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gfF0hDrq1d"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/building-customer-first-relationships-in-a-privacy-first-world-is-critical/">Building customer-first relationships in a privacy-first world is critical</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Building customer-first relationships in a privacy-first world is critical&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/building-customer-first-relationships-in-a-privacy-first-world-is-critical/embed/#?secret=gfF0hDrq1d" data-secret="gfF0hDrq1d" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/yat-thinks-emoji-identities-can-be-a-thing-and-it-has-20m-in-sales-to-back-it-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183855</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calendly CEO Tope Awotona is joining us at Disrupt 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/calendly-ceo-tope-awotona-is-joining-us-at-disrupt-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/calendly-ceo-tope-awotona-is-joining-us-at-disrupt-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 18:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brynn Putnam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chamath Palihapitiya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pete buttigieg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewart butterfield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tope Awotona]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184066</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Early Bird Tickets to Disrupt end today, Friday, July 30. Book your tickets now! ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It all seems so simple. Instead of the dreaded back-and-forth on email, what if there was a solution that helped two parties (or multiple parties) schedule a call or a hangout?</p>
<p>Calendly was born out of that question. Today, the company is worth more than $3 billion, according to reports, and has more than 10 million users. The growth of the product is insane, with more than 1,000% growth from last year.</p>
<p>But that kind of success doesn&#8217;t come without hard work and dedication.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>To hear more about the journey from bootstrapped to billions, Calendly founder and CEO Tope Awotona will <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?utm_medium=editorialpost&amp;utm_campaign=disrupt2021&amp;utm_content=topespeakerpost&amp;utm_source=tcwebsite&amp;promo=topespeakerpost&amp;display=TRUE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">join us at Disrupt this September</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?utm_medium=editorialpost&amp;utm_campaign=disrupt2021&amp;utm_content=topespeakerpost&amp;utm_source=tcwebsite&amp;promo=topespeakerpost&amp;display=TRUE" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient"><strong>P.S. Early Bird Tickets to Disrupt end today, Friday, July 30. Book your tickets now! </strong></span></a></p>
<p>Awotona put his entire life savings into Calendly and managed to bootstrap it for years before taking a $350 million funding round led by OpenView and Iconiq.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aFprKzAjzI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/how-atlantas-calendly-turned-a-scheduling-nightmare-into-a-3b-startup/">How Atlanta&#8217;s Calendly turned a scheduling nightmare into a $3B startup</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How Atlanta&#8217;s Calendly turned a scheduling nightmare into a $3B startup&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/how-atlantas-calendly-turned-a-scheduling-nightmare-into-a-3b-startup/embed/#?secret=aFprKzAjzI" data-secret="aFprKzAjzI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>We&#8217;ll chat with Awotona about the early days of Calendly, how he navigated the hypergrowth phase, what made him choose to finally take institutional funding, his thoughts on pricing and packaging, and much more.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MS2WQJVTdH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/08/bootstrapping-managing-product-led-growth-and-knowing-when-to-fundraise/">Bootstrapping, managing product-led growth and knowing when to fundraise</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bootstrapping, managing product-led growth and knowing when to fundraise&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/08/bootstrapping-managing-product-led-growth-and-knowing-when-to-fundraise/embed/#?secret=MS2WQJVTdH" data-secret="MS2WQJVTdH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Awotona joins an incredible roster of speakers, including Secretary of Transportation Pete Buttigieg, Mirror&#8217;s Brynn Putnam, Chamath Palihapitiya, Slack CEO Stewart Butterfield <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/#0affacde-e0ed-4a3c-abc4-988cb1c0eb3e" target="_blank" rel="noopener">and more</a>. Plus, Disrupt features the legendary Startup Battlefield competition, where startups from across the globe compete for $100,000 and eternal glory.</p>
<p>Disrupt’s virtual format provides plenty of opportunity for questions, so come prepared to ask the experts about the issues that keep you up at night.</p>
<p>One post can’t possibly contain all of Disrupt&#8217;s events. Don’t miss the epic Startup Battlefield competition, hundreds of early-stage startups exhibiting in the Startup Alley expo area, special breakout sessions — like the Pitch Deck Teardown — and so much more.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?utm_medium=editorialpost&amp;utm_campaign=disrupt2021&amp;utm_content=topespeakerpost&amp;utm_source=tcwebsite&amp;promo=topespeakerpost&amp;display=TRUE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> offers tons of opportunities. Don’t miss out on the first one — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?utm_medium=editorialpost&amp;utm_campaign=disrupt2021&amp;utm_content=topespeakerpost&amp;utm_source=tcwebsite&amp;promo=topespeakerpost&amp;display=TRUE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">buy your Disrupt pass</a> today, <strong>July 30, by 11:59 p.m. (PDT)</strong> for less than $100. It’s a sweet deal!</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at Disrupt 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-c8cece2948fb67f4dcb74c1c2da58b16"
			width="99%"
			height="1300"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/c8cece2948fb67f4dcb74c1c2da58b16"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-c8cece2948fb67f4dcb74c1c2da58b16')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-c8cece2948fb67f4dcb74c1c2da58b16'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/calendly-ceo-tope-awotona-is-joining-us-at-disrupt-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184066</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The best way to grow your tech career? Treat it like an app</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/the-best-way-to-grow-your-tech-career-treat-it-like-an-app/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/the-best-way-to-grow-your-tech-career-treat-it-like-an-app/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 18:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career building]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184053</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What happens after a developer or engineer lands that sweet gig? Are they able to harness their skills and grow in interesting and challenging new directions?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Raj Yavatkar</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/ryavatkar">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		As CTO, Raj Yavatkar is responsible for charting <a href="https://www.juniper.net">Juniper Networks</a>' technology strategy through the execution of the company’s innovations and products for intelligent self-driving networks, security, mobile edge cloud, network virtualization, packet-optical integration and hybrid cloud.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Software developers and engineers have rarely been in higher demand. Organizations’ need for technical talent is skyrocketing, but the supply is quite limited. As a result, software professionals have the luxury of being very choosy about where they work and usually command big salaries.</p>
<p>In 2020, the U.S. had nearly 1.5 million full-time developers, who earned a median salary of around $110,000, <a href="https://www.bls.gov/ooh/computer-and-information-technology/software-developers.htm">according to the Bureau of Labor Statistics</a>. Over the next 10 years, the federal agency estimates, developer jobs will grow by 22% to 316,000.</p>
<p>But what happens after a developer or engineer lands that sweet gig? Are they able to harness their skills and grow in interesting and challenging new directions? Do they understand what it takes to move up the ladder? Are they merely doing a job or cultivating a rewarding professional life?</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			To put it bluntly, many developers and engineers stink at managing their own careers.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>These are the kinds of questions that have gnawed at me throughout my 25 years in the tech industry. I’ve long noticed that, to put it bluntly, many developers and engineers stink at managing their own careers.</p>
<p>It’s simply not a priority for some. By nature, developers delight in solving complex technical challenges and working hard toward their company’s digital objectives. Care for their own careers may feel unattractively self-promotional or political — even though it’s in fact neither. Charting a career path may feel awkward or they just don’t know how to go about it.</p>
<p>Companies owe it to developers and engineers, and to themselves, to give these key people the tools to understand what it takes to be the best they can be. How else can developers and engineers be assured of continually great experiences while constantly expanding their contributions to their organizations?</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Developers delight in solving complex challenges and working hard toward their company’s objectives. Care for their own careers may feel unattractively self-promotional or political — even though it’s in fact neither.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Coaching and mentoring can help, but I think a more formal management system is necessary to get the wind behind the sails of a companywide commitment to making developers and engineers believe that, as the late <a href="https://newsroom.intel.com/news-releases/andrew-s-grove-1936-2016/#gs.4o6920">Andy Grove</a> said, “Your career is your business and you are its CEO.”</p>
<p>That’s why I created a career development model for developers and engineers when I was an Intel Fellow at Intel between 2003 and 2013. This framework has since been put into practice at the three subsequent companies I worked at — Google, VMWare, and, now, Juniper Networks — through training sessions and HR processes.</p>
<p>The model is based on a principle that every developer can relate to: Treat career advancement as you would a software project.</p>
<p>That’s right, by thinking of career development in stages like those used in app production, developers and engineers can gain a holistic view of where they are in their professional lives, where they want to go and the gaps they need to fill.</p>
<h2>Step 1: Functional specification</h2>
<p>In software development, a team can’t get started until it has a functional specification that describes the app’s requirements and how it is supposed to perform and behave.</p>
<p>Why should a career be any different? In my model, folks begin by assessing the “functionality” expected of someone at their next career level and how they’re demonstrating them (or not). Typically, a person gets promoted to a higher level only when they already demonstrate that they are operating at that level.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/the-best-way-to-grow-your-tech-career-treat-it-like-an-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184053</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Tesla Megapack caught fire at the Victorian Big Battery facility in Australia</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/a-tesla-megapack-caught-fire-at-the-victorian-big-battery-facility-in-australia/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/a-tesla-megapack-caught-fire-at-the-victorian-big-battery-facility-in-australia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 18:27:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A 13-tonne Tesla Megapack caught fire on Friday morning at a battery storage facility in south-east Australia. The blaze occurred during testing at 10 - 10.15am local time.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Saqib Shah</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Saqib Shah is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/facebooks-next-product-will-be-its-long-awaited-ray-ban-smart-glasses/">Facebook&#8217;s next product will be its long-awaited Ray-Ban smart glasses</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/a-magnetic-helmet-shrunk-a-deadly-tumor-in-world-first-test/">A magnetic helmet shrunk a deadly tumor in its first test</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">A 13-tonne Tesla Megapack caught fire on Friday morning at a battery storage facility in south-east Australia. The blaze occurred during testing at between 10 and 10.15am local time, according to <a href="https://victorianbigbattery.com.au/incident-at-vbb/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1">Victorian Big Battery</a>. The regional fire service said a specialist fire crew had been dispatched to the site in Geelong, Victoria. Firefighters were using a hazmat appliance designed for hazardous chemical spills and specialist drones to conduct atmospheric monitoring, according to <a href="https://www.frv.vic.gov.au/large-battery-fire-moorabool" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="22" data-v9y="1">Fire Rescue Victoria</a>.</p>
<div id="ea61acd14c144908bb20a04bf2011764">
<div class="twitter-tweet twitter-tweet-rendered"><iframe id="twitter-widget-0" class="" title="Twitter Tweet" src="https://platform.twitter.com/embed/Tweet.html?creatorScreenName=eightiethmnt&amp;dnt=false&amp;embedId=twitter-widget-0&amp;features=eyJ0ZndfZXhwZXJpbWVudHNfY29va2llX2V4cGlyYXRpb24iOnsiYnVja2V0IjoxMjA5NjAwLCJ2ZXJzaW9uIjpudWxsfSwidGZ3X2hvcml6b25fdHdlZXRfZW1iZWRfOTU1NSI6eyJidWNrZXQiOiJodGUiLCJ2ZXJzaW9uIjpudWxsfSwidGZ3X3NwYWNlX2NhcmQiOnsiYnVja2V0Ijoib2ZmIiwidmVyc2lvbiI6bnVsbH19&amp;frame=false&amp;hideCard=false&amp;hideThread=false&amp;id=1420932114296446987&amp;lang=en&amp;origin=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.engadget.com%2Ftesla-megapack-fire-victorian-big-battery-105535797.html&amp;sessionId=49a08df5c3f97a44ae97c635120eec36ef083ef2&amp;siteScreenName=%60Engadget%60&amp;theme=light&amp;widgetsVersion=e9dfb5f%3A1627539779275&amp;width=550px" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" data-tweet-id="1420932114296446987" data-mce-fragment="1"></iframe></div>
</div>
<p>The site was evacuated and there were no injuries, Victorian Big Battery said in a statement. It added that the site had been disconnected from the power grid and that there will be no impact to the electric supply. French energy company Neoen, which operates the facility, and contractor Tesla are working with emergency services to manage the situation.</p>
<p>As a result of the fire, a warning for toxic smoke has been issued in the nearby Batesford, Bell Post Hill, Lovely Banks and Moorabool areas, reports <a href="https://www.smh.com.au/business/the-economy/fire-breaks-out-during-testing-of-victorian-big-battery-near-geelong-20210730-p58eh4.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="27" data-v9y="0"><em>The Sydney Morning Herald</em></a>. Residents were warned to move indoors, close windows, vents and fireplace flues and bring their pets inside.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Victorian Big Battery site, a 300 MW/450 MWh battery storage facility, is viewed as key to the Victorian government&#8217;s 50 percent renewable energy target by 2030. It follows the success of Neoen and Tesla&#8217;s 100 MW/129 MWh battery farm in Hornsdale in South Australia, which was completed ahead of <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-12-01-tesla-live-world-largest-battery-south-australia.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="28" data-v9y="1">schedule</a> and has resulted in <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-02-06-tesla-s-big-battery-is-undercutting-australia-s-energy-cartels.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="29" data-v9y="1">multi-million dollar savings</a> for market players and consumers. Both sites essentially provide a regional power backup for when renewable energy is not available, effectively filling the gap when the sun isn&#8217;t shining and the wind isn&#8217;t blowing.</p>
<p>In February, Neoen announced that the Victorian Big Battery would utliize Tesla&#8217;s megapacks — utility-sized batteries produced at the company&#8217;s Gigafactory — and Autobidder software to sell power to the grid. Victorian Big Battery has a contract with the Australian Energy Market Operator (AEMO). As part of the pact, the site will provide energy stability by unlocking an additional 250 MW of peak capacity on the existing Victoria to New South Wales Interconnector over the next decade of Australian summers.</p>
<p><b>Editor’s note:</b> <i><span style="font-weight: 400;">This post originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tesla-megapack-fire-victorian-big-battery-105535797.html">Engadget</a>.</span></i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/a-tesla-megapack-caught-fire-at-the-victorian-big-battery-facility-in-australia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184189</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elon Musk calls Apple&#8217;s App Store fees &#8216;a de facto global tax on the Internet&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/elon-musk-calls-app-store-fees-a-de-facto-global-tax-on-the-internet/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/elon-musk-calls-app-store-fees-a-de-facto-global-tax-on-the-internet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 17:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate governance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Epic Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyperloop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184142</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Elon Musk is siding with Epic Games in the App Store monopoly case, with the Tesla CEO firing off a tweet Friday morning that called Apple&#8217;s Store fees &#8220;a de facto global tax on the Internet,&#8221; also adding that &#8220;Epic is right.&#8221; Epic Games legal battle with Apple is sure to last years and the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Elon Musk is siding with Epic Games in the App Store monopoly case, with the Tesla CEO <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1421152540394143746?s=20">firing off a tweet</a> Friday morning that called Apple&#8217;s Store fees &#8220;a de facto global tax on the Internet,&#8221; also adding that &#8220;Epic is right.&#8221;</p>
<p>Epic Games legal battle with Apple is sure to last years and the Fortnite maker has hardly been secretive about its aims to win the battle for popular opinion as well. Musk&#8217;s vote of confidence could hold sway with consumers who have yet to develop a clear opinion on the topic.</p>
<p>Apple has argued publicly that dissatisfied developers can take their products to Android or mobile web on iOS, but Epic Games and others have argued that Apple&#8217;s stranglehold on apps is nothing short of a monopoly.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>What&#8217;s less clear is why Musk is taking up this issue right now. While Musk is rarely one to pass up offering an outside opinion on a contentious issue that doesn&#8217;t involve him, none of Musk&#8217;s current companies seem to be deeply affected by the fees from the App Store, though there certainly could be action happening behind the scenes.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HjyxjqgXpi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/02/3-guiding-principles-for-ceos-who-post-on-twitter/">3 guiding principles for CEOs who post on Twitter</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 guiding principles for CEOs who post on Twitter&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/02/3-guiding-principles-for-ceos-who-post-on-twitter/embed/#?secret=HjyxjqgXpi" data-secret="HjyxjqgXpi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Apple app store fees are a de facto global tax on the Internet. Epic is right.</p>
<p>&mdash; Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1421152540394143746?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 30, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/elon-musk-calls-app-store-fees-a-de-facto-global-tax-on-the-internet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184142</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>US government watchdog rejects Blue Origin&#8217;s protest over lunar lander contract</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/government-watchdog-rejects-blue-origins-protest-over-lunar-lander-contract/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/government-watchdog-rejects-blue-origins-protest-over-lunar-lander-contract/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 17:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dynetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government Accountability Office]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human landing system program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Government Accountability Office said that it was denying both Blue Origin’s protest and a separate challenge filed by Dynetics.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Blue Origin&#8217;s protest to a U.S. governmental watchdog over NASA’s decision to award SpaceX a multi-billion dollar contract to develop a lunar lander was rejected.</p>
<p>The Government Accountability Office said Friday that it was denying both Blue Origin’s protest and a separate challenge filed by Dynetics, a defense contractor that also submitted a proposal for the contract. GAO concluded that NASA did not violate any laws or regulations when granting the sole award to SpaceX.</p>
<p>“As a result, GAO denied the protest arguments that NASA acted improperly in making a single award to SpaceX,” the agency said <a href="https://www.gao.gov/press-release/statement-blue-origin-dynetics-decision">in a statement</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The formal protest was over NASA’s decision to award the contract for the Human Landing System Program, which aims to return humans to the moon for the first time since Apollo, solely to SpaceX &#8212; and not to two companies, as was originally intended. SpaceX’s proposal for the Human Landing System Program came in at $2.9 billion, around half of Blue Origin’s $5.99 billion proposal. Earlier this week, Bezos penned an open letter to NASA Administrator Bill Nelson offering to knock $2 billion off that price to solve the “near-term budgetary issues” that caused NASA to select just one company for the contract.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OEfbGJZ4CV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/bezos-offers-billions-in-incentives-for-nasas-lunar-lander-contract/">Bezos offers billions in incentives for NASA&#8217;s lunar lander contract</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bezos offers billions in incentives for NASA&#8217;s lunar lander contract&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/bezos-offers-billions-in-incentives-for-nasas-lunar-lander-contract/embed/#?secret=OEfbGJZ4CV" data-secret="OEfbGJZ4CV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>NASA’s decision to give just one company the award did veer from historical standard, but GAO maintained that “the [contract] announcement reserved the right to make multiple awards, a single award, or no award at all.”</p>
<p>Blue Origin maintains that it was not given time to revise its bid after NASA concluded it did not have sufficient funding for two awards. “Blue Origin was plainly prejudiced by the Agency’s failure to communicate this change in requirements,” the company said in the protest. “Blue Origin could have and would have taken several actions to revise its proposed approach, reduce its price to more closely align with funding available to the Agency, and/or propose schedule alternatives.”</p>
<p>Blue Origin and Dynetics submitted their separate protests in April.</p>
<p><em>Update:</em> In response to the decision, a Blue Origin spokesperson told TechCrunch:</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“We stand firm in our belief that there were fundamental issues with NASA’s decision, but the GAO wasn’t able to address them due to their limited jurisdiction. We’ll continue to advocate for two immediate providers as we believe it is the right solution.&#8221;</p>
<p>The spokesperson noted that the company was encouraged by lawmakers adding a provision to a bill in Senate that would require NASA to select two providers for the HLS program.</p>
<p>Elon Musk, meanwhile, had this to say about the decision&#8230;</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="und">GAO <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4aa.png" alt="💪" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1421155803223011333?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 30, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>TechCrunch has reached out to Dynetics for comment. We will update the story if they respond.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/government-watchdog-rejects-blue-origins-protest-over-lunar-lander-contract/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184132</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Design expert Scott Tong outlines 4 concepts founders should consider when designing products</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/design-expert-scott-tong-outlines-4-concepts-founders-should-consider-when-designing-products/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/design-expert-scott-tong-outlines-4-concepts-founders-should-consider-when-designing-products/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 16:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Early Stage 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Early Stage 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[event recap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scott tong]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183708</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At Early Stage 2021, design expert Scott Tong walked us through some of the ways founders should think about design, what design means and the steps that come before focusing on the pixels.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In the last decade, high-quality design has become a necessity in the software space. Great design is a commodity, not a luxury, and yet, designing beautiful products and finding great designers continues to be a struggle for many entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>At Early Stage 2021, design expert Scott Tong walked us through some of the ways founders should think about design. Tong was involved in product and brand design at some of the biggest brands in tech, including IDEO, IFTTT, Pinterest and more. He&#8217;s now a partner at Design Fund.</p>
<p>Tong explained how to think about brand as more than a logo or a social media presence, what design means and the steps that come before focusing on the pixels, and gave guidance on when entrepreneurs should hire third-party design agencies or bring on full-time talent.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Help TechCrunch find the best growth marketers for startups. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">this quick survey</a> and we&#8217;ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<h2>Reputation</h2>
<p>&#8220;The purest treasure mortal times afford is spotless reputation,&#8221; wrote Shakespeare. Though we often think of a brand as a logo or a social media persona, a brand is the equivalent of a person&#8217;s reputation. It signifies what the company and products stand for, and it has an element of being memorable for something, whether it&#8217;s prestige, like for Chanel, or terrible customer service, like for Comcast.</p>
<blockquote><p>The closest word in the English language to brand is actually reputation. The analogy is that brand is to company as reputation is to person. If you can link your brand with your company&#8217;s reputation, I think it&#8217;s a really great place to start when you&#8217;re having conversations about brands. What is the first impression? What are the consistent behaviors that your brand hopes to repeat over and over? What are the memorable moments that stand out and make your brand, your reputation memorable? <em><strong>(Timestamp: 2:40)</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<h2>Existing versus preferred</h2>
<p>Tong outlined what design is truly about. There are many different schools of thought on design methodology and there are many different types of design. You may be thinking about product design and logo design and brand design all at the same time, and the only way to successfully hire for those tasks and complete them is to understand what design is, at its core.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/design-expert-scott-tong-outlines-4-concepts-founders-should-consider-when-designing-products/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183708</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Robinhood&#8217;s CFO says it was ready to go public</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/robinhoods-cfo-says-it-was-ready-to-go-public/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/robinhoods-cfo-says-it-was-ready-to-go-public/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 15:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jason Warnick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stock market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184007</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Robinhood says it went public because it was ready. And our read of the markets is that it's an appealing time for high-growth tech companies with a history of losses to do so. Yet it's underwater.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Robinhood priced at $38 per share this week, opened flat and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/robinhoods-stock-drops-8-in-its-first-days-trading/">closed its first day&#8217;s trading yesterday</a> worth $34.82 per share, or a bit more than 8% underwater. The company posted a mixed picture today, falling early before recovering to breakeven in late-morning trading.</p>
<p>It wasn&#8217;t the debut that <a href="https://twitter.com/bgurley/status/1420446592851607552">some expected Robinhood to have</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>To close out the week, we&#8217;re not going to noodle on banned Chinese IPOs or do a full-week mega-round discussion. Instead, let&#8217;s parse some notes from a chat The Exchange had with Robinhood&#8217;s CFO about his company&#8217;s IPO and go over a few reasonable guesses as to why we&#8217;re not wondering how much money Robinhood left on the table by pricing its public offering lower than it closed on its first day.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995213 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Let&#8217;s not be dicks about it. The time for <a href="https://twitter.com/alex/status/1420845815082352644">Twitter jokes</a> was yesterday. We&#8217;ll put our thinking caps on this morning.</p>
<h2>Why Robinhood went public when it did</h2>
<p>Chatting with Robinhood CFO <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2018/11/27/robinhood-hires-amazon-veteran-as-cfo-a-key-step-in-its-path-to-ipo.html">Jason Warnick</a> earlier this week, we wanted to know why this was the right time for Robinhood to go public.</p>
<p>Now, no public company CEO or CFO will come out and directly say that they are going public because they think that they can defend &#8212; or extend &#8212; their most recent private valuation thanks to current market conditions.</p>
<p>Instead, execs on IPO day tend to deflect the question, pivoting to a well-oiled bon mot about how their public offering is a mere milestone on their company&#8217;s long-term trajectory. For some reason in our capitalist society, during an arch-capitalist event, by a for-profit company, leaders find it critical to downplay their IPO&#8217;s importance.<sup>1</sup></p>
<p>With that in mind, Warnick did not say Robinhood went public because the IPO market has recently rewarded big-brand consumer tech companies like Airbnb and DoorDash with strong debuts. And he didn&#8217;t say that with tech shares near all-time highs and a taste for high-growth concerns, the company was likely set to enter a market that would be willing to price it at a valuation that it found attractive.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/robinhoods-cfo-says-it-was-ready-to-go-public/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184007</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Last day to snag early-bird passes to TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/last-day-to-snag-early-bird-passes-to-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/last-day-to-snag-early-bird-passes-to-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 15:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brian armstrong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brynn Putnam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[duolingo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HashiCorp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jill Wetzler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[luis von ahn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pear vc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pete buttigieg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechStars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2182523</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Don’t miss your chance to experience TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 — the startup world’s must-attend event of the season — for less than $100. Why not get the best ROI of your time while simultaneously learning about the latest industry trends and mining for opportunities that can take your startup to new levels of success? Disrupt [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Don’t miss your chance to experience <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=disrupt2021&amp;utm_content=lastdaypost&amp;utm_source=tcwebsite&amp;promo=lastdaypost&amp;display=TRUE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> — the startup world’s must-attend event of the season — for less than $100. Why not get the best ROI of your time while simultaneously learning about the latest industry trends and mining for opportunities that can take your startup to new levels of success?</p>
<p>Disrupt takes place on September 21-23, but the early-bird deal expires today, <strong>July 30 at 11:59 p.m. (PDT)</strong>. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=disrupt2021&amp;utm_content=lastdaypost&amp;utm_source=tcwebsite&amp;promo=lastdaypost&amp;display=TRUE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Buy your Disrupt 2021 pass</a> now and save.</p>
<p>Let’s talk about what you’ll experience at Disrupt. Over on the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/announcing-the-agenda-for-the-disrupt-stage-this-september/">Disrupt Stage</a> you’ll find one-on-one interviews with icons and interactive, expert-led, presentations from across the tech, investing and policy sectors. Folks like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/coinbase-ceo-brian-armstrong-is-coming-to-disrupt/">Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/us-secretary-of-transportation-pete-buttigieg-is-coming-to-disrupt-draft/">U.S. Secretary of Transportation Pete Buttigieg</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/08/discover-how-duolingo-started-with-ceo-luis-von-ahn-at-disrupt-2021/">Duolingo CEO Luis von Ahn</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/discuss-the-future-of-connected-fitness-with-mirrors-brynn-putnam-at-disrupt-2021/">Mirror CEO Brynn Putnam</a>. And that’s just the tip of the tech iceberg. You can <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/#eb919231-f3e4-4def-8dd0-afb0bc7c9c6e">check out all the speakers here</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>You’ll find plenty of actionable advice and how-to tips and strategies on the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/announcing-the-disrupt-2021-extra-crunch-stage-agenda/">Extra Crunch Stage</a>. Take a gander at just two of the topics we have scheduled there and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/#0affacde-e0ed-4a3c-abc4-988cb1c0eb3e">explore the full Disrupt agenda here</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Crafting a Pitch Deck that Can’t Be Ignored:</strong> Investors may be chasing after the hottest deals, but for founders selling their startup’s vision, it’s never been more important to communicate it in the clearest way possible. Pitch deck experts Mercedes Bent (partner, Lightspeed Venture Partners), Mar Hershenson (co-founder and managing partner, Pear VC) and Saba Karim (Techstars’ head of accelerator pipeline) dig into what’s essential, what’s unnecessary and what could just make all the difference in your next deck.</p>
<p><strong>How Do You Select the Right Tech Stack:</strong> From day zero, startups have to make dozens of trade-offs when it comes to the infinite variety of tech stacks available to today’s engineers. Choose the wrong combination or direction, and a startup could be left with years of refactoring to fix the legacy damage. What are the best practices for assessing potential stacks, and how can you minimize the risk of a painful mistake? Preeti Somal (executive vice president of engineering, HashiCorp) and Jill Wetzler (head of engineering, Pilot) will discuss strategies for improving engineering right from the beginning and at every stage of a startup’s journey.</p>
<p>Disrupt’s virtual format provides plenty of opportunity for questions, so come prepared to ask the experts about the issues that keep you up at night.</p>
<p>One post can&#8217;t possibly contain all the events and opportunities of Disrupt. Don’t miss the epic Startup Battlefield competition, hundreds of early-stage startups exhibiting in the Startup Alley expo area, special breakout sessions — like the Pitch Deck Teardown — and so much more.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=disrupt2021&amp;utm_content=lastdaypost&amp;utm_source=tcwebsite&amp;promo=lastdaypost&amp;display=TRUE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> offers tons of opportunity. Don’t miss out on the first one — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/tickets/">buy your Disrupt pass</a> today, <strong>July 30, by 11:59 p.m. (PDT)</strong> for less than $100. It’s a sweet deal!</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at Disrupt 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			width="99%"
			height="1300"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/last-day-to-snag-early-bird-passes-to-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2182523</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>White-label SaaS shipping startup Outvio closes $3M round led by Change Ventures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/white-label-saas-shipping-startup-outvio-closes-3m-round-led-by-change-ventures/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/white-label-saas-shipping-startup-outvio-closes-3m-round-led-by-change-ventures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 15:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[estonia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[merchandising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online stores]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TMT Investments]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184080</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Outvio offers online stores of any size a post-purchase shipping setup, which seeks to replicate an Amazon-style experience where customers can also return packages.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://outvio.com">Outvio</a>, an Estonian startup that provides a white-label SaaS fulfillment solution for medium-sized and large online retailers in Spain and Estonia, has closed a $3 million early-stage financing round led by Change Ventures.</p>
<p>Also participating were TMT Investments (London), Fresco Capital (San Francisco) and Lemonade Stand (Tallinn). Several angels also joined the round, including James Berdigans (Printify) and Kristjan Vilosius (Katana MRP). This is the startup&#8217;s first institutional round of funding after bootstrapping since 2018.</p>
<p>Online retailers usually have to use a number of different tools or hire expensive developers to create in-house shipping solutions. Outvio offers online stores of any size a post-purchase shipping setup, which seeks to replicate an Amazon-style experience where customers can also return packages. Among others, it competes with <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/shippypro">ShippyPro</a>, which runs out of Italy and has raised $5 million to date.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We can give any online store all the tools needed to offer a superior post-sale customer experience,&#8221; Juan Borras, co-founder and CEO of Outvio, said. &#8220;We can integrate at different points in their fulfillment process, and for large merchants, save them hundreds of thousands in development costs alone.”</p>
<p>“What happens after the purchase is more important than most shops realize,&#8221; he added. &#8220;More than 88% of consumers say it is very important for them that retailers proactively communicate every fulfillment and delivery stage. Not doing so, especially if there are problems, often results in losing that client. Our mission is to help online stores streamline everything that happens after the sale, fueling repeat business and brand-loyal customers with the help of a fantastic post-purchase experience.”</p>
<p>“While online retailing has a long way to go, the expectations of consumers are increasing when it comes to delivery time and standards,&#8221; Rait Ojasaar, investment partner at lead investor Change Ventures, said. &#8220;The same can be said about the online shop operators who increasingly look for more advanced solutions with consumer-like user experience. The Outvio team has understood exactly what the gap in the market is and has done a tremendous job of finding product-market fit with their modern fulfillment SaaS platform.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/white-label-saas-shipping-startup-outvio-closes-3m-round-led-by-change-ventures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184080</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gillmor Gang: Social climbing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/gillmor-gang-social-climbing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/gillmor-gang-social-climbing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 15:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brent Leary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denis Pombriant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frank radice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keith Teare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Markman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183923</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fear is back with the deadly combination of pandemic politics and a vicious variant. The good news is that if enough people took the shots we could cut the damage to something manageable. The other good news is progress on the twin issues of Trump and social media. In both cases some semblance of balanced [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NNEDhARQXX0?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>Fear is back with the deadly combination of pandemic politics and a vicious variant. The good news is that if enough people took the shots we could cut the damage to something manageable. The other good news is progress on the twin issues of Trump and social media. In both cases some semblance of balanced rationality is seeping in to the public discourse.</p>
<p>First is the former president, who has already done about as much damage as he can. Joe Biden is doing a good job of wrestling Congress into some degree of productivity. As the Gang talks about this and the next episode, it appears increasingly likely there will be a bipartisan infrastructure bill. Republicans and particularly Mitch McConnell can still shut the whole thing down, but Democrats hold the budget reconciliation process as a hole card to prompt a semi-partisan bill across the two parties. The Biden strategy is to not only force the right to accommodate some center victory but forestall a significant cave by the centrist Democrat Joe Manchin on the filibuster. This may have some value if Congress puts its foot down on voting rights or the effort to destroy them.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Something similar may be playing out on the social side. Facebook and Twitter seem to be circling each other as Congress forces some antitrust positioning. With the courts giving Facebook a little running room on the operational description of what a monopoly is, Twitter reported strong numbers that beat the Street and make Jack Dorsey&#8217;s feint toward bitcoin and the creator economy easier to swallow when the smoke clears. The newsletterization of media is giving social media some street cred as Congress tries to force Facebook to grow up. Block an MGM deal here and a Section 530 carveout there seems possible although more likely just the beginning of negotiations.</p>
<p>The big battle is over the shape of post-COVID work and lifestyle negotiations. Vaccination reluctance is a five-alarm fire, but the 2022 midterms may well be fought over the intersection of climate change and the speed of recovery led by the accelerated digital economy. I don&#8217;t believe that it&#8217;s a coincidence that back to work and a manageable ecology are deeply related. Silicon Valley can talk all it wants about inventing the future, but desperate consumers are looking for real answers from tech leaders who understand the future to come in a constantly unstable weather crisis that turns a burning West Coast into a choking rest of the country.</p>
<p>Vaccine mandates are a fierce predictor of what&#8217;s to come. In a country under constant threat of a constitutional crisis over voter fraud by one of the two major parties, the federal response may be constrained but not the rules at the workforce level. These are serious issues of privacy and human rights, but in the short term the moves toward practical mandates will be swift at the state and company level, and supported by healthy polling. Do you think some version of work from anywhere will be tied to double vaccination? As a mandate, it&#8217;s not a done deal; as a choice it seems like a popular way of reducing the crisis from the current 35% to something approaching a too-high but winter-ready time frame of 15% where hospitals and state economies need help, red or blue. And those numbers may become the difference between major crisis and economy-crushing lockdowns if an even more egregious variant emerges.</p>
<p>This is also where social and safety meet at a crossroads. Are we willing to cede a Facebook unimpeded from fueling the misinformation plague, or are we going to look for help from the creator economy to bypass the fallow mainstream media stuck in their controversy-fueled business model rather than a fact-based scientific approach to breaking the back of this turgid political cycle? We can see the outline of newsletter-framed social media courage, coupled with stakeholder-aware ethical values and economic leverage.</p>
<p>Less obvious is the path for Clubhouse and its competitors. The Andreessen-Horowitz-backed mobile app came out of invite-only beta and added an internal instant messaging layer to manage moderators, speakers, listener questions, room onboarding and feedback. But the big problem remains why does this mere feature of a livestreaming podcast app buttress the high valuation of the startup. And this from Michael Markman:</p>
<blockquote><p>I&#8217;ve largely lost interest in Clubhouse. This may not be a significant data point, but I&#8217;m no longer fascinated … The thing is, I sometimes find myself in rooms where I was learning something or getting points of view that hadn&#8217;t occurred to me. But usually I was listening to very frustrating conversations that led nowhere.</p></blockquote>
<p>Yeah, that would do it. But the bigger problem is the refusal to allow recording as a feature of the UI. Twitter Spaces won&#8217;t do it, Facebook is really a winner-take-all newsletter subscriber model (Substack) grafted on, and Spotify already has recording enabled on Anchor, its podcasting tool. Building one app is probably where Spotify will go, but then they have the problem that podcasting is considered only an audio product. So then what? Add video multiplatform streaming like ReStream to the hybrid social audio/podcast/recorder/newsletter and we got something. What&#8217;s the holdup?</p>
<p>No recording started as a nod to privacy, a differentiator between the creators and the listeners. The idea was to create a unique quality of serendipity, discovery and credibility. It&#8217;s reminiscent of the theater&#8217;s fourth wall, where characters step out of their circumstances to talk directly to the audience. It&#8217;s exhilarating to experience, a hybrid between writing and improvisation that is largely an illusion. Illusions are no less valuable just because they elegantly transcend their apparent boundaries. Clubhouse spoke directly to our sense that we had lost our way in the insidious virus of both science and truth.</p>
<p>In the decay of the Clubhouse model, we sense that the creator economy is all hat and not enough cowboy. Brent Leary:</p>
<blockquote><p>I see this as just another way to accelerate the few getting most of everything with everybody else getting scraps. You&#8217;re going to hear all these stories about all the folks, all the people that make it big, but they&#8217;re going to be like an infinitesimal fraction of everybody else trying to do the same thing and not being able to do it.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s just so much attention that you can give. And the people who know how to use this stuff and put a nice process together and find a way to really create a well-oiled-process machine; they have the chance of being in that top echelon of creators that get most of the money. But everybody else is going to be there trying and spinning their wheels because it&#8217;s just a continuation of what we&#8217;ve always had.</p></blockquote>
<p>Recording and a calendar page will make a difference if only to bring a vote to the floor. Is this something to look forward to, a social version of Andrea Mitchell or Nicolle Wallace on MSNBC, a system of record for issues that matter in the anywhere, creator, or thought leader economies. Markman&#8217;s question about Clubhouse viability is a broader hedge against the tendency of social media to add to the problems rather than alleviate them. Recording is really a time-shifting tool for user control, and a driver for leaderboard metadata to annotate a calendar either live or personally maintained. In theory Clubhouse should work, but in practice without recording it could be labeled another do-nothing congress.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>from the <a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang/issues/gillmor-gang-newsletter-revue-11-664511"> Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">__________________</p>
<p>The Gillmor Gang — Frank Radice, Michael Markman, Keith Teare, Denis Pombriant, Brent Leary and Steve Gillmor. Recorded live Friday, July 16, 2021.</p>
<p>Produced and directed by Tina Chase Gillmor @tinagillmor</p>
<p>@fradice, @mickeleh, @denispombriant, @kteare, @brentleary, @stevegillmor, @gillmorgang</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang">Subscribe to the new Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></strong> and join the backchannel <a href="https://t.me/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> on Telegram.</p>
<p><a href="http://facebook.com/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Gillmor Gang on Facebook</a> … and here’s our sister show <a href="http://facebook.com/g3show" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">G3 on Facebook</a>.<img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2012361" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2012361" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/gillmor-gang-social-climbing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183923</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>EU hits Amazon with record-breaking $887M GDPR fine over data misuse</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/eu-hits-amazon-with-record-breaking-887m-gdpr-fine-over-data-misuse/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/eu-hits-amazon-with-record-breaking-887m-gdpr-fine-over-data-misuse/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 15:06:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184038</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Luxembourg’s National Commission for Data Protection (CNPD) has hit Amazon with a record-breaking €746 million ($887 million) GDPR fine over the way it uses customer data for targeted advertising purposes. Amazon disclosed the ruling in an SEC filing on Friday in which it slammed the decision as baseless and added that it intended to defend [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Luxembourg’s National Commission for Data Protection (CNPD) has hit Amazon with a record-breaking €746 million ($887 million) <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/20/wtf-is-gdpr/">GDPR</a> fine over the way it uses customer data for targeted advertising purposes.</p>
<p>Amazon disclosed the ruling in an <a href="https://d18rn0p25nwr6d.cloudfront.net/CIK-0001018724/cbae1abf-eddb-4451-9186-6753b02cc4eb.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="16" data-v9y="1">SEC filing</a> on Friday in which it slammed the decision as baseless and added that it intended to defend itself &#8220;vigorously in this matter.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Maintaining the security of our customers’ information and their trust are top priorities,&#8221; an Amazon spokesperson said in a statement. &#8220;There has been no data breach, and no customer data has been exposed to any third party. These facts are undisputed.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We strongly disagree with the CNPD’s ruling, and we intend to appeal. The decision relating to how we show customers relevant advertising relies on subjective and untested interpretations of European privacy law, and the proposed fine is entirely out of proportion with even that interpretation.&#8221;</p>
<p>The penalty is the result of a 2018 <a href="https://gafam.laquadrature.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/05/amazon.pdf">complaint</a> by French privacy rights group La Quadrature du Net, a group that claims to represent the interests of thousands of Europeans to ensure their data isn&#8217;t used by Big Tech companies to manipulate their behavior for political or commercial purposes. The complaint, which also targets Apple, Facebook Google and LinkedIn and was filed on behalf of more than 10,000 customers, alleges that Amazon manipulates customers for commercial means by choosing what advertising and information they receive.</p>
<p>La Quadrature du Net welcomed the fine issued by the CNPD, which &#8220;comes after three years of silence that made us fear the worst.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The model of economic domination based on the exploitation of our privacy and free will is profoundly illegitimate and contrary to all the values that our democratic societies claim to defend,&#8221; <a href="https://www.laquadrature.net/2021/07/30/amende-de-746-millions-deuros-contre-amazon-suite-a-nos-plaintes-collectives/">the group added in a blog post published on Friday</a>.</p>
<p>The CNPD has also ruled that Amazon must commit to changing its business practices. However, the regulator has not publicly committed on its decision, and Amazon didn’t specify what revised business practices it is proposing.</p>
<div class="article-text">
<p>The record penalty, which trumps <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/21/french-data-protection-watchdog-fines-google-57-million-under-the-gdpr/">the €50 million GDPR penalty levied against Google in 2019</a>, comes amid heightened scrutiny of Amazon&#8217;s business in Europe. In November last year, the European Commission announced formal antitrust charges against the company, saying the retailer has misused its position to compete against third-party businesses using its platform. At the same time, the commission began a second investigation into its alleged preferential treatment of its own products on its site and those of its partners.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="w2xQyr0B91"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/3-analysts-weigh-in-what-are-andy-jassys-top-priorities-as-amazons-new-ceo/">3 analysts weigh in: What are Andy Jassy&#8217;s top priorities as Amazon&#8217;s new CEO?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 analysts weigh in: What are Andy Jassy&#8217;s top priorities as Amazon&#8217;s new CEO?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/3-analysts-weigh-in-what-are-andy-jassys-top-priorities-as-amazons-new-ceo/embed/#?secret=w2xQyr0B91" data-secret="w2xQyr0B91" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/eu-hits-amazon-with-record-breaking-887m-gdpr-fine-over-data-misuse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184038</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chilean fintech Xepelin secures $230M in debt and equity from Kaszek, high-profile angels</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/chilean-fintech-xepelin-secures-230m-in-debt-equity-from-kaszek-high-profile-angels/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/chilean-fintech-xepelin-secures-230m-in-debt-equity-from-kaszek-high-profile-angels/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 14:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DST Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hans tung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jüsto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kaszek Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MSA Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Picus Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ricardo Weder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Square Financial Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiger Global Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183963</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Xepelin is built on a SaaS model designed to give SMEs a way to organize their financial information in real time.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chilean startup</span> <a href="https://www.xepelin.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Xepelin</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which has created a financial services platform for SMEs in Latin America, has secured $30 million in equity and $200 million in </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">credit facilities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">LatAm venture fund <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/the-latam-funding-boom-continues-as-kaszek-raises-1b-across-a-duo-of-funds/">Kaszek Ventures</a> led the equity portion of the financing, which also included participation from partners of DST Global and a slew of other firms and founders/angel investors. LatAm- and U.S.-based asset managers and hedge funds &#8212; including Chilean pension funds &#8212; provided the credit facilities. In total over its lifetime, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Xepelin has raised over $36 million in equity and $250 million in asset-backed facilities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also participating in the round were Picus Capital; Kayak Ventures; Cathay Innovation; MSA Capital; Amarena; FJ Labs; Gilgamesh Ventures. A group of angels also participated in the financing, including Kavak founder and CEO Carlos Garcia; Jackie Reses, executive chairman of Square Financial Services; Justo founder and CEO Ricardo Weder; Tiger Global Management Partner John Curtius; GGV’s Hans Tung; and Gerry Giacoman, founder and CEO of Clara, among others.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.xepelin.com/sobre-nosotros/">Nicolás de Camino</a> and <a href="https://www.xepelin.com/sobre-nosotros/">Sebastian Kreis</a> founded Xepelin in mid-2019 with the mission of changing the fact that “only 5% of companies in all LatAm countries have access to recurring financial services.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We want all SMEs in LatAm to have access to financial services and capital in a fair and efficient way,” the pair said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Xepelin is built on a SaaS model designed to give SMEs a way to organize their financial information in real time. Embedded in its software is a way for companies to apply for short-term working capital loans “with just three clicks, and receive the capital in a matter of hours,” the company claimed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It has developed an AI-driven underwriting engine, which the execs said gives it the ability to make real-time loan approval decisions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Any company in LatAm can onboard in just a few minutes and immediately access a free software that helps them organize their information in real time, including cash flow, revenue, sales, tax, bureau info &#8212; sort of a free CFO SaaS,” de Camino said. “The circle is virtuous: SMEs use Xepelin to improve their financial habits, obtain more efficient financing, pay their obligations, and collaborate effectively with clients and suppliers, generating relevant impacts in their industries.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3BwXOuE1XU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/why-latin-american-venture-capital-is-breaking-records-this-year/">Why Latin American venture capital is breaking records this year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why Latin American venture capital is breaking records this year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/why-latin-american-venture-capital-is-breaking-records-this-year/embed/#?secret=3BwXOuE1XU" data-secret="3BwXOuE1XU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fintech currently has over 4,000 clients in Chile and Mexico, which currently has a growth rate “four times faster” than when Xepelin started in Chile. Over the past 22 months, it has loaned more than $400 million to SMBs in the two countries. It currently has</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a portfolio of active loans for $120 million and an asset-backed facility for more than $250 million.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall, the company has been seeing a growth rate of 30% per month, the founders said. It has 110 employees, up from 20 a year ago.</span></p>
<div>Xepelin has more than 60 partnerships (a number that it said is growing each week) with midmarket corporate companies, allowing for their suppliers to onboard to its platform for free and gain access to accounts payable, revenue-based financing. The company also sells its portfolio of non-recourse loans to financial partners, which it says mitigates credit risk exposure and enhances its platform and data play.</div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“When we talk about creating the largest digital bank for SMEs in LatAm, we are not saying that our goal is to create a bank; perhaps we will never ask for the license to have one, and to be honest, everything we do, we do it differently from the banks, something like a non-bank, a concept used today to exemplify focus,&#8221; the founders said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Both de Camino and Kreis said they share a passion for making financial services more accessible to SMEs all across Latin America and have backgrounds rooted deep in different areas of finance.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our goal is to scale a platform that can solve the true pains of all SMEs in LatAm, all in one place that also connects them with their entire ecosystem, and above all, democratized in such a way that everyone can access it,” Kreis said, “regardless of whether you are a company that sells billions of dollars or just a thousand dollars, getting the same service and conditions.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For now, the company is nearly exclusively focused on the B2B space, but in the future, it believes several of its services “will be very useful for all SMEs and companies in LatAm.”</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Xepelin has developed technology and data science engines to deliver financing to SMBs in Latin America in a seamless way,” Nicolas Szekasy, co-founder and managing partner at Kaszek Ventures, said in a statement.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The team has deep experience in the sector and has proven a perfect fit of their user-friendly product with the needs of the market.”</span></p>
<p>Chile was home to another large funding earlier this week. <a href="https://notco.com/">NotCo</a>, a food technology company making plant-based milk and meat replacements, closed on a $235 million Series D round that gives it a $1.5 billion valuation.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IppVSMcGWh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/notco-gets-its-horn-following-235m-round-to-expand-plant-based-food-products/">NotCo gets its horn following $235M round to expand plant-based food products</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;NotCo gets its horn following $235M round to expand plant-based food products&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/notco-gets-its-horn-following-235m-round-to-expand-plant-based-food-products/embed/#?secret=IppVSMcGWh" data-secret="IppVSMcGWh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/chilean-fintech-xepelin-secures-230m-in-debt-equity-from-kaszek-high-profile-angels/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183963</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cheltenham’s GCHQ to get a massive, cyber-oriented tech startup campus right next door</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/cheltenhams-gchq-to-get-a-massive-cyber-oriented-tech-startup-campus-right-next-door/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/cheltenhams-gchq-to-get-a-massive-cyber-oriented-tech-startup-campus-right-next-door/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 14:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gchq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184037</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The development is projected to add 12,000 new jobs, 2 million square feet of offices and 3,700 new homes.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Since U.K. spying headquarters <a href="https://www.gchq.gov.uk/">GCHQ</a> was established in Cheltenham in the 1950s, the city has attracted large firms like IBM, Raytheon, Microsoft and BAE Systems to the region, and startups like Truststamp, Bamboo Technologies, Ripjar, Hub8 and CYNAM have emerged from the city.</p>
<p>All of these firms draw on the talent that naturally gravitates to such a place, especially when you have these kinds of organizations floating around.</p>
<p>Now it appears that Cheltenham is aiming to more closely target entrepreneurs, investors and startups, especially given that the pandemic has seen talent thrown to the four winds, looking for better lifestyles and more access to nature. Smartly, it will be leveraging its association with the cybersecurity-oriented GCHQ.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In 2019, Cheltenham Borough Council spent £37.5 million purchasing 45 hectares of land adjacent to GCHQ, with the goal of capitalizing on the burgeoning cybersecurity and technology community.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OtfPdAZ7y3A?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;start=1&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>After a year-long process, the council selected key partners as &#8220;preferred bidders&#8221; to deliver it – Factory and HBD (formerly Henry Boot Developments). The ambition is to grow the area to 200 hectares, which would make it one of the biggest tech startup campuses in Europe.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.factory.com/">Factory</a>, which developed large-scale tech campuses in Berlin and Lisbon, will partner with U.K. developer <a href="https://hbd.co.uk/">HBD</a> and the council to create the project currently dubbed <a href="https://www.goldenvalleyuk.com/">Golden Valley.</a></p>
<p>The development is projected to add 12,000 new jobs, 2 million square feet of offices and 3,700 new homes, and will be drawn on the Garden City status, building upon the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Garden_city_movement">garden city movement</a> established in the late 19th century by Ebenezer Howard.</p>
<p>“This is a once-in-a-lifetime project &#8212; it’s unprecedented,&#8221; said Jeremy Bamberg, who will be leading the project locally for Factory. &#8220;By embracing tech, nature and innovation we’re working to transform the area into Europe’s most intelligent Garden District &#8212; creating an ideal alternative to chaotic city life.”</p>
<p>The first step of the project will be building Factory Cheltenham. As with Factory’s projects in Berlin and Lisbon, the architecture and design will led by Julian Breinersdorfer, who recently joined Factory to create an in-house offering for similar buildings and districts.</p>
<p>“We were looking for a partner to help the council make our ambitious plans a reality,&#8221; Tim Atkins from Cheltenham Borough Council said. &#8220;HBD and Factory have shown us how they share these goals and, more importantly, how these will be transformed into a living, breathing entity right here in Cheltenham that has a positive impact locally, whilst being a key part of the global cyber sector.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184047" style="width: 705px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184047" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2184047" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/F_CHLTNHM_1.jpg" alt="Factory Cheltenham (image www.mir.no) " width="695" height="463" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/F_CHLTNHM_1.jpg 695w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/F_CHLTNHM_1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/F_CHLTNHM_1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/F_CHLTNHM_1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/F_CHLTNHM_1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 695px) 100vw, 695px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184047" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> www.mir.no. Factory Cheltenham</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/cheltenhams-gchq-to-get-a-massive-cyber-oriented-tech-startup-campus-right-next-door/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184037</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Growth is not enough</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/growth-is-not-enough/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/growth-is-not-enough/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 14:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ascap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[class]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Contentful]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lordstown Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oova]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peppy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Redwood Materials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[squire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183798</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The week brought together both this quarter's earnings cycle and the Q3 IPO rush. So, it was just a little busy!]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/c466ab16-5d47-4cc8-b3ee-66ee9f0a4c75?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/equity/id1215439780">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>We were a smaller team this week, with <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> joined by <a href="https://twitter.com/gracedenhall">Grace</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/cgates123">Chris</a> to sort through a week that brought together both this quarter&#8217;s earnings cycle and the Q3 IPO rush. So, it was just a little busy!</p>
<p>Before we get to topics, however, a note that we are having a lot of fun recording these live on Twitter Spaces. We&#8217;ve found a hacky way to capture local audio and also share the chats live. So, <a href="http://twitter.com/equitypod">hit us up on Twitter</a> so you can hang out with us. It&#8217;s fun &#8212; and we may even bring you up on stage to play guest host.</p>
<p>OK, now, to the Great List of Subjects:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Robinhood went public!</strong> Yep, at long last, it is done. The company priced at $38 per share, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/robinhood-targets-ipo-valuation-up-to-35b-amid-warning-that-crypto-incomes-are-slipping/">the low end of its range</a>, and had a medium-weak day of trading once it started to float. In short, Robinhood seems to have deftly priced its IPO, leaving zero fat on the table. It&#8217;s now public and richer than ever. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/what-robinhoods-warnings-about-crypto-trading-say-about-coinbases-near-term-future/">More here</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Earnings! </strong>We took a moment to chat about earnings reports <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/alphabet-crushes-q2-earnings-estimates-as-google-cloud-cuts-losses-grows-54/">from Alphabet</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/microsoft-bests-earnings-estimates-as-azure-posts-51-growth-shares-fall/">Microsoft</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/shopifys-q2-results-beat-estimates-as-e-commerce-shines/">and Shopify</a>. Why? Because we care lots about the cloud and platform companies. So, we took a minute to discuss public cloud results and what Shopify got up to.</li>
<li><strong>Batteries!</strong> Tesla is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/what-teslas-bet-on-iron-based-batteries-means-for-manufacturers/">moving toward iron-based batteries </a>and is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/tesla-bhp-ink-supply-deal-for-nickel-ahead-of-demand-surge/">looking to source other materials direct</a>. At the same time, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/redwood-materials-raises-700m-to-expand-its-battery-recycling-operation/">battery recycling is raising lots of cash</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/troubled-ev-company-lordstown-motors-gets-400m-lifeline-in-stock-sale-agreement/">Nikola is not dead</a>. We call it two truths and a lie.</li>
<li><strong>Unicorns and soon-to-be&#8217;s</strong>: Contentful <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/contenful-raises-175m-from/">raised $175M at a $3B valuation from Tiger</a> for its content delivery service; Squire, a barbershop tech platform, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/squire-a-barbershop-tech-platform-triples-its-valuation-again-with-tiger-global/">tripled its valuation (again) with Tiger Global (again);</a> and Class squashed acquisition rumors <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/class-a-zoom-only-virtual-classroom-nears-unicorn-status-after-softbank-check/">with SoftBank Vision Fund II funding</a>,</li>
<li><strong>More venture rounds!</strong> To cap off our venture roundup, two neat healthtech investments stood out, namely rounds <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/oova-raises-1-2m-to-develop-a-better-at-home-kit-for-detecting-a-womans-best-time-to-conceive/">from Oova</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/2182193/">and Peppy.</a> Both startups agree with the idea that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/hormonal-health-is-a-massive-opportunity-where-are-the-unicorns/">hormonal health is a massive yet nascent opportunity</a>. (We did an entire show about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/the-imbalanced-landscape-of-hormonal-health/?tpcc=ECTW2020">the imbalanced world of hormone startups</a> if you&#8217;re interested).</li>
<li>We ended on a musical note, which, luckily for you all, didn&#8217;t include us singing: Meet <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/ascap-lab-highlights-a-quartet-of-early-stage-music-startups/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a quartet of early-stage music startups.</span></a></li>
</ul>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content"><em>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PDT, Wednesday, and Friday morning at 7:00 a.m. PDT, so subscribe to us on <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity">Overcast</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ">Spotify</a> and all the casts.</em></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/growth-is-not-enough/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183798</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
