<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 21:37:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Ford&#8217;s powerhouse F-150 Lightning pickup can actually power your house</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/daily-crunch-7/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/daily-crunch-7/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 22:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155656</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>It’s Thursday, everyone, and the technology and startup worlds were a mixed bag today. We learned about the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/so-long-internet-explorer-and-your-decades-of-security-bugs/">final death of Internet Explorer</a> (RIP), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/snap-announces-its-latest-generation-of-its-spectacles-a-streamlined-device-for-experience-the-world-in-ar/">new AR glasses from Snap</a>, fresh <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/new-cryptocurrency-irs-rules-2023-crypto/">cryptocurrency rules for the United States</a>, and even took the time <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/robotics-roundup-12/">to look into</a> all the pizza-robot startups. Hell, Ford even made the cut with its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/ford-unveils-the-f-150-lightning-its-all-electric-pickup-truck-that-will-start-under-40000/">new electric truck</a> that I secretly covet (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/ford-f-150-lightning-electric-pickup-truck-can-power-your-home-in-an-outage/">it can power your house if the grid goes down!</a>).</p>
<p>As always, we’ve collected the three key stories for the day below and then have a rapid-fire breakdown of startup and Big Tech news to follow. Let’s go! &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Consumer financial technology is <em>so</em> hot:</strong> With Berlin-based investing app Trade Republic <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/berlins-trade-republic-nabs-900m-led-by-sequoia-at-a-5b-valuation-to-take-its-neo-broker-app-across-europe/">raising $900 million</a> and Robinhood’s partial, first-quarter results <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/robinhoods-epic-q1-growth-explains-its-fundraising-boom/">looking strong</a>, your Twitter feed may feel all fintech, all the time. And with good reason, as startups in the niche are seeing huge customer demand, which is, in turn, making investors both public and private salivate.</li>
<li><strong>E-commerce roll-ups are raising jillions: </strong>The world is moving toward e-commerce at a rapid clip, which is leading to a host of startups raising piles of cash to buy, and consolidate brands that sell on popular digital platforms. It’s an arms race to own your wallet, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/factory14-raises-200m-to-jump-into-the-amazon-marketplace-roll-up-race/">Factory14 just put together $200 million</a> for its own effort. (More <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/berlins-razor-group-raises-400m-to-buy-and-scale-amazon-marketplace-merchants/">here</a>, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/berlin-brands-group-commits-302m-to-acquire-d2c-and-amazon-merchants/">here</a>.)</li>
<li><strong>Governments are not thrilled with cryptocurrencies:</strong> On the heels of news concerning fresh crackdowns on bitcoin and friends in China, the United States is looking “to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/new-cryptocurrency-irs-rules-2023-crypto/">put new requirements in place</a> that would make it easier for the government to see how money is moving around, including digital currencies,” Taylor reports.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups and VC</h2>
<p>The startup world is awash in capital these days, so we cannot get to all the latest venture capital rounds in one bloc. Here, however, are a few favorites from the day:</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/eanos-stella-wu-is-not-your-typical-construction-tech-startup-founder/"><strong>Eano raises $6M for its home renovation software</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Home renovations are hard because most of us are not trained project managers. Eano wants to make the process simpler for both homeowners and the folks hired to do the renovation work. Thank god.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/workrise-once-known-as-rigup-raises-300m-at-a-2-9b-valuation/"><strong>Workrise raises $300M for its workforce management platform</strong></a><strong>:</strong> With <a href="https://t.co/4ShhCP5Eqc">Procore’s IPO going well today</a>, and Workrise raising $300 million at roughly the same time, it appears to be a great time to build products for less sexy markets. Workrise, for example, “connects skilled laborers with infrastructure and energy companies looking to staff and manage projects efficiently.” With Franklin Templeton now an investor, it looks like it’s headed for an IPO in not too much time.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/pitch-a-platform-for-making-and-sharing-presentations-raises-85m-on-a-600m-valuation/"><strong>Pitch raises $85M to help folks build shareable presentations</strong></a><strong>: </strong>The push to build and fund software that may fit neatly into a remote or hybrid-work world continues today, with Pitch announcing a huge round at a $600 million valuation for what Ingrid describes as the “ability for people to create, collaborate on and share presentations with each other through an online-based interface.” Frankly that sounds cool.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/maven-series-a-a16z/"><strong>Maven raises $20M for its cohort-based professional classes</strong></a><strong>: </strong>The education technology VC rush continues, with Andreessen Horowitz leading a $20 million round into Maven, which Natasha reports “helps professionals teach cohort-based classes.” Notably Maven raised money via equity crowdfunding earlier in its life.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/chile-based-kredito-raises-4m-to-help-businesses-get-loans/"><strong>Kredito raises $4M to get loans for LatAm small businesses</strong></a><strong>:</strong> The fintech lending boom that has impacted consumers (BNPL and the like) and business is not stopping at the borders of the United States. Kredito is testament to that fact, putting together a new round to help get SMBs in Latin America access to credit.</p>
<h2>Chasing hype is human nature: The tyranny of startup trends</h2>
<p>The fear of missing out (FOMO) spreads faster than wildfire and often overwhelms rational decision-making.</p>
<p>In the VC community, investors look for lessons from disruptive startups they can use to identify other potential winners. But hype leads to bad decision-making, rushed due diligence and wishful thinking.</p>
<p>When and if those startups actually do well, &#8220;irrational FOMO takes over&#8221; because the initial assessment was based on bad information, says Victor Echevarria, a partner at Jackson Square Ventures. &#8220;Trends are addictive; to remain disciplined and avoid hype is to deny our innate instincts.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s natural for investors to follow the crowd, but in the race to the bottom, FOMO can be high-octane fuel.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BVkNE2CVY7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/chasing-hype-is-human-nature-the-tyranny-of-startup-trends/">Chasing hype is human nature: The tyranny of startup trends</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chasing hype is human nature: The tyranny of startup trends&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/chasing-hype-is-human-nature-the-tyranny-of-startup-trends/embed/#?secret=BVkNE2CVY7" data-secret="BVkNE2CVY7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> <em>You can sign up here</em></a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>Today’s Big Tech news comes from Microsoft, Google, Twitter and Snap. And TikTok. Enjoy:</p>
<p><strong>Twitter’s epic product run continues:</strong> The product news parade from Twitter continued today, with the social media company announcing a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/twitter-to-revamp-user-profiles-with-about-tab-support-for-pronouns-confirmed-status-and-more/">revamp to user profiles</a> and the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/twitter-opens-account-verification-applications-to-the-public-under-new-guidelines/">restarting of its verification process</a>. Between a rapid-fire rollout of its Clubhouse-competing Spaces product, or its media push with Revue and subscriptions, Twitter has been on a roll.</p>
<p><strong>Google didn’t learn from Microsoft’s retail experiment:</strong> Big Search is following Redmond into the IRL retail game that the latter company already gave up on. Which is a bummer as I kinda dug Microsoft stores. Regardless, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/google-is-opening-a-retail-store-in-new-york-this-summer/">read all about Google’s impending meatspace storefront here</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Microsoft lays Internet Explorer to rest: </strong>The death date of Internet Explorer has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/so-long-internet-explorer-and-your-decades-of-security-bugs/">been fixed for June, 2022</a>. So you have that long to fool around with the venerable, if comedically aged internet browser. Few will miss Internet Explorer, but it was a pretty key product in the rise of the web. Kinda like Yahoo. Even if Yahoo will ride <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/25/verizon-buys-yahoo-for-4-83-billion/">again</a> (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/18/oath-officially-becomes-verizon-media-group-on-january-8/">again</a>). <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/private-equity-firm-apollo-agrees-to-buy-verizon-media-assets-for-5-billion/">Again</a>.</p>
<p><strong>TikTok builds out way-late anti-bullying tooling: </strong>As the founder of its parent company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/zhang-yiming-steps-down-bytedance-ceo/">steps down</a> amidst a Chinese government crackdown on that country’s tech industry, TikTok is rolling out <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/tiktok-rolls-out-tools-to-bulk-delete-and-report-comments-block-users/">some long-awaited features</a> that should make its service a bit better to use. At long last.</p>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Email Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2154311" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2154311" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2154311" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg?w=680" alt="Intellect illustration" width="680" height="427" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg 7311w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg?resize=1536,964 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg?resize=2048,1286 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/experts_gearsinhead.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2154311" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Have you recently worked with an email marketer? We want to hear about your experience!</p>
<p><a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/oYNNmGpd">Fill out the survey here.</a></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants to help startups find the right expert for their needs. To do this, we’re building a shortlist of the top growth marketers.</p>
<p>The answers to this survey will help shape our editorial coverage as we begin to dive into email tools, privacy laws and more! Find more details at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/experts/">techcrunch.com/experts</a>.</p>
<h2>TC Eventful</h2>
<p>We&#8217;re excited to announce that <strong>Mate Rimac</strong> will be joining us at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=editorialpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=rimacpost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=Rimac&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</a>, a one-day virtual event that is scheduled June 9. We have a lot of ground to cover, from how he started a company outside of a traditional incubator or VC network to his upcoming 1,914 hp electric hypercar and plans for the company&#8217;s future.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="g8576o6kSq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/">TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TC Sessions: Mobility 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/embed/#?secret=g8576o6kSq" data-secret="g8576o6kSq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/daily-crunch-7/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155656</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Investors help Procore build a decacorn valuation in public debut</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/investors-help-procore-build-a-decacorn-valuation-in-public-debut/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/investors-help-procore-build-a-decacorn-valuation-in-public-debut/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 19:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[construction tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC News Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Real Estate and Proptech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[procore]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155584</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Procore is thus being valued like a high-growth, high-margin software company, but it is not one that anticipates a rapid ramp to profitability.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Watching construction tech software company Procore go public today <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/as-procore-looks-to-nearly-double-its-private-valuation-the-ipo-market-shows-signs-of-life/">after pricing above its range</a> makes the IPO slowdown look like the deceleration that wasn’t.</p>
<p>Investors quickly bid up the company&#8217;s value in trading, giving Procore a higher valuation than it might have anticipated, along with a boost of confidence for the IPO market in general.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Construction tech may not be as glamorous as space travel, but it’s a massive industry that&#8217;s fraught with inefficiencies.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Procore initially set an IPO range of $60 to $65 per share before pricing at $67 per share last night. Its debut was worth gross proceeds north of $600 million and a fully diluted<a href="https://www.renaissancecapital.com/IPO-Center/News/81944/Construction-software-provider-Procore-Technologies-prices-IPO-above-the-ra"> valuation of $9.6 billion</a>. As of early afternoon today, shares were trading at a solid $85.25.</p>
<p>In light of Procore’s debut, TechCrunch is digging quickly into the company’s new valuation and its resulting revenue multiples.</p>
<p>Following, we have notes from a chat we had with CEO <a href="https://twitter.com/tooeyprocore">Tooey Courtemanche</a> regarding his company’s debut, what it intends to do with its new capital and how it expects its partner platform to evolve and mature.</p>
<p>First, the numbers.</p>
<h2>Procore’s new price</h2>
<p>Starting with Procore’s $9.6 billion, fully diluted valuation that it set in its IPO pricing, the company is richly valued. It generated revenues of $113.9 million in Q1 2021, putting it on a run-rate of $455.8 million. As you can calculate, that valued the company at around 20x its run rate; more precisely, at 21.2x.</p>
<p>But if we do some modest extrapolation of the company’s current value in light of its trading appreciation, Procore is now worth around $12.3 billion on a fully diluted basis. That gives it a run-rate multiple of around 27x.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/investors-help-procore-build-a-decacorn-valuation-in-public-debut/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155584</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Factory14 raises $200M to jump into the Amazon marketplace roll-up race</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/factory14-raises-200m-to-jump-into-the-amazon-marketplace-roll-up-race/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/factory14-raises-200m-to-jump-into-the-amazon-marketplace-roll-up-race/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 19:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[factory14]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fulfilled by amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roll up]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155302</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It doesn&#8217;t feel like a week goes by at the moment that another startup doesn&#8217;t emerge armed with a huge wallet of cash to pursue a strategy of consolidating and then scaling promising brands that have built a business selling on marketplaces like Amazon&#8217;s. In the latest development, a startup called Factory14 is coming out [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It doesn&#8217;t feel like a week goes by at the moment that another startup doesn&#8217;t emerge armed with a huge wallet of cash to pursue a strategy of consolidating and then scaling promising brands that have built a business selling on marketplaces like Amazon&#8217;s. In the latest development, a startup called <a href="https://factory14.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Factory14</a> is coming out of stealth mode in Europe with $200 million in funding to snap up smaller businesses and help them grow through better economies of scale.</p>
<p>Along with this, Factory14 is also announcing its latest acquisition to underscore its acquisition strategy: it&#8217;s acquired <a href="https://www.probiketool.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pro Bike Tool</a>, a popular D2C seller of its own-brand bike accessories and tools, for an undisclosed sum. The company, which is now fully owned by Factory14, has kept the original founders on to lead the smaller company.</p>
<p>This is Factory14&#8217;s fourth acquisition since launching earlier this year, and the company said that its focus on acquiring marketplace sellers that are already seeing success and some scale means that it is already profitable.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup &#8212; based in Luxembourg and has offices in Madrid, London, Shanghai and Taipei &#8212; is describing this funding injection as a seed round, but in fact the majority of it is coming in the form of debt to acquire companies. Dmg Ventures (the VC arm of the Daily Mail Group) and DN Capital co-led the equity-based seed funding, with VentureFriends and unnamed individuals in the tech world also participating. Victory Park Capital, meanwhile, provided the credit facility and also participated in the equity consortium.</p>
<p>CEO Guilherme Steinbruch, an alum of Global Founders Capital (the investment firm co-founded by the Samwer brothers of Rocket Internet fame, among others), co-founded Factory14 with Marcos Ramírez (COO) and Gianluca Cocco (CBO) &#8212; who have respectively worked at e-commerce giants like Amazon and Delivery Hero.</p>
<p>Steinbruch himself also has an interesting background. He hails from Brazil and is a member of the <a href="https://s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/acuris-live/Steinbruch%20Shareholder%20Profile%202%20November_0.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">powerful industrial family</a> that controls a major steel producer, a leading textile producer and a bank (Steinbruch said that Factory14 has no connection to these, and is not an investor in the startup).</p>
<p>He said that the idea for founding Factory14 in Europe came out his interest in e-commerce and specifically the traction that Thrasio, one of the U.S. based the pioneers of the roll-up space, was seeing for the model.</p>
<p>The Marketplace on Amazon is a massive business. <a href="https://www.feedbackexpress.com/amazon-1029528-new-sellers-year-plus-stats/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">One estimate</a> puts the number of third-party sellers at 5 million, with more than 1 million sellers joining the platform in 2020 alone. Thrasio, meanwhile, has in the past <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/thrasio-raises-100m-for-its-amazon-roll-up-play-appoints-retail-cfo-heavyweight-for-its-next-steps/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">estimated to me</a> that there are probably 50,000 businesses selling on Amazon via FBA making $1 million or more per year in revenues.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the latter category that is the target for Factory14, Steinbruch told me. Its belief is that focusing on more successful businesses will mean a better hit rate on finding companies that have already built more solid supply chains, branding and overall quality. Being willing to pay a little more for these sellers, he said, will help it compete against what has become a very crowded field.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are many players, there is no denying it,&#8221; he said, adding that their research has (so far) found more than 50 roll-up players going for the same general opportunities that it is.</p>
<p>But in the process of planning out how Factory14 might differentiate itself in that mix, Steinbruch said it found some distinct differences.</p>
<p>&#8220;Some are looking for volume, and are willing to buy up many companies as cheaply as possible. But we took the decision to focus only on high-quality assets,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We knew we would have to pay higher multiples for a brand growing 200% a year, but when we started targeting these we were surprised to find there was less competition for these assets rather than for the smaller ones. That was a good surprise. It means that, yes, we have competition but we’ve managed to be pretty successful anyway.&#8221;</p>
<p>Even among the bigger retailers selling on Amazon using the e-commerce giant&#8217;s distribution and fulfillment platform, there are reasons for why the consolidators have started to circle beyond just wanting to jump on a good thing. The system has within it a lot of work is repeatable across many different companies, specifically in areas like analytics, supply chain management, marketing and more: building a framework that could handle those processes for many at once makes sense. There is also the fact that in many cases, marketplace sellers may have found themselves sitting on successful businesses but unable to source the investment (or the will) to scale them to the next step.</p>
<p>All the same, the mix of competitors hoping to scoop them up is a pretty formidable one, and the point of differentiation between them all may not in itself may not be as distinct as Factory14 (or any of them) hopes.</p>
<p>Just today, another ambitious player in this space, <a href="https://heyday.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heyday</a> out of San Francisco, today announced a further $70 million in equity funding led by General Catalyst. It, too, is raising large amounts of debt and eyeing up more innovative ways of accommodating the most interesting companies selling on Amazon a bid for more quality and success.</p>
<p>&#8220;The top 1.5% of marketplace sellers are doing $1 million in revenues, and we believe there may be some that cross the $1 billion threshold eventually,&#8221; Heyday CEO and co-founder Sebastian Rymarz told me last week. To woo the best of them in the current market, as part of its ambition to become the &#8220;P&amp;G&#8221; of the 21st century, it too is taking a very open-ended approach, he said.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have some come to Heyday, or we bring in our own brand managers. Sometimes it&#8217;s a matter of some ongoing participation and interest, growth equity where we buy some now and will buy more of your business over time. We are still defining that and that is fine, we are comfortable with that,&#8221; he said. &#8220;It&#8217;s about unique partnerships that we’re forming to accelerate their businesses.&#8221;</p>
<p>Closer to home in more ways than one, Berlin&#8217;s Razor Group &#8212; funded by Steinbruch&#8217;s former colleagues from GFC, and founded by ex-Rocket Internet people &#8212; earlier this month <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/berlins-razor-group-raises-400m-to-buy-and-scale-amazon-marketplace-merchants/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised $400 million</a>. Thrasio itself has raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/thrasio-raises-750m-more-in-equity-for-its-amazon-roll-up-play/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">very large rounds</a> in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/thrasio-raises-100m-for-its-amazon-roll-up-play-appoints-retail-cfo-heavyweight-for-its-next-steps/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rapid succession</a> totaling hundreds of millions of dollars in the last year, and is also profitable. Others in the same area that have also raised huge warchests include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/target-global-leads-150m-round-for-amazon-marketplace-consolidator-branded/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Branded</a>; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/heroes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroes</a>; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/sellerx-raises-118m-to-buy-up-and-grow-amazon-marketplace-businesses/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SellerX</a>; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/perch-raises-123-5m-to-grow-its-stable-of-d2c-brands-that-sell-on-amazon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Perch</a>; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/berlin-brands-group-commits-302m-to-acquire-d2c-and-amazon-merchants/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Berlin Brands Group</a> (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/berlin-brands-group-raises-240m-to-buy-and-scale-up-third-party-amazon-marketplace-brands/">X2</a>); <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/benitago-group-funding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Benitago</a>; Latin America&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/valoreo-raises-50m-to-roll-up-latam-e-commerce-brands/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Valoreo</a> (with its backers including Razor’s CEO), and an emerging group out of Asia including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/founded-by-former-carousell-ovo-and-fave-execs-rainforest-raises-36m-to-aggregate-asia-pacific-amazon-marketplace-sellers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rainforest</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/una-brands-launches-with-40m-to-acquire-brands-on-multiple-asia-pacific-e-commerce-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Una Brands</a>.</p>
<p>Even with all of this, there will be opportunities, these entrepreneurs believe, to bring together more disparate smaller e-commerce retailers to help them better leverage marketing, supply chains, analytics and wider business expertise to grow for the longer term, leveraging the marketplace model that has come to dominate how many shop online today.</p>
<p>Factory14 said it expects to have $20 million in &#8220;trailing twelve months&#8221; Ebitda by the end of 2021 and expects to double its team to 80 by that point too.</p>
<p>For as long as Amazon and its marketplace model remain, it seems investors will come with their checkbooks, too.</p>
<p>&#8220;E-commerce is undergoing structural changes which are enabling thousands of exciting new brands to be born every day,” said Manuel Lopo de Carvalho, CEO at dmg ventures, in a statement. &#8220;Factory14 can provide these brands with the tools, capital and expertise that enable them to play in the big leagues.”</p>
<p>Ian Marsh, principal at DN Capital, said that the VC did its homework before backing the startup, too. “We had discussions with most aggregators and were immediately impressed by factory14’s differentiated vision focused on strong consumer brands and the world-class team they have put together with top tier private equity investors combined with seasoned e-commerce executive and former Amazonians. We are excited to work with Guilherme, Marcos, Gianluca and the rest of the factory14 team to create brands that inspire consumers around the world.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/factory14-raises-200m-to-jump-into-the-amazon-marketplace-roll-up-race/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155302</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In the race for tech talent, the US should look to Mexico</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/in-the-race-for-tech-talent-the-us-should-look-to-mexico/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/in-the-race-for-tech-talent-the-us-should-look-to-mexico/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 18:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silicon Valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151828</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amid a backdrop of skyrocketing tech valuations, the U.S. tech sector should look to Mexico as a key growth market and partner. The time is now for the U.S. to tap into Mexico's surplus tech talent.
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Gustavo Parés</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/gustavo_pares">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Gustavo Parés is CEO of <a href="https://ndscognitivelabs.com/">NDS Cognitive Labs</a>, a leader in cognitive computing and AI business solutions. A professor at Instituto Tecnológico y de Estudios Superiores de Monterrey (ITESM), he's partnered with Microsoft, IBM and Google to deliver digital transformation and cognitive technology services.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/12/chatbots-spotlight-machine-learnings-trillion-dollar-potential/">Chatbots spotlight machine learning&#8217;s trillion-dollar potential</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The global tech sector is booming, and as technologies like cloud and AI accelerate their growth, the demand for tech talent outpaces supply globally. Specifically, the U.S. tech sector has seen unprecedented growth in recent years, with four tech firms reaching a $1 trillion market cap by the beginning of 2020 &#8212; all of which have seen double-digit growth since achieving a 13-digit valuation pre-pandemic.</p>
<p>One of the major factors in the growth and adoption of tech in the U.S. is the increasing focus on software as a service and broader digital transformations across industry sectors, which have accelerated due to the COVID-19 pandemic. As such, there is an insatiable appetite for quality tech talent in the U.S., with <a href="https://www.bls.gov/ooh/computer-and-information-technology/home.htm">projections</a> showing an 11% increase by 2029 from 2019 numbers, which amounts to over half a million new jobs.</p>
<p>Given that the U.S. <a href="https://www.pnas.org/content/116/14/6732">produces</a> only about 65,000 computer science graduates, there is a vast deficit in the tech talent market, which materialized as over <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/americas-got-talent-just-not-enough-in-it-11571168626?mod=hp_featst_pos1">900,000 unfilled IT and related positions</a> in 2019 alone. The problem is so vast that more than 80% of U.S. employers stated that recruiting for tech talent is a top business challenge, according to a <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/supply-of-analytics-workers-set-to-double-11556663406?mod=article_inline">survey</a> by top HR consulting firm Robert Half.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>Demand increasing for Mexican tech talent</h2>
<p>Mexico’s tech talent can help to fill the gaps left in a hypercompetitive U.S. market for tech workers. Unlike the U.S., <a href="https://www.ivemsa.com/industries/it-industry-in-mexico/">20% of Mexican college graduates have relevant engineering degrees</a>, amounting to over 110,000 per year, far surpassing the U.S. in technical talent. Investors and tech firms have noticed and are increasing operations in Mexico.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			20% of Mexican college graduates have relevant engineering degrees, amounting to over 110,000 per year, far surpassing the U.S. in technical talent.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Some have referred to the cities of Monterrey and Guadalajara as the “Silicon Valley of Latin America,” and while their tech sectors are also seeing tremendous growth, the pace falls short of Mexico’s talent production, leading to a surplus of highly trained and capable individuals in the tech sector. The cost of higher education in Mexico is far less than in the U.S., so we’re likely to see that talent surplus grow in the coming years.</p>
<p>Under current conditions, the U.S. has an incredible opportunity to capitalize on the surplus of tech talent in Mexico. Because tech jobs are more scarce than in the U.S., the cost of talent in Mexico is considerably less than in the U.S. or in Canada. In general, <a href="https://convertkit.s3.amazonaws.com/assets/documents/109149/2222545/Mexico_s_Tech_Salary_Report_-_Jun_2019.pdf?ck_subscriber_id=1259576897">talent in Mexico can be two to three times cheaper than in the U.S.</a> while still delivering outstanding quality and specialized experience.</p>
<p>More so than other Latin American countries, Mexico has the experience and economy to support a robust tech talent export ecosystem. In fact, <a href="https://www.gsb.stanford.edu/insights/mexico-city-latin-americas-future-tech-hub">Mexico City’s concentrated market</a> is larger than the sum total of every other Spanish-speaking country in Latin America. Specifically, <a href="https://www.worldbank.org/en/results/2017/11/01/moving-toward-a-knowledge-based-economy-improving-competitiveness-in-mexicos-information-technology-industry">Mexico’s IT outsourcing industry has been growing at an annual rate of 10%-15%</a> and is now considered the third-largest exporter of IT services.</p>
<p>What’s more, the U.S./Mexico relationship is seeing a refresh after several tumultuous years. With <a href="https://www.trade.gov/knowledge-product/exporting-mexico-market-overview#:~:text=Mexico%20ranked%20number%20one%20among,value%20of%20USD%20614.5%20billion.">Mexico ranked No. 1 among U.S. trade partners</a>, the political and economic mechanisms for investments and partnerships are in place. Technology leaders such as <a href="https://newsroom.cisco.com/press-release-content?type=webcontent&amp;articleId=1600815">Cisco</a> and <a href="https://www.eetimes.com/intel-to-invest-177m-in-guadalajara-design-center/#">Intel</a> have already set up shop in Mexico, demonstrating confidence in the country’s ability to support tech and economic growth.</p>
<h2>The benefits of proximity</h2>
<p>Mexico provides a number of benefits that make drawing from its talent surplus easier and more efficient. For one, Mexico’s time zones align with those in the U.S., enabling real-time collaboration at times that work best for both parties. Compare this to the time difference in India, which is over 12 hours ahead of California’s Silicon Valley.</p>
<p>Beyond the time difference, there are also many cultural similarities that make working with Mexico the clear choice for IT outsourcing. For example, the U.S. is home to more than 41 million native Spanish speakers, and plus over 12 million bilingual Spanish speakers, making <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-44201444#:~:text=How%20many%20Spanish%20speakers%20are,world%2C%20ahead%20of%20Spain%20itself.">the U.S. the second-largest Spanish-speaking country</a> after Mexico. While difficult to quantify, the number of consumer and cultural exports from Mexico to the U.S. also helps to build familiarity and solidarity between the two countries, which can only improve an already healthy relationship.</p>
<h2>New geopolitical considerations favor U.S.-Mexico ties</h2>
<p>The steady progression of America’s tech sector is now seen as a strategic priority at the federal level. Meanwhile, public and private sector decision-makers are more interested than ever in conducting business under favorable trade treaty terms with friendly governments amid a new climate of geopolitical uncertainty.</p>
<p>As the U.S. tech sector continues its explosive growth, technology companies in the U.S. will need to seek alternative means to supplement its in-demand tech workforce. Rather than turning to countries undergoing increased regulatory scrutiny, or distant talent bases requiring significant business travel, business leaders are looking to geographically close, diplomatically friendly nations. U.S. companies are finding Mexico’s status as a key business partner and strategic ally to be a massive value driver.</p>
<p>By 2030, <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/higher-technology-investment-and-digital-accessibility-to-position-mexico-as-an-innovation-hub-by-2025-300993540.html">the middle-class population in Mexico is expected to reach 95 million</a>, placing it in the top 10 countries with the highest share of global middle-class consumption. As the middle class rises, so will companies to meet their consumer needs, and, as such, Mexico’s own tech sector will grow and require significantly more tech talent, reducing or potentially eliminating Mexico’s talent surplus.</p>
<p>This is evidenced by the uptick in Mexico-based technology companies, such as Mexican used-car startup <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-mexico-kavak/mexican-used-car-startup-kavak-hits-4-billion-valuation-idUSKBN2BU0FH">Kavak</a>, which recently hit a $4 billion valuation. Amid an exciting backdrop of skyrocketing tech valuations and potential, the U.S. tech sector should look to Mexico as a key growth market and technology partner. The time is now for the U.S. to tap into the surplus of quality tech talent in Mexico.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YPzUUJVVYc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/founders-who-dont-properly-vet-vcs-set-up-both-parties-for-failure/">Founders who don&#8217;t properly vet VCs set up both parties for failure</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Founders who don&#8217;t properly vet VCs set up both parties for failure&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/founders-who-dont-properly-vet-vcs-set-up-both-parties-for-failure/embed/#?secret=YPzUUJVVYc" data-secret="YPzUUJVVYc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/in-the-race-for-tech-talent-the-us-should-look-to-mexico/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151828</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple launches an affiliate program for paid podcast subscriptions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/apple-launches-an-affiliate-program-for-paid-podcast-subscriptions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/apple-launches-an-affiliate-program-for-paid-podcast-subscriptions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 18:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affiliate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affiliate marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcasters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming service]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155470</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple last month unveiled its plans for paid podcast subscriptions in a newly redesigned Apple Podcasts app. Now, it&#8217;s introducing a new program that will help podcast creators grow their subscriber base: affiliate marketing. The company&#8217;s &#8220;Apple Services Performance Partner Program,&#8221; which already exists to help market other Apple services like Apple TV, Apple News, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple last month unveiled its plans for paid podcast subscriptions in a newly redesigned Apple Podcasts app. Now, it&#8217;s introducing a new program that will help podcast creators grow their subscriber base: affiliate marketing. The company&#8217;s &#8220;Apple Services Performance Partner Program,&#8221; which already exists to help market other Apple services like Apple TV, Apple News, and Apple Books, is today <a href="https://podcasters.apple.com/support/979-affiliate-program-for-podcasts">expanding</a> to include paid podcasts.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://podcasters.apple.com/support/979-affiliate-program-for-podcasts">new program</a> &#8212; &#8220;Apple Services Performance Partner Program for Apple Podcasts&#8221; (whew!) &#8212; <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">will be open to anyone, though the company believes it will make the most sense for publishers and creators who already have an audience and a number of marketing channels where they can share these new affiliate links. When users convert by clicking through one of the links and subscribe to a premium podcast, the partner will receive a one-time commission at 50% of the podcast subscription price, after the subscriber accumulates their first month of paid service.</span></p>
<p>So, for example, if a paid podcast was charging subscribers $5 per month, the commission would be $2.50. This commission would apply for every new subscriber that signed up through the affiliate channel, and there&#8217;s no cap.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Podcast creators can also use the affiliate links to promote their <em>own</em> paid programs, which would allow them to generate incremental revenue.</p>
<p>While anyone can <a href="https://partners.applemediaservices.com/vip/c639e75256bc44e1e0b3769b370e3bd6c3d553df8e9bfbe9f77fb3fd5329c43c">apply to join the affiliate program</a>, there is an approval process involved. This is mainly about keeping spammers out of the program, and ensuring that those signing up do have at least some marketing channels where they can distribute the links. The sign-up form asks for specific criteria &#8212; like how many channels are available and how the partner intends to use them to promote the affiliate links, among other things.</p>
<p>The program will be made available to anyone in the 170 countries and regions where paid podcasts subscriptions are being made available.</p>
<p>Once approved and signed in, affiliate partners will gain access to an online dashboard where they can create links (i.e. shortened URLs) much like any other affiliate program. They can also create multiple URLs for an individual podcast to make it easier to track how well different channels are performing. The URLs can be posted on their own, tied to a &#8220;Listen on Apple Podcasts&#8221; badge, or can be made available as a QR code. The latter may make more sense when live events return, as it could be printed on signage or in flyers that were distributed during a live taping, for example. It could also be used in other sorts of advertising, including both print and digital.</p>
<p>Though premium podcasts already existed, until more recently that often involved paying a podcaster directly to access a private RSS feed. Smaller services like Stitcher also used subscriptions to provide paying customers with a series of perks, like ad-free listening and exclusive content. The new efforts by both Apple and Spotify are focused on wooing creators to their platforms, where they&#8217;ll take a cut of the subscription revenues. Spotify is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/spotify-launches-paid-podcasts-through-new-anchor-feature/">waiving its 5% fee</a> for the first two years, while Apple <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/apple-unveils-podcast-subscriptions-and-a-redesigned-apple-podcasts-app/">is employing its usual model</a> of 30% in year 1 that drops to 15% in year two.</p>
<p>While people can begin to <a href="https://partners.applemediaservices.com/vip/c639e75256bc44e1e0b3769b370e3bd6c3d553df8e9bfbe9f77fb3fd5329c43c">enroll</a> in the new affiliate program starting today, paid podcasts aren&#8217;t actually launching until later this month, <a href="https://podcasters.apple.com/878-subscriptions">per Apple</a>. When they do, those enrolled in the affilate program will be able to create links and begin earning commissions on subscriptions.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/apple-launches-an-affiliate-program-for-paid-podcast-subscriptions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155470</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bain Capital Ventures raised $1.3 billion to fund young startups, but young VC firms, too</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/bvc_fund_nine/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/bvc_fund_nine/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 18:17:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aaref hilaly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Attentive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bain capital ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlockFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currency group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DocuSign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redis labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sarah Smith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SurveyMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiger Global Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154925</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bain Capital Ventures (BCV), the venture arm of the 37-year-old private equity firm Bain Capital, announced this morning that it has $1.3 billion more smackers to invest across two funds, a $950 million fund for seed and Series A deals and a $350 million fund for growth-stage opportunities. That amount is up slightly from late [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.baincapitalventures.com/">Bain Capital Ventures</a> (BCV), the venture arm of the 37-year-old private equity firm Bain Capital, announced this morning that it has $1.3 billion more smackers to invest across two funds, a $950 million fund for seed and Series A deals and a $350 million fund for growth-stage opportunities. That amount is up slightly from late 2018, when the outfit announced<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/14/bain-capital-ventures-has-a-fresh-1b-to-invest-in-startups/"> $1 billion</a> across two funds.</p>
<p>While the outfit is backed by all the usual suspects, including endowments and pension funds, it&#8217;s worth noting that around $130 million of that capital comes from investors and other employees inside of Bain, whose contributions typically make up 10% of a fund. (Investors at other firms like Sequoia are big investors in their funds, too.)</p>
<p>More important, of course, is where the capital will be spent. According to partners Sarah Smith and Aaref Hilaly, the focus remains very much on enterprise startups, where the team likes to jump in early and build up a big position. (Some of its biggest bets in terms of dollars invested right now include the text message marketing company Attentive, currently valued at <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/kenrickcai/2020/09/23/attentive-messaging-marketing-startup-series-d-billion-valuation/?sh=795b16b056c0">$2.2 billion</a>, and the in-memory database company Redis Labs, valued at <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/redis-labs-surpasses-2b-valuation-with-latest-funding-round/">$2 billion</a>.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Interestingly, BCV is also investing directly in a lot of emerging managers, 50 of whom BCV has already backed in order improve the diversity of ideas and startups that it gets to see at the earliest stages.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s all part of the firm&#8217;s continuing evolution, says the outfit, which got its start in 2001 on the East Coast and was designed initially to fund Series B and older companies but today funds mostly West Coast- and, to a smaller degree, New York-based startups that are just getting off the ground.</p>
<p>To underscore the shift, says Hilaly, BCV wrote checks to 42 companies last year and 37 of them were either seed-stage or Series A-stage startups and the &#8220;vast majority were pre-revenue.&#8221;</p>
<p>Asked if competition at the later-stage drove the firm to seek out more nascent deals, Hilaly notes that competition at every stage is intense right now and argues that BCV&#8217;s current team composition &#8212; Hilaly spent seven years at Sequoia and earlier founded a company himself; Smith spent a collective seven years at Quora and Facebook; partner Enrique Salem was a former president and CEO of Symantec, for example &#8212; makes it most impactful at the company formation stage, when founders are still getting the fundamentals down.</p>
<p>As for why the organization needs such a massive fund to back such young companies, it&#8217;s a reflection of the changing market, both partners suggest. Not only do firms need to be able to provide the capital that entrepreneurs need to grow at a faster clip than ever before, but it&#8217;s becoming increasingly important for venture outfits to support the ecosystem &#8212; including as a competitive edge.</p>
<p>For some firms, that support comes in the form of scout programs that empower operators and founders to write checks to friends who are starting companies.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gdAW20yPK2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/07/a-peek-inside-sequoia-capitals-low-flying-wide-reaching-scout-program/">A peek inside Sequoia Capital&#8217;s low-flying, wide-reaching scout program</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A peek inside Sequoia Capital&#8217;s low-flying, wide-reaching scout program&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/07/a-peek-inside-sequoia-capitals-low-flying-wide-reaching-scout-program/embed/#?secret=gdAW20yPK2" data-secret="gdAW20yPK2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>For BCV, it means committing an undisclosed but &#8220;material&#8221; amount of capital to emerging seed-fund managers. So far among the managers it has backed is Bobby Goodlatte of Form Capital of Miami, who we talked with recently (see below); Maren Bannon of London-based January Ventures; Ryan Hoover of Weekend Fund; Scribble Ventures, run in part by husband-and-wife duo Elizabeth and Kevin Weil; and Noemis Ventures in New York.</p>
<p>Smith says that BCV is &#8220;really excited about this program because it&#8217;s great for founders, who have more choice than ever as they&#8217;re getting started. It&#8217;s also helping on-ramp a broader group of investors into the venture ecosystem, which is something I&#8217;m personally passion about as I care about diversity of thought.&#8221;</p>
<p>Those newer funds &#8212; 17% of which are run by Black general partners and 21% of which are run by women &#8212;  also help BCV to stay atop the latest enterprise trends, she adds, saying that in addition to checks, BCV helps make limited partner introductions for managers to help get them off the ground. (BCV does not ask for any information rights beyond what the firms&#8217; other limited partners receive.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="94rsge2UXo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/bobby-goodlatte-has-designs-on-how-to-succeed-in-venture-and-so-far-so-good/">Bobby Goodlatte has designs on how to succeed in venture (and so far, so good)</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bobby Goodlatte has designs on how to succeed in venture (and so far, so good)&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/bobby-goodlatte-has-designs-on-how-to-succeed-in-venture-and-so-far-so-good/embed/#?secret=94rsge2UXo" data-secret="94rsge2UXo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As for where BCV will be funneling the rest of its new capital, Smith says that BCV has always been &#8212; and remains &#8212; thesis driven, and that much of what interests the firm right now is application software infrastructure, health tech investing, e-commerce-enabled enterprise tech, and fintech, including crypto, which has become a growing area of intrigue.</p>
<p>Some of the firm&#8217;s related deals include the crypto lending startup BlockFi and Digital Currency Group, the parent company behind the popular Grayscale Bitcoin Trust.</p>
<p>BCV has also invested in &#8220;a few tokens,&#8221; says Hilaly, &#8220;but that&#8217;s not the major focus,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="v08ctz9zP0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/blockfi-lands-a-350m-series-d-at-3b-valuation-for-its-fast-growing-crypto-lending-platform/">BlockFi lands a $350M Series D at a $3B valuation for its fast-growing crypto-lending platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BlockFi lands a $350M Series D at a $3B valuation for its fast-growing crypto-lending platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/blockfi-lands-a-350m-series-d-at-3b-valuation-for-its-fast-growing-crypto-lending-platform/embed/#?secret=v08ctz9zP0" data-secret="v08ctz9zP0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In the meantime, BCV &#8212; which is writing checks as small as several hundred thousand dollars to upwards of $100 million in companies &#8212; is also keeping an eye on the trends that continue to reshape the venture industry, including, right now, bigger and faster deals.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s unprecedented,&#8221; observes Hilaly of what&#8217;s happening in the market, even while he&#8217;s not surprised by it. &#8220;My general feeling is that venture is not so unlike startups, and every firm has to just reinvent itself every five or 10 years because the ecosystem around it is changing so much.</p>
<p>&#8220;You can complain about competition,&#8221; he continues, &#8220;but the reality is competition just forces you to be better.&#8221; Certainly, he says, &#8220;You have to you have to be on your game to a greater extent than ever before.&#8221; Otherwise, there&#8217;s &#8220;just no way a sensible founder would pick you.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/bvc_fund_nine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154925</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Snap announces a new generation of Spectacles, streamlined glasses to experience the world in AR</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/snap-announces-its-latest-generation-of-its-spectacles-a-streamlined-device-for-experience-the-world-in-ar/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/snap-announces-its-latest-generation-of-its-spectacles-a-streamlined-device-for-experience-the-world-in-ar/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 18:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spectacles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amid a pre-recorded Partner Summit where Snap took users through a whole set of new tools for Snapchat users, creators and companies, Snap also threw in a &#8220;one more thing&#8221; at the end that shows the company, after a rocky start several years ago, is definitely not giving up on its hardware ambitions anytime soon. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Amid a pre-recorded <a href="https://www.snappartnersummit.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Partner Summit</a> where Snap took users through a whole set of new tools for Snapchat users, creators and companies, Snap also threw in a &#8220;one more thing&#8221; at the end that shows the company, after a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/28/why-snapchat-spectacles-failed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rocky start several years ago</a>, is definitely not giving up on its hardware ambitions anytime soon.</p>
<p>Snap announced the latest generation of its Spectacles, a streamlined 60s-style design in black that is the company&#8217;s biggest play yet in merging some of the work its been building in augmented reality technology to a specific device tailored to work with it.</p>
<p>Evan Spiegel, Snap&#8217;s co-founder and CEO, described the Spectacles as the company&#8217;s &#8220;first pair of glasses that bring augmented reality to life,&#8221; and if you ever owned or tried out earlier versions of the glasses, it sounds like these are just more intuitive and seamless.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The fourth generation of these glasses will operate at 30 minutes at a time, he said, and will feature dual 3D waveguide displays, and a 26.3-degree diagonal field of view for an immersive lens experiences that &#8220;feel like they&#8217;re naturally overlaid on the world in front of you.&#8221; The glasses pack a lot of brightness to make them as usable inside and outside, and they come with built in microphones, stereo speakers and touchpad controls. They are also relatively light at 134 grams.</p>
<p>Snap seems to be marketing the device for creators on the Snap platform rather than consumers who the company has previously geared its hardware towards. Snap&#8217;s release embodies the strategy others have taken of building augmented reality tech in public even as the underlying tech is not quite ready for a mass market release.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2155669" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-1.40.17-PM.png" alt="" width="1024" height="600" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-1.40.17-PM.png 2326w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-1.40.17-PM.png?resize=150,88 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-1.40.17-PM.png?resize=300,176 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-1.40.17-PM.png?resize=768,450 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-1.40.17-PM.png?resize=680,398 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-1.40.17-PM.png?resize=1536,899 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-1.40.17-PM.png?resize=2048,1199 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-1.40.17-PM.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>The hardware itself is less capable than earlier releases from AR startups like Magic Leap, but Snap seems to have opted to sacrifice functionality for form factor, delivering a device that is less helmet-like than other augmented reality headsets.</p>
<p>Spiegel said that the glasses will feature the company&#8217;s new spatial engine, &#8220;which leverages six degrees of freedom, hand and surface tracking realistic ground digital objects in the physical world,&#8221; with 15 millisecond motion to photon latency for more responsiveness. The glasses are also integrated with Snap&#8217;s Lens Studio so that creators can build custom lenses for the devices. It&#8217;s rolled out the glasses already to a small group of early users, so expect to see these ship pre-populated with a range of lenses and other customizations.</p>
<p>Snap has long banked on augmented reality as a major opportunity but is still an underdog in the space given the size of its massive competitors.</p>
<p>The AR-capable Spectacles arrive ahead of Facebook&#8217;s upcoming smart glasses which the company has partnered with Ray Ban to produce. Those glasses are not expected to include built-in displays and will instead rely heavily on other forms of input. Apple has also long been rumored to be working on augmented reality glasses and reportedly has thousands of employees working to build them.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zahosDB0YY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/facebook-ar-glasses-2021/">Facebook is launching smart glasses in 2021, its &#8216;next step&#8217; to an AR device</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook is launching smart glasses in 2021, its &#8216;next step&#8217; to an AR device&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/facebook-ar-glasses-2021/embed/#?secret=zahosDB0YY" data-secret="zahosDB0YY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/snap-announces-its-latest-generation-of-its-spectacles-a-streamlined-device-for-experience-the-world-in-ar/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155565</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>US Treasury calls for stricter cryptocurrency rules, IRS reporting for transfers over $10K</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/new-cryptocurrency-irs-rules-2023-crypto/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/new-cryptocurrency-irs-rules-2023-crypto/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 18:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internal Revenue Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tax]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden&#8217;s vision for an empowered, expanded IRS is poised to have a big impact on cryptocurrency trading. According to a new report from the U.S. Treasury Department, the administration wants to put new requirements in place that would make it easier for the government to see how money is moving around, including digital currencies. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">President Biden&#8217;s vision for an empowered, expanded IRS is poised to have a big impact on cryptocurrency trading.</p>
<p>According to a <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/system/files/136/The-American-Families-Plan-Tax-Compliance-Agenda.pdf">new report from the U.S. Treasury Department</a>, the administration wants to put new requirements in place that would make it easier for the government to see how money is moving around, including digital currencies. The report notes that cryptocurrencies pose a &#8220;significant detection problem&#8221; and are used regularly by top earners who wish to evade taxes.</p>
<p>The proposed changes would create new reporting requirements built on the framework of existing 1099-INT forms that taxpayers currently use to report interest earned. Cryptocurrency exchanges and custodians would be required to report more information on the &#8220;gross inflows and outflows&#8221; of money moving through their accounts. Businesses would also be required to report cryptocurrency transactions above $10,000 under the new reporting requirements.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Although cryptocurrency is a small share of current business transactions, such comprehensive reporting is necessary to minimize the incentives and opportunity to shift income out of the new information reporting regime,&#8221; the report states.</p>
<p>The Treasury Department notes that wealthy tax filers are often able to escape paying fair taxes through complex schemes that the IRS currently doesn&#8217;t have the resources to disrupt. According to the report, the IRS collects 99% of taxes due on wages, but that number is estimated to be as low as 45% on non-labor income, a discrepancy that hugely benefits high earners with &#8220;less visible&#8221; income sources. The Treasury calls virtual currency, which has some reporting requirements but still operates mostly out of sight in regulatory grey areas, a particular challenge.</p>
<p>&#8220;These opportunities are particularly available for those in the top end of the income distribution who can avoid taxes through sophisticated strategies such as offshoring, creating complex partnership structures, or moving taxable assets into the crypto economy,&#8221; the Treasury report states.</p>
<p>The report details a multiyear effort to bolster IRS enforcement that would bring in as much as $700 billion in tax revenue over the next 10 years. The proposed changes, if implemented, would go into effect starting in 2023.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Y8b0ns5lBt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/29/coinbase-internal-revenue-service-taxation/">Coinbase ordered to give the IRS data on users trading more than $20,000</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Coinbase ordered to give the IRS data on users trading more than $20,000&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/29/coinbase-internal-revenue-service-taxation/embed/#?secret=Y8b0ns5lBt" data-secret="Y8b0ns5lBt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="d6yTbSQN8z"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/chasing-hype-is-human-nature-the-tyranny-of-startup-trends/">Chasing hype is human nature: The tyranny of startup trends</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chasing hype is human nature: The tyranny of startup trends&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/chasing-hype-is-human-nature-the-tyranny-of-startup-trends/embed/#?secret=d6yTbSQN8z" data-secret="d6yTbSQN8z" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/new-cryptocurrency-irs-rules-2023-crypto/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155553</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Portside raises $17M for its business aviation management platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/portside-raises-17m-for-its-business-aviation-management-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/portside-raises-17m-for-its-business-aviation-management-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 18:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expense management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fractional ownership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ownership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portside]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soma capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiger Global Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155509</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Portside, an aviation startup that is building a platform for managing the backend of a corporate flight department, charter operation, government fleet and fractional ownership operation, today announced that it has raised a $17 million funding round led by Tiger Global Management, with participation from existing investors I2BF Global Ventures and SOMA Capital. The idea [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.portside.co/">Portside</a>, an aviation startup that is building a platform for managing the backend of a corporate flight department, charter operation, government fleet and fractional ownership operation, today announced that it has raised a $17 million funding round led by Tiger Global Management, with participation from existing investors I2BF Global Ventures and SOMA Capital.</p>
<p>The idea behind Portside, which was founded in 2018, is that it lets business aviation companies and flight departments manage everything from flight operations to maintenance, crew and staff scheduling, expense management for crew members and staff, and financial data to help them operate <a href="https://www.portside.co/platform/">more efficiently</a>. It&#8217;s basically everything you need to run your flight department in a single solution, but it also <a href="https://www.portside.co/integrations/">integrates</a> with virtually all of the existing scheduling, accounting, expense management and maintenance tools a flight department or fractional ownership operation is likely using today.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2155530" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/portside.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2155530" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2155530" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/portside.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="497" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/portside.jpg 1241w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/portside.jpg?resize=150,73 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/portside.jpg?resize=300,146 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/portside.jpg?resize=768,373 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/portside.jpg?resize=680,330 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/portside.jpg?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2155530" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Portside</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While the COVID pandemic put a halt to most forms of private aviation early on, that market saw a quick rebound. Portside says it saw its revenue grow almost 300% in 2020 and that it added more than 50 aircraft operators in multiple countries to its user base.</p>
<p>&#8220;This infusion of new capital will be used to accelerate investment in product innovation, support further engagement with large enterprise customers and grow our global engineering and customer success teams,&#8221; said <span class="xn-person">Alek Vernitsky</span>, co-founder and CEO of Portside. &#8220;We appreciate the strong support we have received from both our existing and new investors in this round. They have collectively demonstrated their confidence in our strategy and intentional approach to cloud-based digital transformation of the global business aviation industry.&#8221;</p>
<p>Portside is not alone in this market. Companies like <a href="https://www.fl3xx.com/">Fl3xx</a>, for example, offer similar solutions for flight departments and at the lower end, tools like <a href="https://www.flightcircle.com/">Flight Circle</a> offer a subset of these features for general aviation clubs and partnerships.</p>
<p>“Portside has progressed rapidly since inception and is entering the next stage of fulfilling its vision of becoming the undisputed leader in cloud-based solutions for business aviation,” stated John Curtius, partner at Tiger Global Management. &#8220;In our view, Portside represents the future of the industry, and we are pleased to partner with a company we believe will continue to create significant value for many years to come.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oxe9H58bBr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/14/delta-air-lines-startup-partnerships-are-fueling-innovation/">Delta Air Lines&#8217; startup partnerships are fueling innovation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Delta Air Lines&#8217; startup partnerships are fueling innovation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/14/delta-air-lines-startup-partnerships-are-fueling-innovation/embed/#?secret=oxe9H58bBr" data-secret="oxe9H58bBr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/portside-raises-17m-for-its-business-aviation-management-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155509</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Snap emphasizes commerce in updates to its camera and AR platforms</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/snap-emphasizes-commerce-in-updates-to-its-camera-and-ar-platforms/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/snap-emphasizes-commerce-in-updates-to-its-camera-and-ar-platforms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 17:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Augmented Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[allrecipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[augmented reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Farfetch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instant Messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lens studio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playstation home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snap inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap Partner Summit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap Partner Summit 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vertical Video]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155514</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At Snap&#8217;s Partner Summit, the company announced a number of updates to the company&#8217;s developer tools and AR-focused Lens Studio, including several focused on bringing shopping deeper into the Snapchat experience. One of the cooler updates involved the company&#8217;s computer vision Scan product, which analyzes content in a user&#8217;s camera feed to quickly bring up [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At Snap&#8217;s Partner Summit, the company announced a number of updates to the company&#8217;s developer tools and AR-focused Lens Studio, including several focused on bringing shopping deeper into the Snapchat experience.</p>
<p>One of the cooler updates involved the company&#8217;s computer vision Scan product, which analyzes content in a user&#8217;s camera feed to quickly bring up relevant information. Snap says the feature is used by around 170 million users per month. Scan, which has now been given more prominent placement inside the camera section of the app, has been upgraded with commerce capabilities with a feature called Screenshop.</p>
<p>Users can now use their Snap Camera to scan a friend&#8217;s outfit, after which they&#8217;ll quickly be served up shopping recommendations from hundreds of brands. The company is using the same technology for another upcoming feature that will allow users to snap pictures of ingredients in their kitchen and get served recipes from Allrecipes that integrate them.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The features are part of a broader effort to intelligently suggest lenses to users based on what their camera is currently focused on.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2155556" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Allrecipes-Scan.png" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Allrecipes-Scan.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Allrecipes-Scan.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Allrecipes-Scan.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Allrecipes-Scan.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Allrecipes-Scan.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Allrecipes-Scan.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Allrecipes-Scan.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>Businesses will now be able to establish public profiles inside Snapchat, where users can see all of their different offerings, including Lenses, Highlights, Stories and items for sale through Shop functionality.</p>
<p>On the augmented reality side, Snap is continuing to emphasize business solutions with API integrations that make lenses smarter. Retailers will be able to use the Business Manager to integrate their product catalogs so that users can only access try-on lenses for products that are currently in stock.</p>
<p>Partnerships with luxury fashion platform Farfetch and Prada will tap into further updates to the AR platform, including technical 3D mesh advances that make trying on clothing virtually appear more realistic. Users will also be able to use voice commands and visual gestures to cycle between items they&#8217;re trying on in the new experiences.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re excited about the power of our camera platform to bring Snapchatters together with the businesses they care about in meaningful ways,&#8221; said Snap&#8217;s global AR product lead Carolina Arguelles Navas. &#8220;And, now more than ever, our community is eager to experience and try on, engage with, and learn about new products, from home.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/snap-emphasizes-commerce-in-updates-to-its-camera-and-ar-platforms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155514</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Snap brings partner-centric Layers to its social map used by 250 million people</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/snap-brings-partner-centric-layers-to-its-social-map-used-by-250-million-people/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/snap-brings-partner-centric-layers-to-its-social-map-used-by-250-million-people/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 17:36:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google-Maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instant Messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snap inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap Partner Summit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap Partner Summit 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TicketMaster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vertical Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WeChat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155466</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Snap wants users to get a more personal view of the world around them. While products like Google Maps and Apple Maps have long-relied on data partners to juice the quality of their contextual insights, Snap is hoping it can give users a more hands-on approach to mixing and matching third-party tie-ins to its Snap [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Snap wants users to get a more personal view of the world around them.</p>
<p>While products like Google Maps and Apple Maps have long-relied on data partners to juice the quality of their contextual insights, Snap is hoping it can give users a more hands-on approach to mixing and matching third-party tie-ins to its Snap Map product, allowing users to build a view of their geographic surroundings tailored to their interests.</p>
<p>The new product &#8212; announced today at the company&#8217;s Snap Partner Summit &#8212; is called Layers and it allows users to add data from some of Snap&#8217;s chosen developer partners directly to their map so they can see the world in a very particular view.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Layers are how the Map evolves from a singular product to a platform,&#8221; Snap&#8217;s Bryant Detwiller tells TechCrunch. &#8220;Ultimately, we just want our map to be more useful.&#8221;</p>
<p>Snap Map has aimed to be a fundamentally social product, designed around people and friends rather than cars and directions. Layers will theoretically allow its users some customization in deciding which points-of-interest they want their map to be structured around.</p>
<p>The company says that Snap Map has some 250 million monthly active users.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2155506" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2155506" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2155506 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Map-Layers-and-Minis_Ticketmaster.png" alt="" width="1024" height="575" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Map-Layers-and-Minis_Ticketmaster.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Map-Layers-and-Minis_Ticketmaster.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Map-Layers-and-Minis_Ticketmaster.png?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Map-Layers-and-Minis_Ticketmaster.png?resize=768,431 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Map-Layers-and-Minis_Ticketmaster.png?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Map-Layers-and-Minis_Ticketmaster.png?resize=1536,862 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Map-Layers-and-Minis_Ticketmaster.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2155506" class="wp-caption-text">Ticketmaster integration via Snap</p></div></p>
<p>Like Snap&#8217;s approach with its WeChat-like Minis and Games, it&#8217;s starting things off pretty slowly when it comes to partnerships. It has two out of the gate &#8212; a partnership with Ticketmaster and restaurant review site The Infatuation.</p>
<p>With the Ticketmaster Layer, users will be able to sort through shows at nearby concert venues and can get transferred from the Layer directly to a new Ticketmaster Mini to buy tickets inside the Snapchat app. With The Infatuation, users can scan the map for editorialized recommendations for nearby restaurants with lists and reviews from the site. More of these partnerships on the way, though it doesn&#8217;t sound like Snap is planning to open the floodgates to developers anytime soon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/snap-brings-partner-centric-layers-to-its-social-map-used-by-250-million-people/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155466</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Snap announces Story Studio, a new standalone app to edit stories</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/snap-announces-story-studio-a-new-standalone-app-to-edit-stories/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/snap-announces-story-studio-a-new-standalone-app-to-edit-stories/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 17:35:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap Partner Summit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap Partner Summit 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story studio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155521</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During Snap Partner Summit, Snap announced a brand new app focused on creators. Named Story Studio, this standalone iOS app gives you several editing tools so you can make your content look as professional as possible. Story editing tools are still in Snapchat — nothing is changing on this front. But if you’ve been creating [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">During <a href="https://snappartnersummit.com">Snap Partner Summit</a>, Snap announced a brand new app focused on creators. Named Story Studio, this standalone iOS app gives you several editing tools so you can make your content look as professional as possible.</p>
<p>Story editing tools are still in Snapchat — nothing is changing on this front. But if you’ve been creating content for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/snapchat-launches-a-tiktok-like-feed-called-spotlight-kick-started-by-paying-creators/">Spotlight</a>, a TikTok-like feed, or if you&#8217;re a Snap star, you may need more powerful editing tools. Many creators choose to edit their stories on a computer.</p>
<p>But many creators also want to do everything on their phones. That’s why there are already a few powerful video editing tools out there. But Snap is making its own app so that it works better with Snapchat.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>With Story Studio, you can see what’s trending on Snapchat already. It includes sounds, topics and lenses. This way, you can remix popular content and create your own take on the current meme.</p>
<p>Snap says that Story Studio lets you trim your shots with frame-precise editing. You can add captions, stickers and other visual elements. You can also take advantage of the company’s licensed music catalog.</p>
<p>And because it’s supposed to be a serious app for serious stories, you can save a project and edit it later.</p>
<p>When you’re done, you can share your video with Snapchat — you can use it to post a story or a Spotlight video. But Story Studio is also going to work with other platforms. You can save it to your camera roll or export your video to other apps on your phone.</p>
<p>Story Studio is launching later this year. It’s going to be available on iOS exclusively for now.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2155525" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2155525" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2155525" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Story-Studio_GIF.gif" alt="" width="800" height="450" /><p id="caption-attachment-2155525" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Snap</p></div></p>
<h2>Send a gift to your favorite creator</h2>
<p>While Snapchat started as an app to chat with your friends, it’s clear that the company now wants to attract a generation of creators with the right tools and monetization options. Creators have become a competitive space for social apps, such as TikTok, Instagram, YouTube with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/youtube-announces-a-100m-fund-to-reward-top-youtube-shorts-creators-over-2021-2022/">YouTube Shorts</a> and Snapchat.</p>
<p>Snap&#8217;s own take on short viral videos have been working relatively well so far. Spotlight reaches 125 million monthly active users on Snapchat. The number of users watching at least 10 minutes of Spotlight per day has grown by 70% between January and March.</p>
<p>In addition to Story Studio, Snap is launching a <a href="https://story.snapchat.com/spotlight">web platform</a> for Spotlight. This way, people can watch Spotlight content without launching Snapchat even when they’re browsing the web on their desktop computer. It could be a way to attract new Snapchat users as well.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UhkUNYVis9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/12/snapchat-looks-to-maintain-its-own-friendships-with-devs/">Snapchat looks to maintain its own friendships &#8212; with devs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Snapchat looks to maintain its own friendships &#8212; with devs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/12/snapchat-looks-to-maintain-its-own-friendships-with-devs/embed/#?secret=UhkUNYVis9" data-secret="UhkUNYVis9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But creators in particular are going to like this website as you can upload videos to Spotlight from Chrome or Safari.</p>
<p>When it comes to monetization, Snap is distributing $1 million every day to Snapchat users who create the top Snaps for Spotlight — 5,400 creators have earned $130 million since November 2020. The company will stop giving away $1 million per day on June 1st. Snap only says it plans to give millions every month.</p>
<p>But creators will be able to start accepting gifts directly on Snapchat. When Snapchat users reply to a story, they can buy Snap Tokens and send them as a gift — a virtual item with real-life value. The company hasn’t detailed how it plans to split revenue between Snap and creators. Gifting will roll out on Android and iOS later this year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/snap-announces-story-studio-a-new-standalone-app-to-edit-stories/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155521</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Esper raises $30M Series B for its IoT DevOps platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/esper-raises-30m-series-b-for-its-iot-devops-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/esper-raises-30m-series-b-for-its-iot-devops-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 17:31:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ambient intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[device management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[esper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet of Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IoT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[madrona venture group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile device management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Root Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scale venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubiquity Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155473</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There may be billions of IoT devices in use today, but the tooling around building (and updating) the software for them still leaves a lot to be desired. Esper, which today announced that it has raised a $30 million Series B round, builds the tools to enable developers and engineers to deploy and manage fleets [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There may be billions of IoT devices in use today, but the tooling around building (and updating) the software for them still leaves a lot to be desired. <a href="https://esper.io/">Esper</a>, which today <a href="https://blog.esper.io/esper-announces-series-b-funding">announced</a> that it has raised a $30 million Series B round, builds the tools to enable developers and engineers to deploy and manage fleets of Android-based edge devices. The round was led by Scale Venture Partners, with participation from Madrona Venture Group, Root Ventures, Ubiquity Ventures and Haystack.</p>
<p>The company argues that there are thousands of device manufacturers who are building these kinds of devices on Android alone, but that scaling and managing these deployments comes with a lot of challenges. The core idea here is that Esper brings to device development the DevOps experience that software developers now expect. The company argues that its tools allow companies to forgo building their own internal DevOps teams and instead use its tooling to scale their Android-based IoT fleets for use cases that range from digital signage and kiosks to custom solutions in healthcare, retail, logistics and more.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“The pandemic has transformed industries like connected fitness, digital health, hospitality, and food delivery, further accelerating the adoption of intelligent edge devices. But with each new use case, better software automation is required,&#8221; said Yadhu Gopalan, CEO and co-founder at Esper. &#8220;Esper’s mature cloud infrastructure incorporates the functionality cloud developers have come to expect, re-imagined for devices.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2155500" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/esper.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2155500" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2155500" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/esper.gif" alt="" width="800" height="450" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2155500" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Esper</p></div></p>
<p>Mobile device management (MDM) isn&#8217;t exactly a new thing, but the Esper team argues that these tools weren&#8217;t created for this kind of use case. &#8220;MDMs are the solution now in the market. They are made for devices being brought into an environment,&#8221; Gopalan said. &#8220;The DNA of these solutions is rooted in protecting the enterprise and to deploy applications to them in the network. Our customers are sending devices out into the wild. It’s an entirely different use case and model.&#8221;</p>
<p>To address these challenges, Esper offers a range of tools and services that includes a full development stack for developers, cloud-based services for device management and <a href="https://esper.io/hardware?wishlist=">hardware emulators</a> to get started with building custom devices.</p>
<p><span class="il">&#8220;Esper</span> helped us launch our Fusion-connected fitness offering on three different types of hardware in less than six months,&#8221; said Chris Merli, founder at Inspire Fitness. &#8220;Their full stack connected fitness Android platform helped us test our application on different hardware platforms, configure all our devices over the cloud, and manage our fleet exactly to our specifications. They gave us speed, Android expertise, and trust that our application would provide a delightful experience for our customers.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company also offers solutions for running <a href="https://esper.io/android-x86">Android on older x86 Windows devices</a> to extend the life of this hardware, too.</p>
<p>&#8220;We spent about a year and a half on building out the infrastructure,&#8221; said Gopalan. &#8220;Definitely. That&#8217;s the hard part and that&#8217;s really creating a reliable, robust mechanism where customers can trust that the bits will flow to the devices. And you can also roll back if you need to.&#8221;</p>
<p>Esper is working with hardware partners to launch devices that come with built-in Esper-support from the get-go.</p>
<p>Esper says it saw 70x revenue growth in the last year, an 8x growth in paying customers and a 15x growth in devices running Esper. Since we don&#8217;t know the baseline, those numbers are meaningless, but the investors clearly believe that Esper is on to something. Current customers include the likes of <span style="font-weight: 400;">CloudKitchens, Spire Health, Intelity, Ordermark, Inspire Fitness, RomTech and Uber.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FFzQUMx3MD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/15/iot-solutions-are-enabling-social-distancing/">IoT solutions are enabling physical distancing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;IoT solutions are enabling physical distancing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/15/iot-solutions-are-enabling-social-distancing/embed/#?secret=FFzQUMx3MD" data-secret="FFzQUMx3MD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/esper-raises-30m-series-b-for-its-iot-devops-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155473</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to ensure data quality in the era of Big Data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/how-to-ensure-quality-in-the-era-of-big-data/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/how-to-ensure-quality-in-the-era-of-big-data/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 17:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big data analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big data revolution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data quality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Cloud and Enterprise Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startups big data]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154571</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the evident need for solutions to ensure high data quality in the Big Data era, the space has received a lot of attention — especially during the past year.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Patrik Liu Tran</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Patrik Liu Tran is the co-founder and CEO of <a href="http://validio.io/">Validio</a>, an automated real-time data validation and quality monitoring platform. He holds a Ph.D. in Business Administration (as well as an M.Sc. and B.Sc.) from Stockholm School of Economics, and a Civil Engineering degree in Engineering Physics with an M.Sc. in AI and machine learning from KTH Royal Institute of Technology. Patrik is also the chairman of Stockholm AI.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">A little over a decade has passed since <a href="https://www.economist.com/leaders/2010/02/25/the-data-deluge">The Economist warned us</a> that we would soon be drowning in data. The modern data stack has emerged as a proposed life-jacket for this data flood — spearheaded by Silicon Valley startups such as Snowflake, Databricks and Confluent.</p>
<p>Today, any entrepreneur can sign up for BigQuery or Snowflake and have a data solution that can scale with their business in a matter of hours. The emergence of cheap, flexible and scalable data storage solutions was largely a response to changing needs spurred by the massive explosion of data.</p>
<p>Currently, the world produces<a href="https://techjury.net/blog/how-much-data-is-created-every-day/#:~:text=But%20if%20we're%20talking,1.145%20trillion%20MB%20per%20day."> 2.5 quintillion bytes of data daily</a> (there are 18 zeros in a quintillion). The explosion of data continues in the roaring ‘20s, both in terms of generation and storage — the amount of stored data is <a href="https://www.sdxcentral.com/articles/news/stored-data-doubling-every-4-years-idc-says/">expected to continue to double at least every four years</a>. However, one integral part of modern data infrastructure still lacks solutions suitable for the Big Data era and its challenges: Monitoring of data quality and data validation.</p>
<p>Let me go through how we got here and the challenges ahead for data quality.</p>
<h2>The value vs. volume dilemma of Big Data</h2>
<p>In 2005, Tim O’Reilly published his groundbreaking article &#8220;What is Web 2.0?&#8221;, truly setting off the Big Data race. The same year, Roger Mougalas from O’Reilly introduced the term &#8220;Big Data&#8221; in its modern context  —  referring to a large set of data that is virtually impossible to manage and process using traditional BI tools.</p>
<p>Back in 2005, one of the biggest challenges with data was managing large volumes of it, as data infrastructure tooling was expensive and inflexible, and the cloud market was still in its infancy (AWS didn’t publicly launch until 2006). The other was speed: As Tristan Handy from Fishtown Analytics (the company behind dbt) <a href="https://blog.getdbt.com/future-of-the-modern-data-stack/">notes</a>, before Redshift launched in 2012, performing relatively straightforward analyses could be incredibly time-consuming even with medium-sized data sets. An entire data tooling ecosystem has since been created to mitigate these two problems.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2154879" style="width: 1791px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2154879" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2154879 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1-The-emergence-of-the-modern-data-stack-Validio.png" alt="The emergence of the modern data stack (example logos &amp; categories)" width="1781" height="994" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1-The-emergence-of-the-modern-data-stack-Validio.png 1781w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1-The-emergence-of-the-modern-data-stack-Validio.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1-The-emergence-of-the-modern-data-stack-Validio.png?resize=300,167 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1-The-emergence-of-the-modern-data-stack-Validio.png?resize=768,429 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1-The-emergence-of-the-modern-data-stack-Validio.png?resize=680,380 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1-The-emergence-of-the-modern-data-stack-Validio.png?resize=1536,857 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1-The-emergence-of-the-modern-data-stack-Validio.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1781px) 100vw, 1781px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2154879" class="wp-caption-text">The emergence of the modern data stack (example logos and categories). <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Validio</p></div></p>
<p>Scaling relational databases and data warehouse appliances used to be a real challenge. Only 10 years ago, a company that wanted to understand customer behavior had to buy and rack servers before its engineers and data scientists could work on generating insights. Data and its surrounding infrastructure was expensive, so only the biggest companies could afford large-scale data ingestion and storage.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			The challenge before us is to ensure that the large volumes of Big Data are of sufficiently high quality before they&#8217;re used.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Then came a (Red)shift. In October 2012, AWS presented the first viable solution to the scale challenge with Redshift — a cloud-native, massively parallel processing (MPP) database that anyone could use for a monthly price of a pair of sneakers ($100) — about 1,000x cheaper than the previous &#8220;local-server&#8221; setup. With a price drop of this magnitude, the floodgates opened and every company, big or small, could now store and process massive amounts of data and unlock new opportunities.</p>
<p>As Jamin Ball from Altimeter Capital <a href="https://cloudedjudgement.substack.com/p/the-rise-of-dataops-and-the-analytical">summarizes</a>, Redshift was a big deal because it was the first cloud-native OLAP warehouse and reduced the cost of owning an OLAP database by orders of magnitude. The speed of processing analytical queries also increased dramatically. And later on (Snowflake pioneered this), they separated computing and storage, which, in overly simplified terms, meant customers could scale their storage and computing resources independently.</p>
<p>What did this all mean? An explosion of data collection and storage.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/how-to-ensure-quality-in-the-era-of-big-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154571</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eano&#8217;s Stella Wu is not your typical construction tech startup founder</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/eanos-stella-wu-is-not-your-typical-construction-tech-startup-founder/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/eanos-stella-wu-is-not-your-typical-construction-tech-startup-founder/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 16:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[builders vc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[construction tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[danny zhang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eano]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home improvement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Houston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jim Kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NewFund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proptech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seattle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wish]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155452</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Renovating a home is an exciting, yet often fraught-filled, endeavor. One startup that aims to help make the process simpler, cheaper and less stressful by helping people manage the home renovation process has raised $6 million to help it grow even faster. Builders VC led the round, which included participation from Celtic, Newfund and Wish co-founder Danny [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Renovating a home is an exciting, yet often fraught-filled, endeavor.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One startup that aims to help make the process simpler, cheaper and less stressful by helping people manage the home renovation process has raised $6 million to help it grow even faster. Builders VC led the round, which included participation from Celtic, Newfund and Wish co-founder Danny Zhang, who also sits on Eano&#8217;s board.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stella Wu, who formerly worked as a growth product manager at Wish, got firsthand experience of the pain points related to the process when she bought her own house in 2017.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I realized there were a lot of fragmented issues in the renovation space, especially when it came to the individual workers,” she recalls. “They were not reliable and bad at communication.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So in 2019 she founded </span><a href="https://www.eano.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eano</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a San Francisco-based startup that aims to walk a homeowner through a renovation and help connect individual contractors with new clients. Eano also works on projects like building ADUs (accessory dwelling units).</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6j5LIOCeSj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/construction-tech-startups-are-poised-to-shake-up-a-1-3-trillion-dollar-industry/">Construction tech startups are poised to shake up a $1.3-trillion-dollar industry</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Construction tech startups are poised to shake up a $1.3-trillion-dollar industry&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/construction-tech-startups-are-poised-to-shake-up-a-1-3-trillion-dollar-industry/embed/#?secret=6j5LIOCeSj" data-secret="6j5LIOCeSj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As more people spent time at home last year due to the COVID-19 pandemic, the startup saw its contract revenue spike by 5x, Wu says. And in the first quarter of this year, business was up 70% year over year.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2155455" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2155455" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2155455 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_2597.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="270" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_2597.jpg 1470w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_2597.jpg?resize=150,135 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_2597.jpg?resize=300,270 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_2597.jpg?resize=768,692 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_2597.jpg?resize=680,613 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_2597.jpg?resize=50,45 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2155455" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Eano CEO and founder Stella Wu / Eano</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eano, she said, offers competitive and transparent pricing so that homeowners aren’t surprised as a remodeling project goes on. Its automated process tracks all communications and progress in one place and the company has grown what it describes as a “network of experienced, local professionals” that are fully licensed, vetted and insured that it pairs homeowners with on projects.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There’s all these individual contractors out there and even though they are very affordable, it’s very hard for them to get to the homeowners, as they don’t have much resources,” Wu, a Chinese immigrant, told TechCrunch. “So they come to us and we basically take care of it all.” For now, Eano is operating in the Bay Area and Los Angeles, with plans to expand to Seattle and Houston this year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company plans to take its new capital and “go deep into the product side.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once they become a client, homeowners can use Eano to select a certain remodeling package, and then they can check the project progress, communicate with the team and even see the progress through videos.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re also helping contractors make communicating and receiving payment much easier,” Wu said. “We’re also helping these individual contractors increase the brand, and helping them with the administration and customer support side with our software.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jim Kim of Builders VC, said he first encountered Wu and Jung while they were at Wish.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We invest in people, and when you can find extremely talented entrepreneurs who have built successful companies and still have the hunger to win, you jump in with a blank check,” he said. “We love Eano&#8217;s mission &#8212; combining a similar product sourcing strategy as Wish with technology to bring a better experience to all constituents in the antiquated construction industry.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kim is also impressed by the fact that Wu is driven to prove “that you don&#8217;t need to be a 55-year-old man wearing steel-toed boots to have a meaningful impact on construction.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We love that ethos &#8212; it matches with our thinking about backing entrepreneurs who don&#8217;t fit into the stereotypical box,” Kim said.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/eanos-stella-wu-is-not-your-typical-construction-tech-startup-founder/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155452</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Electric hypercar phenom and founder Mate Rimac is heading to TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/electric-hypercar-phenom-and-founder-mate-rimac-is-heading-to-tc-sessions-mobility-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/electric-hypercar-phenom-and-founder-mate-rimac-is-heading-to-tc-sessions-mobility-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 16:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hypercar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hyundai Motor Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mate Rimac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Porsche]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rimac automobili]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions: Mobility 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153341</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A decade ago, Rimac Automobili was a one-person startup in a garage. Today, the EV and technology company founded by Mate Rimac employs more than 1,000 people, has partnerships with Porsche and Hyundai Motor Group and is on track to launch its 1,914 hp, all-electric C_Two hypercar this year. If that weren&#8217;t enough, Rimac also [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A decade ago, <strong>Rimac Automobili</strong> was a one-person startup in a garage. Today, the EV and technology company founded by Mate Rimac employs more than 1,000 people, has partnerships with Porsche and Hyundai Motor Group and is on track to launch its 1,914 hp, all-electric C_Two hypercar this year.</p>
<p>If that weren&#8217;t enough, Rimac also launched a subsidiary company, Greyp Bikes, to produce electrically assisted bicycles. It&#8217;s a notable run for a company that Mate Rimac founded after converting a 1984 BMW into an electric vehicle that at one time was the fastest in the world. What makes it remarkable is he started the company in Croatia and at the time lacked the typical network found in Silicon Valley.</p>
<p>&#8220;Ten years ago today, I was still like one guy in a garage and we did this in a location in Croatia where there is not a lot of technology or industry in general,&#8221; he said in an interview with TechCrunch earlier this year. &#8220;So it was crazy, I didn&#8217;t have a single venture capital fund. There were no tech startups. There was no industry in general, not just like automotive, but industry as such. So, there was no talent, there were no buildings we could use. So, we had a very tough upcoming, and was very hard for us to start we were just surviving and, you know from month to month and trying to pay the bills and most of the times we were struggling with that so the first six or seven years of our life most of the time for me was focusing on keeping the company going and how the hell I&#8217;m going to pay the next payroll or the next rent and stuff like that.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Rimac overcame those challenges, gaining Porsche and Hyundai as investors and importantly, generating revenue from the beginning — and even profits.</p>
<p>And Mate Rimac isn&#8217;t done.</p>
<p>The founder and CEO recently unveiled a design for new headquarters in Croatia that will include an on-site test track, an R&amp;D and production facility, museum, gym and daycare for employees &#8212; and even on-site organic food production and farm animals. The complex, which is expected to be completed by 2023, will allow the company to ramp up from prototype and smaller projects to high-volume production of its high-performance electric drivetrain and battery systems for customers that include Porsche, Hyundai-Kia, SEAT, Renault and Pininfarina.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re excited to announce that Mate Rimac will be joining us at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=editorialpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=rimacpost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=Rimac&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</strong></a>, a one-day virtual event that is scheduled June 9. We have a lot of ground to cover with Mate Rimac, from how he started a company outside of a traditional incubator or VC network, his upcoming electric hypercar and plans for the company&#8217;s future.</p>
<p>In case, you&#8217;re not familiar, each year we bring together engineers and founders, investors and CEOs who are working on all the present and future ways people and packages will get from Point A to Point B. The agenda is packed with leaders in electric vehicles — that would be Mate Rimac — autonomous vehicle technology, micromobility and even urban and regional air taxis.</p>
<p>Among the growing list of speakers are <strong>Motional</strong> President <strong>Karl Iagnemma</strong> and <strong>Aurora</strong> co-founder and CEO <strong>Chris Urmson</strong>, who will team up to talk about technical problems that remain to be solved, the war over talent, the best business models and applications of autonomous vehicles and maybe even hear a few stories from the early days of testing and launching a startup.</p>
<p>Other guests include <strong>GM</strong>&#8216;s VP of Global Innovation <strong>Pam Fletcher</strong>, <strong>Scale AI</strong> CEO <strong>Alexandr Wang</strong>, <strong>Joby Aviation</strong> founder and CEO <strong>JoeBen Bevirt</strong>, investor and<strong> LinkedIn</strong> founder <strong>Reid Hoffman</strong> (whose special purpose acquisition company just merged with Joby), investors <strong>Clara Brenner</strong> of <strong>Urban Innovation Fund</strong>, <strong>Quin Garcia</strong> of <strong>Autotech Ventures</strong> and <strong>Rachel Holt</strong> of <strong>Construct Capital</strong>, <strong>Zoox</strong> co-founder and CTO <strong>Jesse Levinson</strong>, community organizer, transportation consultant and lawyer<strong> Tamika L. Butler</strong>, <strong>Remix</strong> co-founder and CEO <strong>Tiffany Chu</strong> and <strong>Revel</strong> co-founder and CEO <strong>Frank Reig</strong>.</p>
<p>We also recently announced a panel dedicated to China&#8217;s robotaxi industry. We&#8217;re bringing together three female leaders from Chinese autonomous vehicle startups that have an overseas footprint: <strong>Jewel Li</strong> from AutoX, which is backed by Chinese state-owned automakers Dongfeng Motor and SAIC Motor; <strong>Huan Sun</strong> from Momenta, which attracted Bosch, Daimler and Toyota in its<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/momenta-500-million-fundraise/"> $500 million round</a> closed in March; and <strong>Jennifer Li</strong> from WeRide, whose valuation jumped to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/chinas-weride-secures-more-funding-pushing-valuation-to-3-3-billion/">$3 billion</a> after a financing round in May.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t wait to book your tickets to TC Sessions: Mobility as prices go up at the door. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=editorialpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=rimacpost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=Rimac&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Grab your passes</a> right now and hear from today&#8217;s biggest mobility leaders.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-fd9c1cec2f0d59a192ac6b35a32458d1"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/fd9c1cec2f0d59a192ac6b35a32458d1"
			scrolling=""
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-fd9c1cec2f0d59a192ac6b35a32458d1')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-fd9c1cec2f0d59a192ac6b35a32458d1'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/electric-hypercar-phenom-and-founder-mate-rimac-is-heading-to-tc-sessions-mobility-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153341</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Geospatial startup Unfolded.ai acquired by Foursquare</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/geospatial-startup-unfolded-ai-acquired-by-foursquare/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/geospatial-startup-unfolded-ai-acquired-by-foursquare/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 16:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foursquare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geospatial analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unfolded.ai]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, that was fast. Just a few months after raising its seed round, Unfolded.ai announced today that it is being acquired by Foursquare. Terms of the deal were not disclosed. The startup had raised a total of about $6 million when we last checked in with them. The company, founded by a group of ex-Uber [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Well, that was fast.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/ex-uber-team-raises-6m-seed-for-geospatial-analytics-platform-unfolded-ai/">Just a few months after raising its seed round</a>, Unfolded.ai announced today that it is being acquired by Foursquare. Terms of the deal were not disclosed. The startup had raised a total of about $6 million when we last checked in with them.</p>
<p>The company, founded by a group of ex-Uber geospatial engineers, was building on top of popular open-source libraries that its founders had created, including <a href="https://github.com/keplergl/kepler.gl">Kepler.gl</a>, a web application that can take geospatial data sets and visualize them, and <a href="https://github.com/visgl/deck.gl">Deck.gl</a>, which offers an extensible application framework for processing geospatial data sets and preparing them for visualization.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UgUwfehMHK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/ex-uber-team-raises-6m-seed-for-geospatial-analytics-platform-unfolded-ai/">Ex-Uber team raises $6M seed for geospatial analytics platform Unfolded.ai</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ex-Uber team raises $6M seed for geospatial analytics platform Unfolded.ai&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/ex-uber-team-raises-6m-seed-for-geospatial-analytics-platform-unfolded-ai/embed/#?secret=UgUwfehMHK" data-secret="UgUwfehMHK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As I wrote earlier this year:</p>
<blockquote><p>The startup’s main product is called <a href="https://www.unfolded.ai/blog/2021-01-12-introducing-studio/">Unfolded Studio</a>, which acts as a backend-as-a-service for applications built on top of <a href="http://Kepler.gl">Kepler.gl</a> (which is only a frontend library itself) handling components like data management and server communications. In particular, the product is designed to bring different geospatial datasets together and allow them all to interact with each other in one unified view.</p></blockquote>
<p>The acquisition by Foursquare is designed to bring Unfolded’s geospatial technology into <a href="https://foursquare.com/article/a-new-look-and-feel-introducing-foursquare-everywhere/">Foursquare Everywhere</a>, the company’s new brand and product focus on delivering scalable location services to all sorts of customers.</p>
<p>Foursquare has evolved significantly in recent years to become a location-focused advertising and marketing platform. It <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/06/foursquare-merges-with-factual/">announced that it was merging with Factual</a> back in April 2020, and switched out CEO David Shim <a href="https://foursquare.com/article/foursquare-ceo-david-shim-to-depart-company-gary/">with Gary Little in November</a>, who assumed the titles of CEO and president. This acquisition appears to be the first for Little since he took the helm.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2155438" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2155438" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2155438" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GaryLittle.jpg?w=600" alt="" width="600" height="450" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GaryLittle.jpg 600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GaryLittle.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GaryLittle.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GaryLittle.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2155438" class="wp-caption-text">Foursquare CEO and president Gary Little. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Foursquare</p></div></p>
<p>In its press statement, the company said that “this acquisition propels Foursquare’s evolution into the singular source companies turn to for high quality, easy-to-use location data and the technology they need to make sense of it.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="54XB0JbNfh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/06/foursquare-merges-with-factual/">Foursquare merges with Factual</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Foursquare merges with Factual&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/06/foursquare-merges-with-factual/embed/#?secret=54XB0JbNfh" data-secret="54XB0JbNfh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/geospatial-startup-unfolded-ai-acquired-by-foursquare/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155435</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Don&#8217;t tweet about $ASS</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/dont-tweet-about-ass/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/dont-tweet-about-ass/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 15:46:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Economy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am not a smart man. Earlier today I tweeted about $ASS, a cryptocurrency named after a dog. In this case, Australian Shepherds. And after doing that obviously stupid thing, my Twitter feed became chock-full of ass-related imagery, memes and $ASS coin stans breathing on me. It&#8217;s all very annoying as I run Tweetdeck on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">I am not a smart man.</p>
<p>Earlier today I <a href="https://twitter.com/alex/status/1395384930885115911">tweeted about $ASS</a>, a cryptocurrency named after a dog. In this case, Australian Shepherds. And after doing that obviously stupid thing, my Twitter feed became chock-full of ass-related imagery, memes and $ASS coin stans breathing on me.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s all very annoying as I run Tweetdeck on a work laptop which is now very, well, dicey a proposition given what I&#8217;m being sent.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">save me <a href="https://t.co/CtmjcfeWdX">pic.twitter.com/CtmjcfeWdX</a></p>
<p>&mdash; alex (@alex) <a href="https://twitter.com/alex/status/1395395101485060097?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 20, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>$ASS is short for Australian <em>Safe</em> Shepherd, by the by. It&#8217;s a cryptocurrency that, much like Dogecoin, is a joke.</p>
<p>A joke that its own website doesn&#8217;t take too seriously. For example, if you <a href="https://assfinance.com/">navigate to AssFinance</a>, you will find a very detailed look at $ASS&#8217;s technical underpinnings, and plans for the future:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2155412 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-10.52.41-AM.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="417" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-10.52.41-AM.png 1013w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-10.52.41-AM.png?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-10.52.41-AM.png?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-10.52.41-AM.png?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-10.52.41-AM.png?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-10.52.41-AM.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>I found this hilarious. So I tweeted about it. And then everyone in the $ASS world began to assault my Twitter. Pro-tip: This is not a good way to get taken seriously. But as $ASS is not trying to be taken seriously, does that even matter?</p>
<p>The coin is effectively a limpid pump, a cryptocurrency designed to get early adopters to spread the word about it, and then hold. It built its economics around just those goals:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2155427 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-10.55.39-AM.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="99" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-10.55.39-AM.png 1171w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-10.55.39-AM.png?resize=150,22 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-10.55.39-AM.png?resize=300,44 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-10.55.39-AM.png?resize=768,112 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-10.55.39-AM.png?resize=680,99 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-20-at-10.55.39-AM.png?resize=50,7 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>But enough of all that. Why do we give a shit about $ASS? A few reasons:</p>
<ul>
<li>This sort of financial stupidity is funny, but some regular folks are going to get burned.</li>
<li>The $ASS pump is indicative of the level of speculation present in the cryptocurrency world today, which is likely to the credibility detriment of more serious projects. And helps explain how bitcoin has managed the price appreciation it has in recent quarters.</li>
<li>$ASS coin is up 1,794.3% in the last 14 days, <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/australian-safe-shepherd">per CoinGecko</a>. This is likely key to its current charm; people love free money and past gains make for an attractive lie to oneself concerning future returns.</li>
</ul>
<p>As a concept, $ASS fits neatly into my budding view that as current generations of people in their 20s and 30s are desperate for a firmer foothold on a middle-class life than today&#8217;s wage-weak, healthcare-deficient and labor-unfriendly economy is willing to provide, moon-shots on speculative bullshit have outsized appeal compared to other times in American history when it was easier to afford a house.</p>
<p>And while it&#8217;s hard to be serious about a <del>butt</del> dog-themed bit of internet money, $ASS is, well, very 2021. And who are we to pretend to be better than covering a shitcoin? Even if only to mock it.</p>
<p>Bloomberg <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2021-05-20/crypto-market-prices-ass-coin-superdoge-billionaires-prosper-and-fall">has more on $ASS</a> if you want a more serious take about an unserious project.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/dont-tweet-about-ass/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155397</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Slicing up pizza robots</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/robotics-roundup-12/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/robotics-roundup-12/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 15:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chef Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics roundup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2154957</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So, true story. Over the weekend I was talking to someone about restaurant robotics. It’s a concept people often have trouble visualizing &#8212; and understandably so. Among other things, there’s really no commonly accepted form factor in a category that sometimes is literally a robot arm flipping hamburgers. My short response was, “they’re large kiosks [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">So, true story. Over the weekend I was talking to someone about restaurant robotics. It’s a concept people often have trouble visualizing &#8212; and understandably so. Among other things, there’s really no commonly accepted form factor in a category that sometimes is literally a robot arm flipping hamburgers.</p>
<p>My short response was, “they’re large kiosks that make pizza.” And honestly, that’s not really far from the truth. These sorts of self-contained assembly line robots are probably about as close as we have to a consensus design in the category &#8212; and for good reason. They’re designed to operate with minimal interaction &#8212; largely the employee’s involvement is limited to order input, restocking ingredients and cleaning.</p>
<p>The pizza part is two-fold. First: people like pizza. It’s plentiful and popular, so it makes sense that it would be one of the first foodstuffs you’d want to automate. Second: it’s relatively easy to automate. The process for making it is consistent and the constraints are clear. It’s something that can be broken down into an easy to follow, step by step set of instructions.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>I covered two restaurant robots in the past week. It’s a category that saw a pretty sizable boost in interest during the pandemic, as restaurants were short-staffed essential services looking for ways to minimize human contact with food as the scientific world was scrambling to determine how the novel coronavirus is spread.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jalae0XrqG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/pizza-robot-maker-picnic-raises-another-13-3m/">Pizza robot-maker Picnic raises another $16.3M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pizza robot-maker Picnic raises another $16.3M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/pizza-robot-maker-picnic-raises-another-13-3m/embed/#?secret=jalae0XrqG" data-secret="jalae0XrqG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/pizza-robot-maker-picnic-raises-another-13-3m/">Picnic</a> very much fits in with the aforementioned description. It is, quite literally, a big, pizza-making box. This week the Seattle-based company announced a $16.3 million raise that includes a $3 million bridge filed last fall. It’s targeting restaurants, as well as public gathering spaces (remember those?) like schools, stadiums and hospitals. There are a handful of companies in the category, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/xrobotics-is-keeping-the-dream-of-pizza-robots-alive/">XRobotics</a> &#8212; though the formerly best known, Zume,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/25/zume-looks-to-life-beyond-pizza/"> bailed out of the pizza robot space</a> a while back.</p>
<p>Chef Robotics announced a $7.7 million raise this week. I can’t really tell you what the final robot looks like yet, because that’s still trade secret stuff. Here’s what the company says:</p>
<blockquote><p>Chef is designed to mimic the flexibility of humans, allowing customers to handle thousands of different kinds of food using minimal hardware changes. Chef does this using artificial intelligence that can learn how to handle more and more ingredients over time and that also improves. This allows customers to do things like change their menu often. Additionally, Chef’s modular architecture allows customers to quickly scale up just as they would by hiring more staff (but unlike humans, Chef always shows up on time and doesn’t need breaks).</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TAW7Nyax83"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/chef-robotics-raises-7-7m-to-help-automate-kitchens/">Chef Robotics raises $7.7M to help automate kitchens</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chef Robotics raises $7.7M to help automate kitchens&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/chef-robotics-raises-7-7m-to-help-automate-kitchens/embed/#?secret=TAW7Nyax83" data-secret="TAW7Nyax83" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Not a lot to go off there, but the modularity bit is interesting &#8212; and something a lot of these companies are exploring. If you can get a robot to automate a simple, repetitive task, you can potentially offer swappable hardware that can apply the technology to different kinds of food.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/Pj1j9cioj_w?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Other notable raises for the week include <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/ai-robotics-startup-mech-mind-completes-series-c-funding-led-by-tech-giant-meituan-301293375.html">Mech-Mind robots</a>. The Beijing-based company announced a Series C. It hasn’t revealed a specific figure, but given that it says the raise brings its total funding to over $100 million and it had previously raised a total of $79 million (including a $15 million Series B last year), you can extrapolate from there.</p>
<p>Mech-Mind is an industrial robotics and AI company focused on various manufacturing tasks.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/robotics-roundup-12/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2154957</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Robinhood&#8217;s epic Q1 growth explains its fundraising boom</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/robinhoods-epic-q1-growth-explains-its-fundraising-boom/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/robinhoods-epic-q1-growth-explains-its-fundraising-boom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 15:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC News Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2155352</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Each month in Robinhood's Q1 2021 produced more PFOF revenues than its entire year-ago quarter in aggregate.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">An initial analysis of Robinhood&#8217;s Q1 2021 payment for order flow (PFOF) revenues sourced from company filings shows that the free-trading unicorn had a strong start to the year. Given the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/gamestop-memestocks-and-the-revenge-of-the-retail-trader/">raucous trading activity of the first quarter</a>, that news is not a surprise.</p>
<p>The aggregate revenue data helps explain how Robinhood was able to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/robinhoods-long-weekend-brings-a-total-of-3-4-billion-to-its-balance-sheet/">raise as much capital as it did in the first quarter</a> despite running into <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/robinhood-users-say-its-restricting-trades-after-the-gamestop-brouhaha-shakes-markets/">issues with its technology</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/robinhood-goes-to-congress/">the United States government</a>; the company found itself at the center of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/05/how-the-gamestop-stonkathon-helped-robinhood-raise-3-4b-last-week/">the GameStop speculative rush</a>, which likely led to strong trading volumes, along with what The Exchange presumes was an unwelcome level of attention from regulators.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money.  </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>This morning, we&#8217;re sticking close to the company&#8217;s financial results using the lens of PFOF income, which the company said during a congressional hearing constitutes the majority of its revenues.</p>
<p>This particular revenue growth — or the lack thereof — is a good way to understand not only Robinhood&#8217;s own results but also its larger market. If Robinhood is seeing rapid growth and strong trading volumes, we can infer with some confidence that others in its space are enjoying a related, if not similar, level of interest.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1995212" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>For Public.com, eToro and others like Freetrade (as well as our own understanding), how Robinhood performed recently is key. So, let&#8217;s explore the data.</p>
<h2>An epic Q1</h2>
<p>Per an initial TechCrunch analysis of Robinhood&#8217;s collected <a href="https://cdn.robinhood.com/assets/robinhood/legal/RHS%20SEC%20Rule%20606%20and%20607%20Disclosure%20Q1%202021.pdf">PFOF disclosure data</a> for the first quarter, including its revenues from fees related to the trading of stocks that are part of the S&amp;P 500, stocks that are not, and options incomes, here&#8217;s how the company performed:<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/robinhoods-epic-q1-growth-explains-its-fundraising-boom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2155352</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
