<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 08:41:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Motorway&#8217;s auction platform for second-hand cars raises $67.7M Series B led by Index Ventures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/13/motorways-auction-platform-for-second-hand-cars-raises-67-7m-series-b-led-by-index-ventures/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/13/motorways-auction-platform-for-second-hand-cars-raises-67-7m-series-b-led-by-index-ventures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 05:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[auction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car dealership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[danny rimer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Farfetch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motorway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165484</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Motorway, is a UK startup that allows professional car dealers to bid in an auction for privately-owned cars for sale. The startup has had rapid success by removing a lot of friction in the process. It’s now raised £48m / $67.7m in a Series B round led by Index Ventures, along with new investors BMW i Ventures [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://motorway.co.uk/">Motorway</a>, is a UK startup that allows professional car dealers to bid in an auction for privately-owned cars for sale. The startup has had rapid success by removing a lot of friction in the process. It’s now raised £48m / $67.7m in a Series B round led by Index Ventures, along with new investors BMW i Ventures and Unbound. Existing investors Latitude and Marchmont Ventures also participated. The funding will be used to extend its platform and grow the current 160-strong team.</p>
<p>The startup claims it allows consumers to sell their car for up to £1,000 more than they would do via other means, by uploading its details via a smartphone app that also uses computer vision to assess the state of the car. Over 3,000 professional car dealers then bid for the vehicle in a daily online auction. The highest offer wins the car, which is then collected for free by the winning dealer inside 24 hours. </p>
<p>Motorway says it has sold 65,000 cars since its launch in 2017 and seen sales hit £50m in May 2021 alone, £2.5m of transactions a day, and more than 4,000 completed car sales a month. With only 5% of all vehicles in the UK sold online right now, there is plenty of headroom for this market to grow.<br />
 <br />
Tom Leathes, CEO of Motorway, said: “For half a century, inefficient offline processes have led to bad deals and a bad experience for both car sellers and car dealers. Motorway has fundamentally changed a broken experience where everyone ends up dissatisfied – and we’ve transformed it with a superior online experience where everybody wins. Cutting out the middlemen leaves both the consumer and car dealer with a better deal, all from home and without the stress. Our incredible growth so far is testament to our focus on delivering more value through technology – and this investment will provide us with the fuel to take Motorway to the next level.&#8221;<br />
 <br />
Danny Rimer, Partner at Index Ventures, said: “We’re always looking to invest in companies that are truly disrupting an industry and meeting a real customer need. We have found that in Motorway. The team has built an incredibly powerful platform, underpinned by great technology and a deep understanding of the challenges both consumers and car dealers face. Motorway has quickly become the first port of call for tens of thousands of people selling their car.” <br />
 <br />
Motorway previously raised £14m in venture funding since it was founded by Tom Leathes, Harry Jones and Alex Buttle in 2017.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Speaking to me over interview Leathes added: “COVID has been a real accelerator of something that was already happening. The car industry is moving online and that&#8217;s partly about people buying their next car online, but it&#8217;s also about dealers changing their behavior, how they do business, where they buy their cars. It forced that change which they resisted for a long time, and now they&#8217;re embracing it, so it&#8217;s a fundamental shift in the industry. And this is why we see such a massive opportunity to provide the rails to help both sides of the marketplace to move online.”</p>
<p>Rimer added: “It&#8217;s rare that you have founders who have worked together across multiple successful and less successful startups who have that scar tissue and success, and are now going for a much bigger opportunity. The business model is really an important one for us because instead of owning inventory and then having to get rid of your inventory, sort of like the difference between Nat-a-Porter and Farfetch. Motorway&#8217;s marketplace is just like Farfetch &#8211; they don&#8217;t have any inventory, which means that just by merely making that platform happen for buyers and sellers, they win. So there&#8217;s a lot less risk associated with what the money is going to be used for when building the business.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/13/motorways-auction-platform-for-second-hand-cars-raises-67-7m-series-b-led-by-index-ventures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165484</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cyber security training platform Immersive Labs  closes $75M Series C led by Insight Partners</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/13/cyber-security-training-platform-immersive-labs-closes-75m-series-c-led-by-insight-partners/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/13/cyber-security-training-platform-immersive-labs-closes-75m-series-c-led-by-insight-partners/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bristol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CIO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[citi ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Darktrace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gchq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hsbc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immersive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immersive Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[menlo ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NHS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[series C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vodafone]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165480</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Immersive Labs, a platform which teaches cyber security skills corporate employees by using real, up-to-date threat intelligence in a “gamified” way, has closed a $75 million Series C funding round led by new investors Insight Partners alongside Menlo Ventures, Citi Ventures and existing investor Goldman Sachs Asset Management. The investment will be used to scale [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.immersivelabs.com/">Immersive Labs</a>, a platform which teaches cyber security skills corporate employees by using real, up-to-date threat intelligence in a “gamified” way, has closed a $75 million Series C funding round led by new investors Insight Partners alongside Menlo Ventures, Citi Ventures and existing investor Goldman Sachs Asset Management.</p>
<p>The investment will be used to scale Immersive’s offering in the US and take advantage of the new wave of interest in cyber threats caused by so many people working remotely, post-pandemic.  Founded in 2017, Immersive Labs now has 200 people, with joint operations HQs in Bristol, UK, and Boston, US. It plans to raise headcount to over 600 in the next two years and establish operations in new regions throughout APAC and Europe. Immersive&#8217;s &#8216;Cyber Workforce Optimization&#8217; platform claims to offer board-level metrics and benchmarking to gauge how the skills inside organizations are coping.</p>
<p>Immersive has now raised a total of $123m in venture funding and counts HSBC, Vodafone, and the NHS as customers. The company says it is growing at &#8220;over 100% year-on-year”.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>James Hadley, CEO and founder of Immersive Labs, said: “With cyber risk becoming a problem for a growing number of business functions, cybersecurity knowledge and skills should no longer be the preserve of a few technical people hidden away in a back office. Everyone from the teams who build software, to the CEO, now need to play their part in addressing a pervasive company issue. This requires unlocking and evidencing skills in a much broader group of people.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ryan Hinkle, managing director at Insight Partners, said: “With significant global customer and revenue growth over the last few years, Immersive Labs has established a strong position in the fast-developing cyber skills space. With influential leadership, an innovative product in a growing market, and strong user engagement, the company is in a position to continue to lead the cyber readiness market.”</p>
<p>Speaking to me over an interview, Hadley added: &#8220;We chose Insight Partners because they&#8217;ve got a real strength in enterprise B2B which is where we sell to CIOs and CEOs… We want to be the next Darktrace in terms of a successful UK cybersecurity company.”</p>
<p>The comparison might not be that fanciful. Immersive Labs came out of the CYLON cyber accelerator, similar to Darktrace, has the same investors as Darktrace, but has in fact attracted $75m for its Series C, whereas Darktrace didn&#8217;t manage that level until Series D. Darktrace has now IPO&#8217;d in the London for £1.7bn.</p>
<p>Hadley, a former GCHQ security researcher and trainer, came up with the idea for the cyber skills platform while leading cyber training himself. I asked him why he thinks Immersive has managed to come up with a &#8216;flywheel effect&#8217; with its platform.</p>
<p>“People always talk about all the cyber threats getting worse, but it really is now and it&#8217;s in the public domain. We&#8217;ve got a strong belief that cybersecurity is no longer the responsibility of the geeks in the basement. Actually, it&#8217;s business-wide. And now the tidal wave is coming. Cybercrime is going to go off the scale this year and next because companies are paying the ransoms. And as a result of that, we&#8217;re putting in analytics to measure decision-making in a crisis. It’s just resonating really well with every company regardless of CIO or vertical,” he told me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/13/cyber-security-training-platform-immersive-labs-closes-75m-series-c-led-by-insight-partners/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165480</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gillmor Gang: Déjà Vu</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/13/gillmor-gang-deja-vu/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/13/gillmor-gang-deja-vu/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 23:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brent Leary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denis Pombriant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frank radice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keith Teare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Markman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165472</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Gang or a subset did a Clubhouse, longer than a regular show by a good third. The audio only structure lacked the visual cues that distinguish between irony and bad manners, but otherwise it felt familiar if not comfortable. I can&#8217;t remember what we talked about, only that I seemed a little more emphatic [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/kjJj_C6yM7w?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>The Gang or a subset did a Clubhouse, longer than a regular show by a good third. The audio only structure lacked the visual cues that distinguish between irony and bad manners, but otherwise it felt familiar if not comfortable. I can&#8217;t remember what we talked about, only that I seemed a little more emphatic about my opinions than usual. We recorded the meeting, which is close to what it was. Not really a show, more a rally of a political platform with no policies. A few friends joined in, several listeners drifted in and out. All in all, about what I expected.</p>
<p>The following day, I called around to get others&#8217; reactions. Also about what I expected. That evening, someone hosted a Twitter Spaces event that apparently peaked at 22,000 listeners. The subject matter was crypto. I remember walking around below the stage at Woodstock early on the first afternoon of the festival. The fences were down; the concert was declared free, and the crowds began to build. The sense of something big filled the air, but I was more concerned with the foreboding storm clouds gathering at the top of the hill. At some point as the thunder began to roll in, I left and headed back to the safety of the town of Woodstock 40 miles away.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>I grew up part time in Woodstock, the other part in the city at my father&#8217;s apartment in Greenwich Village. From as early as I remember, the conversation around the coffee table in the kitchen was all about the issues of the day, the music and media of the time, the patterns of a family marked by divorce, liberalism, and the key notion that age had little to do with one&#8217;s standing around the table. It always felt profound to me that I could be heard and listen to any subject or feeling, across the multigenerational patchwork of step and half siblings, and in both the Village and Woodstock, a steady stream of artists, musicians, and filmmakers engaged intimately in the moment of the 60&#8217;s and on and on to this day. My point is that Clubhouse and Twitter and a flattened hierarchy of intention and opinion is a constant in my life, not a new freedom or problem to be overcome. It&#8217;s the old normal, for me.</p>
<p>On this edition of the Gang, the subject of Amazon&#8217;s Sidewalk mesh network arises. Suffice it to say, there are security implications. What happens when a company whose scale has captured a significant percentage of the world economy in the pandemic offers an opt out service sharing its customers&#8217; broadband internet access with other Amazon customers? The potential arrogance of providing an opt out date after which you have agreed to this plan by not saying no is, well, breathtaking. Forget that the algorithm uses a very small part of your bandwidth cap and would be unlikely to affect your access to or price of the subscription to the network. In some way, that makes the grab seem even more Machiavellian than it really is. But even more egregious is the suggestion that such a mesh network gives potential access not only to the bandwidth but what you and everybody else in the neighborhood does with it. Wherever you go, there you are indeed. Or, there goes the neighborhood.</p>
<p>For now, the fences are down in the new Woodstock. Washington is coming for its cut of the pie, and the new rules of post-cookie and privacy v. economy are being debated. Apple is challenging the newsletter and its rationale creator economy by breaking access to the open and click rates that drive analytics. Tracking pixels will now open en masse before the beginning of the viewing process rather than firing off as clicks are generated. Substack and Revue tools to track these indications of user preference will have to be replaced by direct appeals for information about preferences, which to me suggests a kind of horse trade in terms of subscriber cost versus user-provided data. By the way, I very much appreciate new subscribers to the Gang newsletter feed, even though we&#8217;ve moved off Substack to Revue and don&#8217;t know why people are subscribing to an empty stream. Come to think of it, the sound of silence may be worth it.</p>
<p>As Professor Corey used to say, &#8220;No, no, I really mean that.&#8221; What is said may not be the most important part of the transaction. Instead, how trust is established and maintained is a core value. The newsletter proposition is to cut to the chase, whether by overt messages or the avoidance of wasted time spent on concerns or attitudes that have already been understood by the nature of the subscribed relationship. As the cost of creator production approaches zero, tools are needed to evaluate the credibility and utility of all these new voices. Where magazines and publishers used to provide a screening process, now the methodology for measuring trust becomes business critical. How many are watching or reading what is still important, but who those people are and how they relate to each other in a retweet/like social culture is more so.</p>
<p>Something akin to this is going on with live audio, where the conversation is a representative democratic process where listeners can evaluate not just what is said but how it is absorbed by the others &#8220;on stage.&#8221; These little signals of discovery between speakers are amplified by the audience reaction and, painfully, their withdrawal from the room via Leave Quietly. You can hear the moderator(s) quickly responding to such attrition with pivots to more viable subject matter or new speakers, but in aggregate these adjustments form a roadmap for future participation by &#8220;subscribers.&#8221; In this structure, the subscription is less about the price and more about the trust the group ascribes to the producers and speakers.</p>
<p>At Woodstock, the downed fences, traffic jams, and general chaos of creating a half-a-million population city in a heartbeat produced a difficult management situation where the very acts promoted by the organizers were unable to reach the stage. Instead, artists like John Sebastian of the Lovin&#8217; Spoonful (attending but not performing) were thrust into the spotlight for iconic performances that changed not only their careers but the rhythm and drama of the film that resulted. Joni Mitchell was convinced by her manager to skip the event in favor of an appearance on the Dick Cavett show, but her boyfriend of the time, Graham Nash, was there as part of CSN&amp;Y and relayed his impressions of the event as Mitchell sat in her hotel room. The result was the song she wrote, as recorded by CSNY, became the lead single from the band&#8217;s next record Déjà Vu, and played over the end credits of the film.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are stardust&#8230; golden&#8230; got to get back to the garden.&#8221; Joni Mitchell&#8217;s invisible pixels sprinkled over the massive economic disaster known as the Woodstock festival captured the top of the hit parade, and with it the moment we remember in history. Altamont, assassinations, pandemics, Nixon bombing in Ohio were soon to replace the aura of the hippie trek, but we still celebrate the idea of what we call Woodstock. The cryptos may be right, and translucent pixels may be suppressed, but I&#8217;ll still take CSNY&#8217;s glowing harmonies any day on my morning Wheaties. I&#8217;ll take shows about nothing for 40, Bob.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><strong><em>from the <a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang/issues/gillmor-gang-newsletter-revue-9-615502"> Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center">__________________</p>
<p>The Gillmor Gang — Frank Radice, Michael Markman, Keith Teare, Denis Pombriant, Brent Leary and Steve Gillmor. Recorded live Friday, June 4, 2021.</p>
<p>Produced and directed by Tina Chase Gillmor @tinagillmor</p>
<p>@fradice, @mickeleh, @denispombriant, @kteare, @brentleary, @stevegillmor, @gillmorgang</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang">Subscribe to the new Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></strong> and join the backchannel <a href="https://t.me/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> on Telegram.</p>
<p><a href="http://facebook.com/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Gillmor Gang on Facebook</a> … and here’s our sister show <a href="http://facebook.com/g3show" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">G3 on Facebook</a>.<img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2012361" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2012361" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/13/gillmor-gang-deja-vu/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165472</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nuclear waste recycling is a critical avenue of energy innovation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/13/nuclear-waste-recycling-is-a-critical-avenue-of-energy-innovation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/13/nuclear-waste-recycling-is-a-critical-avenue-of-energy-innovation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 15:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terrapower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165291</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tristan Abbey Contributor Share on Twitter Tristan Abbey is President of Comarus Analytics LLC. He served as senior policy advisor at the U.S. Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and as director for strategic planning at the National Security Council. No single question bedevils American energy and environmental policy more than nuclear waste. No, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Tristan Abbey</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/tristanabbey">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Tristan Abbey is President of Comarus Analytics LLC. He served as senior policy advisor at the U.S. Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and as director for strategic planning at the National Security Council.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">No single question bedevils American energy and environmental policy more than nuclear waste. No, not even a changing climate, which <a href="https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/feature/2014/09/30/a-wicked-problem-controlling-global-climate-change#:~:text=Toman%2520described%2520the%2520task%2520of,problem%2520is%252C%25E2%2580%259D%2520said%2520Toman.">may be a wicked problem</a> but nonetheless receives a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-19/spending-on-global-energy-transition-hits-record-500-billion#:~:text=The%2520world%2520spent%2520a%2520record,system's%2520dependence%2520on%2520fossil%2520fuels.">great deal</a> of counter-bedeviling attention.</p>
<p>It’s difficult to paint the picture with a straight face. Let’s start with three main elements of the story.</p>
<p>First, nuclear power plants in the United States generate about 2,000 metric tons of nuclear waste (or “spent fuel”) per year. Due to its inherent radioactivity, it is carefully stored at <a href="https://crsreports.congress.gov/product/pdf/IF/IF11201">various sites</a> around the country.</p>
<p>Second, the federal government is in charge of figuring out what to do with it. In fact, power plant operators have paid over <a href="https://www.energy.gov/sites/default/files/2020/11/f80/fy-2020-doe-agency-financial-report.pdf">$40 billion</a> into the Nuclear Waste Fund so that the government can handle it. The idea was to bury it in the “deep geological repository” embodied by Yucca Mountain, Nevada, but this has proved politically impossible. Nevertheless, <a href="https://www.gao.gov/products/gao-11-229">$15 billion</a> was spent on the scoping.</p>
<p>Third, due to the Energy Department’s inability to manage this waste, it simply accumulates. According to that agency’s <a href="https://www.eia.gov/nuclear/spent_fuel/">most recent</a> data release, some 80,000 metric tons of spent fuel—hundreds of thousands of fuel assemblies containing millions of fuel rods—is waiting for a final destination.</p>
<p>And here’s the twist ending: those nuclear plant operators sued the government for breach of contract and, in 2013, they <a href="https://www.cadc.uscourts.gov/internet/opinions.nsf/2708C01ECFE3109F85257C280053406E/$file/11-1066-1466796.pdf">won</a>. Several hundred million dollars is now paid out to them each year by the U.S. Treasury, as part of a series of settlements and judgments. The running total is over <a href="https://www.energy.gov/sites/default/files/2020/11/f80/fy-2020-doe-agency-financial-report.pdf">$8 billion</a>.</p>
<p>I realize this story sounds a little crazy. Am I really saying that the U.S. government collected billions of dollars to manage nuclear waste, then spent billions of dollars on a feasibility study only to stick it on the shelf, and now is paying even more billions of dollars for this failure? Yes, I am.</p>
<p>Fortunately, all of the aggregated waste <a href="https://www.ne.anl.gov/pdfs/NuclearEnergyFAQ.pdf">occupies a relatively small area</a> and temporary storage exists. Without an urgent reason to act, policymakers generally will not.</p>
<p>While attempts to find long-term storage will continue, policymakers should look towards recycling some of this “waste” into usable fuel. This is <a href="https://www.osti.gov/servlets/purl/6362154">actually</a> <a href="https://theconversation.com/harvesting-usable-fuel-from-nuclear-waste-and-dealing-with-the-last-chemical-troublemakers-35284">an</a> <a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/science/article/100831-can-nuclear-waste-spark-an-energy-solution">old</a> <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/smarter-use-of-nuclear-waste/">idea</a>. Only a small fraction of nuclear fuel is consumed to generate electricity.</p>
<p>Proponents of recycling envision reactors that use “reprocessed” spent fuel, extracting energy from the 90% of it leftover after burn-up. <a href="https://www.the-american-interest.com/2020/06/25/the-energy-departments-dangerous-plutonium-dream/">Even its critics</a> admit that the underlying chemistry, physics, and engineering of recycling are technically feasible, and instead assail the disputable economics and perceived security risks.</p>
<p>So-called Generation IV reactors come in <a href="https://www.iaea.org/nuclear-power-and-the-clean-energy-transition/small-reactors-great-potential">all shapes and sizes</a>. The designs have been around for years—in some respects, all the way back to the dawn of nuclear energy—but light-water reactors have dominated the field for a variety of political, economic, and strategic reasons. For example, Southern Company’s twin conventional pressurized water reactors under construction in Georgia each boast a capacity of just over 1,000-megawatt (or 1 gigawatt), standard for Westinghouse’s AP 1000 design.</p>
<p>In contrast, next-generation plant designs are a fraction of the size and capacity, and also may use different cooling systems: Oregon-based NuScale Power’s 77-megawatt small modular reactor, San Diego-based General Atomics’ 50-megawatt helium-cooled fast modular reactor, Alameda-based Kairos Power’s 140-megawatt molten fluoride salt reactor, and so on all have different configurations that can fit different business and policy objectives.</p>
<p>Many Gen-IV designs can either explicitly recycle used fuel or be configured to do so. On June 3, TerraPower (backed by Bill Gates), GE Hitachi, and the State of Wyoming announced an agreement to build a demonstration of the <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2021/bill-gates-terrapower-will-build-first-next-gen-nuclear-reactor-wyoming/">345-megawatt Natrium design</a>, a sodium-cooled fast reactor.</p>
<p>Natrium is <a href="https://www.nationalacademies.org/event/02-22-2021/docs/DF2B6E76040D1809270DD136524F0F5A3F34B7219191">technically capable</a> of recycling fuel for generation. California-based Oklo has already <a href="https://news.mit.edu/2020/oklo-nuclear-energy-1113">reached an agreement</a> with Idaho National Laboratory to operate its 1.5-megawatt “microreactor” off of used-fuel supplies. In fact, the self-professed “preferred fuel” for New York-based Elysium Industries’ <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/597ac945725e255e16e7e607/t/5bc42a6a9140b74027bc768c/1539582572678/IAEA-SMR-Booklet+%255BElysium+Industries+MCSFR%255D.pdf">molten salt reactor</a> design is spent nuclear fuel and Alabama-based Flibe Energy advertises the <a href="https://flibe-energy.com/technology/">waste-burning capability</a> of its thorium reactor design.</p>
<p>Whether advanced reactors rise or fall does not depend on resolving the nuclear waste deadlock. Though such reactors may be able to consume spent fuel, they don’t necessarily have to. Nonetheless, incentivizing waste recycling would improve their economics.</p>
<p>“Incentivize” here is code for “pay.” Policymakers should consider ways that Washington can make it more profitable for a power plant to recycle fuel than to <a href="https://www.eia.gov/energyexplained/nuclear/where-our-uranium-comes-from.php">import it</a>—from Canada, Kazakhstan, Australia, Russia, and other countries.</p>
<p>Political support for advanced nuclear technology, including recycling, is deeper than might be expected. In 2019, the Senate confirmed Dr. Rita Baranwal as the Assistant Secretary for Nuclear Energy at the Department of Energy (DOE). A materials scientist by training, she <a href="https://twitter.com/RitaB66/status/1187058573479538688?s=20">emerged</a> <a href="https://www.exchangemonitor.com/doe-nuclear-energy-chief-suggests-foreign-recycling-u-s-spent-fuel-2/">as</a> <a href="https://news.bloomberglaw.com/environment-and-energy/recycling-reusing-nuclear-fuel-doe-official-wants-to-study-it">a</a> <a href="https://www.eenews.net/stories/1063355089">champion</a> of recycling.</p>
<p>The new Biden administration has continued broadly bipartisan support for advanced nuclear reactors in <a href="https://www.energy.gov/sites/default/files/2021-05/doe-fy2022-budget-in-brief.pdf">proposing in its Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Request</a> to increase funding for the DOE’s Office of Nuclear Energy by nearly $350 million. The proposal includes specific funding increases for researching and developing reactor concepts (plus $32 million), fuel cycle R&amp;D (plus $59 million), and advanced reactor demonstration (plus $120 million), and tripling funding for the Versatile Test Reactor (from $45 million to $145 million, year over year).</p>
<p>In May, the DOE’s Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy (ARPA-E) <a href="https://arpa-e-foa.energy.gov/FileContent.aspx?FileID=a02cd89d-cca8-4218-9666-542ff93088f3">announced a new $40 million program</a> to support research in “optimizing” waste and disposal from advanced reactors, including through waste recycling. Importantly, the announcement explicitly states that the lack of a solution to nuclear waste today “poses a challenge” to the future of Gen-IV reactors.</p>
<p>The debate is a reminder that recycling in general is a very messy process. It is chemical-, machine-, and energy-intensive. Recycling of all kinds, from critical minerals to plastic bottles, produces new waste, too. Today, federal and state governments are <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/environment-and-natural-resources/state-and-federal-efforts-to-revitalize-recycling.aspx">quite active</a> in recycling these other waste streams, and they should be equally involved in nuclear waste.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/13/nuclear-waste-recycling-is-a-critical-avenue-of-energy-innovation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165291</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jeff Bezos&#8217; Blue Origin auctions off seat on first human spaceflight for $28M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-auctions-off-seat-on-first-human-spaceflight-for-28m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-auctions-off-seat-on-first-human-spaceflight-for-28m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 18:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bidding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff bezos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space tourism]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165441</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Blue Origin has its winning bidder for its first ever human spaceflight, and the winner will pay $28 million for the privilege of flying aboard the company&#8217;s debut private astronaut mission. The winning bid came in today during a live auction, which saw 7,600 registered bidders, from 159 countries compete for the spot. This was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Blue Origin has its winning bidder for its first ever human spaceflight, and the winner will pay $28 million for the privilege of flying aboard the company&#8217;s debut private astronaut mission. The winning bid came in today during a live auction, which saw 7,600 registered bidders, from 159 countries compete for the spot.</p>
<p>This was the culmination of Blue Origin&#8217;s three part bidding process for the ticket, which included a blind auction first, followed by an open, asynchronous auction with the highest bid posted to the company&#8217;s website whenever it changed. This last live auction greatly ramped up the value of the winning bid, which was at just under $5 million prior to the event.</p>
<p>This first seat up for sale went for a lot more than what an actual, commercial spot is likely to cost on Blue Origin&#8217;s New Shepard capsule, which flies to suborbital space and only spends a few minutes there before returning to Earth. Estimates put the cost of a typical launch at someone under $1 million, likely closer to $500,000 or so. But this is the first, which is obviously a special distinction, and it&#8217;s also a trip that will allow the winning bidder to pretty much literally rub elbows with Blue Origin founder<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/jeff-bezos-and-his-brother-will-fly-on-blue-origins-first-human-spaceflight-with-auction-winner/"> Jeff Bezos, who is going to be on the flight as well, along with his brother Mark</a>, and a fourth passenger that Blue Origin says it will be announcing sometime in the coming &#8220;weeks,&#8221; ahead of the July 20 target flight date.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As for who won the auction, we&#8217;ll also have to wait to find that out, since the winner&#8217;s identity is also going to be &#8220;released in the weeks following&#8221; the end of today&#8217;s live bidding. And in case you thought that $28 million might represent a big revenue windfall for Blue Origin, which has spent years developing its human spaceflight capability, think again: The company is donating it to its Club for the Future non-profit foundation, which is focused on encouraging kids to pursue careers in STEM in a long-term bid to help Bezos&#8217; larger goals of making humanity a spacefaring civilization.</p>
<p>You can re-watch the entire live bidding portion of the auction via the stream below.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/JUcQmETFmds?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-auctions-off-seat-on-first-human-spaceflight-for-28m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165441</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How many opinions does it take to hit the $100M ARR Club?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/how-many-opinions-does-it-take-to-hit-the-100m-arr-club/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/how-many-opinions-does-it-take-to-hit-the-100m-arr-club/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 18:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups Weekly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165324</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a world of talking points and corporate jargon, opinions are refreshing — and Expensify CEO and founder David Barrett is full of them. One of his earliest lessons in life, for example, was that basically everyone is wrong about basically everything. If instilling that at a young age doesn’t force you to become an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In a world of talking points and corporate jargon, opinions are refreshing — and Expensify CEO and founder David Barrett is full of them. One of his earliest lessons in life, for example, was that basically everyone is wrong about basically everything. If instilling that at a young age doesn’t force you to become an entrepreneur, I don’t know what does.</p>
<p>Barrett’s ethos has, as reporter <a href="https://twitter.com/abracarioca">Anna Heim</a> puts, led to Expensify having “its own take on almost everything” from hiring without job titles and resumes, to going distributed before it was cool, to having an almost non-existent sales team.</p>
<p>And before you roll your eyes at the unconventional, here’s a factoid for you: Today, the 130-person expense management business has reached more than 10 million users and hit $100 million in annual revenue.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Heim has spent months working on the Expensify EC-1 to connect dots and give us a full picture into an anything-but-conventional company as it heads toward an IPO. The final installment published this week so you can read the whole series in one straight shot:</p>
<ul>
<li>Part 1: Origin story “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/expensify-ec1-origin/">How a band of P2P hackers planted the seeds of a unique expense management giant”</a> (2,400 words/10 minutes</li>
<li>Part 2: Culture: “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/expensify-ec1-culture/">How Expensify got to $100M in revenue by hiring ‘stem cells’ and not ‘cogs in a wheel</a>’” (3,120 words/12.5 minutes)</li>
<li>Part 3: Expansion and remote work: “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/expensify-ec1-expansion/">How Expensify shed Silicon Valley arrogance to realize its global ambitions</a>” (3,250 words/13 minutes)</li>
<li>Part 4: Engineering and technology: “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/expensify-ec1-tech/">How Expensify hacked its way to a robust, scalable tech stack</a>” (3,300 words/13 minutes)</li>
<li>Part 5: Business model: “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/expensify-ec1-business/">How bottom-up sales helped Expensify blaze the path for SaaS</a>” (4,200 words/17 minutes)</li>
</ul>
<p>In the rest of this newsletter, I’ll walk you through a refresh of some new investment vehicles and two fintech mega-rounds to know. I also want to give a shout out to our mobility team, with transportation editor <a href="https://techcrunch.com/author/kirsten-korosec/">Kirsten Korosec</a> and reporters <a href="https://techcrunch.com/author/aria-alamalhodaei/">Aria Alamalhodaei</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/author/rebecca-bellan/">Rebecca Bellan</a><strong>, </strong>who led efforts to put on a fantastic event at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021?promo=leftrail&amp;display=true">TC Sessions: Mobility</a> this week.</p>
<p>Ok, into the news!</p>
<h2>More money, more representation?</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1827887 size-full" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GettyImages-931702556.jpg" alt="" width="2121" height="1414" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GettyImages-931702556.jpg 2121w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GettyImages-931702556.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GettyImages-931702556.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GettyImages-931702556.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GettyImages-931702556.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GettyImages-931702556.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GettyImages-931702556.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/GettyImages-931702556.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2121px) 100vw, 2121px" /></p>
<p><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Black_Kira / Getty Images</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/29/so-you-want-to-democratize-venture-capital/">As I discussed last month</a>, venture capital is going through yet another unbundling process. But, for every savvy fintech syndicate out there, I don’t see the same level of explicitness when it comes to the tools that help the communityless, undernetworked and underestimated access opportunities.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know: </strong>Two new efforts this week give me hope. Ten venture capitalists teamed up to launch Screendoor, which Forbes reports is <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/alexkonrad/2021/06/09/screendoor-raises-50-million-to-back-underrepresented-vcs/?sh=5127fd12ba17">a $50 million fund-of-funds</a> to back emerging fund managers from diverse backgrounds. The partners, which include Charles Hudson, Kirsten Green, Aileen Lee and Hunter Walk, will not take any fee or carry in the fund.</p>
<p>Speaking of cross-fund collaboration, Utah-based startup incubator Altitude Lab had similar news to share. The incubator, which spun out of Recursion and the University of Utah, has launched a 13-investor coalition to back underrepresented health tech founders. This week, it announced a $50 million commitment in funding and mentorship.</p>
<p><em>And if you want to have more fun(ds):</em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/seven-seven-six-the-new-venture-firm-from-alexis-ohanian-closes-150-million-fund-1/">Seven Seven Six, the new venture firm from Alexis Ohanian, closes $150M fund</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/todd-and-rahuls-angel-fund-closes-new-24-million-fund/">Todd and Rahul’s Angel Fund closes new $24 million fund</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.supplychangecapital.fund/">Supply Change Capital</a>, founded by Noramay Cadena and Shayna Harris, had its first close for its $40 million fund.</li>
</ul>
<h2>The Fintech twins</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1916305" style="width: 2131px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1916305" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1916305 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-482149917.jpg" alt="Handle of door to bank vault safe" width="2121" height="1414" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-482149917.jpg 2121w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-482149917.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-482149917.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-482149917.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-482149917.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-482149917.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-482149917.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/GettyImages-482149917.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2121px) 100vw, 2121px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1916305" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Janet+Kimber" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Janet Kimber <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Three is a trend, but two means twins, and that matters too! Riddles aside, we saw two fintech giants raise massive tranches of capital within days of each other.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know: </strong>Klarna raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/fintech-giant-klarna-raises-639m-at-a-45-6b-valuation/">$639 million at a $45.6 billion valuation</a>, and Nubank raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/fintech-all-star-nubank-raises-a-750m-mega-round/">$750 million at a $30 billion valuation.</a> Both fintech companies are based outside of the United States, but Klarna attests some of its rapid growth to a growing consumer base in the United States. More than 18 million American consumers are now using Klarna, which is up from 10 million at the end of last year’s third quarter. Meanwhile, Nubank is staying focused on its primary market of Brazil, with some expansion in Colombia and Mexico.</p>
<p><em> </em><em>Demystifying mega-rounds:</em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/the-fintech-endgame-new-supercompanies-combine-the-best-of-software-and-financials/">The fintech endgame: New supercompanies combine the best of software and financials</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/as-buy-now-pay-later-startups-keep-raising-capital-a-dive-into-klarna-afterpay-and-affirms-earnings/">As buy now, pay later startups keep raising capital, a dive into Klarna, Afterpay and Affirm’s earnings</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/visa-takes-a-swipe-in-fintech-builds-new-online-marketplace/">Visa takes a swipe in fintech, builds new online marketplace</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>The huge TAM of fake breaded chicken bits</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2013536" style="width: 2196px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2013536" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2013536 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Nuggs.jpg" alt="" width="2186" height="1324" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Nuggs.jpg 2186w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Nuggs.jpg?resize=150,91 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Nuggs.jpg?resize=300,182 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Nuggs.jpg?resize=768,465 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Nuggs.jpg?resize=680,412 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Nuggs.jpg?resize=1536,930 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Nuggs.jpg?resize=2048,1240 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Nuggs.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2186px) 100vw, 2186px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2013536" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://eatnuggs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Simulate <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Another week, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/the-huge-tam-of-fake-breaded-chicken-bits/">another spicy Equity episode for you</a>. And this week, we mean it literally: Simulate, the company behind those sometimes spicy fake chicken nuggets, raised a ton of money.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know: </strong>Beyond fake meat, topics in this week’s episode include worker empowerment, culture in startups, eldercare and a $900 million exit.</p>
<h2>Around TC</h2>
<ul>
<li>A big theme of this year in tech? Figuring out how to break through the noise. Sure, there are millions of marketers out there, but only a slice of those have actually had experience helping grow startups to success. So, TechCrunch is here to help! We’re making a list of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/help-techcrunch-find-the-best-growth-marketers-for-startups/">best growth marketers for startups</a>. You can help us by nominating <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">your favorites into this survey</a>.</li>
<li>Also, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/pitch-us-pittsburgh/">TechCrunch is coming to Pittsburgh</a>! We want to know the best local talent out there, so if you or someone you know might be a good fit, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/pitch-us-pittsburgh/">pitch us.</a></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/pitch-us-pittsburgh/"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2164781 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg" alt="" width="3200" height="1800" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/pittsburgh-featured.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 3200px) 100vw, 3200px" /></a></p>
<h2>Across the week</h2>
<h3>Seen on TechCrunch</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/softbank-uber-tencent-set-to-reap-rewards-from-didi-ipo/">SoftBank, Uber, Tencent set to reap rewards from Didi IPO</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/does-what-happens-at-yc-stay-at-yc/">Does what happens at YC stay at YC?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/the-imbalanced-landscape-of-hormonal-health/?tpcc=ECTW2020">The imbalance landscape of hormonal health</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-the-wwdc-2021-keynote">Here’s everything Apple announced at the WWDC 2021 keynote</a></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/WWDC-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/wwdc-2021-banner.jpg" alt="read more about Apple's WWDC 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
<h3>Seen on Extra Crunch</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/dont-panic-algorithm-updates-arent-the-end-of-the-world-for-seo-managers/">Don’t panic: ‘Algorithm updates’ aren’t the end of the world for SEO managers </a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/toasts-aman-narang-and-bvps-kent-bennett-on-how-customer-obsession-is-everything/">Toast’s Aman Narang and BVP’s Kent Bennett on how customer obsession is everything</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/what-do-these-4-ipos-tell-us-about-the-state-of-the-market/">What do these 4 IPOs tell us about the state of the market?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/how-to-start-a-company-in-4-days/">How to start a company in 4 days</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/dear-sophie-what-is-a-diversity-green-card-and-how-do-i-apply-for-one/">Dear Sophie: What is a diversity green card and how do I apply for one?</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Talk next week,</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">N</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/how-many-opinions-does-it-take-to-hit-the-100m-arr-club/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165324</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inside Marqeta’s fintech mega-IPO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/inside-marqetas-fintech-mega-ipo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/inside-marqetas-fintech-mega-ipo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 17:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165348</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter for your weekend enjoyment.
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome back to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter. It’s broadly based on </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/the-exchange/"><em>the daily column that appears on Extra Crunch</em></a><em>, but free, and made for your weekend reading. </em><em>Want it in your inbox every Saturday? Sign up </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters"><em>here</em></a><em>.</em></p>
<p><em>Ready? Let’s talk money, startups and spicy IPO rumors.</em></p>
<p><em>A small programming note: The Exchange column and newsletter are off next week (6/14-6/19), returning to regular service 6/21 after I get some sleep and come up with some new ideas! &#8212; </em><a href="http://twitter.com/alex"><em>Alex</em></a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Exchange dug into the mostly bullish IPO market <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/what-do-these-4-ipos-tell-us-about-the-state-of-the-market/">earlier this week</a>, noting that Monday.com and Marqeta put up some pretty big points over the last few days. The unicorn market is looking reasonably healthy, in other words, which itself bodes well for Q3 liquidity.</p>
<p>But today, instead of taking a broader view, I want to niche down to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/inside-marqetas-fascinating-fintech-ipo/">just the Marqeta offering</a>. For fintech companies, the company’s successful pricing and strong share-price performance is a welcome result. But how does the company itself feel about its debut?</p>
<p>To get a handle on just that, The Exchange chatted with the company’s founder and CEO Jason Gardner after his company priced its IPO and started to trade. To annoy my dear friend and TechCrunch superior <a href="https://twitter.com/Pickavet">Henry Pickavet</a>, we’ll proceed in bullet points so that we can cover lots of ground and stay within word count:</p>
<ul>
<li>Gardner said that he spent 34 hours doing Q&amp;A during the Marqeta roadshow. And that he loved it. This detail has little to do with the company’s IPO but does provide a little perspective on the CEO himself. That’s a lot of hours of answering the same 13 questions. I would have gone insane.</li>
<li>Marqeta priced above-range, raising more money than it might have anticipated. Per Gardner, the company will pursue inorganic growth (acquisitions) especially in markets outside the United States as they make sense, with the caveat that he has a high bar for technology quality; Gardner said that he won’t buy companies with lesser tech, as you’d just have to rebuild them after buying them. Shade.</li>
<li>Marqeta started talking internally about its IPO 18 months before it occurred, which made the transition to being a public company easier. I suppose Gardner’s point here that going public is a cultural lift as well as an accounting job. Which makes SPACs appear slightly cavalier, if I can take the point one step further.</li>
<li>What’s changed for Gardner as his company has matured and now gone public? His perspective has pushed farther out, from months to years; I presume that this will continue as Marqeta expands even more.</li>
</ul>
<p>Shares of Marqeta are <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/MQ/">up another 6%</a> as I write to you Friday afternoon.</p>
<h2>What’s up with Embroker?</h2>
<p>As <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/insurtech-is-hot-on-both-sides-of-the-atlantic/">The Exchange reported Friday morning</a>, the global insurtech market is more than hot both in the United States and Europe. Evidence of the fact is not hard to find, but one good indication of the insurtech market’s present climate is <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2021/06/09/2244313/0/en/Embroker-Raises-100-Million-to-Expand-Business-Insurance-Platform.html">Embroker’s $100 million round from earlier in the week</a>.</p>
<p>Embroker is a San Francisco-based insurtech company that sells business insurance. Its products include cyber coverage, business-owner coverage, professional liability and the like. It’s perhaps related to Next Insurance, another insurtech provider with a business focus that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/next-insurance-raises-250m-doubling-its-valuation-to-4b-in-under-a-year/">recently raised a huge round</a>.</p>
<p>The Exchange crew, fascinated as we are by insurtech as a larger category, wanted to get some questions in front of the Embroker crew. Here’s a Q&amp;A that was conducted via email. Bolding via TechCrunch. Questions have been gently edited for clarity:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>From a high level, are the loss ratios that the business insurance products that Embroker offers better/worse/comparable to those that we are familiar with in, say, consumer auto insurance?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, our loss ratios are substantially better than other insurance products like consumer auto or homeowners insurance. And our loss ratios thus far compare favorably to other established small business commercial carriers.</p>
<p><strong>When the company was negotiating valuation for the new round, did recent insurtech IPOs come into the pricing discussion?</strong></p>
<p>The recent insurtech IPOs have provided valuation benchmarks in the public market, which is great for the space overall. But we didn’t use them as direct comps because our loss ratio, retention, and sales and marketing efficiency are all substantially better than other insurtechs currently in the public markets.</p>
<p><strong>We found it interesting that Embroker offers &#8220;cyber risk insurance.” Given growth in market concerns regarding ransomware, is that product in higher demand than before? And is it as economically lucrative as other insurance lines at the company?</strong></p>
<p>Given the recent number of high profile cyber claims we expect cyber to be a rapidly growing line of insurance both in terms of demand and in terms of pricing. While claims activity will likely continue to rise, our models for cyber have been effective at pricing the risk appropriately and we expect that the investments we’re making in our platform will allow us to continue to do so.</p>
<p>For startups specifically, we also currently bundle tech E&amp;O and cyber insurance as many founders were under covered by stand alone E&amp;O or cyber policies when it came to these emerging threats.</p>
<p><strong>Finally, we’re curious what the company&#8217;s marketing spend has looked like over time &#8212; are you finding similarly efficient S&amp;M avenues as you did when Embroker was smaller?</strong></p>
<p>While we’ve been growing our marketing spend materially each year, it has actually been decreasing as a percentage of revenue consistently as we get to larger market share within the verticals we target, as that drives significant organic growth for us. For example, we currently insure a large enough percentage of all active U.S. venture-backed companies that so many companies just know to come to us for insurance when they raise funding.</p></blockquote>
<p>Sure, that’s a lot of words. But inside of the bloc are key nuggets. That Embroker considers its economics better than what we can see in most public comps is notable; the fact implies that there is a wider economic spread amongst insurtech companies than we have been led to believe by the few IPOs we’ve seen.</p>
<p>And that Embroker has operating leverage, at least regarding its S&amp;M spend. That could indicate that the insurtech marketplace is not <em>so</em> crowded as to make intelligent business operations impossible. Surely that terrible turn of events can be solved with a few hundred million more from Tiger and its rivals.</p>
<p>Closing today, on the OKR software beat &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/what-can-the-okr-software-sector-tell-us-about-startup-growth-more-generally/">more here</a> &#8212; Koan <a href="https://www.koan.co/press/koan-okr-software-leader-grows-82-yoy-integrates-with-microsoft-teams">reported 82% customer growth</a> this week. For a scrappy player in a crowded market, that’s a great result. A startup to watch, I reckon.</p>
<p>Chat with you in around ten days. &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/inside-marqetas-fintech-mega-ipo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165348</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple’s iPadOS 15 breaks the app barrier</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/apples-ipados-15-breaks-the-app-barrier/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/apples-ipados-15-breaks-the-app-barrier/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Panzarino]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 15:50:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Craig Federighi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cupertino]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game controller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ios 11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPados]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peer to peer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portable Media Players]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sidecar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siri]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Speech Recognition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tablet computers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Touchscreens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wi-fi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The announcement of new iPad software at this year’s WWDC conference had an abnormally large expectation hung on it. The iPad lineup, especially the larger iPad Pro, has kept up an impressively frantic pace of hardware innovation over the past few years. In that same time frame, the software of the iPad, especially its ability [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">The announcement of new iPad software at this year’s WWDC conference had an abnormally large expectation hung on it. The iPad lineup, especially the larger iPad Pro, has kept up an impressively frantic pace of hardware innovation over the past few years. In that same time frame, the software of the iPad, especially its ability to allow users to use multiple apps at once and in its onramps for professional software makers, has come under scrutiny for an apparently slower pace.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This year’s announcements about iOS 15 and iPadOS 15 seemed designed to counter that narrative with the introduction of a broad number of quality of life improvements to multitasking as well as a suite of system-wide features that nearly all come complete with their own developer-facing APIs to build on. I had the chance to speak to Bob Borchers, Apple’s VP of Worldwide Product Marketing, and Sebastien (Seb) Marineau-Mes, VP, Intelligent System Experience at Apple about the release of iPadOS 15 to discuss a variety of these improvements.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Marineau-Mes works on the team of Apple software SVP Craig Federighi and was pivotal in the development of this new version.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p class="p1">iPad has a bunch of new core features including SharePlay, Live Text, Focuses, Universal Control, on-device Siri processing and a new edition of Swift Playgrounds designed to be a prototyping tool. Among the most hotly anticipated for iPad Pro users, however, are improvements to Apple’s multitasking system.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">If you’ve been following along, you’ll know that the gesture-focused multitasking interface of iPadOS has had its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/24/review-100000-miles-and-one-week-with-an-ipad-pro/">share of critics, including me</a>. Though it can be useful in the right circumstances, the un-discoverable gesture system and confusing hierarchy of the different kinds of combinations of apps made it a sort of floppy affair to utilize correctly for an <i>apt</i> user much less a beginner.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Since the iPad stands alone as pretty much the only successful tablet device on the market, Apple has a unique position in the industry to determine what kinds of paradigms are established as standard. It’s a very unique opportunity to say, hey, this is what working on a device like this feels like; looks like; should be.</p>
<p class="p1">So I ask Borchers and Marineau-Mes to talk a little bit about multitasking. Specifically Apple’s philosophy in the design of multitasking on iPadOS 15 and the update from the old version, which required a lot of acrobatics of the finger and a strong sense of spatial awareness of objects hovering out off the edges of the screen.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">“I think you&#8217;ve got it,” Borchers says when I mention the spatial gymnastics, “but the way that we think about this is that the step forward and multitasking makes it easier discover, easier to use even more powerful. And, while pros I think were the ones who were using multitasking in the past, we really want to take it more broadly because we think there&#8217;s applicability to many, many folks. And that&#8217;s why the, the discovery and the ease of use I think were critical.”</p>
<p class="p1">“You had a great point there when you talked about the spatial model and one of our goals was to actually make the spatial model more explicit in the experience,” says Marineau-Mes, “where, for example, if you&#8217;ve got a split view, and you&#8217;re replacing one of the windows, we kind of open the curtain and tuck the other app to the side, you can see it — it&#8217;s not a hidden hidden mental model, it’s one that&#8217;s very explicit.</p>
<p class="p1">Another great example of it is when you go into the app, switcher to reconfigure your windows, you&#8217;re actually doing drag and drop as you rearrange your new split views, or you dismiss apps and so on. So it&#8217;s not a hidden model, it&#8217;s one where we really try to reinforce a spatial model with an explicit one for the user through all of the animations and all of the kinds of affordances.”</p>
<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.40.03-PM.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="breakout aligncenter size-full wp-image-2162369" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.40.03-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="573" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.40.03-PM.jpg 1528w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.40.03-PM.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.40.03-PM.jpg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.40.03-PM.jpg?resize=768,430 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.40.03-PM.jpg?resize=680,380 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.40.03-PM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p class="p1">Apple’s goal this time around, he says, was to add affordances for the user to understand that multitasking was even an option — like the small series of dots at the top of every app and window that now allows you to explicitly choose an available configuration, rather than the app-and-dock-juggling method of the past. He goes on to say that consistency was a key metric for them on this version of the OS. The appearance of Slide Over apps in the same switcher view as all other apps, for instance. Or the way that you can choose configurations of apps via the button, by drag and drop in the switcher and get the same results.</p>
<p class="p1">In the dashboard, Marineau-Mes says, “you get an at a glance view of all of the apps that you&#8217;re running and a full model of how you&#8217;re navigating that through the iPad’s interface.”</p>
<p class="p1">This ‘at a glance’ map of the system should be very welcome by advanced users. Even as a very aggressive Pro user myself, Slide Over apps became more of a nuisance than anything because I couldn&#8217;t keep track of how many were open and when to use them. The ability to combine them on the switcher itself is one of those things that Apple has wanted to get into the OS for years but is just now making its way onto iPads. Persistence of organization, really, was the critical problem to tackle.</p>
<p class="p1">“I think we believe strongly in building a mental model where people know where things are [on iPad],” says Marineau-Mes. “And I think you&#8217;re right when it comes persistence I think it also applies to, for example, home screen. People have a very strong mental model of where things are in the home screen as well as all of the apps that they&#8217;ve configured. And so we try to maintain a well maintained that mental model, and also allow people to reorganize again in the switcher.”</p>
<p class="p1">He goes on to explain the new ‘shelf’ feature that displays every instance or window that an app has open within itself. They implemented this as a per-app feature rather than a system-wide feature, he says, because the association of that shelf with a particular app fit the overall mental model that they’re trying to build. The value of this shelf may jump into higher relief when more professional apps that may have a dozen documents or windows open at once and active during a project ship later this year.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.43.17-PM.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="breakout aligncenter size-full wp-image-2162379" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.43.17-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="573" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.43.17-PM.jpg 1528w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.43.17-PM.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.43.17-PM.jpg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.43.17-PM.jpg?resize=768,430 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.43.17-PM.jpg?resize=680,380 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.43.17-PM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p class="p1">Another nod to advanced users in iPadOS 15 is the rich keyboard shortcut set offered across the system. The interface can be navigated by arrow keys now, many advanced commands are there and you can even move around on an iPad using a game controller.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">“One of the key goals this year was to make basically everything in the system navigable from the keyboard,” says Marineau-Mes, “so that if you don’t want to, you don’t have to take your hands off the keyboard. All of the new multitasking affordances and features, you can do through the keyboard shortcuts. You&#8217;ve got the new keyboard shortcut menu bar where you can see all the shortcuts that are available. It&#8217;s great for discoverability. You can search them and we even, you know, and this is a subtle point, but we even made a very conscious effort to rationalize the shortcuts across Mac and iPadOS. So that if you&#8217;re using universal control, for example, you’re going to go from one environment to the other seamlessly. You want to ensure that consistency as you go across.”</p>
<p class="p1">The gestures, however, are staying as a nod to consistency for existing users that may be used to those.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ipadOS-15-multitasking.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="breakout aligncenter size-full wp-image-2162376" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ipadOS-15-multitasking.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ipadOS-15-multitasking.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ipadOS-15-multitasking.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ipadOS-15-multitasking.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ipadOS-15-multitasking.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ipadOS-15-multitasking.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ipadOS-15-multitasking.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ipadOS-15-multitasking.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-ipadOS-15-multitasking.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p class="p1">To me, one of the more interesting and potentially powerful developments is the introduction of the Center Window and its accompanying API. A handful of Apple apps like Mail, Notes and Messages now allow items to pop out into an overlapping window.</p>
<p class="p1">“It was a very deliberate decision on our part,” says Marineau-Mes about adding this new element. “This really brings a new level of productivity where you can have, you know, this floating window. You can have content behind it. You can seamlessly cut and paste. And that&#8217;s something that&#8217;s just not possible with the traditional [iPadOS] model. And we also really strive to make it consistent with the rest of multitasking where that center window can also become one of the windows in your split view, or full size, and then go back to to being a center window. We think it’s a cool addition to the model and we look really look forward to 3rd parties embracing it.”</p>
<p class="p1">Early reception of the loop Apple gave at iPadOS 15 has an element of reservation about it still given that many of the most powerful creative apps are made by third parties that must adopt these technologies in order for them to be truly useful. But Apple, Borchers says, is working hard to make sure that pro apps adopt as many of these new paradigms and technologies as possible, so that come fall, the iPad will feel like a more hospitable host for the kinds of advanced work pros want to do there.</p>
<p class="p1">One of the nods to this multi-modal universe that the iPad exists in is Universal Control. This new feature uses Bluetooth beaconing, peer-to-peer WiFi and the iPad’s touchpad support to allow you to place your devices close to one another and — in a clever use of reading user intent — slide your mouse to the edge of a screen and onto your Mac or iPad seamlessly.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2165436" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple.WWDC21.Craig_Federighi.04.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2165436" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2165436" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple.WWDC21.Craig_Federighi.04.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple.WWDC21.Craig_Federighi.04.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple.WWDC21.Craig_Federighi.04.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple.WWDC21.Craig_Federighi.04.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple.WWDC21.Craig_Federighi.04.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple.WWDC21.Craig_Federighi.04.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple.WWDC21.Craig_Federighi.04.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple.WWDC21.Craig_Federighi.04.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple.WWDC21.Craig_Federighi.04.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2165436" class="wp-caption-text">CUPERTINO, CALIFORNIA &#8211; June 7, 2021: Apple&#8217;s senior vice president of Software Engineering Craig Federighi showcases the ease of Universal Control, as seen in this still image from the keynote video of AppleÕs Worldwide Developers Conference at Apple Park. (Photo Credit: Apple Inc.)Ê</p></div></p>
<p class="p1">“I think what we have seen and observed from our users, both pro and and otherwise, is that we have lots of people who have Macs and they have iPads, and they have other iPhones and and we believe in making these things work together in ways that are that are powerful,” says Borchers. “And it just felt like a natural place to be able to go and extend our Continuity model so that you could make use of this incredible platform that is iPadOS while working with your Mac, right next to it. And I think the big challenge was, how do you do that in kind of a magical, simple way. And that&#8217;s what Seb and his team and been able to accomplish.</p>
<p class="p1">“It really builds on the foundation we made with Continuity and Sidecar,” adds Marineau-Mes. “We really thought a lot about how do you make the experience — the set up experience — as seamless as possible. How do you discover that you&#8217;ve got devices side by side.?</p>
<p class="p1">The other thing we thought about was what are the workflows that people want to have and what capabilities that will be essential for that. That’s where thinks like the ability to seamlessly drag content across the platforms or cut and paste was we felt to be really, really important. Because I think that&#8217;s really what brings to the magic to the experience.”</p>
<p class="p1">Borchers adds that it makes all the continuity features that much more discoverable. Continuity’s shared clipboard, for instance, is an always on but invisible presence. Expanding that to visual and mouse-driven models made some natural sense.</p>
<p class="p1">“It&#8217;s just like, oh, of course, I can drag that all the way across all the way across here,” he says.</p>
<p class="p1">“Bob, you say, of course,” Marineau-Mes laughs. “And yet for those of us working in platforms for a long time, the ‘of course’, is technically very, very challenging. Totally non obvious.”</p>
<p class="p1">Another area where iPadOS 15 is showing some promising expansionary behavior is in system-wide activities that allow you to break out of the box of in-app thinking. These include embedded recommendations that seed themselves into various apps, Shareplay, which makes an appearance wherever video calls are found and Live Text, which turns all of your photos into indexed archives searchable with a keyboard.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Another is Quick Note, a system extension that lets you swipe from the bottom corner of your screen wherever you are in the system.</p>
<p class="p1">“There are, I think a few interesting things that we did with with Quick Note,” says Marineau-Mes. “One is this idea of linking. So, that if I&#8217;m working in Safari or Yelp or another app, I can quickly insert a link to whatever content I&#8217;m viewing. I don&#8217;t know about you, but it&#8217;s something that I certainly do a lot when I do research.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">“The old way was, like, cut and paste and maybe take a screenshot, create a note and jot down some notes. And now we&#8217;ve made that very, very seamless and fluid across the whole system. It even works the other way where, if I&#8217;m now in Safari and I have a note that refers to that page in Safari, you&#8217;ll see it revealed as a thumbnail at the bottom of the screen’s right hand side. So, we&#8217;ve really tried to bring the notes experience to be something that just permeates the system and is easily accessible from, from everywhere.”<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.45.45-PM.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="breakout aligncenter size-full wp-image-2162384" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.45.45-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="573" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.45.45-PM.jpg 1528w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.45.45-PM.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.45.45-PM.jpg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.45.45-PM.jpg?resize=768,430 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.45.45-PM.jpg?resize=680,380 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.45.45-PM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p class="p1">Many of the system-wide capabilities that Apple is introducing in iPadOS 15 and iOS 15 have an API that developers can tap into. That is not always the case with Apple’s newest toys, which in years past have often been left to linger in the private section of its list of frameworks rather than be offered to developers as a way to enhance their apps. Borchers says that this is an intentional move that offers a ‘broader foundation of intelligence’ across the entire system.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This broader intelligence includes Siri moving a <i>ton</i> of commands to its local scope. This involved having to move a big chunk of Apple’s speech recognition to an on-device configuration in the new OS as well. The results, says Borchers, are a vastly improved day-to-day Siri experience, with many common commands executing immediately upon request — something that was a bit of a dice roll in days of Siri past. The removal of the reputational hit that Siri was taking from commands that went up to the cloud never to return could be the beginning of a turnaround for the public perception of Siri’s usefulness.</p>
<p class="p1">The on-device weaving of the intelligence provided by the Apple Neural Engine (ANE) also includes the indexing of text across photos in the entire system, past, present and in-the-moment.</p>
<p class="p1">“We could have done live text only in camera and photos, but we wanted it to apply to anywhere we&#8217;ve got images, whether it be in in Safari or quick look or wherever,” says Marineau-Mes. “One of my favorite demos of live text is actually when you&#8217;ve got that long complicated field for a password for a Wi-Fi network. You can just actually bring it up within the keyboard and take a picture of it, get the text in it and copy and paste it into into the field. It&#8217;s one of those things that&#8217;s just kind of magical.”</p>
<p class="p1">On the developer service front of iPadOS 15, I ask specifically about Swift Playgrounds, which add the ability to write, compile and ship apps on the App Store for the first time completely on iPad. It’s not the native Xcode some developers were hoping for, but, Borchers says, Playgrounds has moved beyond just ‘teaching people how to code’ and into a real part of many developer pipelines.</p>
<p class="p1">“ think one of the big insights here was that we also saw a number of kind of pro developers using it as a prototyping platform, and a way to be able to be on the bus, or in the park, or wherever if you wanted to get in and give something a try, this was super accessible and easy way to get there and could be a nice adjunct to hey, I want to learn to code.”</p>
<p class="p1">“If you&#8217;re a developer,” adds Marineau-Mes, “it&#8217;s actually more productive to be able to run that app on the device that you&#8217;re working on because you really get great fidelity. And with the open project format, you can go back and forth between Xcode and Playgrounds. So, as Bob said, we can really envision people using this for a lot of rapid prototyping on the go without having to bring along the rest of their development environment so we think it&#8217;s a really, really powerful addition to our development development tools this year.”</p>
<p class="p1">
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">I can’t be the only developer wondering just how much of my apps I could shoehorn into Swift Playgrounds now that it can build apps, just so I can tweak them on the go <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f605.png" alt="😅" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Especially since it supports UIKit development, not just SwiftUI, and Swift packages <a href="https://t.co/vpsEMlVigs">pic.twitter.com/vpsEMlVigs</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Steve Troughton-Smith (@stroughtonsmith) <a href="https://twitter.com/stroughtonsmith/status/1403564778518454273?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 12, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
</p>
<p class="p1">Way back in 2018 I <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/05/apples-2019-imac-pro-will-be-shaped-by-workflows/">profiled a new team</a> at Apple that was building out a testing apparatus that would help them to make sure they were addressing real-world use cases for flows of process that included machines like the (at the time un-revealed) new Mac Pro, iMacs, MacBooks and iPads. One of the demos that stood out at the time was a deep integration with music apps like Logic that would allow the input models of iPad to complement the core app. Tapping out a rhythm on a pad, brightening or adjusting sound more intuitively with the touch interface. More of Apple’s work these days seems to be aimed at allowing users to move seamlessly back and forth between its various computing platforms, taking advantage of the strengths of each (raw power, portability, touch, etc) to complement a workflow. A lot of iPadOS 15 appears to be geared this way.</p>
<p class="p1">Whether it will be enough to turn the corner on the perception of iPad as a work device that is being held back by software, I’ll reserve judgement until it ships later this year. But, in the near term, I am cautiously optimistic that this set of enhancements that break out of the ‘app box’, the clearer affordances for multitasking both in and out of single apps and the dedication to API support are pointing towards an expansionist mentality on the iPad software team. A good sign in general.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3XQJ93dFCD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-the-wwdc-2021-keynote/">Here&#8217;s everything Apple announced at the WWDC 2021 keynote</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Here&#8217;s everything Apple announced at the WWDC 2021 keynote&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-the-wwdc-2021-keynote/embed/#?secret=3XQJ93dFCD" data-secret="3XQJ93dFCD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/apples-ipados-15-breaks-the-app-barrier/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165435</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 new security features Apple quietly announced at WWDC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/7-new-security-features-apple-quietly-announced-at-wwdc/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/7-new-security-features-apple-quietly-announced-at-wwdc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 15:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clipboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[control center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[face id]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iCloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS 14]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keychain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online purchases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siri]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple went big on security and privacy during its Worldwide Developer Conference (WWDC) keynote this week, showcasing features from on-device Siri audio processing to a new privacy dashboard for iOS that makes it easier than ever to see which apps are collecting your data and when. While typically vocal about security during the Memoji-filled, two-hour-long(!) [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple went big on security and privacy during its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-the-wwdc-2021-keynote/">Worldwide Developer Conference (WWDC) keynote</a> this week, showcasing features from on-device Siri audio processing to a new privacy dashboard for iOS that makes it easier than ever to see which apps are collecting your data and when.</p>
<p>While typically vocal about security during the Memoji-filled, two-hour-long(!) keynote, the company also quietly introduced several new security and privacy-focused features during its WWDC developer sessions. We’ve rounded up some of the most interesting — and important.</p>
<h3>Passwordless login with iCloud Keychain</h3>
<p>Apple is the latest tech company taking steps to ditch the password. During its “<a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2021/10106/">Move beyond passwords</a>” developer session, it previewed Passkeys in iCloud Keychain, a method of passwordless authentication powered by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/10/fido-alliance-and-w3c-have-a-plan-to-kill-the-password/">WebAuthn</a>, and Face ID and Touch ID.</p>
<p>The feature, which will ultimately be available in both <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-wwdc-2021-privacy-security/">iOS 15</a> and macOS Monterey, means you no longer have to set a password when creating an account or a website or app. Instead, you’ll simply pick a username, and then use Face ID or Touch ID to confirm it’s you. The passkey is then stored in your keychain and then synced across your Apple devices using iCloud — so you don&#8217;t have to remember it, nor do you have to carry around a hardware authenticator key.</p>
<p>&#8220;Because it&#8217;s just a single tap to sign in, it&#8217;s simultaneously easier, faster and more secure than almost all common forms of authentication today,&#8221; said Garrett Davidson, an Apple authentication experience engineer.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>While it’s unlikely to be available on your iPhone or Mac any time soon — Apple says the feature is still in its ‘early stages’ and it&#8217;s currently disabled by default — the move is another sign of the growing momentum behind eliminating passwords, which are prone to being forgotten, reused across multiple services, and — ultimately — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/phishing/">phishing attacks</a>. Microsoft previously announced plans to make <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/windows-10/">Windows 10</a> password-free, and Google recently confirmed that it&#8217;s working towards &#8220;creating a future where one day you won’t need a password at all&#8221;.</p>
<h3>Microphone indicator in macOS</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2165424" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2165424" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2165424" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/microphoned-etect-macos.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="632" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/microphoned-etect-macos.jpg 800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/microphoned-etect-macos.jpg?resize=150,119 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/microphoned-etect-macos.jpg?resize=300,237 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/microphoned-etect-macos.jpg?resize=768,607 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/microphoned-etect-macos.jpg?resize=680,537 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/microphoned-etect-macos.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2165424" class="wp-caption-text">macOS has a new indicator to tell you when the microphone is on. (Image: Apple)</p></div></p>
<p>Since the introduction of iOS 14, iPhone users have been able to keep an eye on which apps are accessing their microphone via a green or orange dot in the status bar. Now it&#8217;s coming to the desktop too.</p>
<p>In macOS Monterey, users will be able to see which apps are accessing their Mac&#8217;s microphone in Control Center, <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/06/07/ios-15-macos-monterey-privacy-features/">MacRumors</a> reports, which will complement the existing hardware-based green light that appears next to a Mac&#8217;s webcam when the camera is in use.</p>
<h3>Secure paste</h3>
<p>iOS 15, which will include a bunch of privacy-bolstering tools from Mail Privacy Protection to App Privacy Reports, is also getting a feature called Secure Paste that will help to shield your clipboard data from other apps.</p>
<p>This feature will enable users to paste content from one app to another, without the second app being able to access the information on the clipboard until you paste it. This is a significant improvement over iOS 14, which would notify when an app took data from the clipboard but did nothing to prevent it from happening.</p>
<p><b>“</b>With secure paste, developers can let users paste from a different app without having access to what was copied until the user takes action to paste it into their app,” <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/06/apple-advances-its-privacy-leadership-with-ios-15-ipados-15-macos-monterey-and-watchos-8/">Apple explains</a>. “When developers use secure paste, users will be able to paste without being alerted via the [clipboard] transparency notification, helping give them peace of mind.”</p>
<p>While this feature sounds somewhat insignificant, it’s being introduced following a major privacy issue that came to light last year. In March 2020, security researchers revealed that dozens of popular iOS apps — including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/tiktok/">TikTok</a> — were “snooping” on users’ clipboard without their consent, potentially accessing highly sensitive data.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NI8glTQGQ2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-wwdc-2021-privacy-security/">Apple unveils new iOS 15 privacy features at WWDC</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple unveils new iOS 15 privacy features at WWDC&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-wwdc-2021-privacy-security/embed/#?secret=NI8glTQGQ2" data-secret="NI8glTQGQ2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Advanced Fraud Protection for Apple Card</h3>
<p>Payments fraud is more prevalent than ever as a result of the pandemic, and Apple is looking to do something about it. As first reported by <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/06/08/apple-card-fraud-apple-pay-redesign/#more-728659">9to5Mac</a>, the company has previewed Advanced Fraud Protection, a feature that will let <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/apple-card/">Apple Card</a> users generate new card numbers in the Wallet app.</p>
<p>While details remain thin — the feature isn’t live in the first iOS 15 developer beta — Apple’s explanation suggests that Advanced Fraud Protection will make it possible to generate new security codes — the three-digit number you enter at checkout – when making online purchases.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>“With Advanced Fraud Protection, Apple Card users can have a security code that changes regularly to make online Card Number transactions even more secure,” the brief explainer reads.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> We&#8217;ve asked Apple for some more information. </span></p>
<h3>&#8216;Unlock with Apple Watch&#8217; for Siri requests</h3>
<p>As a result of the widespread mask-wearing necessitated by the pandemic, Apple introduced an ‘Unlock with Apple Watch’ in iOS 14.5 that enabled users to unlock their iPhone and authenticate <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/apple-pay/">Apple Pay</a> payments using an Apple Watch instead of Face ID.</p>
<p>The scope of this feature is expanding with iOS 15, as the company has confirmed that users will soon be able to use this alternative authentication method for Siri requests, such as adjusting phone settings or reading messages. Currently, users have to enter a PIN, password or use Face ID to do so.</p>
<p>“Use the secure connection to your Apple Watch for Siri requests or to unlock your iPhone when an obstruction, like a mask, prevents Face ID from recognizing your Face,” Apple explains. Your watch must be passcode protected, unlocked, and on your wrist close by.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vwCqhA3F3M"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-announces-icloud-with-privacy-focused-features/">Apple announces iCloud+ with privacy-focused features</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple announces iCloud+ with privacy-focused features&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-announces-icloud-with-privacy-focused-features/embed/#?secret=vwCqhA3F3M" data-secret="vwCqhA3F3M" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Standalone security patches</h3>
<p>To ensure iPhone users who don’t want to upgrade to iOS 15 straight away are up to date with security updates, Apple is going to start decoupling patches from feature updates.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> When</span> iOS 15 lands later this year, users will be given the option to update to the latest version of iOS or to stick with iOS 14 and simply install the latest security fixes.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>“iOS now offers a choice between two software update versions in the Settings app,” Apple explains (via <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/06/07/apple-wont-make-you-upgrade-to-ios-15/">MacRumors</a>). “You can update to the latest version of iOS 15 as soon as it&#8217;s released for the latest features and most complete set of security updates. Or continue on ‌iOS 14‌ and still get important security updates until you&#8217;re ready to upgrade to the next major version.”</p>
<p>This feature sees Apple following in the footsteps of Google, which has long rolled out monthly security patches to Android users.</p>
<h3>‘Erase all contents and settings’ for Mac</h3>
<p>Wiping a Mac has been a laborious task that has required you to erase your device completely then reinstall macOS.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> T</span>hankfully, that&#8217;s going to change. Apple is bringing the “erase all contents and settings” option that&#8217;s been on iPhones and iPads for years to macOS Monterey.</p>
<p>The option will let you factory reset your MacBook with just a click. “System Preferences now offers an option to erase all user data and user-installed apps from the system, while maintaining the operating system currently installed,” <a href="https://www.apple.com/macos/monterey-preview/features/">Apple says</a>. “Because storage is always encrypted on Mac systems with Apple Silicon or the T2 chip, the system is instantly and securely &#8216;erased&#8217; by destroying the encryption keys.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="V5APlvoSjK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-the-wwdc-2021-keynote/">Here&#8217;s everything Apple announced at the WWDC 2021 keynote</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Here&#8217;s everything Apple announced at the WWDC 2021 keynote&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-the-wwdc-2021-keynote/embed/#?secret=V5APlvoSjK" data-secret="V5APlvoSjK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/7-new-security-features-apple-quietly-announced-at-wwdc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165042</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This Week in Apps: WWDC 21 highlights, Instagram Creator Week recap, Android 12 beta 2 arrives</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/this-week-in-apps-wwdc-21-highlights-instagram-creator-week-recap-android-12-beta-2-arrives/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/this-week-in-apps-wwdc-21-highlights-instagram-creator-week-recap-android-12-beta-2-arrives/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 14:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app stores]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[augmented reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPados]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swift]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[This Week In Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wwdc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WWDC 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xcode]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164628</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to This Week in Apps, the weekly TechCrunch series that recaps the latest in mobile OS news, mobile applications and the overall app economy. The app industry continues to grow, with a record 218 billion downloads and $143 billion in global consumer spend in 2020. Consumers last year also spent 3.5 trillion minutes using apps on Android devices [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Welcome back to This Week in Apps, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/this-week-in-apps/">the weekly TechCrunch series</a> that recaps the latest in mobile OS news, mobile applications and the overall app economy.</p>
<p>The app industry continues to grow, with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a record</a> 218 billion downloads and $143 billion in global consumer spend in 2020. Consumers last year also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/">spent</a> 3.5 trillion minutes using apps on Android devices alone. And in the U.S., app usage surged ahead of the time spent watching live TV. Currently, the average American <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/">watches</a> 3.7 hours of live TV per day, but now spends four hours per day on their mobile devices.</p>
<p>Apps aren’t just a way to pass idle hours — they’re also a big business. In 2019, mobile-first companies had a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/app-stores-saw-record-204-billion-app-downloads-in-2019-consumer-spend-of-120-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">combined</a> $544 billion valuation, 6.5x higher than those without a mobile focus. In 2020, investors <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/">poured</a> $73 billion in capital into mobile companies — a figure that’s up 27% year-over-year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This week, our series will take a dive into the key announcements impacting app developers from WWDC 21.</p>
<p><em><strong>This Week in Apps will soon be a newsletter! Sign up here: <a href="http://techcrunch.com/newsletters">techcrunch.com/newsletters</a></strong></em></p>
<h1>WWDC 21 Wrap-Up</h1>
<p><div id="attachment_2162553" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162553" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2162553" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-tim-cook-crowd-e1623094087992.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="356" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162553" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>Apple&#8217;s WWDC went virtual again this year, but it didn&#8217;t slow down the pace of announcements. This week, Apple introduced a slate of new developer tools and frameworks, changes to iOS that will impact how consumers use their devices and new rules for publishing on its App Store, among other things. We don&#8217;t have the bandwidth to dig into every dev update &#8212; and truly, there are better places to learn about, say, the new <a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2021/10017/">concurrency</a> capabilities of <a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2021/10192/">Swift</a> 5.5 or what&#8217;s <a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2021/10018/">new with SwiftUI</a>.</p>
<p>But after a few days of processing everything new, here&#8217;s what&#8217;s jumping out as the bigger takeaways and updates.</p>
<h2><strong>Xcode Cloud</strong></h2>
<p>Apple&#8217;s development IDE, Xcode 13, now includes <a href="https://developer.apple.com/xcode-cloud/">Xcode Cloud</a>, a built-in continuous integration and delivery service hosted on Apple&#8217;s cloud infrastructure. Apple says the service, birthed out of its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/02/apple-buys-app-development-service-buddybuild/">2018 Buddybuild acquisition</a>, will help to speed up the pace of development by combining cloud-based tools for building apps along with tools to run automated tests in parallel, deliver apps to testers via TestFlight and view tester feedback through the web-based App Store Connect dashboard. Beyond the immediate improvements to the development process (which developers are incredibly <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=xcode%20cloud%20excited&amp;src=typed_query&amp;f=live">excited</a> about based on #WWDC21 <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=xcode%20cloud&amp;src=typed_query">tweets)</a> Xcode Cloud represents a big step by Apple further into the cloud services space, where Amazon (AWS), Google and Microsoft have dominated. While Xcode Cloud may not replace solutions designed for larger teams with more diverse needs, it&#8217;s poised to make app development easier &#8212; and deliver a new revenue stream to Apple. <em>If only Apple had announced the pricing! </em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Jenkins has left the chat. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/XcodeCloud?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#XcodeCloud</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Alphonso Sensley II (@AlphonsoSensley) <a href="https://twitter.com/AlphonsoSensley/status/1401975504375324678?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 7, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<h2>Swift Playgrounds 4</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2165169" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2165169" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2165169" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple_iPadPro-iPadOS15-SwiftUI-Submit-to-Store_060721.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple_iPadPro-iPadOS15-SwiftUI-Submit-to-Store_060721.jpg 2400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple_iPadPro-iPadOS15-SwiftUI-Submit-to-Store_060721.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple_iPadPro-iPadOS15-SwiftUI-Submit-to-Store_060721.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple_iPadPro-iPadOS15-SwiftUI-Submit-to-Store_060721.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple_iPadPro-iPadOS15-SwiftUI-Submit-to-Store_060721.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple_iPadPro-iPadOS15-SwiftUI-Submit-to-Store_060721.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple_iPadPro-iPadOS15-SwiftUI-Submit-to-Store_060721.jpg?resize=2048,2048 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple_iPadPro-iPadOS15-SwiftUI-Submit-to-Store_060721.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple_iPadPro-iPadOS15-SwiftUI-Submit-to-Store_060721.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple_iPadPro-iPadOS15-SwiftUI-Submit-to-Store_060721.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple_iPadPro-iPadOS15-SwiftUI-Submit-to-Store_060721.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple_iPadPro-iPadOS15-SwiftUI-Submit-to-Store_060721.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2165169" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>Swift Playgrounds got a <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/06/apple-introduces-new-developer-tools-and-technologies-to-create-even-better-apps/">notable update</a> in iPadOS 15, as it will now allow developers to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/ipados-15-announced-at-wwdc-features-improved-multitasking-and-improved-swift-playgrounds-support/">build iPhone and iPad apps</a> right on their iPad and submit them to the App Store. In Swift Playgrounds 4, coming later this year, Apple says developers will be able to create the visual design of an app using SwiftUI, see the live preview of their app&#8217;s code while building and can run their apps full-screen to test them out. App projects can also be opened and edited with either Swift Playgrounds or Xcode.</p>
<p>While it&#8217;s not the Xcode on iPad system some developers <a href="https://twitter.com/AndyyHope/status/1401959409966850054">have been requesting</a>, it will make app building more accessible because of iPad&#8217;s lower price point compared with Mac. It could also encourage more people to try app development, as Swift Playgrounds helps student coders learn the basics then move up to more challenging lessons over time. Now, they can actually build real apps and hit the publish button, too.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">I had to save for a couple of months &#8211; 8-10 months before buying my first Mac.<br />Swift playgrounds on iPad is a very welcome move!</p>
<p>&mdash; Pinal Naik (@swift_geek) <a href="https://twitter.com/swift_geek/status/1401968098496765953?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 7, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<h2><strong>App Store</strong></h2>
<p>Antitrust pressure swirling around Apple has contributed to a growing sentiment among some developers that Apple doesn&#8217;t do enough to help them grow their businesses &#8212; and therefore, is undeserving of a 15%-30% cut of the revenues the developers themselves worked to gain. The new App Store updates may start to chip away at that perception.</p>
<p>Soon, developers will be able to <a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2021/10295/">create up to 35 custom product pages</a> targeted toward different users, each with their unique URL for sharing and analytics for measuring performance. The pages can include different preview videos, screenshots and text.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2162540" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162540" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2162540" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-app-store-icon-variants-e1623094067137.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="326" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162540" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>Apple will also allow developers to split traffic between three treatments of the app&#8217;s default page to measure which ones convert best, then choose the percentage of the App Store audience that will see one of the three treatments.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the App Store will <a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2021/10171/">begin to show to customers in-app events</a> taking place inside developers&#8217; apps &#8212; like game competitions, fitness challenges, film premieres and more &#8212; effectively driving traffic to apps and re-engaging users. Combined, Apple is making the case that its App Store can drive discovery beyond just offering an app listing page.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3kLoqXzxfF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-to-introduce-a-b-testing-and-in-app-events-to-the-app-store/">Apple to introduce A/B testing and in-app events to the App Store</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple to introduce A/B testing and in-app events to the App Store&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-to-introduce-a-b-testing-and-in-app-events-to-the-app-store/embed/#?secret=3kLoqXzxfF" data-secret="3kLoqXzxfF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Beyond the App Store product itself, Apple <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apples-new-app-store-guidelines-aim-to-crack-down-on-fraud-and-scams/">overhauled</a> its App Store policies to address the growing problem of scam apps. The changes give Apple permission to crack down on scammers by removing offenders from its Developer Program. The new guidelines also allow developers to report spam directly to Apple, instead of, you know, relying on <a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou">tweets</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/apple-urged-to-root-out-rating-scams-as-developer-highlights-ugly-cost-of-enforcement-failure/">press</a>.</p>
<p>Apple has historically downplayed the scam problem. It noted how the App Store stopped <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/05/app-store-stopped-over-1-5-billion-in-suspect-transactions-in-2020/">over $1.5 billion in fraudulent transactions</a> in 2020, for example. Even if it&#8217;s a small percentage of the App Store, scam apps with fake ratings not only can cheat users out of <a href="https://www.phonearena.com/news/another-ios-vpn-app-scam-is-uncovered_id131487">millions</a> of dollars, they reduce consumer trust in the App Store and Apple itself, which has longer-term consequences for the ecosystem health. What&#8217;s unclear, however, is why Apple is seemingly trying to solve the App Review issues using forms &#8212; to report fraud (and now, to appeal rulings, too) when it&#8217;s becoming apparent that Apple needs a more systematic way of keeping tabs on the app ecosystem beyond the initial review process.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eZtKSciJ7g"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apples-new-app-store-guidelines-aim-to-crack-down-on-fraud-and-scams/">Apple&#8217;s new App Store Guidelines aim to crack down on fraud and scams</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple&#8217;s new App Store Guidelines aim to crack down on fraud and scams&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apples-new-app-store-guidelines-aim-to-crack-down-on-fraud-and-scams/embed/#?secret=eZtKSciJ7g" data-secret="eZtKSciJ7g" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2><strong>Notifications overhaul</strong></h2>
<p>The App Store discovery updates mentioned above also matter more because developers may need to reduce their reliance on notifications to send users back into their apps. Indeed, iOS 15 users will be able to choose which apps they don&#8217;t need to hear from right away &#8212; these <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-refines-ios-15-notifications-with-focus-summary-features/">will be rounded up into a new Notification Summary</a> that arrives on a schedule they configure, where Siri intelligence helps determine which apps get a top spot. If an app was already struggling to re-engage users through push notifications, getting relegated to the end of a summary is not going to help matters.</p>
<p>And users can &#8220;Send to Summary&#8221; right from the Lock Screen notification itself in addition to the existing options to &#8220;Deliver Quietly&#8221; or be turned off. That  means any ill-timed push could be an app developer&#8217;s last.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2162275" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162275" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2162275" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.17.58-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="380" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.17.58-PM.jpg 1528w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.17.58-PM.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.17.58-PM.jpg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.17.58-PM.jpg?resize=768,430 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.17.58-PM.jpg?resize=680,380 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.17.58-PM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162275" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>Meanwhile, the clever <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-refines-ios-15-notifications-with-focus-summary-features/">new &#8220;Focus&#8221; modes</a> let iOS users configure different quiet modes for work, play, sleeping and more, each with their own set of rules and even their own home screens. But making this work across the app ecosystem will require developer adoption of <a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2021/10091/">four &#8220;interruption levels,&#8221; ranging from passive to critical</a>. A new episode of a fav show should be a &#8220;passive&#8221; notification, for example. &#8220;Active&#8221; is the default setting &#8212; which doesn&#8217;t get to break into Focus. &#8220;Time sensitive&#8221; notifications should be reserved for alerting to more urgent matters, like a delivery that&#8217;s arrived on your doorstep or an account security update. These may be able to break through Focus, if allowed.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2162274" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162274" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2162274" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-notifications.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162274" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Critical&#8221; notifications would be reserved for emergencies, like severe weather alerts or local safety updates. While there is a chance developers may abuse the new system to get their alert through, they risk users silencing their notifications entirely or deleting the app. Focus mode users will be power users and more technically savvy, so they&#8217;ll understand that an errant notification here was a choice and not a mistake on the developer&#8217;s part.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2162531" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162531" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2162531" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-object-capture-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-object-capture-1.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-object-capture-1.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-object-capture-1.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-object-capture-1.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-object-capture-1.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-object-capture-1.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-object-capture-1.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-object-capture-1.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162531" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<h2><strong>Augmented Reality</strong></h2>
<p>Apple has been steadily pushing out more tools for building augmented reality apps, but this WWDC it just introduced a huge update that will make it easier for developers getting started with AR. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/apples-realitykit-2-allows-developers-to-create-3d-models-for-ar-using-iphone-photos/">With the launch of RealityKit 2</a>, Apple’s new Object Capture API will allow developers to create 3D models in minutes using only an iPhone or iPad (or a DSLR or drone if they choose).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DetAgXXRuQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/apples-realitykit-2-allows-developers-to-create-3d-models-for-ar-using-iphone-photos/">Apple&#8217;s RealityKit 2 allows developers to create 3D models for AR using iPhone photos</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple&#8217;s RealityKit 2 allows developers to create 3D models for AR using iPhone photos&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/apples-realitykit-2-allows-developers-to-create-3d-models-for-ar-using-iphone-photos/embed/#?secret=DetAgXXRuQ" data-secret="DetAgXXRuQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Explains Apple this will address one of the most difficult parts of making great AR apps, which was the process of creating 3D models. Before, this could take hours and cost thousands of dollars &#8212; now, developers with just an iPhone and Mac can participate. The impacts of this update will be seen in the months and years ahead, as developers adopt the new tools for things like AR shopping, games and other AR experiences &#8212; including ones we may not have seen yet, but are enabled by more accessible AR technology tools and frameworks.</p>
<h2><strong>SharePlay</strong></h2>
<p>This update is unexpected and interesting, despite missing what would have been an ideal launch window: mid-pandemic back in 2020. With <a href="https://developer.apple.com/shareplay/">SharePlay</a>, developers can bring their apps into what Apple is calling &#8220;Group Activities&#8221; &#8212; or shared experiences that take place right inside FaceTime.</p>
<p>If you were co-watching Hulu with friends during the pandemic, you get the idea. But Apple isn&#8217;t tacking on some co-viewing system here. Instead, it&#8217;s introducing new APIs that let users listen to music, stream video or screen share with friends, in a way that feels organic to FaceTime. There was a hint of serving the locked-down COVID-19 pandemic crowd with this update, as Apple talks about making people feel as if they&#8217;re &#8220;in the same room&#8221; &#8212; a nod to those many months where that was not possible. And that may have inspired the changes, to be sure. Similarly, FaceTime&#8217;s support for Android and scheduled calls &#8212; a clear case of Zoom envy &#8212; feels like a case of playing catch-up on Apple&#8217;s part.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2162251" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162251" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2162251" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-facetime-shareplay.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-facetime-shareplay.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-facetime-shareplay.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-facetime-shareplay.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-facetime-shareplay.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-facetime-shareplay.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-facetime-shareplay.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-facetime-shareplay.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-facetime-shareplay.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162251" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>The immediate demand for these sorts of experiences may be dulled by a population that&#8217;s starting to recover from the pandemic &#8212; people are now going out and seeing others in person again thanks to vaccines. But the ability to use apps while FaceTime&#8217;ing has a lifespan that extends beyond the COVID era, particularly among iPhone&#8217;s youngest users. The demographic growing up with smartphones at ever-younger ages<a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/teens-say-they-never-talk-on-the-phone-2015-12"> don&#8217;t place phone calls</a> &#8212; they text and FaceTime. <a href="https://melmagazine.com/en-us/story/teens-love-facetime">Some argue Gen Z even prefers the latter</a>.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2162252" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162252" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2162252" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.11.51-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="382" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.11.51-PM.jpg 1528w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.11.51-PM.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.11.51-PM.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.11.51-PM.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.11.51-PM.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Apple-WWDC-2021-2021-06-07-at-1.11.51-PM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162252" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>With its immediate support for Apple services like Apple Music and Apple TV+, SharePlay will hit the ground running &#8212; but it will only fully realize its vision with developer adoption. But such a system seems possibly only because of Apple&#8217;s tight control over its platform. It also gives a default iOS app a big advantage over third-parties.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="o9pxEOBiyP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-the-wwdc-2021-keynote/">Here&#8217;s everything Apple announced at the WWDC 2021 keynote</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Here&#8217;s everything Apple announced at the WWDC 2021 keynote&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-the-wwdc-2021-keynote/embed/#?secret=o9pxEOBiyP" data-secret="o9pxEOBiyP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3><strong>More</strong></h3>
<p>There were, of course, hundreds of updates announced this week, like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-maps-upgrade-brings-more-detailed-maps-transit-features-ar-view-and-more/">Spatial audio</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-refines-ios-15-notifications-with-focus-summary-features/">Focus modes</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-the-wwdc-2021-keynote/">AirPods updates</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/ipados-15-announced-at-wwdc-features-improved-multitasking-and-improved-swift-playgrounds-support/">iPadOS improvements</a> (widgets! multi-tasking), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-the-wwdc-2021-keynote/">Health updates</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-announces-icloud-with-privacy-focused-features/">iCloud+ with Private Relay</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/watchos-8-brings-new-mindfulness-features-and-respiratory-tracking/">watchOS improvements</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/spotlight-gets-more-powerful-in-ios-15-even-lets-you-install-apps/">Spotlight&#8217;s upgrade</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-unveils-macos-12-monterey/">macOS 12 Monterey</a> (with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/macos-12-monterey-upgrades-continuity-with-universal-control/">Continuity with Universal Control</a>), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-tv-to-support-using-homepod-mini-as-speakers-among-other-updates/">HomePod updates</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/apples-storekit-2-simplifies-app-store-subscriptions-and-refunds-by-making-them-accessible-inside-apps/">StoreKit 2</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-finally-launches-a-screen-time-api-for-app-developers/">Screen Time APIs</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/apples-new-shazamkit-brings-audio-recognition-to-apps-including-those-on-android/">ShazamKit</a>, <a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2021/10013/">App Clips improvements</a>, <a href="https://www.apple.com/ios/ios-15-preview/features/">Photos improvements</a> and <a href="https://www.apple.com/ios/ios-15-preview/features/">others</a>.</p>
<p>Many, however, were iterative updates &#8212; like<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-maps-upgrade-brings-more-detailed-maps-transit-features-ar-view-and-more/"> a better version Apple Maps</a>, for example, or Siri support for third-party devices. Others are Apple&#8217;s attempt to catch up with competitors, like the Google Lens-like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apples-live-text-lets-you-interact-with-text-in-your-photos/">&#8220;Live Text&#8221; update</a> for taking action on things snapped in your photos. The more significant changes, however, aren&#8217;t yet here &#8212; like the plan to <a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/22526184/digital-drivers-license-apple-ibm-idemia-id-tsa-phones">add Driver&#8217;s Licenses to Wallet</a> and the <a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/apple-says-its-new-logon-tech-is-as-easy-as-passwords-but-far-more-secure/">plan to shift to passwordless authentication systems</a>. These will change how we use devices for years to come.</p>
<h1>Weekly News</h1>
<h3>Platforms: Google</h3>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2728.png" alt="✨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Not to be outdone by WWDC (ha), Google this week </strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/google-launches-android-12-beta-2/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29"><strong>launched Android 12, beta 2</strong>.</a> This release brings more of the new features and design changes to users that weren&#8217;t yet available in the first beta which debuted at Google I/O. <a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2021/06/android-12-beta-2-update.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+blogspot%2FhsDu+%28Android+Developers+Blog%29">This includes</a> the new privacy dashboard; the addition of the mic and camera indicators that show when an app is using those features; an indication <a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/06/09/android-12-will-tell-you-when-apps-read-from-your-clipboard/">when an app is reading from the clipboard</a>; and a new panel that makes it easier to switch between internet providers or Wi-Fi networks.</p>
<p><strong>Google also this week <a href="https://blog.google/products/pixel/feature-drop-starry-videos-pride-wallpapers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+blogspot%2FMKuf+%28The+Keyword+%7C+Official+Google+Blog%29">released its next Pixel feature drop</a></strong> which brought new camera and photo features, privacy features, Google Assistant improvements and more. Highlights included a way to create stargazing videos, a car crash detection feature and a way to answer or reject calls hands-free.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/VDz1uX-ueLs?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<h3>E-commerce</h3>
<p><strong>Pinterest wants to get more users clicking &#8220;buy.&#8221;</strong> The company this week <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/pinterest-adds-a-shopping-list-feature-to-round-up-your-saved-products/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">added a new Shopping List feature</a> which automatically organizes your saved Product Pins for easier access.</p>
<h3>Augmented Reality</h3>
<p><strong>Google <a href="https://androidcommunity.com/google-discontinues-ar-based-app-measure-20210609/">discontinued</a> its AR-based app Measure,</strong> which had allowed users to measure things in the real world using the phone&#8217;s camera. The app had seen some stability and accuracy issues in the past.</p>
<h3>Fintech</h3>
<p><strong>Facebook&#8217;s Messenger app <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/messenger-adds-venmo-like-qr-codes-for-person-to-person-payments-in-the-u-s/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">added Venmo-like QR codes</a> for person-to-person payments inside its app in the U.S.</strong> Users can scan the codes to send or request a payment, even if they&#8217;re not Facebook friends with the other party. Payments are sent over Facebook Pay, which is backed by a users&#8217; credit card, debit card or a PayPal account.</p>
<p><strong>Downloads of fintech apps <a href="https://www.businessofapps.com/news/downloads-of-fintech-apps-up-132/">are up 132%</a> </strong>globally YoY according to an AppsFlyer marketing <a href="https://www.appsflyer.com/resources/others/finance-app-marketing-global/">report</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Twitter and Square CEO Jack Dorsey said Square is thinking about adding a bitcoin hardware wallet</strong> to its product lineup. The exec detailed some of the thinking behind the plan in a <a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1400839179513339905">Twitter thread</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Square is considering making a hardware wallet for <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/bitcoin?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#bitcoin</a>. If we do it, we would build it entirely in the open, from software to hardware design, and in collaboration with the community. We want to kick off this thinking the right way: by sharing some of our guiding principles.</p>
<p>&mdash; jack (@jack) <a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1400839179513339905?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 4, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<h3><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2728.png" alt="✨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Social: Creator Week recap</h3>
<p><strong>Instagram head Adam Mosseri said <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/09/instagram-ceo-facebook-will-help-users-get-around-apple-cut-of-transactions.html">Facebook will help creators</a> get around Apple&#8217;s 30% cut.</strong> While any transactions that take place in iOS will follow Apple&#8217;s rules, Mosseri said Facebook will look for other ways to help creators make a living where they don&#8217;t have to give up a portion of their revenue &#8212; like by connecting brands and creators offline or affiliate deals.</p>
<p><strong>Related to this, Instagram announced during its Creator Week event it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/instagram-adds-affiliate-and-shop-features-for-creators/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">will start testing a native affiliate tool</a> that will allow creators to recommend products and then earn commissions on those sales.</strong> Creators can also now link their merch shops to personal profiles instead of just business profiles, and by year-end, will be able to partner on merch and drops with companies like Bravado/UMG, Fanjoy, Represent and Spring.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2163788" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2163788" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2163788" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Affiliate-IG.jpeg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Affiliate-IG.jpeg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Affiliate-IG.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Affiliate-IG.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Affiliate-IG.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Affiliate-IG.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Affiliate-IG.jpeg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Affiliate-IG.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2163788" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Instagram</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Instagram <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/instagram-adds-affiliate-and-shop-features-for-creators/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">also rolled out a new &#8220;badge&#8221; for live videos</a> which lets viewers tip creators, similar to Facebook&#8217;s Stars.</strong> Facebook also said paid online events, fan subscriptions, badges and its upcoming news products will remain free through 2023. And it rolled out <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-creators-challenges-affiliate-commission-193917455.html">new features and challenges</a> to help creators earn additional payouts for hitting certain milestones.</p>
<p><strong>Finally, Instagram <a href="https://about.instagram.com/blog/announcements/shedding-more-light-on-how-instagram-works">in a blog post </a>explained how its algorithm works.</strong> The post details how the app decides what to show users first, why some posts get more views than others, how Explore works and other topics.</p>
<h3>Messaging</h3>
<p><strong>Giphy&#8217;s Clips (GIFs with sound) are <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/06/09/giphy-launches-video-gifs-imessage-app/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+9To5Mac-MacAllDay+%289+to+5+Mac+-+Apple+Intelligence%29">now available</a> in the Giphy iMessage app</strong>, instead of only on the web and in its iOS app. That means you can send the&#8230;uh, videos (??)&#8230;right from your keyboard.</p>
<h3>Dating</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2161712" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2161712" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2161712" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/phone_en-US.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="413" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/phone_en-US.png 1645w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/phone_en-US.png?resize=150,91 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/phone_en-US.png?resize=300,182 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/phone_en-US.png?resize=768,466 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/phone_en-US.png?resize=680,413 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/phone_en-US.png?resize=1536,933 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/phone_en-US.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2161712" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Tinder</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Match-owned dating app Tinder <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/tinder-finally-adds-a-block-contacts-feature/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">added a way for users to block contacts</a></strong>. The feature requires users grant the app permission to access the phone&#8217;s contacts database, which is a bit privacy-invasive. But then users can go through their contacts and check those they want to block on Tinder. The benefit is this would allow people to block exes and abusers. But on the downside, it permits cheating as users can block partners and those who might see them and report back.</p>
<h3>Streaming &amp; Entertainment</h3>
<p><strong>YouTube will allow creators to repurpose audio from existing YouTube videos</strong> as its &#8220;Shorts&#8221; product &#8212; basically, its TikTok competitor &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/youtube-expands-tiktok-rival-shorts-to-the-uk-canada-latin-america-lets-users-tap-all-of-youtube-for-tunes/">rolls out</a> to more global markets.</p>
<h3>Gaming</h3>
<p><strong>Google&#8217;s cross-platform cloud gaming service Google Stadia</strong> is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522416/google-stadia-chromecast-tv-nvidia-shield-android-devices-list-date">coming to Chromecast with Google TV and Android TV</a> starting on June 23.</p>
<p><strong>Roblox is generating estimated revenue of $3.01 million daily on iPhone</strong>, according to data from <a href="https://finbold.com/roblox-dominates-the-u-s-iphone-gaming-market/">Finbold</a>. Clash of Clans, Candy Crush Saga, Pokémon GO and others follow. Good thing if they have to pay up <a href="https://gamedaily.biz/article/2066/roblox-sued-for-200-million-by-national-music-publishers-association">over that music usage lawsuit</a>.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2164768" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164768" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2164768" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-10-at-6.01.58-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="582" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-10-at-6.01.58-PM.jpg 1436w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-10-at-6.01.58-PM.jpg?resize=150,128 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-10-at-6.01.58-PM.jpg?resize=300,257 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-10-at-6.01.58-PM.jpg?resize=768,658 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-10-at-6.01.58-PM.jpg?resize=680,582 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-10-at-6.01.58-PM.jpg?resize=50,43 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164768" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Finbold</p></div></p>
<h3>Utilities</h3>
<p><strong>Apple-owned weather app Dark Sky, whose technology just powered a big iOS 15 revamp of Apple&#8217;s stock weather app, is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/dark-sky-ios-app-and-website-are-likely-shutting-down-at-the-end-of-2022/">not shutting down just yet.</a></strong> The company announced its iOS app, web app and API will remain online through the end of 2022, instead of 2021 as planned.</p>
<h3>Productivity</h3>
<p><strong>Microsoft&#8217;s Outlook email app for iOS now <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22524014/microsoft-outlook-mobile-voice-dictation-emails-calendar">lets you use your voice to write emails</a> and schedule meetings.</strong> The feature leverages Cortana, and follows the launch of a Play My Emails feature inside Outlook Mobile.</p>
<h3>Government &amp; Policy</h3>
<p><strong>President <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/biden-revokes-and-replace-trump-actions-targeting-tiktok-and-wechat-report/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">Biden revoked and replaced Trump&#8217;s actions</a> which had targeted Chinese apps, like TikTok and WeChat.</strong> The president signed a new executive order that requires the Commerce Dept. to review apps with ties to &#8220;foreign adversaries&#8221; that may pose national security risks. Trump had previously tried to ban the apps outright, but his order was blocked by federal courts.</p>
<p><strong>Google has <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-06-08/google-bows-to-eu-rivals-with-android-choice-screen-tweaks?sref=gni836kR">agreed to show more mobile search apps </a>for users to choose from on new Android phones following feedback from the European Commission.</strong> The company had been showing a choice screen where app providers bid against each other for the slot, and pay only if users download apps. DuckDuckGo and others complained the solution has not been working.</p>
<h3>Security &amp; Privacy</h3>
<p><strong>Security flaws <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/security-flaws-found-in-samsungs-stock-mobile-apps/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">were found in Samsung&#8217;s stock mobile apps</a></strong> impacting some Galaxy devices. One could have allowed for data theft through the Secure Folder app. Samsung Knox security software could have been used to install malicious apps. And a bug in Samsung Dex could have scraped data from notifications. There are no indications users were impacted and the flaws were fixed.</p>
<p><strong>An App Store analysis published by <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/06/06/apple-app-store-scams-fraud/">The Washington Post</a> claims nearly 2% of the top grossing apps on one day were scam apps, which cost people $48 million</strong>. They included several VPN apps that told users their iPhones were infected with viruses, a QR code reader that tricked customers into a subscription for functionality that comes with an iPhone, and apps that pretend to be from big-name brands, like Amazon and Samsung.</p>
<p><strong>Multiple apps were removed from the Chinese app store for violating data collection rules, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/virtual-keyboard-apps-removed-chinese-app-stores-2021-06-11/">Reuters</a> reported</strong>. The apps hailed from Sogou, iFlytek and others, and included virtual keyboards.</p>
<h1>Funding and M&amp;A</h1>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Mexican payments app Clip <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-06-10/softbank-viking-invest-250-million-in-latam-fintech-unicorn?sref=gni836kR">raised $250 million</a></strong> from SoftBank&#8217;s Latin American Fund and Viking Global Investors, valuing the business at $2 billion. The app offers a Square-like credit card reader device and others, and has begun to offer cash advances to clients.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f91d.png" alt="🤝" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Shopify <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/shopify-acquires-augmented-reality-home-design-app-primer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">acqui-hires the team</a> from the augmented reality home design app Primer</strong>. The app, which will be shut down, had allowed users to visualize what tile, wallpaper or paint will look like on surfaces inside their home.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Singapore-based corporate services &#8220;super app&#8221; Osome <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/corporate-services-super-app-osome-lands-16m-series-a">raised $16 million</a></strong> in Series A funding. The app offers online accounting and other business services for SMBs. Investors include Target Global, AltaIR Capital, Phystech Ventures, S16VC and VC Peng T. Ong.</p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4c8.png" alt="📈" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />  <strong>Chinese grocery delivery app Dingdong Maicai, backed by Sequoia and Tiger Global, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/dingdong-ipo-idUSL3N2NQ4AP">has filed for a U.S. IPO</a>.</strong> To date, the company has raised $1 billion.</p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>San Francisco-based MaintainX <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/maintainx-raises-39m-series-b-to-take-factory-floors-from-clipboards-to-digital/">raised $39 million</a> </strong>in Series B funding led by Bessemer Venture Partners for its mobile-first platform for industrial and frontline workers to help track maintenance, safety and operations.</p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Berlin&#8217;s Ada Health <a href="https://www.businessofapps.com/news/ada-health-app-raises-90-million/">raised $90 million</a> </strong>in Series B funding in a round led by Leaps by Bayer, the impact investment arm of Bayer AG. The app lets users monitor their symptoms and track their health and clinical data.</p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Photo app Dispo confirmed its previously leaked <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/amid-controversy-dispo-confirms-series-a-funding-high-profile-advisors-and-investors/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">Series A funding</a>,</strong> which earlier reports had pegged as being around $20 million. The app had been rebranded from David’s Disposable and dropped its association with YouTuber David Dobrik, following sexual assault allegations regarding a member of the Vlog Squad. Spark Capital severed ties with Dispo as a result. Seven Seven Six and Unshackled Ventures remained listed as investors, per Dispo&#8217;s press release, but the company didn&#8217;t confirm the size of the round.</p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Brazilian fintech Nubank raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/fintech-all-star-nubank-raises-a-750m-mega-round/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">a $750 million extension</a></strong> to its Series G (which was $400 million last year) led by Berkshire Hathaway. The company offers a digital bank account accessible from an app, debit card, payments, loans, insurance and more. The funding brings the company to a $1.15 billion valuation.</p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Seattle-based tutoring app Kadama <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2021/seattle-tutoring-app-kadama-gets-quick-lesson-success-raises-1-7m-grows-social-following/">raised $1.7 million</a> in seed funding</strong> led by Grishin Robotics. The app, which offering an online tutoring marketplace aimed at Gen Z, rode the remote learning wave to No. 2 in the Education category on the App Store.</p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4c8.png" alt="📈" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />  <strong>Mark Cuban-based banking app Dave, which helps Americans build financial stability, is planning to <a href="https://markets.businessinsider.com/news/stocks/mark-cuban-dave-baking-app-4-billion-spac-merger-2021-6-1030499822">go public via a SPAC</a></strong> launched by Chicago-based Victory Park Capital called VPC Impact Acquisition Holdings III. It also includes a $210 million private investment from Tiger Global Management.</p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f91d.png" alt="🤝" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />  <strong>Mobile game publisher Voodoo <a href="https://www.gamespress.com/Voodoo-acquires-Bidshake-to-offer-mobile-games-and-apps-marketers-a-ne">acquired</a> Tel Aviv-based marketing automation platform Bidshake</strong> for an undisclosed sum. Launched in January 2020, Bidshake combines data aggregation and analytics with campaign and creative management. It will continue to operate independently.</p>
<h1>Downloads</h1>
<h3>Turntable &#8212; tt.fm</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2163162" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2163162" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2163162" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/CMC_9479.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/CMC_9479.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/CMC_9479.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/CMC_9479.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/CMC_9479.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/CMC_9479.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/CMC_9479.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/CMC_9479.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/CMC_9479.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2163162" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> tt.fm on iPhone/Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/turntable-fm-competitor-tt-fm-launches-beta-app-for-ios-and-android">Newly launched music social network tt.fm</a> is a Turntable.fm rival that lets you virtually hang out with friends while listening to music. To be clear, the app is not the same as Turntable.fm, which shut down in 2013 but then returned during the pandemic as people looked to connect online. While <em>that</em> Turntable was rebirthed by its founder Billy Chasen, Turntable &#8211; tt.fm hails from early Turntable.fm employee, now tt.fm CEO Joseph Perla. But as live events are coming back, the question now may be not which Turntable app to choose, but whether the Turnable.fm experience has missed the correct launch window&#8230;again.</p>
<h3>SketchAR</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2162935" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162935" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2162935" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/SketchAR.jpg?w=680" alt="SketchAR" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/SketchAR.jpg 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/SketchAR.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/SketchAR.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/SketchAR.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/SketchAR.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/SketchAR.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2162935" class="wp-caption-text">SketchAR</p></div></p>
<p>The art app <a href="https://sketchar.io">SketchAR</a> previously offered artists tools to draw with AR, turn photos into AR, create AR masks for Snapchat, play games and more. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/art-app-sketchar-to-allow-artists-to-list-their-artworks-on-nft-marketplaces-directly/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">With its latest update</a>, artists can now turn their work into NFTs directly inside the app and sell it. The app, now used by nearly 500,000 users, will select a &#8220;Creator of the Week&#8221; to NFT on OpenSea. Others can create and auction their art as NFTs on-demand.</p>
<h1>Tweets</h1>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Today is Launch Day <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f680.png" alt="🚀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>Introducing OldOS — iOS 4 beautifully rebuilt in SwiftUI.</p>
<p>* <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f3a8.png" alt="🎨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Designed to be as close to pixel-perfect as possible.<br />*<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4f1.png" alt="📱" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Fully functional, perhaps even usable as a second OS.<br />* <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f5fa.png" alt="🗺" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Fully open source for all to learn, modify, and build on. <a href="https://t.co/K0JOE2fEKM">pic.twitter.com/K0JOE2fEKM</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Zane (@zzanehip) <a href="https://twitter.com/zzanehip/status/1402625414762270723?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 9, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Tell me you are building AR glasses, without telling me that you are building AR glasses, I’ll go first: <a href="https://t.co/4KO2diQyHm">pic.twitter.com/4KO2diQyHm</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Miguel de Icaza (@migueldeicaza) <a href="https://twitter.com/migueldeicaza/status/1402636930051883018?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 9, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">I have successfully used iOS 15 to focus on what I do the most. <a href="https://t.co/UNr47w53yP">pic.twitter.com/UNr47w53yP</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Benjamin Mayo (@bzamayo) <a href="https://twitter.com/bzamayo/status/1402201398947819523?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 8, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">And all the ASO-related WWDC updates in one post!<a href="https://t.co/BCNmNYHHjP">https://t.co/BCNmNYHHjP</a> <a href="https://t.co/9bRzmsNcdk">pic.twitter.com/9bRzmsNcdk</a></p>
<p>&mdash; ilia kukharev (@ilyakuh) <a href="https://twitter.com/ilyakuh/status/1402651440196296708?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 9, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Apple: we created new ways to report App Store scams and issues for developers.</p>
<p>1. Doesn&#39;t tackle end users who get scammed every day and never refunded.</p>
<p>2. They are basically using developers as a free workforce to do their job and report issues instead of hiring more people.</p>
<p>&mdash; Damien Petrilli (@DamienPetrilli) <a href="https://twitter.com/DamienPetrilli/status/1402514095824310273?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 9, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Apple&#39;s Object Capture on a Pineapple. One of my fav things to test Photogrammetry against. This was processed using the RAW detail setting.</p>
<p>More info in thread <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f447.png" alt="👇" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/2mICzbV8yY">pic.twitter.com/2mICzbV8yY</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Mikko Haapoja (@MikkoH) <a href="https://twitter.com/MikkoH/status/1402136906587070469?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 8, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Apple invents… Zoom! <a href="https://t.co/nNbR6gUaTt">pic.twitter.com/nNbR6gUaTt</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Joanna Stern (@JoannaStern) <a href="https://twitter.com/JoannaStern/status/1401949531273678854?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 7, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/this-week-in-apps/"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1952542" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="93" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png 2047w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=150,21 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=300,41 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=768,105 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=680,93 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=1536,210 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=50,7 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/this-week-in-apps-wwdc-21-highlights-instagram-creator-week-recap-android-12-beta-2-arrives/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164628</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The rapid hard-tech emergence</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/the-rapid-hard-tech-emergence/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/the-rapid-hard-tech-emergence/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Riggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 14:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sosv]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165354</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The tools and technology to move forward, from machine learning to sensors to nano materials, are more powerful and affordable than ever, allowing for higher ambition and far faster time to market.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Garrett Winther</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Garrett Winther is a partner and program director at HAX, SOSV’s venture program for hard tech. An engineer by training, venture builder by trade, he is bringing hard-tech ventures to life at SOSV, IDEO and MIT.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When I joined the team at SOSV’s HAX, a venture program designed to help early-stage hardware founders, my friends in tech shook their heads. Hadn’t I learned yet that hardware is too hard? What they didn’t see was a hardware scene evolving rapidly in contrast to its glacial reputation. The old hard-knocks hardware playbook has given way to a new, vastly more exciting one; emerging to meet civilization-level opportunities, like climate, that software cannot resolve alone.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today when I work with with founders in the HAX program, it is normal to build incredible (but feasible) plans to “reduce the world’s energy consumption by 10%” from </span><a href="https://www.seppure.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Seppure</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, “eliminate all waste in the apparel supply chain” at </span><a href="https://unspun.io/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unspun</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or “make global battery recycling 5x more profitable” with </span><a href="https://www.greenli-ion.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Green Li-ion</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ambitions like those reflect emerging mega-trends in the global economy centered around demands to decarbonize, modernize infrastructure, secure supply chains and fully digitize traditional industries.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The tools and technology to move forward &#8212; from machine learning to sensors to nano materials &#8212; are more powerful and affordable than ever, which allows for higher ambition and far faster time to market. Visionaries like Bill Gates and Elon Musk have taken note, institutional giants like Blackrock are piling pressure on climate negligence and we witnessed the rise of HAX’s like-minded communities The Engine, New Lab and Greentown Labs. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The scope of this new world is so broad, in fact, that we no longer define HAX’s thesis around “hardware”; we call it </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hard Tech</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, both because it’s hard, as in difficult, as well as moving far beyond the initial scope of early 2010s personal hardware devices and around-the-home IoT. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What’s emerging all around us is a new generation of hard-tech founders, investors and technology</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">with a few early signals for the hard-tech tidal wave coming. </span></p>
<h2>If “software eats the world,” hard tech gives it teeth</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The last three decades have been defined by “software eating the world,” and it’s been feasting on the lowest hanging fruit. But our screen-based, server-based digital world is increasingly limited to marginal gains in niche markets. As our friends at Ubiquity Ventures say, it’s time for “Software Beyond the Screen”.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Affordable robotics, AI-driven sensor fusion, uninterrupted connectivity and super materials are merging into the technology stack to unlock massive new tranches of value for customers. Many HAX companies are operating 80%+ gross margin businesses that not long ago industry experts said only SaaS companies could achieve. Even more, the hardware + software combination can tackle more significant problems across industries than software alone ever could.</span></p>
<h2>Learn from Tesla: Take big shots at big industries</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When industry experts look to explain the unexpected rise of Tesla in the past 10 years to become a mass production automaker, they point to Tesla’s “software-led” approach. The truth is Tesla’s ascent centered on intense hardware innovation in batteries, motors, manufacturing and distribution models.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This same equation is playing out in dominant, multitrillion-dollar industries such as energy, construction and agriculture. Investors on the hunt for opportunities in these categories will need to be bold, but will find disproportionate returns if they include hard tech. To move the world forward, we will need to take big shots like Commonwealth&#8217;s Fusion Energy </span><a href="https://cfs.energy/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">nuclear fusion reactors</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Boston Metal’s </span><a href="https://www.bostonmetal.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">emissions free steel </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">or Deepspin’s </span><a href="https://www.deepspin.io/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> low-cost MRIs</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Just as with Tesla and transportation, software may kick off opportunities, but industrial revolutions come from innovation in the physical world.</span></p>
<h2>New doors open for B2B sales</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Addressing these massive opportunities requires partners and customers at industrial scale. Startups can’t afford to go it alone. The traditional advice for startups is to avoid corporate partners because they are scary, slow moving beasts that can’t work at startup pace. The reality is that large corporations have noticeably increased their appetite for emerging hard-tech startups and many have set up pipelines to engage with higher risk, more complex technology. In the last few years the number of corporations doing venture </span><a href="https://pitchbook.com/newsletter/cvc-sea-change-corporate-venture-on-the-rise-Hbo"><span style="font-weight: 400;">deals has more than doubled </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">and many more are priming for the industry-wide upheavals already in motion. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This enables startups to get inside corporate, B2B markets more quickly, which accounts for many B2B hard-tech startups scaling to millions in revenue at a pace once formerly limited to their software-only peers. It also accounts for the surge in VC capital to those same firms as well as the shift in HAX’s own make-up. Since our start in 2012, the HAX B2B portfolio has grown from 10% to 70% of our total investments, and that includes a majority of fastest growing early-stage companies. </span></p>
<h2>Tooling hard-tech companies is easier and cheaper</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The technologies and strategies for spinning up early-stage, hard-tech startups have advanced by orders of magnitude in less than a decade. The price of 3D printers had dropped from $20,000 to $200. Printed circuit boards ship around the world in just days (even amongst wild supply chains shortages). Hundreds of thousands of suppliers exist online ready to make and ship components overnight. It’s reasonable for an early-stage founder on a slim budget to build an impressive and revenue-generating prototype. As a result, hard-tech founders can zero in on their core technology development and take for granted many things formerly considered really “hard.” Similar to the rise of APIs, AWS and &#8220;no-code&#8221; that unleashed new applications for software, similar revolutions are the backbone of the new hard tech world. </span></p>
<h2>PhDs are the future icons</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Because hard-tech commercialization is no longer a Quixotic quest, more PhDs and post-docs are signing up to start companies. It’s routine for a HAX startup to have a PhD founder, or one that spent years working on a doctoral thesis (</span><a href="https://medium.com/sosv-accelerator-vc/behind-the-numbers-at-sosvs-climate-tech-100-2ab258caef8f#:~:text=Scientists,particularly%20biomanufacturing)%20and%20energy%20categories."><span style="font-weight: 400;">more than 40% SOSV Climate 100 companies</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> have at least one PhD founder). They are responding to more entrepreneurial nudges directly from universities, but also are inspired by the call for big, civilization-level technology challenges, like climate. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s not an easy road for investors because, almost by definition, the work that comes off a university lab bench is going to be very advanced, somewhat speculative and lacking a proven market. In other words, hard-tech startups are usually in very deep waters, and expert leadership and insight are at a premium. As a result, many VCs are picking up scientists and engineers for their investment teams lest they risk missing out on the next generation of great founders and industry-shifting startups. We are at the start of a golden era of opportunity for our best minds in science and technology. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These highlights from HAX’s emerging Hard Tech rise are not a prediction of years to come, but a reflection of what the HAX team sees happening in our portfolio every day. We are stunned by the quality of ideas, ambition of the founders and the speed of execution against projects that not many years ago were written off as impossible. Sure, it’s still hard, but more entrepreneurs and investors are moving into hard tech as it becomes an inevitable force for the coming decades. </span></p>
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter">
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter__right" data-qa="message_content">
<div class="c-message_kit__blocks c-message_kit__blocks--rich_text">
<div class="c-message__message_blocks c-message__message_blocks--rich_text">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer" data-qa="block-kit-renderer">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper--first">
<div class="p-rich_text_block" dir="auto">
<div class="p-rich_text_section"><i data-stringify-type="italic">Disclosure: Former TechCrunch COO Ned Desmond is now senior operating partner at SOSV.</i></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="c-message_actions__container c-message__actions" role="group">
<div class="c-message_actions__group" role="group" aria-label="Message shortcuts" data-qa="message-actions"></div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/the-rapid-hard-tech-emergence/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165354</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UBS investment makes Byju&#8217;s the most valuable startup in India</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/ubs-investment-makes-byjus-the-most-valuable-startup-in-india/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/ubs-investment-makes-byjus-the-most-valuable-startup-in-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 13:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[byju's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paytm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unacademy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vedantu]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Edtech giant Byju&#8217;s has become the most valuable startup in India after raising about $350 million in a new tranche of investment from UBS Group and Zoom founder Eric Yuan, Blackstone and others that valued the Bangalore-based firm at $16.5 billion (post-money). In a new filing, Byju&#8217;s revealed that scores of investors including Abu Dhabi [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Edtech giant Byju&#8217;s has become the most valuable startup in India after raising about $350 million in a new tranche of investment from UBS Group and Zoom founder Eric Yuan, Blackstone and others that valued the Bangalore-based firm at $16.5 billion (post-money).</p>
<p>In a new filing, Byju&#8217;s revealed that scores of investors including Abu Dhabi government fund ADQ and Phoenix Rising had together invested about $350 million in the startup. The new valuation helps Byju&#8217;s surpass Paytm, which was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/24/paytm-1-billion/">last valued at $16 billion</a>, for the crown position in the Indian startup ecosystem. (Paytm is currently working on exploring the public markets and eyeing to raise as much as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/paytm-ipo-shareholders/">$3 billion and eyeing a valuation of up to $30 billion</a>.)</p>
<p>The new tranche of investment is part of a larger round that Byju&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/indian-edtech-giant-byjus-in-talks-to-raise-over-600-million-at-15-billion-valuation/">kickstarted earlier this year</a> and is looking to secure over $1.5 billion. Some of its recent investors also include B Capital Group and hedge fund XN. The startup was valued at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/07/silver-lake-leads-500-million-round-in-indias-byjus/">$11 billion late last year</a>, and $5.75 billion in July 2019.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup plans to use the fresh capital, in part, to acquire more startups. Byju&#8217;s, which acquired Indian physical coaching institute <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/byjus-acquires-indian-tutor-aakash-for-nearly-1-billion/">Aakash for nearly $1 billion</a> earlier this year, is conducting due diligence to buy and online learning startup Toppr and has also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/byjus-in-talks-to-acquire-us-based-reading-platform-epic/">engaged with U.S.-based Epic</a>, TechCrunch reported earlier this year.</p>
<p>Byju’s prepares students pursuing undergraduate and graduate-level courses, and in recent years it has also expanded its catalog to serve all school-going students. Tutors on the Byju’s app tackle complex subjects using real-life objects such as pizza and cake.</p>
<p>The pandemic, which prompted New Delhi to enforce a months-long nationwide lockdown and close schools, accelerated its growth, and those of several other online learning startups including Unacademy and Vedantu.</p>
<p>As of early this year, Byju&#8217;s said it had amassed over 80 million users, 5.5 million of whom are paying subscribers. Byju’s, which is profitable, generated revenue of over $100 million in the U.S. last year, Deborah Quazzo, managing partner of GSV Ventures (which has backed the Indian startup), said at a session in March held by Indian venture fund Blume Ventures.</p>
<p>The startup executives said at a UBS event earlier this year that Byju’s current revenue run rate is $800 million, a figure they expect will reach $1 billion in the next 12-15 months. It has also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/indian-edtech-giant-byjus-to-expand-to-international-markets/">accelerated its international expansion plans</a> in recent months.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/ubs-investment-makes-byjus-the-most-valuable-startup-in-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165417</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SOSV, the global venture firm, just closed a $100 million fund to back its maturing startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/sosv-the-global-venture-firm-just-closed-a-100-million-fund-to-back-its-maturing-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/sosv-the-global-venture-firm-just-closed-a-100-million-fund-to-back-its-maturing-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 02:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sean O'Sullivan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sosv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165395</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sean O’Sullivan, the founder of the global venture outfit SOSV, has slowly but steadily built up a sizable operation over the years. SOSV started off as a family office, investing the capital of O’Sullivan after he cofounded two companies, including MapInfo, an outfit that went public in 1994 before Pitney Bowes acquired it years later, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Sean O’Sullivan, the founder of the global venture outfit <a href="https://sosv.com/">SOSV</a>, has slowly but steadily built up a sizable operation over the years.</p>
<p>SOSV started off as a family office, investing the capital of O’Sullivan after he cofounded two companies, including MapInfo, an outfit that went public in 1994 before Pitney Bowes acquired it years later, in 2007. The seed-stage investing outfit has since raised three more funds, including a <a href="https://medium.com/sosv-accelerator-vc/sosv-raises-277-million-in-oversubscribed-fourth-fund-to-invest-in-early-stage-deep-tech-startups-264bfffa7dc3">$277 million</a> early-stage fund that it closed in 2019 and is actively investing from right now.</p>
<p>Now, to complement those funds, the organization has raised $100 million for what it’s calling a &#8220;select fund&#8221; that&#8217;s meant to help SOSV maintain its pro rata stake in some of its breakaway portfolio companies.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Because of other tools in the market, SOSV wasn’t completely hamstrung until now. Instead, SOSV has, on occasion, assembled a special purpose vehicle to re-invest in certain of the startups it has backed. But O’Sullivan says these were relatively small SPVs &#8212; think $2 million in size or less. The new fund, he says, is expected to write checks of between $2 million and $5 million and even up to $10 million &#8212; or 10% of the fund, per SOSV’s agreement with its investors.</p>
<p>Certainly, the new fund also gives startups even more reason to work with SOSV, which tends to write its seed checks to first-time founders, who O’Sullivan observes are often overlooked &#8212; wrongly &#8212;  by investors in favor of repeat founders.</p>
<p>He points to Apple, Microsoft, Facebook, Google and Alibaba, noting that landscape would look rather different without them. He says experienced the phenomenon himself when he cofounded a company (NetCentric) after MapInfo. &#8220;People were just lining up to invest,&#8221; he says. &#8220;It was so easy to raise the funds without anything other than a business plan, and these days, you don&#8217;t even need one of those.&#8221;</p>
<p>That doesn&#8217;t mean SOSV will get as big a bite as it might like in every deal. Though SOSV has enjoyed success by betting on new entrepreneurs &#8212; it was among the first investors in FormLabs, for example, a company now valued at $2 billion; it also backed JUMP, the bike-share startup that Uber acquired in 2018 &#8212; a $100 million fund is small by current standards. SOSV could well find itself competing against players that have billions of dollars to deploy and which are writing bigger checks to younger companies at a velocity never before seen in the world of venture capital.</p>
<p>It’s not an absurd concern, agrees O’Sullivan. He says he saw some sharp elbows just this week, in fact. Part of a $100 million-plus round was coming together, and a firm that O&#8217;Sullivan declined to mention didn&#8217;t want to make room for the startup&#8217;s Series B or A investors because it wanted to meet a certain equity threshold.</p>
<p>O&#8217;Sullivan suggests the earlier investors acquiesced. (&#8220;They&#8217;re giving us a multi-billion valuation&#8221; and are also &#8220;trying to buy secondaries from existing investors,&#8221; he explains, while adding that SOSV would generally prefer to hold its shares through an IPO.)</p>
<p>Still, he suggests there&#8217;s no need to worry about SOSV. While it&#8217;s willing to go with the flow, O&#8217;Sullivan says that in &#8220;most cases, there&#8217;s enough to go around for the previous investors.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s simply &#8220;good protocol for the late-stage investors [to make room] if they want to continue to have us introducing deals to them.&#8221;</p>
<p>Put another way, SOSV doesn&#8217;t need to manage a megafund; it has leverage all the same.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/sosv-the-global-venture-firm-just-closed-a-100-million-fund-to-back-its-maturing-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165395</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The air taxi market prepares to take flight</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/the-air-taxi-market-prepares-to-take-flight/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/the-air-taxi-market-prepares-to-take-flight/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 22:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air taxi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Mobility Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric aircraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eVTOL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joby Aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volocopter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wisk Aero]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2163290</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Electric air mobility is gaining elevation. But there's going to be some turbulence ahead.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twelve years ago, Joby Aviation consisted of a team of seven engineers working out of founder JoeBen Bevirt&#8217;s ranch in the Santa Cruz mountains. Today, the startup has swelled to 800 people and a $6.6 billion valuation, ranking itself as the highest-valued electric vertical take-off and landing (eVTOL) company in the industry.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			As in any disruptive industry, the forecast may be cloudier than the rosy picture painted by passionate founders and investors.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not the only air taxi company to reach unicorn status. The field is now dotted with new or soon-to-be publicly traded companies courtesy of mergers and special purpose acquisition companies. Partnerships with major automakers and airlines are on the rise, and CEOs have promised commercialization as early as 2024.</p>
<p>As in any disruptive industry, the forecast may be cloudier than the rosy picture painted by passionate founders and investors. A quick peek at comments and posts on LinkedIn reveals squabbles among industry insiders and analysts about when this emerging technology will truly take off and which companies will come out ahead.</p>
<p>Other disagreements have higher stakes. Wisk Aero <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/wisk-aero-files-injunction-in-trade-secret-lawsuit-against-archer-aviation/">filed a lawsuit</a> against Archer Aviation alleging trade secret misappropriation. Meanwhile, valuations for companies that have no revenue yet to speak of &#8212; and may not for the foreseeable future &#8212; are skyrocketing.</p>
<p>Electric air mobility is gaining elevation. But there&#8217;s going to be some turbulence ahead.</p>
<h2>Big goals and bigger expenses</h2>
<p>Taking an eVTOL from design through to manufacturing and certification will likely cost about $1 billion, Mark Moore, then-head of Uber Elevate, estimated in April 2020 during a conference held by the Air Force&#8217;s Agility Prime program.</p>
<p>That means in some sense, the companies that will come out on top will likely be the ones that have managed to raise enough money to pay for all the expenses associated with engineering, certification, manufacturing and infrastructure.</p>
<p>&#8220;The startups that have successfully raised or that will be able to raise significant amounts of capital to get them through the certification process … that&#8217;s the number one thing that&#8217;s going to separate the strong from the weak,&#8221; Asad Hussain, a senior analyst in mobility technology at PitchBook, told TechCrunch. &#8220;There&#8217;s over 100 startups in the space. Not all of them are going to be able to do that.&#8221;</p>
<p>Just consider some of the expenses accrued by the biggest eVTOLs last year: Joby Aviation spent a whopping $108 million on research and development, a $30 million increase from 2019. Archer spent $21 million in R&amp;D in 2020, according to regulatory filings. Meanwhile, Joby&#8217;s net loss last year was $114.2 million and Archer&#8217;s was $24.8 million, though, of course, neither company has brought a product to market yet. Operating expenses will likely only continue to grow into the future as companies enter into manufacturing and deployment phases.</p>
<p>What that means for the future of the industry is likely two things: more SPAC deals and more acquisitions.</p>
<p>Mobility companies, including those working on electrified transport, are often pre-revenue and have capitally intensive business models — a combination that can make it difficult to find buyers in a traditional IPO. SPACs have become increasingly popular as a shorter, less expensive path to becoming a public company. SPACs have also historically received less scrutiny than IPOs. Should the U.S. Securities Exchange Commission start to take a closer look at SPAC mergers in the future, it may impair the ability of other air taxi companies to go public this way, Hussain said.</p>
<p>That means market consolidation is nearly guaranteed, as smaller companies may find it more advantageous to sell than continue to raise more capital. It&#8217;s already begun: At the end of April, eVTOL developer Astro Aerospace announced the acquisition of Horizon Aircraft.</p>
<p>Horizon cited &#8220;greater access to capital&#8221; as one of the many benefits of the transaction, and other companies will likely find the buy or sell route to be the most beneficial on the road to commercialization. And just last week, British eVTOL Vertical Aerospace, which has an order for 150 aircraft from Virgin Atlantic, said it would go public via a merger with Broadstone Acquisition Corp. at an equity value of around $2.2 billion.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/the-air-taxi-market-prepares-to-take-flight/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2163290</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Michael Brown, the new chair of the powerful lobbying group NVCA, shares his agenda</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/investor-michael-brown-newly-elected-to-chair-the-powerful-lobbying-group-nvca-shares-his-agenda/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/investor-michael-brown-newly-elected-to-chair-the-powerful-lobbying-group-nvca-shares-his-agenda/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 22:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Brown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national venture capital association]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165240</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Michael Brown, a longtime general partner with Battery Ventures, was just elected to the role of chairman of the National Venture Capital Association three years after joining its board of directors. Earlier this week, we caught up with Brown to ask about his new, year-long role with the 48-year-old trade group &#8212; and what issues [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Michael Brown, a longtime general partner with <a href="https://www.battery.com/">Battery Ventures</a>, was just elected to the role of chairman of the National Venture Capital Association three years after joining its board of directors. Earlier this week, we caught up with Brown to ask about his new, year-long role with the 48-year-old trade group &#8212; and what issues he sees as top of mind right now for the many American VCs he is now representing.</p>
<p><strong>TC: VCs are always concerned about tax treatments, but these are obviously even more top of mind, given Joe Biden&#8217;s proposal last month to raise the top rate on long-term capital gains to 39.6% from 20%. What do you think of that proposal?</strong></p>
<p>MB: So you&#8217;re gonna hit me right in the face with a two-by-four on taxes in the first question, I love it.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This is the NVCA&#8217;s position, this is my personal position and if you ask most venture capitalists, this position is pretty widely held: what Biden is trying to do with the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Build_Back_Better_Plan">Build Back Better Plan</a> . . . we are fully supportive of that and we are actively working with both the administration and policymakers in Congress to get done a lot of what he wants to get done. A lot of what he&#8217;s talking about &#8212; whether it&#8217;s the physical infrastructure, like bridges, roads, planes; or the digital infrastructure, meaning internet broadband access more broadly and cybersecurity; or climate infrastructure, [around] how we transition the economy and the country to a greener carbon-neutral or even carbon-negative world &#8212; venture capital is required to fund the entrepreneurs to do all of those things . . . It&#8217;s really almost hand in glove. He wants this to happen, we want it to happen, and we can help facilitate that [because] it&#8217;s not going to come from corporate America, we know that.</p>
<p><strong>TC: To your point, the money does have to come from somewhere. Is there a number at which you would feel more comfortable?</strong></p>
<p>MB: I don&#8217;t want to speak on behalf of the NVCA around what is our target rate. I will say that people in Congress and other talking heads talk about the revenue-maximizing rate in and around 25% to 28% . . . and I think that&#8217;s kind of where people feel it is reasonable to go to. What we do believe is that long-term investment should be rewarded and not disincentivized through tax structure.</p>
<p>What happened under the Trump administration, where they extended the time frame to <a href="https://www.proskauertaxtalks.com/2021/01/section-1061-final-regulations-on-the-taxation-of-carried-interest/">three years</a> [from one year] before you could receive long-term capital gains treatment, we were fine with that because we&#8217;re investing for longer than three years and I think having some time component to decide what is long term and what is not worked very well.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Another topic that comes up time and again is the IPO market. It sure seems healthy right now. Will you have any suggestions for the current administration relating to taking companies public?</strong></p>
<p>MB: We are obviously very supportive of the capital markets. That being said, if you look at the number of public companies today versus the number of public companies 20 years ago &#8212; and this is not just true of technology companies &#8212;  it&#8217;s roughly half the number. We think that&#8217;s a function of a few things. One is just how the capital markets function today &#8212; the ability to get research, etcetera, caused by [specific] legislation; regulatory issues; and just the burdens that a public company have versus a private company. You&#8217;ve also got other [rules] that have been passed over the last few years that impact the accessibility of the capital markets for private companies, and that&#8217;s why you&#8217;re seeing companies raise more money and stay private longer, which is not to the benefit of everyone.</p>
<p><strong>TC: What reform here would you press for most immediately?</strong></p>
<p>MB: Going back a ways now, in 2012, there was a piece of legislation called the Jobs Act that helped open up the public markets by addressing some of the risks and costs associated with going public and the regulatory burden. That needs to be updated. That&#8217;s something in particular that if we can modify it and make it current, it will help create that on ramp for smaller companies to access the public markets sooner and earlier.</p>
<p><strong>TC: What do you think of SPACs, these special purpose acquisition companies that are being raised to take companies public, including, oftentimes by those companies&#8217; own <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/um-where-is-the-sec-when-it-comes-to-spacs-and-conflicts-of-interest/">earlier investors</a>?</strong></p>
<p>MB: It&#8217;s good to have more alternatives and more ways for companies to access capital markets. That being said, those vehicles need to be appropriately regulated, and SPACs is one area where regulation has not kept up with kind of the realities on the ground. I think Chairman Gensler and even before him in the previous administration, [the agency] also felt like there needs to be better controls on the stock market.</p>
<p>One of the benefits of a SPAC is the ability to offer forward guidance. You can&#8217;t have that in an IPO or even a direct listing and I would not be surprised if the SEC comes out with either revised guidance and or a complete restriction on the ability to provide forward guidance. There&#8217;s probably something that should be done there, but we&#8217;ll see.</p>
<p>As for conflicts of interest related to the economics centered on investors buying companies within their own portfolio, I don&#8217;t know if there&#8217;ll be regulatory remedies for the conflicts. The SEC has the ability to review any of these [deals] if they want, but in the meantime, we&#8217;re seeing the market actually changing the economic terms. You&#8217;re seeing reduced promotes by the SPAC sponsors. You&#8217;re seeing reduced warrant coverage or even the elimination of warrant coverage. You have some SPACs that look like venture funds, where there&#8217;s really no promote but instead a success fee if the SPAC completes the merger and does well. You&#8217;re also seeing the vesting of the sponsor interest over a period of time, so they&#8217;re locked in over a longer-term horizon. The market is figuring out a lot on its own.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="u1ps4FSg31"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/um-where-is-the-sec-when-it-comes-to-spacs-and-conflicts-of-interest/">Um, where is the SEC when it comes to SPACs and conflicts of interest?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Um, where is the SEC when it comes to SPACs and conflicts of interest?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/um-where-is-the-sec-when-it-comes-to-spacs-and-conflicts-of-interest/embed/#?secret=u1ps4FSg31" data-secret="u1ps4FSg31" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>TC: The NVCA has long been pro-immigration. What are some of your proposals on this front? What would you like to see change or instituted?</strong></p>
<p>MB: We took a very aggressive stance in the previous administration around the <a href="https://www.uscis.gov/humanitarian/humanitarian-parole/international-entrepreneur-parole">International Entrepreneur Rule</a> and even [successfully] <a href="https://nvca.org/the-international-entrepreneur-rule-at-long-last/">sued</a> the Trump administration to have them enforce or at least roll out the rule, which enables the entrepreneur to come to the U.S. as long as they have a minimum number of dollars in financing to build their business here.</p>
<p>Look, we&#8217;re in a competitive market. If you look at venture capital 15 or 20 years ago, 85% of the dollars that were invested went to companies in the United States, and a lot of those went to companies founded by immigrant entrepreneurs. Today, that number stands at just over 50% [including because] founders who are coming here and getting educated and going back home and founding a company.</p>
<p>We want founders to start their companies here and grow their companies here to create jobs and spread the wealth. The International Entrepreneur Rule was a stopgap to ultimately what is called the Startup Visa, an official visa status that would enable entrepreneurs to come in and give them certainty that they can stay in the United States and start a company and build it. This is something that&#8217;s been in the works for a long time, and we&#8217;re hoping that Congresswoman Zoe Lofgren out of the 19th District of California will <a href="https://today.westlaw.com/Document/I5c716b2f6d7511ebbea4f0dc9fb69570/View/FullText.html">reintroduce this visa bill soon</a>, so that we can put this as part of the Build Back Better Plan, because we need immigrant entrepreneurs to come here and start companies and employ the broader U.S. population.</p>
<p>If you think about the technologies that we used to get through COVID it was Zoom, it was Moderna, it was even Pfizer, dating back 100 years. All three were founded by immigrant entrepreneurs who came to the United States to start their business.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Is this a role you volunteered to do? Is there a game of hot potato that happens amid the NVCA&#8217;s board of directors every year?</strong></p>
<p>MB: [Laughs.] It is not just a hot potato that got passed. [NVCA president and CEO] Bobby Franklin and the outgoing chair discuss who they think would be good based on participation in board meetings and how engaged someone is with the things the NVCA is doing in Washington and who can be a good advocate for the industry and for the entrepreneurial ecosystem.</p>
<p>I think it&#8217;s a pretty cool time to have this job; intellectually, this is going to be super interesting, and it&#8217;s super important to the industry [because] these are big policy initiatives and we&#8217;re a very important part of the solution here, and that needs to be well-known and well-understood by the administration and Congress. That&#8217;s our mission.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/investor-michael-brown-newly-elected-to-chair-the-powerful-lobbying-group-nvca-shares-his-agenda/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165240</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Toptal sues rival Andela for allegedly making ‘a perfect clone&#8217; of its freelancer marketplace</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/daily-crunch-toptal-sues-rival-andela-for-allegedly-making-a-perfect-clone-of-its-freelancer-marketplace/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/daily-crunch-toptal-sues-rival-andela-for-allegedly-making-a-perfect-clone-of-its-freelancer-marketplace/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 22:10:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165280</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for June 11, 2021. As a small note I am off next week, so my dear friend and TechCrunch lifer <a href="https://twitter.com/Pickavet">Henry Pickavet</a> will be taking over. He’s more fun and a better writer than I am, so consider him a temporary upgrade. See you in a week or so! &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<p><em>p.s. Cheap tickets to TC Early Stage 2021: Marketing &amp; Fundraising </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/last-day-to-save-100-on-passes-to-tc-early-stage-2021-marketing-fundraising/"><em>are nearly gone</em></a><em>. Flagging in case you needed a ticket and also like saving money. </em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="I9keOQx1jP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/last-day-to-save-100-on-passes-to-tc-early-stage-2021-marketing-fundraising/">Last day to save $100 on passes to TC Early Stage 2021: Marketing &#038; Fundraising</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Last day to save $100 on passes to TC Early Stage 2021: Marketing &#038; Fundraising&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/last-day-to-save-100-on-passes-to-tc-early-stage-2021-marketing-fundraising/embed/#?secret=I9keOQx1jP" data-secret="I9keOQx1jP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/tech-companies-are-looking-at-more-flexible-work-models-when-offices-reopen/"><strong>Technology companies are trying to figure out post-pandemic work</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Minor tech CEOs look to major tech companies for signals about what to do. Google, for example, is a famous cultural bellwether for other tech firms. But when it comes to post-pandemic work <em>every</em> tech company &#8212; big and small &#8212; is scrambling to come up with a plan that will keep control-oriented managers happy and staff from quitting en masse. TechCrunch has the rundown you need on what the majors are deciding.</li>
<li><strong>Didi’s going public! </strong>If you thought that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/10/uber-ipo-trading-debut/">the Uber and Lyft IPOs were fun</a>, oh boy is this good news for you. TechCrunch has notes on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/softbank-uber-tencent-set-to-reap-rewards-from-didi-ipo/">the venture capital winners’ list</a> and more on the company’s economics for your reading pleasure.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/freelancer-marketplace-toptal-sues-andela-and-ex-employees-alleging-theft-of-trade-secrets/"><strong>The tech labor market is brutal</strong></a><strong>:</strong> So brutal, in fact, two companies that help their customers find remote, freelance technology talent are now in a legal fight. Toptal is taking Andela to court over “the theft of trade secrets in pursuit of a perfect clone of its business,’” TechCrunch reports.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups and VC</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/fresha-raises-100m-for-its-beauty-and-wellness-booking-platform-and-marketplace/"><strong>Vertical SaaS is still hot</strong></a><strong>: </strong>How do we know? Fresha just raised $100 million. The company provides software for hair and nail salons, yoga instructors, and other health, beauty, and wellness SMBs. Vertical SaaS companies can often have both attractive software incomes and strong payments revenues.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/temasek-and-general-atlantic-in-talks-to-back-indian-neobank-open/"><strong>More money for neobanks</strong></a><strong>: </strong>My general philosophy that there is infinite money available for neobanking startups around the world is holding up as TechCrunch broke news that “Bangalore-based neobank Open is in advanced stages of talks to raise about $100 million” from possibly Temasek and General Atlantic. The neobank could be worth $600 million after the deal, TechCrunch reported.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/tiger-global-in-talks-to-invest-in-classplus-at-over-250-million-valuation/"><strong>The edtech boom is not over</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Sure, COVID-19 is receding in some countries, and economic activity is rebounding globally, but that’s not stopping edtech companies that got a pandemic bump from raising more cash. This week it’s Indian edtech company Classplus, which could raise $30 million from Tiger Global we reported, at a valuation of up to $250 million. That’s real money.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/insurtech-is-hot-on-both-sides-of-the-atlantic/"><strong>Neither is global interest in funding more insurtech startups</strong></a><strong>: </strong>That’s what TechCrunch learned chatting up a bunch of EU-based VCs, who said that the European insurtech market is super busy, if perhaps not quite as frenetic as the market for insurance technology startups in America.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Insurtech is hot on both sides of the Atlantic</h2>
<p>This morning, The Exchange dug into the EU insurtech market, interviewing European VCs and collating the biggest recent rounds to get a temperature of the waters across the pond:</p>
<ul>
<li>Alex Timm, CEO, Root</li>
<li>Dan Preston, CEO, Metromile</li>
<li>Luca Bocchio, partner, Accel</li>
<li>Florian Graillot, investor, Astorya.vc</li>
<li>Stephen Brittain, director and founder, Insurtech Gateway</li>
</ul>
<p>Several European-based insurtech startups entered unicorn territory this year, such as Bought By Many, which offers pet insurance, London-based Zego and Alan, a French startup that raised a $220 million round.</p>
<p>According to Brittain, EU startups in this sector are “still at the very early stages of innovation,” having only shown “a fraction of what’s possible” in a market that is “as large as banking.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7Jqb8OsAdn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/insurtech-is-hot-on-both-sides-of-the-atlantic/">Insurtech is hot on both sides of the Atlantic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Insurtech is hot on both sides of the Atlantic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/insurtech-is-hot-on-both-sides-of-the-atlantic/embed/#?secret=7Jqb8OsAdn" data-secret="7Jqb8OsAdn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> <em>You can sign up here</em></a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/volkswagen-says-a-vendors-security-lapse-exposed-3-3-million-drivers-details/"><strong>Everyone sucks at cybersecurity</strong></a><strong>: </strong>This week’s its Volkswagen, via a third-party vendor. The vendor in question exposed 3.3 million customers’ data. At some point the fines for this sort of error have to rise to the level of pain that will force corporations to stop fucking up. Enough is enough.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/apple-confirms-hiring-of-ulrich-kranz-former-ceo-of-ev-company-canoo/"><strong>Apple hires from Canoo for car can-do</strong></a><strong>: </strong>This week Apple confirmed that it hired “former co-founder and CEO [Ulrich Kranz] of electric vehicle company Canoo. Though the company declined to say what he’s working on. It’s 1,000% a new cube-shaped, six-screen iBloc, right? Without wheels?</li>
<li>Sticking to the Apple beat, the company announced its “Design Award” winners. TechCrunch has the run-down you need <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/apple-announces-its-2021-apple-design-award-winners/">here</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2159841 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1500" height="942" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1500px) 100vw, 1500px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend growth marketers who have expertise in SEO, social, content writing and more! If you’re a growth marketer, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
<p>The results from this survey will help influence our editorial coverage of growth marketing. Today, we have a guest column from Fuel Capital CMO <a href="https://twitter.com/jimbovig">Jamie Viggiano:</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/5-questions-startups-should-consider-before-making-their-first-marketing-hire/">5 questions startups should consider before making their first marketing hire</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZBTAfxswFW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/5-questions-startups-should-consider-before-making-their-first-marketing-hire/">5 questions startups should consider before making their first marketing hire</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 questions startups should consider before making their first marketing hire&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/5-questions-startups-should-consider-before-making-their-first-marketing-hire/embed/#?secret=ZBTAfxswFW" data-secret="ZBTAfxswFW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/daily-crunch-toptal-sues-rival-andela-for-allegedly-making-a-perfect-clone-of-its-freelancer-marketplace/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165280</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The rise of robotaxis in China</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/the-rise-of-robotaxis-in-china/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/the-rise-of-robotaxis-in-china/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 21:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ADAS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aptiv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Early Stage 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Mobility Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC TechCrunch Mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotaxi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[techcrunch mobility event 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162850</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[AutoX, Momenta and WeRide took the stage at TC Sessions: Mobility 2021 to discuss the state of robotaxi startups in China and their relationships with local governments in the country.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">AutoX, Momenta and WeRide took the stage at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=editorialpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2022&amp;utm_content=chinacarpanel&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=chinacarpanel&amp;display=true">TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</a> to discuss the state of robotaxi startups in China and their relationships with local governments in the country.</p>
<p>They also talked about overseas expansion &#8212; a common trajectory for China&#8217;s top autonomous vehicle startups &#8212; and shed light on the challenges and opportunities for foreign AV companies eyeing the massive Chinese market.</p>
<hr />
<h2>Enterprising governments</h2>
<p>Worldwide, regulations play a great role in the development of autonomous vehicles. In China, policymaking for autonomous driving is driven from the bottom up rather than a top-down effort by the central government, observed executives from the three Chinese robotaxi startups.</p>
<p>Huan Sun, Europe general manager at Momenta, which is backed by the government of Suzhou, a city near Shanghai, said her company had a &#8220;very good experience&#8221; working with the municipal governments across multiple cities.</p>
<blockquote><p>In China, each local government is incentivized to really act like entrepreneurs like us. They are very progressive in developing the local economy&#8230; <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">What we feel is that autonomous driving technology can greatly improve and upgrade the [local governments&#8217;] economic structure. <em><strong>(Time stamp: 02:56)</strong></em><br />
</span></p></blockquote>
<p>Shenzhen, a special economic zone with considerable lawmaking autonomy, is just as progressive in propelling autonomous driving forward, said Jewel Li, chief operation officer at AutoX, which is based in the southern city.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/the-rise-of-robotaxis-in-china/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162850</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook buys game studio BigBox VR</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/facebook-buys-game-studio-bigbox-vr/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/facebook-buys-game-studio-bigbox-vr/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 20:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BigBox VR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Display technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Downpour Interactive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook Horizon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GSR Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mixed reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus Rift]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Onward]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pioneer Square Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seattle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shasta ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wearable devices]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2165306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook has bought several virtual reality game studios over the past couple of years, and they added one more to their portfolio Friday with the acquisition of Seattle-based BigBox VR. The studio&#8217;s major title, &#8220;Population: One,&#8221; was one of the big post-launch releases for Facebook&#8217;s Oculus Quest 2 headset and is a pretty direct Fortnite [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook has bought several virtual reality game studios over the past couple of years, and they added one more to their portfolio Friday with the acquisition of Seattle-based <a href="https://www.bigboxvr.com/">BigBox VR</a>.</p>
<p>The studio&#8217;s major title, &#8220;Population: One,&#8221; was one of the big post-launch releases for Facebook&#8217;s Oculus Quest 2 headset and is a pretty direct Fortnite clone, copying a number of key gameplay techniques while adapting them for the movements unique to virtual reality and bringing in their own lore and art style.</p>
<p>As has been the case for most of these studio acquisitions, terms weren&#8217;t disclosed. BigBox raised $6.5 million according to <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/bigbox-vr/company_financials">Crunchbase</a>, with funding from Shasta Ventures, Outpost Capital, Pioneer Square Labs and GSR Ventures.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;POP: ONE stormed onto the VR scene just nine months ago and has consistently ranked as one the top-performing titles on the Oculus platform, bringing together up to 24 people at a time to connect, play, and compete in a virtual world,&#8221; Facebook&#8217;s Mike Verdu wrote in a <a href="https://www.oculus.com/blog/welcoming-bigbox-vr-to-facebook/">blog post</a>.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not unusual for a gaming hardware platform owner to build up their own web of studios building platform exclusives, but in the VR world things are a little different, given that Facebook has few real competitors.</p>
<p>While many of the developers inside Oculus Studios continue to build titles for Valve&#8217;s Steam store, which are accessible with third-party headsets, most non-Facebook VR platforms seem to be a shrinking piece of the overall VR pie, having been priced out of the market by Facebook&#8217;s aggressive pursuit of a mass market audience. Facebook&#8217;s Oculus Quest 2 retails for $299 and the company has said that it outsold all of its previous devices combined in its first few months.</p>
<p>In April, Facebook acquired Downpour Interactive, maker of the VR shooter &#8220;Onward.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bNJjDqB09A"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/facebook-is-buying-the-developer-behind-vr-shooter-onward/">Facebook is buying the developer behind VR shooter &#8216;Onward&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook is buying the developer behind VR shooter &#8216;Onward&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/facebook-is-buying-the-developer-behind-vr-shooter-onward/embed/#?secret=bNJjDqB09A" data-secret="bNJjDqB09A" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/facebook-buys-game-studio-bigbox-vr/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2165306</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Extra Crunch roundup: EU insurtech, 30 years of &#8216;Crossing the Chasm,&#8217; embedded finance&#8217;s endgame</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/extra-crunch-roundup-eu-insurtech-30-years-of-crossing-the-chasm-embedded-finances-endgame/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/extra-crunch-roundup-eu-insurtech-30-years-of-crossing-the-chasm-embedded-finances-endgame/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 20:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transportation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164326</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning, Anna Heim and Alex Wilhelm dug into the EU insurtech market, interviewing European VCs and collating the biggest recent rounds to take the temperature of the waters across the pond.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning, Anna Heim and Alex Wilhelm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/insurtech-is-hot-on-both-sides-of-the-atlantic/">dug into the EU insurtech market</a>, interviewing European VCs and collating the biggest recent rounds to take the temperature of the waters across the pond:</p>
<ul>
<li>Alex Timm, CEO, Root</li>
<li>Dan Preston, CEO, MetroMile</li>
<li>Luca Bocchio, partner, Accel</li>
<li>Florian Graillot, investor, Astorya.vc</li>
<li>Stephen Brittain, director and founder, Insurtech Gateway</li>
</ul>
<p>Several European-based insurtech startups entered unicorn territory this year, such as Bought By Many, which offers pet insurance; London-based Zego; and Alan, a French startup that raised a $220 million round.</p>
<p>According to Brittain, EU startups in this sector are “still at the very early stages of innovation,” having only shown “a fraction of what’s possible” in a market that is “as large as banking.” Interestingly, he predicted that AI will play a larger role in the future as companies deploy it for fraud detection, improved customer experiences and processing claims more quickly.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“We are fully expecting the next generation of AI-driven business to unlock real-time risk analysis, pricing and claims resolution in the next few years,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Thanks very much for reading Extra Crunch; I hope you have a safe, relaxing weekend.</p>
<p>Walter Thompson<br />
Senior Editor, TechCrunch<br />
<a href="https://www.twitter.com/yourprotagonist">@yourprotagonist</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0Z4DuSphMN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/insurtech-is-hot-on-both-sides-of-the-atlantic/">Insurtech is hot on both sides of the Atlantic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Insurtech is hot on both sides of the Atlantic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/insurtech-is-hot-on-both-sides-of-the-atlantic/embed/#?secret=0Z4DuSphMN" data-secret="0Z4DuSphMN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>What do these 4 IPOs tell us about the state of the market?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996006" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996006" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996006" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996006" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Earlier this week, The Exchange assessed the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/as-monday-com-targets-6b-ipo-valuation-zoom-and-salesforce-commit-150m/">looming Monday.com IPO</a> before reading the tea leaves about that flotation and three others to sum up the overall state of the market.</p>
<p>So what do the Marqeta, Monday.com, Zeta Global and 1stDibs debuts tell us? We may have been too conservative.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8NUrMxSM9G"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/what-do-these-4-ipos-tell-us-about-the-state-of-the-market/">What do these 4 IPOs tell us about the state of the market?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What do these 4 IPOs tell us about the state of the market?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/what-do-these-4-ipos-tell-us-about-the-state-of-the-market/embed/#?secret=8NUrMxSM9G" data-secret="8NUrMxSM9G" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Toast’s Aman Narang and BVP’s Kent Bennett on how customer obsession is everything</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2138443" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2138443" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2138443" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-26.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-26.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-26.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-26.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-26.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-26.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-26.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-26.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2138443" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bessemer Venture Partners / Toast</p></div></p>
<p>On a recent episode of Extra Crunch Live, we spoke to Toast founder Aman Narang and Kent Bennett of Bessemer Venture Partners about how they came together for a deal, what makes the difference for both founders and investors when fundraising, and the biggest lessons they’ve learned so far.</p>
<p>The episode also featured the Extra Crunch Live Pitch-Off, where audience members pitched their products to Bennett and Narang and received live feedback.</p>
<p>Extra Crunch Live is open to everyone each Wednesday at 3 p.m. EDT/noon PDT, but only Extra Crunch members are able to stream these sessions afterward and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/extra-crunch-live/">watch previous shows on-demand</a> in our episode library.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9fuUtQEXCB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/toasts-aman-narang-and-bvps-kent-bennett-on-how-customer-obsession-is-everything/">Toast&#8217;s Aman Narang and BVP&#8217;s Kent Bennett on how customer obsession is everything</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Toast&#8217;s Aman Narang and BVP&#8217;s Kent Bennett on how customer obsession is everything&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/toasts-aman-narang-and-bvps-kent-bennett-on-how-customer-obsession-is-everything/embed/#?secret=9fuUtQEXCB" data-secret="9fuUtQEXCB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>AI startup investment is on pace for a record year</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996007" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996007" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996007" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996007" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex Wilhelm</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/abracarioca">Anna Heim</a> solicited feedback from investors to get a temperature on the market for AI startup investments.</p>
<p>&#8220;The startup investing market is crowded, expensive and rapid-fire today as venture capitalists work to preempt one another, hoping to deploy funds into hot companies before their competitors,&#8221; they write. &#8220;The AI startup market may be even hotter than the average technology niche.&#8221;</p>
<p>But that&#8217;s not surprising. The Exchange was on it.</p>
<p>&#8220;In the wake of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/12/microsoft-is-acquiring-nuance-communications-for-19-7b/">the Microsoft-Nuance deal</a>, The Exchange <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/expect-an-even-hotter-ai-venture-capital-market-in-the-wake-of-the-microsoft-nuance-deal/">reported that it would be reasonable</a> to anticipate an even more active and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/17/why-its-not-surprising-to-see-nine-figure-ai-rounds/">competitive market</a> for AI-powered startups,&#8221; Alex and Anna note. &#8220;Our thesis was that after Redmond dropped nearly $20 billion for the AI company, investors would have a fresh incentive to invest in upstarts with an AI focus or strong AI component; exits, especially large transactions, have a way of spurring investor interest in related companies.&#8221;</p>
<p>Their expectation is coming true: Investors reported a fierce market for AI startups.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2CkhCeEb63"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/ai-startup-investment-is-on-pace-for-a-record-year/">AI startup investment is on pace for a record year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;AI startup investment is on pace for a record year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/ai-startup-investment-is-on-pace-for-a-record-year/embed/#?secret=2CkhCeEb63" data-secret="2CkhCeEb63" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Dear Sophie: What is a diversity green card and how do I apply for one?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2099516" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2099516" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2099516" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg" alt="lone figure at entrance to maze hedge that has an American flag at the center" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2099516" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin/TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Dear Sophie,</strong></p>
<p><strong>I started a tech company about two years ago, and ever since I’ve dreamed of expanding my company in the United States.</strong></p>
<p><strong>I would love to have a green card. Someone mentioned that I should apply for a diversity green card. Would you please provide me with more details about it and how to apply?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Technical in Tanzania</strong></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zK0FW8xr4T"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/dear-sophie-what-is-a-diversity-green-card-and-how-do-i-apply-for-one/">Dear Sophie: What is a diversity green card and how do I apply for one?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Dear Sophie: What is a diversity green card and how do I apply for one?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/dear-sophie-what-is-a-diversity-green-card-and-how-do-i-apply-for-one/embed/#?secret=zK0FW8xr4T" data-secret="zK0FW8xr4T" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>How to start a company in 4 days</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2164007" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164007" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2164007" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-157418834.jpg" alt="Turtle (real) with a rocket on the back, a match (real flame) is about to ignite it. No turtles were harmed in the making of this stock image." width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-157418834.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-157418834.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-157418834.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-157418834.jpg?resize=768,511 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-157418834.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-157418834.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164007" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=MediaProduction" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MediaProduction <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Pulley founder and three-time YC alum Yin Wu offers a tactical guide to getting a startup running in four days. Yes, just four days.</p>
<p>&#8220;The logistics of setting up a startup should be simple, because over the long run, complicated equity setups and cap tables cost more money in legal fees and administration time,&#8221; Wu notes.</p>
<p>Read on for guidance on how to get your business going in less than a week.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LqvPsoKlSi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/how-to-start-a-company-in-4-days/">How to start a company in 4 days</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to start a company in 4 days&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/how-to-start-a-company-in-4-days/embed/#?secret=LqvPsoKlSi" data-secret="LqvPsoKlSi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Health clouds are set to play a key role in healthcare innovation</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2164093" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164093" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2164093" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1056485590.jpg" alt="Health clouds are important for innovation in healthcare" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1056485590.jpg 2121w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1056485590.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1056485590.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1056485590.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1056485590.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1056485590.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1056485590.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1056485590.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164093" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Natali_Mis / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Innovaccer founder and CEO Abhinav Shashank and CTO Mike Sutten write in a guest column that the U.S. healthcare industry is in the middle of a massive transformation.</p>
<p>This shift, they write, &#8220;is being stimulated by federal mandates, technological innovation, and the need to improve clinical outcomes and communication between providers, patients and payers.&#8221;</p>
<p>Improving healthcare now means we need to process tremendous amounts of healthcare data. How do we do it? The cloud, which &#8220;plays a pivotal role in meeting the current needs of healthcare organizations.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9safMDRLrM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/health-clouds-are-set-to-play-a-key-role-in-healthcare-innovation/">Health clouds are set to play a key role in healthcare innovation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Health clouds are set to play a key role in healthcare innovation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/health-clouds-are-set-to-play-a-key-role-in-healthcare-innovation/embed/#?secret=9safMDRLrM" data-secret="9safMDRLrM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>What SOSV’s Climate Tech 100 tells founders about investors in the space</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2164470" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164470" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2164470" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1159835038.jpg" alt="Climate tech presents a trillion-dollar opportunity" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1159835038.jpg 2309w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1159835038.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1159835038.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1159835038.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1159835038.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1159835038.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1159835038.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1159835038.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164470" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> MrJub / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>SOSV&#8217;s Benjamin Joffe and Meghan Hind round up a &#8220;who&#8217;s who&#8221; from the venture capital firm&#8217;s SOSV Climate Tech 100, a list of the best startups addressing climate change that SOSV has supported from the very beginning.</p>
<p>&#8220;What can founders learn from the list about climate tech investors? In other words, who invested in the Climate Tech 100?&#8221; they ask.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="W8sgSuE25V"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/what-sosvs-climate-tech-100-tells-founders-about-investors-in-the-space/">What SOSV&#8217;s Climate Tech 100 tells founders about investors in the space</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What SOSV&#8217;s Climate Tech 100 tells founders about investors in the space&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/what-sosvs-climate-tech-100-tells-founders-about-investors-in-the-space/embed/#?secret=W8sgSuE25V" data-secret="W8sgSuE25V" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The fintech endgame: New supercompanies combine the best of software and financials</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2164488" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164488" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2164488" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-597317537.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-597317537.jpg 5200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-597317537.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-597317537.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-597317537.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-597317537.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-597317537.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-597317537.jpg?resize=2048,1367 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-597317537.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164488" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Donald+Iain+Smith" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Donald Iain Smith <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now that we can transact from anywhere, a new, hybrid class of software companies with embedded financial services are scooping up consumers — and investors are following the action.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Using data from a Battery Ventures report about &#8220;the intersection of software and financial services,&#8221; this post examines why these companies can be so hard to value and offers a framework for better understanding their business models and investor appeal.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HXtnS7rFg6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/the-fintech-endgame-new-supercompanies-combine-the-best-of-software-and-financials/">The fintech endgame: New supercompanies combine the best of software and financials</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The fintech endgame: New supercompanies combine the best of software and financials&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/the-fintech-endgame-new-supercompanies-combine-the-best-of-software-and-financials/embed/#?secret=HXtnS7rFg6" data-secret="HXtnS7rFg6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>After 30 years, ‘Crossing the Chasm’ is due for a refresh</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2164727" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164727" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2164727" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-170576073.jpg" alt="Hoover Dam area, Mike O'Callaghan, Pat Tillman bridge." width="1024" height="687" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-170576073.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-170576073.jpg?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-170576073.jpg?resize=300,201 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-170576073.jpg?resize=768,516 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-170576073.jpg?resize=680,456 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-170576073.jpg?resize=1536,1031 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-170576073.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164727" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Grant+Faint" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Grant Faint <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Geoffrey Moore&#8217;s &#8220;Chasm,&#8221; a framework for marketing technology products that has been one of the canonical foundational concepts to product-market fit for three decades, needs a bit of an upgrade, Flybridge Capital&#8217;s Jeff Bussgang writes.</p>
<p>&#8220;I have been reflecting on why it is that we venture capitalists and founders keep making the same mistake over and over again — a mistake that has become even more glaring in recent years,&#8221; he writes.</p>
<p>Bussgang goes on to consider the Chasm &#8212; and propose tweaks for thinking about market size in the modern era.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HtEITdKFtj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/after-30-years-crossing-the-chasm-is-due-for-a-refresh/">After 30 years, &#8216;Crossing the Chasm&#8217; is due for a refresh</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;After 30 years, &#8216;Crossing the Chasm&#8217; is due for a refresh&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/after-30-years-crossing-the-chasm-is-due-for-a-refresh/embed/#?secret=HtEITdKFtj" data-secret="HtEITdKFtj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/extra-crunch-roundup-eu-insurtech-30-years-of-crossing-the-chasm-embedded-finances-endgame/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164326</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 questions startups should consider before making their first marketing hire</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/5-questions-startups-should-consider-before-making-their-first-marketing-hire/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/5-questions-startups-should-consider-before-making-their-first-marketing-hire/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 19:19:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2160911</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Your first marketer will have an outsized impact on team dynamics as well as the overall strategic direction of the brand, product and company.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jamie Viggiano</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/jimbovig">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jamie Viggiano is the chief marketing officer at <a href="https://www.fuelcapital.com">Fuel Capital</a>, an early-stage venture capital firm investing in consumer, SaaS and infrastructure businesses.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">&#8220;Who should my first marketing hire be?&#8221;</p>
<p>This is (by far) the most common question I’ve received since starting as Fuel&#8217;s CMO, and for good reason. Your first marketer will have an outsized impact on team dynamics as well as the overall strategic direction of the brand, product and company.</p>
<p>The nature of the marketing function has expanded significantly over the past two decades. So much so that when founders ask this question, it immediately prompts multiple new ones: Should I hire a brand or growth marketer? An offline or an online marketer? A scientific or a creative marketer?</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Once upon a time, the number of marketing channels was fairly limited, which meant the function itself fit into a neater, tighter box. The number of ways to reach customers has since grown exponentially, as has the scope of the marketing role. Today’s startups require at least four broad functions under the umbrella of &#8220;marketing,&#8221; each with its own array of subfunctions.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			The reality is that anyone who excels across all marketing functions is a unicorn and nearly impossible to find.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Here’s a sample of the marketing functions at a typical early-stage startup:</p>
<p><strong>Brand marketing:</strong> Brand strategy, positioning, naming, messaging, visual identity, experiential, events, community.</p>
<p><strong>Product marketing:</strong> UX copy, website, email marketing, customer research and segmentation, pricing.</p>
<p><strong>Communications:</strong> PR and media relations, content marketing, social media, thought leadership, influencer.</p>
<p><strong>Growth marketing:</strong> Direct response paid acquisition, funnel optimization, retention, lifecycle, engagement, reporting and attribution, word of mouth, referral, SEO, partnerships.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;">Have you worked with a talented individual or agency who helped you find and keep more users?<br />
<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/help-techcrunch-find-the-best-growth-marketers-for-startups/">Respond to our survey</a> and help us find the best startup growth marketers!</p>
<hr />
<p>As you can imagine, that’s a lot for one person to manage, let alone be an expert in. What’s more, the skill set and experience required to excel in growth marketing is quite different from the skill set required to succeed in brand marketing. The reality is that anyone who excels across all marketing functions is a unicorn and nearly impossible to find.</p>
<h2>So who do you hire first?</h2>
<p>Unless you’re lucky enough to nab that unicorn, your first hire should be a generalist who can tend to the full stack of the marketing function, learn what they don’t know, and roll up their sleeves to get things done. Someone smart, savvy and super scrappy who understands how to experiment across marketing channels until they find the right mix.</p>
<p>But this utility player should also bring deeper expertise in one of the big marketing functions: brand, product, communications or growth. Before making this key hire, you need to figure out which marketing priorities are most urgent and, consequently, which marketing &#8220;persona&#8221; is most appropriate for your business at the earliest stages.</p>
<p>To figure out which skill set you need most in-house, consider these five questions:</p>
<h2>Which marketing channels have proven successful to date?</h2>
<p>If you’ve done some marketing experimentation previously, have there been any bright spots? Which channels are proving the most efficient from a customer acquisition, conversion, retention, engagement, whatever your key KPI is, perspective? If you find a promising area, find a candidate that has expertise in it. For example, if you are seeing good results with Instagram ads, hiring a candidate who has expertise in growth marketing makes sense.</p>
<h2>Where are the target customers?</h2>
<p>If you don’t have much data from channel testing, consider how your target customers are currently finding competitive products or services. At TaskRabbit, we knew from early customer research that clients were finding help with home services either through recommendations from friends or by asking Google (i.e., SEO and SEM).</p>
<p>So, that was a natural place for us to start. Our focus from a resource and staffing perspective in the early days was on growth marketing — driving more word of mouth, plus optimizing our SEO and SEM.</p>
<h2>How competitive is the market?</h2>
<p>How competitive is the category you’re playing in? Are there dominant players with strong brands? Do these brands have endless marketing budgets? Are CACs exorbitant because well-capitalized competitors are outbidding each other? If so, you might want to focus on building an exceptional brand and product/customer experience.</p>
<p>That means disseminating a unique story through organic channels (word of mouth, PR, influencers and organic social media). A brand marketer or someone with deep PR and communications experience makes sense in this scenario.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Uhe3DrPCux"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/even-startups-on-tight-budgets-can-maximize-their-marketing-impact/">Even startups on tight budgets can maximize their marketing impact</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Even startups on tight budgets can maximize their marketing impact&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/even-startups-on-tight-budgets-can-maximize-their-marketing-impact/embed/#?secret=Uhe3DrPCux" data-secret="Uhe3DrPCux" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Where do the founder&#8217;s skills lie?</h2>
<p>Another aspect to consider is the skills the founder(s) — or other members of the founding/early team — bring to the table. If a founder has a strong vision for the brand and extensive experience building brands, then focus less on a brand marketing hire and rather supplement the branding skill set with another marketing priority (i.e., product marketing). Likewise, if a founder has a strong vision for the brand but no one on the team knows how to build one, that’s a skill gap that your first marketing hire should fill.</p>
<h2>How important is trust building?</h2>
<p>Trust building has become an increasingly important aspect for brands as customers become more and more discerning. But trust building tends to be more critical in certain areas than others: New, nascent industries or markets, sectors with a lot of human interaction (services businesses, dating platforms, etc.), industries that are fundamentally changing consumer behavior (ride-sharing in its earliest days), or industries where the stakes or cost is relatively high (luxury goods).</p>
<p>If trust building is critical, consider a branding expert who understands how to build trust and credibility, and build an experience that consumers are passionate about. This person will likely have deep expertise in PR and brand building, as these channels tend to inspire the most trust among consumers.</p>
<h2>What level of experience is necessary?</h2>
<p>Once you’ve answered these five questions, you should have a pretty good idea of the type of marketing experience you want. But just how much experience should that person have? I typically recommend that seed-stage founders look for senior manager or director-level candidates at midsized companies.</p>
<p>At this experience level (six to 10 years), these candidates’ salaries tend to be more in line with a young company’s budget. Moreover, at this stage of their career, they tend to be both strategic and tactical. This means they can level up and think strategically about the business and the marketing function, but they are also happy to get their hands dirty and execute — actually dive into the Facebook platform and create ads, plan and host an event, or pitch a journalist.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6XUAgZyEYT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/14/5-ways-to-raise-your-startups-pr-game/">5 ways to raise your startup&#8217;s PR game</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 ways to raise your startup&#8217;s PR game&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/14/5-ways-to-raise-your-startups-pr-game/embed/#?secret=6XUAgZyEYT" data-secret="6XUAgZyEYT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/5-questions-startups-should-consider-before-making-their-first-marketing-hire/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2160911</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
