<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 14:37:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>OneTrust adds ethics to its privacy platform with Convercent acquisition</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/onetrust-adds-ethics-to-its-privacy-platform-with-convercent-acquisition/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/onetrust-adds-ethics-to-its-privacy-platform-with-convercent-acquisition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 14:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[convercent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[onetrust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128984</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[OneTrust, a late stage privacy platform startup, announced it was adding ethics and compliance to the mix this morning by acquiring Convercent, a company that was built to help build more ethical organizations. The companies did not share the purchase price. OneTrust just raised $300 million on a fat $5.1 billion valuation at the end [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://onetrust.com/">OneTrust</a>, a late stage privacy platform startup, announced it was adding ethics and compliance to the mix this morning by acquiring Convercent, a company that was built to help build more ethical organizations. The companies did not share the purchase price.</p>
<p>OneTrust <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/onetrust-nabs-300m-series-c-on-5-1b-valuation-to-expand-privacy-platform/">just raised $300 million</a> on a fat $5.1 billion valuation at the end of last year, and it&#8217;s putting that money to work with this acquisition. Alan Dabbiere, co-chairman at OneTrust sees this acquisition as a way to add a missing component to his company&#8217;s growing platform of services.</p>
<p>&#8220;OneTrust instantly brings a proven ethics and compliance technology, team, and customer base into the OneTrust, further aligning the Chief Ethics &amp; Compliance Officer strategy alongside privacy, data governance, third-party risk, GRC (governance, risk and compliance), and ESG (environmental, social and governance) to build trust as a competitive advantage,&#8221; he said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Convercent brings 750 customers and 150 employees to the OneTrust team along with its ethics system, which includes a way for employees to report ethical violations to the company and a tool for managing disclosures.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="r9iByA1WEr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/14/converscent-wants-to-make-it-easier-for-companies-to-measure-ethical-behavior/">Convercent wants to make it easier for companies to measure ethical behavior</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Convercent wants to make it easier for companies to measure ethical behavior&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/14/converscent-wants-to-make-it-easier-for-companies-to-measure-ethical-behavior/embed/#?secret=r9iByA1WEr" data-secret="r9iByA1WEr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Convercent can also use data to help surface bad behavior before it&#8217;s been reported. As CEO Patrick Quinlan explained <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/14/converscent-wants-to-make-it-easier-for-companies-to-measure-ethical-behavior/">in a 2018 TechCrunch article</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Sometimes you have this interactive code of conduct, where there’s a new vice president in a region and suddenly page views on the sexual harassment section of the Code of Conduct have increased 200% in the 90 days after he started. That’s easy, right? There’s a reason that’s happening, and our system will actually tell you what’s happening.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Quinlan wrote <a href="https://www.convercent.com/blog/next-stop-trust-onetrust">in a company blog post</a> announcing the deal that joining forces with OneTrust will give it the resources to expand its vision.</p>
<p>&#8220;As a part of OneTrust, we’ll be combining forces with the leader across privacy, security, data governance, third-party risk, GRC, ESG—and now—ethics and compliance. Our customers will now be able to build centralized programs across these workstreams to make trust a competitive differentiator,&#8221; Quinlan wrote.</p>
<p>Convercent was founded in 2012 and has raised over $100 million, according to Pitchbook data. OneTrust was founded in 2016. It has over 8000 customers and 150 employees and has raised $710 million, according to the company.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NnCPu9jo0G"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/onetrust-nabs-300m-series-c-on-5-1b-valuation-to-expand-privacy-platform/">OneTrust nabs $300M Series C on $5.1B valuation to expand privacy platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;OneTrust nabs $300M Series C on $5.1B valuation to expand privacy platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/onetrust-nabs-300m-series-c-on-5-1b-valuation-to-expand-privacy-platform/embed/#?secret=NnCPu9jo0G" data-secret="NnCPu9jo0G" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/onetrust-adds-ethics-to-its-privacy-platform-with-convercent-acquisition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128984</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple launches the &#8216;Apple Teacher Portfolio recognition, updates Schoolwork and Classroom apps</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/apple-launches-the-apple-teacher-portfolio-recognition-updates-schoolwork-and-classroom-apps/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/apple-launches-the-apple-teacher-portfolio-recognition-updates-schoolwork-and-classroom-apps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 14:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[classroom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creative tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Distance learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garageband]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imovie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[schoolwork]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tablet computers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teacher]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128951</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple this morning announced a handful of education-related updates to its suite of classroom apps as well as a new recognition for teachers, called the Apple Teacher Portfolio. Teachers who complete a total of nine lessons where they learn foundational skills on iPad and Mac to become an officially recognized Apple Teacher will be able [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple this morning <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/03/apple-expands-free-professional-learning-to-help-teachers-champion-creativity/">announced</a> a handful of education-related updates to its suite of classroom apps as well as a new recognition for teachers, called the Apple Teacher Portfolio. Teachers who complete a total of nine lessons where they learn foundational skills on iPad and Mac to become an officially recognized Apple Teacher will be able to submit their portfolio of lesson examples to earn the Apple Teacher Portfolio recognition. They can then also share their portfolio with their colleagues or use it to showcase their work.</p>
<p>Teachers can work towards acquiring the badge through the Apple Teacher Learning Center, which is Apple&#8217;s self-paced learning platform for educators. This offering is designed to help teachers learn how to incorporate Apple technologies in the classroom, including by using iPad and Mac apps for creating art, videos, animations, recordings, page layouts, podcasts, data trackers, music, and more. Across the lessons, Apple provides templates as examples which teachers can customize or combine to make their own projects that use either an iPad or Mac and Apple software like Keynote, GarageBand, iMovie, and others.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2129001" style="width: 523px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2129001" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2129001" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Apple_ipad-apple-teacher-portfolio-green-screen_032321_carousel.jpg.large_2x.jpg?w=513" alt="" width="513" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Apple_ipad-apple-teacher-portfolio-green-screen_032321_carousel.jpg.large_2x.jpg 1306w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Apple_ipad-apple-teacher-portfolio-green-screen_032321_carousel.jpg.large_2x.jpg?resize=113,150 113w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Apple_ipad-apple-teacher-portfolio-green-screen_032321_carousel.jpg.large_2x.jpg?resize=226,300 226w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Apple_ipad-apple-teacher-portfolio-green-screen_032321_carousel.jpg.large_2x.jpg?resize=768,1019 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Apple_ipad-apple-teacher-portfolio-green-screen_032321_carousel.jpg.large_2x.jpg?resize=513,680 513w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Apple_ipad-apple-teacher-portfolio-green-screen_032321_carousel.jpg.large_2x.jpg?resize=1158,1536 1158w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Apple_ipad-apple-teacher-portfolio-green-screen_032321_carousel.jpg.large_2x.jpg?resize=38,50 38w" sizes="(max-width: 513px) 100vw, 513px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2129001" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In addition, Apple today rolled out updates across its Schoolwork and Classroom apps, as well as its &#8220;Everyone Can Create&#8221; curriculum, which has historically focused on taking advantage of Apple&#8217;s creative tools like iMovie, Clips and GarageBand.</p>
<p>In Schoolwork, teachers will gain the option to share Schoolwork projects with colleagues by exporting their assignments, which can then be imported back into Schoolwork or other platforms. Other improvements have been made to the sidebar navigation to make it quicker to access classes, assignments and student accounts.</p>
<p>Classroom, meanwhile, has been updated for remote learning &#8212; a feature that would have been more useful to have rolled out in 2020, amid the height of U.S. lockdowns during the pandemic. With the update, teachers will be able to invite remote students to Classroom sessions where they&#8217;ll be able to guide them to apps, view their screen (with the student&#8217;s permission) and track their engagement. The software has also been rebuilt using Mac Catalyst, making it work across iPad and Mac, including Macs powered by Apple&#8217;s M1 chips.</p>
<p>The Everyone Can Create&#8221; curriculum has had a number of smaller updates. Its Drawing guide has been updated to include motion graphics and animation in Keynote, while Photos now covers the creation of animated GIFs using Keynote, and the Camera and Photos apps. The Video guide will now explore creating short films using a green screen and other special effects, and Music adds new podcasting features using GarageBand, Apple says. Today, more than 5,000 K-12 institutions worldwide are using the curriculum.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2129002" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/everyone-can-create-apple.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="450" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/everyone-can-create-apple.jpg 1960w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/everyone-can-create-apple.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/everyone-can-create-apple.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/everyone-can-create-apple.jpg?resize=768,508 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/everyone-can-create-apple.jpg?resize=680,450 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/everyone-can-create-apple.jpg?resize=1536,1016 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/everyone-can-create-apple.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>Apple last year had <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2020/05/21/apple-schoolwork-classroom-distance-learning/">updated</a> its Schoolwork and Classroom apps, with some updates to Schoolwork to support distance learning &#8212; like managing assignments over the cloud and support for calling students via FaceTime, for example. But even as the pandemic forced schools towards remote learning, Google jumped ahead of edtech rivals by aggressively giving away its software and courting teachers. Its low-cost Chromebooks were being given out across school districts, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/chromebook-shipments-double-due-to-pandemic-193424657.html">doubling demand</a> in 2020. Google Classroom, meanwhile, doubled to more than 100 million active users by April 2020, Bloomberg Quint <a href="https://www.bloombergquint.com/business/google-widens-lead-in-education-market-as-students-rush-online">reported</a>. As of Feb. 2021, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/google-to-roll-out-slate-of-over-50-updates-for-classroom-meet-and-other-online-education-tools/">Google said</a> the service was being used by over 150 million students, teachers and admins, up from just 40 million last year.</p>
<p>Apple didn&#8217;t say today how many users it has for its own educational software programs, by comparison. However, by encouraging teachers to create a portfolio which they can then share, Apple is helping to push towards greater adoption of its tools by more directly involving educators in the process.</p>
<p>Apple Teacher Portfolio launched today and is available in the Apple Teacher Learning Center. The &#8220;Everyone Can Create guides&#8221; are a free download on Apple Books. And new versions of both Schoolwork and Classroom are available in beta now through AppleSeed for IT.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/apple-launches-the-apple-teacher-portfolio-recognition-updates-schoolwork-and-classroom-apps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128951</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>After its near-death experience, AR pioneer Blippar is back with $5M in funding and a B2B model</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/after-its-near-death-experience-ar-pioneer-blippar-is-back-with-5m-in-funding-and-a-b2b-model/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/after-its-near-death-experience-ar-pioneer-blippar-is-back-with-5m-in-funding-and-a-b2b-model/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 14:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128975</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Augmented Reality pioneer Blippar &#8211; which has had a tortuous history after early investors pulled out and the company had to scramble for new backers &#8211; has now closed a $5 million funding round, after 18 months of re-positioning as a B2B company in the AR space. The pre-Series A round was co-led by Chroma [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Augmented Reality pioneer <a href="https://www.blippar.com">Blippar</a> &#8211; which has had a tortuous history after early investors pulled out and the company had to scramble for new backers &#8211; has now closed a $5 million funding round, after 18 months of re-positioning as a B2B company in the AR space.</p>
<p>The pre-Series A round was co-led by Chroma Ventures and West Coast Capital. Canadian entrepreneur Anthony Lacavera also participated via his Globalive Capital investment firm. Chroma is the investment arm of Paddy Burns’ and Chris van der Kuyl’s gaming company 4J Studios, while West Coast is the private equity arm of Scottish entrepreneur Sir Tom Hunter and family.</p>
<p>The new investors join existing shareholder Candy Ventures; the multi-stage investment firm founded by British property entrepreneur Nick Candy, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/23/blippar-finds-life-after-death-as-former-investor-buys-assets-to-relaunch-ar-startup/">who came to Blippar’s rescue</a>. This new entity acquired the company’s assets in a patent sale and managed to keep on sounder Ambarish Mitra, although he is now acting as the company’s “Chief Creative Officer”. At hits height, Blippar burned through $130 million in funding, claiming a $1.5 billion valuation, and tried to crack the consumer AR market. But Blippbuilder, its SaaS AR creation platform, is the asset that is now seeing it make a B2B comeback.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>At its height Blippar employed 340 people, Now it’s 30 people. But it has all the IP and assets from its previous incarnation, and is now ‘making hay while the sun shines’.</p>
<p>AR technology is now being used in several areas such as live events (when they return!) retail, FMCG, automotive, healthcare and education.</p>
<p>Rumoured AR glasses from Apple and the inclusion of AR results in mobile search results may well help its adoption, as well as the continuing need for social distancing.</p>
<p>While the tech giants are developing AR tools, these are platform-dependent, whereas Blippar hopes to be the agnostic alternative.</p>
<p>Its two routes to market are, firstly, via its Blippbuilder SAAS platform, which enables agencies, brands and AR content creators to create communications and campaigns. It also does bespoke work with an in-house team “Studio B”.</p>
<p>Faisal Galaria, CEO of Blippar, commented: “We are very excited to have attracted investors of this caliber to Blippar… 2020 was a transformative year for Blippar with a 200% increase in revenue quarter on quarter, continued strengthening of the senior leadership team, and delivery of cutting-edge AR campaigns for major global brands including OnePlus, Kellogg’s and Dr Pepper. We have leveraged our 10 years of investment, provenance, and technology leadership in the AR space to come back leaner, more focussed and better than ever before.”</p>
<p>Burns and Van der Kuyl are best known for porting Minecraft to the Microsoft, Sony and Nintendo games consoles. The latter said in a statement: “The immersive nature of AR makes it one of the most important use cases for the gaming industry. Blippar’s AR technology is by far the most advanced and innovative that I’ve seen in years and there is huge potential for AR to power the ultimate gaming experience of the future. We look forward to being part of the Blippar journey.”</p>
<p>Hunter commented: “Blippar has demonstrated strong progress with the turnaround plan put in place by Faisal and the team, and the business is now well placed to maximize the opportunities presented by the growing AR ecosystem hence we are delighted to invest.”</p>
<p>In addition, Justin Cooke, Venture Partner at tech investor Northzone, has also been appointed to the Blippar Board this month. The UK Government also has a minority equity stake in Blippar via its Future Fund match funding scheme&lt; which was design to assist struggling tech companies through the pandemic.</p>
<p>Blippar re-enters a market which includes Niantic, Unreal, Unity, 8th Wall, Zappar and Magic Leap. But as AR matures, it may be back in the right place.</p>
<p>Here’s an example of how brands are using the platform:</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/SSlNlNlU_zc?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/after-its-near-death-experience-ar-pioneer-blippar-is-back-with-5m-in-funding-and-a-b2b-model/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128975</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arcadia steps in to Texas&#8217; startup energy market with the acquisition of Real Simple Energy</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/arcadia-steps-in-to-texas-startup-energy-market-with-the-acquisition-of-real-simple-energy/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/arcadia-steps-in-to-texas-startup-energy-market-with-the-acquisition-of-real-simple-energy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 14:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[washington]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128898</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the third greatest television show of all time (sorry Rolling Stone), one of Texas&#8217; most famous fictional football players once said, &#8220;When all the scared rats are leaving a sinking market, that&#8217;s when a real entrepreneur steps in &#8212; a true visionary.&#8221; If that&#8217;s the case, then the startup renewable energy retail reseller Arcadia [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">On the third greatest television show of all time (sorry <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/tv/tv-lists/100-greatest-tv-shows-of-all-time-105998/veep-101740/"><em>Rolling Stone</em></a>), one of Texas&#8217; most famous fictional football players <a href="http://www.mtv.com/news/2761467/friday-night-lights-flip-this-qb-flip-that-house/">once said</a>, &#8220;When all the scared rats are leaving a sinking market, that&#8217;s when a real entrepreneur steps in &#8212; a true visionary.&#8221;</p>
<p>If that&#8217;s the case, then the startup renewable energy retail reseller <a href="https://www.arcadia.com/">Arcadia</a> may be a true visionary. Even as <a href="https://www.houstonchronicle.com/business/energy/article/AG-Ken-Paxton-sues-Griddy-alleging-deceptive-15988077.php#:~:text=sighting%20in%20Gulf-,ERCOT%20shuts%20down%20Griddy%2C%20as%20Paxton%20sues,retailer%20over%20'deceptive%20business%20practices'&amp;text=March%201%2C%202021%20Updated%3A%20March,2%2C%202021%202%3A33%20p.m.&amp;text=The%20Electric%20Reliability%20Council%20of,effectively%20shutting%20down%20the%20company.">energy startups servicing customers throughout the great state of Texas are forced to throw in the towel</a>, the Washington-based, consumer-focused renewable energy power provider (based on renewable energy certificates purchased on the open market), is making an acquisition to enter the Texas market.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The company is buying <a href="http://realsimpleenergy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://realsimpleenergy.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1616587927486000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFGnDWF-CX7Q_PKdWyrNUreHg1FoQ">Real Simple Energy</a>, which not only marks the company&#8217;s availability in all 50 states, but gives Real Simple Energy customers access to both wind and solar power generating projects. The company said it  will leverage Real Simple Energy&#8217;s platform and expertise to secure the best rates for members, monitor for better savings, and provide a smarter yet simpler energy experience.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;Recent events in the Texas market prove that customers shouldn’t be exposed to wholesale or variable rates, and want an energy advocate to protect them,” said Kiran Bhatraju, CEO and Founder of Arcadia. “Both Arcadia and Real Simple Energy recognize the challenges Texas homeowners and renters have historically faced in the energy buying process, and we remain committed to removing these confusing barriers.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">Texans have consistently paid more for power than consumers that buy their energy from regulated market participants thanks to the state&#8217;s disastrously deregulated power markets. The combined companies are pitching fixed rate contracts to Texas consumers that won&#8217;t be vulnerable to bill spikes, but will offer average savings above the flat rates regulated utilities offer.</p>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;The deregulated energy industry, especially in Texas, has underserved customers and as a result, most customers overpay for electricity and receive poor customer service. Using technology, we are helping customers realize the promise of deregulation and always get the best fixed rates available,&#8221; said Trent Crow, CEO of Real Simple Energy, in a statement. “As industry veterans, joining forces with Arcadia will allow us to get better deals for customers and enhance our customer experience.  We manage 100% of the energy experience and become a customer’s independent agent and advocate so they never have to worry about their electricity bill again.&#8221;</p>
<p>The deal is Arcadia&#8217;s first acquisition and follows the company&#8217;s launch of a <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/arcadia-expands-residential-community-solar-to-maine-301240000.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/arcadia-expands-residential-community-solar-to-maine-301240000.html&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1616587927486000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEyodXKZ0kzODVLerFPoyuGUzCBaQ">community solar program</a> all the way across the country in the great state of Maine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/arcadia-steps-in-to-texas-startup-energy-market-with-the-acquisition-of-real-simple-energy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128898</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Huckleberry, offering insurance to SMBs, partners with Berkshire Hathaway</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/huckleberry-offering-insurance-to-smbs-partners-with-berkshire-hathaway/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/huckleberry-offering-insurance-to-smbs-partners-with-berkshire-hathaway/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 14:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Huckleberry]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128958</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Huckleberry, an insurtech company that offers a variety of insurance to small businesses, has announced a partnership with Berkshire Hathaway GUARD. This represents the biggest partnership with a carrier for the startup to date. The startup, cofounded by Bryan O&#8217;Connell, has made some major moves in the past year. The company launched in 2017 offering [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://huckleberry.com/">Huckleberry</a>, an insurtech company that offers a variety of insurance to small businesses, has announced a partnership with Berkshire Hathaway GUARD. This represents the biggest partnership with a carrier for the startup to date.</p>
<p>The startup, cofounded by Bryan O&#8217;Connell, has made some major moves in the past year. The company launched in 2017 offering workers compensation and general liability insurance to small and medium-sized businesses through an online portal, cutting out a lot of the hassle for these businesses as they seek out the right policy.</p>
<p>In the last year, the SF-based company has nearly doubled its geographic footprint and added five new policies to the product suite, including cyber, automotive insurance, umbrella insurance and more.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Moreover, it&#8217;s moving to New York and opening up an office in Columbus, Ohio, called HQ2. O&#8217;Connell says that the move to New York is all about positioning the startup in the midst of NYC&#8217;s burgeoning pool of fintech talent.</p>
<p>With the new partnership and the company&#8217;s growth over the past year, it&#8217;s bringing on new team members, with plans to get to 100 people by the beginning of 2022. In particular, it&#8217;s brought on Bill Kaper as Chief Technology Officer. Kaper hails from Root Insurance, where he served as VP of Engineering and oversaw a team of 200+ engineers. Huckleberry also snagged Braden Davis, formerly of Jetty, as Chief Insurance Officer.</p>
<p>The company raised $18 million in Series A capital back in December of 2019, with investors that include Tribe Capital, with participation from Amaranthine, Crosslink Capital and Uncork Capital.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VQBiDDqBLQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/18/huckleberry-raises-18m-to-put-small-business-insurance-online/">Huckleberry raises $18M to put small business insurance online</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Huckleberry raises $18M to put small business insurance online&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/18/huckleberry-raises-18m-to-put-small-business-insurance-online/embed/#?secret=VQBiDDqBLQ" data-secret="VQBiDDqBLQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The momentum from the new hires and partnership with Berkshire Hathaway will allow Huckleberry to move into higher risk insurance categories.</p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion. Use code “TCARTICLE&#8221; at checkout to get <a href="http://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1?promo=tcarticle&#038;display=true">20 percent off tickets right here</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/huckleberry-offering-insurance-to-smbs-partners-with-berkshire-hathaway/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128958</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>User Interviews, the CRM for qualitative user research, raises $10 million Series A</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/user-interviews-the-crm-for-qualitative-user-research-raises-10-million-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/user-interviews-the-crm-for-qualitative-user-research-raises-10-million-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 14:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurs roundtable accelerator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[user interviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128934</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[User Interviews, the Entrepreneurs Roundtable Accelerator-backed company that has built a CRM for product developers to get user feedback, has closed on a $10 million Series A round. The financing was led by Teamworthy Ventures, with participation from Las Olas, Accomplice, FJ Labs, ERA, Trestle Partners and ValueStream. The company, cofounded by Basel Fakhoury, was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.userinterviews.com/">User Interviews</a>, the Entrepreneurs Roundtable Accelerator-backed company that has built a CRM for product developers to get user feedback, has closed on a $10 million Series A round. The financing was led by Teamworthy Ventures, with participation from Las Olas, Accomplice, FJ Labs, ERA, Trestle Partners and ValueStream.</p>
<p>The company, cofounded by <a href="https://twitter.com/baself90">Basel Fakhoury</a>, was created out of failure, in some ways. Originally, the User Interviews team started with a project called Mobile Suites, an amenities logistics platform for hotels. It was a dud, and the team — Basel Fakhoury, Dennis Meng and Bob Saris — decided to do more user research before determining their next product.</p>
<p>In trying to collect that research, they stumbled upon a huge problem. It often takes companies weeks, if not months, to conduct a study around user research. The company decided to build out a platform that would procure subjects for research quickly and effectively, using an algorithm to pair qualified, engaged testers with the client.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The product became Recruit, and ran on an a la carte model. To complement Recruit, the team also launched Research Hub, which is a CRM tool for all the testing methodologies used with actual users. To be clear, User Interviews doesn&#8217;t run the surveys or A/B tests themselves, but rather helps companies manage the frequency and data of those tests, not unlike what Salesforce does for sales people.</p>
<p>Recently, User Interviews added a subscription layer to its product, allowing companies to purchase access to the software on an annual basis, rather than on a usage basis. Fakhoury says that this dual-model allows companies to try out the platform before they fully commit.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2128954" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2128954" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2128954" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Workspace.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="484" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Workspace.png 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Workspace.png?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Workspace.png?resize=300,213 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Workspace.png?resize=768,546 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Workspace.png?resize=680,484 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Workspace.png?resize=1536,1092 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Workspace.png?resize=2048,1456 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Workspace.png?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2128954" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> User Interviews</p></div></p>
<p>According to the startup, the company has experienced 140 percent annual growth, which has accelerated during the pandemic. Clients include Amazon, Microsoft, Colgate and Spotify.</p>
<p>User Interviews plans on using the new funding to hire more in the product department, as well as build out integrations with user testing software and their clients own data management systems.</p>
<p>Right now, the team is about 50 people, and is fully remote, with nearly half the workforce being female.</p>
<p>Fakhoury said the biggest challenge for the company is being able to do two things at once.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are simultaneously disrupting this legacy industry with Recruit, and we are creating a category with Research Hub,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Those are somewhat different strategies and missions and making sure that we can do both of those in tandem is one big thing for us.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3RUaF5HXH0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/29/user-interviews-a-platform-for-product-feedback-raises-5-million/">User Interviews, a platform for product feedback, raises $5 million</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;User Interviews, a platform for product feedback, raises $5 million&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/29/user-interviews-a-platform-for-product-feedback-raises-5-million/embed/#?secret=3RUaF5HXH0" data-secret="3RUaF5HXH0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion. Use code “TCARTICLE&#8221; at checkout to get <a href="http://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1?promo=tcarticle&amp;display=true">20 percent off tickets right here</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/user-interviews-the-crm-for-qualitative-user-research-raises-10-million-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128934</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8216;Instant needs&#8217; delivery startup goPuff raises $1.15B at an $8.9B valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/gopuff-new-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/gopuff-new-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 14:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[D1 Capital Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goPuff]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128947</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last fall, delivery startup goPuff made a big splash by raising $380 million in funding and acquiring West Coast beverage retailer BevMo shortly afterwards. Just a few months later, the Philadelphia-based company is announcing that it has raised another $1.15 billion in funding at an $8.9 billion valuation (compared to $3.9 billion in October). Available in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last fall, delivery startup <a href="https://gopuff.com">goPuff</a> made a big splash by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/gopuff-funding/">raising $380 million in funding</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/gopuff-acquires-bevmo/">acquiring West Coast beverage retailer BevMo</a> shortly afterwards. Just a few months later, the Philadelphia-based company is announcing that it has raised another $1.15 billion in funding at an $8.9 billion valuation (compared to $3.9 billion in October).</p>
<p>Available in more than 650 U.S. cities, goPuff delivers a wide variety of products in under 30 minutes while charging a flat $1.95 delivery fee. Rafael Ilishayev and Yakir Gola, who serve as co-CEOs, founded the company in 2013 while they were students at Drexel University. When <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/gopuff-funding/">I first spoke to Gola last fall</a>, he told me that the pair thought, &#8220;There has to be a better way to get convenience products delivered.”</p>
<p>The company now says its vertically integrated approach is a key advantage. GoPuff buys products directly from manufacturers, then distributes those products through its 250-plus &#8220;micro-fulfillment centers&#8221; and a network of independent drivers. Ilishayev said this results in rapid deliveries, strong unit economics, and a model that passes delivery fees directly to drivers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s important that we&#8217;re making our margin on product, not people,&#8221; he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3j1ofcNJ55"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/gopuff-funding/">Delivery startup goPuff raises $380M at a $3.9B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Delivery startup goPuff raises $380M at a $3.9B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/gopuff-funding/embed/#?secret=3j1ofcNJ55" data-secret="3j1ofcNJ55" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The company continues to expand its product lineup new Better For You (healthy snacks), Beauty and Baby categories, as well as<a href="https://gopuff.com/mystery_box"> Curated Mystery Boxes</a>. When I asked how new products fit into the larger goPuff brand and strategy, Ilishayev replied, &#8220;People, throughout our whole existence, have tried to put us into an industry: &#8216;Are you convenience? Are you pharmacy?&#8217; The reality is that we&#8217;re neither. We&#8217;re in this category of instant needs, and our production innovation solely stems from consumer demand &#8230; There&#8217;s no category we offer on goPuff that consumers weren&#8217;t crying out for.&#8221;</p>
<p>GoPuff says that the new funding will allow it to continue expanding throughout the United States, as well as internationally, and to introduce new products. The round comes from D1 Capital Partners, Fidelity Management and Research Company, Baillie Gifford, Eldridge, Reinvent Capital, Luxor Capital and SoftBank Vision Fund 1.</p>
<p>In a statement, D1 founder and Chief Investment Officer Daniel Sundheim said:</p>
<blockquote><p>goPuff is truly in a league of its own. We believe that the company&#8217;s vision and differentiated model drive industry-leading economics and sustainable growth. Since we initially invested in goPuff last fall, we have been consistently impressed by the team’s ability to successfully execute against its growth plans. The company&#8217;s potential is tremendous, and we look forward to the unique opportunities that lie ahead.</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5fYcdW0fOm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/go-fancy/">Delivery company goPuff is in talks to acquire the UK&#8217;s Fancy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Delivery company goPuff is in talks to acquire the UK&#8217;s Fancy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/go-fancy/embed/#?secret=5fYcdW0fOm" data-secret="5fYcdW0fOm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/gopuff-new-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128947</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook will bring back F8 on June 2 as a pared-back, single-day, virtual-only conference for developers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/facebook-will-bring-back-f8-on-june-2-as-a-pared-back-single-day-virtual-only-conference-for-developers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/facebook-will-bring-back-f8-on-june-2-as-a-pared-back-single-day-virtual-only-conference-for-developers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 13:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128932</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After a few twists and turns and then ultimately cancelling its F8 developer conference last year over Covid-19 concerns, Facebook today announced a return of the event in a virtual-only format it is calling F8 Refresh. The company today said that it will be holding it as a one-day event on June 2. You can [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After a few twists and turns and then ultimately cancelling its F8 developer conference last year over Covid-19 concerns, Facebook today announced a return of the event in a virtual-only format it is calling F8 Refresh. The company today said that it will be holding it as a <a href="https://developers.facebook.com/blog/post/2021/03/23/join-us-f8-refresh-june-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">one-day event on June 2</a>. You can sign up for F8 Refresh <a href="https://developers.facebook.com/f8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a mark of the times to be right-sizing everything to the place we are in right now. So although F8 has grown in size and scope over the years &#8212; it typically attracts around 5,000 people and many more to its in-person event &#8212; it looks like the social network is taking 2021 to be a little more modest in its approach.</p>
<p>Mark is maybe the operative word here: there will be no Mark Zuckerberg keynote this year, Facebook has confirmed to me. Instead of words from its founder and CEO, Facebook will have Konstantinos Papamiltiadis, VP of Platform Partnerships, delivering the opening presentation at the event, which will as usual provide some updates on new launches for the platform.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It&#8217;s another sign of the times that making plans so far in advance, and in person, just won&#8217;t cut it right now: there have been too many unexpected developments around the spread, then wane, then resurgence of the pandemic, and even one year later, in <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-56486732" target="_blank" rel="noopener">multiple parts</a> of the world authorities are still trying to get activity <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/21/us/miami-beach-curfew-spring-break.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">under control</a> to keep the virus in <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/covid-19-boris-johnson-warns-europes-third-wave-will-hit-uk-but-is-reassured-eu-doesnt-want-jabs-blockade-12253582" target="_blank" rel="noopener">check</a>.</p>
<p>In the past, Facebook has given much more lead time to people for F8, to let developers, partners and other attendees to clear their calendars and organize travel from further afield. Its 2020 two-day event, which had originally been scheduled for May 2020, was announced in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/19/facebook-announces-dates-for-its-2020-f8-developers-conference/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">November 2019</a> for example. Of course, in the months following, as Covid-19 took its grip, F8 2020 became one of a wave of events to be cancelled, with Facebook first looking to replace it with a series of local events, but then cancelling everything altogether.</p>
<p>&#8220;F8 has always brought together an incredible community of people who are building, innovating, and looking for what’s next. And over the last year, our community of developers enabled growth for businesses of all sizes to adapt to a changed world and accelerate their digital transformation,&#8221; noted Papamiltiadis in a blog post. &#8220;In recognition of this, we want to bring F8 back to its roots: a place to celebrate, inspire and help developers grow.&#8221;</p>
<p>The big question will be what topics Facebook will see fit to tackle in June. Some of the bigger themes hanging over it right now are how it plans to continue growing in developing markets, whether/what it will launch in response to newly rising apps like Clubhouse, how it might diversify its business model beyond advertising, whether we will ever see a launch of Novi and Diem, and how Facebook continues to tackle misuse on its platform.</p>
<p>For a company so huge and influential, there is indeed a lot to potentially cover. But at least for now the focus seems to be more modest as well. Rather than big launches and major announcements, it looks like Facebook will keep the F8 focus more on its ecosystem and the developers in it. Among the areas that Papamiltiadis highlighted will be addressed, he mentioned product tools for building in Facebook, Instagram, Messenger, WhatsApp and Oculus; technical deep-dive sessions; demos, and panels.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/facebook-will-bring-back-f8-on-june-2-as-a-pared-back-single-day-virtual-only-conference-for-developers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128932</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trace announces $8M seed to help companies coordinate budgets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/trace-announces-8m-seed-to-help-companies-coordinate-budgets/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/trace-announces-8m-seed-to-help-companies-coordinate-budgets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 13:32:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[budgeting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greylock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trace]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128941</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trace, an early startup that wants to bring a taste of SaaS to the budgeting side of the house, announced an $8 million seed round today led by Greylock and Uncork Capital with participation from Nyca Partners, Redpoint Ventures and various individual angels. Mike Gonzalez, co-founder and CEO at the company describes Trace as the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://www.tracehq.com/">Trace</a>, an early startup that wants to bring a taste of SaaS to the budgeting side of the house, announced an $8 million seed round today led by Greylock and Uncork Capital with participation from Nyca Partners, Redpoint Ventures and various individual angels.</p>
<p>Mike Gonzalez, co-founder and CEO at the company describes Trace as the first service designed specifically for finance teams to deal with budgeting. &#8220;What Trace is really building is an all-in-one platform where financial decisions are made, and people can work with finance to get work done,&#8221; he explained</p>
<p>Trace handles all the core interactions between finance and everyone they need to work with in the business, focusing on budget owners. &#8220;In our platform, budget owners are given visibility into their financial targets, so they know what they&#8217;re working towards,&#8221; he said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The idea is to build a more coordinated workflow between all the stakeholders in the budget process including finance, the department head, legal, security operations and so forth. Instead of cobbling together a bunch of different tools, Trace is attempting to bring this process into a single service.</p>
<p>Gonzalez has a deep background in this area having spent several years building custom financial systems as a consultant, and later working at Zenefits to build an internal system to track this kind of financial information. He took that knowledge, and along with his co-founders built Trace.</p>
<p>The company launched in 2018, spent the next year building the product and debuted the service in 2019. Although the pandemic has been challenging on a personal and company-building level, it did expose how important having a grip on the financial side of the business was when every penny counts.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YkD3aykTPn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/14/recurrency-is-taking-on-giants-like-sap-with-a-modern-twist-on-erp/">Recurrency is taking on giants like SAP with a modern twist on ERP</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Recurrency is taking on giants like SAP with a modern twist on ERP&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/14/recurrency-is-taking-on-giants-like-sap-with-a-modern-twist-on-erp/embed/#?secret=YkD3aykTPn" data-secret="YkD3aykTPn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>For now the startup is taking aim at companies with between 200 and 1500 employees with hopes of ramping up to larger companies over time. Trace currently works with Sage Intacct, Netsuite and QuickBooks ERP financial systems.</p>
<p>It has a dozen employees, mostly in R&amp;D with plans to add to that number as the business grows. As a Hispanic, who co-founded the company with his brother, he says that D&amp;I is a cornerstone of his company building plans.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re both Hispanics, and we grew up in rough neighborhoods without privilege. And so promoting an environment of equal opportunity and inclusion is something that I care deeply about,&#8221; he said. He says that they have already begun to invest to drive diversity and it&#8217;s a huge priority for the company moving forward.</p>
<p>The company has been distributed from the beginning, so the pandemic didn&#8217;t really change that, but as it grows, Gonzalez envisions having an office where people can come together for more collaborative work as needed.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7QstSiu44S"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/26/use-agile-budgeting-to-manage-your-cash/">Use agile budgeting to manage your cash</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Use agile budgeting to manage your cash&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/26/use-agile-budgeting-to-manage-your-cash/embed/#?secret=7QstSiu44S" data-secret="7QstSiu44S" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/trace-announces-8m-seed-to-help-companies-coordinate-budgets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128941</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Planting seed investments on tech&#8217;s frontiers nets KdT Ventures $50 million for its latest fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/planting-seed-investments-on-techs-frontiers-nets-kdt-ventures-50-million-for-its-latest-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/planting-seed-investments-on-techs-frontiers-nets-kdt-ventures-50-million-for-its-latest-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 13:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[54gene]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbnb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[austin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cambridge Associates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chemicals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Databricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fork]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Houston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north carolina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PathAI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solugen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stanford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tulane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[university of texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128846</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Like other venture investors over the past year, Cain McClary, co-founder of the investment firm KdT Ventures, recently made the jump to Austin. But unlike the rest of them, he was coming from Black Mountain, NC. McClary had spent the better part of the last three years with his co-founder Mack Healy building out a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Like other venture investors over the past year, Cain McClary, co-founder of the investment firm <a href="https://www.kdtvc.com/">KdT Ventures</a>, recently made the jump to Austin. But unlike the rest of them, he was coming from Black Mountain, NC.</p>
<p>McClary had spent the better part of the last three years with his co-founder Mack Healy building out a portfolio that would be the envy of almost any investor looking at financing startups whose businesses depend on innovations at the borders of current technological achievement.</p>
<p>Since 2017, when the firm closed on the first $3.5 million of what ended up being a $15 million fund (<a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001716717/000171671717000001/xslFormDX01/primary_doc.xml">they had targeted $30 million</a>), McClary and Healy managed to find their way onto the cap table of businesses like the green chemicals manufacturer, Solugen; health diagnostics technology developer, <span style="font-weight: 400;">PathAI; the Nigerian genetic dataset developer, 54Gene; the novel biomaterials developer, Checkerspot; and the genetics-focused therapy company, Dyno Therapeutics. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That portfolio &#8212; and the subsequent top decile performance that Cambridge Associates has said comes with it &#8212; has allowed McClary and Healy to close on an oversubscribed $50 million new fund to invest in promising startup companies.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2128858" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2128858" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2128858" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/KdT-co-founder.png" alt="" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/KdT-co-founder.png 1784w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/KdT-co-founder.png?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/KdT-co-founder.png?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/KdT-co-founder.png?resize=768,511 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/KdT-co-founder.png?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/KdT-co-founder.png?resize=1536,1023 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/KdT-co-founder.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2128858" class="wp-caption-text">KdT co-founders Cain McClary and Mack Healy. Image Credit: <a href="https://www.kdtvc.com/">KdT Ventures</a></p></div></p>
<p>Hailing from a small Tennessee town outside of Leipers Fork (itself a small Tennessee town) McClary studied medicine at Tulane and business at Stanford where he linked up with Healy through a mutual friend.</p>
<p>Healy, who had done stints throughout big Bay Area startups like Airbnb, Databricks, and Facebook brought the software expertise (and some capital to stake the firm) while McClary provided the life sciences know-how.</p>
<p>Together the two men set out to hang their investment shingle at the intersection of software and life sciences that was proving to be fertile ground for new business creation. Each company in the firm&#8217;s portfolio depends on both the advances in understanding how to code computers and living cells.</p>
<p>McClary had left California for personal reasons when he launched the fund in 2017 and in 2020 relocated to Austin for professional ones. Healy had already set up shop in the city and it was easier, McClary said to fly out to San Francisco to look for companies from the Austin airport than it was from Ashville.</p>
<p>Also, both men were placing big bets on the Dell Medical School at the University of Texas to become the breeding ground for the type of entrepreneurs that the firm is looking to back.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mack was there… the Dell Medical School and we think it’s going to be produce the types of entrpereneurs that we want to support. Houston has a med system. I firmly believe that texas has a place at the table in the future </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;The way that we define it is that we like to invest in the physical layer of the world,&#8221; said McClary. &#8220;That includes not only medicine, but chemicals and agriculture. All of that is driven by some of the things that we have this sourcecode for the physical world.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Mapping the unmapped corners of the frontier tech startup world means that the firm not only has a presence in Austin, but has hired principals to scour Houston and Research Triangle Park in North Carolina for hot deals.</p>
<p>That doesn&#8217;t mean the firm is forsaking California though. One of the most recent deals in the KdT portfolio is Andes Ag, an Emeryville, Calif.-based startup that&#8217;s applying yield-boosting microbes directly to seeds in an effort to improve crop performance for farmers.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The KdT team speaks the language of science, making them an outlier in this area of venture investing,&#8221; said JD Montgomery of Canterbury Consulting, a limited partner in KdT’s first and second fund. “They are passionate about building the science companies of the future that will tackle some of the significant challenges our world faces in the next decade and beyond.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/planting-seed-investments-on-techs-frontiers-nets-kdt-ventures-50-million-for-its-latest-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128846</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Gates wants Western countries to eat &#8220;synthetic meat&#8221;; Meatable has raised $47 million to make it</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/bill-gates-wants-western-countries-to-eat-synthetic-meat-meatable-has-raised-47-million-to-make-it/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/bill-gates-wants-western-countries-to-eat-synthetic-meat-meatable-has-raised-47-million-to-make-it/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 13:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amsterdam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bill Gates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bill maris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlueYard Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cellular agriculture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief technology officer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cultured meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eat Just]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food production]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Illumina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Juno Therapeutics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meatable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memphis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memphis meats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netherlands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tel Aviv]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128860</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a recent interview discussing Bill Gates&#8217; recent book &#8220;How to Avoid a Climate Disaster&#8220;, the Microsoft and Breakthrough Energy founder (and the world&#8217;s third wealthiest man) advocated for citizens of the richest countries in the world to switch to diets consisting entirely of what he called synthetic meat in an effort to curb greenhouse [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/02/14/1018296/bill-gates-climate-change-beef-trees-microsoft/">a recent interview</a> discussing Bill Gates&#8217; recent book &#8220;<a href="https://www.amazon.com/How-Avoid-Climate-Disaster-Breakthroughs/dp/0385546130/ref=asc_df_0385546130/?tag=hyprod-20&amp;linkCode=df0&amp;hvadid=459649254175&amp;hvpos=&amp;hvnetw=g&amp;hvrand=11168314863701036991&amp;hvpone=&amp;hvptwo=&amp;hvqmt=&amp;hvdev=c&amp;hvdvcmdl=&amp;hvlocint=&amp;hvlocphy=9010962&amp;hvtargid=pla-918137739254&amp;psc=1">How to Avoid a Climate Disaster</a>&#8220;, the Microsoft and <a href="https://www.breakthroughenergy.org/">Breakthrough Energy</a> founder (and the world&#8217;s<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/billionaires/"> third wealthiest man</a>) advocated for citizens of the richest countries in the world to switch to diets consisting entirely of what he called synthetic meat in an effort to curb greenhouse gas emissions.</p>
<p>Gates&#8217; call is being met by startups and public companies hailing from everywhere from Amsterdam to Tel Aviv, London to Los Angeles, and Berkeley to&#8230; um&#8230; Chicago.</p>
<p>Indeed, two of the best funded companies in the lab-grown meat market hail from The Netherlands, where <a href="https://mosameat.com/">Mosa Meat</a> is being challenged by a newer upstart, <a href="https://www.meatable.com/">Meatable</a>, which just announced $47 million in new financing.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company aims to have its first product approved by European regulators by 2023 and notching commercial sales by 2025.</p>
<p>Meatable has a long road ahead of it, because, as Gates acknowledged in his interview with MIT Technology Review <em>(ed. note: I&#8217;m</em> available for a call, too, Bill), &#8220;the people like Memphis Meats who do it at a cellular level—I don’t know that that will ever be economical.&#8221;</p>
<p>Beyond the economics, there&#8217;s also the open question of whether consumers will be willing to make the switch to lab grown meat. Some companies, like the San Francisco-based Just Foods and Tel Aviv&#8217;s Supermeat are already selling chicken patties and nuggets made from cultured cells at select restaurants.</p>
<p>These products don&#8217;t get at the full potential for cellular technology according to Daan Luining, Meatable&#8217;s chief technology officer. &#8220;We have seen the nugget and the chicken burger, but we&#8217;re working on whole muscle tissue,&#8221; Luining said.</p>
<p>The sheer number of entrants in the category &#8212; and the capital they&#8217;ve raised &#8212; points to the opportunity for several winners if companies can walk the tightrope balancing cost at scale and quality replacements for free range food.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;The mission of the company is to be a global leader in providing proteins for the planet. Pork and beef and regularly eaten cuts have on environmental and land management,&#8221; Luining said. &#8220;The technology that we are using allows us to go into different species. First we’re focused on the animals that have the biggest impact on climate change and planetary health.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>For Meatable right now, price remains an issue. The company is currently producing meat at roughly $10,000 per pound, but, unlike its competitors, the company said it is producing whole meat. That&#8217;s including the fat and connective tissue that makes meat&#8230; well&#8230; meat.</p>
<p>Now with 35 employees and new financing, the company is trying to shift from research and development into a food production company. Strategic investors like DSM, one of the largest food biotech companies in Europe should help. So should angel investors like Dr. Jeffrey Leiden, the executive chairman of Vertex Pharmaceuticals; and Dr. Rick Klausner, the former executive director of the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation and a founder of Juno Therapeutics, GRAIL, and Mindstrong Health, after leaving Illumina where he served as chief medical officer.</p>
<p>Institutional investors in the company&#8217;s latest round include Google Ventures founder Bill Maris&#8217;<span style="font-weight: 400;"> new fund, </span><a href="https://section32.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Section 32</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and existing investors like: </span><a href="https://blueyard.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">BlueYard Capital</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://agronomics.im/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Agronomics</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://humboldtfund.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Humboldt</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and </span><a href="https://www.weforum.org/people/taavet-hinrikus"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Taavet Hinrikus.</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p>The company&#8217;s first commercial offering will likely be a lab-grown pork product, but with expanded facilities in Delft, the location of one of the top universities in The Netherlands, a beef product may not be far behind.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“[Meatable has] a great team and game-changing technology that can address the challenges around the global food insecurity issues our planet is facing,” said Klausner. “They have all the right ingredients to become the leading choice for sustainably and efficiently produced meat.”</span></p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion. Use code “TCARTICLE&#8221; at checkout to get <a href="http://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1?promo=tcarticle&#038;display=true">20 percent off tickets right here</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/bill-gates-wants-western-countries-to-eat-synthetic-meat-meatable-has-raised-47-million-to-make-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128860</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Customer data platform ActionIQ extends its latest funding round to $100M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/actioniq-series-c-extension/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/actioniq-series-c-extension/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 13:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[actioniq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Data Platforms]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128902</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ActionIQ, which helps companies use their customer data to deliver personalized experiences, is announcing that it has extended its Series C funding, bringing the round to a total size of $100 million. That number includes the $32 million that ActionIQ announced in January of last year. Founder and CEO Tasso Argyros said the company is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.actioniq.com">ActionIQ</a>, which helps companies use their customer data to deliver personalized experiences, is announcing that it has extended its Series C funding, bringing the round to a total size of $100 million.</p>
<p>That number includes <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/actioniq-series-c/">the $32 million that ActionIQ announced</a> in January of last year. Founder and CEO Tasso Argyros said the company is framing this as an extension rather than a separate round because it comes from existing investors — including March Capital — and because ActionIQ still has most of that $32 million in the bank.</p>
<p>Argyros told me that there were two connected reasons to raise additional money now. For one thing, ActionIQ has seen 100% year-over-year revenue growth, allowing it to increase its valuation by more than 250%. (The company isn&#8217;t not disclosing the actual valuation.) That growth has also meant that ActionIQ is getting &#8220;a lot more ambitious&#8221; in its plans for product development and customer growth.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We raised more money because we can, and because we need to,&#8221; Argyros said.</p>
<p>The company continues to develop the core platform, for example by introducing more support for real-time data and analysis. But Argyros suggested that the biggest change has been in the broader market for customer data platforms, with companies like Morgan Stanley, The Hartford, Albertsons, JCPenney and GoPro signing on with ActionIQ in the past year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gmBwu3ZgvI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/actioniq-series-c/">Customer data platform ActionIQ raises $32M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Customer data platform ActionIQ raises $32M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/actioniq-series-c/embed/#?secret=gmBwu3ZgvI" data-secret="gmBwu3ZgvI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Some of these enterprises, he said, &#8220;normally would not work with a cutting-edge technology company like us, but because of the pandemic, they&#8217;re willing to take some risk and really invest in their customer base and their customer experience.&#8221;</p>
<p>Argyros also argued that as regulators and large platforms restrict the ways that businesses can buy and sell third-party data, platforms like ActionIQ, focusing on the first-party data that companies collect for their own use, will become increasingly important. And he said that ActionIQ&#8217;s growth comes as the big marketing clouds have &#8220;failed&#8221; — either announcing products that have yet to launch or launching products that don&#8217;t match ActionIQ&#8217;s capabilities.</p>
<p>Companies that were already using ActionIQ include The New York Times. In fact, the funding announcement includes a statement from The Times&#8217; senior vices president of data and insights Shane Murray declaring that the newspaper is using ActionIQ to deliver &#8220;hundreds of billions of personalized customer experiences&#8221; across &#8220;mail, in-app, site, and paid media.&#8221;</p>
<p>ActionIQ has now raised around $145 million total, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/actioniq">according to Crunchbase</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0hD8scNh2U"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/microsoft-enhances-customer-data-platform-as-pandemic-drives-need-for-personalization/">Microsoft enhances customer data platform as pandemic drives need for personalization</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Microsoft enhances customer data platform as pandemic drives need for personalization&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/microsoft-enhances-customer-data-platform-as-pandemic-drives-need-for-personalization/embed/#?secret=0hD8scNh2U" data-secret="0hD8scNh2U" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion. Use code “TCARTICLE&#8221; at checkout to get <a href="http://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1?promo=tcarticle&#038;display=true">20 percent off tickets right here</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/actioniq-series-c-extension/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128902</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hopin buys two more companies as it triples down on video focus</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/hopin-buys-two-more-companies-as-it-triples-down-on-video-focus/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/hopin-buys-two-more-companies-as-it-triples-down-on-video-focus/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 12:53:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hopin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hopin, a unicorn best known for its online events-hosting service, announced this morning that it has acquired two more companies. The smaller concerns, Jamm and Streamable, were acquired in deals that Hopin declined to detail. However, in an email to TechCrunch, Hopin CEO Johnny Boufarhat said that both companies were &#8220;early-stage&#8221; concerns. We can infer [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://hopin.com/">Hopin</a>, a unicorn best known for its online events-hosting service, <a href="https://hopin.com/blog/hopin-acquires-streamable-and-jamm">announced</a> this morning that it has acquired two more companies. The smaller concerns, <a href="https://jamm.app/en/download/">Jamm</a> and <a href="https://streamable.com/">Streamable</a>, were acquired in deals that Hopin declined to detail.</p>
<p>However, in an email to TechCrunch, Hopin CEO <a href="https://twitter.com/johnnyboufarhat">Johnny Boufarhat</a> said that both companies were &#8220;early-stage&#8221; concerns. We can infer deal scale from the comment.</p>
<p>Hopin has operated with an acquisitive bent in recent months, announcing an acquisition of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/07/hopin-buys-livestreaming-startup-streamyard-for-250m-as-it-looks-to-expand-its-product-lineup/">StreamYard for $250 million</a> in January in addition to today&#8217;s deals.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Jamm sells what it calls &#8220;1-click video collaboration for teams,&#8221; while Streamable helps other companies upload and stream their videos. After acquiring StreamYard, which provided video livestreaming services, it&#8217;s not hard to discern that video is the locus of Hopin&#8217;s checkbook focus.</p>
<p>Boufarhat agrees, explaining to TechCrunch that its latest purchases will help his company &#8220;build even more technology for customers to make professional-grade video capabilities easily accessible at scale.&#8221; The CEO added that his company is &#8220;unofficially&#8221; calling its efforts &#8220;an ecosystem of connection powered by all aspects of video.&#8221;</p>
<p>The total addressable market (TAM) for that vision is likely larger than the online-events work that Hopin is best known for, or even the hybrid online/offline events market that the company was originally born to support.</p>
<p>When Hopin announced its StreamYard buy, it had purchased a company with material revenues. Boufarhat&#8217;s team decided to keep the startup alive as a standalone product. As Jamm and Streamable are earlier-stage affairs, will they receive the same treatment?</p>
<p>Yes and no. Yes for Streamable, no for Jamm. Per Hopin&#8217;s founder, Jamm will be &#8220;fully integrated into Hopin’s products,&#8221; while Streamable will both live on as an individual product while also finding points of integration into its events platform.</p>
<p>TechCrunch was curious if, as in the StreamYard deal, the amount of revenue that Hopin had purchased was material. It is not, per Boufarhat. So, the last revenue number we have for Hopin, some $70 million ARR disclosed during <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/hopin-confirms-400m-raise-at-5-65b-valuation/">its $400 million funding round earlier this month</a>, is likely still pertinent. Hopin was valued at $5.65 billion at the time.</p>
<p>The company did disclose that the number of &#8220;organizers&#8221; using its platform to host events has risen from 85,000 earlier this month to 90,000 as of today. That&#8217;s just under 6% growth in less than a month. Hopin&#8217;s rapid growth trajectory appears intact for now.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/hopin-buys-two-more-companies-as-it-triples-down-on-video-focus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128899</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Telegram raises $150M from Mubadala and Abu Dhabi CP via pre-IPO convertible bonds</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/telegram-raises-150m-from-mubadala-and-abu-dhabi-cp-via-pre-ipo-convertible-bonds/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/telegram-raises-150m-from-mubadala-and-abu-dhabi-cp-via-pre-ipo-convertible-bonds/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 12:42:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abu Dhabi Catalyst Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[messaging apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mubadala Investment Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Patreon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pavel Durov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telegram]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128875</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Messaging platform Telegram, which recently passed 500 million monthly active users but still isn&#8217;t monetizing all the digital chatter it hosts &#8212; has taken in a little more funding to keep its engines ticking over. Mubadala Investment Company, the Abu Dhabi-based sovereign investor, is throwing in $75M in exchange for 5-year pre-IPO convertible bonds of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Messaging platform Telegram, which recently passed 500 million monthly active users but still isn&#8217;t monetizing all the digital chatter it hosts &#8212; has taken in a little more funding to keep its engines ticking over.</p>
<p>Mubadala Investment Company, the Abu Dhabi-based sovereign investor, is throwing in $75M in exchange for 5-year pre-IPO convertible bonds of Telegram &#8212; with Abu Dhabi Catalyst Partners investing a further $75M, the pair said today in a <a href="https://www.wam.ae/en/details/1395302920777">press release</a>.</p>
<p>The investment is touted as a strategic partnership, with Mubadala anticipating benefits for Abu Dhabi&#8217;s startup ecosystem by having a local Telegram presence drawing in skills and talent to the capital.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Per <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-mubadala-inv-telegram/abu-dhabi-funds-invest-150-million-in-telegram-messaging-app-idUSKBN2BF0UR">Reuters</a> Telegram will be opening an office in Abu Dhabi following the investment &#8212; building out its regional presence from a Dubai, UAE base.</p>
<p>Commenting in a statement, Pavel Durov, Telegram founder and CEO, said: &#8220;We are honoured by the $150M investment into Telegram from Mubadala and Abu Dubai Catalyst Partners. We look forward to developing this strategic partnership to continue our growth in the MENA region and globally.&#8221;</p>
<p>To date, Telegram has been bankrolled over a seven+ year lifespan by Durov, who made ~$300M from selling his stake in the vk social network he also founded &#8212; aka Russia&#8217;s &#8216;Facebook&#8217; &#8212; back in 2015.</p>
<p>But sustaining a messaging platform with half a billion users can&#8217;t be done through billionaire bootstrapping alone.</p>
<p>Some additional investment did come in via Telegram&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/08/telegram-open-network/">recent attempt to launch a blockchain platform</a>. However the effort was derailed by US regulators last year &#8212; forcing it to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/26/telegram-to-pay-sec-fine-of-18-5-million-and-return-1-2-billion-to-investors-as-it-dissolves-ton/">refund</a> most (but not all) of the money it had booked for the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/12/telegram-abandons-its-ton-blockchain-platform/">failed TON platform</a> &#8212; so speculation over how Telegram will monetize its platform goes on.</p>
<p>In recent weeks Durov has responded to this chatter via his public Telegram channel to confirm he&#8217;s considering introducing ads for &#8220;large one-to-many channels&#8221; &#8212; but pledging he won&#8217;t do so in chats.</p>
<p>He has also rejected the notion of using user data to target ads &#8212; a move that would undermine the loud privacy promises Telegram repeatedly makes to users to put clear blue water between its platform and the (Facebook-owned) data-mining competition.</p>
<p>&#8220;Users will be able to opt out of ads, but I do think that privacy-conscious ads are a good way for channel owners to monetize their efforts &#8212; as an alternative to donations or subscriptions, which we are also working to offer them,&#8221; Durov wrote last month.</p>
<p>Telegram&#8217;s usage has, meanwhile, continued to swell this year &#8212; boosted by users switching from Facebook-owned WhatsApp <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/e2e-encrypted-email-providers-also-see-sign-ups-surge-as-chat-app-users-flock-to-signal-and-telegram-in-search-of-privacy/">over privacy concerns</a>. So there&#8217;s limited room for copycat monetization, unless Durov is willing to trash his personal &#8216;pro-privacy, pro-user&#8217; brand. To say that&#8217;s highly unlikely is an understatement.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, he has further limited his options by rejecting a series of investment offers in recent months.</p>
<p>A report in Russian press <a href="https://thebell.io/telegram-otklonil-predlozhenie-ob-investitsiyah-s-otsenkoj-v-30-mlrd">earlier this year</a> said he&#8217;d rejected an investment offer for a 5%-10% stake in the company that had valued it at $30BN. We&#8217;ve also been told he rejected a higher offer that had valued Telegram at $35BN &#8212; and another of $4BN at a $40BN pre-money valuation.</p>
<p>&#8220;Durov is afraid of investors of any kind,&#8221; one source told us on why he refused to give up any equity.</p>
<p>Debt financing seems to be Telegram&#8217;s preferred route at this stage. Back in January <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/telegram-founder-in-talks-to-raise-debt-amid-apps-explosive-growth">The Information</a> reported that it was discussing raising up to $1BN in debt financing from with banks and investors &#8212; which would convert to shares in an eventual public offering.</p>
<p>That debt route &#8212; via pre-IPO convertible bonds &#8212; is now taking shape with today&#8217;s investment news out of Abu Dhabi. Although $150M is a lot less than the rumoured $1BN so this may be just an initial tranche. (And may in fact be needed to pay back TON investors&#8217; <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/telegram-offers-ico-investors-refund-or-option-to-hang-on-till-april-2021">whose refunds are falling due</a>.)</p>
<p>But with a couple of debt backers sticking their necks out to take a punt on Durov&#8217;s anti-establishment alternative &#8212; and on the chance of an Telegram IPO by 2026 &#8212; the company is in a better position to get buy in from other debt funders, including in the region as it deepens its geographical commitment to the Middle East.</p>
<p>One key attraction for Telegram backers is likely to be its agile product dev. There Durov has repeatedly shown he can deliver &#8212; growing usage of his platform with the help of a steady pipeline of user-focused features.</p>
<p>Efforts on the product side at this stage look geared towards pivoting into a Patreon-style platform for content creators to build communities of followers willing to pay for their content (which would thereby enable Telegram to monetize by taking a cut as commission).</p>
<p>&#8220;Our end goal is to establish a new class of content creators &#8212; one that is financially sustainable and free to choose the strategy that is best for their subscribers,&#8221; wrote Durov last month. &#8220;Traditional social networks have exploited users and publishers for far too long with excessive data collection and manipulative algorithms. It&#8217;s time to change this.&#8221;</p>
<p>Just over a month later his channel lit up again with more product news &#8212; this time capitalizing on the buzz around social audio with the announcement of the launch of a Clubhouse-clone on Telegram channels dubbed &#8220;voice chats 2.0&#8221;.</p>
<p>He also announced feature that lets admins of channels and public groups host voice chats for millions of live listeners &#8212; taking the cap off the earlier feature. &#8220;No matter how popular your talk gets, new people will be able to tune in. It&#8217;s like public radio reinvented fo the 21st century,&#8221; Telegram&#8217;s blog post enthused.</p>
<p>Durov had more developments to tease: One-to-many video broadcasts that will see the platform let users host their own &#8216;TV stations&#8217; which he said will be coming this &#8220;spring&#8221;. So Telegram continues to evolve as the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/18/clubhouse-app-chat-rooms/">social app landscape shifts</a>.</p>
<p>Commenting on the debt financing in a statement, James Munce, CFO and COO of Abu Dhabi Catalyst Partners (ADCP), lauded Telegram&#8217;s management team’s &#8220;unshakeable dedication to building a platform centred around privacy and user experience&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;We believe this creates a strong value proposition and will be a focal point for social media platforms and a new era of messaging,&#8221; he added.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yjTx5MsCyG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/telegram-to-launch-an-ad-platform-as-it-approaches-500-million-users/">Telegram, nearing 500 million users, to begin monetizing the app</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Telegram, nearing 500 million users, to begin monetizing the app&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/telegram-to-launch-an-ad-platform-as-it-approaches-500-million-users/embed/#?secret=yjTx5MsCyG" data-secret="yjTx5MsCyG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Npm8bV3mjY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/report-social-audio-app-clubhouse-has-topped-8-million-global-downloads/">Report: Social audio app Clubhouse has topped 8 million global downloads</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Report: Social audio app Clubhouse has topped 8 million global downloads&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/report-social-audio-app-clubhouse-has-topped-8-million-global-downloads/embed/#?secret=Npm8bV3mjY" data-secret="Npm8bV3mjY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion. Use code “TCARTICLE&#8221; at checkout to get <a href="http://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1?promo=tcarticle&#038;display=true">20 percent off tickets right here</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/telegram-raises-150m-from-mubadala-and-abu-dhabi-cp-via-pre-ipo-convertible-bonds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128875</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dataminr raises $475M on a $4.1B valuation for real-time insights based on 100k sources of public data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/dataminr-raises-475m-on-a-4-1b-valuation-for-real-time-insights-based-on-100k-sources-of-public-data/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/dataminr-raises-475m-on-a-4-1b-valuation-for-real-time-insights-based-on-100k-sources-of-public-data/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 12:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big data analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dataminr]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128867</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Significant funding news today for one of the startups making a business out of tapping huge, noisy troves of publicly available data across social media, news sites, undisclosed filings and more. Dataminr, which ingests information from a mix of 100,000 public data sources, and then based on that provides customers real-time insights into ongoing events [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Significant funding news today for one of the startups making a business out of tapping huge, noisy troves of publicly available data across social media, news sites, undisclosed filings and more. <a href="http://dataminr.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dataminr</a>, which ingests information from a mix of 100,000 public data sources, and then based on that provides customers real-time insights into ongoing events and new developments, has closed on $475 million in new funding. Dataminr has confirmed that this Series F values the company at $4.1 billion as it gears up for an IPO in 2023.</p>
<p>This Series F is coming from a mix of investors including Eldridge (a firm that owns the LA Dodgers but also makes a bunch of other sports, media, tech and other investments), Valor Equity Partners (the firm behind Tesla and many tech startups), MSD Capital (Michael Dell&#8217;s fund), Reinvent Capital (Mark Pincus and Reid Hoffman&#8217;s firm), ArrowMark Partners, IVP, Eden Global and investment funds managed by Morgan Stanley Tactical Value, among others.</p>
<p>To put its valuation into some context, the New York-based company last raised money <a href="https://www.axios.com/dataminr-raises-new-funds-at-16-billion-valuation-36f1d061-7456-4876-8684-6e83d0855b5d.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in 2018</a> at a $1.6 billion valuation. And with this latest round, it has now raised over $1 billion in outside funding, based on <a href="https://my.pitchbook.com/profile/55319-68/company/profile" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PitchBook data</a>. This latest round has been in the works for a while and was <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-16/dataminr-said-to-discuss-funding-at-over-3-6-billion-valuation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rumored last week</a> at a lower valuation than what Dataminr ultimately got.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The funding is coming at a critical moment, both for the company and for the world at large.</p>
<p>In terms of the company, Dataminr has been seeing a huge surge of business.</p>
<p>Ted Bailey, the founder and CEO, said in an interview that it will be using the money to continue growing its business in existing areas: adding more corporate customers, expanding in international sales and expanding its AI platform as it gears up for an IPO, most likely in 2023. In addition to being used journalists and newsrooms, NGOs and other public organizations, its corporate business today, Bailey said, includes half of the Fortune 50 and a number of large public sector organizations. Over the last year that large enterprise segment of its customers doubled in revenue growth.</p>
<p class="p1">&#8220;Whether it&#8217;s for physical safety, reputation risk or crisis management, or business intelligence or cybersecurity, we&#8217;re providing critical insights on a daily basis,&#8221; he said. &#8220;All of the events of the recent year have created a sense of urgency, and demand has really surged.&#8221;</p>
<p class="p1">Activity on the many platforms that Dataminr taps to ingest information has been on the rise for years, but it has grown exponentially in the last year especially as more people spend more time at home and online and away from physically interacting with each other: that means more data for Dataminr to crawl, but also, quite possibly, more at stake for all of us as a result: there is so much more out there than before, and as a result so much more to be gleaned out of that information.</p>
<p>That also means that the wider context of Dataminr&#8217;s growth is not quite so clear cut.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s data tools have indeed usefully helped first responders react in crisis situations, feeding them data faster than even their own channels might do; and it provides a number of useful, market-impacting insights to businesses.</p>
<p>But Dataminr&#8217;s role in helping its customers &#8212; which include policing forces &#8212; connect the dots on certain issues has not always been seen as a positive. One <a href="https://theintercept.com/2020/10/21/dataminr-twitter-surveillance-racial-profiling/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">controversial accusation made last year</a> was that Dataminr data was being used by police for racial profiling. In years past, it has been <a href="https://www.spglobal.com/marketintelligence/en/news-insights/trending/c3gluptwh219hcwm7de5zw2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">barred</a> by specific partners like Twitter from sharing data with intelligence agencies. Twitter used to be a 5% shareholder in the company. Bailey confirmed to me that it no longer is but remains a key partner for data. I&#8217;ve contacted Twitter to see if I can get more detail on this and will update the story if and when I learn more. Twitter <a href="https://s22.q4cdn.com/826641620/files/doc_financials/2020/q4/FINAL-Q4'20-TWTR-Selected-Metrics-and-Financials.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">made $509 million in revenues</a> from services like data licensing in 2020, up by about $45 million on the year before.</p>
<p class="p1">In defense of Dataminr, Bailey that the negative spins on what it does result from &#8220;misperceptions,&#8221; since it can&#8217;t track people or do anything proactive. &#8220;We deliver alerts on events and it’s [about] a time advantage,&#8221; he said, likening it to the Associated Press, but &#8220;just earlier.&#8221;</p>
<p class="p1">&#8220;The product can’t be used for surveillance,&#8221; Bailey added. &#8220;It is prohibited.&#8221;</p>
<p>Of course, in the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/twitter-partners-alerts-highlight-divide-over-surveillance-11601417319" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ongoing debate about surveillance</a>, it&#8217;s more about how Dataminr&#8217;s customers might ultimately use the data that they get through Dataminr&#8217;s tools, so the criticism is more about what it might enable rather than what it does directly.</p>
<p class="p1">Despite some of those persistent questions about the ethics of AI and other tools and how they are implemented by end users, backers are bullish on the opportunities for Dataminr to continue growing.</p>
<p>Eden Global Partners served as strategic partner for the Series F capital round.</p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion. Use code “TCARTICLE&#8221; at checkout to get <a href="http://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1?promo=tcarticle&amp;display=true">20 percent off tickets right here</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/dataminr-raises-475m-on-a-4-1b-valuation-for-real-time-insights-based-on-100k-sources-of-public-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128867</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ghana&#8217;s Redbird raises $1.5M seed to expand access to rapid medical testing in sub-Saharan Africa</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/ghanas-redbird-raises-1-5m-seed-to-expand-access-to-rapid-medical-testing-in-sub-saharan-africa/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/ghanas-redbird-raises-1-5m-seed-to-expand-access-to-rapid-medical-testing-in-sub-saharan-africa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 12:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chronic disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CTO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diabetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[founders factory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ghana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redbird]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128851</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For patients and healthcare professionals to properly track and manage illnesses especially chronic ones, healthcare needs to be decentralized. It also needs to be more convenient, with a patient’s health information able to follow them wherever they go. Redbird, a Ghanaian healthtech startup that allows easy access to convenient testing and ensures that doctors and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For patients and healthcare professionals to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">properly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> track and manage illnesses especially chronic ones, healthcare needs to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be decentralized</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It also needs to be more convenient, with a patient’s health information able to follow them wherever they go</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.redbird.co/">Redbird</a>, a Ghanaian healthtech startup that allows easy access to convenient testing and ensures that doctors and patients can view the details of those test results at any time, announced today that it has raised a $1.5 million seed investment</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investors who participated in the round include <a href="https://www.jnjfoundation.com/">Johnson &amp; Johnson Foundation</a>, <a href="https://www.newtownpartners.com/">Newton Partners</a> (via the Imperial Venture Fund), and <a href="https://www.foundersfactory.africa/">Founders Factory Africa</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This brings the company&#8217;s total amount raised to date to $2.5 million.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The healthtech company </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was launched</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2018 by <a href="https://gh.linkedin.com/in/pdbeattie">Patrick Beattie</a>, <a href="https://gh.linkedin.com/in/andrewpquao">Andrew Quao</a> and <a href="https://gh.linkedin.com/in/edward-grandstaff-501913162">Edward Grandstaff</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a founding scientist at a medical diagnostics startup in Boston, Beattie&#8217;s job was to develop new rapid diagnostic tests</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. During his time at Accra in 2016, he met Quao, a trained pharmacist in Ghana at a hackathon whereupon talking found out that their interests in medical testing overlapped.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beattie says to TechCrunch that while he saw many exciting new tests in development in the US, he didn&#8217;t see the same in Ghana</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Quao, who is familiar with how Ghanaians use pharmacies as their primary healthcare point, felt perturbed that these pharmacies weren&#8217;t doing more than transactional purchases</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">They both settled that pharmacies in Ghana needed to imbibe the world of medical testing. Although both didn&#8217;t have a tech background, they realized technology was necessary to execute this</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, they enlisted the help of Grandstaff to be CTO of Redbird while Beattie and Quao became CEO and COO, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">respectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2128862" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2128862" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2128862" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Founders-at-Demo-Day-1024x683-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="454" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Founders-at-Demo-Day-1024x683-1.jpg 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Founders-at-Demo-Day-1024x683-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Founders-at-Demo-Day-1024x683-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Founders-at-Demo-Day-1024x683-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Founders-at-Demo-Day-1024x683-1.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Founders-at-Demo-Day-1024x683-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2128862" class="wp-caption-text">L-R: Patrick Beattie (CEO), Andrew Quao (COO), and Edward Grandstaff (CTO)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Redbird enables pharmacies in Ghana to add rapid diagnostic testing for 10 different health conditions to their pharmacy services</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">These tests include anaemia, blood sugar, blood pressure, BMI, cholesterol, Hepatitis B, malaria, typhoid, prostate cancer screening, and pregnancy</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Redbird provides pharmacies with the necessary equipment, supplies and software to make this possible</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The software &#8212;  Redbird Health Monitoring &#8212; </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is networked</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> across all partner pharmacies and enables patients to build medical testing records after going</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> through 5-minute medical tests offered through these pharmacies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rather than employing a SaaS model that Beattie says is not well appreciated by its customers, Redbird&#8217;s revenue model </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is based</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on the supply of disposable test strips</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Pharmacies who partner with Redbird gain access to the software and all the ways Redbird supports our partners for free as long as they </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">purchase</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the consumables through us</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This aligns our revenue with their success, which </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is aligned</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with patient usage,&#8221; said the CEO.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This model is being used with over over 360 pharmacies in Ghana, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">mainly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in Accra and Kumasi. It was half this number in 2019 which Redbird has since doubled despite the pandemic. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">These pharmacies have recorded over 125,000 tests in the past three years from more than 35,000 patients registered on the platform</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Redbird will use the seed investment </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">to grow its operations within Ghana and expand to new markets that remain undisclosed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2018, Redbird <a href="https://www.alchemistaccelerator.com/blog/patrick-beattie-redbird-founder-story-2">participated in the Alchemist Accelerator </a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a few months before launch</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was the second African startup after fellow Ghanaian healthtech startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/10/ghanas-mpharma-partners-with-ethiopian-conglomerate-to-enter-its-eighth-market/">mPharma</a> to take part in the six-month-long program</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The company also got into Founders Factory Africa last year April.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Beattie, most of the disease burden Africans might experience in the future will be chronic diseases. For instance, diabetes is projected to grow by 156% over the next 25 years</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is why he sees decentralized, digitized healthcare as the next leapfrog opportunity for sub-Saharan Africa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Chronic disease is exploding and with it, patients </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">require</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> much more frequent interaction with the healthcare system</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The burden of chronic disease will make a health system that is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">highly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> centralized impossible,&#8221; he said.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8220;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like previous leapfrog events, this momentum is happening all over the world, not </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in Africa. Still, the state of the current infrastructure means that healthcare systems here will </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be forced</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to innovate and adapt before health systems elsewhere </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are forced</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to, and therein lies the opportunity,&#8221; he said</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But while the promise of technology and data is exciting, it&#8217;s important to realize that healthtech only provides value if it matches patient behaviors and preferences</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It doesn&#8217;t </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">really</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> matter what amazing improvements you can realize with data if you can&#8217;t build the data asset and offer a service that patients actually value</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beattie knows this all too well and says Redbird respects these preferences. For him, the next course of action will be to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">play a larger role in the world&#8217;s developing ecosystem where healthcare systems build decentralised networks and move closer to the average patient</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="k51JrtC5Nz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/05/healthcare-by-2028-will-be-doctor-directed-patient-owned-and-powered-by-visual-technologies/">Healthcare by 2028 will be doctor-directed, patient-owned and powered by visual technologies</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Healthcare by 2028 will be doctor-directed, patient-owned and powered by visual technologies&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/05/healthcare-by-2028-will-be-doctor-directed-patient-owned-and-powered-by-visual-technologies/embed/#?secret=k51JrtC5Nz" data-secret="k51JrtC5Nz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This decentralised approach is what attracted U.S. and South African early-stage VC firm Newtown Partners to cut a check. Speaking on behalf of the firm, Llew Claasen, the managing partner, had this to say</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re excited about Redbird’s decentralised business model that enables rapid diagnostic testing at the point of primary care in local community pharmacies</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Redbird’s digital health record platform has the potential to drive significant value to the broader healthcare value chain and is a vital step toward improving healthcare outcomes in Africa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We look forward to supporting the team as they prove out their  business model and scale across the African continent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.”</span></p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion. Use code “TCARTICLE&#8221; at checkout to get <a href="http://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1?promo=tcarticle&#038;display=true">20 percent off tickets right here</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/ghanas-redbird-raises-1-5m-seed-to-expand-access-to-rapid-medical-testing-in-sub-saharan-africa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128851</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ServiceNow takes RPA plunge by acquiring India-based startup Intellibot</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/servicenow-takes-rpa-plunge-by-acquiring-india-based-startup-intellibot/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/servicenow-takes-rpa-plunge-by-acquiring-india-based-startup-intellibot/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 12:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RPA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ServiceNow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128877</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ServiceNow became the latest company to take the robotic process automation (RPA) plunge when it announced it was acquiring Intellibot, an RPA startup based in Hyderabad, India. The companies did not reveal the purchase price. The purchase comes at a time where companies are looking to automate workflows across the organization. RPA provides a way [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://servicenow.com">ServiceNow</a> became the latest company to take the robotic process automation (RPA) plunge when it announced it was acquiring Intellibot, an RPA startup based in Hyderabad, India. The companies did not reveal the purchase price.</p>
<p>The purchase comes at a time where companies are looking to automate workflows across the organization. RPA provides a way to automate a set of legacy processes, which often involve humans dealing with mundane repetitive work.</p>
<p>The announcement comes on the heels of the company&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/servicenow-adds-new-no-code-capabilities/">no-code workflow announcements</a> earlier this month and is part of the company&#8217;s broader workflow strategy, according to Josh Kahn, SVP of Creator Workflow Products at ServiceNow.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;RPA enhances ServiceNow’s current automation capabilities including low code tools, workflow, playbooks, integrations with over 150 out of the box connectors, machine learning, process mining and predictive analytics,&#8221; Khan explained. He says that the company can now bring RPA natively to the platform with this acquisition, yet still use RPA bots from other vendors if that&#8217;s what the customer requires.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eBGy5ypOwe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/looking-ahead-after-2020s-epic-ma-spree/">Looking ahead after 2020&#8217;s epic M&#038;A spree</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Looking ahead after 2020&#8217;s epic M&#038;A spree&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/looking-ahead-after-2020s-epic-ma-spree/embed/#?secret=eBGy5ypOwe" data-secret="eBGy5ypOwe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;ServiceNow customers can build workflows that incorporate bots from the pure play RPA vendors such as Automation Anywhere, UiPath and Blue Prism, and we will continue to partner with those companies. There will be many instances where customers want to use our native RPA capabilities alongside those from our partners as they build intelligent, end-to-end automation workflows on the Now Platform,&#8221; Khan explained.</p>
<p>The company is making this purchase as other enterprise vendors enter the RPA market. SAP <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/servicenow-adds-new-no-code-capabilities/">announced a new RPA</a> tool at the end of December and acquired <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/sap-is-buying-berlin-business-process-automation-startup-signavio/">process automation startup Signavio</a> in January. Meanwhile <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsofts-power-automate-desktop-is-now-free-for-all-windows-10-users/">Microsoft announced a free RPA tool</a> earlier this month, as the space is clearly getting the attention of these larger vendors.</p>
<p>ServiceNow has been on a buying spree over the last year or so buying five companies including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/servicenow-is-acquiring-element-ai-the-canadian-startup-building-ai-services-for-enterprises/">Element AI</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/22/servicenow-acquires-loom-systems-to-expand-aiops-coverage/">Loom Systems</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/28/servicenow-acquires-conversational-ai-startup-passage-ai/">Passage AI</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/22/servicenow-to-acquire-belgian-configuration-management-startup-sweagle/">Sweagle</a>. Khan says the acquisitions are all in the service of helping companies create automation across the organization.</p>
<p>&#8220;As we bring all of these technologies into the Now Platform, we will accelerate our ability to automate more and more sophisticated use cases. Things like better handling of unstructured data from documents such as written forms, emails and PDFs, and more resilient automations such as larger data sets and non-routine tasks,&#8221; Khan said.</p>
<p>Intellibot was founded in 2015 and will provide the added bonus of giving ServiceNow a stronger foothold in India. The companies expect to close the deal no later than June.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="j57ZSnyG4W"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/servicenow-adds-new-no-code-capabilities/">ServiceNow adds new no-code capabilities</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;ServiceNow adds new no-code capabilities&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/servicenow-adds-new-no-code-capabilities/embed/#?secret=j57ZSnyG4W" data-secret="j57ZSnyG4W" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion. Use code “TCARTICLE&#8221; at checkout to get <a href="http://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1?promo=tcarticle&#038;display=true">20 percent off tickets right here</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/servicenow-takes-rpa-plunge-by-acquiring-india-based-startup-intellibot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128877</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Orca Security raises $210M Series C at a unicorn valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/orca-security-raises-210m-series-c-at-a-unicorn-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/orca-security-raises-210m-series-c-at-a-unicorn-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 12:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Axonius]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CapitalG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybersecurity startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ggv capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[identity access management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orca Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redpoint ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YL Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128664</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Orca Security, an Israeli cybersecurity startup that offers an agent-less security platform for protecting cloud-based assets, today announced that it has raised a $210 million Series C round at a $1.2 billion valuation. The round was led by Alphabet&#8217;s independent growth fund CapitalG and Redpoint Ventures. Existing investors GGV Capital, ICONIQ Growth and angel syndicate [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://orca.security/">Orca Security</a>, an Israeli cybersecurity startup that offers an agent-less security platform for protecting cloud-based assets, today announced that it has raised a $210 million Series C round at a $1.2 billion valuation. The round was led by Alphabet&#8217;s independent growth fund CapitalG and Redpoint Ventures. Existing investors GGV Capital, ICONIQ Growth and angel syndicate Silicon Valley CISO Investment also participated. YL Ventures, which led Orca&#8217;s seed round and participated in previous rounds, is not participating in this round &#8212; and it&#8217;s worth noting that the firm recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/yl-ventures-sells-its-stake-in-cybersecurity-unicorn-axonius-for-270m/">sold its stake in Axonius</a> after that company reached unicorn status.</p>
<p>If all of this sounds familiar, that may be because Orca only raised its $55 million Series B round in December, after it announced its $20.5 million Series A round in May. That&#8217;s a lot of funding rounds in a short amount of time, but something we&#8217;ve been seeing more often in the last year or so.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2128672" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/orca-security-avi-gil.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2128672" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2128672 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/orca-security-avi-gil.png" alt="" width="1024" height="512" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/orca-security-avi-gil.png 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/orca-security-avi-gil.png?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/orca-security-avi-gil.png?resize=300,150 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/orca-security-avi-gil.png?resize=768,384 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/orca-security-avi-gil.png?resize=680,340 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/orca-security-avi-gil.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2128672" class="wp-caption-text">Orca Security co-founders Gil Geron (left) and Avi Shua (right). <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Orca Security</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As Orca co-founder and CEO Avi Shua told me, the company is seeing impressive growth and it &#8212; and its investors &#8212; want to capitalize on this. The company ended last year beating its own forecast from a few months before, which he noted was already aggressive, by more than 50%. Its current slate of customers includes Robinhood, Databricks, Unity, Live Oak Bank, Lemonade and BeyondTrust.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are growing at an unprecedented speed,&#8221; Shua said. &#8220;We were 20-something people last year. We are now closer to a hundred and we are going to double that by the end of the year. And yes, we&#8217;re using this funding to accelerate on every front, from dramatically increasing the product organization to add more capabilities to our platform, for post-breach capabilities, for identity access management and many other areas. And, of course, to increase our go-to-market activities.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HBjJ6UCsjY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/yl-ventures-sells-its-stake-in-cybersecurity-unicorn-axonius-for-270m/">YL Ventures sells its stake in cybersecurity unicorn Axonius for $270M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;YL Ventures sells its stake in cybersecurity unicorn Axonius for $270M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/yl-ventures-sells-its-stake-in-cybersecurity-unicorn-axonius-for-270m/embed/#?secret=HBjJ6UCsjY" data-secret="HBjJ6UCsjY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Shua argues that most current cloud security tools don&#8217;t really work in this new environment. Many, because they are driven by metadata, can only detect a small fraction of the risks, and agent-based solutions may take months to deploy and still not cover a business&#8217; entire cloud estate. The promise of Orca Security is that it can not only cover a company&#8217;s entire range of cloud assets but that it is also able to help security teams prioritize the risks they need to focus on. It does so by using what the company calls its &#8220;SideScanning&#8221; technology, which allows it to map out a company&#8217;s entire cloud environment and file systems.</p>
<p>&#8220;Almost all tools are essentially just looking at discrete risk trees and not the forest. The risk is not just about how pickable the lock is, it&#8217;s also where the lock resides and what&#8217;s inside the box. But most tools just look at the issues themselves and prioritize the most pickable lock, ignoring the business impact and exposure &#8212; and we change that.&#8221;</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/dM1VU-akFGI?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>It&#8217;s no secret that there isn&#8217;t a lot of love lost between Orca and some of its competitors. Last year, Palo Alto Networks <a href="https://orca.security/cybersecurity-community-transparency/">sent Orca Security</a> a sternly worded letter (<a href="https://orca.security/wp-content/uploads/PANW-Legal-Letter-Cease-Desist.pdf">PDF</a>) to stop it from comparing the two services. Shua was not amused at the time and decided to fight it. &#8220;I completely believe there is space in the markets for many vendors, and they&#8217;ve created a lot of great products. But I think the thing that simply cannot be overlooked, is a large company that simply tries to silence competition. This is something that I believe is counterproductive to the industry. It tries to harm competition, it&#8217;s illegal, it&#8217;s unconstitutional. You can&#8217;t use lawyers to take your competitors out of the media.&#8221;</p>
<p>Currently, though, it doesn&#8217;t look like Orca needs to worry too much about the competition. As GGV Capital managing partner Glenn Solomon told me, as the company continues to grow and bring in new customers &#8212; and learn from the data it pulls in from them &#8212; it is also able to improve its technology.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="E6dBOAjQPg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/04/2020-was-a-record-year-for-israels-security-startup-ecosystem/">2020 was a record year for Israel&#8217;s security startup ecosystem</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;2020 was a record year for Israel&#8217;s security startup ecosystem&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/04/2020-was-a-record-year-for-israels-security-startup-ecosystem/embed/#?secret=E6dBOAjQPg" data-secret="E6dBOAjQPg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;Because of the novel technology that Avi and [Orca Security co-founder and CPO] Gil [Geron] have developed &#8212; and that Orca is now based on &#8212; they see so much. They&#8217;re just discovering more and more ways and have more and more plans to continue to expand the value that Orca is going to provide to customers. They sit in a very good spot to be able to continue to leverage information that they have and help DevOps teams and security teams really execute on good hygiene in every imaginable way going forward. I&#8217;m super excited about that future.&#8221;</p>
<p>As for this funding round, Shua noted that he found CapitalG to be a &#8220;huge believer&#8221; in this space and an investor that is looking to invest into the company for the long run (and not just trying to make a quick buck). The fact that CapitalG is associated with Alphabet was obviously also a draw.</p>
<p>&#8220;Being associated with Alphabet, which is one of the three major cloud providers, allowed us to strengthen the relationship, which is definitely a benefit for Orca,&#8221; he said. &#8220;During the evaluation, they essentially put Orca in front of the security leadership at Google. Definitely, they&#8217;ve done their own very deep due diligence as part of that.&#8221;</p>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-end-end-radius: initial; border-end-start-radius: initial; border-inline: initial; border-start-end-radius: initial; border-start-start-radius: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/techcrunch-early-stage-is-the-startup-bootcamp-youve-always-needed/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Early Stage</a> is the premier ‘how-to’ event for startup entrepreneurs and investors. You’ll hear first-hand how some of the most successful founders and VCs build their businesses, raise money and manage their portfolios. We’ll cover every aspect of company-building: Fundraising, recruiting, sales, product market fit, PR, marketing and brand building. Each session also has audience participation built-in – there’s ample time included for audience questions and discussion. Use code “TCARTICLE&#8221; at checkout to get <a href="http://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1?promo=tcarticle&#038;display=true">20 percent off tickets right here</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/orca-security-raises-210m-series-c-at-a-unicorn-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128664</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>D2C furniture startup Tylko closes $26M Series C growth round led by Pitango and Evli</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/d2c-furniture-startups-tylko-closes-26m-series-c-growth-round-led-by-pitango-and-evli/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/d2c-furniture-startups-tylko-closes-26m-series-c-growth-round-led-by-pitango-and-evli/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 11:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evli Growth Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Experior Venture Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Made.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Market Leader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MasterClass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pitango]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pitango Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tylko]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128876</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Polish startup Tylko, a modular furniture company that employs Augmented Reality as part of its sales cycle, has closed a €22 million ($26m) investment Series C funding round, led by Israel-based Pitango Growth and Finnish Evli Growth Partners, following previous investors TDJ Pitango and Experior Venture Fund. Additionally, Brian Walker, former CEO of Hermann Miller, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Polish startup <a href="https://tylko.com/">Tylko</a>, a modular furniture company that employs Augmented Reality as part of its sales cycle, has closed a €22 million ($26m) investment Series C funding round, led by Israel-based Pitango Growth and Finnish Evli Growth Partners, following previous investors TDJ Pitango and Experior Venture Fund. Additionally, Brian Walker, former CEO of Hermann Miller, and Mark Williamson, COO of  US-based MasterClass, join as new investors. Tylko has now raised a total of €33 million since its inception in 2015.</p>
<p>It now plans to more than double its team of 140, as well as launch in new markets, and expand its portfolio, which right now is limited to shelving only.</p>
<p>Tylko is not dissimilar from made.com which, to some extent, pioneered the direct-to-consumer furniture market. Like Made, the idea behind Tylko is also direct-to-consumer, ‘design-on-demand’. The company says it has taken advantage of the period when people have been stuck at home during the pandemic, ordering online, to hit a 132% increase in sales in 2020 in comparison to previous years.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Jacek Majewski, co-founder, Co-CEO Tylko, commented in a statement: “Tylko’s vision has always been about putting the user experience first, in order to create a product that is perfectly designed, high-quality and sustainable. We believe that driving sustainability into this huge industry can only be done by creating highly desirable products that will win over customers by their features rather than certificates.”</p>
<p>Tylko says its furniture of based on ‘parametric design’, with each item being quite individual. Tylko’s platform then automates the manufacturing process for its production partners.</p>
<p>Mikko Kuitunen, Growth Partner at Evli Growth Partners, added: “We are impressed by Tylko’s exceptional growth and ability to scale the company as a market leader, offering new, customized solutions within the furniture market. Tylko’s strong impact-driven vision and made-to-order  business model drives the market’s transition towards more sustainable solutions.”</p>
<p>Rami Kalish, General Managing Partner &amp; Co-Founder at Pitango Venture Capital commented: “Tylko has a huge vision to disrupt the furniture industry.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/d2c-furniture-startups-tylko-closes-26m-series-c-growth-round-led-by-pitango-and-evli/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128876</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Real estate platform Loft raises $425M at a $2.2B valuation in one of Brazil&#8217;s largest venture rounds</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/real-estate-platform-loft-raises-425m-at-a-2-2b-valuation-in-one-of-brazils-largest-venture-rounds/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/real-estate-platform-loft-raises-425m-at-a-2-2b-valuation-in-one-of-brazils-largest-venture-rounds/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 11:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[D1 Capital Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Loft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2128696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Buying and selling residential real estate is a complex business, no matter where you live. A slew of startups in the United States are focused on streamlining that process for people. But in Brazil, where no MLS exists, the challenge of digitizing real estate is even greater. One startup that has set out to serve [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Buying and selling residential real estate is a complex business, no matter where you live. A slew of startups in the United States are focused on streamlining that process for people. But in Brazil, where no MLS exists, the challenge of digitizing real estate is even greater.</p>
<p dir="ltr">One startup that has set out to serve as a “one-stop shop” for Brazilians to help them manage the home buying and selling process has managed to attract one of the largest &#8212; if not the largest &#8212; funding rounds ever raised by a Brazilian startup.</p>
<p dir="ltr">This morning, digital real estate platform <a href="https://www.loft.com.br/">Loft</a> announced it has closed on $425 million in Series D funding led by New York-based D1 Capital Partners. A mix of new and existing investors also participated in the round, including Advent, Altimeter, DST, Silver Lake, Soros, Tarsadia, Tiger Global, Andreessen Horowitz, Caffeinated, Fifth Wall, Monashees, QED and Vulcan, among others.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p dir="ltr">The round values Loft at $2.2 billion, a huge jump from its being just near unicorn territory in January 2020, when it raised a $175 million Series C.</p>
<p dir="ltr">A round of this size is impressive for any startup, but especially for one that was founded just over three years ago in Latin America. The region has seen explosive growth <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/latin-americas-digital-transformation-is-making-up-for-lost-time/">as of late</a>, with a maturing startup scene in Brazil in particular. São Paulo-based Loft too has seen major growth. While the company was less forthcoming about its financials as of late, it told me last year that it had notched “over $150 million in annualized revenues in its first full year of operation” via more than 1,000 transactions.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6v2GJS0EYD"><p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/latin-americas-digital-transformation-is-making-up-for-lost-time/">Latin America&#8217;s digital transformation is making up for lost time</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Latin America&#8217;s digital transformation is making up for lost time&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/latin-americas-digital-transformation-is-making-up-for-lost-time/embed/#?secret=6v2GJS0EYD" data-secret="6v2GJS0EYD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p dir="ltr">In 2020, Loft saw the number of listings on its site increase “10 to 15 times,” according to co-founder and co-CEO Mate Pencz. Today, the company actively maintains more than 13,000 property listings in approximately 130 regions across São Paulo and Rio de Janeiro, partnering with more than 30,000 brokers. Not only are more people open to transacting digitally, more people are looking to buy versus rent in the country.</p>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;We did more than 6x YoY growth with many thousands of transactions over the course of 2020,&#8221; Pencz told TechCrunch. “We’re now growing into the many tens of thousands, and soon hundreds of thousands, of active listings.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">The company’s revenues and GMV (gross merchandise value) also “increased significantly” in 2020, according to Pencz, who declined to provide more specifics. He did say those figures are “multiples higher from where they were,” and that Loft has “a very clear horizon to profitability.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">“Loft has adapted really fast to the new reality we’re living in, with COVID having only propelled or accelerated our growth,” Pencz said.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Pencz and Florian Hagenbuch founded Loft in early 2018 and today serve as its co-CEOs. The aim of the platform, in the company’s words, is “bringing Latin American real estate into the e-commerce age by developing online alternatives to analogue legacy processes and leveraging data to create transparency in highly opaque markets.” The U.S. real estate tech company with the closest model to Loft’s is probably Zillow, according to Pencz.</p>
<p dir="ltr">In the United States, prospective buyers and sellers have the benefit of MLSs, which in the words of the National Association of Realtors, are private databases that are created, maintained and paid for by real estate professionals to help their clients buy and sell property. Loft itself spent years and many dollars in creating its own such databases for the Brazilian market. Besides helping people buy and sell homes, it offers services around insurance, renovations and rentals.</p>
<p dir="ltr">In 2020, Loft also entered the mortgage business by acquiring one of the largest mortgage brokerage businesses in Brazil. The startup now ranks among the top-three mortgage originators in the country, according to Pencz. When it comes to helping people apply for mortgages, he likened Loft to U.S.-based Better.com.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The startup has also grown its number of employees in the past year, growing from 450 last January to 700 today. In particular, it’s significantly beefed up its tech team, according to Pencz.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2128715" style="width: 639px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2128715" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2128715" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Loft-product-image.png?w=300" alt="" width="629" height="608" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Loft-product-image.png 1033w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Loft-product-image.png?resize=150,145 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Loft-product-image.png?resize=300,290 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Loft-product-image.png?resize=768,743 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Loft-product-image.png?resize=680,658 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Loft-product-image.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Loft-product-image.png?resize=50,48 50w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2128715" class="wp-caption-text">Image courtesy of Loft</p></div></p>
<p dir="ltr">Notably, at the time of its series C, the investment marked the first and only investment in Latin America for Vulcan Capital (the investment arm of Microsoft co-founder Paul Allen) and the first and only Brazilian investment for Andreessen Horowitz.</p>
<p dir="ltr">This latest financing brings Loft’s total funding raised to an impressive $700 million. Other backers include Brazil’s Canary and a group of high-profile angel investors such as Max Levchin of Affirm and PayPal, Palantir co-founder Joe Lonsdale, Instagram co-founder Mike Krieger and David Vélez, CEO and founder of Brazilian fintech Nubank. In addition, Loft has also raised more than $100 million in debt financing through a series of publicly listed real estate funds.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Loft plans to use its new capital in part to expand across Brazil and eventually in Latin America and beyond. The company is also planning to explore more M&amp;A opportunities.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QlM698q8Kg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/this-is-a-good-time-to-start-a-proptech-company/">This is a good time to start a proptech company</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;This is a good time to start a proptech company&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/this-is-a-good-time-to-start-a-proptech-company/embed/#?secret=QlM698q8Kg" data-secret="QlM698q8Kg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p dir="ltr">“We&#8217;re now going into this year extremely well-capitalized and I think that in addition to doubling down on the core business, there might be strategic acquisitions also on the horizon,” Pencz told TechCrunch. “We also plan to make Loft as much of a regional and potentially global business, following in the footsteps of some of the other Brazilian companies who recently have been expanding globally.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">Andreessen Horowitz General Partner Alex Rampell said one of the things that really excites his firm about Loft is the idea of it &#8220;being a transactional marketplace for the largest asset class in one of the largest economies on earth&#8230;Loft started off as an iBuyer but now has a vibrant marketplace as well.&#8221; The firm led Loft&#8217;s Series A in July 2018 and has invested in every funding round since.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dan Sundheim, founder of D1 Capital, said that part of his firm&#8217;s approach as investors is identifying opportunities &#8220;at the confluence of structural shifts, secular trends and world-class management teams.&#8221;</span></p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Analyzing Loft, we were particularly impressed by the team’s focus and relentless execution, which has allowed them to build scale as well as deep data and technology moats in a short amount of time,&#8221; he said in a written statement.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/real-estate-platform-loft-raises-425m-at-a-2-2b-valuation-in-one-of-brazils-largest-venture-rounds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2128696</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
