<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 18:08:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Tinder will soon make voluntary ID Verification available globally</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/tinder-will-soon-make-voluntary-id-verification-available-globally/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/tinder-will-soon-make-voluntary-id-verification-available-globally/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 17:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garbo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grindr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Match Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[noonlight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OKCupid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PlentyofFish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tinder]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2190004</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tinder announced this morning that in the &#8220;coming quarters,&#8221; users will be able to verify their ID on the app. This feature was first rolled out in Japan in 2019, where Tinder users must verify that they are at least 18 years old. Aside from places like Japan, where this is mandated by law, ID [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tinder announced this morning that in the &#8220;<a href="https://www.tinderpressroom.com/2021-08-16-Tinder-Commits-to-ID-Verification-for-Members-Globally,-a-First-in-the-Dating-Category">coming quarters</a>,&#8221; users will be able to verify their ID on the app. This feature <a href="https://www.help.tinder.com/hc/en-us/articles/360041821872-Age-verify-to-chat-with-matches">was first rolled out in Japan</a> in 2019, where Tinder users must verify that they are at least 18 years old. Aside from places like Japan, where this is mandated by law, ID verification will &#8220;begin as voluntary,&#8221; Tinder wrote in a <a href="https://www.tinderpressroom.com/2021-08-16-Tinder-Commits-to-ID-Verification-for-Members-Globally,-a-First-in-the-Dating-Category">blog post</a>.</p>
<p>ID verification will be free for all users, similar to its <a href="https://www.help.tinder.com/hc/en-us/articles/360034941812-What-is-Photo-Verification-">photo verification</a> feature. According to a Tinder spokesperson, the company will also use ID verification to cross-reference data like the sex offender registry in regions where that information is accessible. Tinder already does this via credit card lookup when users sign up for a subscription. Per its <a href="https://policies.tinder.com/terms/us/en">terms of use</a>, Tinder requires that users &#8220;have never been convicted of or pled no contest to a felony, a sex crime, or any crime involving violence, and that you are not required to register as a sex offender with any state, federal or local sex offender registry.&#8221;</p>
<p>The existing photo verification feature adds a Twitter-like blue check to a user&#8217;s profile, while ID verification will yield another distinct badge. That way, users can tell whether or not a potential date has confirmed their identity via photo verification, ID verification, both or neither.</p>
<p>&#8220;Creating a truly equitable solution for ID Verification is a challenging, but critical safety project and we are looking to our communities as well as experts to help inform our approach,&#8221; the company <a href="https://www.tinderpressroom.com/2021-08-16-Tinder-Commits-to-ID-Verification-for-Members-Globally,-a-First-in-the-Dating-Category">wrote</a>.</p>
<p>While Tinder has made continued investments in safety features, free ID verification can only go so far &#8212; especially when voluntary, putting the onus on individual users to decide whether or not they feel comfortable meeting up with unverified users. But in March 2021, <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Match Group, the parent company to Tinder, announced its </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/match-group-makes-seven-figure-investment-in-background-check-nonprofit-garbo/">seven-figure contribution</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> to the nonprofit background check company Garbo. </span>Garbo&#8217;s background checks could help detect dating app users with a history of violence or abuse, but we have yet to see how that will be integrated into Tinder, and if users will be charged for access. Notably, Garbo conducts &#8220;equitable background&#8221; checks, meaning that it will exclude <a href="https://medium.com/garbo/update-to-garbos-database-policy-to-create-a-more-equitable-background-check-da94028ad715">drug possession charges and minor traffic incidents</a> on its platform, citing the way that these charges are disproportionately levied against vulnerable communities.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Though Tinder said it will not be using Garbo&#8217;s tech to power its ID verification tools, the company noted to TechCrunch that it will have more information to share about background checks via Garbo in the fall. Tinder didn&#8217;t share whether or not access to information from Garbo will be paywalled. At the time of the acquisition, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/match-group-makes-seven-figure-investment-in-background-check-nonprofit-garbo/">Match Group said</a> it would determine pricing &#8212; if it does choose to paywall this information &#8212; based on factors like user adoption, how many people want to use it and how many searches they want to perform.</span></p>
<p>Tinder&#8217;s investment in safety features is encouraging, but if left behind a paywall, impact may be limited. Match Group faced serious scrutiny in December 2019, when <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/tinder-lets-known-sex-offenders-use-the-app-its-not-the-only-one">an investigation</a> by Columbia Journalism Investigations (CJI) and ProPublica found that the company screened for sexual predators on Match, a paid service, but not on free apps like Tinder, OkCupid and PlentyofFish. At the time, a spokesperson for the company said, “There are definitely registered sex offenders on our free products.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In January 2020, Representative Raja Krishnamoorthi (D-IL) <a href="https://oversight.house.gov/news/press-releases/subcommittee-chairman-krishnamoorthi-launches-investigation-into-user-safety">launched an investigation</a> into user safety policies on dating apps, sending letters to Match Group, The Meet Group, Bumble and Grindr. He wrote, &#8220;Protection from sexual predators should not be a luxury confined to paying customers.” The following month, U.S. Representatives Ann Kuster (D-NH) and Jan Schakowsky (D-IL) wrote a <a href="https://schakowsky.house.gov/media/press-releases/schakowsky-kuster-lead-letter-match-group-president-calling-improvements">letter to Match Group</a>, signed by nine other representatives, stating their concern that Match Group doesn&#8217;t cross-reference user responses with sex offender registries.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Around the same time, Match Group made several moves to invest more deeply in </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.tinderpressroom.com/2021-02-25-The-Top-10-Safety-Focused-Features-on-Tinder">user safety</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> &#8212; for example, it </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/23/match-group-invests-in-noonlight-to-power-new-safety-features-in-tinder-and-other-dating-apps/">acquired Noonlight</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> in January 2020, which allows users in the U.S. to share who, when and where they&#8217;re meeting someone. In dangerous situations, users can discreetly trigger emergency services &#8212; Noonlight will first reach out to the user, then call 911 if necessary (Noonlight&#8217;s basic version is free, but some features like connecting to an Apple Watch, Google Home or Alexa are only available by upgrading to a </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="http://help.noonlight.com/en/articles/3270559-how-much-does-noonlight-cost">$5 or $10 monthly plan</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">). Features like these can be controversial due to concerns about police intervention, but might help some users feel a sense of security. But blocking offenders prior to signup could lessen the need for such intervention in the first place.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YM4Snm4xPS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/match-group-makes-seven-figure-investment-in-background-check-nonprofit-garbo/">Match Group makes seven-figure investment in background check nonprofit Garbo</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Match Group makes seven-figure investment in background check nonprofit Garbo&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/match-group-makes-seven-figure-investment-in-background-check-nonprofit-garbo/embed/#?secret=YM4Snm4xPS" data-secret="YM4Snm4xPS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/tinder-will-soon-make-voluntary-id-verification-available-globally/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2190004</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Regulating crypto is essential to ensuring its global legitimacy</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/regulating-crypto-is-essential-to-ensuring-its-global-legitimacy/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/regulating-crypto-is-essential-to-ensuring-its-global-legitimacy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 17:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[know your customer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money laundering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We must eventually find a halfway point between those with valid concerns about the anonymity crypto assets provide and those who see regulation as prohibitively restrictive on crypto. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Henrik Gebbing</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/henrikgebbing">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Henrik Gebbing is co-CEO and co-founder of <a href="https://finoa.io/">Finoa</a>, a leading European digital asset custody and financial services platform for institutional investors and corporations.	</div>
	
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Wilhelm Nöffke</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/finoa_banking">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Wilhelm Nöffke is the senior compliance manager of <a href="https://finoa.io/">Finoa</a>, a leading European digital asset custody and financial services platform for institutional investors and corporations.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The past decade has seen several structural changes in know your customer (KYC) and anti-money laundering (AML) regulations in Europe and globally. High-profile money laundering cases and the penetration of illicit funds into global markets have caught the attention of regulators and the public, and rightfully so.</p>
<p>The Wirecard scandal was a particularly salacious example, in which the investigation into widespread fraud <a href="https://www.moneylaunderingnews.com/2020/07/wirecard-a-scandal/">revealed a chain of shell companies involved in illegal distribution of narcotics and pornography</a>. Over at Danske Bank, some <a href="https://www.complianceweek.com/aml/how-danske-is-cleaning-up-after-a-200b-money-laundering-scandal/29595.article">$227 billion was laundered through an Estonian subsidiary</a>, going virtually unnoticed for nine years.</p>
<p>In the United States, the Securities and Exchange Commission filed an action <a href="https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2020-338">against Ripple Labs and two of its executives</a>, claiming they had raised over $1.3 billion through an unregistered, ongoing digital asset securities offering. That case is ongoing.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Traditional forms of regulation from the fiat world do not reciprocally apply to every aspect of crypto nor to the fundamental nature of blockchain technology.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>As regulators and financial institutions improve their understanding of these criminal practices, AML requirements have likewise been improved. But these adjustments have been an overwhelmingly reactive, trial-by-fire process.</p>
<p>To address the challenges of the fast-evolving blockchain ecosystem, the European Union has begun to introduce more stringent financial regulations that further bolster the regulatory system in order to improve licensing models. Many member states now regulate crypto assets individually, and Germany is leading the way in being the first to regulate cryptocurrencies.</p>
<p>These individual regulations clearly prescribe the pathway for crypto companies, outlining the requirements for obtaining and maintaining a financial license from the regulator. Compliance naturally boosts investor confidence and protection.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As these financial crimes and crypto itself evolves, so have regulatory bodies’ efforts to monitor, address and enforce restrictions. Internationally, the most prominent monitoring body is the Financial Action Task Force (FATF), which outlines general guidance and determines best practices in anti-money-laundering practices and combating the financing of terrorism.</p>
<p>Although FATF is considered soft law, the task force sets the bar for workable regulations within crypto assets. Especially notable is FATF’s Recommendation 16, better known as the “travel rule,” which requires businesses to collect and store the personal data of participants in blockchain transactions. In theory, access to this data will enable authorities to have better oversight and enforcement of crypto market regulations. In other words, they’ll know exactly who is doing exactly what. Transparency is key.</p>
<h2>The travel rule conundrum</h2>
<p>FATF’s travel rule impacts two types of businesses: traditional financial institutions (banks, credit firms and so on) and crypto companies, otherwise known as <a href="https://sumsub.com/blog/latest-fatf-rules-jolt-crypto-businesses-what-are-the-new-realities-crypto-has-to-acknowledge-to-stay-afloat/">virtual asset service providers</a> (VASPs).</p>
<p>In its original incarnation, the travel rule only applied to banks, but was expanded to crypto companies in 2019. In 2021, many of the FATF member jurisdictions began to incorporate the travel rule into their local AML laws. This regulatory shift sent shockwaves through the crypto sector. The stakes of refusal are high: Failure to incorporate the travel rule results in a service provider being declared noncompliant, which is a major obstacle to doing business.</p>
<p>But, the travel rule is also a major hindrance that doesn’t take into account the novelty of crypto technology. It is problematic for crypto businesses to integrate due to the major amount of effort it poses when obtaining KYC data about the recipient and integrating it into day-to-day business.</p>
<p>In order for crypto businesses to obtain this information for outgoing payments, data would have to be provided by the client and would end up being virtually impossible to verify. This is highly disruptive to the crypto’s emblematic efficiency. Moreover, its implementation presents challenges regarding the accuracy of the data received by VASPs and banks. Also, it creates further data vulnerabilities due to additional data silos being created across the globe.</p>
<p>When it comes to international standardization measures rather than those isolated within certain communities, there is a wide gap between exclusively on-chain solutions (transactions that are recorded and verified on one specific blockchain) and cross-chain communication, which allows for interactions between different blockchains or for combining on-chain transactions with off-chain transactions that are conducted on other electronic systems, such as PayPal.</p>
<p>We must eventually find a halfway point between those with valid concerns about the anonymity crypto assets provide and those who see regulation as prohibitively restrictive on crypto. Both sides have a point, but crypto’s continued legitimacy and viability within the larger financial markets and industry is a net positive for all parties, making this negotiation nothing short of crucial.</p>
<h2>Not anti-regulation, just anti-unworkable regulations</h2>
<p>Ultimately, we need to regulate with efficacy, which necessitates legislation that is applicable specifically to digital assets and does not hinder the market without really solving any AML-related problems.</p>
<p>The already global nature of the traditional financial industry underscores the value of and need for FATF’s issuance of an international framework for regulatory oversight within crypto.</p>
<p>The criminal financial trade &#8212; money laundering, illegal weapons sales, human trafficking and so on &#8212; is also an international business. Thus, cracking down on it is, out of necessity, an international effort.</p>
<p>The decentralized nature of blockchain, which runs contrary to the central-server standard we know and use nearly everywhere, presents a formidable challenge here. Rules and regulations for traditional financial institutions are being implemented part and parcel onto crypto — a misstep and misunderstanding that ignores the innovation and novelty this economic ecosystem and its underlying technology entails.</p>
<p>Traditional forms of regulation from the fiat world do not reciprocally apply to every aspect of crypto nor to the fundamental nature of blockchain technology. However well intentioned they may be, because these imposed regulations are built on an old system, they must be adapted and modified.</p>
<p>The creation of fair restrictions on the technology’s use requires a fundamental understanding and cooperation within the limits and characteristics of those technologies. In traditional financial circles, the topic of blockchain is currently subject to more impassioned rhetoric than genuine understanding.</p>
<p>At the heart of the issue is the fundamental misunderstanding that blockchain transactions are anonymous or untraceable. Blockchain transactions are pseudo-anonymous and, in most circumstances, can offer more traceability and transparency than traditional banking. Illegal activity conducted on the blockchain will always be far more traceable than cash transactions, for example.</p>
<p>Technology with such immense potential should be made accessible, regulated and beneficial for everyone. Blockchain and digital assets are already revolutionizing the way we operate, and regulatory measures need to follow suit. The way forward cannot simply be delivering old-school directives, demanding obedience and doling out unfair punishments. There’s no reason a new way forward isn’t possible.</p>
<h2>The end of the outlaw era</h2>
<p>Activity can already be monitored through a collective database of users known to abide by international standards. This knowledge of approved users and vendors allows the industry to spot misconduct or malfeasance far sooner than usual, singling out and restricting illegitimate users.</p>
<p>By means of a well-thought-through tweaking of the suggested regulations, a verified network can collectively be built to ensure trust and properly leverage blockchain’s potential, while barring those bad actors intent on corrupting or manipulating the system. That would be a huge step forward in prosecuting international financial crimes and ensuring crypto’s legitimacy globally.</p>
<p>Crypto’s outlaw days are over, but it’s gained an unprecedented level of legitimacy that can only be preserved and bolstered by abiding with regulatory oversight.</p>
<p>That regulatory oversight can’t just be the old way of doing things copy-and-pasted onto blockchain transactions. Instead, it needs to be one that helps fight criminal activity, shores up investor confidence and throws a bone &#8212; not a wrench &#8212; to the very mechanics that make crypto a desirable financial investment.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uhagRfbZY1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/a16zs-new-2-2b-fund-wont-just-bet-on-the-crypto-future-it-will-defend-it/">a16z&#8217;s new $2.2B fund won&#8217;t just bet on the crypto future, it will defend it</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;a16z&#8217;s new $2.2B fund won&#8217;t just bet on the crypto future, it will defend it&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/a16zs-new-2-2b-fund-wont-just-bet-on-the-crypto-future-it-will-defend-it/embed/#?secret=uhagRfbZY1" data-secret="uhagRfbZY1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/regulating-crypto-is-essential-to-ensuring-its-global-legitimacy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189363</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pearson to pay $1M fine for misleading investors about 2018 data breach</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/pearson-to-pay-1m-fine-for-misleading-investors-about-2018-data-breach/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/pearson-to-pay-1m-fine-for-misleading-investors-about-2018-data-breach/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 16:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberattack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Bureau of Investigation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pearson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2190067</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pearson, a London-based publishing and education giant that provides software to schools and universities has agreed to pay $1 million to settle charges that it misled investors about a 2018 data breach resulting in the theft of millions of student records. The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission announced the settlement on Monday after the agency found [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/pearson/">Pearson</a>, a London-based publishing and education giant that provides software to schools and universities has agreed to pay $1 million to settle charges that it misled investors about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/31/education-software-maker-pearson-says-data-breach-affected-thousands-of-accounts-in-the-u-s/">a 2018 data breach resulting in the theft of millions of student records</a>.</p>
<p>The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission announced the <a href="https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2021-154">settlement</a> on Monday after the agency found that Pearson made “misleading statements and omissions” about its 2018 data breach, which saw millions of student usernames and scrambled passwords stolen, along with the administrator login credentials of 13,000 schools, district and university customer accounts.</p>
<p>The agency said that in Person&#8217;s semi-annual review filed in July 2019, the company referred to the incident as a “hypothetical risk,” even after the data breach had happened. Similarly, <a href="https://www.pearson.com/news-and-research/announcements/2019/07/pearson-customer-notification.html">in a statement that same month</a>, Pearson said the breach may include dates of birth and email addresses, when it knew that such records were stolen, according to the SEC.</p>
<p>Pearson also said that it had &#8220;strict protections&#8221; in place when it actually took the company six months to patch the vulnerability after it was notified.</p>
<p>“As the order finds, Pearson opted not to disclose this breach to investors until it was contacted by the media, and even then Pearson understated the nature and scope of the incident, and overstated the company’s data protections,” said Kristina Littman, chief of the SEC Enforcement Division’s Cyber Unit. “As public companies face the growing threat of cyber intrusions, they must provide accurate information to investors about material cyber incidents.”</p>
<p>While Pearson did not admit wrongdoing as part of the settlement, Pearson agreed to pay a $1 million penalty — a small fraction of the $489 million in pre-tax profits that the company raked in last year.</p>
<p>A Pearson spokesperson told TechCrunch: “We&#8217;re pleased to resolve this matter with the SEC. We also appreciate the work of the FBI and the Justice Department to identify and charge those responsible for a global cyberattack that affected Pearson and many other companies and industries, including at least one government agency.&#8221;</p>
<p>Pearson said the breach related to its AIMSweb1.0 web-based software for entering and tracking students’ academic performance, which it retired in July 2019. &#8220;Pearson continues to enhance its cybersecurity efforts to minimize the risk of cyberattacks in an ever-changing threat landscape,&#8221; the spokesperson added.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1jhk57wDGo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/to-guard-against-data-loss-and-misuse-the-cybersecurity-conversation-must-evolve/">To guard against data loss and misuse, the cybersecurity conversation must evolve</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;To guard against data loss and misuse, the cybersecurity conversation must evolve&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/to-guard-against-data-loss-and-misuse-the-cybersecurity-conversation-must-evolve/embed/#?secret=1jhk57wDGo" data-secret="1jhk57wDGo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AyzXkFMDTM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/31/education-software-maker-pearson-says-data-breach-affected-thousands-of-accounts-in-the-u-s/">Education software maker Pearson says data breach affected thousands of accounts in the US</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Education software maker Pearson says data breach affected thousands of accounts in the US&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/31/education-software-maker-pearson-says-data-breach-affected-thousands-of-accounts-in-the-u-s/embed/#?secret=AyzXkFMDTM" data-secret="AyzXkFMDTM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/pearson-to-pay-1m-fine-for-misleading-investors-about-2018-data-breach/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2190067</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roblox acquires Discord competitor Guilded</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/roblox-acquires-discord-competitor-guilded/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/roblox-acquires-discord-competitor-guilded/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 16:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[core]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freeware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guilded]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[league of legends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matrix Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metaverse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roblox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2190050</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roblox is using M&#38;A to bulk up its social infrastructure, announcing Monday morning that they had acquired the team at Guilded which has been building a chat platform for competitive gamers. The service competes with gaming chat giant Discord, with the team&#8217;s founders telling TechCrunch in the past that as Discord&#8217;s ambitions had grown beyond [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Roblox is using M&amp;A to bulk up its social infrastructure, announcing Monday morning that they had acquired the team at <a href="https://www.guilded.gg/">Guilded</a> which has been building a chat platform for competitive gamers.</p>
<p>The service competes with gaming chat giant Discord, with the team&#8217;s founders telling TechCrunch in the past that as Discord&#8217;s ambitions had grown beyond the gaming world, its core product was meeting fewer competitive gaming needs. Like Discord, users can have text and voice conversations on the Gulded platform, but Guilded also allowed users to organize communities around events and calendars, with plenty of specific functionality designed around ensuring that tournaments happened seamlessly.</p>
<p>The startup&#8217;s product supported hundreds of games, with specific functionality for a handful of titles including League of Legends, Fortnite, CS: GO and, yes, Roblox. Earlier this year, the company launched a bot API designed to help non-technical users build bots that could enrich their gaming communities.</p>
<p>Guilded had raised $10.2 million in venture capital funding to date according to <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/guilded/company_financials">Crunchbase</a>, including a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/01/guilded-raises-7-million-for-its-competitive-gaming-focused-chat-app/">$7 million Series A</a> led by Matrix Partners early last year. The company launched out of Y Combinator in mid-2017.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FsUtTmImvs"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/01/guilded-raises-7-million-for-its-competitive-gaming-focused-chat-app/">Guilded raises $7 million for its competitive gaming-focused chat app</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Guilded raises $7 million for its competitive gaming-focused chat app&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/01/guilded-raises-7-million-for-its-competitive-gaming-focused-chat-app/embed/#?secret=FsUtTmImvs" data-secret="FsUtTmImvs" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Terms of the Roblox deal weren&#8217;t disclosed. In an announcement <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210816005389/en/Roblox-Acquires-Guilded-a-Platform-to-Connect-Gaming-Communities">post</a>, Roblox detailed that the Guilded team will operate as an independent product group going forward. In a<a href="https://www.guilded.gg/blog/joining-roblox"> separate blog post</a>, Guilded CEO Eli Brown wrote that existing stakeholders will be able to continue using the product as they have previously.</p>
<p>&#8220;Everyone &#8211; including communities, partners, and bot developers &#8211; will be able to keep using Guilded the same way you are now,&#8221; Brown wrote. &#8220;Roblox believes in our team and in our mission, and we&#8217;re going to continue to operate as an independent product in order to achieve it.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Roblox has seen profound success and heightened investor attention in recent years as the pandemic has pushed more gamers online and brought more users into the fold, but that success has drawn the attention of competitors. In June, Facebook acquired a small Roblox competitor called Crayta, with CEO Mark Zuckerberg announcing just weeks ago that he planned to transform Facebook into a &#8220;metaverse&#8221; company, using a term many have come to associate closely with what Roblox has been building. Guilded represents an opportunity for Roblox to bring its user base deeper inside its own suite of products, creating a social infrastructure that keeps users bought in.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="T0mLYjhJFs"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/zuckerberg-is-turning-trillion-dollar-facebook-into-a-metaverse-company-he-tells-investors/">Zuckerberg is turning trillion-dollar Facebook into a &#8216;metaverse&#8217; company, he tells investors</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Zuckerberg is turning trillion-dollar Facebook into a &#8216;metaverse&#8217; company, he tells investors&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/zuckerberg-is-turning-trillion-dollar-facebook-into-a-metaverse-company-he-tells-investors/embed/#?secret=T0mLYjhJFs" data-secret="T0mLYjhJFs" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/roblox-acquires-discord-competitor-guilded/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2190050</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jeff Bezos’ Blue Origin goes toe-to-toe with NASA in federal court over award to SpaceX</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-goes-toe-to-toe-with-nasa-in-federal-court-over-award-to-spacex/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-goes-toe-to-toe-with-nasa-in-federal-court-over-award-to-spacex/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 16:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artemis program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff bezos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2190037</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Blue Origin, the space company helmed by billionaire Jeff Bezos, is taking NASA to court. The company filed a complaint with a federal claims court on Monday over the agency’s decision to award a lunar lander contract solely to rival company SpaceX. The complaint, which Blue Origin successfully petitioned to have sealed, says NASA&#8217;s evaluation [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Blue Origin, the space company helmed by billionaire Jeff Bezos, is taking NASA to court. The company filed a complaint with a federal claims court on Monday over the agency’s decision to award a lunar lander contract solely to rival company SpaceX.</p>
<p>The complaint, which Blue Origin successfully petitioned to have sealed, says NASA&#8217;s evaluation of proposals for the the Human Landing System was &#8220;unlawful and improper.&#8221;</p>
<p>“Blue Origin filed suit in the U.S. Court of Federal Claims in an attempt to remedy the flaws in the acquisition process found in NASA’s Human Landing System,&#8221; a company spokesperson told TechCrunch. &#8220;We firmly believe that the issues identified in this procurement and its outcomes must be addressed to restore fairness, create competition, and ensure a safe return to the moon for America.”</p>
<p>The Human Landing System, a key part of NASA’s forthcoming Artemis program, is the lander that will return humans to the moon’s surface for the first time since the days of Apollo. NASA aims to have the human lander touching down at the lunar south pole in 2024.</p>
<p>In April, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/spacex-wins-nasa-contract-to-develop-human-landing-system-for-returning-to-the-moon/">NASA awarded the HLS contract</a> to a single company — SpaceX, which submitted a $2.9 billion bid. That NASA selected only one company, rather than two, was a surprise (the agency likes to hedge its bets). Only a few weeks later, Blue Origin and defense contractor Dynetics, which also submitted a bid for the lander program, filed separate protests with the Government Accountability Office over the decision. GAO later upheld NASA’s decision, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/government-watchdog-rejects-blue-origins-protest-over-lunar-lander-contract/">maintaining that</a> “the [contract] announcement reserved the right to make multiple awards, a single award, or no award at all.”</p>
<p>(Read a blow-by-blow of GAO’s rationale by TechCrunch’s Devin Coldewey <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/feds-dismantle-blue-origin-and-dynetics-protests-of-nasas-spacex-lunar-lander-award/">here</a>).</p>
<p>When GAO released its decision, it seemed like that might have been case closed: SpaceX won, Blue Origin lost. This new lawsuit, filed to the U.S. Court of Federal Claims, is a clear signal that Jeff Bezos’ company has no intention of backing down.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>If a federal court filing represents Blue Origin’s buttoned-up protests, the company has also been waging a separate attack on social media, releasing a series of infographics aimed at discrediting SpaceX’s Starship and NASA’s decision to use it for moon missions.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2190043" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2190043" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2190043" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/blue-origin-hls-national-team-lunar-starship-infographic.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="1325" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/blue-origin-hls-national-team-lunar-starship-infographic.jpg 1275w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/blue-origin-hls-national-team-lunar-starship-infographic.jpg?resize=116,150 116w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/blue-origin-hls-national-team-lunar-starship-infographic.jpg?resize=232,300 232w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/blue-origin-hls-national-team-lunar-starship-infographic.jpg?resize=768,994 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/blue-origin-hls-national-team-lunar-starship-infographic.jpg?resize=525,680 525w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/blue-origin-hls-national-team-lunar-starship-infographic.jpg?resize=1187,1536 1187w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/blue-origin-hls-national-team-lunar-starship-infographic.jpg?resize=39,50 39w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2190043" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://www.blueorigin.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blue Origin <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>On one infographic, referring to Starship, the words “IMMENSELY COMPLEX &amp; HIGH RISK” blaze across the image in red; another described it as “a launch vehicle that has never flown to orbit and is still being designed.”</p>
<p>The case number is 1:21-cv-01695-RAH. TechCrunch has reached out to NASA for comment and will update the story if they respond.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TZmw5CzXBd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/15/extra-crunch-members-save-money-with-partner-perks-and-event-discounts/">Extra Crunch members save money with Partner Perks and event discounts</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Extra Crunch members save money with Partner Perks and event discounts&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/15/extra-crunch-members-save-money-with-partner-perks-and-event-discounts/embed/#?secret=TZmw5CzXBd" data-secret="TZmw5CzXBd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fkHg4axMkk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/feds-dismantle-blue-origin-and-dynetics-protests-of-nasas-spacex-lunar-lander-award/">Feds dismantle Blue Origin and Dynetics protests of NASA&#8217;s SpaceX lunar lander award</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Feds dismantle Blue Origin and Dynetics protests of NASA&#8217;s SpaceX lunar lander award&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/feds-dismantle-blue-origin-and-dynetics-protests-of-nasas-spacex-lunar-lander-award/embed/#?secret=fkHg4axMkk" data-secret="fkHg4axMkk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-goes-toe-to-toe-with-nasa-in-federal-court-over-award-to-spacex/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2190037</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tropic picks up $25M to streamline software procurement experiences</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/tropic-picks-up-25m-to-streamline-software-procurement-experiences/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/tropic-picks-up-25m-to-streamline-software-procurement-experiences/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 16:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canaan Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Campbell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founder Collective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hootan Rashidifard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[procurement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tropic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189760</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The pandemic was a catalyst for showing companies looking to cut costs, just how much they were spending on their software tools.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The pandemic was a catalyst for showing companies looking to cut costs just how much they were spending on their software tools. New York-based <a href="https://tropicapp.io/">Tropic</a>’s platform not only uncovers those savings, but also brings a click-and-approve approach to buying software. Today, the company announced a $25 million Series A round of funding.</p>
<p>Canaan Partners led the round, with participation from Founder Collective and Mo Koyfman’s new fund, Shine. It gives Tropic $27.1 million in total funding since the company emerged from stealth in 2020, CEO David Campbell told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Prior to founding the company with Justin Etkin, Campbell was in technology and sales roles, selling software contracts of every size, and realized how complex and rigid the contracts were getting as companies grew larger and the lack of price transparency increased. The complexity of some contracts can cause companies to overpay, even locking companies into payments they can’t afford, Campbell said.</p>
<p>On top of that, more buyers are younger now and their experience with purchasing software is pulling out their phone to download an app, while buying a customer relationship management tool will take six months to buy and cost thousands of dollars.</p>
<p>“Looking at the space, we are in a mirror maze of software, including companies using software to build products that they then sell back to the software companies,” Campbell said. “Companies are only buying software once a year, yet the process can be so complex.”</p>
<p>Tropic’s SaaS procurement model gathers the whole process under one platform. Unlike some competitors’ approaches, it takes on the heavy lifting so when companies have to buy or renew a contract, users can access Tropic’s one-click purchasing service to outsource the transaction. After the contracts are signed, its platform manages the technology and ensures financing is in order. This approach saves companies 23%, on average, on the software purchases, which Campbell said “moves the needle” for many companies where software is the No. 1 cost after salary.</p>
<p>In recent years, cloud software has become a fast-growing spend category across most businesses. Campbell said the average company can have more than 100 software contracts, while that jumps to over 500 for enterprise organizations. Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/203428/total-enterprise-software-revenue-forecast/">global spend on enterprise software</a> is forecasted to reach $599 billion by the end of 2021, a 13.2% increase over the previous year, according to Statista.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In the last 12 months, the company added over 60 customers, counting Qualtrics, Vimeo, Zapier and Intercom, surpassed $250 million in managed spend and processed transactions for over 1,200 vendors. The company is seeing 100% quarter over quarter growth, and in the last quarter, doubled its annual recurring revenue, Campbell said.</p>
<p>Tropic will use the funding for R &amp; D and to deepen integrations with existing procurement tools in the cloud software ecosystem. Over the past year, the company’s headcount has grown to 50 and Campbell has “aggressive hiring plans between now and the rest of the year” focused on the tech side with engineering and product management.</p>
<p>Hootan Rashidifard, principal from Canaan Partners, said his firm was tracking the software procurement sector and learned about Tropic through Founder Collective, which led the company’s seed round.</p>
<p>“We&#8217;re seeing software and financial services converge and Tropic sits squarely at the intersection of both in a category with massive tailwinds,” Rashidifard said via email. “Software is accelerating the share of expenses while also penetrating every part of an organization, and software purchasing is becoming more decentralized. Tropic’s platform is in a fragmented market with high payment volume, which is ripe for layering on all kinds of adjacent services.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5WNEWIvXVP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/how-to-overcome-the-challenges-of-switching-to-usage-based-pricing/">How to overcome the challenges of switching to usage-based pricing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to overcome the challenges of switching to usage-based pricing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/how-to-overcome-the-challenges-of-switching-to-usage-based-pricing/embed/#?secret=5WNEWIvXVP" data-secret="5WNEWIvXVP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/tropic-picks-up-25m-to-streamline-software-procurement-experiences/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189760</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Nuro EC-1</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec-1/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec-1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 15:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cvs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dave Ferguson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Domino's Pizza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dominos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Mobility Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ec-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emerging-Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch EC-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fedex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kroger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuro ec-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotaxi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seattle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187462</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Six years ago, I sat in the Google self-driving project's Firefly vehicle — which I described, at the time, as a "little gumdrop on wheels" — and let it ferry me around a course in Mountain View.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Six years ago, I sat in the Google self-driving project&#8217;s Firefly vehicle — which I described, at the time, as a &#8220;little gumdrop on wheels&#8221; — and let it ferry me around a closed course in Mountain View, California.</p>
<p>Little did I know that two of the people behind Firefly&#8217;s ability to see and perceive the world around it and react to that information would soon leave to start and steer an autonomous vehicle company of their very own.</p>
<p>Dave Ferguson and Jiajun Zhu aren&#8217;t the only Google self-driving project employees to launch an AV startup, but they might be the most underrated. Their company, <strong>Nuro</strong>, is valued at $5 billion and has high-profile partnerships with leaders in retail, logistics and food including FedEx, Domino&#8217;s and Walmart. And, they seem to have navigated the regulatory obstacle course with success — at least so far.</p>
<p>Yet, Nuro has remained largely in the shadows of other autonomous vehicle companies. Perhaps it&#8217;s because Nuro&#8217;s focus on autonomous delivery hasn&#8217;t captured the imagination of a general public that envisions themselves being whisked away in a robotaxi. Or it might be that they&#8217;re quieter.</p>
<p>Those quiet days might be coming to an end soon.</p>
<p>This series aims to look under Nuro&#8217;s hood, so to speak, from its earliest days as a startup to where it might be headed next — and with whom.</p>
<p>The lead writer of this EC-1 is <strong>Mark Harris</strong>, a freelance reporter known for investigative and long-form articles on science and technology. Our resident scoop machine, Harris is based in Seattle and also writes for Wired, The Guardian, The Economist, MIT Technology Review and Scientific American. He has broken stories about self-driving vehicles, giant airships, AI body scanners, faulty defibrillators and monkey-powered robots. In 2014, he was a Knight Science Journalism Fellow at MIT, and in 2015 he won the AAAS Kavli Science Journalism Gold Award.</p>
<p>The lead editor of this EC-1 was <strong>Kirsten Korosec</strong>, transportation editor at TechCrunch (that&#8217;s me), who has been writing about autonomous vehicles and the people behind them since 2014; OK maybe earlier. The assistant editor for this series was <strong>Ram Iyer</strong>, the copy editor was<strong> Richard Dal Porto</strong>, and illustrations were drawn by <strong>Nigel Sussman</strong>. The EC-1 series editor is <strong>Danny Crichton</strong>.</p>
<p><em>Nuro had no say in the content of this analysis and did not get advance access to it. Harris nor Korosec have any financial ties to Nuro.</em></p>
<p>The Nuro EC-1 comprises four articles numbering 10,600 words and a reading time of 43 minutes. Here are the topics we&#8217;ll be dialing into:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Part 1: Origin story</strong> &#8220;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-origin/">How Google&#8217;s self-driving car project accidentally spawned its robotic delivery rival</a>&#8221; (3,200 words/13 minutes) — explores the early days of Nuro and its founders and how they realized that the most useful robot they could ever build would be an autonomous delivery vehicle.</li>
<li><strong>Part 2: Regulations</strong> &#8220;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-regulations/">Why regulators love Nuro&#8217;s self-driving delivery vehicles</a>&#8221; (2,400 words/10 minutes) — analyzes how Nuro won over federal regulators and navigated a patchwork of policies to be able to test and deploy its autonomous delivery vehicles in several states.</li>
<li><strong>Part 3: Partnerships</strong> &#8220;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-partnerships/">How Nuro became the robotic face of Domino&#8217;s</a>&#8221; (2,500 words/10 minutes) — digs into Nuro&#8217;s relationship with Domino&#8217;s as well its trials with other companies including fast casual restaurant chain Chipotle, Kroger grocery stores and CVS pharmacies and how those relationships have affected the design and functions of the R2 bot.</li>
<li><strong>Part 4: Operations</strong> &#8220;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-operations/">Here&#8217;s what the inevitable friendly neighborhood robot invasion looks like</a>&#8221; (2,500 words/10 minutes) — examines where Nuro has set up shop, and more importantly, how it goes about picking locations and learning from its experiences.</li>
</ul>
<p>We&#8217;re always iterating on the EC-1 format. If you have questions, comments or ideas, please send an email to TechCrunch Managing Editor Danny Crichton at <a href="mailto:danny@techcrunch.com">danny@techcrunch.com</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WQYj3oTiH4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-origin/">How Google&#8217;s self-driving car project accidentally spawned its robotic delivery rival</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How Google&#8217;s self-driving car project accidentally spawned its robotic delivery rival&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-origin/embed/#?secret=WQYj3oTiH4" data-secret="WQYj3oTiH4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187462</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Google&#8217;s self-driving car project accidentally spawned its robotic delivery rival</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-origin/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-origin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 15:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dave Ferguson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Domino's Pizza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch EC-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fidelity Management & Research Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greylock capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuro ec-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Series A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[woven planet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2186014</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nuro doesn't have a typical Silicon Valley origin story. It didn't emerge after a long, slow slog from a suburban garage or through a flash of insight in a university laboratory.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Nuro doesn&#8217;t have a typical Silicon Valley origin story. It didn&#8217;t emerge after a long, slow slog from a suburban garage or through a flash of insight in a university laboratory. Nor was it founded at the behest of an eccentric billionaire with money to burn.</p>
<p>Nuro was born — and ramped up quickly — thanks to a cash windfall from what is now one of its biggest rivals.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Nuro was born — and ramped up quickly — thanks to a cash windfall from what is now one of its biggest rivals.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>In the spring of 2016, Dave Ferguson and Jiajun Zhu were teammates on Google&#8217;s self-driving car effort. Ferguson was directing the project&#8217;s computer vision, machine learning and behavior prediction teams, while Zhu (widely JZ) was in charge of the car&#8217;s perception technologies and cutting-edge simulators.</p>
<p>&#8220;We both were leading pretty large teams and were responsible for a pretty large portion of the Google car&#8217;s software system,&#8221; Zhu recalls.</p>
<p>As Google prepared to spin out its autonomous car tech into the company that would become Waymo, it first needed to settle a bonus program devised in the earliest days of its so-called Chauffeur project. Under the scheme, early team members could choose staggered payouts over a period of eight years — or leave Google and get a lump sum all at once.</p>
<p>Ferguson and Zhu would not confirm the amount they received, but court filings released as part of Waymo&#8217;s trade secrets case against Uber suggest they each received payouts in the neighborhood of $40 million by choosing to leave.</p>
<p>&#8220;What we were fortunate enough to receive as part of the self-driving car project enabled us to take riskier opportunities, to go and try to build something that had a significant chance of not working out at all,&#8221; Ferguson says.</p>
<p>Within weeks of their departure, the two had incorporated Nuro Inc, a company with the non-ironic mission to &#8220;better everyday life through robotics.&#8221; Its first product aimed to take a unique approach to self-driving cars: Road vehicles with all of the technical sophistication and software smarts of Google&#8217;s robotaxis, but none of the passengers.</p>
<p>In the five years since, Nuro&#8217;s home delivery robots have proven themselves smart, safe and nimble, outpacing Google&#8217;s vehicles to secure the first commercial deployment permit for autonomous vehicles in California, as well as groundbreaking concessions from the U.S. government.</p>
<p>While robotaxi companies struggle with technical hitches and regulatory red tape, Nuro has already made thousands of robotic pizza and grocery deliveries across the U.S., and Ferguson (as president) and Zhu (as CEO) are now heading a company that as of its last funding round in November 2020 valued it at $5 billion with more than 1,000 employees.</p>
<p>But how did they get there so fast, and where are they headed next?</p>
<h2>Turning money into robots</h2>
<p>&#8220;Neither JZ nor I think of ourselves as classic entrepreneurs or that starting a company is something we had to do in our lives,&#8221; Ferguson says. &#8220;It was much more the result of soul searching and trying to figure out what is the biggest possible impact that we could have.&#8221;</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-origin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2186014</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why regulators love Nuro&#8217;s self-driving delivery vehicles</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-regulations/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-regulations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 15:03:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alliance of Automobile Manufacturers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[auto safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dave Ferguson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[department of defense]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ec-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch EC-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Highway Traffic Safety Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Science Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuro ec-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2186354</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nuro's autonomous vehicles (AVs) don't have a human driver on board. There's no room in the narrow chassis for a driver's seat, no need for a steering wheel, accelerator or brake pedals.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Nuro&#8217;s delivery autonomous vehicles (AVs) don&#8217;t have a human driver on board. The company&#8217;s founders Dave Ferguson (president) and Jiajun Zhu&#8217;s (CEO) <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-origin/">vision of a driverless delivery vehicle</a> sought to do away with a lot of the stuff that is essential for a normal car to have, like doors and airbags and even a steering wheel. They built an AV that spared no room in the narrow chassis for a driver&#8217;s seat, and had no need for an accelerator, windshield or brake pedals.</p>
<p>So when the company <a href="https://www.regulations.gov/document/NHTSA-2019-0017-0001">petitioned the U.S. government</a> in 2018 for a minor exemption from rules requiring a rearview mirror, backup camera and a windshield, Nuro might have assumed the process wouldn&#8217;t be very arduous.</p>
<p>They were wrong.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			If Nuro is to become the generation-defining company its founders desire, it will be due as much to innovation in regulation as advances in the technology it develops.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://www.aamva.org/AAMVA-Comments-on-Nuro-AV-Exemption-Petition/">2019 letter</a> to the U.S. Department of Transportation, The American Association of Motor Vehicle Administrators (AAMVA) &#8220;[wondered] about the description of pedestrian &#8216;crumple zones,&#8217; and whether this may impact the vehicle&#8217;s crash-worthiness in the event of a vehicle-to-vehicle crash. Even in the absence of passengers, AAMVA has concerns about cargo ejection from the vehicle and how Nuro envisions protections from loose loads affecting the driving public.&#8221;</p>
<p>The National Society of Professional Engineers similarly complained that Nuro&#8217;s request lacked information about the detection of moving objects. &#8220;How would the R2X function if a small child darts onto the road from the passenger side of the vehicle as a school bus is approaching from the driver&#8217;s side?&#8221; it asked. It also recommended the petition be denied until Nuro could provide a more detailed cybersecurity plan against its bots being hacked or hijacked. (R2X is now referred to as R2)</p>
<p>The Alliance of Automobile Manufacturers (now the Alliance Automotive Innovation), which represents most U.S. carmakers, wrote that the National Highway Transportation Safety Agency (NHTSA) should not use Nuro&#8217;s kind of petition to &#8220;introduce new safety requirements for [AVs] that have not gone through the rigorous rule-making process.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;What you can see is that many comments came from entrenched interests,&#8221; said David Estrada, Nuro&#8217;s chief legal and policy officer. &#8220;And that&#8217;s understandable. There are multibillion dollar industries that can be disrupted if autonomous vehicles become successful.&#8221;</p>
<p>To be fair, critical comments also came from nonprofit organizations genuinely concerned about unleashing robots on city streets. The Center for Auto Safety, an independent consumer group, thought that Nuro did not provide enough information on its development and testing, nor any meaningful comparison with the safety of similar, human-driven vehicles. &#8220;Indeed, the planned reliance on &#8216;early on-road tests … with human-manned professional safety drivers&#8217; suggests that Nuro has limited confidence in R2X&#8217;s safe operation,&#8221; it wrote.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2189997" style="width: 1930px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/R2-specs-infographic.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2189997" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2189997 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/R2-specs-infographic.jpg" alt="Nuro-R2-specs-infographic" width="1920" height="1080" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/R2-specs-infographic.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/R2-specs-infographic.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/R2-specs-infographic.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/R2-specs-infographic.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/R2-specs-infographic.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/R2-specs-infographic.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/R2-specs-infographic.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2189997" class="wp-caption-text">Nuro&#8217;s R2 delivery autonomous vehicle. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nuro</p></div></p>
<p>Despite such concerns, the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) <a href="https://www.nhtsa.gov/sites/nhtsa.gov/files/documents/nuro_grant_notice_final-unofficial.pdf">granted</a> Nuro the exemptions it sought in February last year. Up to 5,000 R2 vehicles could be produced for a limited period of two years and subject to Nuro reporting any incidents, without a windshield, rearview mirror or backup camera. Although only a small concession, it was the first — and so far, only — time the U.S. government had relaxed vehicle safety requirements for an AV.</p>
<p>Now Estrada and Nuro hope to use that momentum to chip away at a mountain of regulations that never envisaged vehicles controlled by on-board robots or distant humans, extending from the foothills of local and state government to the peaks of federal and international safety rules.</p>
<p>If Nuro is to become the generation-defining company its founders desire, it will be due as much to innovation in regulation as advances in the technology it develops.</p>
<h2>Regulate for success</h2>
<p>&#8220;I don&#8217;t think any of the credible, big AV players want this to be a free-for-all,&#8221; said Dave Ferguson, Nuro&#8217;s co-founder and president. &#8220;We need the confidence of a clear regulatory framework to invest the hundreds of millions or billions of dollars necessary to manufacture vehicles at scale. Otherwise, it&#8217;s really going to limit our ability to deploy.&#8221;</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-regulations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2186354</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Nuro became the robotic face of Domino&#8217;s</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-partnerships/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-partnerships/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 15:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[EC-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Domino's Pizza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ec-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch EC-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greylock capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Lilly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kroger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuro ec-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Refraction AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2186587</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pandemic pizza was definitely a thing. U.S. consumers forked out a record-breaking $14bn to have pizza delivered to their doors in 2020, and nearly half of that was spent with one brand: Domino's.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Pandemic pizza was definitely a thing.</p>
<p>U.S. consumers forked out a record-breaking $14 billion to have pizza delivered to their doors in 2020, and nearly half of that total was spent with just one brand: Domino&#8217;s.</p>
<p>&#8220;Domino&#8217;s is the home of pizza delivery,&#8221; said Dennis Maloney, Domino&#8217;s chief innovation officer. &#8220;Delivery is at the core of who we are, so it&#8217;s very important for us to lead when it comes to the consumer experience of delivery.&#8221;</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			U.S. consumers forked out a record-breaking $14 billion to have pizza delivered to their doors in 2020, and nearly half of that total was spent with just one brand: Domino&#8217;s.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>In its <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FYM1flimFa4">latest TV ad</a>, an order of Domino&#8217;s pizza speeds to its destination inside a Nuro R2X delivery autonomous vehicle (AV). The R2X (now known as R2) deftly avoids potholes, falling trees and traffic jams caused by The Noid — a character created by Domino&#8217;s in the 1980s to symbolize the difficulties of delivering a pizza in 30 minutes or less.</p>
<p>The reality is much more sedate. Domino&#8217;s currently has just one R2X that operates from a single Domino&#8217;s store on the generally calm streets of Woodland Heights in Houston, Texas. And since the AV&#8217;s introduction in April, The Noid has yet to put in an appearance.</p>
<p>&#8220;The R2X adds a bunch of efficiencies while not taking away from any existing capabilities,&#8221; Maloney said. &#8220;As we start getting the bot into regular operation, we&#8217;ll see if it plays out the way we expect it to. So far, all the indications are good.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2186589" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-x-Domino_s-Image-2.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2186589" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2186589 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-x-Domino_s-Image-2.jpg" alt="Nuro-Domino" width="2000" height="1334" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-x-Domino_s-Image-2.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-x-Domino_s-Image-2.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-x-Domino_s-Image-2.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-x-Domino_s-Image-2.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-x-Domino_s-Image-2.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-x-Domino_s-Image-2.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-x-Domino_s-Image-2.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2186589" class="wp-caption-text">Nuro and Domnio&#8217;s launched the autonomous pizza delivery service in Houston in April this year. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nuro</p></div></p>
<p>Partnerships are key for Nuro. The company&#8217;s business model is to sign contracts with established brands that either have their own branded vehicles or use traditional delivery companies like UPS or the U.S. Postal Service.</p>
<p>Nuro is carrying out trials and pilot deliveries with a number of companies, including fast casual restaurant chain Chipotle, Kroger grocery stores, CVS pharmacies, bricks-and-mortar retail behemoth Walmart, and, most recently, global parcel courier FedEx. While it is a dizzyingly impressive list for a company less than five years old, their interest was driven as much by global trends as by Nuro&#8217;s technology, admits Cosimo Leipold, head of partnerships at Nuro.</p>
<p>&#8220;Everybody today wants what they want and they want it faster than ever, but frankly they&#8217;re not willing to pay for it,&#8221; Leipold said. &#8220;We&#8217;ve reached a point where almost every company is going to have to offer delivery services, and now it&#8217;s just the question of how they&#8217;ll do it in the best possible way and with the most possible control.&#8221;</p>
<p>Nuro&#8217;s delivery AVs — aka bots — offer the tantalizing promise of safe, reliable and efficient delivery without sacrificing revenue and customer data to third-party platforms like Grubhub, DoorDash or Instacart. Alongside Nuro&#8217;s stated aim of driving the <a href="https://medium.com/nuro/serving-americas-food-deserts-a7442e922053">cost of delivery</a> down to zero, it is little surprise that Nuro now finds itself in the enviable position of being able to pick and choose the partners it wants — and the less enviable position of having to choose which partner to prioritize.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the story of how one of Nuro&#8217;s biggest partnerships came to be, and the lessons and companies that will drive its future growth.</p>
<h2>Deliveries with extra cheese</h2>
<p>Domino&#8217;s has a long history of innovating in delivery, usually accompanied by a strong marketing campaign. In the 1980s, the company bought 10 customized Tritan Aerocar 2s, a <a href="https://www.thedrive.com/news/25651/a-slice-of-history-buy-this-rare-tritan-a2-dominos-delivery-car">Jetsons-styled three-wheeler</a>, for use as delivery vehicles. In 2015, the company unveiled the <a href="https://www.hagerty.com/media/car-profiles/why-dominos-dxp-delivery-cars-were-anything-but-half-baked/">DXP</a>, a Chevrolet Spark modified with a single seat and a built-in warming oven, designed specifically for transporting pizza.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-partnerships/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2186587</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here&#8217;s what the inevitable friendly neighborhood robot invasion looks like</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-operations/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-operations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 15:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dave Ferguson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Domino's Pizza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ec-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch EC-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greylock capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Houston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Lilly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuro ec-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Refraction AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The first sign that your town is about to welcome a horde of Nuro robots will be the appearance of a fleet of human-driven Toyota Priuses modified with cameras, lidars and radars.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In early 2021, a Nuro autonomous delivery vehicle pulled to a halt at a four-way stop in its hometown of Mountain View, California to let a user cross. This seemingly humdrum moment quickly looked like a decidedly science fiction storyline — the user was a small sidewalk robot from another startup on its own mission.</p>
<p>&#8220;Obviously, we yielded to it, but it was, wow, we have entered a different world,&#8221; said Amy Jones Satrom, head of Operations at Nuro.</p>
<p>Mountain View is home to competitor Waymo and other autonomous vehicle testing activity. But for those who want to take part in that science fiction scene, Houston provides the full experience.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Nuro&#8217;s operations team has to delicately balance speed, safety, convenience and congestion, even as the company embarks on a growth spurt that will see robots spreading to other cities, states and partners in the months ahead.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Waymo is testing self-driving trucks in Houston, and a fully driverless shuttle service is due to start public service there early next year. Nuro&#8217;s Texas effort started in April, when an R2 robot began its commercial pizza delivery service in partnership with Domino&#8217;s. Some customers ordering pizzas from the Domino&#8217;s Woodland Heights store will see the option to have their pies delivered by robot.</p>
<p>Customers can trace the progress of the self-driving vehicle on the Domino&#8217;s app and, when it pulls up outside their home, tap in a unique PIN on its touchscreen to access their order. Nuro is also operating in Houston with Kroger supermarkets and FedEx.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of the things we laugh about is how customers constantly talk to the bot,&#8221; Dennis Maloney, Domino&#8217;s chief innovation pfficer said. &#8220;It&#8217;s almost like they think it&#8217;s &#8216;Knight Rider.&#8217; It&#8217;s very common for customers to thank it or say goodbye, which is great because that indicates we&#8217;re creating an engaging experience that they&#8217;re not frustrated by.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2190001" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-team-on-test-track-during-early-validation-in-AZ-before-first-ever-public-road-deployment-in-AZ.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2190001" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2190001 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-team-on-test-track-during-early-validation-in-AZ-before-first-ever-public-road-deployment-in-AZ.jpg" alt="Nuro-validation test" width="2000" height="1500" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-team-on-test-track-during-early-validation-in-AZ-before-first-ever-public-road-deployment-in-AZ.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-team-on-test-track-during-early-validation-in-AZ-before-first-ever-public-road-deployment-in-AZ.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-team-on-test-track-during-early-validation-in-AZ-before-first-ever-public-road-deployment-in-AZ.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-team-on-test-track-during-early-validation-in-AZ-before-first-ever-public-road-deployment-in-AZ.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-team-on-test-track-during-early-validation-in-AZ-before-first-ever-public-road-deployment-in-AZ.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-team-on-test-track-during-early-validation-in-AZ-before-first-ever-public-road-deployment-in-AZ.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-team-on-test-track-during-early-validation-in-AZ-before-first-ever-public-road-deployment-in-AZ.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2190001" class="wp-caption-text">Nuro team on test track during early validation in AZ, before first-ever public road deployment in Arizona. <strong>Image Credits</strong>: Nuro</p></div></p>
<p>Creating an experience, where people want to chat with their new robot neighbors instead of chasing them down the street with pitchforks, falls to Jones Satrom&#8217;s operations team. It has to delicately balance speed, safety, convenience and congestion, even as Nuro embarks on a growth spurt that will see robots spreading to other cities, states and partners in the months ahead.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s how it manages that, and what the future holds for Nuro&#8217;s ever-so-gentle robot invasion.</p>
<h2>Mapping the territory</h2>
<p>Few people are as well suited to overseeing Nuro&#8217;s high-stakes robot rollout as Jones Satrom, who started her career as a nuclear engineer on an aircraft carrier and previously managed the integration of Kiva Systems&#8217; robots into Amazon&#8217;s warehouses.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-operations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187127</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The hyperactive late-stage market should keep the startup investing game afoot</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/the-hyperactive-late-stage-market-should-keep-the-startup-investing-game-afoot/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/the-hyperactive-late-stage-market-should-keep-the-startup-investing-game-afoot/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 14:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unicorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[valuation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189941</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Understanding why investors are so willing to buy small stakes in dozens of private companies worth billions of dollars is key to grokking the crush of investment we see among younger tech startups.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As last week came to a close, funding news involving three major U.S. technology startups lit up on Twitter.</p>
<p>Carta <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/13/carta-says-it-just-used-its-own-product-to-establish-a-new-and-far-higher-valuation-for-itself/">closed a $500 million Series G</a> at a $7.4 billion price tag. Chime put together <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/chime-financial-raises-750-million-in-latest-funding-round-11628872069">a $750 million round</a> at a $25 billion valuation. And Discord <a href="https://www.newcomer.co/p/sources-discord-raising-at-roughly">was reported</a> to be hunting up new cash that would value it at around $15 billion.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>Each funding round has something special about it that we need to discuss. Why? Because while it&#8217;s well known that the unicorn market is crowded &#8212; reaching a $1 billion valuation in today&#8217;s capital-flush markets is no longer particularly rare for startups &#8212; the number of startups worth a multiple of that valuation threshold is growing rapidly. And understanding why investors are so willing to buy minute stakes in dozens of private companies worth billions of dollars is key to grokking the crush of investment we see among younger technology startups.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995211 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-grn.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>To make the point, CB Insights&#8217; <a href="https://www.cbinsights.com/research-unicorn-companies">unicorn leaderboard</a> lists 55 companies with valuations of $7.5 billion or more. That&#8217;s nearly five dozen companies worth more than Carta after its most recent round. According to the list, 38 of today&#8217;s unicorns are worth $10 billion or more.</p>
<p>The 55 startups valued at $7.5 billion and more are worth more than $1 trillion in aggregate, while the 38 decacorns are worth more than $900 billion when counted as a group.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve become too accustomed to simply reading the latest nine-figure round invested at an 11-figure price and shrugging. So, this morning, let&#8217;s talk about Carta and Chime and Discord and why each of them may have managed their latest, or anticipated, valuation gain.</p>
<p>When we talk about unicorns, we&#8217;re simply discussing a generally growth-oriented cohort of technology upstarts. But once a startup reaches closer to the $10 billion valuation threshold, we&#8217;re really talking about ducks increasingly too big for their pond. They are the next set of IPOs both domestically and abroad.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/the-hyperactive-late-stage-market-should-keep-the-startup-investing-game-afoot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189941</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cisco beefing up app monitoring portfolio with acquisition of Epsagon for $500M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/cisco-beefing-up-app-monitoring-portfolio-with-acquisition-of-epsagon-for-500m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/cisco-beefing-up-app-monitoring-portfolio-with-acquisition-of-epsagon-for-500m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 14:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[applications performance monitoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[containers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Epsagon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israeli startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189962</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cisco announced on Friday that it&#8217;s acquiring Israeli applications-monitoring startup Epsagon at a price pegged at $500 million. The purchase gives Cisco a more modern microservices-focused component for its growing applications-monitoring portfolio. The Israeli business publication Globes reported it had gotten confirmation from Cisco that the deal was for $500 million, but Cisco would not confirm [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://cisco.com">Cisco</a> announced <a href="https://blogs.cisco.com/news/12082021">on Friday</a> that it&#8217;s acquiring Israeli applications-monitoring startup Epsagon at a price pegged at $500 million. The purchase gives Cisco a more modern microservices-focused component for its growing applications-monitoring portfolio.</p>
<p>The Israeli business publication <a class="c-link" href="https://en.globes.co.il/en/article-cisco-confirms-acquisition-of-israeli-startup-epsagon-1001381718" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Globes reported</a> it had gotten confirmation from Cisco that the deal was for $500 million, but Cisco would not confirm that price with TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The acquisition comes on top of a couple of other high-profile app-monitoring deals, including AppDynamics, which the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/01/24/cisco-snaps-up-appdynamics-for-3-7b-right-before-its-ipo/">bought in 2018</a> for $3.7 billion, and ThousandEyes, which it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/29/cisco-to-acquire-internet-monitoring-solution-thousandeyes/">nabbed last year for $1 billion</a>.</p>
<p>With Epsagon, the company is getting a way to monitor more modern applications built with containers and Kubernetes. Epsagon&#8217;s value proposition is a solution built from the ground up to monitor these kinds of workloads, giving users tracing and metrics, something that&#8217;s not always easy to do given the ephemeral nature of containers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rPt0eyEesK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/29/cisco-to-acquire-internet-monitoring-solution-thousandeyes/">Cisco to acquire internet monitoring solution ThousandEyes</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cisco to acquire internet monitoring solution ThousandEyes&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/29/cisco-to-acquire-internet-monitoring-solution-thousandeyes/embed/#?secret=rPt0eyEesK" data-secret="rPt0eyEesK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As Cisco&#8217;s Liz Centoni wrote <a href="https://blogs.cisco.com/news/12082021">in a blog post</a> announcing the deal, Epsagon adds to the company&#8217;s concept of a full-stack offering in their applications-monitoring portfolio. Instead of having a bunch of different applications monitoring tools for different tasks, the company envisions one that works together.</p>
<p>&#8220;Cisco’s approach to full-stack observability gives our customers the ability to move beyond just monitoring to a paradigm that delivers shared context across teams and enables our customers to deliver exceptional digital experiences, optimize for cost, security and performance and maximize digital business revenue,&#8221; Centoni wrote.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That experience point is particularly important because when an application isn&#8217;t working, it isn&#8217;t happening in a vacuum. It has a cascading impact across the company, possibly affecting the core business itself and certainly causing customer distress, which could put pressure on customer service to field complaints, and the site reliability team to fix it. In the worst case, it could result in customer loss and an injured reputation.</p>
<p>If the application-monitoring system can act as an early warning system, it could help prevent the site or application from going down in the first place, and when it does go down, help track the root cause to get it up and running more quickly.</p>
<p>The challenge here for Cisco is incorporating Epsagon into the existing components of the application-monitoring portfolio and delivering that unified monitoring experience without making it feel like a Frankenstein&#8217;s monster of a solution globbed together from the various pieces.</p>
<p>Epsagon launched in 2018 and has raised $30 million. According to a report in <a href="https://www.calcalistech.com/ctech/articles/0,7340,L-3915194,00.html">the Israeli publication, Calcalist</a>, the company was on the verge of a big Series B round with a valuation in the range of $200 million when it accepted this offer. It certainly seems to have given its early investors a good return. The deal is expected to close later this year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="obn4Q9SMu4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/vcs-are-betting-big-on-kubernetes-here-are-5-reasons-why/">VCs are betting big on Kubernetes: Here are 5 reasons why</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;VCs are betting big on Kubernetes: Here are 5 reasons why&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/vcs-are-betting-big-on-kubernetes-here-are-5-reasons-why/embed/#?secret=obn4Q9SMu4" data-secret="obn4Q9SMu4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/cisco-beefing-up-app-monitoring-portfolio-with-acquisition-of-epsagon-for-500m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189962</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How one founder identified a gap in education working as a teacher and built a startup to fix it</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/how-one-founder-identified-a-gap-in-education-working-as-a-teacher-and-built-a-startup-to-fix-it/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/how-one-founder-identified-a-gap-in-education-working-as-a-teacher-and-built-a-startup-to-fix-it/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 14:20:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Found]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amanda DoAmaral]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiveable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote learning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amanda DoAmaral was an educator herself before she decided to found a tech company aimed at improving the education system. That&#8217;s a surprisingly rare credential for a startup founder in this area to possess — despite the obvious benefits of real, first-hand experience. Her company, Fiveable, focuses on modernizing (including a remote-first approach) a key [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Amanda DoAmaral was an educator herself before she decided to found a tech company aimed at improving the education system. That&#8217;s a surprisingly rare credential for a startup founder in this area to possess — despite the obvious benefits of real, first-hand experience. Her company, <a href="https://fiveable.me/">Fiveable</a>, focuses on modernizing (including a remote-first approach) a key and often overlooked part of education for students: building an active community of peers to share knowledge with. Hear how she took her dissatisfaction with an inadequate system and turned that into the motivation to build a venture-scale business outside of it on this week&#8217;s episode of <a href="https://pod.link/found">Found</a>.</p>
<p>We talked to Amanda about her path to entrepreneurship, which is not your typical founder story, despite her experience living and teaching in the Bay Area. Amanda shares how her considerable experience in education, both in terms of her own education, as well as her job as a teacher, led her to the frustrating realization that while tech had a lot to offer kids in school, the system just wasn&#8217;t set up to support that or make it happen. Building a company that focused on a particularly underserved aspect of remote learning ended up being the best path forward — and it just so happened that the market Fiveable entered would accelerate dramatically shortly after the company&#8217;s founding due to the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pUELRnl9X5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/14/edtechs-next-mission-go-everywhere/">Edtech’s next mission: Go everywhere</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Edtech’s next mission: Go everywhere&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/14/edtechs-next-mission-go-everywhere/embed/#?secret=pUELRnl9X5" data-secret="pUELRnl9X5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>We loved our time chatting with Amanda, and we hope you love yours listening to the episode. And of course, we’d love if you can subscribe to <a href="http://apple.co/found">Found in Apple Podcasts</a>, on <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/0Dqmcq2aDrZkS9v1fITOKV?si=Hfp6dAwAQKyenJnprGxnqg">Spotify</a>, on <a href="https://podcasts.google.com/feed/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5zaW1wbGVjYXN0LmNvbS9lMmI0QU5vYg?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwiYisj3nZfwAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQCQ">Google Podcasts</a> or in <a href="https://pod.link/found">your podcast app of choice</a>. Please leave us a review and let us know what you think, or send us direct feedback either on <a href="https://twitter.com/found">Twitter </a>or via email at <a href="mailto:found@techcrunch.com">found@techcrunch.com</a>, or leave us a voicemail at (510) 936-1618. And please join us again next week for our next featured founder.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/7265fdb6-b00f-47ae-82df-80447095cf5b?dark=false" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/how-one-founder-identified-a-gap-in-education-working-as-a-teacher-and-built-a-startup-to-fix-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189980</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook, telecom operators, add four new branches to the 2Africa subsea cable network</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/facebook-adds-four-new-branches-to-its-2africa-subsea-cable-network/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/facebook-adds-four-new-branches-to-its-2africa-subsea-cable-network/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 14:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China Mobile International]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subsea cable]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189954</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook today announced that it would extend to four more branches the “most comprehensive” subsea cable to serve the African continent and Middle East region. Facebook will do this in collaboration with the 2Africa consortium that includes China Mobile International, MTN GlobalConnect, Orange, STC, Telecom Egypt, Vodafone and WIOCC. The new branches are Seychelles, the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Facebook today announced that it would extend to four more branches the “most comprehensive” subsea cable to serve the African continent and Middle East region. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Facebook will do this in collaboration with the 2Africa consortium that includes China Mobile International, MTN GlobalConnect, Orange, STC, Telecom Egypt, Vodafone and WIOCC.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The new branches are Seychelles, the Comoros Islands, Angola and the south-eastern part of Nigeria. They join the recently announced extension to the Canary Islands.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last year, Facebook <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/14/2africa-africa-middle-east-facebook-subsea-cable/">announced the 2Africa project</a> would lay 37,000 km (22,990 miles) of cables. These cables interconnect Europe, via Egypt, and the Middle East, via Saudi Arabia, and 21 landings in 16 African countries.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the time, the involved parties said the 2Africa project would be completed either by 2023 or early 2024. And once live, 2Africa should be able to serve more than the total combined capacity of all subsea cables serving Africa at the moment. </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2189985" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2189985" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2189985" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/2Africa-Web_Color-Print-2021.png?w=680" alt="2Africa" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/2Africa-Web_Color-Print-2021.png 1999w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/2Africa-Web_Color-Print-2021.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/2Africa-Web_Color-Print-2021.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/2Africa-Web_Color-Print-2021.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/2Africa-Web_Color-Print-2021.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/2Africa-Web_Color-Print-2021.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/2Africa-Web_Color-Print-2021.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2189985" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> 2Africa</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the company&#8217;s new statement released by the consortium, the plan is still to go live in late 2023. The consortium says 2Africa has made some progress, as a big part of the subsea route survey activity is complete. The Egypt and Mediterranean Seas connections are almost complete, as well, the statement read. In addition, the marine surveys for the new sections are scheduled to be completed by the end of this year.  </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The consortium selected Nokia’s Alcatel Submarine Networks (ASN) to build the new branches, bringing 2Africa landings to 35 in 26 countries. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;The significant investment by Facebook in 2Africa builds on several other investments we have made in the continent, including infrastructure investments in South Africa, Uganda, Nigeria and DRC. The COVID-19 pandemic has highlighted the importance of connectivity as billions of people around the world rely on the internet to work, attend school and stay connected to the people they care about,&#8221; a Facebook spokesperson said regarding the company&#8217;s continued investment in Africa.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;2Africa will not only be an important element for advancing connectivity infrastructure across the African continent, but it will also be a major investment that comes at a critical time for economic recovery. With more and more people relying on the internet, subsea cables are a vital ingredient to ensure they always are connected to what matters. While Facebook invests in submarine cables to provide better experiences for people using our products, our investments drive a more cost-effective internet for all.&#8221; </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Q0BCduP4gy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/14/2africa-africa-middle-east-facebook-subsea-cable/">Facebook, telcos to build huge subsea cable for Africa and Middle East</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook, telcos to build huge subsea cable for Africa and Middle East&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/14/2africa-africa-middle-east-facebook-subsea-cable/embed/#?secret=Q0BCduP4gy" data-secret="Q0BCduP4gy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/facebook-adds-four-new-branches-to-its-2africa-subsea-cable-network/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189954</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Equity Monday: Hacks, IPOs and the next generation of American tech giants</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/equity-monday-hacks-ipos-and-the-next-generation-of-american-tech-giants/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/equity-monday-hacks-ipos-and-the-next-generation-of-american-tech-giants/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 14:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ixigo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[T-Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zomato]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. This is Equity Monday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/bbe849ac-155a-44fe-8880-dba2d91213fd?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>This is Equity Monday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You can follow the show on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/equitypod">here</a>. I <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">also tweet</a>.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a surreal day to talk about technology, but here we are. If you can pull your eyes away from the greater geopolitical tragedy that is our world today, here&#8217;s what we talked about:</p>
<ul>
<li>T-Mobile may have suffered a material breach. If this bears out, it could be a leading tech story for the week. Vice has confirmed that at least some of the data in the leak <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/akg8wg/tmobile-investigating-customer-data-breach-100-million">appears genuine</a>.</li>
<li>Indian travel service ixigo <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/tech/startups/travel-platform-ixigo-files-for-rs-1600-crore-ipo/articleshow/85285737.cms">is going public</a>. The company&#8217;s IPO follows Zomato&#8217;s own domestic debut.</li>
<li>And speaking of IPOs, the Tencent Music offering in Hong Kong <a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Business/Media-Entertainment/Tencent-Music-s-plan-stalls-for-5bn-Hong-Kong-listing-in-2021">could be on hold until next year</a>.</li>
<li>And a trio of American tech companies raised a raft of capital as last week concluded. Carta <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/13/carta-says-it-just-used-its-own-product-to-establish-a-new-and-far-higher-valuation-for-itself/">put together $500 million</a> in a huge deal, as <a href="https://www.msn.com/en-us/money/companies/chime-raises-24750-million-earns-big-jump-in-valuation-as-another-fintech-moves-closer-to-ipo/ar-AANi7Du">Chime raised $750 million</a>. And as the week closed, Discord <a href="https://www.newcomer.co/p/sources-discord-raising-at-roughly">was reported</a> to be hunting up a new round at a $15 billion price tag.</li>
</ul>
<p>And stocks are set to open lower this morning. That&#8217;s the morning report. Equity is back on Wednesday.</p>
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 a.m. PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts!</i></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ylQHJtO0VQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/13/carta-says-it-just-used-its-own-product-to-establish-a-new-and-far-higher-valuation-for-itself/">Carta says it just used its own product to establish a new &#8212; and far higher &#8212; valuation for itself</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Carta says it just used its own product to establish a new &#8212; and far higher &#8212; valuation for itself&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/13/carta-says-it-just-used-its-own-product-to-establish-a-new-and-far-higher-valuation-for-itself/embed/#?secret=ylQHJtO0VQ" data-secret="ylQHJtO0VQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/equity-monday-hacks-ipos-and-the-next-generation-of-american-tech-giants/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189935</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>US safety regulator opens investigation into Tesla Autopilot following crashes with parked emergency vehicles</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/u-s-safety-regulator-opens-investigation-into-tesla-autopilot-following-crashes-with-parked-emergency-vehicles/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/u-s-safety-regulator-opens-investigation-into-tesla-autopilot-following-crashes-with-parked-emergency-vehicles/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 13:31:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ADAS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced driver assistance system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Highway Traffic and Safety Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nhtsa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla Autopilot]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189945</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[U.S. auto regulators have opened a preliminary investigation into Tesla’s Autopilot advanced driver assistance system, citing 11 incidents in which vehicles crashed into parked first responder vehicles while the system was engaged. The Tesla vehicles involved in the collisions were confirmed to have either have had engaged Autopilot or a feature called Traffic Aware Cruise [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">U.S. auto regulators have opened a preliminary investigation into Tesla’s Autopilot advanced driver assistance system, citing 11 incidents in which vehicles crashed into parked first responder vehicles while the system was engaged.</p>
<p>The Tesla vehicles involved in the collisions were confirmed to have either have had engaged Autopilot or a feature called Traffic Aware Cruise Control, according to <a href="https://static.nhtsa.gov/odi/inv/2021/INOA-PE21020-1893.PDF">investigation documents</a> posted on the National Highway Traffic and Safety Administration’s website. Most of the incidents took place after dark and occurred despite “scene control measures,” such as emergency vehicle lights, road cones and an illuminated arrow board signaling drivers to change lanes.</p>
<p>“The investigation will assess the technologies and methods used to monitor, assist, and enforce the driver&#8217;s engagement with the dynamic driving task during Autopilot operation,” the document says.</p>
<p>The investigation covers around 765,000 Tesla vehicles that span all currently available models: Tesla Model Y, Model X, Model S and Model 3. The 11 incidents or fires resulted in 17 injuries and one fatality. They occurred between January 2018 and July 2021.</p>
<p>This is not the first time Tesla’s Autopilot has fallen under the scrutiny of NHTSA, the country’s top vehicle safety regulator. In 2017, the agency investigated an incident that resulted in a fatal crash in 2016, though the EV maker was found to be at no-fault in the accident. NHSTA has investigated a further 25 crashes involving Tesla’s ADAS since, the Associated Press reported when it broke the story Monday.</p>
<p>In June, NHTSA issued an order requiring automakers to report crashes involving vehicles equipped with ADAS or Levels 3-5 of automated driving systems.</p>
<p>“NHTSA reminds the public that no commercially available motor vehicles today are capable of driving themselves,” an agency spokesperson told TechCrunch on Monday.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>TechCrunch has reached out to Tesla, which has dissolved its media relations division, for comment, and will update the story if the company responds.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ysI1bmz06C"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/23/as-autonomy-stalls-lidar-companies-learn-to-adapt/">As autonomy stalls, lidar companies learn to adapt</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As autonomy stalls, lidar companies learn to adapt&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/23/as-autonomy-stalls-lidar-companies-learn-to-adapt/embed/#?secret=ysI1bmz06C" data-secret="ysI1bmz06C" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="16p6V49JNz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/15/teslas-decision-to-scrap-its-pr-department-could-create-a-pr-nightmare/">Tesla&#8217;s decision to scrap its PR department could create a PR nightmare</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tesla&#8217;s decision to scrap its PR department could create a PR nightmare&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/15/teslas-decision-to-scrap-its-pr-department-could-create-a-pr-nightmare/embed/#?secret=16p6V49JNz" data-secret="16p6V49JNz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/u-s-safety-regulator-opens-investigation-into-tesla-autopilot-following-crashes-with-parked-emergency-vehicles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189945</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Early-stage benchmarks for young cybersecurity companies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/early-stage-benchmarks-for-young-cybersecurity-companies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/early-stage-benchmarks-for-young-cybersecurity-companies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 13:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer success]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybersecurity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Cybersecurity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[executive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YL Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Entrepreneurs require guideposts when building large companies, and customer and revenue expectations can be established by looking at what successful cybersecurity companies have accomplished.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Yoav Leitersdorf</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/ylventures">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a>Yoav Leitersdorf</a> is the Silicon Valley-based managing partner at YL Ventures, where he accelerates cybersecurity startups in the U.S. market.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/20/israels-cybersecurity-startup-scene-spawns-new-entrants-in-2019/">Israel&#8217;s cybersecurity startup scene spawned new entrants in 2019</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/06/a-look-back-at-the-israeli-cyber-security-industry-in/">A look back at the Israeli cybersecurity industry in 2018</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Michael Cortez</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/ylventures">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Michael Cortez, vice president at YL Ventures, focuses on business development initiatives to grow the market leadership of the firm and its portfolio companies, with an emphasis on strategic and tactical support for early-stage go-to-market activities.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">We’re quick to celebrate the extraordinary victories of Israel’s multiplying cybersecurity unicorns, but every success story must start somewhere. The early days of any young startup decide how successful it can be, which is why we’ve developed a focused, value-add program to support cybersecurity founders during this most critical stage and maximize their potential in building market-leading companies.</p>
<p>However, the early stages of cybersecurity company-building are often shrouded in mystery, only coming into the light for fundraising and feature announcements. This leaves many entrepreneurs we speak with asking what exactly cybersecurity companies are achieving behind the curtain to earn these huge victories.</p>
<p>Though every company&#8217;s journey is unique, we can tease out trends and patterns to establish performance benchmarks for the cybersecurity ecosystem as a whole. To most entrepreneurs, however, the sensitive data required to understand the early success of a company is often unavailable or obscured. Moreover, the industry has yet to formally define proxies for growth and momentum beyond fundraising — leaving cybersecurity founders aiming for landmarks without guideposts.</p>
<p>Entrepreneurs require guideposts to aspire to when building large companies, and critical customer and revenue expectations can be best established by looking at what already successful cybersecurity companies have accomplished. Such metrics have been previously established for wider areas of technology, such as SaaS.</p>
<p>Leveraging our experience and resources, we collect this knowledge to keep our founders informed with the most up-to-date cybersecurity-specific metrics for long-term and large-scale growth. We hope that sharing these unique insights into early-stage cybersecurity companies — based on our own portfolio companies’ average performance — will help entrepreneurs in the wider Israeli ecosystem more confidently build their budgets and roadmaps with industry evidence.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2189576" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2189576" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2189576" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_0889.jpg" alt="Benchmarks for early-stage cybersecurity companies" width="1024" height="630" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_0889.jpg 1310w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_0889.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_0889.jpg?resize=300,185 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_0889.jpg?resize=768,473 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_0889.jpg?resize=680,418 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_0889.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2189576" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> YL Ventures</p></div></p>
<h2>What should revenue look like over the first few years?</h2>
<p>Though today’s investors are growing more aggressive, $500,000 in annual recurring revenue (ARR) is a traditional baseline requirement for a successful Series A from strong investors, and hitting that mark quickly should remain every entrepreneur&#8217;s goal. Hitting this target indicates product-market fit and customer willingness to commit to your solution.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			When it comes to contracts, timing can provide important insight into the quality and performance of the sales pipeline. On average, successful companies will have closed their first paying customers in the U.S. within 12 months of their seed round.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Discounting variances in pricing, the best companies we&#8217;ve seen are able to reach the $500,000 benchmark in less than 18 months. From there, top-performing companies can expect to gain momentum and reach $1 million in ARR in 18 to 24 months. Such momentum is contingent on a number of factors for Israeli cybersecurity entrepreneurs, but growth is mainly reliant on how well founders connect with relevant customers outside the Israeli market.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/early-stage-benchmarks-for-young-cybersecurity-companies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189553</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shopistry bags $2M to provide ‘headless commerce without the headaches’</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/shopistry-bags-2m-to-provide-headless-commerce-without-the-headaches/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/shopistry-bags-2m-to-provide-headless-commerce-without-the-headaches/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 13:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amar Varma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Duncan Hill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garage Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[headless commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jaafer Haidar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jonathan Weiner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mantella Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raiven Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopistry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tariq Zabian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189785</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shopistry enables customers to create personalized commerce experiences accessible to all.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Canada-based <a href="https://www.shopistry.com/">Shopistry</a> wants to turn the concept of headless commerce, well, on its head. On Monday, the e-commerce startup announced $2 million in seed funding to continue developing its toolkit of products, integrations, services and managed infrastructure for brands to scale online.</p>
<p>Jaafer Haidar and Tariq Zabian started Shopistry in 2019. Haidar’s background is as a serial technology founder with exits and ventures in e-commerce and cloud software. He was working as a venture capitalist when he got the idea for Shopistry. Zabian is a former general manager at OLX, an online classified marketplace.</p>
<p>Shopistry enables customers to create personalized commerce experiences accessible to all. Haidar expects headless will become the dominant architecture over the next five years, though he isn’t too keen on calling it “headless.” He much prefers the term “modular.”</p>
<p>“It’s a modular system, we call it ‘headless without the headaches,’ where you grab the framework to manage APIs,” Haidar told TechCrunch. “After a company goes live, they can spend 50% of their budget just to keep the lights on. They use marketplaces like Shopify to do the tech, and we are doing the same thing, but providing way more optionality. We are not a monolithic system.”</p>
<p>Currently, the company offers five products:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Shopistry Console: Brands turn on their optimal stack and change anytime without re-platforming. There is support for multiple e-commerce administrative tools like Shopify or Square, payment providers, analytics and marketing capabilities.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Shopistry Cloud is a managed infrastructure spearheading performance, data management and orchestration across services.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Shopistry Storefront and Mobile to manage web storefronts and mobile apps.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Shopistry CMS, a data-driven, headless customer management system to create once and publish across channels.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Shopistry Services, an offering to brands that need design and engineering help.</li>
</ul>
<p>Investors in the seed round include Shoptalk founder Jonathan Weiner, Hatch Labs’ Amar Varma, Garage Capital, Mantella Venture Partners and Raiven Capital.</p>
<p>“At MVP we love companies that can simplify complexity to bring the proven innovations of large, technically sophisticated retailers to the masses of small to midsize retailers trying to compete with them,” said Duncan Hill, co-founder and general partner at Mantella Venture Partners, in a written statement. “Shopistry has the team and tech to be a major player in this next phase of the e-commerce evolution. This was easy to get excited about.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Shopistry is already working with retailers like Honed and Oura Ring to manage their e-commerce presences without the cost, complexity or need for a big technology team.</p>
<p>Prior to going after the seed funding, Haidar and Zabian spent two years working with high growth brands to build out its infrastructure. Haidar intends to use the new capital to future that development as well as bring on sales and marketing staff.</p>
<p>Haidar was not able to provide growth metrics just yet. He did say the company was growing its customer base and expects to be able to share that growth next year. He is planning to add more flexibility and integrations to the back end of Shopistry’s platform and add support for other platforms.</p>
<p>“We are focusing next on the go-to-market perspective while we gear up for our big launch coming in the fourth quarter,” he added. “There is also a big component to ‘after the sale,’ and we want to create some amazing experiences and focus on back office operations. We want to be the easiest way to control and manage data while maintaining a storefront.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="n9ZyTc0sai"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/22/where-is-the-e-commerce-app-ecosystem-headed-in-2021/">Where is the e-commerce app ecosystem headed in 2021?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Where is the e-commerce app ecosystem headed in 2021?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/22/where-is-the-e-commerce-app-ecosystem-headed-in-2021/embed/#?secret=n9ZyTc0sai" data-secret="n9ZyTc0sai" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/shopistry-bags-2m-to-provide-headless-commerce-without-the-headaches/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189785</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Swiftarc Ventures launches beauty fund aimed at women-led startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/swiftarc-ventures-launches-beauty-fund-aimed-at-women-led-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/swiftarc-ventures-launches-beauty-fund-aimed-at-women-led-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 13:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fabian Urquiljo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leslie Wolfson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sid Jawahar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swiftarc Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2189763</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The $10 million Swiftarc Beauty Fund supports female founders leading the next wave of beauty and wellness brands. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.swiftarcventures.com/">Swiftarc Ventures</a> announced its $10 million Swiftarc Beauty Fund to support female founders leading the next wave of beauty and wellness brands.</p>
<p>Swiftarc started in 2019 and this is its fourth fund, Sid Jawahar, founder and managing partner told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>“We are being socially conscious and deliberate in solving the funding issue for female founders and diverse founders,” he said. “We took a hard look around Black Lives Matter and other awakenings and made the decision to be deliberate in trying to right an industry wrong.”</p>
<p>At the same time, Swiftarc itself is matching this by aiming for its firm’s employee base to be 50% diverse by 2022, Jawahar added.</p>
<p>He feels the beauty industry is stuck in time, where 75% to 80% of sales are still made from wholesale. E-commerce and digitally native brands are just the tip of the iceberg, he said. What has changed is the emphasis on inclusive beauty, with buyers of diverse backgrounds becoming majority purchasers. In addition, it is now not just about the brand, but building a community in order to be successful, Jawahar said.</p>
<p>That’s why Swiftarc brought in Fabian Urquijo, president, whose background is in P&amp;G and Revlon, to lead the firm’s beauty efforts.</p>
<p>“While at Revlon, we saw that independent brands that were digitally native could address unmet needs with personalization that the legacy brands can’t address,” Urquijo said. “Most of their growth is driven by that, and they end up being acquired by the big brands and continue to lead that growth.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The fund will target categories including clean and sustainable beauty, science-backed beauty products, technology-enabled and community-driven beauty and gender-neutral and inclusive brands.</p>
<p>Jawahar anticipates funding five to seven companies so that Swiftarc can provide the right kind of expertise to the companies, but could increase that to 10. The firm already invested in Alleyoop, a makeup and skincare line for busy women.</p>
<p>The fund combines financing with mentorship, peer-to-peer networking opportunities and targeted training facilitated by an all-female Beauty Council that includes industry, investment and beauty startup executives providing unique and relevant perspectives to the women-led startups. The council committed to helping 100 to 200 female founders in their journey from key introductions to foundational expertise.</p>
<p>Swiftarc’s engagement director Leslie Wolfson is building the Beauty Council and said she “wanted to curate a group of strong women with diverse backgrounds, career experiences and willingness to mentor and share their experiences and knowledge with founders.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eFUkJQbIhV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/25/black-founders-face-a-unique-set-of-challenges/">Black founders face a unique set of challenges</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Black founders face a unique set of challenges&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/25/black-founders-face-a-unique-set-of-challenges/embed/#?secret=eFUkJQbIhV" data-secret="eFUkJQbIhV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/swiftarc-ventures-launches-beauty-fund-aimed-at-women-led-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2189763</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
