<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 12:09:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Netradyne raises $150M in Series C to improve commercial driver safety</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/netradyne-raises-150m-in-series-c-to-improve-commercial-driver-safety/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/netradyne-raises-150m-in-series-c-to-improve-commercial-driver-safety/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 12:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computer Vision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[netradyne]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177873</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Netradyne, a startup that uses cameras and edge computing to improve commercial driver safety, has scored $150 million in Series C funding. The fresh cash will help the company double down on its current product, Driveri, according to Avneesh Agrawal, CEO and co-founder. Agrawal told TechCrunch the company is very confident in its product, which [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Netradyne, a startup that uses cameras and edge computing to improve commercial driver safety, has scored $150 million in Series C funding. The fresh cash will help the company double down on its current product, Driveri, according to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Avneesh Agrawal, CEO and co-founder.</span></p>
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter">
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter__right" data-qa="message_content">
<div class="c-message_kit__blocks c-message_kit__blocks--rich_text">
<div class="c-message__message_blocks c-message__message_blocks--rich_text">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer" data-qa="block-kit-renderer">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper--first">
<div class="p-rich_text_block" dir="auto">
<div>Agrawal told TechCrunch the company is very confident in its product, which rewards good driver behavior while sending real-time notifications to drivers for bad behavior, and will now focus on expanding outside its <span style="font-weight: 400;">current markets in North America and India and into Europe.</span></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Earlier this year, </span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/3/22265031/amazon-netradyne-driveri-survelliance-cameras-delivery-monitor-packages"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Netradyne partnered with Amazon</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to install its hardware and software in its delivery vehicles. The tech giant has faced accusations that it puts speed and efficiency over driver safety, all the while avoiding liability for accidents by employing third-party firms. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other companies may not have that same morally dubious luxury, which makes Netradyne’s service all the more relevant for fleets. Commercial auto insurance rates are expected to climb 14.2% in 2021, in large part due to distracted drivers using smartphones, which has increased the number of accidents resulting in death, according to a <a href="https://www.iwins.com/survey-commercial-insurance-rates-to-continue-rising-in-2021/">report</a> by insurance company Alera Group. The study also found the cost of repairing modern vehicles and medical costs continue rising at rates higher than inflation. Fleet managers looking to cut costs might be lured by promises of safer driving behavior. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Nuclear verdicts, in which judgements exceed $10 million, have gone up by almost 500% according to some statistics,&#8221; Agrawal told TechCrunch. &#8220;It’s becoming the biggest expense for commercial fleets, pretty much after the drivers and fuel. There are a lot of commercial insurance carriers actually going out of business, or they’re passing on the risk to the fleets.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If Agrawal is to be believed, Netradyne’s service is very much in demand, with subscribers and annual recurring revenue increasing three times in 2020. The CEO would not share the base, but he did say Netradyne has over 1,000 customers today. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oFJZTynxLb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/traffic-management-platform-notraffic-raises-17-5m-in-series-a-to-double-team-size/">Traffic management platform NoTraffic raises $17.5M in Series A to double team size</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Traffic management platform NoTraffic raises $17.5M in Series A to double team size&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/traffic-management-platform-notraffic-raises-17-5m-in-series-a-to-double-team-size/embed/#?secret=oFJZTynxLb" data-secret="oFJZTynxLb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Netradyne has an agreement with National Interstate Insurance that subsidizes the company’s product, but generally Netradyne sells to a fleet. The pitch is that the fleet should see a reduction in accidents and can then take that data to insurance companies to negotiate better claims. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Netradyne doesn’t provide an average of how its cameras and software has made driving safer, but anecdotally, Agrawal said a couple of the companies that have used the product saw claims decrease by up to 80% in a year.</span></p>
<h3><b>So how does it work?</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Netradyne, which combines <i>netra</i> which means “vision” in Sanskrit and <i>dyne</i> which is a unit of power or force in Greek, has built a full stack system that is purely vision-based, according to Agrawal. That means cameras in simpler terms. The system comes in two form factors. The D-210, built for small-to-medium-sized vehicles </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is a dual-facing dashcam featuring both an inward and outward-facing camera, recording both the driver and the road. The D-410 has four HD cameras providing a 360-degree picture, which includes two side window views, and is better suited for heavy duty vehicles.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The cameras pick up anything from a driver being cut off and correctly slowing down to create space between the vehicles to a driver being distracted by texting. A device that connects to the cloud is on board the vehicle, and it’s on the edge of that device that real-time computations are done, which might result in the driver getting feedback and automated suggestions like “please slow down” or “distracted driving.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Most importantly, we track the positive driving behavior because we want to change the discussion with the drivers,” said Agrawal. “Drivers are so used to being penalized, and in most cases, it&#8217;s actually after the incident has happened or based on a customer&#8217;s complaint. This is very proactive and it&#8217;s positive.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the moment, rewarding behavior can look like a notification to the driver, giving them a little dopamine hit that might encourage continued good driving. Drivers are rewarded with DriverStars, an attempt to gamify commercial operations by encouraging them to rack up points. Those points may be converted to bonuses or other incentives.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The drivers are the biggest assets for the fleet, and traditionally, if you ask the fleets, who are your worst drivers, they&#8217;ll tell you who because they are the ones who got into accidents, who customers have complained about,” said Agrawal. “If you ask them who are your safer drivers, they can&#8217;t really tell, but in our situation because we micro identify not just the drivers who haven&#8217;t gotten into accidents, but also drivers are actually being proactive with safe driving behaviour, fleets can focus on those drivers and create retention packages, give them incentives, make them into managers and leadership positions.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of course, there’s another upside to all this data collection on driver behavior. Agrawal says his company collects about 700 million miles per month worth of data, analyzing it to identify every potential scenario a driver can get themselves into. And it’s all being done on the edge, which is an experiment in and of itself. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Investing in autonomous driving is definitely a possibility, but it’s not our focus right now,” said Agrawal.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This Series C round was led by SoftBank Vision Fund 2. Existing investors Point72 Ventures and M12 also participated in the round, bringing </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Netradyne’s total funding to over $197 million. Agrawal told TechCrunch the company aims to make $100 million in revenue by the end of the year.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1idxVKWDyv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/investors-dont-expect-the-us-startup-funding-market-to-slow-down/">Investors don’t expect the US startup funding market to slow down</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Investors don’t expect the US startup funding market to slow down&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/investors-dont-expect-the-us-startup-funding-market-to-slow-down/embed/#?secret=1idxVKWDyv" data-secret="1idxVKWDyv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/netradyne-raises-150m-in-series-c-to-improve-commercial-driver-safety/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177873</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Play2Pay raises $13M to convert mobile user engagement into bill payment</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/play2pay-raises-13m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/play2pay-raises-13m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 12:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gamification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Play2Pay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telesoft Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177628</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The gamification of payments is not a new concept. A number of companies are attempting to combine gamification and payments in creative ways. And today, one such company, Play2Pay, has raised $13 million in a Series A round of funding. The Fort Lauderdale, Florida-based startup has a straightforward mission. It wants to give consumers a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The gamification of payments is not a new concept.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A number of companies are attempting to combine gamification and payments in creative ways. And today, one such company, </span><a href="https://play2pay.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Play2Pay</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, has raised $13 million in a Series A round of funding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Fort Lauderdale, Florida-based startup has a straightforward mission. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It wants to give consumers a way to reduce their bills &#8212; it claims by an average of 30%! &#8212; by playing games, watching videos and completing daily challenges, offers and surveys.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Play2Pay was bootstrapped for the first five years of its life, raising its first external capital in June of 2020 &#8212; a $7.5 million seed round from individual angel investors. <a href="https://www.telesoftvc.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.telesoftvc.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1626375657609000&amp;usg=AFQjCNH_jweeiHvgtK8S5mf6pjtim28iRQ">Telesoft Partners </a>led its Series A round, which included participation from Harbor Spring Capital and individual investors including former AT&amp;T vice chairman Ralph de la Vega, former Reuters CEO Tom Glocer, Madison Dearborn Partners co-founder and senior advisor Jim Perry and Virtusa founder and former CEO, Kris Canekeratne.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The alternative payment platform says it brokers a “value exchange” between brands and consumers, converting attention and engagement into a currency, which can be redeemed for bill payment. Meanwhile, brands get a new way to promote their products and services.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Play2Pay founder and CEO Brian Boroff started the company in 2015 based on a vision that prepaid mobile phone users should have an alternative way to pay for their mobile phone service and that wireless carriers would adopt an ad-funded commercial model.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, the company claims to be positioned to be the world&#8217;s first &#8220;ad supported payment rail&#8221; directly integrated into payments platforms of major service providers and financial institutions. It also claims to be the only company that converts user engagement directly into bill payment.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2177670" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2177670" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2177670 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Play2Pay.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="455" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Play2Pay.jpg 1300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Play2Pay.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Play2Pay.jpg?resize=300,201 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Play2Pay.jpg?resize=768,514 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Play2Pay.jpg?resize=680,455 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Play2Pay.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2177670" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Play2Pay</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The “opt-in” offering is currently available to more than 100 million mobile subscribers across the United States, United Kingdom, Mexico, Brazil and Indonesia through partnerships with telecom companies such as AT&amp;T Mexico, Cricket in the U.S., TIM in Brazil, lndosat Ooredoo in Indonesia and U.K.-based Lycamobile.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The rewarding approach seems to be resonating with users. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">From </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">June 2020 to June 2021, the startup saw its ARR (annual recurring revenue) spike by nearly 300%, according to Boroff, a telecom veteran.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Among the users engaged on the platform, about 25% generated revenue daily, he said. And </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">service providers realized up to 17% revenue expansion as a result of subscriber engagement on the Play2Pay platform, according to Boroff.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our distribution model is B2B2C, with Tier-1 service providers worldwide directly integrating our bill payment capability. We’re growing our audience through promotion of the service to their customer base,” he told TechCrunch. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">End users, he added, can share their targeting preferences in exchange for value, giving mobile app developers and brands more information when promoting their own products and services to Play2Pay’s audience.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The platform is free for service providers and merchants, meaning the payment does not have costs or fees from interchange, acquirers, chargebacks or gateways.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5vzrliTyK0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/19/social-payments-why-fintechs-need-social-features/">Social+ payments: Why fintechs need social features</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Social+ payments: Why fintechs need social features&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/19/social-payments-why-fintechs-need-social-features/embed/#?secret=5vzrliTyK0" data-secret="5vzrliTyK0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Instead, Play2Pay generates revenue from mobile app developers and brands. Those developers and brands pay to access Play2Pay’s mobile audience in order to promote their products and services. For example, a mobile gaming company might pay Play2Pay $100 for every user that downloads their app from the Play2Pay app and plays the game for a period of time (such as two hours). Through its technology and partner network, Play2Pay has attribution tracking to ensure that the end user and mobile gaming company both know how much progress has been made toward completing that goal. Other formats include watching videos, completing surveys and more conventional native advertising in some areas.</p>
<div>All of this revenue is aggregated by Play2Pay, the majority of which is passed on to the end user in the form of in-app currency. The balance goes to service providers such as its wireless carrier partners for promoting the Play2Pay platform and to Play2Pay for running the service and processing payment. Play2Pay collects all of the cash and pays out the various parties accordingly.</div>
<div></div>
<div>The company will use the new capital toward product development, hiring and partner engagement.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/play2pay-raises-13m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177628</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Leap, a &#8216;social learning&#8217; platform aimed at over 55s, raises a $3.1M Seed round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/leap-a-social-learning-platform-aimed-at-over-55s-raises-a-3-1m-seed-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/leap-a-social-learning-platform-aimed-at-over-55s-raises-a-3-1m-seed-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 11:59:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creandum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learn capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michelle Kennedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sahil lavingia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Screenhero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toca boca]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Leap, a platform for people over 55 to learn via social interaction, has raised $3.1M funding in a seed round led by European early-stage investor Creandum, and SF-based South Park Commons. Also participating was Learn Start/Learn Capital, alongside angels Michelle Kennedy (Peanut founder), Sahil Lavingia, and Tim Tuttle. Leap members gather online to collectively &#8220;learn, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://leap.so/">Leap</a>, a platform for people over 55 to learn via social interaction, has raised $3.1M funding in a seed round led by European early-stage investor Creandum, and SF-based South Park Commons. Also participating was Learn Start/Learn Capital, alongside angels Michelle Kennedy (Peanut founder), Sahil Lavingia, and Tim Tuttle.</p>
<p>Leap members gather online to collectively &#8220;learn, connect and grow together,” says the company, via small online groups built around shared interests. Users connect over audio and video, in groups of between five and ten. The current beta features conversations and classes hosted by specially recruited members.</p>
<p>Leap was founded by Swedish entrepreneur Caroline Ingeborn, former CEO of Toca Boca, a Swedish app development studio that builds learning apps for kids, and Vishal Kapur, former CTO and co-founder of Screenhero, which was acquired by Slack in 2015. The two founders met through South Park Commons, an intentional learning community that practices many of the concepts applied in Leap. </p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In a statement, Caroline Ingeborn said: &#8220;When I looked at other online offerings created for this demographic, I didn&#8217;t feel that they particularly encouraged meaningful connections. Groups described as &#8216;small&#8217; were often bursting at the seams, and experiences often felt flimsy and random. In most instances, it felt like we were all just alone, together. It motivated me to create something far more tailored and intimate.&#8221;</p>
<p>Fredrik Cassel, General Partner at Creandum: “Leap is targeting an interesting segment of society: retirees – the wealthiest and fastest-growing demographic who have been largely overlooked by tech developers. It is a generation of people with considerable time, energy, and spending power that have smartphones at their fingertips. The diverse founding team convinced us with their determination and unique experiences to build a product that is truly engaging.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/leap-a-social-learning-platform-aimed-at-over-55s-raises-a-3-1m-seed-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177993</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kenya&#8217;s AIfluence closes $1M for its AI-powered influencer marketing platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/kenyas-aifluence-closes-1m-for-its-ai-powered-influencer-marketing-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/kenyas-aifluence-closes-1m-for-its-ai-powered-influencer-marketing-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 11:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Antler East Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Influencer Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177973</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Influencer marketing is one of the fastest-growing and one of the most impactful media channels today. There&#8217;s a growing ad-blocking movement and key demographics are spending less time in front of TVs. Marketers have now realized that their customers trust the recommendations of people they relate with. However, despite this being an impactful channel, brand [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Influencer marketing is one of the fastest-growing and one of the most impactful media channels today. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">There&#8217;s a growing ad-blocking movement and key demographics are spending less time in front of TVs</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Marketers have now realized that their customers trust the recommendations of people they relate with</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, despite this being an impactful channel, brand teams globally face a major dilemma: determining the ROI of influencer marketing campaigns.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://ai-fluence.com/">AIfluence</a> is a two-year-old startup with an AI-driven influencer marketing approach to measuring these campaigns. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, the company is announcing that it has raised $1 million in seed investment led by Dubai-based EQ2 Ventures</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other investors include Antler East Africa, Oui Capital, ArabyAds, and an unnamed European family office</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">AIfluence </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was founded by</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://ke.linkedin.com/in/nelson-aseka-5656a216"> Nelson Aseka,</a> George Issaias, Lamusia Anzaya, and Ankit Jindal in 2019</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Placing AI at the core of the product, the founders started AIfluence to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">accurately</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> match influencers to brands, run end to end influencer marketing campaigns, and bring transparency to the measurement of impact (ROI)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to CEO Aseka, AIfluence </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is developed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for an audience-first approach. It identifies and gains deep insights into a target audience and works backwards to identify influencers that impact this target audience. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The platform </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is built</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on a trust network model where it deploys thousands of nano influencers and followers who have a natural affinity to a brand and exhibit a high emotional connection with the target audience.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We are at the cusp of a revolution. Globally the way marketing works is changing. We find ourselves at an intersection of advanced technology and the fastest-growing region in the world </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in terms of</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> digital and social media penetration. It’s an exciting place to be. Africa’s rich tradition for storytelling is alive and kicking,&#8221; Aseka said in a statement. &#8220;We </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">simply</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> enable such stories to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be shared</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> between peers who know and trust each other, and can place our brand messages into the heart of this communication ecosystem.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The platform was launched out of company builder and VC firm <a href="https://www.antler.co/nairobi">Antler East Africa</a> in late 2019 as one of its first cohorts before officially going live in April 2020</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Antler </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is known</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for bringing together professionals with, on average, 10 years of experience in their respective industries to start companies. That is the case with AIfluence, where its C-level executives have varying experiences in influencer marketing, growing brands, and consumer tech products.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="v33aaai25B"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/how-antler-east-africa-is-building-early-stage-startups-with-experienced-professionals/">How Antler East Africa is building early-stage startups with experienced professionals</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How Antler East Africa is building early-stage startups with experienced professionals&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/how-antler-east-africa-is-building-early-stage-startups-with-experienced-professionals/embed/#?secret=v33aaai25B" data-secret="v33aaai25B" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">AIfluence is the first startup from the builder to have raised up to $1 million. “We‌ ‌are‌ ‌excited‌ ‌to‌ ‌see‌ ‌local‌ ‌founders‌ ‌with‌ ‌deep‌ ‌expertise‌ ‌in‌ ‌the‌ ‌African‌ ‌market‌ ‌take‌ ‌a‌ ‌global‌ ‌problem‌ ‌head-on,‌ ‌and‌ ‌in‌ ‌a‌ ‌short‌ ‌time‌ ‌</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">demonstrate</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">‌ ‌a‌ ‌tech‌ ‌solution‌ ‌that‌ ‌is‌ ‌fast‌ ‌attracting‌ ‌demand‌ ‌in‌ ‌Africa‌ ‌and‌ ‌beyond,”‌  Antler‌ ‌East‌ ‌Africa’s‌ ‌partner‌ Melalite‌ ‌Ayenew ‌said in a statement.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Talking about tackling a global problem, AIfluence says it is currently running campaigns for clients across 13 countries in African and Asia. These clients are regional and global advertisers that </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">span across</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> FMCG, banking, travel and electronics sectors. Aseka says Alfluence has closed over $1 million in contracts from these clients.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">AIfluence makes money by running brand campaigns that drive awareness of products and services, and lead generation and conversion campaigns that drive sales. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company is currently working on a SaaS offering it says will &#8220;lace the power of the platform in the hands of its customers</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A major challenge the company has had, Aseka describes, is identifying robust payments solutions to cater to its thousands of influencers across different regions. However, it is in the past now. &#8220;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fortunately</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, we have so far been able to solve this by identifying a reliable payment partner, who we will grow with as we expand across new markets,&#8221; he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These markets include the rest of Africa, the Middle East and Asia. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">With the recently raised investment, AIfluence plans to launch into these markets by the end of the year and invest in its tech and SaaS platform</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“People are the new media in today’s digital world, and AIfluence is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">uniquely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> positioned to turn this reality into tangible results for advertisers. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’ve </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">been impressed by</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the team’s obsession to use data </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in order to</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> spread authentic and relevant messages to the right audience</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This is what advertising should always be. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’re looking forward to AIfluence’s journey ahead,”  CEO of EQ2 Ventures Patrick Thiriet CEO said in a statement</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/kenyas-aifluence-closes-1m-for-its-ai-powered-influencer-marketing-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177973</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Egyptian social e-commerce platform Taager raises $6.4M led by 4DX Ventures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/egyptian-social-e-commerce-platform-taager-raises-6-4m-led-by-4dx-ventures/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/egyptian-social-e-commerce-platform-taager-raises-6-4m-led-by-4dx-ventures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 11:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4DX Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taager]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177371</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The global social market is rapidly growing. With over 1.25 million online social sellers in Egypt alone, the Egyptian social e-commerce market is forecast to be worth more than $14.8 billion by 2024. One of its players, Taager, is a social e-commerce platform enabling online merchants with end-to-end logistics. Today, it is announcing that it [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The global social market is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">rapidly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> growing. With over 1.25 million online social sellers in Egypt alone, the Egyptian social e-commerce market is forecast to be worth more than $14.8 billion by 2024</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of its players, <a href="https://taager.com/">Taager</a>, is a social e-commerce platform enabling online merchants with end-to-end logistics</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Today, it is announcing that it has secured $6.4 million in seed funding. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The seed round </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was led by</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Pan-African focused VC <a href="https://www.4dxventures.com/">4DX Ventures</a>. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It also included participation from Raed Ventures, Beco Capital, Breyer Capital and some private investors, including Magnus Olsson, co-founder of Careem</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is Breyer Capital’s first investment in the MENA region, and the round brings Taager’s total investment to more than $7 million since launching in December 2019</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Social media platforms such as Facebook, Instagram and more recently TikTok have made advertising easier for online merchants to target customers with their products</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Offline, there&#8217;s a wide range of last-mile companies to distribute these products. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, there is a fragmentation between these processes for new merchants. They </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are left</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to fend for themselves when starting out and during the delivery of products; a </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">perfectly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> executed end-to-end cycle, if you will</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Consider I&#8217;m an undergraduate, and I want to own my own e-commerce store. Where do I get the product from? How do I ship them, where do I store them? Where do I make the fulfilment, what about financing it, how am I going to deliver it?&#8221; CEO Mohammed Elhorishy said to TechCrunch concerning the dilemma new merchants face.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Elhorishy argues that </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">typically</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a merchant would need to meet different suppliers to strike deals before proceeding to do the same with shipping and last-mile delivery companies</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;With Taager, we can now see the trend of people who would never have been able to build businesses on their own, now using Taager and getting the exact outcome of the very painful processing they would have gone through if they went about it </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">manually</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">,&#8221; he added</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So how does this work exactly? Essentially</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Taager has built a B2B platform to provide a one-stop shop for these online merchants and suppliers</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The platform provides online merchants and suppliers with a suite of backend and integrated services, from operational and logistical infrastructure such as storage and shipping to an online marketplace to host their products, connecting sellers with wholesalers</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2177899" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2177899" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2177899" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Taager-Team-.jpg?w=680" alt="Taager" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Taager-Team-.jpg 6000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Taager-Team-.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Taager-Team-.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Taager-Team-.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Taager-Team-.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Taager-Team-.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Taager-Team-.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Taager-Team-.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2177899" class="wp-caption-text">Taager Team</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company claims to use AI and data science to enable first-time sellers to start and scale their online business with </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">relatively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> low risk</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It offers a transparent pricing structure and an enhanced product selection process, freeing online sellers to focus on running their business while Taager handles end-to-end operations</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After getting products from suppliers on Taager, merchants can take pictures and descriptions to Facebook (via ads or its Marketplace platform), TikTok or Instagram</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;They start utilising their marketing skills. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">They do advertising, run campaigns, and once an order </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is fulfilled</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the merchants will put it on our site and Taager fulfils the end-to-end cycle</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">This way, merchants, without any inventory or stock or cash, can start a business and scale it from one order to a thousand orders per day because Taager made it seamless for them,&#8221; said the CEO</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the other end, Taager takes a margin of every sale and aggregates data points. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The platform does this </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">to</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> suggest the products that often sell to merchants and what pricing is best</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Elhorishy explains the need to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">employ</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> this strategy. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to him, while Taager is not involved with the day-to-day sale of merchant&#8217;s products, the data it provides will act as growth engines alongside the heavy lifting performed by providing warehousing and last-mile services</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;It&#8217;s all about phases. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">You need to reach specific data-critical points where you can suggest products that make sense to the merchants</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We perceive ourselves </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">mainly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as a technology and data company that has the necessary presence on the ground </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">to</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> fulfil this</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. We&#8217;re trying to automate operations as much as possible.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Presently</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Taager claims to have 5,000 merchants on its platform, critical components to the 40% month-on-month increase in Gross Merchandise Value (GMV) Elhorishy says the startup enjoys</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">While he did not comment on the platform&#8217;s number of suppliers, he talks about how difficult it was to onboard them initially</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">These suppliers, currently in their hundreds, have a plethora of options to sell their products, so Taager&#8217;s catch was to provide them with better pricing and thousands of merchants, meaning their products get sold faster</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to this was insights on how to expand their products and make faster imports.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Now they come to us asking what </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">we think</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the market needs, whereas it was a very big challenge in the beginning because they weren&#8217;t used to this kind of business</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another challenge was managing the last-mile operations, and now we have teams managing relationships with a wide variety of last-mile companies,&#8221; Elhorishy said of some challenges faced by the company early on</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A high margin business, as Elhorishy claims, Taager will be looking to deploy the new capital into its </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">rapidly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> growing operations</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It is also making hires across all levels in the company and plans to scale across MENA.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Social e-commerce globally is on the rise, and in MENA as well. Jim Breyer of Breyer Capital </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is enthused by</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> this growth and Taager&#8217;s traction in the space. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">He believes there’s a great opportunity for Taager to replicate its unique data-driven approach for further growth across the region</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Taager&#8217;s growth also proved decisive in getting a check from its lead investor. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Peter Orth, co-founder and managing partner at 4DX Ventures, said, &#8220;The Taager team have achieved very impressive results </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">incredibly</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">quickly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and also built one of the most impressive teams in the ecosystem</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Their focus on quality and execution and a very unique approach to empowering e-commerce entrepreneurs is a dominant combination</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. We’re thrilled to partner with the team in the next phase of the company’s growth.&#8221;</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/egyptian-social-e-commerce-platform-taager-raises-6-4m-led-by-4dx-ventures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177371</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Verve Motion raises $15M following exosuit pilot with grocery workers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/verve-motion-raises-15m-following-exosuit-pilot-with-grocery-workers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/verve-motion-raises-15m-following-exosuit-pilot-with-grocery-workers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 11:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Construct Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exoskeleton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[verve motion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177753</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The exoskeleton/exosuit category has been heating up over the past few years. It makes sense, really. There are two giant &#8212; and dramatically different &#8212; potential customer bases. On one end are those sorts of jobs that could benefit from some wearable assistance. On the other are people with mobility issues for whom such technology [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The exoskeleton/exosuit category has been heating up over the past few years. It makes sense, really. There are two giant &#8212; and dramatically different &#8212; potential customer bases. On one end are those sorts of jobs that could benefit from some wearable assistance. On the other are people with mobility issues for whom such technology might go a long way.</p>
<p>Founded last year by a team spun out of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/15/these-robo-shorts-are-the-precursor-to-a-true-soft-exoskeleton/">Conor Walsh‘s lab</a> at Harvard’s Wyss Institute and the John A. Paulson School of Engineering and Applied Sciences, Verve Motion is targeting the former for now. You probably don’t need a bunch of stats to realize that labor-intensive work often ends in injury, but here are a trio from the startup’s site anyway:</p>
<ul>
<li>One million back injuries occur in U.S. workplaces each year, according to the Bureau of Labor Statistics</li>
<li>260+ million work days are lost every year due to back injury, according to the United States Bone and Joint Initiative</li>
<li>$14 billion in direct costs hit U.S. employers annually, according to Liberty Mutual Workplace Index 2018</li>
</ul>
<p><div id="attachment_2177761" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2177761" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2177761 size-full" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-14-at-5.10.43-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="779" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-14-at-5.10.43-PM.jpg 1204w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-14-at-5.10.43-PM.jpg?resize=150,114 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-14-at-5.10.43-PM.jpg?resize=300,228 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-14-at-5.10.43-PM.jpg?resize=768,584 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-14-at-5.10.43-PM.jpg?resize=680,517 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-14-at-5.10.43-PM.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2177761" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> ADUSA Distribution</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>If you can’t appeal to people’s sense of common decency, then at least you can appeal to their wallets. Whichever the case, Verve Motion is announcing some fresh funding, following both a seed round and a <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/warehouse-operators-turn-to-wearable-technology-to-solve-workplace-strains-11624975200">successful pilot with ADUSA (Ahold Delhaize)</a>, a large grocery distribution firm. That funding arrived during the pandemic, when many essential workers in the food supply chain were being pushed to their physical limits on a daily basis.</p>
<p>This time out, the firm has raised a $15 million Series A, led by Construct Capital and featuring a bunch of existing investors, like Founder Collective, Pillar VC, Safar Partners and OUP.</p>
<p>“This new round of funding will fuel the continued development of our solution and scale operations to meet the growing demand for our product in order to get it to the workers who need it most right now,” co-founder and CEO Ignacio Galiana said in a release. “We are grateful for the support of this exceptional group of new and existing investors, and are thrilled to welcome Construct Capital as we create solutions for the industrial workforce of the future.”</p>
<p>Verve’s first product is the SafeLift, a fabric-based soft exosuit capable of adapting to its wearer’s movements and reducing up to 30 to 40% of back strain.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hWGMI1SbCW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/15/these-robo-shorts-are-the-precursor-to-a-true-soft-exoskeleton/">These robo-shorts are the precursor to a true soft exoskeleton</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;These robo-shorts are the precursor to a true soft exoskeleton&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/15/these-robo-shorts-are-the-precursor-to-a-true-soft-exoskeleton/embed/#?secret=hWGMI1SbCW" data-secret="hWGMI1SbCW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VevtFaVO1U"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/5-fundraising-imperatives-for-robotics-startups/">5 fundraising imperatives for robotics startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 fundraising imperatives for robotics startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/5-fundraising-imperatives-for-robotics-startups/embed/#?secret=VevtFaVO1U" data-secret="VevtFaVO1U" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/verve-motion-raises-15m-following-exosuit-pilot-with-grocery-workers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177753</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Butlr Technologies, developing anonymous people sensors, inks $7.9M seed round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/butlr-technologies-developing-anonymous-people-sensors-inks-7-9m-seed-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/butlr-technologies-developing-anonymous-people-sensors-inks-7-9m-seed-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[500 startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Butlr Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric Paley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founder Collective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Honghao Deng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hyperplane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jiani Zeng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mit media lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scott Belsky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sosv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Union Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wireless sensors]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177685</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New funding boosts Butlr's ability to apply real-time people-sensing technology beyond real estate and retail uses to monitor falls and other movements for active seniors who are aging in place.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A new $7.9 million seed round boosts <a href="https://www.butlr.io/">Butlr Technologies</a>’ ability to apply its real-time people-sensing technology beyond commercial real estate and retail uses to monitor falls and other movements for active seniors who are aging in place.</p>
<p>Hyperplane led the round, with Founder Collective, Union Labs, 500 Startups, SOSV, E14 Fund, Tectonic Ventures, Scott Belsky, Chad Laurans and Sunny Vu participating.</p>
<p>The new funding comes one year after the Burlingame, California-based proptech company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/butlr-privacy-sensors-coronavirus/">raised $1.2 million</a> in convertible notes, which is included in the $7.9 million. It is developing a platform and Heatic sensors that detect someone’s body heat anonymously to determine occupancy, headcount and activity.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Co-founders Honghao Deng and Jiani Zeng, who spun Butlr out of the MIT Media Lab in 2019, refer to their technology as “Alexa for spatial.” Their wireless sensors capture five frames per second of thermal body heat data — posture, quality of sleep and temperature — and then turn that into insights that customers can use to make decisions on anything from constructing a building to planning how people will coexist in physician spaces.</p>
<p>Deng told TechCrunch the company is “the only one combining accuracy with wireless.” The wireless aspect of the sensors, which can fit in the palm of your hand, means that they can be placed anywhere, require a one-time setup and the batteries last for two years. Butlr is also all about protecting privacy, so the replay doesn’t show faces, but instead the person’s “heat” moving around.</p>
<p>“The sensors can be used in any environment,” Deng said. “It should be invisible and not something people have to worry about. We can bring dignity back to the technology world, while also understanding users&#8217; needs. This is about new things people couldn’t do before, how to use the space in real-time and in a way that is easy to deploy.”</p>
<p>Basic kits, which start at $880, can be purchased from the company’s website, and include space-designing software that someone can use to easily determine where to place the sensors for maximum coverage.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2021073" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2021073" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2021073" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/butlr-.gif?w=600" alt="Butlr Technologies' simulation of movement and detection." width="600" height="336" /><p id="caption-attachment-2021073" class="wp-caption-text">Butlr Technologies&#8217; simulation of movement and detection. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Butlr Technologies</p></div></p>
<p>The funding is earmarked for continued market expansion and technology development, including a more advanced API, to meet explosive demand for spatial intelligence — the company is shipping out hundreds of thousands of sensors and grew almost 10 times in revenue last year. Deng expects that to continue as companies figure out their return-to-work policies following the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>Though Butlr initially started with real estate and retailers, Deng sees potential in other use cases, like car traffic flow and assisted living facilities, where early diagnostics and cognitive function can be monitored before an accident happens.</p>
<p>“The assisted living market is huge,” Deng added. “One of the most important things coming from monitoring is understanding where a person is. We can get early predictions about their frailty.”</p>
<p>For example, by being able to transmit images in real time, Butlr is better able to detect rigid movements or behavior that looks like falling. This is unlike incumbent technology, which Deng said “misses minutes” during the transmission of the images.</p>
<p>Incumbents are also relying on wearables or health bands, which have to be charged and can be cumbersome to use in a senior care or home health environment. In addition, by having a sensor versus a camera, it also preserves dignity, Zeng said.</p>
<p>Founder Collective partner Eric Paley told TechCrunch that he loved what Butlr is doing because of its “incredible simplicity,” what he called “the holy grail of indoor sensing.”</p>
<p>He’s seen other startups go after this same market and fail due to making it difficult for an average user to set it up or require an electrician. For the sensors to be fixed in one place and be there for years “is huge,” Paley said.</p>
<p>“What they have been able to do at an early stage is impressive,” he added. “There are so many uses for what Butlr’s technology is doing, and many industries are coming after them to use it. We are constantly having conversations on what are the best opportunities, and by having an API approach we can serve lots of customers.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6ShN4V392L"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/as-tech-offices-begin-to-reopen-the-workplace-could-look-very-different/">As tech offices begin to reopen, the workplace could look very different</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As tech offices begin to reopen, the workplace could look very different&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/as-tech-offices-begin-to-reopen-the-workplace-could-look-very-different/embed/#?secret=6ShN4V392L" data-secret="6ShN4V392L" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/butlr-technologies-developing-anonymous-people-sensors-inks-7-9m-seed-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177685</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revolut confirms a fresh $800M in funding at a $33B valuation to supercharge its financial services superapp</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/revolut-confirms-a-fresh-800m-in-funding-at-a-33b-valuation-to-supercharge-its-financial-services-superapp/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/revolut-confirms-a-fresh-800m-in-funding-at-a-33b-valuation-to-supercharge-its-financial-services-superapp/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 08:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neobank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neobanks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Revolut]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177962</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The fintech funding continues to roll in at a rapid pace, a result of the huge shift underway in how consumers spend and manage their money. In the latest development, Revolut &#8212; the London-based financial &#8220;superapp&#8221; that provides banking, investing, currency transfer and other money management services to some 16 million users globally &#8212; this [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div title="Page 1">
<div>
<div>
<div>
<p id="speakable-summary">The fintech funding continues to roll in at a rapid pace, a result of the huge shift underway in how consumers spend and manage their money. In the latest development, <a href="https://www.revolut.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Revolut</a> &#8212; the London-based financial &#8220;superapp&#8221; that provides banking, investing, currency transfer and other money management services to some 16 million users globally &#8212; this morning confirmed that it has raised $800 million. The company said that this Series E round of funding values Revolut at $33 billion.</p>
<p>This makes Revolut the most valuable fintech out of the UK, as well as one of the biggest of the privately-backed scaled-up startups not just in Europe, but the world. It&#8217;s also following in the footsteps of Klarna, the buy-now-pay-later startup out of Sweden that is also diversifying into a wider range of other services for consumers and the businesses that integrate it. Klarna <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/fintech-giant-klarna-raises-639m-at-a-45-6b-valuation/">last month raised $639 million</a> valued at just under $46 billion. Stripe in the US earlier this year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/14/stripe-closes-600m-round-at-a-95b-valuation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised at a $95 billion valuation</a>.</p>
<p>This latest Series E is being co-led by Softbank Vision Fund 2 and Tiger Global, who appear to be the only backers in this round. It comes on the heels of <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/klarna-effect-propels-digital-bank-revolut-to-30bn-valuation-in-softbank-talks-12347766" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rumors earlier this month</a> Revolut was raising big. Revolut last raised about a year ago, when it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/24/revolut-extends-series-d-round-to-580-million-with-80-million-in-new-funding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">closed out a Series D at $580 million</a>, but what is stunning is how much its valuation has changed since then, growing 6x (it was $5.5 billion last year).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“SoftBank and Tiger Global’s investments are an endorsement of our mission to create a global financial superapp that enables customers to manage all their financial needs through a single platform,&#8221; said Nikolay Storonsky, Revolut&#8217;s founder and CEO, in a statement.</p>
<p>As a further point of reference, when Revolut <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/revolut-revenue-grew-by-57-in-2020/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported financial figures for 2020 last month</a>, it noted that it made $361 million in revenue (£261 million) in the fiscal year, a 57% increase versus 2019 revenue of $229 million (£166 million). Gross profit in the period was $170 million (£123 million) last year, although it still operates at a net loss, with Q1 2020 racking up an adjusted operating loss of $76 million (£55 million), with  $277 million (£200.6 million) in operating losses for the whole of the year. In other words, the big money being placed down now, and this big valuation, are long-term bets.</p>
<p>Revolut now has over 16 million customers and sees over 150 million transactions/month, and the plan will be to bring on a wider range of services and promotions both to grow that base, and to get its users putting more money and time into the app. That will also include exploring newer areas like insurance and a deeper dive into investing and trading, and likely a significant increase in credit services (which have been a big growth engine for other neobanks and financial tech companies). Revolut will also be doing more to build out its user bases in the U.S. and India, it said.</p>
<p>Like other &#8220;neobanks&#8221; that have emerged in recent years, Revolut has been built around the idea of tapping already-built banking and financial services infrastructure, which it <a href="https://truelayer.com/customers/revolut" target="_blank" rel="noopener">uses by way of APIs</a> and integrates into its service. Revolut then focuses on creating a slick and user-friendly experience both within its app and with its customer service.</p>
<p>The focus of its technology, then, is to improve personalization in the service, and to create new tools that aren&#8217;t as commoditized, such as budgeting tools and other financial management features.</p>
<p>“We believe Revolut’s superior customer experience and focus on rapid product development put the company in a strong position to continue scaling in both existing and new geographies,&#8221; said Scott Shleifer, partner, Tiger Global, in a statement. &#8220;We are excited to partner with Nik and the Revolut team as they build the next generation of financial services.”</p>
<p>This has particularly appealed to younger users, who not only are more comfortable using digital services, but will be less experienced jn all things finance.</p>
<p>But it will be interesting to see how and if Revolut brings more core financial infrastructure into its app, or whether embedded finance reigns supreme. (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/revolut-applies-for-uk-banking-license/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Applying for a banking license</a> as Revolut did earlier this year in the UK could be one sign of what it might build in the future. It&#8217;s also <a href="https://www.fintechfutures.com/2018/02/revolut-ditches-wirecard-for-in-house-card-issuing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">parted ways with some of its third-party providers</a> over the years to build its own infrastructure.)</p>
<p>In the meantime, investors believe that there is plenty of room for developing technology in its current model.</p>
<p>“Revolut’s rate of innovation has redefined the role of financial services, placing [Revolut] at the forefront of Europe’s nascent neobanking sector. The company’s rapidly growing user base reflects a sustained demand for Revolut’s expanding suite of services,&#8221; said Karol Niewiadomski, senior investor for SoftBank Investment Advisers, in a statement. &#8220;We look forward to supporting Nikolay and the team in continued product innovation and bringing their services to new markets globally.”</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div title="Page 2">
<div>
<div>
<div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/revolut-confirms-a-fresh-800m-in-funding-at-a-33b-valuation-to-supercharge-its-financial-services-superapp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177962</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India&#8217;s Inshorts raises $60 million following Public social network app growth</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/india-inshorts-raises-60-million-to-scale-public-social-network-app/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/india-inshorts-raises-60-million-to-scale-public-social-network-app/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 07:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Addition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inshorts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lee Fixel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vy capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177949</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Indian startup Inshorts, which operates an eponymous news aggregator service, has raised $60 million in a new financing round as its two-year-old bet &#8212; launch of a new social media app called Public &#8212; continues to impress, the startup confirmed to TechCrunch on Thursday. Vy Capital led the new round in Inshorts, which has raised [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Indian startup <a href="http://www.inshorts.com">Inshorts</a>, which operates an eponymous news aggregator service, has raised $60 million in a new financing round as its two-year-old bet &#8212; launch of a new social media app called Public &#8212; continues to impress, the startup confirmed to TechCrunch on Thursday.</p>
<p>Vy Capital led the new round in Inshorts, which has raised $140 million in the last one year. The new investment values the startup at about $550 million, up from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/indian-social-network-public-app-raises-41-million/">about $250 million valuation in $41 million fundraise in March</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/lee-fixels-addition-leads-35-million-investment-in-india-inshorts-public-social-network/">$125 million valuation in September last year</a>, according to three people familiar with the matter.</p>
<p>Azhar Iqubal, co-founder and chief executive of Inshorts, confirmed the size of the round and lead investor but declined to comment on the valuation. The startup counts Addition, Tiger Global, SIG, A91 and Tanglin Venture Partners among its investors.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“The world is changing every minute, and each one of us has an inherent desire to remain updated about these changes,&#8221; he said in a brief statement. &#8220;Both Inshorts app and Public app are aimed to help some of these people in their quest of keeping themselves informed and we are thrilled to have Vy Capital join us in our journey.&#8221;</p>
<p>Inshorts is a popular aggregator app that summarizes news articles in 60 words and covers a wide-range of topics including tech and business. But arguably it&#8217;s the startup&#8217;s expansion into the social media category that has helped it scale widely and attract so many high-profile investors.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2177956" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2177956" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2177956 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/inshorts-public-app.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="274" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/inshorts-public-app.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/inshorts-public-app.jpg?resize=150,40 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/inshorts-public-app.jpg?resize=300,80 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/inshorts-public-app.jpg?resize=768,205 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/inshorts-public-app.jpg?resize=680,182 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/inshorts-public-app.jpg?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2177956" class="wp-caption-text">Downloads of Public app, according to mobile insight platform App Annie.</p></div></p>
<p>Launched two years ago, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.cardfeed.video_public&amp;hl=en_IN&amp;gl=US">Public</a> app has already emerged as one of the fastest growing social apps in the South Asian country with over 60 million monthly active users. The location-based social network connects individuals to people in their vicinity. Think about people living in the same society, or people in a mall or within a few miles from each other.</p>
<p>The app, which is available in several major Indian languages (including Hindi, Bengali, Punjabi, Telugu, Tamil, Kannada, Malayalam, Odia, Assamese, Gujarati and Marathi), allows shop owners to drive e-commerce, and also serves as a classified, entertainment and recruiting platform.</p>
<p>“We are excited to partner with Azhar and team in their journey to build one of the largest content platforms out of India, running two market leading properties with a rapidly growing user base. We look forward to working closely with the company and the team as it enters the next phase of scaling,” said Vamsi Duvvuri, Partner, Vy Capital, in a statement.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/india-inshorts-raises-60-million-to-scale-public-social-network-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177949</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Singapore-based Tinvio raises $12M Series A to build financial services for supply chain merchants</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/singapore-based-tinvio-raises-12m-series-a-to-build-financial-services-for-supply-chain-merchants/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/singapore-based-tinvio-raises-12m-series-a-to-build-financial-services-for-supply-chain-merchants/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 06:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inventory management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tinvio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wholesalers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177944</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[First created to give supply chain merchants a streamlined way to communicate with buyers, Tinvio is now preparing to launch financial services, including financing and credit card issuing. The Singapore-based startup announced today it has raised a $12 million Series A to build out its B2B transactions platform. The round was led by AppWorks Ventures, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">First created to give supply chain merchants a streamlined way to communicate with buyers, <a href="https://tinvio.com/">Tinvio</a> is now preparing to launch financial services, including financing and credit card issuing. The Singapore-based startup announced today it has raised a $12 million Series A to build out its B2B transactions platform. The round was led by AppWorks Ventures, with participation from strategic investor MUFG Innovation Partners (MUIP), a venture capital firm for collaborations between startups and Mitsubishi UFJ Financial Group.</p>
<p>All of Tinvio’s existing investors—Sequoia Capital India’s Surge, Global Founders Capital and Partech Ventures—also returned for its Series A, which brings Tinvio’s total raised to $18.5 million.</p>
<p>Tinvio’s last funding announcement<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/27/tinvio-a-communication-platform-for-supply-chain-merchants-gets-5-5-million-seed-round"> was a $5.5 million seed round in April 2020</a>. The company was founded in July 2019 by Ajay Gopal, whose prior professional experience included leading initial public offering and merger and acquisition transactions as a fintech investment banker for Credit Suisse in London.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PtLBUVOhfp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/27/tinvio-a-communication-platform-for-supply-chain-merchants-gets-5-5-million-seed-round/">Tinvio, a communication platform for supply chain merchants, gets $5.5 million seed round</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tinvio, a communication platform for supply chain merchants, gets $5.5 million seed round&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/27/tinvio-a-communication-platform-for-supply-chain-merchants-gets-5-5-million-seed-round/embed/#?secret=PtLBUVOhfp" data-secret="PtLBUVOhfp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Since its seed funding, Tinvio says its client base has increased four times to over 5,000 businesses in Singapore, Indonesia, Thailand and other Asian markets. Gopal told TechCrunch that as its user base grows, it is acquiring more new customers through word-of-mouth and referrals. For example, Southeast Asian F&amp;B supplier QQ Group onboarded all of its merchants onto Tinvio and now uses the platform for all trade orders.</p>
<p>One of the reasons Tinvio focuses on F&amp;B businesses is because they deal with a lot of perishable goods and constantly need to manage orders and inventory. Gopal said the company also has clients in the healthcare and automotive sectors, but plans to keep targeting growth in F&amp;B.</p>
<p>Tinvio app was originally launched as a way to consolidate orders from different places, including email, SMS and WhatsApp, and let suppliers keep real-time digital ledgers.</p>
<p>It recently entered financial services by adding a digital payments collection and reconciliation features. Gopal says many suppliers still take payment in the form of bank transfers or cash and paper checks on delivery, making it difficult to keep manage their cash cycles. So Tinvio launched a “super dirty pilot” for on-platform payments late last year in Indonesia, and after validating it, added B2B payments to its core product. Tinvio supports payments through credit cards, direct debits and automated bank transfers, and is integrated with regional payment gateways. Over the last two months, 95% of suppliers on the platform have continued to use Tinvio to collect payments from their merchants.</p>
<p>“It’s only been live for a couple of months, but we’ve already gotten so much feedback from our users and we’re sprinting to unlock new capabilities such as real-time payments and credit,” said Gopal.</p>
<p>The company has a 12-month roadmap for its other financial services, including transaction financing, credit card issuing and invoice factoring, with pilots planned for the next two quarters. “In this Series A, we’ve teamed up with MUFG bank,” Gopal said. “This sets us up in a fantastic position to go-to-market even sooner with our financial technology stack that we’ve been building.”</p>
<p>In a statement, AppWorks Ventures managing partner Jessica Liu said, “Tinvio&#8217;s focus on modernizing B2B trade with a seamless user experience has seen it onboard and digitalize thousands of merchant and supplier teams without disrupting their daily routines or procurement workflows. Despite COVID-19, we still see great growth momentum, led by increasing network effects, leaving Tinvio well positioned to dominate this category.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iT801MgmdZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/17/how-tech-can-build-more-resilient-supply-chains/">How tech can build more resilient supply chains</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How tech can build more resilient supply chains&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/17/how-tech-can-build-more-resilient-supply-chains/embed/#?secret=iT801MgmdZ" data-secret="iT801MgmdZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/singapore-based-tinvio-raises-12m-series-a-to-build-financial-services-for-supply-chain-merchants/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177944</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Easy Eat AI raises $5M to help Southeast Asian restaurants digitize their operations</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/easy-eat-ai-raises-5m-to-help-southeast-asian-restaurants-digitize-their-operations/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/easy-eat-ai-raises-5m-to-help-southeast-asian-restaurants-digitize-their-operations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 05:12:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easy Eat AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malaysia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Restaurants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177932</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Easy Eat AI, a Singapore-based startup that wants to “transform restaurants into technology companies,” announced today it has raised $5 million in funding. Easy Eat AI offers an operating system for restaurants that lets them digitize all parts of their business, from inventory and customer orders to delivery, and gain AI-based data analytics to improve [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://easyeat.ai/">Easy Eat AI</a>, a Singapore-based startup that wants to “transform restaurants into technology companies,” announced today it has raised $5 million in funding. Easy Eat AI offers an operating system for restaurants that lets them digitize all parts of their business, from inventory and customer orders to delivery, and gain AI-based data analytics to improve revenue.</p>
<p>Many food and beverage businesses started digitizing orders and payments so they could offer deliveries during the COVID-19 pandemic. Though Easy Eat AI lets restaurants integrate with third-party food ordering apps, it also has its own delivery infrastructure, including on-demand riders, that costs just 4% per order, compared to the 20%-30% that many of the largest food delivery platforms charge.</p>
<p>Founded in 2019 by Mohd Wassem, Rhythm Gupta and Abdul Khalid, Easy Eat AI currently has operations in Malaysia, and plans to expand into other Southeast Asian markets. The funding included participation from Aroa Ventures, the family office of OYO founder Ritesh Agarwal; Reddy Futures Family Office; Prophetic Ventures; OYO global chief strategy officer Maninder Gulati; Alarko Ventures managing partner Cem Garih; and Esas Ventures founder and managing partner Fethi Sabancı Kamışlı.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Wassem told TechCrunch that Easy Eat AI was created because even though Southeast Asia “is a food paradise, everyone eats out, eating out is a culture here,” the restaurant industry is still one of the least advanced digitally. Before the pandemic, he said that about 80% of restaurant business came from in-person dining, but taking orders manually resulted in very little data kept about who customers are, what they like to order or how often they return.</p>
<p>Easy Eat AI’s platform helps restaurants create that digital connection with their customers. Some of its clients include chains like Richiamo Coffee, Mr. Fish Fishhead Noodles, WTF Group and Hailam Toast. During COVID-19 lockdowns, Easy Eat AI has helped restaurants fulfill deliveries and its other features, like targeted marketing campaigns and loyalty reward programs, are relevant to in-person dining, too.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2177941" style="width: 441px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Easy-Eat-Screen.jpeg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2177941" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-full wp-image-2177941" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Easy-Eat-Screen.jpeg" alt="A menu created with Easy Eat AI" width="431" height="687" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Easy-Eat-Screen.jpeg 431w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Easy-Eat-Screen.jpeg?resize=94,150 94w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Easy-Eat-Screen.jpeg?resize=188,300 188w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Easy-Eat-Screen.jpeg?resize=427,680 427w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Easy-Eat-Screen.jpeg?resize=31,50 31w" sizes="(max-width: 431px) 100vw, 431px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2177941" class="wp-caption-text">A menu created with Easy Eat AI</p></div></p>
<p>Easy Eat AI’s consumer interface is based on QR code ordering—customers scan the code with their smartphone and are taken directly to the restaurant’s menu online. They pick what they want, then create an account or sign-in by entering their mobile number. Payments and reward programs can also be accessed through the platform.</p>
<p>The company says that after analyzing 100,000 orders at more than 50 restaurants over six months, it found that people spend about 30% more when they order digitally compared to through a waiter—similar to when people go shopping for a specific item online and end up adding more items to their cart while browsing.</p>
<p>After a restaurant uses Easy Eat AI for about 30 to 45 days, it is able to build a customer database for targeted online marketing strategies, sending offers to the people who are most likely to use them.</p>
<p>For example, a month after launching in its third outlet of Mr. Fish, the platform had collected data from more than 1,400 customers. The restaurant was able to see that about 20% visited the restaurant more than once, and the average duration between their visits was 12 days. Based on that information, it created marketing campaigns to draw back people who hadn’t returned in 20 days. During that time, Mr. Fish also started fulfilling delivery orders through Easy Eat AI, and by the end of the month, 13.4% of its orders were coming through the platform, reducing its reliance on third-party delivery apps.</p>
<p>In a statement about the funding, Keshav Reddy, managing partner of Reddy Futures Family Office, said, “The team is customer obsessed and understands the pain problems of the industry. Their innovative software platform will be disruptive to the entire F&amp;B ecosystem and how customers engage through the entire F&amp;B lifecycle in the online-to-offline world.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zVSRzfkg88"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/malaysia-based-inventory-management-platform-food-market-hub-raises-4-million-from-go-ventures-sig/">Malaysia-based inventory management platform Food Market Hub raises $4 million from Go-Ventures, SIG</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Malaysia-based inventory management platform Food Market Hub raises $4 million from Go-Ventures, SIG&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/malaysia-based-inventory-management-platform-food-market-hub-raises-4-million-from-go-ventures-sig/embed/#?secret=zVSRzfkg88" data-secret="zVSRzfkg88" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HV6KEjXy8c"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/deliverect-gobbles-up-65m-for-a-platform-that-streamlines-online-and-offline-food-orders/">Deliverect gobbles up $65M for a platform that streamlines online and offline food orders</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Deliverect gobbles up $65M for a platform that streamlines online and offline food orders&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/deliverect-gobbles-up-65m-for-a-platform-that-streamlines-online-and-offline-food-orders/embed/#?secret=HV6KEjXy8c" data-secret="HV6KEjXy8c" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/easy-eat-ai-raises-5m-to-help-southeast-asian-restaurants-digitize-their-operations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177932</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>YC-backed Deskimo, an on-demand coworking space app, launches in Singapore and Hong Kong</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/yc-backed-deskimo-an-on-demand-coworking-space-app-launches-in-singapore-and-hong-kong/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/yc-backed-deskimo-an-on-demand-coworking-space-app-launches-in-singapore-and-hong-kong/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 03:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coworking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177313</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Part of Y Combinator’s current batch, Deskimo wants to make finding coworking spaces easier. Its on-demand booking app is currently available in Singapore and Hong Kong, with plans to enter more markets after Demo Day. Its founders are former Rocket Internet executives who say that their main competition aren’t spaces like WeWork or other hot [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2177314" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/2-Arcc-Spaces.jpeg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2177314" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2177314 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/2-Arcc-Spaces.jpeg" alt="A photograph of Arcc, one of Deskimo's coworking spaces in Singapore" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/2-Arcc-Spaces.jpeg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/2-Arcc-Spaces.jpeg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/2-Arcc-Spaces.jpeg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/2-Arcc-Spaces.jpeg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/2-Arcc-Spaces.jpeg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/2-Arcc-Spaces.jpeg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2177314" class="wp-caption-text">Arcc, a coworking space in Singapore available for bookings on Deskimo</p></div></p>
<p>Part of Y Combinator’s current batch, <a href="https://www.deskimo.com/">Deskimo</a> wants to make finding coworking spaces easier. Its on-demand booking app is currently available in Singapore and Hong Kong, with plans to enter more markets after Demo Day. Its founders are former Rocket Internet executives who say that their main competition aren’t spaces like WeWork or other hot desk booking apps. Instead, its Starbucks, since Deskimo caters to people who usually work from home, but occasionally need a place nearby where they can get away from distractions or take meetings. Deskimo partners with employers and charges them by the time their workers spend at space, instead of a monthly or yearly fee.</p>
<p>Deskimo was launched in February by Raphael Cohen, Rocket Internet’s former head of Asia, and Christian Mischler, who co-founded Foodpanda and served as its global chief operating officer. After Rocket Internet, the two started HotelQuickly, an on-demand booking app they sold in 2017.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The pandemic has quickly changed attitudes toward remote work, with a<a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/organization/our-insights/what-employees-are-saying-about-the-future-of-remote-work"> McKinsey survey </a>finding that 62% of respondents said they only wanted to return to the office a few days a week, or not at all. As a result, many companies, especially startups, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/tech-companies-are-looking-at-more-flexible-work-models-when-offices-reopen/">will continue offering flexible arrangements</a>.</p>
<p>Mischler and Cohen already have experience watching peoples’ behavior shift after Foodpanda was launched. “Back in 2012, people were saying that food ordering is not going to work online, people just order on the phone or in person,” Cohen said. “What we learned from on-demand restaurant delivery, the shared market-based model, is very similar in that case to setting up with workspace partners.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oaSGFWtn4X"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/tech-companies-are-looking-at-more-flexible-work-models-when-offices-reopen/">Tech companies are looking at more flexible work models when offices reopen</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tech companies are looking at more flexible work models when offices reopen&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/tech-companies-are-looking-at-more-flexible-work-models-when-offices-reopen/embed/#?secret=oaSGFWtn4X" data-secret="oaSGFWtn4X" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Deskimo now has about 50 properties in Singapore and 40 in Hong Kong, and wants to expand in both residential and business districts, since many remote workers prefer to find a space close to their homes. It works with several different types of property owners and is approaching each group step-by-step. The first are office spaces that are already set up for coworking and see Deskimo as an additional distribution channel. The second are hotels that are converting some of their space into coworking areas. Finally, Deskimo plans to partner with spaces like social clubs and event venues that usually sit empty during weekdays.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2177315" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/phone-check-in.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2177315" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2177315" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/phone-check-in.png" alt="Deskimo app's QR code" width="1024" height="726" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/phone-check-in.png 1623w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/phone-check-in.png?resize=150,106 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/phone-check-in.png?resize=300,213 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/phone-check-in.png?resize=768,545 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/phone-check-in.png?resize=680,482 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/phone-check-in.png?resize=1536,1089 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/phone-check-in.png?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2177315" class="wp-caption-text">Deskimo app&#8217;s QR code</p></div></p>
<p>On the client side, Deskimo contracts with companies, who then offer the app to their employees. Each person gets a monthly budget on Deskimo, and their employers are only billed for the time they spend at a space. The Deskimo app generates a QR code that workers use to gain access to one of its spaces, and they also scan it when checking out to record how long they were there. Pricing ranges from about $2 to $4 USD per hour, with desks in central business districts typically costing more. Aggregated invoices are sent to clients each month and revenue is then shared with coworking space owners.</p>
<p>“Many companies realize they can save a lot of costs by having people work from home so they can reduce their office space, and instead of adding more fixed costs, they just add variable costs,” said Mischler. “They provide their employees with the ability to go to an office, but if they don’t want to because they have a great home to work from, employees are also more than welcome to work from home.”</p>
<p>In Deskimo’s current markets, other on-demand coworking space apps include Switch, Flydesk, WorkBuddy and Booqed. But Mischler says its main competitors are large F&amp;B chains like Starbucks, since they are easy to find. He adds that Deskimo is more efficient for workers, who are guaranteed a table and don’t need to worry about finding outlets or the quality of Wi-Fi. Besides expanding into more markets, Deskimo also wants to add other services on top of coworking to give it a competitive edge.</p>
<p>“Once we have the company relationships and their employees use Deskimo for their bookings, there’s a lot of different things we can build on top of it, whether it&#8217;s employee engagement or workforce management, not just workplace management,” says Mischer. “But we’re focused on the transactional model right now because that’s the biggest pain point.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CtWOXmdI7I"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/wework-unbundles-its-products-in-an-attempt-to-make-itself-over-but-will-the-strategy-work/">WeWork unbundles its products in an attempt to make itself over, but will the strategy work?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;WeWork unbundles its products in an attempt to make itself over, but will the strategy work?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/wework-unbundles-its-products-in-an-attempt-to-make-itself-over-but-will-the-strategy-work/embed/#?secret=CtWOXmdI7I" data-secret="CtWOXmdI7I" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="auE1LYMVv6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/as-tech-offices-begin-to-reopen-the-workplace-could-look-very-different/">As tech offices begin to reopen, the workplace could look very different</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As tech offices begin to reopen, the workplace could look very different&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/as-tech-offices-begin-to-reopen-the-workplace-could-look-very-different/embed/#?secret=auE1LYMVv6" data-secret="auE1LYMVv6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/yc-backed-deskimo-an-on-demand-coworking-space-app-launches-in-singapore-and-hong-kong/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177313</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NHTSA urges some Chevy Bolt owners to park their car away from home, citing fire risk</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/nhtsa-urges-some-chevy-bolt-owners-to-park-their-car-away-from-home-citing-fire-risk/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/nhtsa-urges-some-chevy-bolt-owners-to-park-their-car-away-from-home-citing-fire-risk/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 22:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chevrolet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chevrolet bolt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nhtsa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recall]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chevrolet Bolts are back in the news &#8212; this time for another consumer alert issued by the National Highway Traffic and Safety Administration, less than a year after the agency issued a recall for a similar issue. NHTSA is recommending owners of Model Year 2017-2019 park their Bolts away from homes due to the risk [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Chevrolet Bolts are back in the news &#8212; this time for another consumer alert issued by the National Highway Traffic and Safety Administration, less than a year after the agency issued a recall for a similar issue.</p>
<p>NHTSA is recommending owners of Model Year 2017-2019 park their Bolts away from homes due to the risk of fire. Those are the same vehicles that were recalled in November 2020, due to the possibility of fire from the battery pack underneath the backseat’s cushion. The recall affected 50,932 2017-2019 Chevy Bolt vehicles.</p>
<p>But this recall seems to have been triggered by two recent fire incidents in vehicles that were supposedly remedied as part of that previous safety recall, General Motors said on its website.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Out of an abundance of caution, we are asking owners of 2017-2019 Chevrolet Bolt EVs who were part of the recall population to park their vehicles outdoors immediately after charging and not leave their vehicles charging overnight while we investigate these incidents.”</p>
<p>GM says it has potentially identified a remedy to the battery anomalies, which customers can access by visiting a participating Bolt dealer. Customers of 2019 Bolts were able to access this remedy from April 29, and owners of 2017 and 2018 Bolts were eligible from May 26. The diagnostic software GM used to identify the anomalies will be standard in 2022 Bolts, and other future GM vehicles, the automaker said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZeB92EVpmS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/how-to-make-the-math-work-for-todays-sky-high-startup-valuations/">How to make the math work for today&#8217;s sky-high startup valuations</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to make the math work for today&#8217;s sky-high startup valuations&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/how-to-make-the-math-work-for-todays-sky-high-startup-valuations/embed/#?secret=ZeB92EVpmS" data-secret="ZeB92EVpmS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/nhtsa-urges-some-chevy-bolt-owners-to-park-their-car-away-from-home-citing-fire-risk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177829</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Citing data storage violations, India blocks Mastercard from onboarding new customers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/daily-crunch-31/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/daily-crunch-31/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 22:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177700</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for July 14, 2021. We have a jam-packed newsletter for you today, so we’re getting something out of the way up top. We’ve covered India’s technology regulatory market often in recent weeks. Why? Because the Indian startup scene is crazy busy. How India’s government handles the boom is going to be critical for a host of founders, investors and workers.</p>
<p>In that vein, the latest chapter in the story involves Mastercard, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/india-bans-mastercard-from-adding-new-customers/">which just got blocked from onboarding new users</a>. Why? Per our reporting, “noncompliance with local data storage rules.” Data rules, you will recall, are a big part of the changing regulatory world for Chinese startups as well. Something to keep an eye on! &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="U8A1n7vsfQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/india-bans-mastercard-from-adding-new-customers/">India bans Mastercard from adding new customers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;India bans Mastercard from adding new customers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/india-bans-mastercard-from-adding-new-customers/embed/#?secret=U8A1n7vsfQ" data-secret="U8A1n7vsfQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<p>Today’s Top 3 are all about social networks. Yes, the massive companies that we share our lives with, day in and day out. Let’s start with Facebook.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/facebook-is-shook-asks-for-removal-of-ftc-chair-khan-from-antitrust-cases-against-it/">Facebook, like Amazon, is not thrilled with the new U.S. antitrust boss:</a></strong> Lina Khan’s appointment as the head of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission (FTC) is causing waves among the largest tech companies in the world. Amazon demanded that she recuse herself from regulating its business. Facebook is now making similar noises. In short, the tech giants think that her prior criticism of their business practices is disqualifying. This is at once risible and notable; that a regulator has a perspective about, well, regulation seems more like a qualification than a disqualifying fact.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/facebook-creator-bonuses/">Facebook is also willing to buy creator love:</a></strong> Sticking to the Facebook world for a moment, the company announced a $1 billion fund that will be paid out to digital creators who produce work that lives on its platforms. The dollar amount is what we should pay attention to here; Facebook is willing to pay up for the sort of attention that TikTok has managed to accrue for free.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/twitter-is-shutting-down-fleets-on-august-3-citing-low-usage/">Twitter is killing Fleets:</a> </strong>The final bit of Hot New Social Media News is that Twitter is killing off its little-loved stories feature called Fleets. First, read the TechCrunch story, then enjoy <a href="https://twitter.com/MartinSFP/status/1415364172599136258">this fine tweet</a> and this <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577166/twitter-fleets-shuts-down-stories-clone">utterly perfect subheadline</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Really though, are you going to miss Fleets? No.</p>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>We have a lot to get into from the startup world today, starting with two pieces looking at the subject from a more meta level. Then we have a grip of neat new rounds for your enjoyment:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/how-to-make-the-math-work-for-todays-sky-high-startup-valuations/"><strong>How to make today’s high-flying startup valuations work:</strong></a><strong> </strong>I wrote this earlier today to distill some conversations I’ve had with investors and founders about today’s startup valuations, and how the high prices being paid may work out for both founders and venture capitalists. They may not! But here’s a bullish take.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/lg-chem-will-invest-5-2b-in-battery-materials-through-2025/"><strong>Billions for battery tech:</strong></a> LG Chem is planning on spending some $5.2 billion on battery tech in the next four years. That’s more than $1 billion per <em>year</em>. This move details just how hot this sector is. Hell, it’s even <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/1-ev-battery-maker-ses-104454594.html">minting SPACs</a> for companies with revenue still years in the future.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/crypto-startup-phantom-banks-funding-from-andreessen-horowitz-to-scale-its-multi-chain-wallet/"><strong>a16z not done investing in crypto:</strong></a><strong> </strong>That’s the news today, with the venture firm leading a $9 million Series A into Phantom, which Lucas describes as a “crypto wallet startup.” Recall that a16z has reloaded its venture cannon <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/a16zs-new-2-2b-fund-wont-just-bet-on-the-crypto-future-it-will-defend-it/">with fresh crypto-focused funds</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/flymachine-raises-21-million-to-built-a-virtual-concerts-platform-for-a-post-pandemic-world/"><strong>$21M for virtual concerts:</strong></a><strong> </strong>One nice thing about the pandemic was musical acts putting on neat virtual shows. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=veqQXYhJNeg">Here’s an example</a>. Now FlyMachine has lots of money to “capture some of the magic of live concerts and performances in a livestreamed setting.” Yes, please &#8212; that sounds amazing.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/cybereason-raises-275m-at-series-f-adds-steven-mnuchin-to-board/"><strong>More money for cybersecurity:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Life has three absolutes: death, taxes and huge new cybersecurity rounds. Today’s is a $275 million Series F for Cybereason, which works in the extended detection and response (XDR) space.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/m1-finance-raises-150m-in-softbank-led-series-e-boosts-valuation-to-1-45b/"><strong>Meet the newest Midwest unicorn:</strong></a><strong> </strong>It’s M1 Finance, a startup that TechCrunch has covered extensively in the last year. Why? Because the company built a finance superapp that has proven very attractive to users. The company now has $150 million more under its belt &#8212; the new funds come just four months after it raised $75 million! &#8212; and $4.5 billion in assets under management.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/next-gen-foods-to-launch-its-plant-based-chicken-in-the-u-s-after-raising-a-20m-seed-extension-from-investors-like-ggv/"><strong>Finally, more money for fake meat:</strong></a> Raising animals is a pretty inefficient way to generate calories for consumption, and it’s hell on the environment. That’s why investors are pouring capital into fake meat companies. Next Gen Foods announced today that it has raised a $20 million seed extension (yep) for its “plant-based chicken alternative,” TechCrunch reports.</li>
</ul>
<h2>How to navigate an acquisition without alienating your current employees</h2>
<p>Now that COVID-19 vaccines are encouraging the world to reopen, two trends are underway:</p>
<p>In the first half of 2021, mergers and acquisitions increased by more than 150% YOY to $2.4 trillion; in several surveys, an overwhelming majority of workers said they intend to seek employment elsewhere.</p>
<p>If your startup is angling toward an exit, the promise of a big payday may not be enough to retain employees who feel burned out or dissatisfied.</p>
<p>Many founders don&#8217;t have prior management experience, and, frankly, the uncertainty associated with an exit makes it a poor time for on-the-job learning. With that in mind, here are several communication strategies that can help you keep your winning team intact.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="McwJvtWLEC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/how-to-navigate-an-acquisition-without-alienating-your-current-employees/">How to navigate an acquisition without alienating your current employees</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to navigate an acquisition without alienating your current employees&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/how-to-navigate-an-acquisition-without-alienating-your-current-employees/embed/#?secret=McwJvtWLEC" data-secret="McwJvtWLEC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> <em>You can sign up here</em></a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>Sure, we covered a lot of Big Tech news up top, but there’s even more to get to:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/amazon-launches-its-mobile-first-kindle-vella-serialized-story-platform/">Remember Kindle?</a></strong> Amazon has put together a new Kindle service to allow for serialized fiction. Which is super cool. Even better, the service is now live. It’s called Kindle Vella. Anything that gives authors more creative room is good by me.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/twilios-new-tools-will-let-anyone-add-live-video-and-audio-to-their-apps/">Twilio wants to help you add audio, video to your app:</a> </strong>API-delivered service trendsetter Twilio has announced Twilio Live, a service that will help developers embed live audio and video into their apps. Details are a bit scarce so far, but there are startups working on related products, so it will be interesting to see how this market shares out.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/microsoft-launches-windows-365/"><strong>Microsoft built cloud Windows while no one was looking:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Redmond has a new service out called Windows 365 &#8212; which is not <em>Microsoft</em> 365, the rebrand of its Office 365 service. Windows 365 will allow companies to stream Windows to devices. Frederic reports that “Windows 365 has been long expected and is really just an evolution of existing remote desktop services.” We still think it’s neat, however.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Are you all caught up on last week’s coverage of growth marketing? If not, read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/growth-marketing-roundup-cool-saas-marketing-lies-vr-ads-and-more/">here</a>.</p>
<p>As usual, if you have a recommendation of a growth marketer we should know about, <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">fill out the survey here.</a></p>
<p>Read one of the testimonials we received below!</p>
<p><strong>Marketer: </strong>Mitch Causey, <a href="https://www.demandwell.com/">Demandwell</a></p>
<p><strong>Recommended by:</strong> Drew Beechler, <a href="https://highalpha.com/">High Alpha</a></p>
<p><strong>Testimonial: “</strong>Mitch and the Demandwell team are some of the smartest content, SEO and digital marketers I&#8217;ve ever met, and their results speak for themselves. Their process, proprietary software and expertise around organic search and content is some of the best out there in helping companies think about organic search as a repeatable, proven method for growth and demand gen. Mitch and the Demandwell playbook worked so well that after being a client for two years and recommending to many in our portfolio, High Alpha ended up bringing Demandwell into the portfolio to turn their playbook into a scalable software platform.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KdjwviGRv6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/growth-marketing-roundup-cool-saas-marketing-lies-vr-ads-and-more/">Growth marketing roundup: Cool SaaS, marketing lies, VR ads and more</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Growth marketing roundup: Cool SaaS, marketing lies, VR ads and more&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/growth-marketing-roundup-cool-saas-marketing-lies-vr-ads-and-more/embed/#?secret=KdjwviGRv6" data-secret="KdjwviGRv6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/daily-crunch-31/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177700</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Khosla&#8217;s Adina Tecklu breaks down how to nail your pitch</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/khoslas-adina-tecklu-breaks-down-how-to-nail-your-pitch/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/khoslas-adina-tecklu-breaks-down-how-to-nail-your-pitch/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 21:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canaan Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Early Stage 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[event recap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundraising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Khosla Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pitch decks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pitching]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176424</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It's so critical to frame the problem from your perspective. And I also think that this is a really great opportunity to introduce emotion to really build a more compelling story.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Pitching is perhaps the single most important skill that any founder needs to hone, so not surprisingly, we kicked off our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/">TechCrunch Early Stage 2021 — Marketing &amp; Fundraising</a> event with a deep dive on all the tips and tricks required to get the most out of pitching and slide decks. On hand was <a href="https://www.khoslaventures.com/team/adina-tecklu">Adina Tecklu</a>, a principal at Khosla Ventures, and who formerly built out Canaan Beta, the consumer seed practice at Canaan Partners.</p>
<p>We talked about the importance of knowing your customer (aka your potential investor), focusing on story, typical slides in a deck, the appendix slides, formatting, and then alternative formats and which to avoid in a pitch deck.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Help TechCrunch find the best growth marketers for startups. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">this quick survey</a> and we&#8217;ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="Know your customer, in this case, your investor">Know your customer, in this case, your investor</h2>
<p>We kicked off our discussion with advice that remains as valuable as it is obvious. Even today, despite the wealth of resources available on the internet to background research potential investors, founders regularly walk into their pitch meetings like deer in headlights with no sense of that particular investor’s interests, tastes, stage of investment and more. Don’t be that founder.</p>
<blockquote><p>Key number one is know your audience. The best founders understand their users, whether that is an end consumer, or an enterprise customer. They&#8217;ve done the research to understand what motivates their customers, how they make buying decisions, and also what their customers like and don&#8217;t like as much about their own product. When fundraising, your VC essentially becomes your customer. And so before you begin pitching, or even building your deck, it&#8217;s really important to do your research beforehand to understand the firms and the partners that you intend to pitch. <em><b>(Timestamp: 2:25)</b></em></p></blockquote>
<p>If you do that right,</p>
<blockquote><p>That knowledge allows you to proactively address any concerns that they might have. And really make sure that you position your business in a way that is both authentic, but in a way that will be well received by the VC. <em><b>(Timestamp: 3:20)</b></em></p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/28/six-things-venture-capitalists-are-looking-for-in-your-pitch/">Six things venture capitalists are looking for in your pitch</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/07/what-to-expect-when-pitching-european-vcs/">What to expect when pitching European VCs</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/21/should-you-pay-50k-for-your-pitch-deck-yes-why-the-hell-not/">Should you pay $50K for your pitch deck? Yes, why the hell not?</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Story-driven, not data-driven">Story-driven, not data-driven</h2>
<p>Data is the most important source of wisdom in Silicon Valley, or so the belief holds. But the reality, particularly in early-stage investing, is that the data can only paint a partial picture of a startup and a founder’s ambition. Don’t let a dense copse of trees occlude the wider forest, which is what investors are really investing in.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/khoslas-adina-tecklu-breaks-down-how-to-nail-your-pitch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176424</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clubhouse ventures beyond audio with Backchannel, a new messaging feature</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/clubhouse-dms-backchannel/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/clubhouse-dms-backchannel/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 21:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[live audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We knew DMs were on the way to Clubhouse and today the new feature landed, spicing up the audio-only app with a text-based chat feature. Clubhouse&#8217;s new direct messaging system, called &#8220;Backchannel,&#8221; gives users an oft-requested way to start conversations behind the scenes on the social audio app. Backchannel offers both one-on-one messaging as well [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/clubhouse-dms-text-chat/">knew DMs were on the way to Clubhouse</a> and today the new feature landed, spicing up the audio-only app with a text-based chat feature. Clubhouse&#8217;s new direct messaging system, called &#8220;Backchannel,&#8221; gives users an oft-requested way to start conversations behind the scenes on the social audio app.</p>
<p>Backchannel offers both one-on-one messaging as well as group chat and generally adds quite a bit of utility into the voice-only social network. Speakers can organize in advance or coordinate live through messaging while running a room. They can also accept text-based questions, which some listeners are probably more comfortable with.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">My hat? Tipped<br />My mic? Flashed<br />My messaging? Direct.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>After we unintentionally leaked their feature 5 times, here&#39;s our beloved engineering team introducing the new Clubhouse Backchannel <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f970.png" alt="🥰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/3bPHeGxQaZ">pic.twitter.com/3bPHeGxQaZ</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Clubhouse (@Clubhouse) <a href="https://twitter.com/Clubhouse/status/1415356229430304770?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 14, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Clubhouse users can send links but not images or videos through Backchannel for now, but it sounds like more new features are just around the corner. The messaging system also includes a message request area where communication from people you don&#8217;t know lives until you approve it. So far, Clubhouse&#8217;s DMs are focused on chatting with people you know or people you&#8217;d like to know. Without a roomwide text chat option, the main action will remain firmly centered in voice-based rooms.</p>
<p>The messaging system is live now across Clubhouse&#8217;s iOS and Android apps. To start a DM — fine, a &#8220;Backchannel&#8221; — look for the little paper airplane icon on anybody&#8217;s profile page or swipe right from the main menu to pull it up. One thing worth noting: It doesn&#8217;t look like you can delete messages yet (though you can copy or report them!), so be sure you really mean whatever it is that you&#8217;re backchanneling about.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SyFMQXzzIN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/clubhouse-ux-teardown-a-closer-look-at-homepage-curation-follow-hooks-and-other-features/">Clubhouse UX teardown: A closer look at homepage curation, follow hooks and other features</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Clubhouse UX teardown: A closer look at homepage curation, follow hooks and other features&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/clubhouse-ux-teardown-a-closer-look-at-homepage-curation-follow-hooks-and-other-features/embed/#?secret=SyFMQXzzIN" data-secret="SyFMQXzzIN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Gn1mXOUyWN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/09/clubhouse-android-app-launch/">Clubhouse finally launches its Android app</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Clubhouse finally launches its Android app&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/09/clubhouse-android-app-launch/embed/#?secret=Gn1mXOUyWN" data-secret="Gn1mXOUyWN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/clubhouse-dms-backchannel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177731</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Could Cloud PCs be Microsoft&#8217;s gateway to Chromebook-like hardware?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/could-cloud-pcs-be-microsofts-gateway-to-chromebook-like-hardware/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/could-cloud-pcs-be-microsofts-gateway-to-chromebook-like-hardware/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 21:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chromebooks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft 365]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Office]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PCs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177638</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When Microsoft announced this morning that it was releasing a cloud PC service called Windows 365, it got me thinking. While Windows 365 is about packaging a virtual Windows business desktop in a cloud context, if you think about the announcement in a different way, perhaps it could herald the beginning of a lightweight, cloud-based [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When Microsoft announced this morning that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/microsoft-launches-windows-365/">it was releasing a cloud PC service called Windows 365</a>, it got me thinking. While Windows 365 is about packaging a virtual Windows business desktop in a cloud context, if you think about the announcement in a different way, perhaps it could herald the beginning of a lightweight, cloud-based version of Windows &#8212; something that has been talked about for some time.</p>
<p>To be clear, the cloud PC announcement wasn&#8217;t related to hardware at all. It&#8217;s taking a Windows desktop and moving it fully virtualized to the cloud, where you can run it from anywhere, giving you a replica of your Windows desktop PC in the cloud. But what if you stretched that idea a bit by taking Microsoft 365 with Office apps and threw it onto a low-cost PC and used the Edge browser as your primary way of interacting with the computer? Now you have something that could compete directly with a Chromebook-style computer.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s exactly what Google has done with Chrome and Chromebooks for over a decade, working with partners to deliver low-cost hardware with most required compute work taking place in the cloud. The Chrome browser is the primary desktop environment; Google Workspace (aka G Suite) is the default set of office suite apps with word processor, spreadsheet and presentation software along with email and calendar and other services. In fact, you can run any software service you wish in Chrome, including Microsoft&#8217;s cloud office tools. Regardless, the end-result of this is a low-end business (or personal) laptop that gets most of its power from the cloud.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Most people don&#8217;t need a modern notebook computer, and the hardware required to run full-strength operating systems contributes to the high cost of the underlying machine, something Google discovered long ago. If you simplified everything to a browser, an office suite and web access to your favorite tools, you would have just about everything you need without all of the management headaches associated with owning a PC with a traditional OS sitting on it.</p>
<p>Think about the person who just uses email, office tools and watches a little Netflix. This kind of machine would be perfect for them without blowing their budget out of the water or being overly complex.</p>
<p>Last year when the pandemic hit and everyone had to hunker down and work on a PC, including children, people went looking for a low-cost option. They voted for Chromebook in droves, <a href="https://www.canalys.com/newsroom/canalys-global-pc-market-Q4-2020">accounting for more than 30 million units sold</a>, including over 11 million in the fourth quarter alone, according to Canalys data.</p>
<p>While growth slowed a bit in the first quarter of this year, Canalys found <a href="https://canalys.com/newsroom/canalys-global-pc-q1-2021">Chromebook shipments still grew by 275%</a>. Brian Lynch, an analyst at Canalys, wrote in the report that “Chromebooks are well and truly a mainstream computing product now,&#8221; adding that &#8220;while the education sector still accounts for the majority of shipments, their popularity with consumers and traditional commercial customers has reached new heights over the course of the last year.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8jgf6ulTQs"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/04/after-5-years-microsoft-ceo-satya-nadella-has-transformed-more-than-the-stock-price/">After 5 years, Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella has transformed more than the stock price</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;After 5 years, Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella has transformed more than the stock price&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/04/after-5-years-microsoft-ceo-satya-nadella-has-transformed-more-than-the-stock-price/embed/#?secret=8jgf6ulTQs" data-secret="8jgf6ulTQs" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Windows did well too, but given the number of Chromebooks flying off the shelves &#8212; led by Lenovo and HP, two companies that also make machines running Microsoft software &#8212; a Windows-based cloud PC could give Chromebook a run for its money.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that, yes, there are low-cost Windows PCs out there &#8212; you can get <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/EVOO-11-6-Ultra-Thin-Notebook-HD-Display-Intel-Celeron-Processor-64GB-Storage-4GB-Memory-Front-Camera-HDMI-Windows-10-S-Microsoft-365-Personal-1-Year/759978816?wmlspartner=wlpa&amp;selectedSellerId=0&amp;&amp;adid=22222222227429711665&amp;wl0=&amp;wl1=g&amp;wl2=c&amp;wl3=512975689814&amp;wl4=pla-1217450159913&amp;wl5=9032951&amp;wl6=&amp;wl7=&amp;wl8=&amp;wl9=pla&amp;wl10=8175035&amp;wl11=online&amp;wl12=759978816&amp;veh=sem&amp;gclid=CjwKCAjwlrqHBhByEiwAnLmYUCWKiRYKkXWqnQpH2rX349pdyAkytK-iY1xEt7RD4nG8aqFxn9DsWxoCz8MQAvD_BwE&amp;gclsrc=aw.ds">one at Walmart for $149</a>, which competes price-wise with any Chromebook computer out there. But these lower-end Windows machines are still a full-fledged Windows PC and you still have to deal with all the management. From an IT (or personal use) perspective, Chromebooks are much easier to manage than Windows PCs.</p>
<p>Since Satya Nadella <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/02/04/microsofts-new-ceo-is-officially-satya-nadella/">came on board as CEO at Microsoft in 2014</a>, the company has shown a strong willingness to shift its focus away from the PC where it made its name (and its money) and move toward the cloud. So far, Redmond has done well moving in that direction, with its market cap recently breaking the $2 trillion threshold.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more, Microsoft&#8217;s cloud infrastructure <a href="https://www.srgresearch.com/articles/cloud-market-ends-2020-high-while-microsoft-continues-gain-ground-amazon">market share sits at around 20%</a>, more than doubling <a href="https://www.srgresearch.com/articles/microsoft-cloud-revenues-leap-amazon-still-way-out-front">where it was in 2014</a> when Nadella took over. Even more, the company had around <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/office-365-overtakes-google-apps-for-cloud-based-productivity-adoption-bitglass/">16% of cloud office suite market share in 2014</a>, a figure that has grown to 40% today. Google&#8217;s office suite is the fairest of them all, though, with almost 60%, <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/961105/japan-market-share-of-office-suites-technologies/">according to Statista</a>. That is due at least in part to its Chromebook sales pushing users toward its suite.</p>
<p>If Microsoft wants to dent that number, a good way to do that would be to create a cloud-based notebook that looks a lot like Chromebook, but with a Windows bent. It would mean eating into their traditional desktop PC OS dominance, but much like in 2014, it could be about trading a past with diminishing returns for a future with much more promising ones.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZzvMBb5IUu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/microsoft-launches-windows-365/">Microsoft launches Windows 365</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Microsoft launches Windows 365&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/microsoft-launches-windows-365/embed/#?secret=ZzvMBb5IUu" data-secret="ZzvMBb5IUu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/could-cloud-pcs-be-microsofts-gateway-to-chromebook-like-hardware/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177638</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Semiconductor wafer producer SK Siltron CSS to invest $300M in US to boost EV supply chain</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/semiconductor-wafer-producer-sk-siltron-to-invest-300m-in-us-to-boost-ev-supply-chain/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/semiconductor-wafer-producer-sk-siltron-to-invest-300m-in-us-to-boost-ev-supply-chain/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 21:17:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semiconductor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semiconductor wafers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semiconductors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sk siltron css]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177668</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States has fallen behind China and Europe in the production and adoption of electric vehicles, especially from 2017 to 2020, according to a study by the International Council on Clean Transportation. One important piece of the puzzle that the U.S. does have supremacy in, however, is the production of semiconductors, which are used [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p data-testid="paragraph-0">The United States has fallen behind China and Europe in the production and adoption of electric vehicles, especially from 2017 to 2020, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/29/the-us-is-falling-further-behind-china-and-europe-in-ev-production.html">according to a study by the International Council on Clean Transportation</a>. One important piece of the puzzle that the U.S. does have supremacy in, however, is <a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2021/02/16/semiconductors-us-china-taiwan-technology-innovation-competition/">the production of semiconductors</a>, which are used in everything from smartphones to computers to electric vehicles. Now, it might be strengthening that hold.</p>
<p data-testid="paragraph-0">SK Siltron CSS, a unit of South Korean semiconductor wafer manufacturer SK Siltron, announced Wednesday plans to invest $300 million and create up to 150 high-paying, skilled jobs in Bay County, Michigan, which is a couple of hours north of Detroit, the country&#8217;s first automaking haven. The wafer manufacturer already has a presence in nearby Auburn, so the new factory will more than double its employee base. Over the next three years, SK Siltron says its investment will provide manufacturing and R&amp;D capabilities of advanced materials for electric vehicles.</p>
<p data-testid="paragraph-0">SK Siltron CSS chief executive Jianwei Dong told <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/sustainable-business/sk-siltrons-us-unit-plans-300-million-investment-michigan-support-ev-growth-2021-07-14/">Reuters</a>, which first reported the news, the $300 million investment would &#8220;help develop a domestic EV supply chain based in Michigan because we have our end customers in nearby communities.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XmxkQ4UpCH"><p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/fords-30b-investment-in-electric-revs-up-in-house-battery-rd/">Ford’s $30B investment in electric revs up in-house battery R&#038;D</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ford’s $30B investment in electric revs up in-house battery R&#038;D&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/fords-30b-investment-in-electric-revs-up-in-house-battery-rd/embed/#?secret=XmxkQ4UpCH" data-secret="XmxkQ4UpCH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p data-testid="paragraph-0">This new investment comes amid an ever-increasing lineup of new electric vehicles and investments in electrification from American automakers, including legacy companies <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/gm-ups-electric-and-autonomous-vehicle-spending-to-27-billion-through-2025/">General Motors</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/fords-30b-investment-in-electric-revs-up-in-house-battery-rd/">Ford</a>, as well as Tesla and upstarts such as Rivian.</p>
<p data-testid="paragraph-0">It&#8217;s also joining the sticky pot of trade wars between China and the U.S.</p>
<p data-testid="paragraph-0">China has owned EV production globally, producing 44% of all vehicles made from 2010 to 2020, but the U.S. has put a strangle hold on semiconductors, <a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2021/06/22/biden-semiconductors-south-korea-china-trade-war/">consistently blocking China from acquiring other chipmakers</a>. Strong policies that both invest in EV production and spur demand have proven successful in both China and Europe, according to the ICCT report. The Biden administration&#8217;s call for $174 billion in funding to expand EV subsidies and charging networks could help the country catch up.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WG1PYbgqpm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/29/the-trump-administration-will-add-smic-chinas-largest-chipmaker-to-its-defense-blacklist-report/">The Trump administration will add SMIC, China&#8217;s largest chipmaker, to its defense blacklist: report</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Trump administration will add SMIC, China&#8217;s largest chipmaker, to its defense blacklist: report&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/29/the-trump-administration-will-add-smic-chinas-largest-chipmaker-to-its-defense-blacklist-report/embed/#?secret=WG1PYbgqpm" data-secret="WG1PYbgqpm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p data-testid="paragraph-0">&#8220;As we build toward a more sustainable future, it is important that we create new, robust supply chains in the U.S. to support our corporations and the end consumer,&#8221; said U.S. Secretary of Commerce <span class="xn-person">Gina M. Raimondo in a statement. &#8220;</span>The automotive industry has a tremendous opportunity with the rise of the electric vehicle, and we&#8217;re excited to see companies like SK Siltron CSS expanding to help support the transition to a green future.&#8221;</p>
<p data-testid="paragraph-0">The SK Siltron CSS expansion still needs approval from state and local authorities, the company said, although it&#8217;s unlikely it will meet much resistance. The Michigan Economic Development Corporation said the state has been trying to attract EV-related jobs, spending nearly $9 billion in investments over the last two years and adding more than 10,000 jobs for the EV transition. SK Siltron said as it works with the state and local agencies to find employees, 70% will be skilled workers and the rest will be professional engineers.</p>
<h2 data-testid="paragraph-0">Wafers 101</h2>
<p data-testid="paragraph-0">A wafer is a thin slice of semiconductor that&#8217;s used to make integrated circuits, which essentially help make semiconductor chips smaller and faster. The wafer serves as the base upon which the rest of the semiconductor is built, making it a crucial ingredient to the whole process. EVs need semiconductors because they allow batteries to operate at higher voltages, drive the powertrain and support modern car features like touchscreen interactivity.</p>
<p data-testid="paragraph-0">SK Siltron&#8217;s wafer is made of silicon carbide, which can handle higher powers and conduct heat better than normal silicon, the company says.</p>
<p data-testid="paragraph-11">&#8220;When used in EV system components, this characteristic can allow a more efficient transfer of electricity from the battery to the motor, increasing the driving range of an EV by 5% to 10%,&#8221; the company said in a statement.</p>
<p class="Text__text___3eVx1j Text__dark-grey___AS2I_p Text__regular___Bh17t- Text__large___1i0u1F Body__base___25kqPt Body__large_body___3g04wK ArticleBody__element___3UrnEs" data-testid="paragraph-1">The wafers can also be used in 5G communications equipment, and Dong told Reuters that the company is also considering additional investments.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vjVQkytp3f"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/28/semiconductors-in-2021/">2021 will be a calmer year for semiconductors and chips (except for Intel)</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;2021 will be a calmer year for semiconductors and chips (except for Intel)&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/28/semiconductors-in-2021/embed/#?secret=vjVQkytp3f" data-secret="vjVQkytp3f" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/semiconductor-wafer-producer-sk-siltron-to-invest-300m-in-us-to-boost-ev-supply-chain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177668</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Toyota&#8217;s Woven Planet acquires HD mapping startup Carmera</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/toyotas-woven-planet-acquires-hd-mapping-startup-carmera/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/toyotas-woven-planet-acquires-hd-mapping-startup-carmera/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 21:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carmera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mapping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toyota]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[woven planet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176510</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Woven Planet Holdings — an entity created by Toyota to invest in, develop and eventually bring future of transportation technologies like automated driving to market — has acquired HD mapping startup Carmera for an undisclosed amount. The announcement comes less than two months since Woven Planet Holdings acquired Lyft&#8217;s autonomous vehicle unit known as Level [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Woven Planet Holdings — an entity created by Toyota to invest in, develop and eventually bring future of transportation technologies like automated driving to market — has acquired HD mapping startup Carmera for an undisclosed amount. The announcement comes less than two months since Woven Planet Holdings acquired <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/lyft-sells-self-driving-unit-to-toyotas-woven-planet-for-550m/">Lyft&#8217;s autonomous vehicle unit</a> known as Level 5 for $550 million.</p>
<p>It also follows another HD mapping acquisition — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/nvidia-acquires-hi-def-mapping-startup-deepmap-to-bolster-av-technology/">Nvidia&#8217;s purchase of DeepMap</a> — that was announced in June.</p>
<p>Under terms of the deal, Carmera will become a wholly owned subsidiary of Woven Planet. The startup&#8217;s 50-person team will maintain its offices in New York and Seattle and will eventually be integrated into Woven Planet&#8217;s 1,000-person-and-growing enterprise, according to Woven Planet CEO James Kuffner.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Carmera will essentially become the U.S. outpost of Woven Planet&#8217;s automated mapping platform (AMP) team, which is headquartered in Tokyo. Ro Gupta, co-founder and CEO of Carmera, will report to Mandali Khalesi, who heads up AMP.</p>
<p>Carmera launched in 2015 with a barter-type business model that uses data collected from a service it provides for free to commercial fleet operators to maintain and expand its primary mapping product. Carmera&#8217;s main and initial product is a high-definition map developed for autonomous vehicle customers like automakers, suppliers and robotaxis. Autonomous vehicle startup Voyage, which was acquired this year by Cruise, was an early Carmera customer. Baidu also used Carmera&#8217;s technology to support the open-source Apollo mapping project.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GJ5TyVrzMt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/nvidia-acquires-hi-def-mapping-startup-deepmap-to-bolster-av-technology/">Nvidia acquires hi-def mapping startup DeepMap to bolster AV technology</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Nvidia acquires hi-def mapping startup DeepMap to bolster AV technology&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/nvidia-acquires-hi-def-mapping-startup-deepmap-to-bolster-av-technology/embed/#?secret=GJ5TyVrzMt" data-secret="GJ5TyVrzMt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The company uses data crowdsourced from its fleet-monitoring service product to keep those AV maps fresh. The fleet product is a telematics and video monitoring service used by professional fleets that want to manage risk and improve safety with their vehicles and drivers. These fleets of camera-equipped human-driven vehicles deliver new information to the autonomous map as they go about their daily business in cities.</p>
<p>Carmera has evolved its product lineup over time. It added a real-time events and change-management engine to its autonomous map and created a spatial data and street analytics product for cities and urban planners. Last year, Carmera launched its so-called Change-as-a-Service platform, a suite of products that detects changes and can be integrated into other third-party maps.</p>
<p>&#8220;The problem I&#8217;ve always had with some of the HD map companies is it&#8217;s nice that you have this capability, but until you can figure out how to scale it, host it and keep it updated, you&#8217;re stuck in the &#8216;I-have-a-neat-piece-of-software-that-someone-is-going-to-buy-from-me role,&#8217; &#8221; Mike Ramsey, VP analyst at Gartner said. &#8220;This deal solves Carmera&#8217;s scale problem.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2177740" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Cobra_Tokyo_PoC_animated.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2177740" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2177740 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Cobra_Tokyo_PoC_animated.gif" alt="Carmera Toyota" width="600" height="337" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2177740" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Carmera</p></div></p>
<p>While Carmera is tiny in size and capital compared to Woven Planet, those following the industry might have predicted this union.</p>
<p>Carmera has been working with Toyota Research Institute-Advanced Development, which was the impetus of Woven Planet, for three years. The startup first participated in a proof of concept project in Japan to develop camera-based automation of HD maps for urban and surface roads. The partnership expanded in 2020 to include mapping of roadways in Detroit and other roads in Michigan, as well as in Japan.</p>
<p>&#8220;It was really easy to invest a lot into the relationship,&#8221; Gupta said, reflecting on Carmera&#8217;s first partnership with Toyota in 2018. &#8220;The vision was just so similar; it&#8217;s almost eerie looking at our seed deck from five years ago and comparing it to what Woven Planet&#8217;s overall vision is and their vision for this automated mapping platform.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="B6kGT7zkyR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/lyft-sells-self-driving-unit-to-toyotas-woven-planet-for-550m/">Lyft sells self-driving unit to Toyota&#8217;s Woven Planet for $550M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lyft sells self-driving unit to Toyota&#8217;s Woven Planet for $550M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/lyft-sells-self-driving-unit-to-toyotas-woven-planet-for-550m/embed/#?secret=B6kGT7zkyR" data-secret="B6kGT7zkyR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Woven Planet (and by extension Toyota) already has satellite-based mapping and the massive amounts of data gleaned from its millions of vehicles on the road today. Carmera brings to Woven Planet&#8217;s portfolio the dynamic mapping piece as well as its experience in the commercial fleets and safety business.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;For me, there&#8217;s immediate near-term applications that we&#8217;ve already worked on as proofs-of-concept with Carmera, and that we haven&#8217;t yet announced, but are in the area of safety and automated driving,&#8221; Kuffner said, noting that the automaker&#8217;s new Lexus LS and Toyota Mirai models will offer an advanced driving assistance technology called Teammate that uses HP maps. &#8220;I&#8217;m really excited about that generation of products, but for fleets, absolutely. HD maps. There are a lot of applications in fleets.&#8221;</span></p>
<h2>What Woven Planet is weaving</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2177735" style="width: 1930px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/woven-city-prototype.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2177735" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2177735 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/woven-city-prototype.jpg" alt="woven city prototype" width="1920" height="1008" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/woven-city-prototype.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/woven-city-prototype.jpg?resize=150,79 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/woven-city-prototype.jpg?resize=300,158 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/woven-city-prototype.jpg?resize=768,403 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/woven-city-prototype.jpg?resize=680,357 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/woven-city-prototype.jpg?resize=1536,806 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/woven-city-prototype.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2177735" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Woven Planet/Toyota</p></div></p>
<p>The Lyft and now Carmera acquisitions represent a sliver of Woven Planet&#8217;s myriad activities since its formation in January 2021, as the automaker seeks a competitive edge against established rivals and upstarts, particularly on the software front. The entity, which is based in Tokyo and is a subsidiary of Toyota Motor Corp., includes two operating companies called Woven Alpha and Woven Core as well as a VC fund called Woven Capital. The holding company also has a project called Woven City, a testing ground for new technologies set in an interconnected smart city prototype. Toyota broke ground in February 2021 at future site of Woven City, the Higashi-Fuji site in Susono City, Japan, at the base of Mount Fuji.</p>
<p>The two operating companies are Woven Alpha and Woven Core, formerly Toyota Research Institute &#8212; Advanced Development Inc. Woven Core includes the mapping unit and is focused on automated driving while Woven Alpha is charged with developing new concepts and projects including the prototype city.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Woven Capital invests in those next-generation mobility innovations. The VC arm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/woven-capital-kicks-off-portfolio-with-investment-in-autonomous-delivery-company-nuro/">kicked off its new $800 million strategic fund</a> in March 2021 by announcing an investment into autonomous delivery vehicle company Nuro. Last month, Woven Capital invested an undisclosed amount into Ridecell, a transportation software startup that has developed a platform designed to help car-sharing, ridesharing and autonomous technology companies manage their vehicles.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jjfQJpxGpe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/woven-capital-kicks-off-portfolio-with-investment-in-autonomous-delivery-company-nuro/">Woven Capital kicks off portfolio with investment in autonomous delivery company Nuro</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Woven Capital kicks off portfolio with investment in autonomous delivery company Nuro&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/woven-capital-kicks-off-portfolio-with-investment-in-autonomous-delivery-company-nuro/embed/#?secret=jjfQJpxGpe" data-secret="jjfQJpxGpe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/toyotas-woven-planet-acquires-hd-mapping-startup-carmera/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176510</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon launches its mobile-first Kindle Vella serialized story platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/amazon-launches-its-mobile-first-kindle-vella-serialized-story-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/amazon-launches-its-mobile-first-kindle-vella-serialized-story-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Henry Pickavet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 19:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon-kindle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177620</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As it promised last month, Amazon has launched its serialized fiction Kindle Vella store that lets you unlock episodic, self-published stories via in-app purchases. The new platform is a way for readers to discover new fiction and a new way for authors to generate revenue from the Kindle Direct Publishing service. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Steve Dent</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Steve Dent is an associate editor at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">As it <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-kindle-vella-episodic-stories-113522440.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="18" data-v9y="1">promised</a> last month, Amazon has <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210713006218/en/Amazon-Launches-Kindle-Vella-Serialized-Stories-in-a-Mobile-First-Interactive-Reading-Experience/?feedref=JjAwJuNHiystnCoBq_hl-bsjWlVyeNLyq_m2tvaHJJaCbS9GfOaU05M3U1TVIJEgj_R0p0VFN6GsXdq8PYoIcFEYGffXvFUnUBNNmxNkJdnQqLx557vS7ZRxiEolcr-hVDp-2-rCtDK_aRLJhTuAhA==" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1">launched</a> its serialized fiction Kindle Vella store that lets you unlock episodic, self-published stories via in-app purchases. The new platform is a way for readers to discover new fiction and a new way for authors to generate revenue from the Kindle Direct Publishing service.</p>
<p>While the name might suggest otherwise, Kindle Vella isn&#8217;t available on Amazon&#8217;s Kindle e-readers. Rather, you&#8217;ll only find it on Amazon.com or the Kindle iOS app (no Android for now). To start with, the service will be limited to US-based authors who publish stories in English.</p>
<p>The serialized stories will run from 600 to 5,000 words per episode, with the first three offered for free. To see subsequent episodes, you&#8217;ll need to pay for &#8220;tokens,&#8221; with prices ranging from $2 for 200 tokens up to $15 for 1,700 tokens. The latter will give you about 34 episodes, though prices per episode depend on the word count — the more words, the more you&#8217;ll have to spend.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VjBoQrFgOms?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>Authors, meanwhile, will receive 50 percent of the revenue along with bonuses based on engagement with the app&#8217;s social media-style features. To that end, readers can follow stories to be notified of new episodes, leave a thumbs up for episodes they like, apply a &#8220;Fave&#8221; for their favorite story of the week (provided they purchase tokens), and share on Twitter, Facebook and other social media. To boost engagement, authors can speak directly to readers at the end of episodes to &#8220;share story insights and behind-the-scenes content,&#8221; Amazon wrote.</p>
<p>Since Amazon opened Vella to authors three months ago, &#8220;thousands of authors&#8221; have published &#8220;tens of thousands of Kindle Vella episodes across dozens of genres and microgenre,&#8221; Amazon said. Authors appear to be interested as well. &#8220;I’ve published close to 30 novels, and I’m enjoying the adventure of writing <em>The Marriage Auction</em> in this new format,” said bestselling author Audrey Carlan in a statement. Whether or not the format takes off now depends on readers — to try it out, you can access Vella <a href="https://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fkdp.com%2Fkindle-vella&amp;esheet=52458701&amp;newsitemid=20210713006218&amp;lan=en-US&amp;anchor=kdp.com%2FKindle-Vella&amp;index=10&amp;md5=35e4153bc11f4ea71707d449060f3d31" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This post originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-launches-its-kindle-vella-serialized-story-platform-085016781.html">Engadget</a>. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/amazon-launches-its-mobile-first-kindle-vella-serialized-story-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177620</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
