<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 18:01:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>John Deere buys autonomous tractor startup Bear Flag Robotics</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/john-deere-buys-autonomous-tractor-startup-bear-flag-robotics/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/john-deere-buys-autonomous-tractor-startup-bear-flag-robotics/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 18:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bear Flag Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Deere]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2186326</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the world of robotic startups, acquisition is often as good an outcome as any. And when it comes to robotic tractor startups, you could do worse than being acquired by John Deere. The agricultural technology giant announced today that it’s set to acquire Bear Flag Robotics for $250 million. The Bay Area-based firm, which [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In the world of robotic startups, acquisition is often as good an outcome as any. And when it comes to robotic tractor startups, you could do worse than being acquired by John Deere. The agricultural technology giant announced today that <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/john-deere-acquires-bear-flag-robotics-to-accelerate-autonomous-technology-on-the-farm-301349496.html">it’s set to acquire Bear Flag Robotics</a> for $250 million.</p>
<p>The Bay Area-based firm, which specializes in autonomous farming heavy machinery, was founded in 2017. They first crossed our radar the following year, as a member of YC’s Winter 2018 cohort.</p>
<p>“We got a tour of an orchard and just how pronounced the labor problem is,” co-founder Aubrey Donnellan told TechCrunch at the time. “They’re struggling to fill seats on tractors. We talked to other growers in California. We kept hearing the same thing over and over: Labor is one of the most significant pain points. It’s really hard to find quality labor. The workforce is aging out. They’re leaving the country and going into other industries.”</p>
<p>In the intervening years, John Deere tapped Bear Flag for its own Startup Collaborator initiative. And the robotics firm has also begun to deploy its technology to an undisclosed (“limited,” per their wording) number of sites in the U.S.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of the biggest challenges farmers face today is the availability of skilled labor to execute time-sensitive operations that impact farming outcomes. Autonomy offers a safe and productive alternative to address that challenge head on,&#8221; co-founder and CEO Igino Cafiero, says in a release. &#8220;Bear Flag&#8217;s mission to increase global food production and reduce the cost of growing food through machine automation is aligned with Deere&#8217;s and we&#8217;re excited to join the Deere team to bring autonomy to more farms.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gydubrZyQB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/07/volocopter-and-john-deere-team-up-for-a-crop-spraying-autonomous-agricultural-drone/">Volocopter and John Deere team up for a crop-spraying autonomous agricultural drone</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Volocopter and John Deere team up for a crop-spraying autonomous agricultural drone&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/07/volocopter-and-john-deere-team-up-for-a-crop-spraying-autonomous-agricultural-drone/embed/#?secret=gydubrZyQB" data-secret="gydubrZyQB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Agricultural is one of several robotics categories that have seen a spike in interest in the past year, due to labor shortages that predate but were exacerbated by the global pandemic. Of course, that interest doesn’t make anyone immune from the difficulties of launching a robotics startup.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Last month, apple-picking robotics firm Abundant<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/robotics-roundup-19/"> confirmed it was closing up shop</a>, noting, “After a series of promising commercial trials with prototype apple harvesters, the company was unable to raise enough investment funding to continue development and launch a production system,” the company noted at the time.</p>
<p>An acquisition seems like a reasonable outcome for a company like Bear Flag. The startup gains a lot of resources from its massive new owner, and its new owner adds some new tech to its portfolio. Indeed, John Deere has been pretty aggressively looking to expand into more cutting-edge technologies like robotics and drones in recent years.</p>
<p>Bear Flag will retain operations in the Bay Area.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RQvEtgGwt2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/19/bear-flag-robotics-wants-to-sell-an-autonomous-tractor-for-farms/">Bear Flag Robotics wants to sell an autonomous tractor for farms</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bear Flag Robotics wants to sell an autonomous tractor for farms&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/19/bear-flag-robotics-wants-to-sell-an-autonomous-tractor-for-farms/embed/#?secret=RQvEtgGwt2" data-secret="RQvEtgGwt2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="usd1NDn74S"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/farmland-could-be-the-next-big-asset-class-modernized-by-marketplace-startups/">Farmland could be the next big asset class modernized by marketplace startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Farmland could be the next big asset class modernized by marketplace startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/farmland-could-be-the-next-big-asset-class-modernized-by-marketplace-startups/embed/#?secret=usd1NDn74S" data-secret="usd1NDn74S" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/john-deere-buys-autonomous-tractor-startup-bear-flag-robotics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2186326</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Drunk-driving provision could fuel demand for driver detection technology</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/drunk-driving-provision-could-fuel-demand-for-driver-detection-technology/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/drunk-driving-provision-could-fuel-demand-for-driver-detection-technology/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 17:51:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nhtsa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nissan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toyota]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volvo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185332</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Companies developing driver detection technology could get a boost from a provision tucked inside the 2,702-page $1 trillion infrastructure bill that would require automakers to build into new cars technology that can tell if drivers have had a few cold ones. The provision in the bill, which is actually a piece of bipartisan legislation called [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Companies developing driver detection technology could get a boost from a provision tucked inside the 2,702-page <span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.epw.senate.gov/public/_cache/files/e/a/ea1eb2e4-56bd-45f1-a260-9d6ee951bc96/F8A7C77D69BE09151F210EB4DFE872CD.edw21a09.pdf">$1 trillion infrastructure bill</a> that would require automakers to build into new cars technology that can tell if drivers have had a few cold ones.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The provision in the bill, which is actually a piece of bipartisan legislation called the Reduce Impaired Driving for Everyone Act that was introduced in April 2021, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">would direct the U.S. Department of Transportation to establish a technology safety standard for automakers within three years. Automakers would then have another two years to comply and implement tech that detects and prevents drunk driving. Reuters was the first to</span><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-senate-bill-seeks-require-anti-drunk-driving-vehicle-tech-2021-08-02/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">notice the language</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the provision doesn’t dictate what type of tech has to be in these vehicles, industry experts believe that companies developing camera-based driver monitoring systems (DMS) stand to benefit the most. DMS systems are already mature in the auto industry, representing a technological byproduct of autonomous driving developments. While the auto industry explores self-driving cars as a way to drastically reduce road deaths in the future, advocates and regulators say there&#8217;s room to use some of this tech to solve problems that exist <em>now,</em> like drunk or distracted driving. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“What&#8217;s happening in the U.S. Senate this week potentially opens the door to a camera-based real-time solution, which will be the first time that the U.S. automakers will have the ability and the requirement to look at real-time physiological changes in your body that occur when you are inebriated,” Dr. Mike Lenné, chief science and innovation officer at Seeing Machines told TechCrunch. &#8220;There are distinct reliable changes to the way you scan the environment, to the way your eyes respond to stimuli, which is why the police use that ‘follow the finger’ test.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The system would have to monitor the performance of a driver to detect impairment and prevent or limit vehicle operation if impairment is detected; detect whether BAC (blood alcohol concentration) is equal to or greater than the legal limit, potentially preventing operation of the vehicle at all; or a combination of both systems. </span></p>
<p>Cameras aren&#8217;t the only solution that has been trotted out in recent years.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Driver Alcohol Detection System for Safety (DADSS) program, a technology that’s been developed in partnership between the Automotive Coalition for Traffic Safety and the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA), has advocated using a breath or touch-based approach to determine BAC levels. The touch-based approach involves measuring BAC through the skin&#8217;s surface by shining an infrared light through the driver&#8217;s fingertip.</span><a href="https://www.dadss.org/faq"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">According to DADSS</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the current timeline for bringing the breath-based approach to vehicles is by 2024, and the touch-based approach by 2025. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lenné argues that a camera-based approach would be far more successful than a breath or touch-based approach because BAC levels can rise within minutes. Someone could theoretically down a bunch of shots immediately before getting behind the wheel and it wouldn’t show up on a reading for several minutes. Or they could get wasted while driving. And BAC detection doesn’t help at all when it comes to drug-impaired driving. </span></p>
<h2>Europe versus U.S.</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moves are already being made in Europe to encourage automakers to include drunk driving detection technology, specifically through camera-based DMS approaches, whereas most of the discussion on this type of tech in the U.S. has been, until recently, focused on DMS for assisted driving and Level 2 autonomous driving and above. (According to the Society of Automotive Engineers, Level 2 autonomy means the vehicle has combined functions like steering and acceleration but requires the driver to remain engaged.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The U.S. provision could propel an industry that has already seen growth in recent years as automakers like GM and Ford implement hands-free advanced driver assistance systems.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“From an integration viewpoint, it’s actually not a step change at all from what the OEMs are doing right now for distracted driving and drowsy driving with camera-based DMS. It’s just another feature to offer, another algorithm on the chip, if you like,” Lenné said. </span></p>
<h2>Near-term tech</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Billions of dollars have gone into developing the technology to make AVs a reality but they are really far off,&#8221; Stephanie Manning, chief government affairs officer at Mothers Against Drunk Driving (MADD), told TechCrunch. &#8220;In the process, automakers have developed a lot of technology that can help us right now in terms of saving lives. If this passes, it&#8217;s going to be the biggest safety rulemaking that NHTSA has ever done in terms of lives saved, and it couldn&#8217;t have come at a better time. But the more we wait, the more we delay, the more people die.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The technology is not at all far from market, said Lenné, and he would know. Seeing Machines provides the DMS that is used in Super Cruise, GM&#8217;s hands-free advanced driver assistance system. Super Cruise, once relegated to just one Cadillac model, has expanded in capability and GM&#8217;s portfolio and is now in the Cadillac CT6, CT4, CT5, Escalade and Chevrolet Bolt. Seeing Machine&#8217;s tech is also used in the new Mercedes-Benz S-Class and EQS sedans.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Once it&#8217;s regulated, we can expect to see more entrants to the market because what this does is it creates a top-down demand,” said Lenné. &#8220;It takes it out of the consumers&#8217; hands and tells vehicles they must have these safety features, so the market size will increase dramatically, and so will the market opportunity.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>The global DMS market is estimated to surpass $2.1 billion by 2026, growing at a compound annual growth rate of 9.8% from this year, <a href="https://www.industryarc.com/Report/172/driver-monitoring-systems-global-market-report.html">according to IndustryARC</a>. Top-down demand due to regulations like the infrastructure bill will certainly increase demand, but it won&#8217;t make the problem easier to solve.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re trying to assess what&#8217;s going on in someone&#8217;s head, and that&#8217;s really different from having a forward-facing radar that&#8217;s trying to look at what&#8217;s 30 meters in front of you,&#8221; he said. &#8220;You&#8217;re trying to interpret whether or not this person is safe to drive. So it&#8217;s a really difficult technical problem to solve. Our company is 21 years old. Smart Eye has been around for over 10 years. Whilst the market size has increased dramatically, it&#8217;s a hard problem to solve as a new entrant.&#8221;</p>
<p>Newcomers will face competition from established and large Tier 1 suppliers like Seeing Machines and Smart Eye, a Swedish computer vision company that people familiar with the industry say works with Ford (Ford did not confirm or deny this). IndustryARC also names major players as Faurecia, Aptiv PLC, Bosch, Denso, Continental AG and others. But new players are finding their way into the scene, like Israel-based Cipia, formerly Eyesight Technology, and Sweden-based Tobii Tech.</p>
<h2>Room for growth in the market</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">More entrants to market means more advancements to the technology. Smart Eye&#8217;s recent acquisition of </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/emotion-detection-software-startup-affectiva-acquired-for-73-5m/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">emotion-detection startup Affectiva for $73.5 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> hints at the potential future applications of DMS in passenger vehicles. Today it might be distracted, drowsy or drunk driving, but in a few years DMS could detect other types of drug impairment, cognitive impairments or even road rage.</span></p>
<p>Tobii, an eye-tracker technology company, just announced its entrance into the DMS market, a space it&#8217;s been exploring for the past few years as it has watched the legislative changes happening first in Europe and now in the U.S.</p>
<p>While a new entrant to the automotive space, Tobii has been in the eye tracking space since 2001, working in industries like marketing, scientific research, virtual reality, gaming and more. Anand Srivatsa, Tobii&#8217;s division CEO, told TechCrunch he thinks one of the biggest challenges will be scaling across different populations, given the different eye shapes of different ethnicities, which he says puts Tobii at an advantage, even with its limited automotive experience.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8hdnxcuY6m"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/emotion-detection-software-startup-affectiva-acquired-for-73-5m/">Emotion-detection software startup Affectiva acquired for $73.5M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Emotion-detection software startup Affectiva acquired for $73.5M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/emotion-detection-software-startup-affectiva-acquired-for-73-5m/embed/#?secret=8hdnxcuY6m" data-secret="8hdnxcuY6m" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;Because of this long history, we have what it takes to deliver a full solution from a component level all the way to end software because we&#8217;ve done it in other parts of our business,&#8221; Srivatsa told TechCrunch. &#8220;Some of our automotive partners see that as a unique capability from Tobii where we can talk about the compute that is needed for eye tracking because we build our own asix, we&#8217;ve built our own sensor. We have end user software in some aspects of our business, so we understand the implications and the constraints of each of these parts of the stack, and we can work with them to create a more disruptive solution. And that&#8217;s something that I think is going to be quite important in this space. How do you reduce the total cost of the solution to allow it to scale efficiently across all cars?&#8221;</p>
<p>Srivatsa also said there&#8217;s room to extend into other spaces the biometrics or physiological signals that eye tracking yields, reconfiguring information based on outside road conditions or what else is going on in the car in a way that optimizes the tech to ensure drivers are spending the bulk of their time looking at the road.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“What I am hoping and dreaming for is technologies like forward collision warning, or blind spot warning or even the lane swerving warnings help me out when I need it most by understanding if I&#8217;m becoming complacent or tired, perhaps distracted, and then adjust how the systems perform, the warning timing and things like that, based on what I need in the moment,” Kelly Funkhouser, program manager of vehicle interface testing and head of connected and automated vehicles at Consumer Reports, told TechCrunch</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. “Counter to that is I would like it to not bother me and nag and annoy me when I am fully paying attention. I&#8217;m like ‘Yeah I know exactly what I&#8217;m doing, I am purposely driving over this line so that I don&#8217;t hit the mom and kids.’ ”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lenné said there&#8217;s a potential for driver monitoring systems that capture what is really going on inside of a car to become more personalized in order to provide a better driving experience. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I think in all of this, writing a better driving experience is absolutely pivotal,” said Lenné. “If it doesn’t do that, it risks not being accepted by the consumers.”</span></p>
<h2>Advancing existing ADAS tech</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Automakers have been a part of the conversation regarding drunk driving technology for years. Back in 2007,</span><a href="https://global.nissannews.com/en/releases/release-95e86dba49c0e8277e3c7b662e6aac68-070803-02-e"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Nissan revealed a drunk driving concept car</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that would use alcohol odor sensors, facial monitoring and vehicle operational behavior to detect driver impairment.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the same year,</span><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/id/wbna16449687"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Toyota announced a similar system</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that it said would be in cars by 2009. More recently,</span><a href="https://www.motortrend.com/news/volvo-drunk-driving-distracted-cameras-sensors-safety/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Volvo announced in 2019</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that it would install cameras and sensors in cars to monitor drivers for signs of being drunk or distracted and then signal the vehicle to intervene, but that tech is designed for Volvo&#8217;s SPA2 architecture for hands-free driving, which hasn&#8217;t been released yet. The bottom line is without legislation mandating drunk driving prevention and detection, automakers haven’t really moved forward on implementing the tech, despite much of the building blocks being in place already. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Manning thinks that’s because automakers want to be able to upcharge for safety features. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Automakers want to test their supercomputers on the open road, but they don&#8217;t want to put the money and time and energy into solving drunk driving, because they don&#8217;t feel it&#8217;s their responsibility, and they don&#8217;t want this rule-making,” she said. “We fully expect that they&#8217;re going to fight us tooth and nail throughout the rule-making process.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Representatives from GM and Ford could not be reached for comment, but John Bozzella, president and CEO of the Alliance for Automotive Innovation, which worked with NHTSA on the DADSS program, told TechCrunch that the auto industry is committed to supporting public and private efforts to address this threat to road safety.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We appreciate the efforts of congressional leaders and other stakeholders to advance a legislative approach that provides NHTSA the ability to review all potential technologies as options for federal regulation and, consistent with the Motor Vehicle Safety Act, to make a well-informed decision as to whether any specific technologies meet the standard for consumer vehicles,” he said.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="M1KlaC72AH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/gm-is-bringing-its-upgraded-hands-free-super-cruise-driving-system-to-six-vehicles-in-2022/">GM is bringing its upgraded hands-free Super Cruise driving system to 6 vehicles in 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GM is bringing its upgraded hands-free Super Cruise driving system to 6 vehicles in 2022&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/gm-is-bringing-its-upgraded-hands-free-super-cruise-driving-system-to-six-vehicles-in-2022/embed/#?secret=M1KlaC72AH" data-secret="M1KlaC72AH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/drunk-driving-provision-could-fuel-demand-for-driver-detection-technology/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185332</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aduhelm approval sparks HHS watchdog review of FDA&#8217;s accelerated approval pathway</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/aduhelm-approval-sparks-hhs-watchdog-review-of-fdas-accelerated-approval-pathway/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/aduhelm-approval-sparks-hhs-watchdog-review-of-fdas-accelerated-approval-pathway/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Betuel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 17:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drug development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pharmaceuticals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thearpeutics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2186302</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) Office of the Inspector General will review the FDA’s accelerated approval pathway, the office announced Wednesday. This sweeping review comes just two months after the controversial approval of Biogen’s Alzheimer’s drug Aduhelm. The review will focus on the FDA’s accelerated approval pathway – a route that allows drugs [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) Office of the Inspector General will review the FDA’s accelerated approval pathway, the office announced Wednesday. This sweeping review comes just two months after the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/alzheimers-is-open-for-business-controversial-fda-approval-could-pave-the-way-for-future-drugs/">controversial approval of Biogen’s Alzheimer’s drug Aduhelm</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The review will focus on the FDA’s </span><a href="https://www.fda.gov/drugs/information-health-care-professionals-drugs/accelerated-approval-program"><span style="font-weight: 400;">accelerated approval pathway</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> – a route that allows drugs for serious diseases without existing treatments to be approved if they hit certain interim benchmarks (called surrogate endpoints). These drugs are thought to provide clinical benefit, but that benefit hasn’t actually been demonstrated before the drug is approved. Once the drug is approved, a phase four study would need to demonstrate clinical efficacy. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is the pathway that allowed for the highly </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/after-contentious-debate-fda-approves-first-alzheimers-drug-since-2003/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">controversial approval</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of Aduhelm, the first Alzheimer’s drug to be approved since 2003. It’s this approval that set the HHS-OIG review process in motion, per the Inspector General’s </span><a href="https://oig.hhs.gov/reports-and-publications/workplan/summary/wp-summary-0000608.asp"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wednesday announcement</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The FDA&#8217;s approval of Aduhelm raised concerns due to alleged scientific disputes within the FDA, the advisory committee&#8217;s vote against approval, allegations of an inappropriately close relationship between the FDA and the industry, and the FDA&#8217;s use of the accelerated approval pathway,” the announcement reads. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“In response to these concerns, we will assess how the FDA implements the accelerated approval pathway.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the FDA has </span><a href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMc2111960"><span style="font-weight: 400;">defended its decision</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to approve Aduhlem via this pathway, there has been significant backlash about the drug’s efficacy and how it got approved in the first place. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aduhelm, also known as aducanumab, </span><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nature19323'"><span style="font-weight: 400;">had demonstrated</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> it could reduce amyloid plaques in the brain (sticky compounds that disrupt communications between brain cells). However, there have been </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/after-contentious-debate-fda-approves-first-alzheimers-drug-since-2003/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">lingering questions</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> about how much patients actually benefited from the drug. It was unclear whether lowering levels of amyloid plaques would actually slow rates of Alzheimer’s most pernicious symptom: cognitive decline. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In March 2019, two phase three trials of the drug were </span><a href="https://www.alzforum.org/therapeutics/aduhelm"><span style="font-weight: 400;">shut down</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> after independent monitoring committees found that the drug wasn’t improving patients rates of cognitive decline. Another analysis conducted by Biogen in October, however, yielded different results. One phase three clinical trial of the drug did not show any improvements in cognitive decline, but the other trial did show some modest effects in patients who got the highest doses. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In November 2020 an independent FDA committee declined to endorse the drug for approval. Yet, by June 2021, the drug was approved anyway. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Within the pharmaceutical industry, the approval of Aduhelm initially </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/alzheimers-is-open-for-business-controversial-fda-approval-could-pave-the-way-for-future-drugs/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">sparked optimism</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that the FDA might open its doors to more biomarker-based approvals. However, that optimism wasn’t shared by the wider scientific community. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Three members of the independent committee that had advised against the drug’s approval </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/10/health/aduhelm-fda-resign-alzheimers.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">resigned in protest</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Based on the inconsistent data, major hospital systems like Mt. Sinai and the Cleveland Clinic have indicated they </span><a href="https://www.fiercehealthcare.com/hospitals/nyt-cleveland-clinic-mount-sinai-won-t-prescribe-controversial-alzheimer-s-disease-drug"><span style="font-weight: 400;">won’t prescribe the drug</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Part of the controversy around Aduhelm’s approval has centered around </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/19/health/alzheimers-drug-aduhelm-fda.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">allegations of an especially close working relationship</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> between the FDA and Biogen leading up to the drug’s approval. As </span><a href="https://www.statnews.com/2021/06/29/biogen-fda-alzheimers-drug-approval-aduhelm-project-onyx/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">STAT first reported</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Biogen launched an internal effort called Project Onyx to try to convince regulators to approve the drug, and some FDA officials eventually played active roles in the drug’s approval, including joint presentations before external experts. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a </span><a href="https://twitter.com/DrWoodcockFDA/status/1413540804962947072"><span style="font-weight: 400;">July 9 letter,</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Janet Woodcock, acting FDA Commissioner, called for HHS-OIG to conduct an external review that would investigate this working relationship.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We believe an independent assessment is the best manner in which to determine whether any interactions that occurred between the manufacturer and the agency’s review staff were inconsistent with FDA’s policies and procedures,” she wrote on Twitter. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the HHS-OIG investigation was spurred by the Aduhelm controversy, this review will not focus on reviewing the scientific evidence behind aduhlem (or any other drug, for that matter). Rather it will peek under the hood of the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">entire </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">accelerated approval pathway to assess how, and when, the FDA chooses to allow drugmakers to go down that road. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">HHS-OIG will review interactions between the FDA and outside parties, policies and procedures, and interrogate the FDA’s compliance with those procedures. The review will cover the Aduhelm review process but will also interrogate how the pathway was used to approve other drugs as well. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a </span><a href="https://twitter.com/DrWoodcockFDA/status/1422957204802506755?s=20"><span style="font-weight: 400;">statement on Twitter</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Woodcock also said that the FDA will “fully cooperate” with the HHS-OIG review. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“S</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">hould the HHS OIG identify any actionable items and provide the agency with any recommendations, the FDA would review those expeditiously to determine the best course of action,” she said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Should actions be required, they could have significant ramifications for drugs in the future, as this pathway is already an attractive option for other companies pursuing Alzheimer’s drugs. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eli Lilly, for instance, is also working on an Alzheimer’s drug called donanemab, has released </span><a href="https://investor.lilly.com/news-releases/news-release-details/lilly-releases-donanemab-data-demonstrated-relationship-between"><span style="font-weight: 400;">exploratory findings</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from a Phase II trial showing that the drug lowered levels of amyloid and other biomarkers, and was associated with patient improvements. However, the bulk of the results rest on the drug’s efficacy against biomarkers of Alzheimer’s, rather than individual patient outcomes. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a </span><a href="https://www.fool.com/earnings/call-transcripts/2021/08/03/eli-lilly-and-company-lly-q2-2021-earnings-call-tr/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Q2 earnings call this week</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Eli Lilly’s Senior Vice President and Chief Scientific Medical officer, Daniel M. Skovronsky,  noted that the FDA’s approval of Aduhelm “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">reflects a shift in policy and sets a new path for Alzheimer&#8217;s drug approval in the U.S,” and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eli Lilly still intends to file for FDA approval for donanemab using the FDA accelerated approval pathway by the end of the year. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But, that’s the same pathway that will now be under investigation by HHS-OIG. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still, we might not see results anytime soon, so it is unclear how this news will impact future Alzheimer’s drugmakers seeking to capitalize on a perceived “shift in policy.” The report is scheduled to be released in 2023. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="riPEHzs5sA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/alzheimers-is-open-for-business-controversial-fda-approval-could-pave-the-way-for-future-drugs/">&#8220;Alzheimer&#8217;s is open for business:&#8221; Controversial FDA approval could pave the way for future drugs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;&#8220;Alzheimer&#8217;s is open for business:&#8221; Controversial FDA approval could pave the way for future drugs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/alzheimers-is-open-for-business-controversial-fda-approval-could-pave-the-way-for-future-drugs/embed/#?secret=riPEHzs5sA" data-secret="riPEHzs5sA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/aduhelm-approval-sparks-hhs-watchdog-review-of-fdas-accelerated-approval-pathway/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2186302</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Qualcomm wants to buy Veoneer for $4.6B, beating Magna&#8217;s offer</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/qualcomm-wants-to-buy-veoneer-for-4-6b-beating-magnas-offer/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/qualcomm-wants-to-buy-veoneer-for-4-6b-beating-magnas-offer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 16:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ADAS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced driver assistance system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magna International]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qualcomm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Veoneer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2186280</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The $3.8 billion sale of Swedish automotive tech company Veoneer to Magna International hit a roadblock Thursday after chipmaker Qualcomm submitted a bid for the company for $800 million more. Qualcomm’s $4.6 billion bid, which comes in at $37 per share, has already received approval from the company’s board and would not need a stockholder [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The $3.8 billion sale of Swedish automotive tech company Veoneer to Magna International hit a roadblock Thursday after chipmaker Qualcomm submitted a bid for the company for $800 million more.</p>
<p>Qualcomm’s $4.6 billion bid, which comes in at $37 per share, has already received approval from the company’s board and would not need a stockholder vote, the chipmaker said in a statement. Veoneer and Magna said in July that both companies’ boards had approved the acquisition.</p>
<p>Veoneer is a developer of advanced driver assistance systems, decision-making vehicle hardware and software that can perform a limited set of actions under certain conditions, like changing lanes on a highway or emergency braking. While ADAS is a far cry from “self-driving cars,” it has become a popular &#8212; and attainable &#8212; set of features that are appearing in a greater share of new vehicles on offer today.</p>
<p>The burgeoning bidding war between Magna and Qualcomm is bullish on the future of ADAS technology, as each company seeks to stay competitive with Tier-1 ADAS suppliers Continental and Bosch. Qualcomm’s market capitalization currently sits at $164.8 billion, while Magna’s is $25.3 billion. It&#8217;s unclear whether Magna will submit a counter-bid.</p>
<p>The market has responded to the new bid, with the stock price of Veoneer rising nearly $7 per share, from $31.22 to $38.20 between Wednesday and Thursday. Prior to the announcement of the sale to Magna on July 23, Veoneer stock sat at $19.93 per share.</p>
<p>Veoneer was spun off from automotive safety system maker Autoliv in 2018. The company formed a joint venture with Volvo Cars, dubbed Zenuity, that was focused on advanced driver assistance systems. That venture was later split last July.</p>
<p>The ADAS developer also has a pre-existing relationship with Qualcomm. The two companies signed an agreement in January to collaborate on an ADAS platform.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="A9WSDRoFaE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/scale-ai-ceo-alex-wang-weighs-in-on-software-bugs-and-what-will-make-av-tech-good-enough/">Scale AI CEO Alex Wang weighs in on software bugs and what will make AV tech good enough</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Scale AI CEO Alex Wang weighs in on software bugs and what will make AV tech good enough&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/scale-ai-ceo-alex-wang-weighs-in-on-software-bugs-and-what-will-make-av-tech-good-enough/embed/#?secret=A9WSDRoFaE" data-secret="A9WSDRoFaE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/qualcomm-wants-to-buy-veoneer-for-4-6b-beating-magnas-offer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2186280</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yelp adds tools that let businesses share their COVID policies related to vaccines</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/yelp-adds-tools-that-let-businesses-share-their-covid-policies-related-to-vaccines/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/yelp-adds-tools-that-let-businesses-share-their-covid-policies-related-to-vaccines/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 16:23:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reputation management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yelp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2186148</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As more businesses around the U.S. are choosing to implement vaccine requirements for patrons or staff, business discovery and review site Yelp is introducing new tools that allow businesses to communicate those changes to their customers. On Thursday, Yelp will begin rolling out two profile attributes, &#8220;Proof of vaccination required&#8221; and &#8220;Staff fully vaccinated,&#8221; to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As more businesses around the U.S. are choosing to implement vaccine requirements for patrons or staff, business discovery and review site Yelp is introducing new tools that allow businesses to communicate those changes to their customers. On Thursday, Yelp will begin rolling out two profile attributes, &#8220;Proof of vaccination required&#8221; and &#8220;Staff fully vaccinated,&#8221; to help consumers to understand how a business is operating with regard to the pandemic.</p>
<p>While there is no federal mandate for businesses to require proof of vaccination, some cities are introducing their own policies. Recently, New York City became the first to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/03/nyregion/new-york-city-vaccine-mandate.html">require proof of vaccination for indoor restaurants and gyms</a>, and, San Francisco is <a href="https://abc7news.com/san-francisco-coronavirus-vaccine-francico-mandate/10928812/">now exploring</a> a similar set of mandates. Other cities may choose to follow suit in the future.</p>
<p>In addition, <a href="https://kutv.com/news/local/requiring-proof-of-vaccination-utah-business-owners-weighing-new-risks">local</a> <a href="https://fox59.com/news/coronavirus/indiana-business-leaders-urge-workers-to-get-covid-19-vaccinations-take-other-safety-precautions/">business</a> <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/business-owners-defend-their-decisions-to-require-vaccines-2021-8">owners</a> across the U.S. are implementing their own measures outside of federal or state guidance, including requiring masks or proof of vaccination for customers, or requiring their staff to be vaccinated. These choices often come at a price, as the businesses risk social media backlash and bad reviews from the anti-vaccine crowd.</p>
<p>Yelp&#8217;s new features will represent an attempt to help mitigate that reaction, the company explains.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2186277" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2186277" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2186277" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Vaccination-Attributes-on-Biz-Page.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Vaccination-Attributes-on-Biz-Page.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Vaccination-Attributes-on-Biz-Page.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Vaccination-Attributes-on-Biz-Page.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Vaccination-Attributes-on-Biz-Page.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Vaccination-Attributes-on-Biz-Page.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Vaccination-Attributes-on-Biz-Page.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Vaccination-Attributes-on-Biz-Page.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2186277" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Yelp</p></div></p>
<p>Yelp says it will proactively leverage a combination of automated systems and human moderators to safeguard businesses from attacks from customers if a business opts to activate either of the two new options related to their COVID vaccine policies.</p>
<p>Though the company has long since had <a href="https://trust.yelp.com/consumer-alerts/">systems</a> in place to address &#8220;review bombing&#8221; incidents, Yelp says the practice has gotten worse in recent months.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In the past, businesses that gained negative public attention may have had an influx of reviews from those who didn&#8217;t have a firsthand experience with the business in question, which violates Yelp&#8217;s policy. Yelp may then alert a visitor to the business&#8217;s page that there&#8217;s the potential for fake reviews or that there had been spikes in unusual activity. The company will sometimes even temporarily block users from being able to leave reviews. And in some cases, Yelp will also need to <a href="https://www.yelp-support.com/article/Will-Yelp-remove-a-false-or-defamatory-review">remove</a> false reviews or those that otherwise violate its policies.</p>
<p>But since January 2021, Yelp says it&#8217;s had to place over 100 <a href="https://trust.yelp.com/consumer-alerts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://trust.yelp.com/consumer-alerts/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1628112440794000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGLmzIXaNJ27RlgZGP96EsKslekxA">Unusual Activity Alerts</a> on its pages in response to a business gaining public attention for their COVID health and safety practices. This has included if a business notified customers that vaccinations were required for its employees or for its patrons.</p>
<p>As a result, Yelp has had to remove nearly 4,500 reviews for violating its content guidelines.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2186276" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2186276" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2186276" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Sees-Rise-in-Unusual-Activity-Alerts-Related-to-COVID-Precautions.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="518" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Sees-Rise-in-Unusual-Activity-Alerts-Related-to-COVID-Precautions.png 2496w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Sees-Rise-in-Unusual-Activity-Alerts-Related-to-COVID-Precautions.png?resize=150,114 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Sees-Rise-in-Unusual-Activity-Alerts-Related-to-COVID-Precautions.png?resize=300,229 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Sees-Rise-in-Unusual-Activity-Alerts-Related-to-COVID-Precautions.png?resize=768,585 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Sees-Rise-in-Unusual-Activity-Alerts-Related-to-COVID-Precautions.png?resize=680,518 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Sees-Rise-in-Unusual-Activity-Alerts-Related-to-COVID-Precautions.png?resize=1536,1170 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Sees-Rise-in-Unusual-Activity-Alerts-Related-to-COVID-Precautions.png?resize=2048,1561 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Sees-Rise-in-Unusual-Activity-Alerts-Related-to-COVID-Precautions.png?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2186276" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Yelp</p></div></p>
<p>As Yelp was already handling these types of incidents, it&#8217;s now more formally introducing a way for businesses to flag their COVID policies through the new products.</p>
<p>The company notes it put a similar system in place when it launched the <a href="https://blog.yelp.com/2020/06/yelp-teams-up-with-my-black-receipt-to-support-black-owned-businesses" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://blog.yelp.com/2020/06/yelp-teams-up-with-my-black-receipt-to-support-black-owned-businesses&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1628196935959000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHg6aPudWeRNDHcFJWW0ow0DPrMEA">Black-owned attribute</a> in June 2020 and again followed the same process for other identity attributes (e.g., <a href="https://blog.yelp.com/2020/09/yelp-partners-with-momento-latino-to-support-latinx-owned-businesses" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://blog.yelp.com/2020/09/yelp-partners-with-momento-latino-to-support-latinx-owned-businesses&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1628196935959000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEG6OAaDRC58UrPmKujvwcTcRGgEQ">Latinx-owned</a>, <a href="https://blog.yelp.com/2021/04/yelp-and-gold-house-partner-to-make-it-easier-to-support-asian-owned-businesses" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://blog.yelp.com/2021/04/yelp-and-gold-house-partner-to-make-it-easier-to-support-asian-owned-businesses&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1628196935959000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEKJzcRB2AAQm1ALLqLfpxo4gllZQ">Asian-owned</a> and <a href="https://blog.yelp.com/2021/05/yelp-makes-it-easy-to-support-lgbtq-owned-businesses" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://blog.yelp.com/2021/05/yelp-makes-it-easy-to-support-lgbtq-owned-businesses&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1628196935959000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGB4fYRUx9ntK3Ka7UEsazUy9pXYg">LGBTQ-owned</a>) by proactively monitoring business pages that activated these attributes for any hateful, racist or other harmful content that violated its content guidelines.</p>
<p>The company tells TechCrunch there was demand for its new COVID policy feature from business owners, as well.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2186274" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2186274" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2186274" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Vaccination-Attribute-Filters.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Vaccination-Attribute-Filters.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Vaccination-Attribute-Filters.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Vaccination-Attribute-Filters.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Vaccination-Attribute-Filters.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Vaccination-Attribute-Filters.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Vaccination-Attribute-Filters.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Yelp-Vaccination-Attribute-Filters.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2186274" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Yelp</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Both business owners and consumers have expressed interest in Yelp releasing vaccine-related attributes,&#8221; said Noorie Malik, Yelp&#8217;s VP of User Operations. &#8220;For many months we’ve seen businesses implement vaccine requirements for both their customers and staff. As a result, we’ve also seen a rise in reviews focused on people’s stance on COVID vaccinations rather than their actual experience with the business,&#8221; Malik noted.</p>
<p>The businesses want to be assured that their page will be more actively monitored for false reviews when they choose to share this information.</p>
<p>Yelp, of course, understands that if allowed its reviews platform to become a place that veered away from customers detailing their firsthand experiences, it service overall would become less useful.</p>
<p>&#8220;Yelp has always served as a trusted source of information on local businesses, helping the millions of people that come to Yelp every day make informed spending decisions,&#8221; Malik said. &#8220;It’s important that consumers have a resource for relevant firsthand information when engaging with a business. You could argue this is even more important during a public health crisis, making reviews from relevant firsthand consumer experiences critical.&#8221;</p>
<p>The feature is rolling out now and can be found on the <a href="https://business.yelp.com/">Yelp for Business</a> account page.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/yelp-adds-tools-that-let-businesses-share-their-covid-policies-related-to-vaccines/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2186148</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do bronze medals ever make sense for unicorns?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/do-bronze-medals-ever-make-sense-for-unicorns/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/do-bronze-medals-ever-make-sense-for-unicorns/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 16:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deliveroo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Ecommerce and D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Floodgate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GGV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hans tung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2186135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When should a startup decide to cease its efforts to challenge leading players in a specific market?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last week, Deliveroo <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/deliveroo-could-leave-spanish-market-ahead-of-on-demand-labor-reclassification/">made news</a> when it announced it was preparing to leave the Spanish market. The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/what-to-make-of-deliveroos-rough-ipo-debut/">recently listed</a> Deliveroo couched its explanation in market terms, noting its market position in Spanish on-demand delivery wasn&#8217;t sufficient to warrant continued investment. Left unmentioned: A <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/spain-agrees-on-labor-reform-that-will-recognize-delivery-platform-riders-as-employees/">Spanish legal change</a> requiring companies that previously depended on freelance couriers to hire their delivery staff.</p>
<p>Race Capital’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/hear-startup-alley-companies-pitch-expert-vc-judges-on-the-next-episode-of-extra-crunch-live/">Edith Yeung</a> helped explain the Deliveroo choice to The Exchange, saying the Spanish market doesn&#8217;t have a very large population, which may mean that the “potential upside for being #1 in Spain has [a] ceiling.”</p>
<p>While she noted that she doesn&#8217;t have access to Deliveroo data, her statement jibes with the company&#8217;s own comment that Spain made up less than 2% of its aggregate gross transaction value (GTV) in the first half of 2021.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>One company exiting a market is not a big deal, but we were curious about Deliveroo’s comments regarding the need for market leadership — or something close to it — to warrant continued investment. Is this the common reality for startups battling for market position, no matter if those markets are cities or countries?</p>
<p>Some startup markets have trended toward monopolies or duopolies. The Uber-Didi battle in China led to the companies agreeing to stop competing. Uber also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/03/uber-sold-its-food-delivery-business-in-india-to-zomato-for-206m/">recently sold its Uber Eats business in India to Zomato</a>. In the United States, Uber and Lyft&#8217;s smaller competitors have long been forgotten and both the American ride-hailing giants continue to battle for dominance.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995212 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>There are other familiar examples of this trend of consolidation. The food delivery game is concentrated amongst leading players. Postmates failed to survive as an independent company, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/06/uber-takes-out-postmates/">winding up as part of Uber’s operations</a>. Perhaps Gopuff will manage to claw out a spot in the market, but DoorDash and Uber Eats together accounted for 83% of the U.S. food delivery business in June this year, <a href="https://secondmeasure.com/datapoints/food-delivery-services-grubhub-uber-eats-doordash-postmates/">per Second Measure data</a>.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s no surprise that some startup markets lean toward monopolies or duopolies. Many countries protect intellectual property via patents that can constrain new innovation to one or two players for an extended period of time. Monopolies can also arise when a new technology or method of business is invented — Google’s internet parsing search tech led to a nigh-monopoly in many markets, for example.</p>
<p>In businesses where efficiencies of scale have a large effect, monopolies can form when leading players consolidate smaller competitors until just one or two companies remain. Standard Oil is the canonical example of this process.</p>
<p>What’s interesting about the on-demand delivery market is that it is both incredibly expensive but isn&#8217;t very technologically difficult to get into, which has meant that many companies have jumped into the sector around the world. This means on-demand delivery is the opposite of other patent-protected markets from which we might expect monopolies to form or competition to be extinguished past the top two players.</p>
<p>Yet, it’s also an industry where economies of scale can play a key role in profit generation, and increased competition can lead to price wars and advertising tussles. It’s a ripe market, then, for consolidation, even if it lacks an exploitable IP base.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/do-bronze-medals-ever-make-sense-for-unicorns/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2186135</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Allocations sees a world where myriad, smaller private equity funds are the norm</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/allocations-sees-a-world-where-myriad-smaller-private-equity-funds-are-the-norm/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/allocations-sees-a-world-where-myriad-smaller-private-equity-funds-are-the-norm/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 16:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2186139</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning Allocations, a fintech startup building software to help smaller private equity funds form and operate, announced that it has raised a $4 million round at a $100 million valuation. The startup also shared a host of performance metrics, including that it reached a $4.6 million revenue run rate in June, and a $6 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a href="https://www.allocations.com/">Allocations</a>, a fintech startup building software to help smaller private equity funds form and operate, announced that it has raised a $4 million round at a $100 million valuation.</p>
<p>The startup also shared a host of performance metrics, including that it reached a $4.6 million revenue run rate in June, and a $6 million bookings run rate in the same month.</p>
<p>Allocations also told TechCrunch that it has posted 28% monthly revenue growth over the last 12 months. With metrics like that, our curiosity was piqued. What is Allocations building that is attracting so much early demand? And how does the company&#8217;s thesis regarding the future of private equity funds intersect with microventure funds themselves?</p>
<h2>What Allocations does</h2>
<p>Born from CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kadvani/">Kingsley Advani&#8217;s</a> efforts in building a community of angel investors, and the issues that he ran into spinning up special purpose vehicles (SPVs), Allocations started off as software built to scratch its founder&#8217;s itch. SPVs are an increasingly common way to raise capital for a single investment from pooled sources, and in today&#8217;s rapid-fire venture capital market, Advani had to race to get capital into deals before they closed.</p>
<p>As with many technology startups, Allocations is software designed to solve a known pain point. The old way of putting together SPVs just didn&#8217;t match the expected pace at which private investors are expected to commit to investing.</p>
<p>Today the startup&#8217;s software helps its users to create new SPVs and funds more quickly, also helping investors manage capital calls and the like after their fund is formed. The startup <a href="https://www.allocations.com/pricing">charges</a> either one-time (in the case of an SPV, by definition a single-shot investment), or recurring fees (multiasset SPVs and funds). A 30-investment fund will cost its managers $15,000 per year through Allocations.</p>
<p>But how many funds are there for the startup to support? Is there enough market to allow Allocations to become a large enterprise itself? So far, the company has attracted some 300 funds to its roster. Advani thinks that there will be plenty of demand. In an interview with TechCrunch, the founder noted that present-day denizens of major funds locked out of material carry &#8212; venture economic upside, more simply &#8212; can peel off and start their own fund, allowing them much better economics. That dynamic could spur demand for his startup&#8217;s services.</p>
<p>Advani also said that family offices and other major capital pools that once fought for allocation into brand-name venture capital funds and other private equity vehicles &#8212; venture capital is a subset of private equity &#8212; are increasingly chasing smaller funds that may post better returns than larger investing partnerships can manage. This is the law of large numbers in reverse; it&#8217;s easier to 10x a $10 million fund than a $10 billion vehicle.</p>
<p>Advani expects his customers will put together multiple funds. Per the CEO, the goal of new fund managers is to get to their second fund. So, new managers often invest their first fund quickly in hope of reaching their second more quickly &#8212; more funds means more fees for Allocations.</p>
<p>In the startup&#8217;s view, the market will see many more small-scale private equity funds in time, perhaps smaller than $10 million in capital. This perspective mirrors what TechCrunch has seen in the market lately, with rolling funds rising to prominence in the early-stage startup investing, and solo GPs putting together what feels like more microfunds than ever.</p>
<p>Allocations fits into the larger trend of fintech startups taking antiquated models in the world of money and making them faster, more modern and often lower cost. Sure, there&#8217;s miles of distance between Allocations and Robinhood, but as both are about smaller investors, democratization of investing access, and using tech to tear down old walls, they are more brethren than different species.</p>
<p><em><strong>Update:</strong> It&#8217;s a $4 million round, not $5 million. Post has been corrected.</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GFO3evmkCi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/how-public-markets-can-help-address-venture-capitals-limitations/">How public markets can help address venture capital&#8217;s limitations</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How public markets can help address venture capital&#8217;s limitations&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/how-public-markets-can-help-address-venture-capitals-limitations/embed/#?secret=GFO3evmkCi" data-secret="GFO3evmkCi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/allocations-sees-a-world-where-myriad-smaller-private-equity-funds-are-the-norm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2186139</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Automakers urge greater government investment to meet Biden&#8217;s EV sales target</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/automakers-urge-greater-government-investment-to-meet-bidens-ev-sales-target/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/automakers-urge-greater-government-investment-to-meet-bidens-ev-sales-target/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 15:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BMW]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[donald trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiat-chrysler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe Biden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stellantis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volkswagen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volvo Cars]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2186144</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden is expected to set an ambitious new target for half of all new auto sales in the U.S. to be low- or zero-emission by 2030, a plan that has received tentative support from the Big Three automakers pending what they say will require hefty government support. General Motors, Ford and Stellantis (formerly [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">President Joe Biden is expected to set an ambitious new target for half of all new auto sales in the U.S. to be low- or zero-emission by 2030, a plan that has received tentative support from the Big Three automakers pending what they say will require hefty government support.</p>
<p>General Motors, Ford and Stellantis (formerly Fiat Chrysler) issued a joint statement Thursday that they had “shared aspiration[s]” to achieve a 40% to 50% share of electric in new vehicle sales by the end of the decade, with the caveat that such a target “can be achieved only with the timely deployment of the full suite of electrification policies committed to by the Administration in the Build Back Better Plan.”</p>
<p>Some of the investments they list include consumer incentives, a national EV charging network “of sufficient density,” funding for R&amp;D and manufacturing and supply chain incentives.</p>
<p>Biden’s target, which will come in the form of an executive order on Thursday, will be nonbinding and entirely voluntary. The target includes vehicles powered by batteries, hydrogen fuel cells or plug-in hybrids.</p>
<p>Executives from the three OEMs, as well as representatives from the United Automobile Workers union, are expected to attend an event on the new target at the White House Thursday. Tesla, it seems, was not invited, according to a tweet from CEO Elon Musk.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Yeah, seems odd that Tesla wasn’t invited</p>
<p>— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1423156475799683075?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2021</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>Biden will also be calling for new fuel economy standards for passenger and medium- and heavy-duty vehicles through model year 2026, which were rolled back under President Trump’s tenure, according to a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-steps-to-drive-american-leadership-forward-on-clean-cars-and-trucks/">White House factsheet</a> released Thursday. The new standards, which will be crafted under the jurisdiction of the Department of Transportation and the Environmental Protection Agency, should come as no surprise to automakers: They were included in Biden’s so-called “Day One Agenda” and mark a cornerstone of his strategy to combat climate change.</p>
<p>The new standards will likely borrow from those passed by California last year, which were finalized in concert with a coalition of five automakers: BMW AG, Ford, Honda Motor Co., Volkswagen AG, and Volvo AB. Those automakers, in a separate statement Thursday, said they supported the White House’s plan to reduce emissions. However, like the Big Three, they said that “bold action” from the federal government will be needed to achieve emission reductions targets.</p>
<h2>The road to 2030</h2>
<p>While Biden’s nonbinding order is more of a symbolic one, the targets are likely achievable, Jessica Caldwell, Edmunds&#8217; executive director of insights said in a statement. She added that automotive industry leaders “have seen the writing on the wall for some time now” regarding electrification, regardless of who has been in the White House.</p>
<p>Thanks to the relatively long product development lead time, many of the major automakers have already announced multibillion-dollar investments in EVs and AVs at least through the middle of the decade. That includes a $35 billion investment through 2025 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/gm-increases-ev-and-av-investments-to-35b-through-2025/">from GM</a> and $30 billion through the same year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/fords-30b-investment-in-electric-revs-up-in-house-battery-rd/">from Ford</a> &#8212; not to mention similar announcements <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/auto-giant-stellantis-to-invest-e30b-in-electrification-through-2025/">from Stellantis</a> and many billions earmarked for battery R&amp;D <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/volkswagens-new-business-strategy-puts-software-and-autonomous-driving-front-and-center/">from Volkswagen</a>, and even <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/volvo-to-sell-only-all-electric-vehicles-by-2030/">Volvo Cars’ shift</a> to all-electric by 2030.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="F4NafdPaoI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/auto-giant-stellantis-to-invest-e30b-in-electrification-through-2025/">Auto giant Stellantis to invest €30B in electrification through 2025</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Auto giant Stellantis to invest €30B in electrification through 2025&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/auto-giant-stellantis-to-invest-e30b-in-electrification-through-2025/embed/#?secret=F4NafdPaoI" data-secret="F4NafdPaoI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>These massive numbers follow the automakers’ own sales targets, which are for the most part in line with Biden’s goal.</p>
<p>Fuel economy rules, however, have historically garnered slightly more mixed reactions from automakers. GM, Fiat Chrysler (now Stellantis) and Toyota had previously supported a Trump-era lawsuit that sought to strip California’s authority to set its own emissions standards &#8212; but each company eventually made an about-face, leaving the road open for Biden to introduce his own standards this year.</p>
<p>In a very real sense, Biden’s announcement is as much about geopolitics as it is about climate change. He, too, has seen the writing on the wall regarding EVs. His administration notes in the factsheet that “China is increasingly cornering the global supply chain” for EVs and EV battery materials. “By setting clear targets for electric vehicle sale trajectories, these countries are becoming magnets for private investment into their manufacturing sectors &#8212; from parts and materials to final assembly.”</p>
<p>While three times as many EVs were registered in the U.S. in 2020 versus 2016, America still lags behind both Europe and China in terms of EV market share, according to the <a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/global-ev-outlook-2021">International Energy Agency</a>.</p>
<p>The news has garnered a slew of mixed reactions, with some environmental groups urging more decisive action on the part of the administration. Carol Lee Rawn, senior director of transportation at Ceres, said in a statement that future standards should target a 60% reduction in emissions and a “clear trajectory” to 100% vehicle sales by 2035.</p>
<p>Although the UAW will be joining Biden at the White House on Thursday, President Ray Curry said in a statement that the group is “not focused on hard deadlines or percentages, but on preserving the wages and benefits that have been the heart and soul of the American middle class.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2gYz1V8dpc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/23/automakers-have-battery-anxiety-so-theyre-taking-control-of-the-supply/">Automakers have battery anxiety, so they&#8217;re taking control of the supply</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Automakers have battery anxiety, so they&#8217;re taking control of the supply&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/23/automakers-have-battery-anxiety-so-theyre-taking-control-of-the-supply/embed/#?secret=2gYz1V8dpc" data-secret="2gYz1V8dpc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/automakers-urge-greater-government-investment-to-meet-bidens-ev-sales-target/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2186144</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 invaluable founder lessons I learned on my immigration journey</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/3-invaluable-founder-lessons-i-learned-on-my-immigration-journey/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/3-invaluable-founder-lessons-i-learned-on-my-immigration-journey/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 15:12:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B visa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ShipBob]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Turkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184630</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In my journey to the U.S., I became good at three things: accepting uncertainty, building resilience and maintaining a positive mental attitude. I needed them all to get my startup off the ground.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Mustafa Bayramoglu</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/mustafa_bay_">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Mustafa Bayramoglu is the founder and CEO at <a href="https://preflight.com/">Preflight</a>. Previously, he was the software architect and the first engineer at <a href="https://shipbob.com/">ShipBob</a>.  	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">I was four years old when my dad first showed me a computer. I immediately asked him if we could take it apart to see how it worked. I was hooked.</p>
<p>When I learned that Windows and Mac were based in the United States, I was 10. Since then, I’ve wanted to come here to launch my own tech business.</p>
<p>What I didn’t realize back then was that the first half of that dream — coming to the U.S. — would provide me with essential training for realizing the second half — launching a business.</p>
<p>As it turns out, the behaviors, attitude and mindset required to traverse the U.S. immigration system are many of the same ones required to navigate the uncertain waters of entrepreneurship.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			The behaviors, attitude and mindset required to traverse the U.S. immigration system are many of the same ones required to navigate the uncertain waters of entrepreneurship.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>In 2019, I launched <a href="https://preflight.com/">Preflight</a>, which makes smart and fast no-code test automation software for web applications. One big reason the business currently exists is that, in my journey to getting asylee status in the United States, I became really good at three things: accepting uncertainty, building resilience and maintaining a positive mental attitude.</p>
<p>I needed them all to get Preflight off the ground.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>The many paths to the U.S. (and launching a startup)</h2>
<p>I had my first shot at making my longtime dream a reality when I was applying to college as an undergraduate. I figured if I could go to school in the United States, I could find a way to stay and start a business.</p>
<p>After doing some research, though, I realized that U.S. colleges were too expensive.</p>
<p>But I figured getting out of Turkey, my home country, would be a start. I looked around for affordable schools and saw that France had good options. So I went to France.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, even after three attempts, I wasn’t able to get a student visa. So I headed back to Turkey and went to college there. After graduation, I knew I had a second shot at the U.S.: a master’s degree. I applied to computer science programs and got accepted &#8212; a huge win!</p>
<p>I first arrived in Georgia, where I got my TOEFL certification, then enrolled at Tennessee State University, where I got a teaching assistantship.</p>
<p>Keep in mind, to do all this, I had to have the right visas. I needed a student visa for my master’s degree, but if I wanted to work after graduation, I’d need a work visa.</p>
<p>The thing is, though, I didn’t want to work at a “job.” I wanted to start my own business, which requires a different type of visa altogether.</p>
<p>Oh, and there was another factor at play: I was enrolled at Tennessee State from 2014 to 2016, during the lead-up to the election of Donald Trump. So in addition to trying to figure out which visa I could reasonably get, I had to deal with the fact that the rules for visas could all change in the coming months.</p>
<p>These experiences are similar to what many founders deal with every day in the process of launching and running a business.</p>
<p>We don’t know if our products will work or if they’ll find a market. We don’t know how changing regulations might affect what we’re doing. We have no idea when something like a pandemic will pull the rug out from everything we’ve built.</p>
<p>But we keep going anyway. In my experience, the most successful founders are the ones who don’t wait for all the pieces to fall into place — they know that will never happen. They’re the ones who do the best they can with what they have. They trust that they’ll be able to adapt and adjust when things inevitably change.</p>
<p>Which brings me to my next lesson.</p>
<h2>Resilience: Hearing &#8220;no&#8221; as &#8220;not yet&#8221;</h2>
<p>Hearing “no” isn’t fun, especially when that “no” is about something you’ve wanted for more than a decade.</p>
<p>I experienced a lot of “no”s in my immigration journey, as one visa attempt after another failed. If I’d let any one of those failures stop me, I wouldn&#8217;t be where I am today — working at my own startup in the U.S.</p>
<p>The lesson I learned was to hear “no” as “not yet.” It’s been invaluable to me in my journey to becoming a founder.</p>
<p>For example: In 2014, while I was in graduate school, I learned about Y Combinator and decided that I wanted to be a part of it. Throughout grad school, I applied and got rejected three times.</p>
<p>The clock was ticking on my student visa, so I decided to shift my tactics. I applied to jobs at companies that were Y Combinator graduates to see what I could learn.</p>
<p>In 2016, I got hired at ShipBob, a Chicago-based company that was in <a href="https://www.ycdb.co/batch/s14">Y Combinator’s Summer 2014 batch</a>. I joined the team as its first full-time developer and the first one based in the States. From there, things changed dramatically.</p>
<p>For starters, I learned a lot. In my time with ShipBob — just two and a half years — we grew from 10 people to more than 400. I built two apps and applied to Y Combinator twice more and got rejected both times.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9kaAXYJ8Wr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/4-lessons-i-learned-about-getting-into-y-combinator-after-13-applications/">4 lessons I learned about getting into Y Combinator (after 13 applications)</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;4 lessons I learned about getting into Y Combinator (after 13 applications)&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/4-lessons-i-learned-about-getting-into-y-combinator-after-13-applications/embed/#?secret=9kaAXYJ8Wr" data-secret="9kaAXYJ8Wr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But in my work growing and leading a team of developers, I saw a need for a product that didn’t yet exist: a smart, fast, no-code test automation tool.</p>
<p>My team was spending way too much time building tests for ShipBob’s latest updates to make sure existing functionalities worked when we deployed. But when the code changed too quickly, our tests were outdated. It was incredibly frustrating.</p>
<p>Then we hired two quality assurance engineers and it took them four months to get 10% automated test coverage.</p>
<p>These problems led me to an aha moment: I could build a company to address this. A tool that is fast in test creation and can adapt to the UI changes.</p>
<p>That company is Preflight, and it’s the one that finally got me admitted to Y Combinator in the Winter 2019 batch. I was ecstatic when I heard that we’d been accepted. But then I realized that I couldn’t actually work on Preflight full time with my current visa status — at least, if I wanted to one day make a salary, I couldn’t.</p>
<p>And that brings me to my next point.</p>
<h2>Maintaining a positive mental attitude as you face (many) challenges</h2>
<p>My professional life wasn’t the only thing that changed dramatically while I was at ShipBob. My immigration status also evolved.</p>
<p>ShipBob applied for and got me an H-1B visa, which made me eligible to work in the U.S.</p>
<p>But when I got accepted to Y Combinator on my sixth application, I knew I needed an alternative: If I left ShipBob to run Preflight, I would lose my H-1B and my ability to work in the U.S.</p>
<p>This kind of conundrum is all too familiar to most startup founders: There’s no new opportunity without a new challenge to accompany it.</p>
<p>So I did what any founder would do: I focused on the positive (I’d gotten into YC!) and dedicated myself to figuring out a different way to stay in the country.</p>
<p>First, I tried to apply for the EB-1 visa, but the required documentation was too burdensome. I don’t think any founder could prepare for that application without several months of preparation.</p>
<p>Then I tried the O-1. No luck.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IdtsDs5eGy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/dear-sophie-can-i-transfer-my-h-1b-to-a-startup-i-founded/">Dear Sophie: Can I transfer my H-1B to a startup I founded?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Dear Sophie: Can I transfer my H-1B to a startup I founded?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/dear-sophie-can-i-transfer-my-h-1b-to-a-startup-i-founded/embed/#?secret=IdtsDs5eGy" data-secret="IdtsDs5eGy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>So I asked ShipBob if I could take an unpaid sabbatical, which would let me keep my H-1B status while I attended Y Combinator and worked on Preflight. They agreed. My brothers, who had both moved to Chicago and started working at ShipBob (you’re welcome, guys!) agreed to support me (thanks, guys!).</p>
<p>Finally, I had a solution that worked — but only for the time being. If Preflight was successful, I’d have to find a different way to stay in the country.</p>
<p>Transferring my H-1B to Preflight wouldn’t work, in part because it would require me to yield 70% to 80% ownership to my co-founder and agree that he could fire me at any time.</p>
<p>But there was another option I’d been reluctant to lean on: asylee status. In 2016, there was an attempted coup in Turkey (that’s the official story, anyway). I won’t get into the political details, but my family and I were supporters of the movement blamed for the attempt. As a result, we were at risk of imprisonment if we stayed in Turkey — and eligible for asylum status in the U.S.</p>
<p>I applied, but hoped that I’d land a work visa in the meantime, partly because asylum status can take years to get approved and partly because there was no telling whether the current administration would change the rules to make me ineligible before my status came through.</p>
<p>When I got accepted to Y Combinator, my asylum status was pending. When my initial sabbatical from ShipBob ran out, it was still pending. I asked for an extension and got it (thanks, ShipBob!). A few months later, I figured I could not get the visa sorted. I wanted to focus on my business and use asylum-pending status, which would give me work authorization for two years. I was therefore able to work on and take a salary from Preflight.</p>
<h2>Putting it all together</h2>
<p>My asylum was granted early this year, four years after applying. Getting asylee status was a big win because it meant I could realize my dream of running a business in the U.S. So I was, in some ways, at the resolution of my immigration journey — but I was just at the beginning of my journey as a founder.</p>
<p>Right away, I had my first experience applying all the lessons I’d learned in the last six years: We wanted to raise our first funding round. That funding would let me start taking a salary.</p>
<p>All told, we approached more than 100 VCs before we got a yes. But we did get that yes, and we raised a seed round of $1.2 million in September 2019.</p>
<p>It was a big win for Preflight, but it didn’t have the transformational power for the company I’d hoped for. That’s because, after closing our round, we didn’t focus on sales and marketing to the extent that we should have.</p>
<p>After several months of frustrating results, I consulted with my advisers about how to proceed. They offered me insight that seemed obvious once I had it — but that I may not have gotten on my own &#8212; which was discussing everything that’s happening internally with the investors. And the outcome was me being the CEO.</p>
<p>In the month and a half after I adjusted course based on my vision, I grew Preflight’s revenue 600% in just about two months.</p>
<h2>The only constant is change</h2>
<p>The whole startup ethos of disrupting what’s not working to improve people’s lives is based on the premise that the world is constantly changing. The global disruption caused by COVID-19 underscored that in a major way.</p>
<p>Founders who accept that change is inevitable and who embrace uncertainty, develop resilience for when things go wrong, and maintain a positive mental attitude about the ups and (especially) the downs of running a startup will be the ones who succeed for the long haul.</p>
<p>I’ve known since I was 10 that I wanted to run a company in the United States. Given the choice, I would have opted for a much smoother road to entrepreneurship. But what I’ve discovered is that the difficult immigration path I had to follow provided exactly the training I needed to succeed in the challenging role of a founder.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/3-invaluable-founder-lessons-i-learned-on-my-immigration-journey/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184630</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Warehouse drones take flight</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/robotics-roundup-23/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/robotics-roundup-23/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 15:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Electric]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[third wave automation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185933</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Drones are neat and fun and all that good stuff (I should probably add the caveat here that I’m obviously not referring to the big, terrible military variety), but when it comes to quadcopters, there’s always been the looming question of general usefulness. The consumer-facing variety are pretty much the exclusive realm of hobbyists and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Drones are neat and fun and all that good stuff (I should probably add the caveat here that I’m obviously not referring to the big, terrible military variety), but when it comes to quadcopters, there’s always been the looming question of general usefulness. The consumer-facing variety are pretty much the exclusive realm of hobbyists and imaging.</p>
<p>We’ve seen a number of interesting applications for things like agricultural surveillance, real estate and the like, all of which are effectively extensions of that imaging capability. But a lot can be done with a camera and the right processing. One of the more interesting applications I’ve seen cropping up here and there is the warehouse drone — something perhaps a bit counterintuitive, as you likely (and understandably) associate drones with the outdoors.</p>
<p>Looking back, it seems we’ve actually had two separate warehouse drone companies compete in Disrupt Battlefield. There was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/12/intelligent-flying-machines/">IFM (Intelligent Flying Machines)</a> in 2016 and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/06/vtrus-launches-drones-to-inspect-and-protect-your-warehouses-and-factories/">Vtrus two years later</a>. That’s really the tip of the iceberg for a big list of startups effectively pushing to bring drones to warehouses and factory floors.</p>
<p>The list now also includes <a href="https://www.corvus-robotics.com/">Corvus Robotics</a>, a YC-backed startup presumably named for the genus of birds that includes surprisingly intelligent species like crows and ravens (though, presumably, these ones don’t also travel together in murders). The company calls its offering &#8220;the world&#8217;s first unmanned warehouse inventory drones,” which is potentially disputable.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9SzI27FyhQY?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;start=1&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>But the offering is interesting, nonetheless, effectively flying around to scan pallets for inventory purposes. According to a piece from <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/drone-warehouse-corvus-robotics">IEEE Spectrum</a>, the level-four autonomous drone network is capable of scanning 200 to 400 pallets an hour, including the downtime spent recharging (flying is hard work).</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2185527" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2185527" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2185527" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/third-wave.jpg" alt="third wave automation" width="1024" height="487" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/third-wave.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/third-wave.jpg?resize=150,71 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/third-wave.jpg?resize=300,143 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/third-wave.jpg?resize=768,365 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/third-wave.jpg?resize=680,323 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/third-wave.jpg?resize=1536,730 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/third-wave.jpg?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2185527" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Third Wave Automation</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Speaking of that industry holy grail of full warehouse automation, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/third-wave-automation-raises-40m-to-bring-its-autonomous-forklifts-to-warehouses/">Third Wave Automation just announced</a> a $40 million Series B, led by Norwest Venture Partners and featuring Innovation Endeavors, Eclipse and Toyota Ventures. The latter has been working with the Bay Area-based startup to develop an autonomous forklift — because, among other things, forklift accidents hurt a lot of people every year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Mrqma9miyU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/third-wave-automation-raises-40m-to-bring-its-autonomous-forklifts-to-warehouses/">Third Wave Automation raises $40M to bring its autonomous forklifts to warehouses</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Third Wave Automation raises $40M to bring its autonomous forklifts to warehouses&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/third-wave-automation-raises-40m-to-bring-its-autonomous-forklifts-to-warehouses/embed/#?secret=Mrqma9miyU" data-secret="Mrqma9miyU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Here’s CEO Arshan Poursohi:</p>
<blockquote><p>We’ve covered just about every kind of robot there is. But all of these robots that we built ended up, you know, sitting in a closet somewhere because ultimately, Google or, in my case, Sun Microsystems, would decide it’s not worth scaling it out because it’s not the core business, or some other reason.</p></blockquote>
<p>The company plans to have 100 units out in the world by the end of next year.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2185935" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2185935" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2185935 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/picker-specs@2x.png" alt="" width="1024" height="805" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/picker-specs@2x.png 1058w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/picker-specs@2x.png?resize=150,118 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/picker-specs@2x.png?resize=300,236 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/picker-specs@2x.png?resize=768,604 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/picker-specs@2x.png?resize=680,535 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/picker-specs@2x.png?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2185935" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> InVia Robotics</p></div></p>
<p>Fellow warehouse automator inVia Robotics, meanwhile, <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210728005353/en/Microsoft%E2%80%99s-M12-and-Qualcomm-Ventures-%E2%80%93-Joined-by-Hitachi-Ventures-%E2%80%93-Co-Lead-Series-C-Round-for-Award-Winning-Robotics-Company-inVia-Robotics">announced a $30 million Series C</a> at the tail end of last month. Tech giants Microsoft (M12) and Qualcomm (Qualcomm Ventures LLC) led the round, which brings the California firm’s total funding up to $59 million to date. Hitachi Ventures also joined for the round. The company says it was able to grow pandemic-fueled growth to a 600% revenue increase in 2020.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/37OpI8dHTGU?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>And just because we couldn’t do all warehouse news this week (as tempting and easy as that might be), here’s a robot <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=37OpI8dHTGU">from General Electric named ATVer</a>. The sundry tech conglomerate has been field testing the autonomous &#8216;bot with the U.S. Army. Military funding, mind, continues to be a pretty massive driver in robotics, for better and worse.</p>
<p>“Our project and partnership with the US Army has really enabled us to make some important advances in autonomous systems,” GE’s senior robotics Shiraj Sen says in a release. “We believe the advances made on this project will not only help accelerate the deployment of future driver-less vehicle technologies; they will help encourage more autonomous solutions in other industry sectors like energy, aviation and healthcare that people depend on every day.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2186103" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2186103" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2186103" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/SARCOS_GuardianDX_TelescopicBoom_SenSuit_v001_001.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="1152" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/SARCOS_GuardianDX_TelescopicBoom_SenSuit_v001_001.jpeg 1778w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/SARCOS_GuardianDX_TelescopicBoom_SenSuit_v001_001.jpeg?resize=133,150 133w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/SARCOS_GuardianDX_TelescopicBoom_SenSuit_v001_001.jpeg?resize=267,300 267w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/SARCOS_GuardianDX_TelescopicBoom_SenSuit_v001_001.jpeg?resize=768,864 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/SARCOS_GuardianDX_TelescopicBoom_SenSuit_v001_001.jpeg?resize=605,680 605w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/SARCOS_GuardianDX_TelescopicBoom_SenSuit_v001_001.jpeg?resize=1366,1536 1366w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/SARCOS_GuardianDX_TelescopicBoom_SenSuit_v001_001.jpeg?resize=44,50 44w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2186103" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sarcos</p></div></p>
<p>In just under the wire, Sarcos this morning announced a partnership with T-Mobile that will bring 5G teleoperation to the company&#8217;s  Guardian XT robot. Robotics are, of course, one of those things that frequently get tossed around when discussing the potential benefits of 5G&#8217;s low-latency connection. Honestly, it&#8217;s the sort of thing that gets rolled out on stage during press events (<em>cough</em> Verizon), because robots are surefire crowd pleasers. So, it&#8217;s nice seeing it applied to some actual systems here.</p>
<p>From the release,</p>
<blockquote><p>The T-Mobile and <span class="il">Sarcos</span> collaboration begins with the integration of 5G to develop a remote viewing system powered by T-Mobile’s high bandwidth, low latency 5G network. This enables workers, supervisors, outside experts, and others, whether they are based locally or remote, to watch tasks being performed by the robot as it is controlled by an operator in the field. The second phase of development is expected to include full T-Mobile 5G wireless network integration, allowing teleoperation of the Guardian XT robot over 5G, giving operators greater flexibility and increasing their safety by enabling them to perform tasks from a distance.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/robotics-roundup-23/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185933</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tomorrow’s the final day for early-bird passes to TC Disrupt 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/tomorrows-the-final-day-for-early-bird-passes-to-tc-disrupt-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/tomorrows-the-final-day-for-early-bird-passes-to-tc-disrupt-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 15:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185838</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Great news for budget-conscious startuppers of every stripe. The early-bird price extension on passes to TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 remains in play for just about two more days. Buy an early-bird pass — Innovator, Founder or Investor — and you’ll revel in three full days of Disruption for less than $100. This is what you call [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Great news for budget-conscious startuppers of every stripe. The early-bird price extension on passes to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?promo=earlybirdhard24hours&amp;display=true">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> remains in play for just about two more days. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/tickets/?promo=earlybirdhard24hours&amp;display=true">Buy an early-bird pass</a> — Innovator, Founder or Investor — and you’ll revel in three full days of Disruption for less than $100.</p>
<p>This is what you call a “buy now or pay more later” situation, people — the deal disappears for good tomorrow, <strong>August 6 at 11:59 pm (PT).</strong></p>
<p><strong>Pro Tips:</strong> We also offer deep discounts on tickets for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/tickets/?promo=earlybirdhard24hours&amp;display=true">students, nonprofits and government employees</a>. Just want to explore the companies exhibiting in Startup Alley? <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/tickets/?promo=earlybirdhard24hours&amp;display=true">Grab an Expo Pass for less than $50</a>. Want to register more than five people? Email <a href="mailto:events@techcrunch.com">events@techcrunch.com</a> for a group rate quote.</p>
<p>No matter where you and your business fall on the startup spectrum, you’ll find plenty of information, inspiration and opportunity at Disrupt 2021. Here’s why three of your contemporaries think going to Disrupt is an essential part of the startup experience:</p>
<blockquote><p>I love Disrupt because it features incredible companies. My work exposes me to lots of companies all over the world but, inevitably, I run across startups at Disrupt I haven&#8217;t heard of yet. It&#8217;s always fascinating to explore opportunities and find ways to work together. — Rachael Wilcox, creative producer, Volvo Cars.</p>
<p>When you’re building a startup, you’re in the weeds. It&#8217;s hard to get a 30,000-foot view, see where your company is and where it can go. Going to Disrupt and seeing what other startups are doing gives you that important perspective. It’s a huge benefit. — Jessica McLean, director of Marketing and Communications, Infinite-Compute.</p>
<p>As a cross-border VC fund manager, I’m always looking to identify new tech trends and how we can bring them to Latin America. Disrupt provides terrific insight on trends in different industries like e-grocery, AI and big data. — Daniel Lloreda, general partner at H20 Capital Innovation.</p></blockquote>
<p>The Disrupt experience also includes watching the world-renowned <a href="https://techcrunch.com/startup-battlefield/">Startup Battlefield</a> pitch competition. A field of 20 off-the-hook startups will take the stage and vie for $100,000 in equity-free prize money. Plenty of household tech names — like Vurb, Yammer, Dropbox and Mint — launched their company during Startup Battlefield. Watch the future giants of tech launch here.</p>
<p>Whether you consider networking an art, a science or a full-on contact sport, Disrupt offers exceptional opportunities to connect and collaborate with like-minded people who can help build your business. CrunchMatch, our free, AI-powered platform, makes finding those folks — out of 10,000+ global attendees — quick and painless.</p>
<p>And of course, we have a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/#0affacde-e0ed-4a3c-abc4-988cb1c0eb3e">packed agenda</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/#eb919231-f3e4-4def-8dd0-afb0bc7c9c6e">world-class speakers</a>, vital trends, actionable tips and advice, pitch deck teardowns and breakout sessions. Plus, hundreds of innovative startups exhibiting in the Startup Alley expo area.</p>
<p>It all goes down on September 21-23 at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?promo=earlybirdhard24hours&amp;display=true">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a>. And it’s all available to you for less than $99 — if you <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/tickets/?promo=earlybirdhard24hours&amp;display=true">buy your pass</a> before tomorrow, <strong>August 6 at 11:59 pm (PT)</strong>. What the heck are you waiting for?</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at Disrupt 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			width="99%"
			height="1300"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/tomorrows-the-final-day-for-early-bird-passes-to-tc-disrupt-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185838</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Avoid these common financial mistakes so your startup doesn&#8217;t die on the vine</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/avoid-these-common-financial-mistakes-so-your-startup-doesnt-die-on-the-vine/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/avoid-these-common-financial-mistakes-so-your-startup-doesnt-die-on-the-vine/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 15:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Future of Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185962</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many founders are blessed with brilliance. But that doesn’t mean that they inherently understand the complex finances and metrics needed to run a company effectively.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Swapnil Shinde</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/swapnil_shinde">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Swapnil Shinde is the co-founder and CEO of <a href="https://www.zeni.ai/">Zeni</a>, the first AI-powered finance concierge for startups. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The startup world can be a rollercoaster. While investment continues to pour in — with both founders and investors looking for the next unicorn — the reality is that <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/articles/personal-finance/040915/how-many-startups-fail-and-why.asp" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.investopedia.com/articles/personal-finance/040915/how-many-startups-fail-and-why.asp&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1628200999412000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFGYa_67fqHf9_gyI50MwlGdDlDXg">90% of startups fail</a>, with over half of those going under in the first three years.</p>
<p>I’ve founded two companies that I grew and sold (Mezi and Dhingana). I encountered many of the issues that new founders face, learned on the job, and thankfully persevered. Using the knowledge that I acquired in my previous companies, I’ve founded a third — Zeni — to try and help founders make more informed, sustainable financial decisions.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			For many founders, a transformative idea and initial outside investment doesn’t translate into understanding the underlying financial complexities of running a business.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Whether you&#8217;re just wrapping your seed round, or on to Series B, avoiding these common issues is the best way to ensure that you&#8217;re set on solid ground and free to focus on your vision.</p>
<h2>Why most startups fail</h2>
<p>Startups go under for a variety of reasons. Some fail to achieve product-market fit in a scalable way. Many others simply run out of money. While the above two reasons are often cited as the two primary reasons for startup failure, they’re also related. If you don’t solve a market problem and don’t generate customers, you’re eventually going to run out of money.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, many of the startups that fail shouldn’t. They’re led by bright entrepreneurs with a great idea. But for many founders, a transformative idea and initial outside investment doesn’t translate into understanding the underlying financial complexities of running a business.</p>
<p>When you break down the various complexities founders face in understanding business finances, there are three primary hurdles they face:</p>
<ol>
<li>Fragmentation of financial systems.</li>
<li>Time-consuming manual tasks.</li>
<li>Lack of real-time financial insights.</li>
</ol>
<p>All of the above issues put increased workload and strain on founders, which can lead to burnout. Owners, on average,<a href="https://www.embroker.com/blog/startup-statistics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.embroker.com/blog/startup-statistics/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1628200999412000&amp;usg=AFQjCNESUXqQJ_XngrRe-KD8Qkd9u2VBiA"> spend around 40% of their working hours</a> on tasks like hiring, HR and payroll. While hiring is integral to a founders’ day-to-day role, other administrative tasks related to finance, HR and payroll distract founders from focusing on their overall vision and goals.</p>
<p>The good news is that by being aware of the above issues, you can solve them and eliminate the consequences of burnout, distraction and, ultimately, failure. Let’s talk about how.</p>
<h2>Consolidate fragmentation</h2>
<p>The financial decision-making and tasks of most startups start and stop with the founder. This means that bookkeeping, bill paying, invoicing, financial projections, employee payments and taxes all run into a bottleneck. Even worse, each of these functions requires another employee, vendor or third-party expert — finance firms, admins, CFOs, CPA firms — each using its own software and applications to accomplish their goals.</p>
<p>Each of these parties is reporting back up to the founder, who is then in charge of making sense of it all and disseminating the information to the entities that need it. This means that not only is everything slower, but often things fall through the cracks, as communication can become a serious issue.</p>
<p>Worse still, this creates cash flow problems, as bills go unpaid, invoices go unsent, and important financial documents are delayed. I’ve seen revenue go unreported and invoices unsent and uncollectable due to the fragmentation-bottleneck system most founders experience.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/avoid-these-common-financial-mistakes-so-your-startup-doesnt-die-on-the-vine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185962</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>With DoubleDash, DoorDash users can tack on multiple orders without additional fees</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/with-doubledash-doordash-users-can-tack-on-multiple-orders-without-additional-fees/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/with-doubledash-doordash-users-can-tack-on-multiple-orders-without-additional-fees/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 15:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doubledash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food delivery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185996</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During the thick of the pandemic last year, online food delivery company DoorDash expanded its offerings to include convenience store delivery. Now, DoorDash customers in the U.S. and Canada can shop across multiple stores and categories in a single order. With DoubleDash, as the program is called, customers can now tack onto your order of a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p data-selectable-paragraph="">During the thick of the pandemic last year, online food delivery company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/01/doordash-now-delivers-from-over-1800-convenience-stores-nationwide/">DoorDash expanded its offerings to include convenience store delivery</a>. Now, DoorDash customers in the U.S. and Canada can shop across multiple stores and categories in a single order.</p>
<p data-selectable-paragraph="">With DoubleDash, as the program is called, customers can now tack onto your order of a pad thai dinner some tampons and ice cream from the local 7-Eleven. In most cases, it&#8217;ll all be brought to them by the same delivery person in one bundle, allowing customers to forgo any additional delivery fees.</p>
<p data-selectable-paragraph="">The goal for customers is to increase convenience while preserving price expectations. For local businesses, there&#8217;s a possibility that some light prodding of the customer while they&#8217;re hungry and uninterested in leaving their homes will lead to more business. And for DoorDash, this move is another step toward making the app the ever-coveted &#8220;one-stop-shop&#8221; for all things delivery.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2185998" style="width: 364px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2185998" loading="lazy" class="vertical  wp-image-2185998" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DoubleDash-flow-2.png?w=152" alt="" width="354" height="700" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DoubleDash-flow-2.png 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DoubleDash-flow-2.png?resize=76,150 76w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DoubleDash-flow-2.png?resize=152,300 152w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DoubleDash-flow-2.png?resize=768,1519 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DoubleDash-flow-2.png?resize=344,680 344w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DoubleDash-flow-2.png?resize=777,1536 777w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DoubleDash-flow-2.png?resize=25,50 25w" sizes="(max-width: 354px) 100vw, 354px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2185998" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> DoorDash</p></div></p>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;Ever since we began offering convenience as a category on DoorDash over a year ago, we’ve observed that many customers organically order their restaurant meal and then place another order for convenience items within a 30-minute window,&#8221; Fuad Hannon, DoorDash&#8217;s head of new verticals, told TechCrunch. &#8220;We are always thinking about ways to improve our platform to serve our customers’ needs and after observing this consumer behavior, we wanted to make this process easier and more affordable for consumers.&#8221;</p>
<p data-selectable-paragraph="">With DoubleDash, after a customer place their original order, a pop-up on the app will entice them with additional items from nearby stores. Customers can also look for the DoubleDash option on the in-app map to search for nearby stores. Depending on the customer&#8217;s location and proximity to the merchant, anywhere from one to five merchants will show up on the map. Customers can add on as much or as little as they want for the second order, as there&#8217;s no minimum order size.</p>
<p data-selectable-paragraph="">Delivery workers, or &#8220;Dashers,&#8221; will be able to collect tips on both the first restaurant order and the second merchant order, according to the company. Dashers can use DoorDash&#8217;s logistics platform to accept both orders at once and deliver them together without deviating from the primary route, thus potentially increasing earnings without going too far out of their way.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p data-selectable-paragraph="">This new feature is available with 7-Eleven, Walgreens, Wawa, QuickChek, the Ice Cream Shop and DashMart, a DoorDash-owned convenience and grocery store. DoorDash is also piloting the ability to partner local restaurants with DoubleDash in several markets like Los Angeles, Denver and Portland, so if you want to start with sushi and end with a chocolate torte, it&#8217;ll be just a little bit cheaper and easier to do so.</p>
<p id="c25d" class="ic id gr ie b if jk ig ih ii jl ij ik il jm im in io jn ip iq ir jo is it iv cx ew" data-selectable-paragraph="">“We are excited to be a part of DoorDash’s newest endeavor, DoubleDash, and for the opportunity to reach new customers and drive additional sales for our business,&#8221; said Benjamin D. Arreola, owner of Señor G’s Fresh &amp; Healthy Mexican Food in Playa Del Rey, California, in a statement.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fYpUSLKiai"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/13/how-covid-19-accelerated-doordashs-business/">How COVID-19 accelerated DoorDash&#8217;s business</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How COVID-19 accelerated DoorDash&#8217;s business&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/13/how-covid-19-accelerated-doordashs-business/embed/#?secret=fYpUSLKiai" data-secret="fYpUSLKiai" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/with-doubledash-doordash-users-can-tack-on-multiple-orders-without-additional-fees/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185996</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>European refurbished electronics marketplace Refurbed raises $54M Series B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/european-refurbished-electronics-marketplace-refurbed-raises-54m-series-b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/european-refurbished-electronics-marketplace-refurbed-raises-54m-series-b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 14:20:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Almaz Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[austria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[C4 Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evli Growth Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hermes GPE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Isomer Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online marketplace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Refurbed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trivago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2186101</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Refurbed, a European marketplace for refurbished electronics which raised a $17 million Series A round of funding last year, has now raised a $54 million Series B funding led by Evli Growth Partners and Almaz Capital. They are joined by existing investors such as Speedinvest, Bonsai Partners and All Iron Ventures, as well as a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.refurbed.co.uk/">Refurbed</a>, a European marketplace for refurbished electronics which raised a $17 million Series A round of funding <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/17/refurbished-electronics-startup-refurbed-raises-17m-round-led-by-evli-growth-partners/">last year</a>, has now raised a $54 million Series B funding led by Evli Growth Partners and Almaz Capital.</p>
<p>They are joined by existing investors such as Speedinvest, Bonsai Partners and All Iron Ventures, as well as a group of new backers — Hermes GPE, C4 Ventures, SevenVentures, Alpha Associates, Monkfish Equity (Trivago Founders), Kreos, Expon Capital, Isomer Capital and Creas Impact Fund.</p>
<p>Refurbed is an online marketplace for refurbished electronics that are tested and renewed. These then tend to be 40% cheaper than new, and come with a 12-month warranty. The company claims that in 2020, it grew by 3x and reached more than €100 million in GMV.</p>
<p>Operating in Germany, Austria, Ireland, France, Italy and Poland, the startup plans to expand to three other countries by the end of 2021.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="b3OxTrf4pM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/17/refurbished-electronics-startup-refurbed-raises-17m-round-led-by-evli-growth-partners/">Refurbished electronics startup Refurbed raises $17M round, led by Evli Growth Partners</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Refurbished electronics startup Refurbed raises $17M round, led by Evli Growth Partners&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/17/refurbished-electronics-startup-refurbed-raises-17m-round-led-by-evli-growth-partners/embed/#?secret=b3OxTrf4pM" data-secret="b3OxTrf4pM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Riku Asikainen at Evli Growth Partners said: “We see the huge potential behind the way Refurbed contributes to a sustainable, circular economy.”</p>
<p>Peter Windischhofer, co-founder of refurbed, told me: “We are cheaper and have a wider product range, with an emphasis on quality. We focus on selling products that look new, so we end up with happy customers who then recommend us to others. It makes people proud to buy refurbished products.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup has 130 refurbishers selling through its marketplace.</p>
<p>Other players in this space include Back Market (raised €48 million), Swappa (U.S.) and Amazon Renew. Refurbed also competes with Rebuy in Germany and Swapbee in Finland.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qnbmBS7SSf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/06/covid-19-crisis-spurs-triple-digit-growth-for-refurbishing-startup-back-market/">COVID-19 crisis spurs triple-digit growth for refurbishing startup Back Market</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;COVID-19 crisis spurs triple-digit growth for refurbishing startup Back Market&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/06/covid-19-crisis-spurs-triple-digit-growth-for-refurbishing-startup-back-market/embed/#?secret=qnbmBS7SSf" data-secret="qnbmBS7SSf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/european-refurbished-electronics-marketplace-refurbed-raises-54m-series-b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2186101</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Astra targets first commercial orbital launch for August 27</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/astra-targets-first-commercial-orbital-launch-for-august-27/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/astra-targets-first-commercial-orbital-launch-for-august-27/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 13:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alaska]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Astra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kodiak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[launch vehicle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Space Force]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2186097</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Astra&#8217;s last test launch went better than expected, nearly achieving orbit — kind of a stretch goal for that specific mission. The company at the time said that it would only need to tweak software to reach an orbital destination, and now we know when it&#8217;s going to get the chance to prove it: Astra [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Astra&#8217;s last test launch went better than expected, nearly achieving orbit — kind of a stretch goal for that specific mission. The company at the time said that it would only need to tweak software to reach an orbital destination, and now we know when it&#8217;s going to get the chance to prove it: Astra revealed a launch window today of August 27 for its first-ever commercial orbital launch, a demonstration mission for the U.S. Space Force.</p>
<p>The contract Astra has with the Space Force also includes a second launch, set for sometime later this year, with the exact schedule for that launch yet to be finalized.</p>
<p>The payload that Astra&#8217;s rocket will carry for the Space Force will be a test spacecraft flown for the agency&#8217;s Space Test Program. The launch will take place from Astra&#8217;s spaceport in Kodiak, Alaska, which is where it has flown its test missions previously.</p>
<p>While the launch window officially opens at 1 PM PT on August 27, it will remain open all the way through Saturday, September 11, and Astra could easily shift the launch within that window based on weather conditions and other factors.</p>
<p>Astra, which became a publicly traded company at the start of July through a SPAC merger, builds it own launch vehicles at its factory in Alameda, California. The launch provider is targeting cheap, high-volume, low-mass launches as its milieu, offering more flexible services relative to SpaceX, and a cost advantage when compared to Rocket Lab.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lJAbFXK3RQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/astra-to-acquire-electric-in-space-propulsion-company-apollo-fusion/">Astra to acquire electric in-space propulsion company Apollo Fusion</a></p></bl<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>ockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Astra to acquire electric in-space propulsion company Apollo Fusion&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/astra-to-acquire-electric-in-space-propulsion-company-apollo-fusion/embed/#?secret=lJAbFXK3RQ" data-secret="lJAbFXK3RQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/astra-targets-first-commercial-orbital-launch-for-august-27/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2186097</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cent, the platform that Jack Dorsey used to sell his first tweet as an NFT, raises $3M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/cent-the-platform-that-jack-dorsey-used-to-sell-his-first-tweet-as-an-nft-raises-3m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/cent-the-platform-that-jack-dorsey-used-to-sell-his-first-tweet-as-an-nft-raises-3m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 13:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[author]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chairman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deviantART]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Galaxy Interactive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jack dorsey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeffrey Katzenberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mark pincus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zynga]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184714</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cent was founded in 2017 as an ad-free creator network that allows users to offer each other crypto rewards for good posts and comments &#8212; it&#8217;s like gifting awards on Reddit, but with Ethereum. But in late 2020, Cent&#8217;s small, San Francisco-based team created Valuables, an NFT market for tweets, and by March, the small [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.cent.co/">Cent</a> was founded in 2017 as an ad-free creator network that allows users to offer each other crypto rewards for good posts and comments &#8212; it&#8217;s like gifting awards on Reddit, but with Ethereum. But in late 2020, Cent&#8217;s small, San Francisco-based team created <a href="https://v.cent.co/">Valuables</a>, an NFT market for tweets, and by March, the small blockchain startup was thrown a serendipitous curveball.</p>
<p>&#8220;We just wrapped up for the day, and I was about to go eat dinner, and all these people started texting me,&#8221; remembers CEO Cameron Hejazi. Then, he realized that Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey had minted Twitter&#8217;s first-ever Tweet through Cent&#8217;s Valuables application. &#8220;I was basically like, mildly shivering for the rest of the night. The whole team, we were like, &#8216;Okay, battle stations, prepare to get hacked!&#8217; &#8221;</p>
<p>Dorsey ended up <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/22/twitter-ceo-jack-dorseys-first-tweet-nft-sells-for-2point9-million.html">selling his NFT</a> for $2.9 million, and he <a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1374071729467707394">donated</a> the proceeds to Give Directly&#8217;s Africa Response fund for COVID-19 relief. But for Cent, it was as if the small company had just been handed a free marketing campaign. Now, about five months later, Cent is announcing a $3 million round of seed funding with investors like Galaxy Interactive, former Disney chairman Jeffrey Katzenberg, will.i.am and Zynga founder Mark Pincus.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">On <a href="https://v.cent.co/">Valuables</a>, anyone on the internet can place an offer on any tweet, which then makes it possible for someone else to make a counter-offer. If the author of the tweet accepts an offer (logging into Valuables requires you to validate your Twitter account), then Cent will mint the tweet on the blockchain and create a 1-of-1 NFT. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The NFT itself contains the text of the tweet, the username of the creator, the time it was minted and the creator&#8217;s digital signature. The NFT also includes a link to the tweet, though the linked content lives outside the blockchain.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2185667" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2185667" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2185667" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/centdorseytweet.jpeg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/centdorseytweet.jpeg 1290w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/centdorseytweet.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/centdorseytweet.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/centdorseytweet.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/centdorseytweet.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/centdorseytweet.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2185667" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.cent.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cent <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>There&#8217;s nothing proprietary about minting tweets as NFTs &#8212; another company could do the same thing that Cent is doing. Even Twitter itself has recently dabbled in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/twitter-is-making-nfts-now-apparently/">giving away free NFT art</a>, though it hasn&#8217;t tried to sell actual tweets as NFTs like Cent. Still, Hejazi sees Dorsey&#8217;s use of Cent like an endorsement &#8212; he thinks it would be difficult for Twitter to shut them down, since Dorsey made $2.9 million on the platform himself. After all, Dorsey chose Cent instead of taking a screenshot of his first tweet, minting the .JPG as an NFT and posting it on a larger NFT platform, like OpenSea.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve spoken with people at Twitter. I&#8217;m positive that we have a healthy relationship going,&#8221; Hejazi said (Twitter declined to comment on or confirm whether that&#8217;s true). &#8220;We thought about applying this approach to other social platforms, like Instagram and TikTok, but we hypothesized that this is particularly suited for Twitter, because it&#8217;s a conversation platform, and it&#8217;s where all of the crypto people are actually living.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Hgygouua7h"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/twitter-is-making-nfts-now-apparently/">Twitter is making NFTs now, apparently</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter is making NFTs now, apparently&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/twitter-is-making-nfts-now-apparently/embed/#?secret=Hgygouua7h" data-secret="Hgygouua7h" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>With Cent&#8217;s seed funding Hejazi hopes to continue building the platform. The company&#8217;s goal is to enable anyone creative to make an income through the use of NFTs &#8212; that means developing tools to make it simpler for its users to mint NFTs, but also, building out its existing creator-focused social network. The content people post on Cent is usually creative work, like art and writing, rather than short posts &#8212; it&#8217;s closer to DeviantArt than it is to Reddit. These are lofty goals for a $3 million seed funding round, but there are aspects of Cent&#8217;s <a href="https://beta.cent.co/~discover/">Beta</a> platform that make it promising.</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s already value in what we post on social media. It&#8217;s just being proxied through ad dollars, and it doesn&#8217;t have to be the case that there&#8217;s so much wealth concentration in a single entity. We can work toward a system that decentralizes that wealth,&#8221; said Hejazi. &#8220;These networks as they exist have monopolies on distribution &#8212; you can&#8217;t take your Twitter audience, download it as a .CSV and send them all an email.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2185671" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2185671" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2185671" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-04-at-1.14.35-PM.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="334" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-04-at-1.14.35-PM.png 2868w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-04-at-1.14.35-PM.png?resize=150,74 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-04-at-1.14.35-PM.png?resize=300,147 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-04-at-1.14.35-PM.png?resize=768,377 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-04-at-1.14.35-PM.png?resize=680,334 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-04-at-1.14.35-PM.png?resize=1536,754 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-04-at-1.14.35-PM.png?resize=2048,1005 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-04-at-1.14.35-PM.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2185671" class="wp-caption-text">A screenshot of Cent&#8217;s social platform.</p></div></p>
<p>In addition to independent distribution lists, Hejazi wants to move away from the ad-supported internet. He references <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/is-substack-really-worth-650m/">Substack</a> as an example of a company where the creator has control of their list, and at the same time, the platform can remain ad-free, since the money that propels it comes from the users who pay to subscribe to newsletters (and also, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/substack-confirms-65m-raise-promises-to-rapidly-expand-its-financial-backing-of-newly-independent-writers/">venture capital</a> helps).</p>
<p>But Cent does something different by allowing users to essentially invest in creators who they think have the potential to take off on their platform.</p>
<p>Users can &#8220;seed&#8221; a post, which is how you subscribe to a creator participating <a href="https://www.cent.co/#Beta">on the creatives side of Cent&#8217;s platform</a>. As the seeder, you pay a set fee of at least one dollar per month. There&#8217;s an incentive to support up-and-coming creators on the platform, because seeders get a portion of the creators&#8217; future profit &#8212; it&#8217;s like making a bet on them that they will continue to make great content in the future. Five percent of profits go toward Cent, but the remaining 95% is split 50/50 between the creator and all of their past seeders. Participating on this platform would allow creators to network and show support for one another, but doesn&#8217;t prevent them from more directly monetizing their work on other creator platforms, like Patreon.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Z0Ue0pcmEN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/yat-thinks-emoji-identities-can-be-a-thing-and-it-has-20m-in-sales-to-back-it-up/">Yat thinks emoji &#8216;identities&#8217; can be a thing, and it has $20M in sales to back it up</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Yat thinks emoji &#8216;identities&#8217; can be a thing, and it has $20M in sales to back it up&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/yat-thinks-emoji-identities-can-be-a-thing-and-it-has-20m-in-sales-to-back-it-up/embed/#?secret=Z0Ue0pcmEN" data-secret="Z0Ue0pcmEN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In addition to seeding posts, users can also &#8220;spot&#8221; other people&#8217;s posts &#8212; Cent&#8217;s version of a &#8220;like&#8221; button. Each &#8220;spot&#8221; is the equivalent of one cent from the user&#8217;s crypto wallet. Cent&#8217;s argument is that getting 1,000 likes on a post on other platforms yields nothing but a vague sensation of social clout. But on Cent, if a user gets 1,000 &#8220;spots,&#8221; that&#8217;s $10. Still, a project like this can only work if enough people use the platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we started Cent, we chose cryptocurrencies because we loved the idea of someone being able to earn money with nothing more than their creativity and a crypto address,&#8221; Hejazi said. &#8220;Over time, we&#8217;ve found it to be limiting as a payment type &#8212; very few people actually own it and have it ready to spend. We&#8217;re working on ways to make payments to creators using Cent easier, and are exploring both crypto-native and non-crypto options.&#8221;</p>
<p>This mindset echoes other NFT startups like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/yat-thinks-emoji-identities-can-be-a-thing-and-it-has-20m-in-sales-to-back-it-up/">Yat</a>, which allows payments via credit card as part of its &#8220;progressive decentralization&#8221; model. So much of these companies&#8217; success depends on public buy-in toward an eventual decentralized, blockchain-based internet. But until then, companies like Cent will continue to experiment in reimagining how creatives can get paid online.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="noKeIntj6C"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/the-nft-market-is-just-getting-started-but-where-is-it-headed/">The NFT market is just getting started, but where is it headed?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The NFT market is just getting started, but where is it headed?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/the-nft-market-is-just-getting-started-but-where-is-it-headed/embed/#?secret=noKeIntj6C" data-secret="noKeIntj6C" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/cent-the-platform-that-jack-dorsey-used-to-sell-his-first-tweet-as-an-nft-raises-3m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184714</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bluecore lands $125M Series E on $1B valuation as e-commerce personalization grows</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/bluecore-lands-125m-series-e-on-1b-valuation-as-e-commerce-personalization-grows/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/bluecore-lands-125m-series-e-on-1b-valuation-as-e-commerce-personalization-grows/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 13:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bluecore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Georgian Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[late stage funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personalization]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2186079</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During the pandemic, especially when we were in lockdown, just about every retailer had to build its online presence and do it quickly. As people move to shop online in larger numbers, being able to personalize that experience has become more crucial. That made the pandemic a pivotal moment for Bluecore, an e-commerce personalization platform, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">During the pandemic, especially when we were in lockdown, just about every retailer had to build its online presence and do it quickly. As people move to shop online in larger numbers, being able to personalize that experience has become more crucial. That made the pandemic a pivotal moment for <a href="https://www.bluecore.com/">Bluecore</a>, an e-commerce personalization platform, and today the company announced a $125 million Series E on a $1 billion valuation.</p>
<p>Existing investor Georgian led the round, with participation from other existing investors FirstMark and Norwest, along with new investor Silver Lake Waterman. Today&#8217;s investment brings the total raised to $225 million, according to the company.</p>
<p>Until fairly recently, Bluecore CEO and co-founder Fayez Mohamood says that retail outreach was mostly about driving traffic to brick and mortar stores or to the company website, but as more business gets conducted online, it has changed how brands have to interact with their customers.</p>
<p>&#8220;We believe in that shift, and Bluecore is a retail-specific, multichannel personalization platform, and we combine basically three types of data. First is customer identity. Second is shopper behavior. And then thirdly and most importantly, the product catalog of a retailer, and using that we drive personalized experiences on various channels,&#8221; Mohamood explained.</p>
<p>The company was founded in 2013, and has been able to evolve the notion of personalization since then in a significant way. Mohamood says the pandemic really pushed things into the digital realm where his company&#8217;s strength lies, and that&#8217;s one of the primary reasons they are taking on this funding.</p>
<p>&#8220;Personalization has always been important, but I think the value retailers can derive from it has dramatically accelerated as digital became a bigger and bigger portion of everybody&#8217;s revenue stream. And over the last year, that became even more critical,&#8221; he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hz5vTELACZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/boost-roi-with-intent-data-and-personalized-multichannel-marketing-campaigns/">Boost ROI with intent data and personalized multichannel marketing campaigns</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Boost ROI with intent data and personalized multichannel marketing campaigns&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/boost-roi-with-intent-data-and-personalized-multichannel-marketing-campaigns/embed/#?secret=hz5vTELACZ" data-secret="hz5vTELACZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As the company&#8217;s growth has accelerated, so has the hiring. In May 2020, Bluecore had 236 employees; today it has more than 300, and it&#8217;s shooting to be over 400 by the end of the year. He says that as he grows the company, diversity and inclusion is a crucial component to have the employee base reflect the diversity of the customers they serve.</p>
<p>&#8220;It starts with the executive team, so I&#8217;m extremely proud of the fact that on our executive team close to half our team is female. We have a committee that is represented by the core employees that is a diversity, equity and inclusion committee where we have thoughts and ideas and most most importantly actions on how we can build a better diverse, inclusive workplace. And that translates it into OKRs,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>As a Series E company with a billion-dollar valuation, Mohamood can see becoming a public company at some point, but it is not an immediate goal, as he pursues growth over profitability. &#8220;The way we think about it is we have this brand that&#8217;s going to help us invest in our product capabilities, our leadership capabilities and our go-to-market capabilities to build something that has the ability to [be a public company some day]. Having said that, we&#8217;re pursuing growth, and if that&#8217;s the goal, we find that staying private helps us do that,&#8221; he said. And with $125 million of runway, the company has plenty of freedom to take its time.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oA9KHHXnor"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/26/bluecore-raises-50m-for-its-first-party-ai-based-marketing-automation-tools/">Bluecore raises $50M for its first-party, AI-based marketing automation tools</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bluecore raises $50M for its first-party, AI-based marketing automation tools&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/26/bluecore-raises-50m-for-its-first-party-ai-based-marketing-automation-tools/embed/#?secret=oA9KHHXnor" data-secret="oA9KHHXnor" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/bluecore-lands-125m-series-e-on-1b-valuation-as-e-commerce-personalization-grows/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2186079</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elude raises $2.1M to show spontaneous travelers the best destinations for their budgets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/elude-raises-2-1m-to-show-spontaneous-travelers-the-best-destinations-for-their-budgets/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/elude-raises-2-1m-to-show-spontaneous-travelers-the-best-destinations-for-their-budgets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 13:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alex Simon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elude]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Erik Rannala]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FlightVC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frankie Scerbo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grayson Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mucker Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[StartupO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unicorn Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Upfront Scout Fund]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185839</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As more people dust off their luggage and passports after stowing them away during the global pandemic, Elude aims to show travelers a new way to take spontaneous trips.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As more people dust off their luggage and passports after stowing them away during the global pandemic, <a href="https://elude.co/">Elude</a> aims to show travelers a new way to take spontaneous trips.</p>
<p>The Los Angeles-based startup launched its travel discovery mobile app Thursday, a budget-first search engine that shows people how far their money will take them. The platform’s personalized onboarding experience customizes trip packages and offers future travel suggestions based on those preferences.</p>
<p>The idea for the company came three years ago from Alex Simon, CEO, and Frankie Scerbo, CMO, who met in college and bonded over their love of traveling and would do so together any time they had a long weekend. One New Year’s they tried planning a trip, but everything was too expensive. Not being able to find something on their budget, they came up with the idea for Elude.</p>
<p>Rather than searching by destination, Elude gathers information like budget, time frame and trip preferences (think beach versus mountains), then presents users with flight and hotel results for destinations they may never have thought existed or could be traveled to on their budgets.</p>
<p>The company taps into the same flight and hotel databases that all online travel companies use that store hundreds of thousands of flights and hotels and only suggests hotels with 3.5 stars and above.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2185849" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2185849" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2185849" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Elude_PressKit_12.gif" alt="" width="600" height="338" /><p id="caption-attachment-2185849" class="wp-caption-text">Elude app</p></div></p>
<p>The co-founders have now raised $2.1 million in seed funding led by a group of investors including Mucker Capital, Unicorn Ventures, Upfront Scout Fund, StartupO, Grayson Capital and Flight VC.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>When Erik Rannala, co-founder and managing partner at Mucker Capital, initially invested in Elude, it was before the global pandemic. However, he sees travel getting back to normal, though with flights now more expensive than before, more people are looking for travel deals, something that wasn’t being addressed until Elude came along.</p>
<p>Travel is “a massive category,” with most people in either “look mode” or “book mode,” with the money only being made in book mode, Rannala said. By taking a budget-first approach, Elude is bridging people from look mode to book mode more quickly.</p>
<p>“The way they have done it is to help people discover something new based on their budget that is available to book right now,” he added. “It’s a unique way to solve the problem and to give people a good deal.”</p>
<p>With millenials spending over<a href="https://www.thewanderingrv.com/millennials-travel-statistics/"> $200 billion annually</a> on travel, Elude’s goal is to reduce the hours of scrolling in search of a trip and more time actively booking vacations. Whereas competitors may show flights only or hotels only, Elude produces flight and hotel packages.</p>
<p>“In just a few clicks, we can show you, for example, that you could go to Barcelona for the same price as Miami,” Scerbo told TechCrunch. “If you knew that kind of information, you would take a better trip. This opens doors to taking a trip every few months instead of the one or two trips a year most people take.”</p>
<p>Prior to today, Elude was in private beta mode where the company had amassed some 40,000 people on the waitlist. Simon said.</p>
<p>Elude plans to use the funding to advance technology, marketing function, operations and customer support.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jxdSR1Oq1J"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/even-amid-the-pandemic-this-newly-funded-travel-startup-is-tackling-the-stodgy-timeshare-market/">Even amid the pandemic, this newly funded travel startup is tackling the stodgy timeshare market</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Even amid the pandemic, this newly funded travel startup is tackling the stodgy timeshare market&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/even-amid-the-pandemic-this-newly-funded-travel-startup-is-tackling-the-stodgy-timeshare-market/embed/#?secret=jxdSR1Oq1J" data-secret="jxdSR1Oq1J" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/elude-raises-2-1m-to-show-spontaneous-travelers-the-best-destinations-for-their-budgets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185839</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google’s Nest Cams and Doorbell get a refresh</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/googles-nest-cams-and-doorbell-get-a-refresh/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/googles-nest-cams-and-doorbell-get-a-refresh/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 13:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google nest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nest cam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185876</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday’s leak didn’t leave much to the imagination. And today’s big Nest reveal confirms pretty much everything we saw — which is precisely what happens when Google’s the one doing the leaking. Still, this morning’s announcement marks one of the biggest refreshes to Google’s home security line in recent memory, with updates to various configurations [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Yesterday’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608507/google-leaks-unannounced-nest-camera-doorbell-online-store">leak</a> didn’t leave much to the imagination. And today’s big Nest reveal confirms pretty much everything we saw — which is precisely what happens when Google’s the one doing the leaking. Still, this morning’s announcement marks one of the biggest refreshes to Google’s home security line in recent memory, with updates to various configurations of Nest’s security cam and doorbell.</p>
<p>Depending on how you count, Google’s announcing up to four devices today. The list includes: the Google Nest Cam battery, Google Nest Doorbell ($180, each), the $280 Google Nest Cam with floodlight and the $100 Google Nest Cam.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2185884" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2185884" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2185884" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-cam-Wired-Sand-with-maple-wood-base-5x4-1.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="819" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-cam-Wired-Sand-with-maple-wood-base-5x4-1.jpg 4000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-cam-Wired-Sand-with-maple-wood-base-5x4-1.jpg?resize=150,120 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-cam-Wired-Sand-with-maple-wood-base-5x4-1.jpg?resize=300,240 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-cam-Wired-Sand-with-maple-wood-base-5x4-1.jpg?resize=768,614 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-cam-Wired-Sand-with-maple-wood-base-5x4-1.jpg?resize=680,544 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-cam-Wired-Sand-with-maple-wood-base-5x4-1.jpg?resize=1536,1229 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-cam-Wired-Sand-with-maple-wood-base-5x4-1.jpg?resize=2048,1638 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-cam-Wired-Sand-with-maple-wood-base-5x4-1.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2185884" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>The Nest Cams feature a design that looks a bit like they stepped out of some Pixar movie. The $100 basic Nest Cam is a second-gen wired device, designed for indoor-use only. The $180 model, meanwhile, adds battery power and waterproofing, making it suitable for either indoor or outdoor use.</p>
<p>The company says it should get around three months of battery life on a charge, assuming your home has an average of nine to 12 recorded “events” a day. The numbers obviously fluctuate a fair bit, depending on how much action your house sees on a typical day. The AI/ML is trained to record specific activities, triggered by things like people, animals or package deliveries, depending on the setting.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2185885" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2185885" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2185885" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-Cam-with-Floodlight-US-SKU-night-close-5x4-1.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="819" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-Cam-with-Floodlight-US-SKU-night-close-5x4-1.jpg 6015w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-Cam-with-Floodlight-US-SKU-night-close-5x4-1.jpg?resize=150,120 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-Cam-with-Floodlight-US-SKU-night-close-5x4-1.jpg?resize=300,240 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-Cam-with-Floodlight-US-SKU-night-close-5x4-1.jpg?resize=768,614 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-Cam-with-Floodlight-US-SKU-night-close-5x4-1.jpg?resize=680,544 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-Cam-with-Floodlight-US-SKU-night-close-5x4-1.jpg?resize=1536,1229 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-Cam-with-Floodlight-US-SKU-night-close-5x4-1.jpg?resize=2048,1638 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-Cam-with-Floodlight-US-SKU-night-close-5x4-1.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2185885" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>“Building a camera that uses ML to recognize objects requires showing the ML model millions of images first,” Google writes in<a href="http://blog.google/new-google-nest-latest-cams-and-doorbells-are-here"> a blog post</a>. &#8220;Our new Nest Cameras and Doorbells have been trained on 40 million images to accommodate lots of different environments and lighting conditions. Thanks to a cutting edge TPU chip, our new cameras run an ML model up to 7.5 times per second, so reliability and accuracy are even better. 3. Works in any home: Nest Cam and Doorbell’s wire-free design.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2185882" style="width: 510px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2185882" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2185882" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-Doorbell-battery-Snow-lifestyle-A-5x4-1.jpeg" alt="" width="500" height="400" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-Doorbell-battery-Snow-lifestyle-A-5x4-1.jpeg 500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-Doorbell-battery-Snow-lifestyle-A-5x4-1.jpeg?resize=150,120 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-Doorbell-battery-Snow-lifestyle-A-5x4-1.jpeg?resize=300,240 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nest-Doorbell-battery-Snow-lifestyle-A-5x4-1.jpeg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2185882" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>I quite like the new streamlined design for the doorbell. Being battery powered means you can install it without having to futz with wiring. Without direct access to a hardwired chime, you can configure to ring through connected Google devices like Nest speakers and smart displays. Unlike the wired Nest Hello (which Google is keeping on the market), the new doorbell doesn’t offer continuous recording, owing to battery constraints. It should give you around three months of use, on average.</p>
<p>The new nest devices are up for preorder today in 18 countries and will go on sale August 24.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="469r4BzKMX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/27/googles-nest-doorbell-camera-plan-gets-a-package-detection-feature/">Google’s Nest doorbell camera plan gets a package-detection feature</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google’s Nest doorbell camera plan gets a package-detection feature&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/27/googles-nest-doorbell-camera-plan-gets-a-package-detection-feature/embed/#?secret=469r4BzKMX" data-secret="469r4BzKMX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/googles-nest-cams-and-doorbell-get-a-refresh/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185876</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Former Facebook teammates raise $10.4M in Sequoia-led round to launch features development</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/former-facebook-teammates-raise-10-4m-in-sequoia-led-round-to-launch-features-development/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/former-facebook-teammates-raise-10-4m-in-sequoia-led-round-to-launch-features-development/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 13:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[madrona venture group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Vernal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Statsig]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vijaye Raji]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Statsig is taking the A/B testing applications that drive Facebook’s growth and putting similar functionalities into the hands of any product team.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://statsig.com">Statsig</a> is taking the A/B testing applications that drive Facebook’s growth and putting similar functionalities into the hands of any product team so that they, too, can make faster, data-informed decisions on building products customers want.</p>
<p>The Seattle-based company on Thursday announced $10.4 million in Series A funding, led by Sequoia Capital, with participation from Madrona Venture Group and a group of individual investors, including Robinhood CPO Aparna Chennapragada, Segment co-founder Calvin French-Owen, Figma CEO Dylan Field, Instacart CEO Fidji Simo, DoorDash exec Gokul Rajaram, Code.org CEO Hadi Partovi and a16z general partner Sriram Krishnan.</p>
<p>Co-founder and CEO Vijaye Raji started the company with seven other former Facebook colleagues in February, but the idea for the company started more than a year ago.</p>
<p>He told TechCrunch that while working at Facebook, A/B testing applications, like Gatekeeper, Quick Experiments and Deltoid, were successfully built internally. The Statsig team saw an opportunity to rebuild these features from scratch outside of Facebook so that other companies that have products to build — but no time to build their own quick testing capabilities — can be just as successful.</p>
<p>Statsig’s platform enables product developers to run quick product experiments and analyze how users respond to new features and functionalities. Tools like Pulse, Experiments+ and AutoTune allow for hundreds of experiments every week, while business metrics guide product teams to build and ship the right products to their customers.</p>
<p>Raji intends to use the new funding to hire folks in the area of design, product, data science, sales and marketing. The team is already up to 14 since February.</p>
<p>“We already have a set of customers asking for features, and that is a good problem, but now we want to scale and build them out,” he added.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Statsig has no subscription or upfront fees and is already serving millions of end-users every month for customers like Clutter, Common Room and Take App. The company will always offer a free tier so customers can try out features, but also offers a Pro tier for 5 cents per event so that when the customer grows, so does Statsig.</p>
<p>Raji sees adoption of Statsig coming from a few different places: developers and engineers that are downloading it and using it to serve a few million people a month, and then through referrals. In fact, the adoption the company is getting is “bottom up,” which is what Statsig wants, he said. Now the company is talking to bigger customers.</p>
<p>There are plenty of competitors for this product, including incumbents in the market, according to Raji, but they mostly focus on features, while Statsig provides insights and ties metrics back to features. In addition, the company has automated analysis where other products require manual set up and analysis.</p>
<p>Sequoia partner Mike Vernal worked at Facebook prior to joining the venture capital firm and had worked with Raji, calling him “a top 1% engineer” that he was happy to work with.</p>
<p>Having sat on many company boards, he has found that many companies spend a long time talking about sales and marketing, but very little on product because there is not an easy way to get precise numbers for planning purposes, just a discussion about what they did and plan to do.</p>
<p>What Vernal said he likes about Statsig is that the company is bringing that measurement aspect to the table so that companies don’t have to hack together a poorer version.</p>
<p>“What Statsig can do, uniquely, is not only set up an experiment and tell if someone likes green or blue buttons, but to answer questions like what the impact this is of the experiment on new user growth, retention and monitorization,” he added. “That they can also answer holistic questions and understand the impact on any single feature on every metric is really novel and not possible before the maturation of the data stack.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jUqCErYxzD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/the-truth-about-sdk-integrations-and-their-impact-on-developers/">The truth about SDK integrations and their impact on developers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The truth about SDK integrations and their impact on developers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/the-truth-about-sdk-integrations-and-their-impact-on-developers/embed/#?secret=jUqCErYxzD" data-secret="jUqCErYxzD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/former-facebook-teammates-raise-10-4m-in-sequoia-led-round-to-launch-features-development/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185819</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
