<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 17:37:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Cutting out carbon emitters with bioengineering at XTC Global Finals on July 22</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/cutting-out-carbon-emitters-with-bioengineering-at-xtc-global-finals-on-july-22/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/cutting-out-carbon-emitters-with-bioengineering-at-xtc-global-finals-on-july-22/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 16:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[algiknit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alternative protein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bioengineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biotechnology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon footprint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cultured meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jennifer Holmgren]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LanzaTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orbillion Bio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2174697</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bioengineering may soon provide compelling, low-carbon alternatives in industries where even the best methods produce significant emissions. Utilizing natural and engineered biological process has led to low-carbon textiles from Algiknit, cell-cultured premium meats from Orbillion, and fuels captured from waste emissions via LanzaTech — and leaders from those companies will be joining us on stage [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Bioengineering may soon provide compelling, low-carbon alternatives in industries where even the best methods produce significant emissions. Utilizing natural and engineered biological process has led to low-carbon textiles from Algiknit, cell-cultured premium meats from Orbillion, and fuels captured from waste emissions via LanzaTech — and leaders from those companies will be joining us on stage <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extreme-tech-challenge-global-finals-presented-by-techcrunch?ref=aa110dd2add8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">for the Extreme Tech Challenge Global Finals on July 22</a>.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re co-hosting the event, with panels like this one all day and a pitch-off that will feature a number of innovative startups with a sustainability angle.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll be moderating a panel on using bioengineering to create change directly in industries with large carbon footprints: textiles, meat production, and manufacturing.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://www.algiknit.com/">Algiknit</a> is a startup that is sourcing raw material for fabric from kelp, which is an eco-friendly alternative to textile crop monocultures and artificial materials like acrylic. CEO Aaron Nesser will speak to the challenge of breaking into this established industry and overcoming preconceived notions of what an algae-derived fabric might be like (spoiler: it&#8217;s like any other fabric).</p>
<p><a href="https://www.orbillion.com/">Orbillion Bio</a> is one of the new crop of alternative protein companies offering cell-cultured meats (just don&#8217;t call them &#8220;lab&#8221; or &#8220;vat&#8221; grown) to offset the incredibly wasteful livestock industry. But it&#8217;s more than just growing a steak — there are regulatory and market barriers aplenty that CEO Patricia Bubner can speak to as well as the technical challenge.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.lanzatech.com/">LanzaTech</a> works with factories to capture emissions as they&#8217;re emitted, collecting the useful particles that would otherwise clutter the atmosphere and repurposing them in the form of premium fuels. This is a delicate and complex process that needs to be a partnership, not just a retrofitting operation, so CEO Jennifer Holmgren will speak to their approach convincing the industry to work with them at the ground floor.</p>
<p>It should be a very interesting conversation, so tune in on July 22 to hear these and other industry leaders focused on sustainability discuss how innovation at the startup level can contribute to the fight against climate change. <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extreme-tech-challenge-global-finals-presented-by-techcrunch?ref=aa110dd2add8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Plus it&#8217;s free!</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/cutting-out-carbon-emitters-with-bioengineering-at-xtc-global-finals-on-july-22/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2174697</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Android 12 will let you play games before they finish downloading</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/android-12-will-let-you-play-games-before-they-finish-downloading/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/android-12-will-let-you-play-games-before-they-finish-downloading/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 16:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play Store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google stadia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[play store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176165</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At its Game Developer Summit, Google today announced a new feature for Android game developers today that will speed up the time from starting a download in the Google Play store to the game launching by almost 2x &#8212; at least on Android 12 devices. The name of the new feature, &#8216;play as you download,&#8217; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At its Game Developer Summit, Google today announced a new feature for Android game developers today that will speed up the time from starting a download in the Google Play store to the game launching by almost 2x &#8212; at least on Android 12 devices. The name of the new feature, &#8216;play as you download,&#8217; pretty much gives away what this is all about. Even before all the game&#8217;s assets have been downloaded, players will be able to get going.</p>
<p>On average, modern games are likely the largest apps you&#8217;ll ever download and when that download takes a couple of minutes, you may have long moved on to the next TikTok session before the game is ever ready to play. With this new feature, Google promises that it&#8217;ll take only half the time to jump into a game that weighs in at 400MB or so. If you&#8217;re a console gamer, this whole concept will also feel familiar, given that Sony pretty much does the same thing for PlayStation games.</p>
<p>Now, this isn&#8217;t Google&#8217;s first attempt at making games load faster. With &#8216;<a href="https://developer.android.com/topic/google-play-instant">Google Play Instant</a>,&#8217; the company already offers a related feature that allows gamers to immediately start a game from the Play Store. The idea there, though, is to completely do away with the install process and give potential players an opportunity to try out a new game right away.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Like Play Instant, the new &#8216;play as you download&#8217; feature is powered by Google&#8217;s <a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2021/06/the-future-of-android-app-bundles-is.html">Android App Bundle format,</a> which is, for the most part, replacing the old APK standard</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2176169" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Google_Play_As_You_Download_Mid.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176169" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2176169" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Google_Play_As_You_Download_Mid.gif" alt="" width="1024" height="857" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2176169" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/android-12-will-let-you-play-games-before-they-finish-downloading/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176165</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft confirms it&#8217;s buying cybersecurity startup RiskIQ</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/microsoft-to-acquire-riskiq/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/microsoft-to-acquire-riskiq/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 15:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Azure IoT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud based software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kaseya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RiskIQ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SolarWinds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vulnerability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176145</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft has confirmed it&#8217;s buying RiskIQ, a San Francisco-based cybersecurity company that provides threat intelligence and cloud-based software as a service for organizations. Terms of the deal, which will see RiskIQ&#8217;s threat intelligence services integrated into Microsoft&#8217;s flagship security offerings, were not disclosed, although Bloomberg previously reported that Microsoft will pay more than $500 million [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Microsoft has confirmed it&#8217;s buying <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/riskiq/">RiskIQ</a>, a San Francisco-based cybersecurity company that provides threat intelligence and cloud-based software as a service for organizations.</p>
<p>Terms of the deal, which will see RiskIQ&#8217;s threat intelligence services integrated into Microsoft&#8217;s flagship security offerings, were not disclosed, although <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-07-11/microsoft-is-said-to-be-buying-cybersecurity-company-riskiq?sref=BAcrnccI">Bloomberg</a> previously reported that Microsoft will pay more than $500 million in cash for the company. Microsoft declined to confirm the reported figure.</p>
<p>The announcement comes amid a heightened security landscape as organizations shift to remote and hybrid working strategies.</p>
<p>RiskIQ scours the web, mapping out details about websites and networks, domain name records, certificates and other information, like WHOIS registration data, providing customers visibility into what assets, devices and services can be accessed outside of a company&#8217;s firewall. That helps companies lock down their assets and limit their attack surface from malicious actors. It&#8217;s that data in large part that helped the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/13/magecart-hackers-persistent-credit-card-skimmer-groups/">discover and understand Magecart</a>, a collection of groups that inject credit card stealing malware into vulnerable websites.</p>
<p>Microsoft says that by embedding RiskIQ&#8217;s technologies into its core products, its customers will be able to build a more comprehensive view of the global threats to their businesses as workforces continue to work outside of the traditional office environment.</p>
<p>The deal will also help organizations to keep an eye on supply-chain risks, Microsoft says. This is likely a growing priority for many: an attack on software provider SolarWinds last year saw affected at least 18,000 of its customers, and just this month IT vendor <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/05/kaseya-hack-flood-ransomware/">Kaseya fell victim to a ransomware attack</a> that spread to more than 1,000 downstream businesses.</p>
<p>Eric Doerr, vice president of cloud security at Microsoft, said: &#8220;RiskIQ helps customers discover and assess the security of their entire enterprise attack surface — <wbr></wbr>in the Microsoft cloud, AWS, other clouds, on-premises, and from their supply chain. With more than a decade of experience scanning and analyzing the internet, RiskIQ can help enterprises identify and remediate vulnerable assets before an attacker can capitalize on them.&#8221;</p>
<p>RiskIQ was founded in 2009 and has raised a total of $83 million over four rounds of funding. Elias Manousos, who co-founded RiskIQ and serves as its chief executive, said he was &#8220;thrilled&#8221; at the acquisition.</p>
<p>“The vision and mission of RiskIQ is to provide unmatched internet visibility and insights to better protect and inform our customers and partners’ security programs,&#8221; said Manousos. &#8220;Our combined capabilities will enable best-in-class protection, investigations, and response against today’s threats.”</p>
<p>The acquisition is one of many Microsoft has made recently in the cybersecurity space in recent months. The software giant last year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/22/microsoft-confirms-acquisition-of-cyberx-to-boost-security-in-its-iot-business/">bought Israeli security startup CyberX in a bid to boost its Azure IoT business, </a>and just last month it acquired Internet of Things security firm ReFirm Labs.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nXvokP3lpf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/equity-monday-cybersecurity-startups-see-deluge-of-capital-as-microsoft-looks-to-buy-riskiq/">Equity Monday: Cybersecurity startups see deluge of capital as Microsoft looks to buy RiskIQ</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Equity Monday: Cybersecurity startups see deluge of capital as Microsoft looks to buy RiskIQ&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/equity-monday-cybersecurity-startups-see-deluge-of-capital-as-microsoft-looks-to-buy-riskiq/embed/#?secret=nXvokP3lpf" data-secret="nXvokP3lpf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/microsoft-to-acquire-riskiq/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176145</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elon Musk defends Tesla&#8217;s $2.6B acquisition of SolarCity in Delaware court</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/elon-musk-defends-teslas-2-6b-acquisition-of-solarcity-in-delaware-court/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/elon-musk-defends-teslas-2-6b-acquisition-of-solarcity-in-delaware-court/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 15:26:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Powerwall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SolarCity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176148</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Elon Musk is testifying Monday morning in a lawsuit over Tesla’s 2016 acquisition of SolarCity, a $2.6 billion transaction that a group of shareholders allege was a “bailout” of the failing solar company. The shareholders are seeking repayment to Tesla of the cost to purchase SolarCity. The suit, filed in the Delaware District Court in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Elon Musk is testifying Monday morning in a lawsuit over Tesla’s 2016 acquisition of SolarCity, a $2.6 billion transaction that a group of shareholders allege was a “bailout” of the failing solar company. The shareholders are seeking repayment to Tesla of the cost to purchase SolarCity.</p>
<p>The suit, filed in the Delaware District Court in 2017, alleges that SolarCity was near bankruptcy at the time of the acquisition. Musk, who was the ailing company’s chairman of the board of directors and its largest stockholder, directly benefited from the transaction, as did some of his friends and family, the lawsuit alleges. SolarCity’s founders, Lyndon and Peter Rive, are Musk’s cousins.</p>
<p>SolarCity “had consistently failed to turn a profit, had mounting debt, and was burning through cash at an unsustainable rate,” the plaintiffs say. The suit goes on to note that the company had accumulated over $3 billion in debt in its 10-year history, nearly half of which was due for repayment before the end of 2017. The purchase by Tesla was approved by vote by 85% of shareholders.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Attorneys for Musk say that the acquisition was part of the CEO’s longer-term vision to transform Tesla into a transportation and energy company. In a blog post titled “<a href="https://www.tesla.com/blog/master-plan-part-deux">Master Plan, Part Deux</a>,” published to Tesla’s website around the time of the deal’s closing, Musk says that combining SolarCity and the electric vehicle startup was key to realizing his vision of combining Powerwall (Tesla’s home and industry battery storage product) and solar roof panels.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1463267" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1463267" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1463267" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/tesla-kauai-14.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/tesla-kauai-14.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/tesla-kauai-14.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/tesla-kauai-14.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/tesla-kauai-14.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/tesla-kauai-14.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/tesla-kauai-14.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/tesla-kauai-14.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1463267" class="wp-caption-text">A Model X stood ready for inspection by attendees at the Kauai solar storage facility launch. Tesla acquired SolarCity in November 2016. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Darrell Etherington</p></div></p>
<p>In his testimony Monday, Musk said Tesla was forced to shift focus away from its solar business to meet production deadlines for the Model 3 sedan, The Washington Post’s Will Oremus <a href="https://twitter.com/WillOremus/status/1414595938186932227">tweeted</a> from outside the courtroom. USA Today reporter Isabel Hughes, also at the courtroom, <a href="https://twitter.com/izzihughes_/status/1414598289475911682">tweeted</a> that Musk blamed the pandemic for poor performance of the company’s solar division. He was being questioned by attorney for the plaintiffs Randall Baron, whom Musk called “a shameful person” at a 2019 deposition.</p>
<p>Musk’s lawyers say that he recused himself from board discussions and negotiations relating to the acquisition &#8212; but the plaintiffs maintain that the recusal was “superficial.” A primary question for the court will be whether Musk exerted undue influence over the transaction, and whether he and other board members concealed information relating to the transaction from shareholders.</p>
<p>The other board members named in the suit &#8212; Robyn Denholm, Ira Ehrenpreis, Antonio Gracias, Kimbal Musk and Stephen Jurvetson &#8212; settled for $60 million last year, plus $16.8 million in legal fees and expenses, paid for by insurance. The trial, with Musk as the sole defendant, was postponed a year due to the coronavirus pandemic.</p>
<p>The trial is expected to last 10 business days. The Delaware Court of Chancery, where the suit is being heard, does not have a jury; instead, the case will be heard by judge Vice-Chancellor Joseph Slights III. Even if Slights finds that the deal was improper, he could order Musk to pay far less than the $2.6 billion that Tesla paid for SolarCity at the time.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2XW39Pjn2y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/eat-the-rich-but-let-them-build-rockets-in-the-meantime/">Eat the rich, but let them build rockets in the meantime</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Eat the rich, but let them build rockets in the meantime&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/eat-the-rich-but-let-them-build-rockets-in-the-meantime/embed/#?secret=2XW39Pjn2y" data-secret="2XW39Pjn2y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/elon-musk-defends-teslas-2-6b-acquisition-of-solarcity-in-delaware-court/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176148</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elevate Brands banks $250M to roll up third-party merchants selling on Amazon&#8217;s marketplace</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/elevate-brands-banks-250m-to-roll-up-third-party-merchants-selling-on-amazons-marketplace/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/elevate-brands-banks-250m-to-roll-up-third-party-merchants-selling-on-amazons-marketplace/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 15:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elevate brands]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175995</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Amazon roll-up play &#8212; where one company creates economies of scale by buying up and consolidating multiple smaller third-party merchants that sell their goods via Amazon&#8217;s marketplace &#8212; continues to be a strong e-commerce trend, and in the latest development, one of the hopefuls in this space is announcing a major injection of capital [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Amazon roll-up play &#8212; where one company creates economies of scale by buying up and consolidating multiple smaller third-party merchants that sell their goods via Amazon&#8217;s marketplace &#8212; continues to be a strong e-commerce trend, and in the latest development, one of the hopefuls in this space is announcing a major injection of capital to fuel its own place in the field.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.elevatebrands.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Elevate Brands</a>, a New York- and Austin-based startup that acquires and runs third-party Amazon merchants, has picked up $250 million in funding, money that it will be using both to continue investing in its technology, as well as to buy up more small businesses.</p>
<p>Elevate is already profitable, with 25 brands currently in its stable, many of which also have come to Elevate with patents for their products, CEO and founder Ryan Gnesin told TechCrunch. The plan will be to continue to enhance the systems it has in place for evaluating potential M&amp;A and analyzing the landscape overall &#8212; today its algorithms use some 100 million data points, it says, to find suitable acquisition targets &#8212; and to continue building out other organizational efficiencies.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Elevate&#8217;s funding is coming as a mix of debt and equity &#8212; quite standard for these e-commerce businesses that are raising huge rounds to go after the roll-up opportunity &#8212; with backers including a number of individuals and investors with track records in fintech and e-commerce. They include FJ Labs, Novel TMT, Adam Jacobs (who founded The Iconic in Australia), the founders of buy now, pay later business QuadPay, Intermix (acquired by Gap) founder Khajak Keledjian, Ron Suber (of YieldStreet and MoneyLion) and more. No valuation is being disclosed.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s <a href="https://www.feedbackexpress.com/amazon-1029528-new-sellers-year-plus-stats/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">estimated</a> there are some 5 million third-party sellers on Amazon today, with some 1 million sellers joining the platform in 2020 alone. Thrasio &#8212; one of Elevated&#8217;s larger consolidator-competitors &#8212; believes that around 50,000 of them are making $1 million or more annually in sales. Elevate estimates that the Amazon marketplace, currently valued at $300 billion, will double in the next five years.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, all that has led to a number of companies like Elevated racking up hundreds of millions of dollars in debt and equity to consolidate the most promising of these businesses. Their rationale: The founders and management of these third-party sellers may lack the appetite to stay with their businesses for the longer-term, or they may lack the capital to scale to the next level; so consolidating these businesses to leverage investments in technology for better market analytics, marketing, manufacturing and supply chains is the logical solution.</p>
<p>Given the size of the market opportunity, that&#8217;s led to a lot of investment. Thrasio has raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/thrasio-raises-100m-for-its-amazon-roll-up-play-appoints-retail-cfo-heavyweight-for-its-next-steps/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">nearly $2 billion</a> &#8212; in both debt and equity &#8212; for its efforts; Heyday recently <a href="https://heyday.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised $70 million</a> from General Catalyst; The Razor Group in Berlin <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/berlins-razor-group-raises-400m-to-buy-and-scale-amazon-marketplace-merchants/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised $400 million</a>. Others with huge war chests include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/target-global-leads-150m-round-for-amazon-marketplace-consolidator-branded/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Branded</a>; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/heroes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroes</a>; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/sellerx-raises-118m-to-buy-up-and-grow-amazon-marketplace-businesses/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SellerX</a>; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/perch-raises-123-5m-to-grow-its-stable-of-d2c-brands-that-sell-on-amazon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Perch</a>; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/berlin-brands-group-commits-302m-to-acquire-d2c-and-amazon-merchants/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Berlin Brands Group</a> (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/berlin-brands-group-raises-240m-to-buy-and-scale-up-third-party-amazon-marketplace-brands/">X2</a>); <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/benitago-group-funding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Benitago</a>; Latin America’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/valoreo-raises-50m-to-roll-up-latam-e-commerce-brands/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Valoreo</a> and emerging groups out of Asia including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/founded-by-former-carousell-ovo-and-fave-execs-rainforest-raises-36m-to-aggregate-asia-pacific-amazon-marketplace-sellers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rainforest</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/una-brands-launches-with-40m-to-acquire-brands-on-multiple-asia-pacific-e-commerce-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Una Brands</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SKEnADSIcL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/valoreo-raises-50m-to-roll-up-latam-e-commerce-brands/">Valoreo closes on $50M to roll up LatAm e-commerce brands</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Valoreo closes on $50M to roll up LatAm e-commerce brands&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/valoreo-raises-50m-to-roll-up-latam-e-commerce-brands/embed/#?secret=SKEnADSIcL" data-secret="SKEnADSIcL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Elevate&#8217;s pitch to the market is that it&#8217;s a little different from the rest of the roll-up pack, in that it started out as one of the millions of third-party sellers itself.</p>
<p>&#8220;We started selling at the end of 2016, testing the waters by selling a few private label products,&#8221; Ryan Gnesin, the CEO and founder of Elevated, told TechCrunch in an interview. That gave the company an early look at how to handle supply chains in manufacturing, and to think about how to differentiate its products from similar ones that are sold alongside them on Amazon. <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">By 2017, Elevate was managing some 8,000 SKUs under that model. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">That shifted in 2018 to a wholesale model, he said, reselling established brands on Amazon. It ran into trouble multiple times in that period, with Amazon shutting it down three times under suspicion of running counterfeit activities. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;We got caught up in an algorithm because we were scaling so quickly,&#8221; he said. &#8220;They assumed we were doing something wrong.&#8221; All of that helped Elevate learn how to navigate the waters more adeptly, with the first shut down taking three months to fix, but the second only one month, and the third a mere 24 hours. Eventually, in 2019, the company decided to take what it had learned and apply it to a wider range of brands, which it would pick up by way of acquisition.</p>
<p>&#8220;We began as third-party merchants and so we truly relate to them,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We didn’t just wake up and start buying Amazon businesses. This is what we are in our core, operators first. Anyone can buy a business, but the ones who can grow them are the most successful. That is our long-term view.&#8221;</p>
<p>Companies that become the target of roll-up acquirers are an interesting lot. As Gnesin describes it, in many cases the businesses Elevate talks to were built as side-hustles, and so when they take off, the founders are just as happy to pass them on to someone else for a decent exit than they are to stay the course. This is one reason why some of the acquisitions end up staying confidential, he said. Another is that the sellers are simply getting on, looking to retire and don&#8217;t have anyone to pass the business on to. Other times, this is just how entrepreneurs work. &#8220;If they make $5 million in a sale to Elevate, they will keep back $4 million for themselves, and use $1 million to start their next business,&#8221; he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LIw8kaGel1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/e-commerce-roll-ups-present-the-next-wave-of-disruption-in-consumer-packaged-goods/">E-commerce roll-ups are the next wave of disruption in consumer packaged goods</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;E-commerce roll-ups are the next wave of disruption in consumer packaged goods&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/e-commerce-roll-ups-present-the-next-wave-of-disruption-in-consumer-packaged-goods/embed/#?secret=LIw8kaGel1" data-secret="LIw8kaGel1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As for target companies, Elevate right now doesn&#8217;t focus on any specific product categories as other roll-up players might, although that may change in the future as the company gets more focused. What is a priority, however, is intellectual property &#8212; which to me is notable, given what sometimes feels like a genuine lack of differentiation when you look for products on Amazon.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have preferences for businesses with patents, since those tend to be more differentiated,&#8221; he said. From there, it goes to those that have strong traction and brand pull. &#8220;When a product is doing well on Amazon, there is an enormous amount of data there, and so you tend to have copycats. We look for business that can maintain a competitive position, adding new variations and taking that to other marketplaces. And all of that is important in the building of communities. If you can build it that gives you an additional competitive advantage.&#8221;</p>
<p>Acquisition valuations vary, he added, but on average are around four times a company&#8217;s EBITDA, but might go as high as five times or as low as 2.5x, depending on how competitive bidding is. Elevated&#8217;s acquisitions typically are already making between $2 million and $3 million in sellers&#8217; discretionary earnings, he added.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/elevate-brands-banks-250m-to-roll-up-third-party-merchants-selling-on-amazons-marketplace/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175995</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>MSCHF drops tiny action figures of your favorite failed startup hardware</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/mschf-drops-vinyl-action-figures-of-your-favorite-failed-startup-hardware/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/mschf-drops-vinyl-action-figures-of-your-favorite-failed-startup-hardware/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Panzarino]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 15:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coolest cooler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Juicero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MSCHF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theranos]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176032</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hardware is hard. You can browse the archives of this site and come up with dozens of bold attempts to make new consumer electronics gadgets work &#8212; some of them very close to home. But, like all startups, most hardware companies run into the hard-core grind of turning atoms into something worth buying.  To commemorate [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hardware is hard. You can browse the archives of this site and come up with dozens of bold attempts to make new consumer electronics gadgets work &#8212; some of them </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2009/11/30/crunchpad-end/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">very close to home</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. But, like all startups, most hardware companies run into the hard-core grind of turning atoms into something worth buying. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To commemorate the hardness of hardware, idea factory/art house MSCHF is releasing a set of five </span><a href="https://deadstartuptoys.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dead Startup Toys as vinyl figurines</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that you can buy for $39.99 each or $159.99 for the set. It bills these as &#8220;iconic failed startups&#8221; and the sales site offers a brief history of the rise and fall of each endeavor. They range from products that never really existed, like the Theranos minilab, to poorly timed early movers like Jibo, to exercises in over-engineering like Juicero. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Given that I have spent much of my career absorbing and trying to understand the difficult and complicated process of bringing consumer hardware to market, I love these things. There could be a lens of malice here, but I choose not to see it that way. Fraud is fraud and the people behind Theranos and debacles like the Coolest Cooler have or will see the business end of the legal system. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But big visions and hardware dreams are not always so clearly pocketed into the hole of &#8220;failure.&#8221; Sometimes the hardware works but the supply chain doesn’t. Sometimes the vision is sound but the product is just too early. There are any number of reasons products fail &#8212; but (in as much as they were actually real) you often have to give it up for the teams of people and visionaries that wanted a thing to exist in the universe and dragged it kicking and screaming to that point. And off the cliffs.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2176034" style="width: 1210px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/003.4f787ee.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176034" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2176034 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/003.4f787ee.jpg" alt="" width="1200" height="703" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/003.4f787ee.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/003.4f787ee.jpg?resize=150,88 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/003.4f787ee.jpg?resize=300,176 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/003.4f787ee.jpg?resize=768,450 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/003.4f787ee.jpg?resize=680,398 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/003.4f787ee.jpg?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2176034" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <span style="font-weight: 400;">MSCHF</span></p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The figures themselves are really well done, with crisp stamping and accurate detailing with readable text and nicely printed logos. Some of them are articulated as well, and accessorized. The Coolest Cooler gets its infamous blender and the Juicero has a removable (proprietary of course) &#8220;fresh veg&#8221; pouch. The quality on these is quite high overall; I’d rank them up with some of the better novelty toys I’ve bought over the years &#8212; it’s not phoned in, much like the Cooler’s feature set.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The packaging, too, is quite impressive; each gets a customized box and the big set of all of them comes in a bigger rack box. Each one also comes with a &#8220;cause of death&#8221; on the back that tells you why each venture went under. MSCHF went the lengths to make this a pretty premium &#8220;toy&#8221; drop, which is only fitting, given that it’s a monument to physical products. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As with much of MSCHF’s work, there’s an element of &#8220;wait, is this legal?&#8221; as well, because there are likely a bunch of holes that the IP connected to these products fell into but some of those holes could still have legal entities attached. But that element of danger is what has made many of its projects resonate so far. so I don’t think they’re worried. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After all, none of these products have the </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/08/style/satan-shoe-settlement-nike.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">sign of the beast on them</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Physically, anyway. (<strong>Image Credits:</strong> MSCHF)</span></p>
<p>[gallery ids="2176106,2176121,2176107,2176105,2176096,2176086,2176090,2176099,2176072,2176079,2176066,2176068,2176071,2176053,2176051,2176058"]</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="T4Y2X1ujM5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/from-surviving-to-thriving-as-a-hardware-startup/">From surviving to thriving as a hardware startup</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;From surviving to thriving as a hardware startup&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/from-surviving-to-thriving-as-a-hardware-startup/embed/#?secret=T4Y2X1ujM5" data-secret="T4Y2X1ujM5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/mschf-drops-vinyl-action-figures-of-your-favorite-failed-startup-hardware/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176032</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beyond Pride: The fight against tech’s brogrammer culture</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/beyond-pride-the-fight-against-techs-brogrammer-culture/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/beyond-pride-the-fight-against-techs-brogrammer-culture/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 14:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lgbtq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pride]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teacher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unconscious bias]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Companies that jump on the rainbow bandwagon without fully living those values aren’t only hypocritical — they’re also doing themselves a disservice.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Phil Schraeder</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/philschraeder">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/phil-schraeder-a971855/">Phil Schraeder</a> is CEO of <a href="https://gumgum.com/">GumGum</a>, the global technology and media company specializing in contextual intelligence.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">I was 4 years old when I started playing what I’ve come to think of as “the game.” It was dressing-up time at school, and, as I ran over to a costume box, my teacher grabbed me by the shoulders. Right up in my face, she admonished: “That’s the girls’ box — the boys’ stuff is over there.”</p>
<p>I was taken aback; I didn’t understand what I’d done wrong. But I remember thinking: “Oh! There are rules to how we live together in the world.” Right then and there, I started conforming to the parameter of the game that so many of us operate by: the game that gives us unwritten codes on what is acceptable and how to behave &#8212; at school, in work or in society at large.</p>
<p>This game meant I spent years dialing down my “gayness,” even after I came out in my 20s, and the impulse was particularly acute at the early stage of my career. With each new meeting or business deal, I was constantly preempting what parts of me were “OK”’ or what might put people off. Just how much gay was too much?</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In some ways, then, the endemic “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brogrammer">brogrammer</a>” culture in tech — the industry I call home — is no great surprise to me. When everyone is busy filtering their core identity, sanding down the edges to fit the collective mold, it’s inevitable that minority voices will be pushed out. Follow this picture to its natural conclusion and Silicon Valley — the home of bold disruptors, the armada of innovation — is reduced to a narrow few.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			With Pride Month drawn to a close, it’s my greatest hope that we can use its particular kind of open-minded energy to activate deeper change.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>In many ways, Pride Month and the celebrations we’ve just seen are the antidote to this hegemony. Pride, with its rainbow symbolism, is a cornucopia of all that is free, true and uninhibited. With Pride Month drawn to a close, it’s my greatest hope that we can use its particular kind of open-minded energy to activate deeper change.</p>
<h2>Show up for your team first</h2>
<p>I truly love Pride and the meaningful action that goes with it, but it can’t be denied that some brands are venturing into the territory of window dressing. <a href="https://realbusiness.co.uk/branding-corporate-performative-activism-pride">“Performative activism,”</a> whereby companies mobilize the Pride flag for marketing purposes without necessarily making tangible changes in their own backyards, is on the rise. So too are the businesses that pay lip service to Pride from one side of their mouth while covertly supporting politicians behind <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/20/the-right-way-for-brands-to-approach-pride-month-and-all-year-round.html">anti-transgender legislation</a> on the other.</p>
<p>If you are a leader who’s really committed to diversity in the workplace, it stands to reason that you look within to help your own team first. How can you create a culture where employees can be present in the fullness of themselves — regardless of gender, race, sexuality or even incidental things like taste in clothes or music?</p>
<p>According to a 2019 study by <a href="https://medicine.yale.edu/news-article/the-global-closet-is-hugevast-majority-of-worlds-lesbian-gay-bisexual-population-hide-orientation-ysph-study-finds/">the Yale School of Public Health</a>, an estimated 83% of those who identify as lesbian, gay or bisexual keep their sexuality hidden from all or most of the people in their lives.</p>
<p>This inhibition is magnified in the workplace, where it is woven into the fabric of myriad discriminatory behaviors that are particularly prominent in tech. Almost <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/lgbtq-employees-tech-companies-witness-discrimination-blind-survey-2019-6?r=US&amp;IR=T">40% of LGBTQ tech employees</a> polled by anonymous workplace chat app Blind say they&#8217;ve witnessed homophobic discrimination and harassment at work.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.wired.com/story/five-years-tech-diversity-reports-little-progress/">Annual diversity reports</a> show that Big Tech companies employ far fewer women and underrepresented minorities than other industries, too. This is a sector that routinely labels people from nonmajority culture groups as “diversity hires,” doling out discrimination in everything from pay to promotions &#8212; as reported by thousands of personal experiences shared under the hashtag <a href="https://eu.usatoday.com/story/tech/2020/02/10/racial-discrimination-persists-facebook-google-employees-say/4307591002/">#SiliconValleySoWhite</a>. The same industry is also <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/mar/17/sexual-harassment-silicon-valley-emily-chang-brotopia-interview">hardwired to marginalize women</a>, says Emily Chang, the Bloomberg Technology anchor whose book, “<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Brotopia-Breaking-Boys-Silicon-Valley/dp/0735213534">Brotopia</a>,” lifts the lid on Silicon Valley’s culture of machismo.</p>
<p>These aren’t easy issues to solve, but I believe authenticity has an important part in the solution. It’s about calling time on that game that I used to play. When I finally learned that I could show up as I pleased at work and not worry about how people judge me, the freedom was so sweet I could practically taste it. After years of faking it without fully realizing it &#8212; in a draining, relentless loop &#8212; I was able to be the person and CEO I wanted to be. The more familiar I became with California’s tech scene, and the farther up the ladder I progressed, the more confident I became to be me.</p>
<p>You shouldn’t have to wait until you run a company for the permission to express your full self, however. As the research shows, the price paid for not doing so reaches far beyond personal freedom alone. Though we’ve made steps with important conversations around diversity in recent years, the world we work in is still, overwhelmingly, one-dimensional. It’s full of people not able or willing to reveal the genuine, hi-def version of who they are.</p>
<h2>The power of listening and shared vulnerability</h2>
<p>If we, as tech leaders, are unable to roll our sleeves up and dig deep on the issue of authenticity, we have little hope of chipping away at the <a href="https://www.rand.org/blog/2018/05/ending-the-brogrammer-culture-how-to-close-the-gender.html">“brogrammer” attitude</a> that seems all too pervasive in our industry.</p>
<p>Not only does this kind of climate engender unsaid <a href="https://www.talkspace.com/blog/code-switching-what-is/">fear, fatigue and anxiety</a>, it also affects the bottom line. Research is clear on the fact that happy employees are <a href="https://www.ox.ac.uk/news/2019-10-24-happy-workers-are-13-more-productive">more productive</a>, while companies with more diverse management teams have greater <a href="https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2019/04/business-case-for-diversity-in-the-workplace/">profitability, creativity and problem-solving abilities</a>. Having the freedom to be your authentic self at work is a conduit to success and fulfillment.</p>
<p>So, how can tech CEOs and management get to this place? In my mind, a dual-sided approach is called for. First, efforts to harness authentic expression have to be enacted as policies. Leaders must give their teams direct responsibility for helping employees to bring their full selves to work. Help make your people accountable for an inside effort allowing all voices in your organization to be heard.</p>
<p>In GumGum’s case, this includes the formation of a STRIDE (Seeking Talent Representation Inclusion Diversity &amp; Equity) Council. Made up of employees from all divisions, locations and levels of seniority across the company, council members make tangible recommendations to improve diversity and inclusivity in the company as part of their paid daily roles.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.hcamag.com/ca/specialization/diversity-inclusion/five-myths-on-unconscious-bias-and-how-to-tackle-the-issue/259328">Unconscious bias training</a> is also vital for empowering authentic expression in the workplace. If I walked down the street in glitter shorts and a crop top, everyone around me would have some kind of reaction to my chosen outfit — regardless of whether they’d admit it. Building awareness of subconscious judgments like this is the first step to reining them in, and creates understanding of how bias inevitably impacts decision-making at work.</p>
<p>Second, the quest for business authenticity lies with CEOs and senior management and their ability to lead by example. I think today&#8217;s <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-54374824">cancel culture</a> has made leaders hypersensitive about the need to keep it together, to toe the line with their behavior, to be professional and not make mistakes.</p>
<p>Professionalism has its time and a place, of course, but I’ve always made it a point to be as open as possible as a CEO &#8212; to shine a light over every element of my personality, even the aspects that other people may judge or find less desirable. My determination to do this comes directly from the hidden identity that I used to struggle with. The fear I felt over being gay is now my fuel to showing my true self. By doing so, I aim to give those around me permission to do the same.</p>
<p>No one really wants their tech company to breed a bro culture where only one type of person can thrive. But it’s not enough to simply say that. You have to start by <em>showing</em> that it&#8217;s OK to be different, to turn up in every shade of gray. I have a penchant for flamboyant fashion, for example, so I don’t think twice about attending a Zoom meeting in a baby blue fedora. That’s just how I express myself as a CEO.</p>
<p>Showing up like this involves an element of fear, and I think it’s important to be open about that, too. As CEOs, we should share our vulnerabilities, our struggles with identity, the secret parts of ourselves that we’re tempted to keep masked away. This includes owning up to failures &#8212; CEOs are only human, and that humanity should be put on a pedestal if authenticity is the goal.</p>
<p>People need to feel that their vulnerabilities are heard without judgment. Whether they&#8217;re in an interview or taking on a new project, one of my favorite questions to ask employees is simply, “What are you afraid of?”</p>
<p>We all have fears, and by answering that question, you get to access someone’s vulnerable side. They might be scared of failing, making the wrong decision or upsetting the apple cart in some way. Tapping into that emotion is a great way of giving people permission to be their full selves.</p>
<h2>A turning point for tech</h2>
<p>Pride Month is part of a wider narrative around acceptance and freedom of being. Companies that jump on the rainbow bandwagon <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/20/the-right-way-for-brands-to-approach-pride-month-and-all-year-round.html">without fully living those values</a> aren’t only hypocritical — they’re also doing themselves a disservice. Pride isn’t a revenue opportunity, and even if it was, those brands that attach messaging to it without substance are missing a trick.</p>
<p>Beneath the LGBTQ+ Pride gift wrap lies a thousand work environments in urgent need of the values that the Pride movement espouses. Making those values a living, breathing part of everyday work life is no mean feat. But allowing people to untether from who they “should&#8221; be at work is a vital starting point for a change that is long overdue.</p>
<p>I know the shame of hiding my true self away, which is why I make every effort for others to avoid that experience. Nowadays, I show up at work as more myself than I’d ever dared in my younger years. In this one small act, I challenge my co-workers to follow suit. It’s only when, together, we embark on that exploration of what authenticity in business looks like that the endless game-playing can stop — and the real work gets underway.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rXqe5RUxvu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/despite-gains-gender-diversity-in-vc-funding-struggled-in-2020/">Despite gains, gender diversity in VC funding struggled in 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Despite gains, gender diversity in VC funding struggled in 2020&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/despite-gains-gender-diversity-in-vc-funding-struggled-in-2020/embed/#?secret=rXqe5RUxvu" data-secret="rXqe5RUxvu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/beyond-pride-the-fight-against-techs-brogrammer-culture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175569</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eat the rich, but let them build rockets in the meantime</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/eat-the-rich-but-let-them-build-rockets-in-the-meantime/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/eat-the-rich-but-let-them-build-rockets-in-the-meantime/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 14:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Space Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff bezos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[richard branson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175987</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Do you really want Bezos tackling child hunger? Do you want Musk trying to expand healthcare access? Do you want Branson to focus on voting rights? Hell no.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Richard Branson&#8217;s Virgin Galactic <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/virgin-galactic-and-richard-branson-celebrate-launch-of-first-passengers-into-space/">went to space (or the vicinity of space)</a> in a PR-suffused event over the weekend. It was all rather twee, packed with maudlin riffs about childhood dreams and riddled with hero worship. And the stream kept stuttering while some of the planned vehicle-to-Earth communications failed.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><b><i>The Exchange is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/startups-have-never-had-it-so-good/">continuing its look into Q2 venture capital results this week</a>. If you&#8217;re a VC with a hot take on the numbers, we&#8217;re collecting comments and observations at <a href="mailto:alex.wilhelm@techcrunch.com">alex.wilhelm@techcrunch.com</a>. Use subject line &#8220;hot dang look at all this money.&#8221; Thanks! &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/abracarioca">Anna</a></i></b></p>
<hr />
<p>But the launch accomplished what it set out to do: A few folks made it to into zero gravity after launching their rocket-powered space plane from a larger aircraft, flipping it around at the top of its arc so that its passengers could get a good view of our home while floating. Then it came back to the surface and, we&#8217;re sure, much champagne was consumed.</p>
<p>In the aftermath of the event, lots of folks are pissed. Complaints have rolled in, dissing the event and generally mocking the expense involved when there are other issues to manage. A sampling follows. Note that these are merely illustrative examples of a general vibe. I have precisely zero beef with anyone in the following tweets or articles:</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">How’s this headline:</p>
<p>Branson, Musk, and Bezos who could tackle child hunger, climate change, racial injustice, health care, the rise of fascism etc and still be richer than 99.9999% of us choose to be narcissistic assholes and shoot their money into space.</p>
<p>That about right?</p>
<p>&mdash; Mary L Trump (@MaryLTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/MaryLTrump/status/1414254171340124163?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 11, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Branson wants to bring space to the average person.<br />How about food?<br />let&#39;s do that one first.</p>
<p>&mdash; <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2728.png" alt="✨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/262e.png" alt="☮" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f499.png" alt="💙" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Kim Ruxton <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f499.png" alt="💙" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/262e.png" alt="☮" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2728.png" alt="✨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@KimRuxton) <a href="https://twitter.com/KimRuxton/status/1414271297501212677?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 11, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>And from the media side of things, <a href="https://tribunemag.co.uk/2021/07/leave-the-billionaires-in-space">this stood out today from the Tribune</a>:</p>
<p><a href="https://tribunemag.co.uk/2021/07/leave-the-billionaires-in-space"><img loading="lazy" class="breakout aligncenter size-full wp-image-2175992" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-12-at-9.08.21-AM.png" alt="" width="1024" height="425" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-12-at-9.08.21-AM.png 1146w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-12-at-9.08.21-AM.png?resize=150,62 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-12-at-9.08.21-AM.png?resize=300,125 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-12-at-9.08.21-AM.png?resize=768,319 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-12-at-9.08.21-AM.png?resize=680,282 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-12-at-9.08.21-AM.png?resize=50,21 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>I disagree.</p>
<p>Sure, it&#8217;s maddening that Jeff Bezos&#8217; new yacht will <a href="https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/politics/jeff-bezos-roasted-for-buying-yacht-so-big-it-comes-with-smaller-support-yacht/ar-BB1gEIEK">require a second boat</a> so that he can have a mobile heliport on the go &#8212; his new boat has sails, so you can&#8217;t chopper to it &#8212; while the company that built his fortune <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2021/06/15/us/amazon-workers.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=Top%20Stories&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage">churns through workers with abandon</a> and <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/amazon-drivers-peeing-in-bottles-union-vote-worker-complaints/">squeezes its drivers</a> so much that they have to piss in bottles due to scheduling constraints.</p>
<p>And, yes, Branson is annoying quite a lot of the time. He also owns an island and likes himself too much.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/eat-the-rich-but-let-them-build-rockets-in-the-meantime/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175987</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gembah raises $11M to &#8216;democratize product innovation&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/gembah-raises-11m-to-democratize-product-innovation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/gembah-raises-11m-to-democratize-product-innovation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ATX Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gembah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2174863</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gembah’s mission statement is a deceptively simple one. The Austin-based company says it’s looking to “democratize product innovation by drastically lowering barriers to entry for creation of new products.” In that respect, at least, it’s not so dissimilar from various startup initiatives that have arrived over the past decade, from crowdfunding to additive manufacturing. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Gembah’s mission statement is a deceptively simple one. The Austin-based company says it’s looking to “democratize product innovation by drastically lowering barriers to entry for creation of new products.” In that respect, at least, it’s not so dissimilar from various startup initiatives that have arrived over the past decade, from crowdfunding to additive manufacturing.</p>
<p>The company’s product is a platform/marketplace designed to guide users through the product-creation process, promising results in “as little as 90 days.” The forum connects smaller businesses to factories, supply chain experts, designers, engineers, etc. to help speed up the process. Just ask anyone who has attempted to launch a hardware startup &#8212; these things can be massively difficult to navigate.</p>
<p>To help accelerate its own vision, <a href="https://gembah.com/">Gembah</a> has raised an $11 million Series A, led by local firm ATX Venture Partners along with Silverton, Flexport, Brett Hurt, Jim Curry and Dan Graham.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2174867" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2174867" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2174867" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Gembah-Screenshot-Customer-Example-Trail-Buddy-2.0.png" alt="" width="1024" height="759" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Gembah-Screenshot-Customer-Example-Trail-Buddy-2.0.png 1172w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Gembah-Screenshot-Customer-Example-Trail-Buddy-2.0.png?resize=150,111 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Gembah-Screenshot-Customer-Example-Trail-Buddy-2.0.png?resize=300,222 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Gembah-Screenshot-Customer-Example-Trail-Buddy-2.0.png?resize=768,569 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Gembah-Screenshot-Customer-Example-Trail-Buddy-2.0.png?resize=680,504 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Gembah-Screenshot-Customer-Example-Trail-Buddy-2.0.png?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2174867" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Gembah</p></div></p>
<p>It follows a <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/exclusive-gembah-secures-3-28m-seed-funding-round-for-product-development-platform/">$3.28 million seed</a> round led by Silverton announced in April of last year, bringing its total funding up to $14.75 million.</p>
<p>The company says the pandemic has actually been something of a boon for its business model, as hardware startups are looking toward a more online model &#8212; and something a bit closer to home than the traditional sales channels. The company says its revenue grew 500% in 2020 and is on track to triple revenues this year. It&#8217;s impressive growth in the face of some major supply chain issues that have impacted the industry during the past year and a half.</p>
<p>It currently has 300 active customers, though it was yet to achieve profitability &#8212; hence the new round. “Since most of our customers are e-commerce companies we benefited from the accelerated growth of e-commerce,” CEO and co-founder Henrik Johansson tells TechCrunch. “Supply chains have been impacted to some degree, but as the global supply chain gets more complex and many companies want to diversify outside of China, they need help to navigate that change, and Gembah can help with that transition.”</p>
<p>The funding will go toward increasing the company’s engineering team. At present, Gembah has 55 employees in the U.S., and 19 in other locations, including Asia and Mexico. The new headcount will be focused on growing the marketplace, supply chain workflow and machine-learning capabilities. Gembah will also look to grow its global network and make additional hires in marketing and UI/UX.</p>
<p>“Gembah is a true innovator poised to help businesses capitalize on the growth of global eCommerce,” ATX Venture Partners&#8217; Chris Shonk said in a statement. “The Gembah marketplace promises to unlock virtually unlimited entrepreneurial equity by enabling a whole new breed of creators to enter the market.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LhObVh1L0w"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/21/5-predictions-for-the-future-of-e-commerce/">5 predictions for the future of e-commerce</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 predictions for the future of e-commerce&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/21/5-predictions-for-the-future-of-e-commerce/embed/#?secret=LhObVh1L0w" data-secret="LhObVh1L0w" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/gembah-raises-11m-to-democratize-product-innovation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2174863</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indian financial services firm MobiKwik looks to raise $255 million in IPO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/indian-financial-services-firm-mobikwik-looks-to-raise-255-million-in-ipo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/indian-financial-services-firm-mobikwik-looks-to-raise-255-million-in-ipo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 13:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[initial public offering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobikwik]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital India]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gurgaon-based mobile wallet service firm MobiKwik plans to raise up to $255 million in an initial public offering, becoming the latest Indian startup to explore the public markets. The 12-year-old firm, which counts Sequoia Capital India and Abu Dhabi Investment Authority among its investors and has raised about $250 million to date, plans to offer [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Gurgaon-based mobile wallet service firm MobiKwik plans to raise up to $255 million in an initial public offering, becoming the latest Indian startup to explore the public markets.</p>
<p>The 12-year-old firm, which counts Sequoia Capital India and Abu Dhabi Investment Authority among its investors and has raised about $250 million to date, plans to offer new shares of up to $201 million and sell up to $54 million worth of equity shares, according to papers submitted to the market regulator on Monday.</p>
<p>The firm, which allows users to pay digitally and also cross-sells a small sachet of insurance and loans as well as provides them with American Express-powered credit cards, is targeting a valuation of about $1 billion in the IPO, according to two people familiar with the matter.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2175999" style="width: 1010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175999" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2175999 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/mobikwik-ipo.jpg" alt="" width="1000" height="504" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/mobikwik-ipo.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/mobikwik-ipo.jpg?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/mobikwik-ipo.jpg?resize=300,151 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/mobikwik-ipo.jpg?resize=768,387 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/mobikwik-ipo.jpg?resize=680,343 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/mobikwik-ipo.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175999" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;We believe our key competitive advantages include our ability to (i) cross-sell; (ii) leverage data science and technology; and (iii) efficiently manage risk,&#8221; wrote MobiKwik in papers submitted to the market regulator on Monday. (Image: MobiKwik)</p></div></p>
<p>MobiKwik, which has amassed over 101 million registered users and 3.44 million online, offline and billing merchant partners, <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">said its total income for the financial year that ended in March 2021 was about $40.5 million, down 18%, while its loss also shrank 12% to $14.9 million during the period.</span></p>
<p>MobiKwik’s move comes as a handful of Indian startups, including Zomato and Paytm, are working to list on stock exchanges. Zomato, a food delivery startup in India, last week <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/zomato-ipo/">boosted its plan to raise $1.3 billion</a> in its initial public offering, which opens on July 14 and closes July 16.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Fi6xyWj8Yx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/zomato-ipo/">Zomato targets $1.3 billion IPO at as high as $8.6 billion valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Zomato targets $1.3 billion IPO at as high as $8.6 billion valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/zomato-ipo/embed/#?secret=Fi6xyWj8Yx" data-secret="Fi6xyWj8Yx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PXNjwuAqe9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/reading-the-ipo-markets-tea-leaves/">Reading the IPO market&#8217;s tea leaves</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Reading the IPO market&#8217;s tea leaves&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/reading-the-ipo-markets-tea-leaves/embed/#?secret=PXNjwuAqe9" data-secret="PXNjwuAqe9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/indian-financial-services-firm-mobikwik-looks-to-raise-255-million-in-ipo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175993</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Equity Monday: Cybersecurity startups see deluge of capital as Microsoft looks to buy RiskIQ</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/equity-monday-cybersecurity-startups-see-deluge-of-capital-as-microsoft-looks-to-buy-riskiq/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/equity-monday-cybersecurity-startups-see-deluge-of-capital-as-microsoft-looks-to-buy-riskiq/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 12:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybersecurity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flipkart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[richard branson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RiskIQ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175985</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. This is Equity Monday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/ac28381e-6148-4137-84de-6beb235386ef?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>This is Equity Monday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You can follow the show on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/equitypod">here</a> and myself <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">here</a>.</p>
<p>It was a busy weekend for everyone, regardless of whether you were watching the technology, what Branson was up to or the footie. I won&#8217;t take sides on the match, but I will say that it was gripping unto the very end and a great example of sport. Now, the news:</p>
<ul>
<li>Microsoft is said to be <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-07-11/microsoft-is-said-to-be-buying-cybersecurity-company-riskiq">hunting up the purchase of RiskIQ</a>, a cybersecurity firm. The deal is reported to be worth around $500 million.</li>
<li>And this weekend, Twitter began to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/twitter-appoints-resident-grievance-officer-in-india-to-comply-with-new-internet-rules/">conform with new regulations in India</a>, moves that come after it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/twitter-has-lost-liability-protection-in-india-government-says/">lost some legal protections</a> during a scrap with the Indian government.</li>
<li>China&#8217;s tech market has been busy: News is out <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/bytedance-shelvedipo-intentions-after-chinese-regulators-warned-about-data-security-11626078000?mod=djemalertNEWS">concerning ByteDance&#8217;s IPO delay</a>, Tencent is <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/exclusive-china-order-tencent-music-give-up-music-label-exclusivity-sources-2021-07-12/">being forced to drop some music label exclusivity</a> and the Chinese government recently <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/chinese-streaming-firm-douyu-terminates-%245.3-bln-merger-with-huya-2021-07-12">blocked a merger of streaming giants in the country</a>.</li>
<li>There&#8217;s big news out from Flipkart this morning, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/flipkart-valued-at-37-6-billion-in-new-3-6-billion-fundraise/">thanks to its recent and huge new funding round worth $3.6 billion</a>.</li>
<li>And returning to the cybersecurity theme from earlier, <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/funding-pours-into-cybersecurity-as-first-half-numbers-eclipse-last-years-total/">startups in the sector are having a lovely time raising capital in recent months</a>, it turns out.</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zYcNFgSDW4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/flipkart-valued-at-37-6-billion-in-new-3-6-billion-fundraise/">Flipkart valued at $37.6 billion in new $3.6 billion fundraise</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Flipkart valued at $37.6 billion in new $3.6 billion fundraise&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/flipkart-valued-at-37-6-billion-in-new-3-6-billion-fundraise/embed/#?secret=zYcNFgSDW4" data-secret="zYcNFgSDW4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>And don&#8217;t forget that earnings season is just around the corner. It&#8217;s a pretty important cycle. Why? Because startup valuations are hot, and could take a hit if earnings come up short. And the IPO market is pretty freaking active; poor earnings from major tech companies could crimp exit prices for mature startups.</p>
<p>OK! Talk to you on Wednesday!</p>
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 a.m. PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts!</i></p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/equity-monday-cybersecurity-startups-see-deluge-of-capital-as-microsoft-looks-to-buy-riskiq/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175985</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>VU raises $12M to remove cybersecurity friction from digital experiences</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/vu-raises-12m-to-remove-cybersecurity-friction-from-digital-experiences/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/vu-raises-12m-to-remove-cybersecurity-friction-from-digital-experiences/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 12:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybersecurity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Globant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sebastián Stranieri]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vu]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175927</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pretty soon, people won’t have to provide a fingerprint or a driver’s license to prove their identity — if VU has its way.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Pretty soon, people won’t have to provide a fingerprint or a driver license to prove their identity — if <a href="https://www.vusecurity.com/en">VU</a> has its way.</p>
<p>The Argentina-based fraud and identity protection company announced $12 million in Series B funding Monday from backers including software developer Globant, as well as Agrega Partners, NXTP Ventures, Bridge One, the IDB Lab and Telefónica. The new funding gives the company total venture-backed investments of $20 million, CEO Sebastián Stranieri told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Stranieri, who has worked in the cybersecurity industry for the past 20 years, got the idea for VU in 2007 after spending hours helping his grandmother verify her identity with the Argentinian government in what turned out to be a two-minute process.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“It pushed me to create a company to help create digital experiences without the friction,” he told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>VU’s technology takes a person’s “online persona” and uses geolocation, biometrics and user behavior analysis to provide identity verification for users and enable a continuous authentication process that sees and connects the users’ online and offline personas. Simply put, it works mainly with government entities in countries like Argentina and Ecuador, providing them a way to confirm if people are who they say they are.</p>
<p>VU is one of several startups applying technology to fraud and identity within a global digital identity market expected to reach over $33 billion by 2025, according to <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2020/07/14/2061673/0/en/Digital-Identity-Solutions-Market-to-grow-at-16-CAGR-to-reach-US-33-billion-by-2025-Global-Insights-on-Top-Trends-Expansion-Plans-Investments-Analysis-Key-Growth-Drivers-Leading-Pl.html">Adroit Market Research</a>. Companies recently capturing investment dollars for similar technology include Sift, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/fraud-prevention-platform-sift-raises-50m-at-over-1b-valuation-eyes-acquisitions/">raised $50 million</a> in April for a valuation of over $1 billion, and <a href="https://www.socure.com/">Socure</a>, which announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/socure-raises-100m-at-1-3b-valuation-proving-identity-verification-is-hotter-than-ever/">$100 million in Series D funding</a> at a $1.3 billion valuation.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WhCFNvMF49"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/socure-raises-100m-at-1-3b-valuation-proving-identity-verification-is-hotter-than-ever/">Socure raises $100M at $1.3B valuation, proving identity verification is hotter than ever</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Socure raises $100M at $1.3B valuation, proving identity verification is hotter than ever&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/socure-raises-100m-at-1-3b-valuation-proving-identity-verification-is-hotter-than-ever/embed/#?secret=WhCFNvMF49" data-secret="WhCFNvMF49" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In the past three years, VU has grown to more than 150 employees and is operating across Latin America and Europe, catering to big name customers like Santander and Prisma, and governments in Latin America. The company also opened its first office in New York, where Stranieri expects to more than quadruple headcount in the next year.</p>
<p>The company is averaging 85% year over year revenue growth, and he expects that to continue in 2021 with 100% growth forecasted for 2022. In addition to New York, VU opened an office in Madrid and will open offices in Italy, France and the United Kingdom.</p>
<p>As such, he intends to use the new funding to hire developers across Europe and in the U.S.</p>
<p>Globant’s investment into VU also serves as a partnership. Globant provides software development to the likes of Google, Disney and Apple. Together, they will package VU’s digital experience so that companies can purchase the basic software and then customize it. Currently, VU’s technology is suited for banks and to provide a one-click e-commerce checkout where a retailer’s system will recognize and confirm the buyer.</p>
<p>“Globant is changing the digital experience, so having their backing is a great message to our customers and partners that we are performing well,” Stranieri said. “Their backup and those of all of our investors provides an opportunity to take a risk and help us grow faster.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5HmEKWFQPJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/its-time-for-security-teams-to-embrace-security-data-lakes/">It’s time for security teams to embrace security data lakes</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;It’s time for security teams to embrace security data lakes&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/its-time-for-security-teams-to-embrace-security-data-lakes/embed/#?secret=5HmEKWFQPJ" data-secret="5HmEKWFQPJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/vu-raises-12m-to-remove-cybersecurity-friction-from-digital-experiences/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175927</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Station: Rimac-Bugatti is born, Tesla releases FSD beta v9 and Ola raises $500M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/the-station-rimac-bugatti-is-born-tesla-releases-fsd-beta-v9-and-ola-raises-500m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/the-station-rimac-bugatti-is-born-tesla-releases-fsd-beta-v9-and-ola-raises-500m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 12:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Station]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome to The Station, your central hub for all past, present and future means of moving people and packages from Point A to Point B. I&#8217;m back from my road trip and swimming in emails. If you sent me a message on Twitter, email or pigeon post, please give me a few days [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hello and welcome to The Station, your central hub for all past, present and future means of moving people and packages from Point A to Point B.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m back from my road trip and swimming in emails. If you sent me a message on Twitter, email or pigeon post, please give me a few days to dig out of the pile that awaits me.</p>
<p>You might recall that I mentioned I was off to do some backpacking and climbing in Grand Teton National Park and then eventually would make it to Yellowstone National Park. Yes, the crowds were real, especially for those who stuck to the traditional schedule of sightseeing between 9 a.m. and 5 p.m. I took the early morning and late evening approach and never encountered the infamous parking lot traffic jams.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It&#8217;s that tactic that allowed me to take a ride in an empty T.E.D.D.Y., the autonomous vehicle that is being piloted in Yellowstone this summer. Beep, in partnership with Local Motors, is operating the autonomous shuttle called T.E.D.D.Y., which stands for The Electric Driverless Demonstration in Yellowstone. The company plans to operate two routes, seven days a week. Information collected during the pilot will be used to inform future deployments in national parks across the country.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s what I discovered. The two shuttles, which always have a human operator who can take manual control if needed, are currently shuttling folks around the busy Canyons section of the park, specifically between the lodging area and main shopping area, where there is a general store, post office and eateries. The folks operating the shuttle told me about 1,240 people a week are riding the TEDDY vehicles and that riders were both curious and more knowledgeable about the tech than they expected.</p>
<p>My ride was on eventful, as it should have been. The vehicle did pause unnecessarily because the self-driving system thought it needed to. The human safety operator warned me that this pause would likely occur, as it had been happening regularly over the past few days.</p>
<p>One final item. <a href="https://twitter.com/theautonocast?lang=en">The Autonocast</a>, the podcast I co-host with Alex Roy and Ed Niedermeyer, is teaming up with SAE for a zoom call to have a wide-ranging discussion on the future of transportation and how the discourse about autonomous vehicle technology that occurs online — yes, Twitter I&#8217;m looking at you — impacts public perception. Specifically, we&#8217;re going to dig into a term coined by <a href="https://twitter.com/lizadixon?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor">Liza Dixon</a> called &#8220;autonowashing.</p>
<p>SAE MidCal, in conjunction with SAE SoCal, is hosting the meeting, which you can <a href="https://saesocal-org.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_vbQaj2qCSEyZLLt9bab7dw">register for here</a>. Please join us and post your questions in advance to get the conversation started.</p>
<p>As always, you can email me at <a href="mailto:kirsten.korosec@techcrunch.com">kirsten.korosec@techcrunch.com</a> to share thoughts, criticisms, opinions or tips. You also can send a direct message to me at Twitter — <a href="https://twitter.com/kirstenkorosec">@kirstenkorosec</a>.</p>
<h2>Micromobbin&#8217;</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1999054 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png" alt="" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-station-scooter1.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>With many people blissfully still on holiday after the fourth of July weekend, it was a slow week in the micromobility universe. One thing that did catch my eye though was an announcement from Stockholm-based e-scooter operator <strong>Voi</strong> that it launched the &#8220;world&#8217;s first large scale pilot of computer vision on e-scooters&#8221; using Irish computer vision startup Luna&#8217;s technology.</p>
<p>Now, I&#8217;m not quite sure what Voi means by &#8220;at scale&#8221; since the press release had no mention of how many of these scooters the company would be bringing to its pilot beginning this month in Northampton, U.K. However, the release did make reference to Luna&#8217;s AI models getting more accurate by using data captured from 100 cameras on e-scooters in the English city, so that&#8217;s at least 100 scooters. The problem is, Voi is by no means the first. Spin beat them to the punch.</p>
<p>Last month, Ford-owned <strong>Spin</strong> launched its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/ford-owned-spin-shakes-up-scooter-business-with-new-ceo-e-bikes-and-city-strategy/">Spin Insight Level 2</a> &#8212; its bundle of sensors, cameras and on-board computing power to detect sidewalk- and bike-lane riding and validate parking from its partner Drover AI &#8212; with 100 e-scooters in Milwaukee. Spin also has some computer vision-enabled scooters in Santa Monica, where it just launched, and will be bringing them to Seattle and Miami in the coming months.</p>
<h3>BMW is finally producing its electric scooter</h3>
<p><strong>BMW&#8217;s</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/bmw-is-finally-producing-its-retro-futuristic-ce-04-electric-scooter-but-at-12k-will-anyone-buy-it/">new electric scooter</a> is very cool-looking, with a retro-futuristic vibe and a low to the ground ride. But it ain&#8217;t cheap. At $12,000, is anyone gonna buy this thing? I guess we&#8217;ll find out. The first scooter actually produced from the Motorrad Concept Link series will be part of BMW&#8217;s 2022 lineup.</p>
<h3>More electric scooter news &#8230;</h3>
<p>Indian ride hailing company <strong>Ola</strong> has announced its giant e-scooter facility is ready and will soon begin production, with an expected launch this month. Late last year, the company invested $327 million to set it up, so we&#8217;ll potentially see the fruits of that investment. Apparently, Ola Electric has 3,000 robots building a scooter every two minutes, and the factory has 10 production lines, bringing total production capacity to about 10 million e-scooters.</p>
<p>According to a <a href="https://www.acutemarketreports.com/report/electric-kick-scooters-market">new report</a> by <strong>Acute Market Reports</strong>, electric kick scooters are expected to reach a market volume of 1.4 million units by 2028. The analysis found kick scooters are getting more popular as more people try to avoid public transportation, and that there&#8217;s a growing demand for longer range scooters for heavy usage. The report identified some of the key manufacturers of electric kick scooters to be Razor USA LLC, GOTRAX, Xiaomi, Segway, Inc., ZERO Electric Scooters, MINIMOTORS Co., Ltd., Kaabo Electric Scooter, Titan Group, Glion, and SWAGTRON.</p>
<p><strong>Helbiz</strong>, micromobility operator that recently went SPAC by merging with GreenVision Acquisition Corp, has <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/helbiz-partners-irengo-telepass-launch-120000016.html">announced a partnership</a> with IrenGo and Telepass to deploy 50 MiMoto electric mopeds throughout the Italian cities of Portofino, Santa Margherita Ligure, Rapallo, Paraggi and Punta Pedale. Hellbiz is the first and only operator in this region.</p>
<h3>What&#8217;s a newsletter without a hint of Lime</h3>
<p><strong>Lime&#8217;s</strong> e-bikes are officially in <a href="https://www.wkyc.com/article/news/local/cleveland/lime-e-bikes-now-available-downtown-cleveland/95-5ada4947-9822-4f42-94dc-1c7d516d7f17">downtown Cleveland</a> after the city issued permits allowing the bikes this year. The company started with 50 but will add more soon. Lime&#8217;s bikes will also be accompanied by more from Spin and Bird.</p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><em>— Rebecca Bellan</em></p>
<h2>Deal of the week</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1896226 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png" alt="money the station" width="1600" height="400" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=1536,384 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>The deal I&#8217;ve been waiting for is finally done. <strong>Rimac Automobili</strong>, the Porsche-backed Croatian company that makes electric hypercars and components for automakers, is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/05/vw-offloads-bugatti-to-rimac-to-form-new-ev-company-bugatti-rimac/">taking over <strong>Bugatti</strong></a>. Rimac will own a controlling 55% share in the new company, Bugatti-Rimac, with VW&#8217;s Porsche owning the remaining 45%.</p>
<p>A few nuts and bolts on the deal: Rimac is going to separate the development, production and supply of battery systems, drivetrains and other EV components into a new entity owned by Rimac Group called Rimac Technology, which will work independently with other global car manufacturers.</p>
<p>Founder Mate Rimac will continue to hold his 37% share in Rimac Group, with Hyundai Motor Group holding the same 12% and other investors at 27%. Porsche recently upped its stake in Rimac from 15% to 24%, but its total ownership doesn&#8217;t give It a controlling interest in the new EV company. Mate Rimac will lead Bugatti-Rimac, which will be headquartered in Zagreb, Croatia. Bugatti&#8217;s manufacturing will remain in Molsheim, France.</p>
<p>Mate Rimac was on our virtual stage in June and talked about the company&#8217;s future plans, including confirming that they were in talks with Bugatti. Extra Crunch members can watch the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/video/building-an-electric-powerhouse/">entire interview</a> or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/rimac-automobili-founder-mate-rimac-shares-lessons-from-bootstrapping-an-ev-company/">read a recap here</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CPLF3wlNV9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/rimac-automobili-founder-mate-rimac-shares-lessons-from-bootstrapping-an-ev-company/">Rimac Automobili founder Mate Rimac shares lessons from bootstrapping an EV company</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Rimac Automobili founder Mate Rimac shares lessons from bootstrapping an EV company&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/rimac-automobili-founder-mate-rimac-shares-lessons-from-bootstrapping-an-ev-company/embed/#?secret=CPLF3wlNV9" data-secret="CPLF3wlNV9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Other deals that caught my eye as I emerge from vacation mode &#8230;</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kurly</strong>, a South Korea startup that provides next-day grocery delivery services across the country, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/kurly-the-korean-grocery-startup-raises-200m-on-a-2-2b-valuation-after-shifting-ipo-plans-away-from-the-nyse/">raised $200 million</a> in funding in a Series F valuing the company at $2.2 billion. The company&#8217;s valuation has more than doubled in the last year. Last April, Kurly closed a Series E of $150 million at a $780 million valuation.</p>
<p><strong>Lacuna Technologies</strong>, a startup that helps cities create and enforce transportation policies by building and managing open-source digital tools, has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/lacuna-raises-16-million-in-series-a-to-help-cities-manage-mobility-via-digital-twin/">raised $16 million</a> in a Series A round, bringing the company&#8217;s total investment to $33.5 million. The round was led by Xplorer Capital Management, and includes Playground Global, the company&#8217;s founding investor. Participating investors include JetBlue Technology Ventures and Lauder Partners. Along with the funding news Lacuna is announcing the addition of Keith Nilsson, MP and co-founder of Xplorer, to the company&#8217;s board.</p>
<p><strong>MaxAB</strong>, an Egyptian startup based out of Cairo that serves a network of traditional food and grocery retailers across Egypt, has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/05/maxab-the-egyptian-b2b-food-and-grocery-delivery-startup-raises-40m-for-expansion/">raised $40 million</a> in Series A financing.</p>
<p><strong>Ola</strong>, the Indian ride-hailing giant, is flush with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/temasek-and-warburg-pincus-invest-500-million-in-ola/">$500 million in new capital</a> thanks to investments from Temasek and an affiliate of Warburg Pincus .Ola co-founder and chief executive Bhavish Aggarwal is also participating in the new investment, the startup said. Ola said in a statement that the investment comes &#8220;ahead of IPO&#8221; &#8212; but didn&#8217;t elaborate.</p>
<p><strong>Stellantis</strong>, the global automaker born out of a merger between Fiat Chrysler Automobiles and French automaker Groupe PSA, will <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/auto-giant-stellantis-to-invest-e30b-in-electrification-through-2025/">invest €30 billion</a> ($35.5 billion) in electric vehicles and new software over the next four years as part of a major push to transition away from internal combustion engines. Stellantis shared a few of its plans, including manufacturing an electric Dodge muscle car and an electric Ram pickup truck by 2024. Stellantis also said it would offer an electric or plug-in model in every vehicle segment under its Jeep brand by 2025.</p>
<p><strong>Volvo Group</strong>, <strong>Daimler Truck</strong> and Volkswagen&#8217;s AG heavy-truck business the <strong>Traton Group </strong>plan to<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/05/volvo-daimler-traton-invest-593-million-to-build-electric-truck-charging-network/"> invest €500 million</a> (~$593 million USD) to install and operate 1,700 charging points in strategic locations and close to highways for electric heavy-duty long-haul trucks and buses around Europe. The automakers intend to finalize the agreement by the end of this year and start operations next year, with the hopes of increasing the number of charge points significantly as the companies seek additional partners for the future joint venture.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="12OLNNnHo4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/05/volvo-daimler-traton-invest-593-million-to-build-electric-truck-charging-network/">Volvo, Daimler, Traton invest $593 million to build electric truck charging network</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Volvo, Daimler, Traton invest $593 million to build electric truck charging network&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/05/volvo-daimler-traton-invest-593-million-to-build-electric-truck-charging-network/embed/#?secret=12OLNNnHo4" data-secret="12OLNNnHo4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Zomato</strong>, a food delivery startup in India that competes with Swiggy, has boosted its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/zomato-ipo/">plan to raise $1.3 billion</a> in its initial public offering, which opens on July 14 and closes July 16. Zomato said it will price its shares in the range of 72 Indian rupees (96 cents) to 76 ($1) and is targeting an upper limit valuation of $8.56 billion. It plans to list on Indian stock exchanges.</p>
<h2>Policy corner</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-2037863 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png" alt="the-station-delivery" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/the-station-delivery.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>Welcome back to Policy Corner! The big news this week comes from across the Atlantic, where European lawmakers are planning to introduce a ban on the sale of new internal combustion engine vehicles by 2035.</p>
<p>Yep &#8212; less than 15 years from now. The ban would be phased in; countries would first be required to drop emissions from new vehicles by 65% by 2030, according to a document from the European Commission that was <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-07-09/europe-to-propose-end-of-combustion-engine-era-in-green-overhaul">viewed by Bloomberg</a>. The ruling would accompany a larger set of procedures for lowering greenhouse gas emissions across sectors, with the overall aim of reaching net-zero emissions on the continent by 2050.</p>
<p>News of a 2035 ban has been floating around for a while, but it seems that we&#8217;re now approaching the introduction of the proposal on July 14. Nor will it likely shock automakers, many of whom have been announcing their own ambitious zero-emissions targets. Fiat and Volvo have both set their own ICE phase outs in the continent by the end of the decade, for example. Volvo, along with Uber, also <a href="https://icephaseout.org/">signed a letter in support</a> of the ban in April.</p>
<p>If the ban is included in the final proposal, it would still need to be approved by European Commissioners before going into effect. We&#8217;ll be keeping our eyes out for that final proposal &#8212; I&#8217;m especially interested to see if it will include any mandates for installing EV chargers or other rulings to help spur the transition toward electric mobility. While many EU countries have already set electrification targets separate from the proposed mandate, auto-making remains a cornerstone of the economy in countries like France and Germany. Whatever ends up happening, it&#8217;ll likely be expensive.</p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><em>&#8212; Aria Alamalhodaei</em></p>
<h2>Notable reads and other tidbits</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1926823 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png" alt="" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>A short week + vacation means this won&#8217;t be as long as usual. (At least for me.) Let&#8217;s dig in.</p>
<h3>Autonomous vehicles</h3>
<p><strong>Yandex Self-Driving Group</strong>, a unit of the publicly-traded Russian tech giant, is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/yandex-self-driving-group-partners-with-grubhub-to-bring-robotic-delivery-to-college-campuses/">partnering with food delivery service GrubHub</a> to be its multi-year robotic delivery provider across American college campuses. Yandex hopes to reach over 250 campuses over the course of this partnership, beginning with dozens of robots in the fall, according to Yandex Self-Driving CEO Dmitry Polishchuk.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jXDuZFo6cj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/yandex-self-driving-group-partners-with-grubhub-to-bring-robotic-delivery-to-college-campuses/">Yandex Self-Driving Group partners with GrubHub to bring robotic delivery to college campuses</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Yandex Self-Driving Group partners with GrubHub to bring robotic delivery to college campuses&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/yandex-self-driving-group-partners-with-grubhub-to-bring-robotic-delivery-to-college-campuses/embed/#?secret=jXDuZFo6cj" data-secret="jXDuZFo6cj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Electric vehicles</h3>
<p><strong>Bentley Motors</strong> revealed its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/bentley-reveals-flying-spur-hybrid-its-latest-in-the-push-towards-electric/">newest hybrid model</a> that is<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> part of the company&#8217;s Beyond100 plan to become a carbon-neutral organization with an entirely electrified range by 2023 and a totally electric lineup by 2030. As Rebecca Bellan noted, that&#8217;s a tall order given the fact that the British company&#8217;s first all-electric vehicle isn&#8217;t expected to come to market until 2025. So far, Bentley only has this hybrid and another, the Bentayga SUV.</span></p>
<p><strong>Tesla</strong> has started the long-promised updates for its &#8220;Full Self-Driving&#8221; Beta v9 software. This is not full self-driving, which is why this item is housed under &#8220;electric vehicles.&#8221; Instead, this is an advanced driver assist system. But it&#8217;s important because this is the first &#8220;feature complete&#8221; version of the so-called FSD. This version also only relies on cameras and doesn&#8217;t include radar, a sensor that was previously used by Tesla&#8217;s advanced driver assistance system.</p>
<p>There are already a bunch of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7NW6mICjUvM&amp;t=1128s">videos</a> popping up on the beta V9 FSD. And while many folks are excited to have early access, what struck me was the numerous disengagements I viewed during these videoed drives. Check out this one on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OrHCz4wnW8g">unprotected left hand turns</a>.</p>
<h3>Other stuff</h3>
<p>The <strong>European Union </strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/eu-fines-bmw-vw-1b-for-running-emissions-cartel-since-the-90s/">issued fines of $1 billion</a> (€875 million) to<strong> Volkswagen</strong> and <strong>BMW</strong>  for their involvement in an emissions cartel. According to the EU, Volkswagen, Audi, Porsche, BMW and Mercedes-Benz parent company Daimler have been illegally colluding to restrict competition in emission cleaning for new diesel passenger cars, essentially slowing the deployment of cleaner emissions tech.</p>
<p><strong>Halo</strong>, the Las Vegas-based startup, is launching a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/halo-will-launch-a-remotely-operated-car-service-powered-by-5g-in-las-vegas/">remotely operated electric car service</a> powered by 5G. This is starting as a pilot with just five vehicles. Halo users can order a vehicles via an app. Once a vehicle is ordered, a remote operator will drive it to the waiting customer. The user takes delivery and then manually operates the vehicle until they&#8217;re done. When the trip is complete, the remote operator takes back over and drives it to the next waiting customer. The pilot is being conducted in partnership with T-Mobile.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RNgXj8Tm34"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/halo-will-launch-a-remotely-operated-car-service-powered-by-5g-in-las-vegas/">Halo will launch a remotely operated car service powered by 5G in Las Vegas</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Halo will launch a remotely operated car service powered by 5G in Las Vegas&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/halo-will-launch-a-remotely-operated-car-service-powered-by-5g-in-las-vegas/embed/#?secret=RNgXj8Tm34" data-secret="RNgXj8Tm34" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/the-station-rimac-bugatti-is-born-tesla-releases-fsd-beta-v9-and-ola-raises-500m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175935</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Controversial WhatsApp policy change hit with consumer law complaint in Europe</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/controversial-whatsapp-policy-change-hit-with-consumer-law-complaint-in-europe/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/controversial-whatsapp-policy-change-hit-with-consumer-law-complaint-in-europe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 11:42:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BEUC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Data Protection Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hamburg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175968</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook has been accused of multiple breaches of European Union consumer protection law as a result of its attempts to force WhatsApp users to accept controversial changes to the messaging platforms&#8217; terms of use &#8212; such as threatening users that the app would stop working if they did not accept the updated policies by May [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook has been accused of multiple breaches of European Union consumer protection law as a result of its attempts to force WhatsApp users to accept controversial changes to the messaging platforms&#8217; terms of use &#8212; such as threatening users that the app would stop working if they did not accept the updated policies by May 15.</p>
<p>The consumer protection association umbrella group, the Beuc, <a href="https://www.beuc.eu/publications/consumer-groups-file-complaint-against-whatsapp-unfairly-pressuring-users-accept-its/html">said today</a> that together with eight of its member organizations it&#8217;s filed a complaint with the European Commission and with the European network of consumer authorities.</p>
<p>&#8220;The complaint is first due to the persistent, recurrent and intrusive notifications pushing users to accept WhatsApp’s policy updates,&#8221; it wrote in a press release.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;The content of these notifications, their nature, timing and recurrence put an undue pressure on users and impair their freedom of choice. As such, they are a breach of the EU Directive on Unfair Commercial Practices.&#8221;</p>
<p>After earlier telling users that notifications about the need to accept the new policy would become persistent, interfering with their ability to use the service, WhatsApp later <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/whatsapp-is-doing-fine-despite-months-long-backlash-over-policy-update/">rowed back from its own draconian deadline</a>.</p>
<p>However the app continues to bug users to accept the update &#8212; with no option not to do so (users can close the policy prompt but are unable to decline the new terms or stop the app continuing to pop-up a screen asking them to accept the update).</p>
<p>&#8220;In addition, the complaint highlights the opacity of the new terms and the fact that WhatsApp has failed to explain in plain and intelligible language the nature of the changes,&#8221; the Beuc went on. &#8220;It is basically impossible for consumers to get a clear understanding of what consequences WhatsApp’s changes entail for their privacy, particularly in relation to the transfer of their personal data to Facebook and other third parties. This ambiguity amounts to a breach of EU consumer law which obliges companies to use clear and transparent contract terms and commercial communications.&#8221;</p>
<p>The organization pointed out that WhatsApp&#8217;s policy updates remain under scrutiny by privacy regulations in Europe &#8212; which it argues is another factor that makes Facebook&#8217;s aggressive attempts to push the policy on users highly inappropriate.</p>
<p>And while this consumer-law focused complaint is separate to the privacy issues the Beuc also flags &#8212; which are being investigated by EU data protection authorities (DPAs) &#8212; it has called on those regulators to speed up their investigations, adding: &#8220;We urge the European network of consumer authorities and the network of data protection authorities to work in close cooperation on these issues.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Beuc has produced a <a href="https://www.beuc.eu/publications/beuc-x-2021-063_report_-_whats_up_with_whatsapp.pdf">report</a> setting out its concerns about the WhatsApp ToS change in more detail &#8212; where it hits out at the &#8220;opacity&#8221; of the new policies, further asserting:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;WhatsApp remains very vague about the sections it has removed and the ones it has added. It is up to users to seek out this information by themselves. Ultimately, it is almost impossible for users to clearly understand what is new and what has been amended. The opacity of the new policies is in breach of Article 5 of the UCTD [Unfair Contract Terms Directive] and is also a misleading and unfair practice prohibited under Article 5 and 6 of the UCPD [Unfair Commercial Practices Directive].&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Reached for comment on the consumer complaint, a WhatsApp spokesperson told us:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Beuc’s action is based on a misunderstanding of the purpose and effect of the update to our terms of service. Our recent update explains the options people have to message a business on WhatsApp and provides further transparency about how we collect and use data. The update does not expand our ability to share data with Facebook, and does not impact the privacy of your messages with friends or family, wherever they are in the world. We would welcome an opportunity to explain the update to Beuc and to clarify what it means for people.”</p></blockquote>
<p>The Commission was also contacted for comment on the Beuc&#8217;s complaint &#8212; we&#8217;ll update this report if we get a response.</p>
<p>The complaint is just the latest pushback in Europe over the controversial terms change by Facebook-owned WhatsApp &#8212; which triggered a privacy warning from Italy back in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/confusion-over-whatsapps-new-tcs-triggers-privacy-warning-from-italy/">January</a>, followed by an urgency procedure in Germany in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/facebook-ordered-not-to-apply-controversial-whatsapp-tcs-in-germany/">May</a> when Hamburg&#8217;s DPA banned the company from processing additional WhatsApp user data.</p>
<p>Although, earlier this year, Facebook&#8217;s lead data regulator in the EU, Ireland&#8217;s Data Protection Commission, appeared to accept Facebook&#8217;s reassurances that the ToS changes do not affect users in the region.</p>
<p>German DPAs were less happy, though. And Hamburg invoked emergency powers allowed for in the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) in a bid to circumvent a mechanism in the regulation that (otherwise) funnels cross-border complaints and concerns via a lead regulator &#8212; typically where a data controller has their regional base (in Facebook/WhatsApp&#8217;s case that&#8217;s Ireland).</p>
<p>Such emergency procedures are time-limited to three months. But the European Data Protection Board (EDPB) <a href="https://twitter.com/EU_EDPB/status/1414533127511420928">confirmed today</a> that its plenary meeting will discuss the Hamburg DPA&#8217;s request for it to make an urgent binding decision &#8212; which could see the Hamburg DPA&#8217;s intervention set on a more lasting footing, depending upon what the EDPB decides.</p>
<p>In the meanwhile, calls for Europe&#8217;s regulators to work together to better tackle the challenges posed by platform power are growing, with a number of regional competition authorities and privacy regulators actively <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/18/perspectives-on-tackling-big-techs-market-power/">taking steps to dial up their joint working</a> &#8212; in a bid to ensure that expertise across distinct areas of law doesn&#8217;t stay siloed and, thereby, risk disjointed enforcement, with conflicting and contradictory outcomes for Internet users.</p>
<p>There seems to be a growing understanding on both sides of the Atlantic for a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/biden-executive-order-tech-antitrust/">joined up approach to regulating platform power</a> and ensuring powerful platforms don&#8217;t simply get let off the hook.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="z2FQ6UET98"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/18/perspectives-on-tackling-big-techs-market-power/">Perspectives on tackling Big Tech&#8217;s market power</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Perspectives on tackling Big Tech&#8217;s market power&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/18/perspectives-on-tackling-big-techs-market-power/embed/#?secret=z2FQ6UET98" data-secret="z2FQ6UET98" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jOyDxuLpXb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/whatsapp-is-doing-fine-despite-months-long-backlash-over-policy-update/">WhatsApp, growing despite backlash, relaxes May 15 policy update deadline</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;WhatsApp, growing despite backlash, relaxes May 15 policy update deadline&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/whatsapp-is-doing-fine-despite-months-long-backlash-over-policy-update/embed/#?secret=jOyDxuLpXb" data-secret="jOyDxuLpXb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Oj2abIPJMZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/confusion-over-whatsapps-new-tcs-triggers-privacy-warning-from-italy/">Confusion over WhatsApp&#8217;s new T&#038;Cs triggers privacy warning from Italy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Confusion over WhatsApp&#8217;s new T&#038;Cs triggers privacy warning from Italy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/confusion-over-whatsapps-new-tcs-triggers-privacy-warning-from-italy/embed/#?secret=Oj2abIPJMZ" data-secret="Oj2abIPJMZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dMEnhBr4Sg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/facebook-ordered-not-to-apply-controversial-whatsapp-tcs-in-germany/">Facebook ordered not to apply controversial WhatsApp T&#038;Cs in Germany</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook ordered not to apply controversial WhatsApp T&#038;Cs in Germany&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/facebook-ordered-not-to-apply-controversial-whatsapp-tcs-in-germany/embed/#?secret=dMEnhBr4Sg" data-secret="dMEnhBr4Sg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/controversial-whatsapp-policy-change-hit-with-consumer-law-complaint-in-europe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175968</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ex-SafeBoda executive Babajide Duroshola joins M-KOPA to lead expansion into Nigeria</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/ex-safeboda-executive-babajide-duroshola-joins-m-kopa-to-lead-expansion-into-nigeria/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/ex-safeboda-executive-babajide-duroshola-joins-m-kopa-to-lead-expansion-into-nigeria/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 09:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[m-kopa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SafeBoda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[west africa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175939</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On June 18, Babajide Duroshola, ex-Country Head, SafeBoda Nigeria, stepped down from his role two years after taking the job post-Andela. Less than a month later, the executive has found a new role as General Manager in Kenyan company, M-KOPA. His appointment coincides with M-KOPA&#8217;s broader expansion strategy, which includes a move to Nigeria. In [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">On June 18, Babajide Duroshola, ex-Country Head, SafeBoda Nigeria, <a href="https://babajiide.medium.com/and-its-curtains-call-755735f71ca3">stepped down</a> from his role two years after taking the job post-Andela</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Less than a month later, the executive has found a new role as General Manager in Kenyan company, M-KOPA</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">His appointment coincides with M-KOPA&#8217;s broader expansion strategy, which includes a move to Nigeria</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2019 when SafeBoda hired Duroshola, the Ugandan ride-hailing company was in the news for its imminent expansion to Nigeria</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. To the company and most of the public, Lagos was the obvious option. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">But Duroshola and his on the ground team chose to stay away from one of Africa&#8217;s most viable tech ecosystems and launch in neighbouring city Ibadan</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although it </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was considered</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a huge risk, the gamble looks to have paid off. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">While major ride-hailing platforms in Lagos like ORide, MAX.ng, and Gokada completely halted their operations in the state after a ride-hailing ban, SafeBoda thrived in Ibadan</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">By the time Duroshola left the company, it had onboarded 5,000 drivers and completed more than 1.5 million rides in a full year of operation</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cmn1mpyWzn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/the-motorcycle-ride-hailing-wars-in-nigeria-and-uganda-is-safebodas-to-lose/">The motorcycle ride-hailing wars in Nigeria and Uganda are SafeBoda&#8217;s to lose</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The motorcycle ride-hailing wars in Nigeria and Uganda are SafeBoda&#8217;s to lose&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/the-motorcycle-ride-hailing-wars-in-nigeria-and-uganda-is-safebodas-to-lose/embed/#?secret=cmn1mpyWzn" data-secret="cmn1mpyWzn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SafeBoda runs an asset-financing model when offering smartphones to its riders</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. M-KOPA has used t</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">his concept since its inception and it</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> played a major role in Duroshola&#8217;s decision to join the company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Part of the things that excite me asides from ride-hailing is the credit space. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I like asking questions on how to extend credits to people and help them build their digital footprints</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. That was why M-KOPA seemed attractive,&#8221; Duroshola said to TechCrunch. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">M-KOPA launched in Kenya ten years ago. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is known</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to have kickstarted the wider pay-as-you-go (PAYG) solar market in the country</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the years, M-KOPA has expanded its offerings to include televisions, fridges, other electronic appliances, and financial services to customers in Kenya and Uganda</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Through its pay-as-you-go financing model, customers can build ownership over time by paying an initial deposit followed by flexible and affordable micro-payments</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So far, M-KOPA has sold over 1 million PAYG solar systems and provided $400 million in financing to millions of customers while raising over $180 million in equity and debt</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last year, the company added <a href="https://technext.ng/2020/01/29/m-kopa-partners-safaricom-samsung-to-roll-out-a-pay-as-you-go-mobile-phone-plan-in-kenya/">smartphone financing to its offerings</a> in Kenya by partnering with Safaricom and Samsung</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Per a <a href="https://www.gsma.com/mobileeconomy/sub-saharan-africa/">GSMA report</a>, mobile technologies and services generated 9% of sub-Saharan Africa&#8217;s GDP in 2019, representing about $155 billion in economic value</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">And when you think about it, smartphones </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are used</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in people&#8217;s everyday lives more than solar systems, so it isn&#8217;t surprising that M-KOPA has already sold 500,000 smartphones, half the units solar systems have managed in a ten-year period.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Early this year, M-KOPA ran a pilot test in the Nigerian market by providing customers with its solar systems and smartphone financing options</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Smartphone financing had a higher uptake as M-KOPA sold over 20,000 devices in Lagos, its first market. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company considered this a success, and the appointment of Duroshola is seen as a prerequisite for </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">scaling the offering rapidly in Nigeria.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We’ve been deliberate about finding the right person with a strong track record and in-depth knowledge of the Nigerian tech community to lead our team as we scale up our country operations. And the milestone coincided with Babajide’s appointment as we look to grow and expand into new regions,&#8221; Mayur Patel, M-KOPA&#8217;s CCO, said to TechCrunch in an email.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">M-KOPA is now present in both Lagos and Oyo after expanding to the latter last month. Just as in Kenya, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">M-KOPA partnered with Samsung, but a different mobile network operator in Airtel, to make its smartphone financing accessible to Nigerian customers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Patel, both Nokia and Samsung provide entry- and mid-tier handsets at different prices to their customers</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. He argues that a top priority for MNOs on the continent is converting 2G/3G network users to 4G. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">To him, M-KOPA has a shot at tackling the challenge of 4G device affordability in Nigeria because 75% of its total customers are first time 4G smartphone owners</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Our partnership with both these OEMs has allowed M-KOPA to offer affordable ownership of quality 4G smartphones for underbanked customers, who are otherwise excluded because they lack credit histories or salaried incomes,&#8221; he said</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p>In Nigeria, M-KOPA deals with various products in the Samsung A series (A02, A12, A22, A32) ranging from $80-$250 (~₦40,000 to ₦125,000). <span style="font-weight: 400;">The company plans to include more devices and handset manufacturers, but the COO doesn&#8217;t say when</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Kenya and Uganda, however, M-KOPA sells Nokia phones in addition to the aforementioned Samsung products.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although M-KOPA is focused on smartphone financing in the West African country, Duroshola wants to mirror what Kenyan M-KOPA&#8217;s customers enjoy (where other products asides from smartphones are sold) in Nigeria</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. He reckons it will help build their credit history and worthiness over time.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Kenyan company is currently recruiting for engineering roles in Nigeria and globally as part of its expansion plans</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Duroshola will lead the charge in Nigeria in what can be described as his</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> third stint of scaling African startups in the country</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. He seems to have a knack for it. Judging from our conversation, there&#8217;s an optimistic feel about the general manager in his ability to take on a market where PAYG models outside solar systems have had relatively low success.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“My vision as a person and what </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">really</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">typically</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> drives me on a normal day is to help African startups scale and being that person that would help build, set up, get to the point where they&#8217;re able to think about their business strategy and how they can plug into the Nigerian space. What I&#8217;m looking to build with M-KOPA is a full credit machine. I want it to become a household name within the Nigerian market space where when people are thinking about pay-as-you-go financing for everyday use cases, M-KOPA is what comes to their mind.” </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jpkpX6o5lb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/04/28/solar-startup-m-kopa-leapfrogs-africas-electricity-grid/">Solar startup M-KOPA leapfrogs Africa&#8217;s electricity grid</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Solar startup M-KOPA leapfrogs Africa&#8217;s electricity grid&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2016/04/28/solar-startup-m-kopa-leapfrogs-africas-electricity-grid/embed/#?secret=jpkpX6o5lb" data-secret="jpkpX6o5lb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/ex-safeboda-executive-babajide-duroshola-joins-m-kopa-to-lead-expansion-into-nigeria/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175939</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flipkart valued at $37.6 billion in new $3.6 billion fundraise</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/flipkart-valued-at-37-6-billion-in-new-3-6-billion-fundraise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/flipkart-valued-at-37-6-billion-in-new-3-6-billion-fundraise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 06:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flipkart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175949</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Flipkart said on Monday it has raised $3.6 billion at a post-money valuation of $37.6 billion in what is widely believed to be the pre-IPO round for the Indian e-commerce conglomerate as it works to list in the public markets as soon as early next year. The new round of funding &#8212; by far the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Flipkart said on Monday it has raised $3.6 billion at a post-money valuation of $37.6 billion in what is widely believed to be the pre-IPO round for the Indian e-commerce conglomerate as it works to list in the public markets as soon as early next year.</p>
<p>The new round of funding &#8212; by far the largest for any Indian startup &#8212; was led by GIC, Canada Pension Plan Investment Board (CPP Investments), SoftBank Vision Fund 2 and Walmart, along with investments from sovereign funds DisruptAD, Qatar Investment Authority, Khazanah Nasional Berhad, Tencent, Willoughby Capital, Antara Capital, Franklin Templeton and Tiger Global.</p>
<p>The Monday investment marks the return of SoftBank as a shareholder of Flipkart. SoftBank, which had taken the exit from the startup when the Bangalore-based firm sold majority stakes to Walmart in 2018 at a valuation of $22 billion, has reinvested about $500 million in the new round.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;At Flipkart, we are committed to transforming the consumer internet ecosystem in India and providing consumers access and value. This investment by leading global investors reflects the promise of digital commerce in India and their belief in Flipkart’s capabilities to maximise this potential for all stakeholders,&#8221; said Kalyan Krishnamurthy, Chief Executive Officer at Flipkart Group, in a statement.</p>
<p>&#8220;As we serve our consumers, we will focus on accelerating growth for millions of small and medium Indian businesses, including kiranas. We will continue to invest in new categories and leverage made-in-India technology to transform consumer experiences and develop a world-class supply chain.”</p>
<p>As part of the new fundraise, Flipkart is also giving its employees the option to sell their stock options worth $80.5 million, Krishnamurthy told them on Monday.</p>
<p>Flipkart had originally hit the market to raise money early this year and was initially looking to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/flipkart-in-early-talks-to-raise-1-billion-ahead-of-ipo/">raise just about $1 billion</a>, TechCrunch first reported.</p>
<p>The Bangalore-headquartered firm competes neck to neck with Amazon in India. The American e-commerce group has invested over $6.5 billion in the South Asian market.</p>
<p>Both the firms are struggling to aggressively expand their footprint in India, where physical stores continue to drive the vast majority of retail sales. Both the firms are also expected to be severely hit by India&#8217;s new e-commerce rules</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="a5ICkENkPI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/india-proposes-tougher-e-commerce-rules-following-widespread-cheating-and-unfair-trade-by-amazon-and-flipkart/">India proposes tougher e-commerce rules to address &#8216;widespread cheating&#8217; complaints</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;India proposes tougher e-commerce rules to address &#8216;widespread cheating&#8217; complaints&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/india-proposes-tougher-e-commerce-rules-following-widespread-cheating-and-unfair-trade-by-amazon-and-flipkart/embed/#?secret=a5ICkENkPI" data-secret="a5ICkENkPI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>E-commerce platform JioMart, a joint venture between Reliance Retail (India’s largest retail chain) and Google and Facebook-backed Jio Platforms (India’s largest telecom operator), launched last year in over 200 cities and towns across the nation.</p>
<p>At stake is one of the world’s fastest-growing e-commerce markets that is poised to grow even further as more first-time internet users begin to shop online. India’s e-commerce market is estimated to reach more than 300 million shoppers by 2025, according to estimates by Bain &amp; Company. These shoppers would have bought items worth more than $100 billion from online platforms, the firm projected.</p>
<p>In recent years, Flipkart and Amazon have made a number of bets to expand their reach in India. Both of them have rolled out support for Hindi language (Flipkart has added several additional Indian languages as well), and partnered with neighborhood stores.</p>
<p>“Flipkart is a great business whose growth and potential mirrors that of India as a whole — that’s why we invested in 2018 and why we continue to invest today,” said Judith McKenna, President and CEO of Walmart International, in a statement.</p>
<p>Flipkart says it has amassed over 350 million registered users across its services &#8212; including fashion e-commerce Myntra &#8212; in the country. &#8220;Flipkart’s logistics and supply chain arm, Ekart, employs more than 100,000 people and makes deliveries to more than 90% of the addressable pin-codes in India, which, coupled with strategic warehouse infrastructure investments, is one of the group’s core strengths. Venturing into the social commerce space, Flipkart recently announced the launch of Shopsy, which will encourage local entrepreneurship,&#8221; the firm said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/flipkart-valued-at-37-6-billion-in-new-3-6-billion-fundraise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175949</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dovetail, the venture studio that has worked with startups like Afterpay, is raising a new fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/dovetail-the-venture-studio-that-has-worked-with-startups-like-afterpay-is-raising-a-new-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/dovetail-the-venture-studio-that-has-worked-with-startups-like-afterpay-is-raising-a-new-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 03:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AfterPay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Auckland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dovetail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dovetail Studios]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sydney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture studio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175945</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Based in Sydney and Auckland, Dovetail is a full-service venture studio that works closely with founders who have a great idea, but may lack technical backgrounds. Dovetail helps them build companies from the ground up, preparing them for growth and more funding. Founded in 2014, Dovetail’s success stories include Afterpay, the Melbourne-headquartered unicorn that is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2175946" style="width: 4042px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Ash-and-Nick.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175946" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2175946 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Ash-and-Nick.jpg" alt="A photo of Dovetail co-founders Ash Fogelberg and Nick Frandsen" width="4032" height="3024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Ash-and-Nick.jpg 4032w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Ash-and-Nick.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Ash-and-Nick.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Ash-and-Nick.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Ash-and-Nick.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Ash-and-Nick.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Ash-and-Nick.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Ash-and-Nick.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 4032px) 100vw, 4032px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2175946" class="wp-caption-text">Dovetail co-founders Ash Fogelberg and Nick Frandsen</p></div></p>
<p>Based in Sydney and Auckland, <a href="https://dovetailstudios.com/">Dovetail</a> is a full-service venture studio that works closely with founders who have a great idea, but may lack technical backgrounds. Dovetail helps them build companies from the ground up, preparing them for growth and more funding. Founded in 2014, Dovetail’s success stories include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/afterpay/">Afterpay</a>, the Melbourne-headquartered unicorn that is one of the highest-profile players in the buy now, play later space, along with Klarna and Affirm.</p>
<p>“People can think of us as the technical co-founder, responsible for driving and executing product strategy, design and the development of scalable products,” Dovetail co-founder Nick Frandsen told TechCrunch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Dovetail is currently raising a $10 million AUD (about $7.5 million USD) fund that will be used for seed, Series A and Series B rounds in 15 of the most promising companies that have gone through its venture studio program. As an investor, Dovetail has written check sizes ranging from $150,000 to $1 million AUD.</p>
<p>One of Dovetail’s goals is prepare startups to seek funding from other VCs; firms that have invested in Dovetail’s portfolio companies include Blackbird, Qantas and Wavemaker.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Z5SgEShOR6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/as-buy-now-pay-later-startups-keep-raising-capital-a-dive-into-klarna-afterpay-and-affirms-earnings/">As buy now, pay later startups keep raising capital, a dive into Klarna, Afterpay and Affirm&#8217;s earnings</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As buy now, pay later startups keep raising capital, a dive into Klarna, Afterpay and Affirm&#8217;s earnings&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/as-buy-now-pay-later-startups-keep-raising-capital-a-dive-into-klarna-afterpay-and-affirms-earnings/embed/#?secret=Z5SgEShOR6" data-secret="Z5SgEShOR6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“By the time we need to make an investment decision, we would have worked collaboratively on a day-to-day basis with them for at least three months prior to a seed round and 12 months for a Series A. This means we’re essentially investing with the informational edge of a co-founder,” said Frandsen. “Another trait that makes Dovetail unique is that we share our ownership in our portfolio companies with the entire team. This further drives unity, dedication and a desire to succeed from our team.”</p>
<p>Dovetail began working with Afterpay in 2017, when the company had less than 40 employees. Frandsen said Afterpay’s founders, Nick Molnar and Anthony Eisen, were looking for a digital product development partner to build and scale their mobile and web apps. While both had deep experience in financial services, they came from non-technical backgrounds. That’s where Dovetail came into play, building out Afterpay’s tech platforms and helping launch its consumer-facing products.</p>
<p>Some other notable startups that have gone through its venture studio program are resource planning SaaS platform <a href="https://www.runn.io/">Runn</a>; one-click invoicing tool <a href="https://www.withmarmalade.com.au/">Marmalade</a>; <a href="https://providerchoice.com.au/">Provider Choice</a>, a management platform for providers in Australia’s National Disability Insurance Scheme; <a href="https://www.landmarksid.com/">Landmarks ID</a>, a privacy-compliant mobile location intelligence platform for marketers; and <a href="https://www.fluenccy.com/">Fluenccy</a>, a service that helps importers and exporters save money on foreign exchange.</p>
<p>Before they started Dovetail, Frandsen and co-founder Ash Fogelberg’s startup, ticketing and payments platform 1-Night, was acquired by TicketDirect in 2013.</p>
<p>Dovetail’s venture studio is sector-agnostic (though it has strong experience in fintech, SaaS and marketplaces), and works with startups that may not have a product yet, but have founders who “are ambitious, commercially-savvy and bring industry expertise from the field in which they are trying to solve a problem,” said Frandsen.</p>
<p>When deciding what founders to work with, Dovetail considers at the viability and growth potential of their idea.This includes looking at how well-suited founders are to the issue, if there is enough market potential for the startup to grow into a large company and how much competition there is.</p>
<p>Dovetail has a product agency that serves mostly U.S. companies, but its venture studio is currently focused on Australasian startups, with plans to expand into North America in the future.</p>
<p>“We are actively seeking industries that are large yet underappreciated by the startup community,” Frandsen said. “We’re looking for ideas. that require hard-earned industry experience and can’t easily be replicated by teams of young aspiring entrepreneurs.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nYQJmOhJKK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/early-stage-venture-firm-the-fund-launches-in-australia/">Early-stage venture firm The Fund launches in Australia</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Early-stage venture firm The Fund launches in Australia&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/early-stage-venture-firm-the-fund-launches-in-australia/embed/#?secret=nYQJmOhJKK" data-secret="nYQJmOhJKK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/dovetail-the-venture-studio-that-has-worked-with-startups-like-afterpay-is-raising-a-new-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175945</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Virgin Galactic and Richard Branson celebrate launch of first passengers into space</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/virgin-galactic-and-richard-branson-celebrate-launch-of-first-passengers-into-space/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/virgin-galactic-and-richard-branson-celebrate-launch-of-first-passengers-into-space/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 18:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[astronaut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff bezos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[richard branson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space tourism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175878</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic has successfully taken its first passengers to space, including its billionaire founder Richard Branson. The event, at Spaceport America in New Mexico, was a field day for press and employees, complete with an early-morning Khalid set and hero walk by Branson and the crew. &#8220;Just imagine a world where people of all ages, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Virgin Galactic has successfully taken its first passengers to space, including its billionaire founder Richard Branson. The event, at Spaceport America in New Mexico, was a field day for press and employees, complete with an early-morning Khalid set and hero walk by Branson and the crew.</p>
<p>&#8220;Just imagine a world where people of all ages, all backgrounds, from anywhere, of any gender, of any ethnicity, have equal access to space,&#8221; Branson said on returning. &#8220;Welcome to the dawn of a new space age!&#8221;</p>
<p>The remark is a bit premature, of course — that world is still some distance off, but it&#8217;s true that this flight marks a historic moment in the nascent space tourism industry. At present, leisurenauts are still an elite class, but the events of the day suggest we&#8217;re closer than ever to seeing that change.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>After an incredibly early start to the day (shuttles to the Spaceport left at 2:45 AM from nearby Las Cruces), the festivities began in true space launch style with a delay. A thunderstorm overnight prevented the team from rolling out the spacecraft, which believe it or not can&#8217;t get wet. At the speeds and temperatures involved nothing can be left to chance — like ice forming from water in or on the chassis.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2175898" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/P1010053.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175898" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2175898" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/P1010053.jpg" alt="Press set up before dawn at Spaceport America." width="1024" height="654" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/P1010053.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/P1010053.jpg?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/P1010053.jpg?resize=300,192 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/P1010053.jpg?resize=768,490 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/P1010053.jpg?resize=680,434 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/P1010053.jpg?resize=1536,981 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/P1010053.jpg?resize=2048,1307 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/P1010053.jpg?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2175898" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Devin Coldewey / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>Soon the sun rose and crowds arrived: VIPs, employees, a bunch of local students, and Branson&#8217;s own guest list (reportedly numbering around 150). <a href="https://twitter.com/richardbranson/status/1414199651037716485">Elon Musk showed up as well</a>, presumably to congratulate his fellow spaceman personally, billionaire to billionaire.</p>
<p>At 8:30 local time the engines started on VMS Eve, the &#8220;mothership&#8221; carrying VSS Unity, the rocket-powered spaceplane that Branson, along with Virgin Galactic&#8217;s Beth Moses (her second flight), Sirisha Bandla, and Colin Bennett, would ride to the edge of space.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2175906" style="width: 1415px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/eve-takeoff.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175906" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2175906 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/eve-takeoff.jpg" alt="" width="1405" height="787" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/eve-takeoff.jpg 1405w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/eve-takeoff.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/eve-takeoff.jpg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/eve-takeoff.jpg?resize=768,430 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/eve-takeoff.jpg?resize=680,381 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/eve-takeoff.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1405px) 100vw, 1405px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2175906" class="wp-caption-text">VMS Eve takes off. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Virgin Galactic</p></div></p>
<p>Eve was wheels up at 8:40, commencing a wait on the ground while it climbed to about 36,000 feet. Unity detached and began its rocket-powered climb at about 9:24, reaching Mach 3 and after two minutes reached its peak altitude of about 282,000 feet — about 53 miles, as planned.</p>
<p>The crew and passengers enjoyed a minute or two of microgravity, which they seem to have employed gainfully:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2175909" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Unity-3_6.00_41_15_01.Still002.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175909" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2175909" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Unity-3_6.00_41_15_01.Still002.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Unity-3_6.00_41_15_01.Still002.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Unity-3_6.00_41_15_01.Still002.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Unity-3_6.00_41_15_01.Still002.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Unity-3_6.00_41_15_01.Still002.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Unity-3_6.00_41_15_01.Still002.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Unity-3_6.00_41_15_01.Still002.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Unity-3_6.00_41_15_01.Still002.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2175909" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Virgin Galactic</p></div></p>
<p>A planned mid-air speech by Branson proved impossible as the signal cut in and out, but the craft itself proved more reliable, touching down at 9:38.</p>
<p>In a celebratory stage appearance (following a brief Khalid concert) Branson expanded on the ideas cut short in transmission, beginning with: &#8220;It&#8217;s hot, I&#8217;m sorry,&#8221; but quickly moving on to more inspiring words. &#8220;I have dreamt about this moment since I was a child, but nothing could have prepared me for the view of Earth from space. We are at the vanguard of a new space age.&#8221;</p>
<p>At a press conference following shortly after, Branson fielded questions from elementary schoolers, and the crew described the view from space and whether they saw any planets. (No, just an alien that the pilot shook off during descent, Branson said. At least one kid I saw believed him.)</p>
<h2>A long road to space</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2086560" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Virgin_Galactic_Pilots_on_their_way_to_the_Virgin_Galactic_Spaceflight_System.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2086560" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2086560" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Virgin_Galactic_Pilots_on_their_way_to_the_Virgin_Galactic_Spaceflight_System.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Virgin_Galactic_Pilots_on_their_way_to_the_Virgin_Galactic_Spaceflight_System.jpg 2560w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Virgin_Galactic_Pilots_on_their_way_to_the_Virgin_Galactic_Spaceflight_System.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Virgin_Galactic_Pilots_on_their_way_to_the_Virgin_Galactic_Spaceflight_System.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Virgin_Galactic_Pilots_on_their_way_to_the_Virgin_Galactic_Spaceflight_System.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Virgin_Galactic_Pilots_on_their_way_to_the_Virgin_Galactic_Spaceflight_System.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Virgin_Galactic_Pilots_on_their_way_to_the_Virgin_Galactic_Spaceflight_System.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Virgin_Galactic_Pilots_on_their_way_to_the_Virgin_Galactic_Spaceflight_System.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Virgin_Galactic_Pilots_on_their_way_to_the_Virgin_Galactic_Spaceflight_System.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2086560" class="wp-caption-text">Virgin Galactic Pilots on their way to the Virgin Galactic Spaceflight System. <strong>Image Credits: </strong>Virgin Galactic</p></div></p>
<p>It&#8217;s a triumph long in the making for Virgin Galactic and Branson. The company was ahead of the curve in its space tourism ambitions, but in 2014 a test flight <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/10/31/virgin-galactics-spaceshiptwo-has-crashed/">ended in a horrific crash</a> and the death of one of the pilots.</p>
<p>Virgin&#8217;s engineers and leaders worked through it, however, and built a stronger, better spacecraft which was christened Unity by Stephen Hawking, who was then still living — and, not surprisingly, hoping to hitch a ride someday.</p>
<p>Pilots flew test flight after test flight over the years, slowly ratcheting up the power and finally, in 2018, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/13/virgin-galactic-touches-the-edge-of-space-with-mach-2-9-test-flight-of-spaceshiptwo/">touching the edge of space</a>. On that note there is some slight controversy in that the exact altitude where the atmosphere gives way to space isn&#8217;t completely agreed upon. Some authorities place the Kármán line, as the imaginary boundary is called, at 100 kilometers above sea level, others at 50 miles, or about 80 kilometers.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2175922" style="width: 1930px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/virgin-galactic-u22-space.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175922" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2175922 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/virgin-galactic-u22-space.jpg" alt="" width="1920" height="1080" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/virgin-galactic-u22-space.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/virgin-galactic-u22-space.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/virgin-galactic-u22-space.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/virgin-galactic-u22-space.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/virgin-galactic-u22-space.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/virgin-galactic-u22-space.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/virgin-galactic-u22-space.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2175922" class="wp-caption-text">Unity 22 spreads its &#8220;feathers&#8221; during descent. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Virgin Galactic</p></div></p>
<p>Virgin uses the lower estimate, while its arch rival, Jeff Bezos&#8217;s Blue Origin, uses the higher. This led Bezos to throw shade on Virgin&#8217;s flights, saying he didn&#8217;t want his customers to have an &#8220;asterisk&#8221; on their trip to space. When I asked about this before, a Virgin representative said they use the same standard that NASA and the U.S. Air Force does: pilots are given their &#8220;astronaut wings&#8221; if they pass the 50-mile mark.</p>
<p>Kármán quibbles aside, the race to send passengers to space has been heating up lately, and Bezos recently announced that he would be flying aboard the first crewed launch of Blue Origin&#8217;s New Shepard rocket on July 22 — with his brother, a mystery passenger who has paid $28M for the privilege, and Wally Funk, among the first women trained to be astronauts in 1961 but who never made it to space.</p>
<p>But Branson rained on his parade by announcing shortly afterward that he would fly aboard Virgin&#8217;s first passenger launch to space (crew and pilots have been up several times) about a week earlier.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YOtB7mXPck"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/branson-aims-to-beat-bezos-to-orbit-in-final-stretch-of-billionaire-space-race/">Branson aims to beat Bezos to orbit in final stretch of billionaire space race</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Branson aims to beat Bezos to orbit in final stretch of billionaire space race&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/branson-aims-to-beat-bezos-to-orbit-in-final-stretch-of-billionaire-space-race/embed/#?secret=YOtB7mXPck" data-secret="YOtB7mXPck" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>While Branson has good-naturedly denied any competition between himself and Bezos (&#8220;We wish Jeff the absolute best,&#8221; he said, adding that Bezos sent over a message of goodwill before the flight) it&#8217;s hard to believe that&#8217;s completely true. Though neither man has anything to prove at this point, there must surely be some satisfaction in Branson&#8217;s not merely going to space (a lifelong dream, as he tells it) but doing so before his upstart rival. However much he denies it, the narrative is too tempting to quash completely.</p>
<p>The direction forward for Virgin Galactic now is, clearly, towards paying customers, of which there are plenty lined up. Of course, they all have a quarter of a million dollars to spare, but you might not, and for you Branson has a special offer. <a href="https://www.omaze.com/products/virgin-galactic-2021">They&#8217;ve partnered with Omaze</a>, and donations to the chosen charity will enter you into a raffle of sorts, with the winner receiving two tickets on an upcoming Virgin Galactic flight. &#8220;And with my Willy Wonka hat on, a guided tour of Spaceport America, given by yours truly,&#8221; Branson added.</p>
<p>Branson expressed hope that this would become an ongoing thing as long as donations continue, so perhaps this is the answer to the question of how they hope to, as he so frequently promises, make space available to <em>everyone</em>.</p>
<p>You can watch the whole day unfold as it happened in Virgin Galactic&#8217;s archived livestream below:</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RTpWYWIfP7Y?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/virgin-galactic-and-richard-branson-celebrate-launch-of-first-passengers-into-space/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175878</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Retail Zipline&#8217;s Series A pitch deck ticked every box for Emergence Capital</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/how-retail-ziplines-series-a-pitch-deck-ticked-every-box-for-emergence-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/how-retail-ziplines-series-a-pitch-deck-ticked-every-box-for-emergence-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 15:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ECL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Ecommerce and D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emergence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Live]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Retail Zipline]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2172627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["She pointed to the screen projected behind her to help us stay on the most relevant piece of information. The way she did it really made us stay with her. Like, we couldn't break eye contact."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Melissa Wong spent more than a decade working for major retail brands before founding Retail Zipline. That kind of outrageous advantage &#8212; a complete understanding of the industry &#8212; is something that investors struggle to resist in a vertical SaaS company. At least, according to Emergence Capital investor Lotti Siniscalco.</p>
<p>Wong and Siniscalco joined us on a recent episode of Extra Crunch Live and went into detail on why Emergence was eager to finance Retail Zipline&#8217;s Series A round, walking us through Zipline&#8217;s Series A pitch deck and sharing which slides and bits clinched the deal.</p>
<p>Extra Crunch Live is a weekly virtual event series meant to help founders build better venture-backed businesses. We sit down with investors and the founders they finance to hear what brought them together, what they saw in each other and how they work together moving forward. We also host the ECL pitch-off, where founders in the audience can pitch their startups to our outstanding speakers.</p>
<p>Extra Crunch Live is accessible to everyone on a live basis, but the on-demand content is reserved exclusively for Extra Crunch members. You can check out the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/check-out-the-expert-speakers-joining-us-on-extra-crunch-live-in-july/">July slate here</a> and see the full <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">ECL library here</a>.</p>
<h2>Stand up, stand out</h2>
<p>During Wong&#8217;s fundraising process, Zipline was also attending a big industry conference. Emergence suggested that they do a virtual pitch meeting while Wong was at the trade show, but Wong pushed back, insisting on an in-person pitch meeting. Not only did she know that she would deliver a better pitch in person, but she didn&#8217;t want to squander the limited amount of time she had at the trade show with potential clients and partners.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			&#8220;She pointed to the screen projected behind her to help us stay on the most relevant piece of information. The way she did it really made us stay with her. Like, we couldn&#8217;t break eye contact.&#8221;					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Once the in-person meeting did take place, Wong surprised the Emergence team. For one, she stood up to pitch. Wong explained that her co-founder is a bigger guy, and she&#8217;s a smaller woman, and she feels more confident and comfortable presenting from a standing position.</p>
<p>&#8220;She was one of the few or maybe the only CEO who ever stood up to pitch the entire team,&#8221; said Siniscalco. &#8220;She pointed to the screen projected behind her to help us stay on the most relevant piece of information. The way she did it really made us stay with her. Like, we couldn&#8217;t break eye contact.&#8221;</p>
<p>In terms of delivery, Wong had already made an impact. But the content of the deck, and her experience in retail, clinched the deal.</p>
<p>&#8220;I look for an unfair reason for a founder to be the perfect person to build this product,&#8221; said Siniscalco. &#8220;Wong gave us her background in the first slide, and I knew quickly that she was a credible person in the retail industry. Then, what I look for in a pitch, is customer love.&#8221;</p>
<p>Siniscalco said the combination of that unfair advantage and intense customer love is highly correlated with a very positive outcome for a company.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we first started out, I was really insecure <em>because</em> I came from the industry versus coming from a lot of Silicon Valley knowledge,&#8221; said Wong. &#8220;In retrospect, I really underestimated the competitive advantage of coming from the industry. People said it to me, but I didn&#8217;t understand what that resulted in. But it resulted in the numbers in our deck, because I know what customers want, what they want to buy next, how to keep them happy and I was able to be way more capital-efficient.&#8221;</p>
<h2>The Zipline deck</h2>
<p>Zipline&#8217;s entire deck (with some minor redactions) is embedded below. You can swipe on through at your leisure, but the real value here (in my humble opinion) is Siniscalco&#8217;s breakdown of how she reacted to the information in the deck. I&#8217;ll relay that here in text, but I also strongly suggest you watch (at least) the first half of the episode below to hear the founder/investor duo walk us through this deck.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/how-retail-ziplines-series-a-pitch-deck-ticked-every-box-for-emergence-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2172627</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter appoints resident grievance officer in India to comply with new internet rules</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/twitter-appoints-resident-grievance-officer-in-india-to-comply-with-new-internet-rules/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/twitter-appoints-resident-grievance-officer-in-india-to-comply-with-new-internet-rules/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 06:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter india]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175890</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter has appointed a resident grievance officer in India days after the American social media firm said to have lost the liability protection on user-generated content in the South Asian nation over non-compliance with local IT rules. On Sunday, Twitter identified Vinay Prakash as its new resident grievance officer and shared a way to contact [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter has appointed a resident grievance officer in India days after the American social media firm said to have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/twitter-has-lost-liability-protection-in-india-government-says/">lost the liability protection</a> on user-generated content in the South Asian nation over non-compliance with local IT rules.</p>
<p>On Sunday, Twitter <a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/report-twitter-abuse-india">identified</a> Vinay Prakash as its new resident grievance officer and shared a way to contact him as required by India’s new IT rules, which was unveiled in February this year and went into effect in late May. Twitter has also published a compliance report, another requirement listed in the new rules.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, the Indian government had told a local court that Twitter had lost the liability protection on user-generated content in the country, as it had failed to appoint compliance, grievance and a so-called nodal contact officials to address on-ground concerns.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Other internet giants including Facebook, Google, and Telegram have already appointed these local compliance officers in India.</p>
<p>Internet services enjoy what is broadly referred to as “safe harbor” protection that say that tech platforms won’t be held liable for the things their users post or share online. If you insult someone on Twitter, for instance, the company may be asked to take down your post (if the person you have insulted has approached the court and a takedown order has been issued) but it likely won’t be held legally responsible for what you said or did.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JkLoOjJkwG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/delhi-police-run-by-indias-central-government-raids-twitter-offices-over-manipulated-label/">Police in India visited Twitter offices over &#8216;manipulated media&#8217; label</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Police in India visited Twitter offices over &#8216;manipulated media&#8217; label&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/delhi-police-run-by-indias-central-government-raids-twitter-offices-over-manipulated-label/embed/#?secret=JkLoOjJkwG" data-secret="JkLoOjJkwG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Without the protection, Twitter — which according to mobile insight firm App Annie, has over 100 million users in India — is on paper responsible for everything those users say on its platform. Indian police have already filed at least five cases against the company or its officials in the country over a range of issues.</p>
<p>The new development should help assuage the tension between Twitter and the Indian government. A special squad of Delhi police <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/delhi-police-run-by-indias-central-government-raids-twitter-offices-over-manipulated-label/">made a surprise visit to two of Twitter’s offices</a> in late May in what many perceived as an intimidation tactic. Twitter said at the time that it was “concerned by recent events regarding our employees in India and the potential threat to freedom of expression for the people we serve” and requested the Indian government to grant it three additional months to comply with the new IT rules.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, Twitter told an Indian court that it was working to &#8220;fully comply&#8221; with the new rules.</p>
<p>More countries are formulating similar requirements for tech giants in their nations. Russia President Vladimir Putin signed a law that mandates foreign social media giants to open offices in Russia. Any social firm with a daily user base of 500,000 people or more is required to comply with the new law.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4AejhKhEsH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/india-it-ravi-shankar-prasad-and-broadcasting-minister-javadekar-resign/">India&#8217;s IT and Broadcasting ministers resign</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;India&#8217;s IT and Broadcasting ministers resign&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/india-it-ravi-shankar-prasad-and-broadcasting-minister-javadekar-resign/embed/#?secret=4AejhKhEsH" data-secret="4AejhKhEsH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/twitter-appoints-resident-grievance-officer-in-india-to-comply-with-new-internet-rules/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175890</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
