<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 09:05:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Stock trading app Trade Republic expands to France</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/stock-trading-app-trade-republic-expands-to-france/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/stock-trading-app-trade-republic-expands-to-france/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 09:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trade Republic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105855</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[German startup Trade Republic is rolling out its app and service in France this week. This is a significant expansion move as Trade Republic has only been available in Germany and Austria so far. Trade Republic lets you buy and sell shares or exchange-traded funds (ETFs) from your phone with low, transparent fees. The company [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">German startup <a href="https://traderepublic.com">Trade Republic</a> is rolling out its app and service in France this week. This is a significant expansion move as Trade Republic has only been available in Germany and Austria so far.</p>
<p>Trade Republic lets you buy and sell shares or exchange-traded funds (ETFs) from your phone with low, transparent fees. The company charges €1 ($1.21) in fees per order, whether you’re buying a single share worth €100 or allocating €10,000 of your savings on an ETF. The company promises that it doesn’t add any commission on top of that €1.</p>
<p>The startup lets you buy European shares as well as stock in Asian or American companies. Overall, there are 7,500 shares and ETFs available in the app. While the service is relatively new, Trade Republic has been working on its infrastructure for several years.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Behind the scenes, the company has partnered with <a href="https://www.solarisbank.com/en/">Solarisbank</a>, a German banking-as-a-service platform regulated by German authorities. It means that your deposits are covered up to €100,000 ($121,000) in case of bankruptcy. When you’re submitting an order, Trade Republic works with LS Exchange and HSBC Transaction Services to handle those shares.</p>
<p>Trade Republic wants to position itself differently from Robinhood. The company thinks there are currently two options when it comes to trading.</p>
<p>You can open a trading account with your bank or a legacy broker, but they’ll charge a lot of money. Or you can use a mobile-first broker, but they’ll push you toward risky assets and day-trading. And we’ve seen this week <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/robinhood-users-say-its-restricting-trades-after-the-gamestop-brouhaha-shakes-markets/">with the GameStop saga</a> that the second option can lead to some backlash.</p>
<p>Trade Republic is promoting a third way — low fees and low risk. The company wants to promote savings plans for instance. Those plans let you buy shares progressively, which should protect users against volatility.</p>
<p>The company raised a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/trade-republic-a-german-robinhood-raises-67m-led-by-accel-and-founders-fund/">€62 million funding round</a> ($75.22 million at today’s rate) last year. The Series B round was co-led by Accel and Founders Fund.</p>
<p>As for French users, don’t forget that you have to declare that you have a <a href="https://www.impots.gouv.fr/portail/international-particulier/questions/comment-declarer-mes-comptes-et-mes-contrats-dassurance-vie">foreign bank account</a> when you file your taxes. Foreign brokers also don’t necessarily send information to tax authorities to pre-fill your tax reports. But if you’re fine with that, Trade Republic is most likely cheaper than your bank.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OB74LhEVNb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/trade-republic-a-german-robinhood-raises-67m-led-by-accel-and-founders-fund/">Trade Republic, a German Robinhood, raises $67M led by Accel and Founders Fund</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Trade Republic, a German Robinhood, raises $67M led by Accel and Founders Fund&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/trade-republic-a-german-robinhood-raises-67m-led-by-accel-and-founders-fund/embed/#?secret=OB74LhEVNb" data-secret="OB74LhEVNb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/stock-trading-app-trade-republic-expands-to-france/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105855</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Huawei&#8217;s struggles hurt overall smartphone shipments in China, but rivals like Apple found new opportunities</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/huaweis-struggles-hurt-overall-smartphone-shipments-in-china-but-rivals-like-apple-found-new-opportunities/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/huaweis-struggles-hurt-overall-smartphone-shipments-in-china-but-rivals-like-apple-found-new-opportunities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 05:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Honor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Huawei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oppo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone shipments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vivo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Xiaomi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105839</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The impact of United States government sanctions on Huawei is continuing to hurt the company and dampen overall smartphone shipments in China, where it is the largest smartphone vendor, according to a new report by Canalys. But Huawei’s decline also opens new opportunities for its main rivals, including Apple. Canalys says Apple’s performance in China [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The impact of United States government sanctions on Huawei is continuing to hurt the company and dampen overall smartphone shipments in China, where it is the largest smartphone vendor, according to a <a href="https://www.canalys.com/newsroom/china-smartphone-market-declines-11-in-2020">new report by Canalys</a>. But Huawei’s decline also opens new opportunities for its main rivals, including Apple.</p>
<p>Canalys says Apple’s performance in China during the fourth-quarter of 2020 was its best in years, thanks to the iPhone 11 and 12. Its full-year shipments returned to its 2018 levels, and it reached its highest quarterly shipments in China since the end of 2015, when the iPhone 6s was launched.</p>
<p>Overall, smartphone shipments in China fell 11% to about 330 million units in 2020, with market recovery hindered by Huawei’s inability to ship new units. Even though demand in China for Huawei devices remains high, the company has struggled to cope with sanctions imposed by the U.S. government under the Trump administration that banned it from doing business with American companies and drastically curtailed its ability to procure new chips.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In May 2020, Huawei rotating chairman Guo Ping said even though the firm can design some semiconductor components, like integrated circuits, it is &#8220;incapable of doing a lot of other things.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1O9K1VF6YY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/18/huawei-uncertainties-new-us-chip-rules-tsmc/">Huawei admits uncertainty following new US chip curbs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Huawei admits uncertainty following new US chip curbs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/18/huawei-uncertainties-new-us-chip-rules-tsmc/embed/#?secret=1O9K1VF6YY" data-secret="1O9K1VF6YY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This left Huawei unable to meet demand for its devices, but gives its main rivals new opportunities, wrote Canalys vice president of mobility Nicole Peng. &#8220;Oppo, Vivo and Xiaomi are fighting to win over Huawei’s offline channel partners across the country, including small rural ones, backed by huge investments in store expansion and marketing support. These commitments brought immediate results, and market share improved within mere months.&#8221;</p>
<p>Apple benefited from Huawei’s decline because the company’s Mate series is the iPhone’s main rival in the high-end category, and only 4 million Mate units were shipped in the fourth quarter. &#8220;However, Apple has not relaxed its market promotions for iPhone 12,” wrote Canalys research analyst Amber Liu. “Aggressive online promotions across e-commerce players, coupled with widely available trade-in plans and interest-free installments with major banks, drove Apple to its stellar performance.&#8221;</p>
<p>During the fourth-quarter of 2020, smartphone shipments in mainland China fell 4% year-over-year to a total of 84 million units. Even though it held onto its number one position in terms of shipments, Huawei’s total market share plummeted to 22% from 41% a year earlier, and it shipped just 18.8 million smartphones, including units from budget brand Honor, which it agreed to sell in November.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2105840" style="width: 614px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Canalys_Q42020_China.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2105840" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2105840 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Canalys_Q42020_China.png" alt="Canalys' graph showing shipments by the top five smartphone vendors in China" width="604" height="340" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Canalys_Q42020_China.png 604w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Canalys_Q42020_China.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Canalys_Q42020_China.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Canalys_Q42020_China.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 604px) 100vw, 604px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2105840" class="wp-caption-text">Canalys&#8217; graph showing shipments by the top five smartphone vendors in China</p></div></p>
<p>Huawei’s main competitors, on the other hand, all increased their shipments at the end of 2020. Oppo took second place, shipping 17.2 million smartphones, a 23% increase year-over-year. Oppo’s closest competitor Vivo increased its quarterly shipment to 15.7 million units. Apple shipped more than 15.3 million units, putting its market share at 18%, up from 15% a year ago. Xiaomi rounded out the top five vendors, shipping 12.2 million units, a 52% year-over-year increase.</p>
<p>Huawei’s decision to sell Honor means the brand may rapidly gain market share in 2021, since it already has consumer recognition, wrote Peng. 5G is also expected to help smartphone shipments in China, especially for premium models.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="H73IwY7K88"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/huawei-sells-budget-phone-unit-honor-to-government-distribution-partners/">Huawei sells budget phone unit Honor to state-backed firms, distribution partners</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Huawei sells budget phone unit Honor to state-backed firms, distribution partners&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/16/huawei-sells-budget-phone-unit-honor-to-government-distribution-partners/embed/#?secret=H73IwY7K88" data-secret="H73IwY7K88" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/huaweis-struggles-hurt-overall-smartphone-shipments-in-china-but-rivals-like-apple-found-new-opportunities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105839</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hong Kong startup ICW eyes supply chain diversification demand amid trade war</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/icw-supply-chain-5-8-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/icw-supply-chain-5-8-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 01:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[icw]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trade war]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2102896</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For American importers, finding suppliers these days can be challenging not only due to COVID-19 travel restrictions. The U.S. government&#8217;s entity list designations, human rights-related sanctions, among other trade blacklists targeting Chinese firms have also rattled U.S. supply chains. One young company called International Compliance Workshop, or ICW, is determined to make sourcing easier for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">For American importers, finding suppliers these days can be challenging not only due to COVID-19 travel restrictions. The U.S. government&#8217;s entity list designations, human rights-related sanctions, among other trade blacklists targeting Chinese firms have also rattled U.S. supply chains.</p>
<p>One young company called <a href="https://www.icw.io/">International Compliance Workshop</a>, or ICW, is determined to make sourcing easier for companies around the world as it completed a fresh round of funding. The Hong Kong-based startup has just raised $5.75 million as part of its Series A round, boosting its total funding to around $10 million, co-founder and CEO Garry Lam told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>ICW works like a matchmaker for suppliers and buyers, but unlike existing options like Alibaba&#8217;s B2B platform or international trade shows, ICW also vets suppliers over compliance, product quality, and accreditation. It gathers all that information into its growing database of over 40,000 suppliers &#8212; 80% of which are currently in China &#8212; and recommends them to customers based on individual needs.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Founded in 2016, ICW&#8217;s current client base includes some of the world&#8217;s largest retailers, including Ralph Lauren, Prenatal Retail Group, Blokker, Kmart, and a major American pharmacy chain that declined to be named.</p>
<p>ICW&#8217;s latest funding round was led by Infinity Ventures Partners with participation from Integrated Capital and existing investors MindWorks Capital and the Hong Kong government&#8217;s $2 billion<a href="https://www.itf.gov.hk/l-eng/ITVF.asp"> Innovation and Technology Venture Fund</a>.</p>
<h2>Supply chain shift</h2>
<p>In line with the ongoing shift of sourcing outside China, in part due to the U.S.-China trade war and China&#8217;s growing labor costs, ICW has seen more customers diversifying their supply chains. But the transition has limitations in the short run.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s still very difficult to find suppliers of certain product categories, for example, Bluetooth devices and power banks, in other countries,&#8221; observed Lam. &#8220;But for garment and textile, the transition already began to happen a decade ago.&#8221;</p>
<p>In Southeast Asia, which has been replacing a great deal of Chinese manufacturing activity, each country has its slight specialization. Whereas Vietnam abounds with wooden furniture suppliers, Thailand is known for plastic goods and Malaysia is a good source for medical supplies, said Lam.</p>
<p>When it comes to trickier compliance burdens, such as human rights sanctions, ICW relies on third-party certification institutes to screen and verify suppliers.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is a [type of] qualification standard that verifies whether a supplier has fulfilled its corporate social responsibility&#8230; like whether the factory fulfills the labor law, the minimum labor rights, or the payroll, everything,&#8221; Lam explained.</p>
<p>ICW plans to use the fresh proceeds to further develop its products, including its compliance management system, product testing platform, and B2B sourcing site.</p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/icw-supply-chain-5-8-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2102896</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why calendar invites are worth $3B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/calendly-3-billion/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/calendly-3-billion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 23:53:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ClassDojo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qualtrics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rhino]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TCV]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105541</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. Natasha and Danny and Alex and Grace hopped online for our weekly show, sans Gamestop news (which you can find here) to talk about all the other busy news happening in startup world right now. Here&#8217;s a taste of what we got into:  Qualtrics [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/97a87305-9f13-4d1b-bfcf-1c06b9fb28fe?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/DannyCrichton">Danny</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/gracedenhall">Grace</a> hopped online for our weekly show, sans Gamestop news (which you can find <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/robinhood-gamestop-this-is-2021/">here</a>) to talk about all the other busy news happening in startup world right now.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s a taste of what we got into:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/qualtrics-prices-ipo-at-30-per-share-above-its-upgraded-target-range/"><strong> Qualtrics</strong> IPO pricing</a>, and the future of major acquisition pricing schemes. This company&#8217;s path to the public markets has been a long-time coming, so we had plenty to say.</li>
<li> How Atlanta&#8217;s <strong>Calendly</strong> turned a scheduling nightmare <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/how-atlantas-calendly-turned-a-scheduling-nightmare-into-a-3b-startup/">into a $3 billion company</a>. This story was not only neat, but also operated as a sort of palate cleanser for the team.</li>
<li><strong> Rhino</strong>&#8216;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/rhino-raises-95m-to-scale-its-rental-deposit-replacing-insurance-product/">interesting insurtech play</a>, and how it is pre-IPO pretty damn early. Revenue questions, the power of insurtech, and public markets impacting startups? This story had it all!</li>
<li> Alex talks about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/fast-raises-102m-as-the-online-checkout-wars-continue-to-attract-huge-investment/">how <strong>Fast</strong> is raising fast money</a> ($102 million to be exact). Even more, the Fast story fits into a broader narrative of online checkout startups raising a zillion dollars in recent weeks.</li>
<li> A boom in food delivery and restaurant startups, and why Danny is bearish on a plastic-free play. Natasha is in favor. Alex gets a company&#8217;s model mixed up with Spoon Rocket.</li>
<li> Natasha explains how <strong>Clubhouse</strong> isn&#8217;t the first company to raise millions off of millions of users with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/24/clubhouse-announces-plans-for-creator-payments-and-raises-new-funding-led-by-andreessen-horowitz/">no known near-term monetization plan</a>. Her piece on <strong>ClassDojo</strong> illustrates how a quiet edtech giant finally turned its<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/classdojos-second-act-comes-with-first-profits/"> 51 million users into a profitable base</a>. There&#8217;s also a new edtech<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/12-investors-say-lifelong-learning-is-taking-edtech-mainstream/"> investor survey</a> for you to check out <em>(<a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">Discount code: EQUITY</a>).</em></li>
<li><strong>TCV&#8217;</strong>s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/tcv-closes-record-4b-fund-to-invest-in-e-commerce-fintech-edtech-travel-and-more/">record fund</a>, and a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/these-investors-want-to-back-ridiculously-early-female-led-african-startups/">female-focused angel fund</a> coming out of Africa.</li>
</ul>
<p>As always, it was a ton to get through because there is just so much going on. More Monday morning, until then stay cool!</p>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST and Thursday afternoon as fast as we can get it out, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts</i></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/calendly-3-billion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105541</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Robinhood restricts GameStop trading</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/daily-crunch-robinhood-restricts-gamestop-trading/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/daily-crunch-robinhood-restricts-gamestop-trading/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 23:14:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gamestop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105786</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The GameStop stock saga continues, Apple releases more details about its privacy changes and Qualtrics goes public. This is your Daily Crunch for January 28, 2021. The big story: Robinhood restricts GameStop trading Robinhood has responded to an upsurge in retail investors buying shares in companies like GameStop, AMC and Blockbuster by restricting trading on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The GameStop stock saga continues, Apple releases more details about its privacy changes and Qualtrics goes public. This is your Daily Crunch for January 28, 2021.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: Robinhood restricts GameStop trading</strong></p>
<p>Robinhood has responded to an upsurge in retail investors buying shares in companies like GameStop, AMC and Blockbuster by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/robinhood-users-say-its-restricting-trades-after-the-gamestop-brouhaha-shakes-markets/">restricting trading on &#8220;certain securities&#8221;</a> to &#8220;position closing only,&#8221; meaning that users can no longer buy more of the companies&#8217; stocks. (It says <a href="https://blog.robinhood.com/news/2021/1/28/an-update-on-market-volatility">it will allow &#8220;limited buys&#8221;</a> tomorrow.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This comes after the current buying spree — targeting stocks shorted by institutional investors and spurred by the WallStreetBets forum on Reddit — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/robinhood-and-reddit-top-the-app-store-as-trading-apps-surge-following-gamestop-mania/">took Robinhood and Reddit</a> to the top of the app charts.</p>
<p>Now, Robinhood is being hit with numerous 1-star reviews, and the move also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/gamestop-robinhood-aoc-ted-cruz-tlaib-khanna-robinhood/">attracted criticism from politicians on both sides of the aisle</a>, with Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez describing it as &#8220;unacceptable&#8221; and Senator Ted Cruz tweeting, &#8220;Fully agree.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/apple-app-tracking-transparency/">Apple’s App Tracking Transparency feature will be enabled by default and arrive in ‘early spring’ on iOS</a> — The plan is to launch these changes in early spring, with a version of the feature coming in the next iOS 14 beta release.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/qualtrics-prices-ipo-at-30-per-share-above-its-upgraded-target-range/">Qualtrics prices IPO at $30 per share, above its upgraded target range</a> — The company sold 50.4 million shares in the process.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/twitter-is-already-working-on-integrating-newsletters-on-its-site-following-revue-acquisition/">Twitter is already working on integrating newsletters on its site, following its Revue acquisition</a> — It appears “Newsletters” will soon be the newest addition to Twitter’s sidebar navigation.</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/workday-nabs-employee-feedback-platform-peakon-for-700m/">Workday acquires employee feedback platform Peakon for $700M</a> — Peakon says companies have used its platform&#8217;s weekly surveys to ask more than 153 million questions since inception six years ago.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/fintech-darling-nubank-raises-blockbuster-400m-series-g-at-25b-valuation/">Fintech darling Nubank raises blockbuster $400M Series G at $25B valuation</a> — The fintech company now has 34 million customers.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/flowhaven-raises-16m-to-evolve-brand-licensing-management-beyond-emails-and-spreadsheets/">Flowhaven raises $16M to evolve brand licensing management beyond emails and spreadsheets</a> — The media licensing business is a massive market, but much of the work involved is still handled manually through emails and spreadsheets.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/12-investors-say-lifelong-learning-is-taking-edtech-mainstream/">Thirteen investors say lifelong learning is taking edtech mainstream</a> — As learners become more multi-layered and nuanced, so have the edtech companies that back them.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/chasing-the-cybersecurity-investment-opportunity/">Talent and capital are shifting cybersecurity investors’ focus away from Silicon Valley</a> — Solving the cybersecurity problem will take more time and resources than we are currently allocating.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/mind-the-gap-e-commerce-marketers-should-revise-their-tam-and-sam-estimates/">Mind the gap: E-commerce marketers should revise their TAM and SAM estimates</a> — 2021 is going to be another glorious year for e-commerce.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/smartphone-sales-slowed-decline-in-q4-with-a-big-assist-from-apple/">Smartphone sales slowed decline in Q4, with a big assist from Apple</a> — The past year was, of course, a major blow to an industry already suffering a slide.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/gm-pledges-to-be-carbon-neutral-by-2040-with-zero-tailpipe-emission-vehicles-by-2035/">GM pledges to be carbon neutral by 2040 with zero tailpipe emission vehicles by 2035</a> — It’s a big step for a company whose products are responsible for a large percentage of global greenhouse gas emissions.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/ucla-is-building-a-digital-archive-of-mass-incarceration-with-a-new-3-6m-grant/">UCLA is building a digital archive of mass incarceration with a new $3.6M grant</a> — The “Archiving the Age of Mass incarceration” effort is being led by Kelly Lytle Hernandez, director of the university’s Bunche Center for African American Studies.</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/daily-crunch-robinhood-restricts-gamestop-trading/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105786</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SoftBank earmarks $100 million for Miami-based startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/softbank-launches-a-100-million-fund-for-miami-based-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/softbank-launches-a-100-million-fund-for-miami-based-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 23:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[francis suarez]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miami]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105752</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Miami, an emerging startup hub, has a new check-writer in town: SoftBank. The Japanese multinational conglomerate announced plans today to invest $100 million, drawn from across its funds, into Miami-based startups. Notably, SoftBank’s $5 billion Latin America fund is headquartered in Miami, as well. The initiative is led by SoftBank CEO Marcelo Claure. The fund [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Miami, an emerging startup hub, has a new check-writer in town: SoftBank. The Japanese multinational conglomerate announced plans today to invest $100 million, drawn from across its funds, into Miami-based startups. Notably, SoftBank’s $5 billion Latin America fund is headquartered in Miami, as well.</p>
<p>The initiative is led by SoftBank CEO Marcelo Claure. The fund will back companies who are in Miami or plan to move there.</p>
<p>A SoftBank check is somewhat of a Silicon Valley rite-of-passage, so the firm’s involvement in the scene will likely signal to others that the growth of Miami is something to be taken seriously. The tax-free haven is attracting swathes of investors and founders from around the country looking to join the growing scene. Relocators include Keith Rabois of Founders Fund, David Blumberg of Blumberg Capital, Chris Dixon of Andreessen Horowitz and David Sacks of Craft Ventures.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Miami Mayor Francis Suarez, who has been on a <a href="https://twitter.com/FrancisSuarez/status/1335037068108554241">Twitter tear</a> asking techies to move to Miami, has spearheaded much of the efforts to turn the city into a startup epicenter.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Big Win for <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MiamiTech?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MiamiTech</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/marceloclaure?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@marceloclaure</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/SoftBank?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@SoftBank</a>’s latest investment initiative: The $100M Miami Tech Fund will directly fund and support Miami-based businesses, creating Miami unicorns right here at home. <a href="https://t.co/b15skzokhN">pic.twitter.com/b15skzokhN</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Mayor Francis Suarez (@FrancisSuarez) <a href="https://twitter.com/FrancisSuarez/status/1354912470238961666?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 28, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Ruben Harris, founder of Career Karma, has been working with Suarez <a href="https://twitter.com/rubenharris/status/988430185484685313">since 2018</a> to help people break into tech.</p>
<p>“Now that Softbank has made this move, we will see more funds follow their example and this is a huge win for diversity not just from a race perspective, but also from a socioeconomic perspective, and from a gender perspective,” Harris said, who is thinking about moving to the city. Career Karma is currently working with VC funds to get old laptops into its Reskill America program, to help train an emerging workforce <a href="https://careerkarma.com/reskill-america/apply/">in Miami. </a></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/monicasblack">Monica Black</a>, who is behind Function, a Miami-based non-profit investor syndicate, hopes that SoftBank&#8217;s entrance &#8220;will not only increase the amount of capital going to local startups and help them grow to the Series A stage and beyond, but also attract other institutional VCs as co-investors.&#8221; Historically, she said, it&#8217;s been tough for local startups to raise capital from Silicon Valley or New York funds. The exception to this was Papa, which raised $18 million in September to connect older adults with virtual companions from Sound Ventures and Canaan.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nicberardi">Nico Berardi</a>, the founder of Miami-based fund ANIMO Ventures, connected the new SoftBank initiative to the recent announcement by San Francisco’s Founders Fund to open an office in Miami.</p>
<p>“Both are symbolic and I think symbols matter,” Berardi said. “[They] are planting a flag here and saying look this is a viable scene.” Of his 16 portfolio companies, Berardi says only one startup is based in Miami. With more and more investors moving to the city, Berardi is optimistic that it can magnetize more talent to move, too.</p>
<p>“I’m hopeful that this can attract tens or hundreds of founders to build their next thing in Miami,” he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/softbank-launches-a-100-million-fund-for-miami-based-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105752</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>After soaring above $23B, Qualtrics&#8217; founder and CEO reflect on a stellar debut</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/after-soaring-above-23b-qualtrics-founder-and-ceo-reflect-on-a-stellar-debut/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/after-soaring-above-23b-qualtrics-founder-and-ceo-reflect-on-a-stellar-debut/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 22:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Cloud and Enterprise Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qualtrics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silver lake]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105693</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amidst the sturm und drang of l'affaire GameStop, the cloud software vendor received a warm welcome from public investors.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Amidst all of the the <em>sturm und drang</em> of <em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/robinhood-gamestop-this-is-2021/">l&#8217;affaire GameStop</a>,</em> Qualtrics went public today.</p>
<p>After <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/qualtrics-prices-ipo-at-30-per-share-above-its-upgraded-target-range/">pricing its stock</a> above its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/qualtrics-raises-ipo-pricing-ahead-of-debut/">raised IPO range</a>, the company received a warm welcome from public investors. After starting its trading life worth $41.85, Qualtrics closed the day worth $45.50, up some 51.67%.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Qualtrics did everything that it said it was going to.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>The software company&#8217;s debut comes after a lengthy path to the public markets; Qualtrics <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/11/sap-agrees-to-buy-qualtrics-for-8b-in-cash-just-before-the-survey-software-companys-ipo/">sold to SAP</a> on the eve of its first run at a public listing back in 2018. Now, SAP has completed spinning the company out, though the software giant remains the Utah unicorn&#8217;s largest shareholder.</p>
<p>That Qualtrics&#8217; IPO might perform well was presaged in its pricing run, having prices far above its initial valuation estimates; there was evidence of strong demand even before its shares started to trade.</p>
<p>But did Qualtrics misprice, given its strong first-day performance? TechCrunch spoke with Qualtrics CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/zigserafin/">Zig Serafin</a>, and its founder and current executive chairman <a href="https://twitter.com/RyanQualtrics">Ryan Smith</a> about its public offering, hoping to learn a bit about what is next for the company.</p>
<h2>Pricing, plans</h2>
<p>Having spoken to myriad folks on IPO days, I&#8217;ve learned the best way to kick off is to ask about emotions. Most CEOs and other execs are tied up in what they can (and cannot) say. And they are well-trained by communications experts regarding what to repeat and emphasize. You can sometimes loosen them up a little, however, by asking them how they feel.</p>
<p>In response to that question, Serafin described a feeling of gratitude and Smith brought up the long game. Qualtrics, he said, had been told that it couldn&#8217;t bootstrap, that it couldn&#8217;t build in Utah, that SAP had overpaid, that SAP had messed up and so forth.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/after-soaring-above-23b-qualtrics-founder-and-ceo-reflect-on-a-stellar-debut/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105693</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The somewhat boring reason it appears that Robinhood yanked trading on some securities</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/the-somewhat-boring-reason-it-appears-that-robinhood-yanked-trading-on-some-securities/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/the-somewhat-boring-reason-it-appears-that-robinhood-yanked-trading-on-some-securities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 22:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gamestop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hedge fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[us government]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105747</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After enduring a day&#8217;s worth of taking a beating across social media, government, and the various app stores of the mobile world, Robinhood took to its own blog and CEO&#8217;s Twitter account to explain why it had halted trading of some stocks earlier today. That Robinhood had restricted trading in a number of securities was bombshell [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After enduring a day&#8217;s worth of taking a beating <a href="https://twitter.com/stoolpresidente/status/1354886106001649679">across social media</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/NewYorkStateAG/status/1354917642507866114">government</a>, and the <a href="https://twitter.com/alex/status/1354814429511131138">various app stores</a> of the mobile world, Robinhood <a href="https://blog.robinhood.com/news/2021/1/28/an-update-on-market-volatility">took to its own blog</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/vladtenev/status/1354900958942175233">CEO&#8217;s Twitter account</a> to explain why it had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/robinhood-users-say-its-restricting-trades-after-the-gamestop-brouhaha-shakes-markets/">halted trading</a> of some stocks earlier today.</p>
<p>That Robinhood had restricted trading in a number of securities was bombshell news after the consumer trading platform had become synonymous with not only a rise in retail investing, but also a risky wager by some individual investors to push shares of heavily-shorted companies, including GameStop, AMC and others higher. Speculation that Robinhood was limiting the trading ability of those users at the behest of, pick your poison, Citadel, the US government, hedge funds, Janet Yellen, or others, ran rampant.</p>
<p>But none of it was true – at least according to Robinhood&#8217;s telling. In its post, Robinhood wrote that (emphasis TechCrunch):</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<blockquote>
<p id="yui_3_17_2_1_1611870043839_198" class="">[a]mid this week’s extraordinary circumstances in the market, we made a tough decision today to temporarily limit buying for certain securities. <strong>As a brokerage firm, we have many financial requirements, including SEC net capital obligations and clearinghouse deposits. Some of these requirements fluctuate based on volatility in the markets and can be substantial in the current environment.</strong> These requirements exist to protect investors and the markets and we take our responsibilities to comply with them seriously, including through the measures we have taken today.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That reads like Robinhood ran low on capital and had to make some hard decisions, quickly. The securities its users wanted to trade likely generated the highest capital obligations given how volatile they proved and how long it takes for trades to settle, so Robinhood had to shut off some trades to stay on the right side of its capital needs. (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mg5HOnq7zD0">Not great, not terrible?</a>)</p>
<p>Reporting <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-28/robinhood-is-said-to-draw-on-credit-lines-from-banks-amid-tumult?sref=gni836kR">from Bloomberg indicates</a> that Robinhood &#8220;tapped at least several hundred million dollars&#8221; from credit lines today makes sense in this context. As does the unicorn&#8217;s decision to allow for some trading of the afore-limited securities in the near future (&#8220;starting tomorrow, we plan to allow limited buys of these securities,&#8221; the company wrote); now reloaded with more capital, Robinhood can afford to let its users get back, somewhat, to business.</p>
<p>Of course Robinhood could have been more clear about all of this earlier in the day. Instead, unfairly or not, it became the face of theoretical corruption and other nefarious forces. (Here&#8217;s a tip, if your theory sounds like it could fit inside the Qanon orbit, try again?)</p>
<p>Nothing is settled. Congress has its hackles up. Other trading platforms had to suspend trading in GameStop and other stocks for a spell as well. Social media is pissed. Some Robinhood users were forced to liquidate positions. And somehow GameStop closed the day worth more than $196 per share. And after-hours it is up $72.40, or 37.40% to $266 per share.</p>
<p>Who knows what comes next. But grains of salt, please, as we continue this bizarre adventure.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/the-somewhat-boring-reason-it-appears-that-robinhood-yanked-trading-on-some-securities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105747</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lawmakers announce hearings on GameStop and online trading platforms</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/gamestop-hearings-congress-waters-robinhood/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/gamestop-hearings-congress-waters-robinhood/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 22:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gamestop]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105742</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The GameStop short squeeze saga caught the attention of Congress Thursday morning and that buzz is already panning out into hearings on the topic. Rep. Maxine Waters (D-CA), chairwoman of the House Committee on Financial Services, announced plans for an investigation into the situation, pointing to a history of &#8220;predatory conduct&#8221; from hedge funds. Waters [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The GameStop short squeeze saga <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/gamestop-robinhood-aoc-ted-cruz-tlaib-khanna-robinhood/">caught the attention of Congress Thursday morning</a> and that buzz is already panning out into hearings on the topic.</p>
<p>Rep. Maxine Waters (D-CA), chairwoman of the House Committee on Financial Services, announced plans for an investigation into the situation, pointing to a history of &#8220;predatory conduct&#8221; from hedge funds.</p>
<p>Waters didn&#8217;t call out Robinhood or any other trading services by name, but did note that a future hearing would focus on the systemic financial impact of short selling, &#8220;gamification&#8221; and online trading platforms. The hearing date is not yet set.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Addressing that predatory and manipulative conduct is the responsibility of lawmakers and securities regulators who are charged with protecting investors and ensuring that our capital markets are fair, orderly, and efficient,&#8221; Waters said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f6a8.png" alt="🚨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BREAKING?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BREAKING</a>: Following Recent Market Instability, Chairwoman <a href="https://twitter.com/RepMaxineWaters?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@RepMaxineWaters</a> Announces Hearing on Short Selling, Online Trading Platforms | <a href="https://t.co/qarYouEIGo">https://t.co/qarYouEIGo</a> <a href="https://t.co/M4goKnio5e">pic.twitter.com/M4goKnio5e</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Financial Svcs Cmte (@FSCDems) <a href="https://twitter.com/FSCDems/status/1354901344704991232?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 28, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In the Senate, incoming Senate Banking Chairman Sherrod Brown <a href="https://twitter.com/SenSherrodBrown/status/1354881250922819585">announced his own plans for a hearing on the &#8220;current state of the stock market&#8221;</a> in light of recent events. &#8220;People on Wall Street only care about the rules when they&#8217;re the ones getting hurt,&#8221; Brown said.</p>
<p>Earlier on Thursday, Democratic Reps. Rep. Rashida Tlaib, Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez and Ro Khanna <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/gamestop-robinhood-aoc-ted-cruz-tlaib-khanna-robinhood/">all condemned the startup Robinhood</a> for halting some trades in the midst of the Reddit retail investor-led volatility. Morgan Stanley-owned E-Trade followed suit.</p>
<p>Texas Republican Senator Ted Cruz echoed Democrats&#8217; concerns over Robinhood&#8217;s actions, signaling that even in the midst of pandemic relief negotiations and an impeachment trial that lawmakers on both sides of the aisle still have an appetite for dragging tech in for questioning.</p>
<p>And apparently it&#8217;s not just Congress. New York Attorney General Letitia James also issued a short statement Thursday noting that her office is &#8220;aware of concerns raised regarding activity on the Robinhood app&#8221; and would be reviewing the situation.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rQUWlRzXdQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/gamestop-robinhood-aoc-ted-cruz-tlaib-khanna-robinhood/">AOC, Ted Cruz slam Robinhood for freezing some trades amid GameStop volatility</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;AOC, Ted Cruz slam Robinhood for freezing some trades amid GameStop volatility&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/gamestop-robinhood-aoc-ted-cruz-tlaib-khanna-robinhood/embed/#?secret=rQUWlRzXdQ" data-secret="rQUWlRzXdQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/gamestop-hearings-congress-waters-robinhood/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105742</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Early Snapchat employee debuts Yoni Circle, a social storytelling app for womxn</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/early-snapchat-employee-debuts-yoni-circle-a-social-storytelling-app-for-womxn/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/early-snapchat-employee-debuts-yoni-circle-a-social-storytelling-app-for-womxn/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 22:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mindfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video chat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105646</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An early Snapchat employee who once architected the &#8220;Our Stories&#8221; product, Chloë Drimal, has now launched her own social app, Yoni Circle. Described as a membership-based community, the app aims to connect womxn using storytelling &#8212; including through both live video chat sessions as well as with pre-recorded stories that are available at any time. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">An early Snapchat employee who once architected the &#8220;Our Stories&#8221; product, Chloë Drimal, has now launched her own social app, <a href="https://www.yonicircle.com/">Yoni Circle</a>. Described as a membership-based community, the app aims to connect <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Womxn">womxn </a>using storytelling &#8212; including through both live video chat sessions as well as with pre-recorded stories that are available at any time.</p>
<p>The company has been quietly operating in beta since April 2020, but is now making its public launch.</p>
<p>Drimal came up with the idea for a social storytelling app, in part, because she saw the potential when working on the Snapchat &#8220;Our Stories&#8221; product.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2105726" style="width: 361px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2105726" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2105726" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Chloë-Drimal-Headshot.jpeg?w=500" alt="" width="351" height="351" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Chloë-Drimal-Headshot.jpeg 500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Chloë-Drimal-Headshot.jpeg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Chloë-Drimal-Headshot.jpeg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Chloë-Drimal-Headshot.jpeg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Chloë-Drimal-Headshot.jpeg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Chloë-Drimal-Headshot.jpeg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Chloë-Drimal-Headshot.jpeg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Chloë-Drimal-Headshot.jpeg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 351px) 100vw, 351px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2105726" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Yoni Circle; founder Chloë Drimal</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;I got to see that storytelling connects us,&#8221; she explains. &#8220;I got to peer into global experiences like New Year&#8217;s Eve or witnessing the Hajj pilgrimage to Mecca, and I just saw firsthand how connected we are as people,&#8221; Drimal continues. &#8220;I got to see how that was affecting our Snapchat users and making them feel more connected to the world because of this art of storytelling,&#8221; she adds.</p>
<p>But another inspiration came from Drimal&#8217;s personal experience in being taken off the &#8220;Our Stories&#8221; product to work on other projects at Snap &#8212; a difficult time in her career that started to make her feel very alone. She later ended up having conversations with other women &#8212; often older women who shared their own experiences &#8212; who helped her realized that she wasn&#8217;t as alone as she first thought.</p>
<p>&#8220;Their stories empowered me to write my next chapter, and know that this wasn&#8217;t the end of my career as I dramatically thought as a twenty-five or twenty-four year-old. It really was just the beginning and it helped me see the healing of storytelling &#8212; but also the importance of what strangers being vulnerable can do,&#8221; she says.</p>
<p>After leaving Snap, where she had later run women&#8217;s initiatives, Drimal began hosting an in-person community focused around more structured storytelling circles. The community evolved to become what&#8217;s now the Yoni Circle app, whose beta version was built with help from former Snap engineer <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/akivab/">Akiva Bamberger</a>, now a Yoni Circle advisor.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2105723" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2105723" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2105723" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Home-Screen.jpg?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Home-Screen.jpg 828w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Home-Screen.jpg?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Home-Screen.jpg?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Home-Screen.jpg?resize=768,1662 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Home-Screen.jpg?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Home-Screen.jpg?resize=710,1536 710w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Home-Screen.jpg?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2105723" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Yoni Circle</p></div></p>
<p>Today, the app has two main features: the interactive Storytelling Circles component and the more passive Yoni Radio.</p>
<p>The former allows members to join 60-minute moderated live video chat sessions with up to six womxn who connect with one another by listening to each others&#8217; stories. During the Circle, a trained &#8220;Salonniere&#8221; guide will first lead the group through introductions, a breathing exercise, and will then introduce a storytelling prompt based on a specific theme, like &#8220;Stories on Gratitude,&#8221; or &#8220;Stories on Surprise,&#8221; for example.</p>
<p>The Salonnieres are not volunteers, but rather paid contractors who have undergone specific training to lead these sorts of sessions. Over time, they&#8217;ll also be able to gather members to paid web-based events, which could be things like yoga classes, book clubs, cooking classes and more.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2105721" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2105721" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2105721" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Circles-Available.jpg?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Circles-Available.jpg 828w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Circles-Available.jpg?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Circles-Available.jpg?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Circles-Available.jpg?resize=768,1662 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Circles-Available.jpg?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Circles-Available.jpg?resize=710,1536 710w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Circles-Available.jpg?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2105721" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Yoni Circle</p></div></p>
<p>The Circle sessions have a basic rule: take the stories with you, and leave the names behind. In other words, what&#8217;s shared in circles is meant to remain confidential, unless the member chooses to share it publicly. Anyone violating that rule will be banned.</p>
<p>Members are also advised to speak simply, leave their egos at the door, and respect differences. No one receives the topic beforehand, either, so members can&#8217;t rehearse their speeches and put on a &#8220;performance.&#8221; The act of participating is meant to be about authenticity and vulnerability.</p>
<p>During the session, each participant takes their turn to share their own story and will listen to the others&#8217; in return. Users only speak when they have the &#8220;talking piece,&#8221; and they can react to another story with snaps, or by clicking a snap icon.</p>
<p>While the sessions may uplift members the way that group therapy does, they&#8217;re not really focused on addressing psychological issues. Instead, Drimal says members compare them to &#8220;a slumber party combined with a mindfulness class.&#8221;</p>
<p>Still, she says, members feel like participating is an act of self-care.</p>
<p>&#8220;You just feel lighter,&#8221; Drimal explains. &#8220;It&#8217;s hard not to listen to other stories, to see yourself and just be reminded that you aren&#8217;t alone in the highs and lows of life.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2105725" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2105725" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2105725" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Profile-_-Personal-Yoni-Radio.jpg?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Profile-_-Personal-Yoni-Radio.jpg 828w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Profile-_-Personal-Yoni-Radio.jpg?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Profile-_-Personal-Yoni-Radio.jpg?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Profile-_-Personal-Yoni-Radio.jpg?resize=768,1662 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Profile-_-Personal-Yoni-Radio.jpg?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Profile-_-Personal-Yoni-Radio.jpg?resize=710,1536 710w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Profile-_-Personal-Yoni-Radio.jpg?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2105725" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Yoni Circle</p></div></p>
<p>Members can also opt to record their own stories and then set them as either public or private on their Yoni Circle profile. The team then curates the public stories to share as highlights on the app&#8217;s homepage, allowing users to listen at any time. This also powers the Yoni Radio feature.</p>
<p>Recently, the company had been testing a weekly broadcast of these recorded stories, but will soon trial a new &#8220;story of the day&#8221; feature instead.</p>
<p>The Yoni Circle app first launched into beta last April, just as the COVID-19 pandemic in the U.S. had begun. That led to people isolating themselves at home away from friends, extended family, and other social interactions &#8212; driving demand for new social experiences.</p>
<p>But Yoni Circle doesn&#8217;t quite fit into the new live, interactive mobile market that&#8217;s developed as of late, led by apps like <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/clubhouse-voice">Clubhouse</a> and Twitter Spaces.</p>
<p>&#8220;I like to think we&#8217;ve carved out something different,&#8221; says Drimal. &#8220;It is intimate because we&#8217;re creating a safe space to be vulnerable&#8230;the things that I share in any circle I would never share on Clubhouse,&#8221; she says. &#8220;I think that&#8217;s also why we&#8217;ve been so focused on the way we grow our community. Yes, we&#8217;re looking to have millions of members, but we need to get there carefully.&#8221;</p>
<p>Currently, Yoni Circle is open to people who identify as womxn, and it involves an application process where you have to share who you are and what you&#8217;re looking to gain from the experience. Longer-term, the goal is to evolve the platform into a safe space that&#8217;s open to all.</p>
<p>Though the pandemic helped generate initial interest in the app  &#8212; it now has members from 1,000 cities across 80 countries &#8212; the startup sees a future in the post-pandemic market with in-person events that further connect its members.</p>
<p>Yoni Circle today is <a href="https://apps.apple.com/th/app/yoni-circle/id1499411785?ign-mpt=uo%3D2">available on iOS</a> for free. It will later monetize through an Audible-like credits model which provides access to the Circle sessions.</p>
<p>The L.A. and New York-based team of seven is backed by $1.3 million in pre-seed funding, led by <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/boxgroup">BoxGroup</a>. Investors include <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/cassius-family">Cassius Family</a>, <a href="https://www.advancitcapital.com/">Advancit</a>, and angels including Rent the Runway co-founder <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/jenny-fleiss">Jenny Fleiss</a>, Mirror founder and CEO <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/brynn-jinnett-putnam">Brynn Putnam</a>, Beme CTO <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/matt-hackett-2">Matt Hackett</a>, early Snap engineer <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/danoz73/">Daniel Smith</a>.</p>
<p>Yoni Circle plans to raise a seed round in a few weeks.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/early-snapchat-employee-debuts-yoni-circle-a-social-storytelling-app-for-womxn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105646</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Talent and capital are shifting cybersecurity investors&#8217; focus away from Silicon Valley</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/chasing-the-cybersecurity-investment-opportunity/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/chasing-the-cybersecurity-investment-opportunity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 21:15:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crowdstrike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyberwarfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Market Map]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SolarWinds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital investments]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With better access to capital and worldwide talent, there will be further opportunities outside Silicon Valley to scale and create a new wave of solutions to solve today’s cybersecurity problems.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">William Kilmer</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/wkilmer">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/wkilmer">William Kilmer</a> is managing partner with <a href="https://www.c5capital.com/">C5 Capital</a>, a venture capital fund investing in the secure data ecosystem. He was formerly an operating partner at Mercato Growth Partners and served as CEO and Chairman of PublicEngines (acquired by Motorola), and Avinti (merged with M86 Security) and served as Chief Marketing Officer/Chief Strategy Officer of M86 Security (acquired by Trustwave).	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Just when we thought things couldn’t get worse in 2020, we received the news on the SolarWinds hack and its impact on more than 18,000 businesses and potentially dozens of U.S. government agencies — including the departments of <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/russian-hackers-breach-u-s-government-effort-aimed-agencies-private-n1251057" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/russian-hackers-breach-u-s-government-effort-aimed-agencies-private-n1251057&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1611799919469000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFo4hqSz_1cvBrX11ToX95vFfGxhQ">Commerce</a>, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/department-energy-says-it-was-hacked-suspected-russian-campaign-n1251630" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/department-energy-says-it-was-hacked-suspected-russian-campaign-n1251630&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1611799919469000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGwpP4E_sgSQS9pe6M89Sk_fDnSHQ">Energy</a> and <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/security/treasury-also-hacked-suspected-russian-campaign-mnuchin-says-n1251938" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/security/treasury-also-hacked-suspected-russian-campaign-mnuchin-says-n1251938&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1611799919469000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFKUmvSlBJBgbUHW-nNl-5oPr-yKw">Treasury</a>.</p>
<p>We’re just beginning to understand the extent of their infiltration, but this story brings to light what the cybersecurity industry has already known: Solving the cybersecurity problem will take more time and resources than we are currently allocating.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Solving the cybersecurity problem will take more time and resources than we are currently allocating.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Adding to the challenge, COVID-19 has created fertile ground for the acceleration of cyberattacks that are more sophisticated, dangerous and prevalent. In this dire setting, cybersecurity has become even more competitive and a national security imperative and created higher demand for new solutions.</p>
<p>This is something we all — enterprises, startups, government and investors — need to work together to solve. So, from the venture capital perspective, where are cybersecurity investments being made, and where is the talent coming from to help stem the onslaught of hacks?</p>
<p>California’s Silicon Valley has traditionally been the epicenter of cybersecurity innovation. It’s home to some of the largest cybersecurity companies including McAfee, Palo Alto Networks and FireEye, as well as more recent high flyers such as CrowdStrike and Okta, providing a robust talent base for many willing venture investors.</p>
<p>However, that’s rapidly changing. Cybersecurity expertise is now budding in new regions where there is talent and a hands-on recognition of the need for innovative solutions. In particular we are seeing growth in areas such as the East Coast of the U.S. and in Europe, led by the United Kingdom.</p>
<p>Investment in Silicon Valley cybersecurity startups remained flat in 2020 as we are seeing record venture funding of cybersecurity companies in these emerging regions. And the reasons why may mean better solutions to solve current and future cyber needs.</p>
<h2>The emergence of a new cybersecurity ecosystem</h2>
<p>A new generation of cyber-experienced practitioners coming from government and financial services are becoming the next generation of entrepreneurs. Fueling new innovation, this newest breed of cybersecurity startups in emerging in cities like New York, Washington, D.C. and London, and away from Silicon Valley. East Coast businesses like <a href="https://www.ironnet.com/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.ironnet.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1611799919469000&amp;usg=AFQjCNH263cl9DZYsUMfk5a-5P2ct2SR5w">IronNet</a>*, founded by former NSA director General Keith Alexander, is one example of this growing trend of new leaders coming from federal government backgrounds.</p>
<p>These new cybersecurity leaders with front-line experience are developing solutions that fix the problems they faced as customers and, thanks to COVID-19, are hiring the best talent to join them regardless of their location. The pandemic has accelerated remote-working trends, increasing more flexible-location working opportunities in the cybersecurity industry. These companies are creating advantages over their West Coast counterparts in the ability to recruit better talent, lower costs and have closer proximity to customers and prospects.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/chasing-the-cybersecurity-investment-opportunity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101479</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pivoting to home fitness, Aviron offers gamified rowing machines</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/pivoting-to-home-fitness-aviron-offers-gamified-rowing-machines/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/pivoting-to-home-fitness-aviron-offers-gamified-rowing-machines/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 21:08:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aviron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105697</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Few tech sectors had more to gain from the events of 2020 than home fitness. Interest in the category was swift, as gyms were declared one of the bigger problem areas amid the worldwide spread of COVID-19. Suddenly home workouts were more than just luxury. For YC-backed Aviron, it was the ideal time to pivot. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Few tech sectors had more to gain from the events of 2020 than home fitness. Interest in the category was swift, as gyms were declared one of the bigger problem areas amid the worldwide spread of COVID-19. Suddenly home workouts were more than just luxury.</p>
<p>For YC-backed <a href="https://avironactive.com/">Aviron</a>, it was the ideal time to pivot. The Toronto-based startup had been providing gamified rowing machines for the B2B market — specifically for use in high-traffic settings like hotels and apartment buildings. It’s still a small operation with 10 employees and around $750,000 raised to date.</p>
<p>Suddenly the company found itself attempting to compete for market share against tech giants like Peloton.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Of course, thus far Aviron’s own sales are considerably more humble than the cycling giant&#8217;s. Until now, the company has largely relied on word of mouth sales, having sold in the neighborhood of 1,000 rowing machines since launching for the consumer market in July. The equipment retails for $2,299 a piece — though you can find it online for less.</p>
<p>Aviron works with an ODM to create the machine. While it touts some nice touches like a quiet nylon belt and 100 pounds of automatic electronic resistance, Aivron’s main differentiator is the software — especially a connected gaming experience via the built-in display. The monthly subscription runs $20-$30 and the company is quick to note that you can cancel at any time.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/0ke_RXQz7Ak?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>“Rowing engages 85% of your muscles,” founder and CEO Andy Hoang tells TechCrunch. “It’s low impact. There are a ton of benefits, but it’s super boring and super tough. When you combine it with high-intensity training, you have a death machine that pretty much no one’s gonna want to do. What better way to make it fun and exciting than by putting video games on there?”</p>
<p>The system sports six different workout categories, including real-time competition with other rowers. There are a few introductory workouts, to ensure that first-timers don’t injure themselves by just jumping directly into competitive rowing, but on the whole, the system avoids Peloton-style classes.</p>
<p>“Our workouts are short,” says Hoang. “They’re like 10-15 minutes. You do maybe one or two of them, and by the end of it, you feel like you&#8217;re going to die because it’s so tough. Peloton is typically 40-60 minutes, a little bit lower intensity and with less resistance. And obviously it’s a class led by an instructor, rather than getting chased by zombies.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TomRxaMvMy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/companies-rush-to-replace-the-gym-at-ces/">Companies rush to replace the gym at CES</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Companies rush to replace the gym at CES&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/companies-rush-to-replace-the-gym-at-ces/embed/#?secret=TomRxaMvMy" data-secret="TomRxaMvMy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/pivoting-to-home-fitness-aviron-offers-gamified-rowing-machines/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105697</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Webull, M1 and Public remove restrictions on &#8216;meme stocks&#8217; after citing trade settlement firm as the cause</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/webull-and-public-remove-restrictions-on-memestocks-after-citing-trade-settlement-firm-as-the-cause/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/webull-and-public-remove-restrictions-on-memestocks-after-citing-trade-settlement-firm-as-the-cause/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 19:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anthony noto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gamestop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reddit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stock market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yahoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105468</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Three of the popular retail stock market trading apps that have hosted much of the activity related to the Wall Street Bets subreddit-spurred run on stocks including GameStop (GME) and AMC, among others, have removed all restrictions on their exchange by their users. M1, Webull and Public had restricted transactions for the affected stocks earlier [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Three of the popular retail stock market trading apps that have hosted much of the activity related to the Wall Street Bets subreddit-spurred run on stocks including GameStop (GME) and AMC, among others, have removed all restrictions on their exchange by their users. M1, Webull and Public had restricted transactions for the affected stocks earlier in the day, along with Robinhood.</p>
<p>M1, Webull and Public all attributed the restrictions placed on these volatile stocks not to any effort to curb their purchase or sale, but instead cited the costs associated with settling the trades on the part of their clearing firm, Apex. All three platforms employ Apex to clear trades made by users via their platform.</p>
<p>In an interview with Webull CEO Anthony Denier, Yahoo Finance confirmed that the restriction was not something the company had any hand in deciding.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">NEW: The CEO of Webull tell us the decision to join Robinhood in restricting AMC and GameStop trades came from soaring costs to settle its users trades:</p>
<p>&quot;It wasn&#39;t our choice &#8230; this has to do with settlement mechanics in the market.&quot;<a href="https://t.co/Micz5U6SRc">pic.twitter.com/Micz5U6SRc</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Zack Guzman (@zGuz) <a href="https://twitter.com/zGuz/status/1354854476801302528?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 28, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Public confirmed via Twitter that users can now buy and sell $GME and $AMC and $KOSS on the platform, thanks to the resolution of the Apex blocker. Meanwhile Webull noted that all three stocks are now also available for exchange via their app, as <a href="https://twitter.com/M1_Finance/status/1354881668843188226?s=20">did M1 shortly after</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">We&#39;re back. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/26a1.png" alt="⚡" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>Our clearing firm, Apex, has resumed the ability to buy <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24GME&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$GME</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24AMC&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$AMC</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24KOSS&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$KOSS</a> on Public. We appreciate their cooperation and are grateful to our members for their patience and understanding.</p>
<p>&mdash; Public.com (@public) <a href="https://twitter.com/public/status/1354877232762810370?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 28, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Other platforms like SoFi so far haven&#8217;t restricted the stocks, <a href="https://twitter.com/anthonynoto/status/1354879252303286273">CEO Anthony Noto confirmed on Twitter</a>.</p>
<p>Robinhood earlier <a href="https://blog.robinhood.com/news/2021/1/28/keeping-customers-informed-through-market-volatility">issued a blog post</a> noting that it is restricting a number of stocks tied to the r/WallStreetBets action to counter short-seller hedge funds, arguing that it&#8217;s doing so in the best interest of users. This has not seemed to have been much appreciated by most users, based on the reaction on social media to that action thus far. Robinhood at no time references any technical barriers imposed by any clearing house.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="epyCjJ2ybG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/robinhood-users-say-its-restricting-trades-after-the-gamestop-brouhaha-shakes-markets/">Robinhood restricts trading in GameStop after retail brouhaha shakes markets</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Robinhood restricts trading in GameStop after retail brouhaha shakes markets&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/robinhood-users-say-its-restricting-trades-after-the-gamestop-brouhaha-shakes-markets/embed/#?secret=epyCjJ2ybG" data-secret="epyCjJ2ybG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/webull-and-public-remove-restrictions-on-memestocks-after-citing-trade-settlement-firm-as-the-cause/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105468</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mind the gap: E-commerce marketers should revise their TAM and SAM estimates</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/mind-the-gap-e-commerce-marketers-should-revise-their-tam-and-sam-estimates/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/mind-the-gap-e-commerce-marketers-should-revise-their-tam-and-sam-estimates/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 19:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Ecommerce and D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Total Addressable Market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web applications]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105600</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Have you built your total addressable market (TAM) and serviceable addressable market (SAM) estimates for 2021 considering how things evolved in 2020?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Ashwin Ramasamy</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Ashwinizer">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a>Ashwin Ramasamy</a> is the co-founder of <a href="//pipecandy.com/">PipeCandy</a>, an online merchant graph company that discovers and analyzes business and consumer perception metrics about D2C brands and e-commerce companies.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/17/how-d2c-brands-are-holding-up-during-the-pandemic/">How D2C brands are holding up during the pandemic</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/17/is-the-e-commerce-shift-going-to-last/">Is the e-commerce shift going to last?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">2021 is going to be another glorious year for e-commerce.</p>
<p>It is that time of the year when most of us are looking back at the &#8220;total addressable market&#8221; estimates to plan for specific campaigns. Unlike us, if you had your 2021 kick off in Q3, bless your soul. You are an enlightened being.</p>
<p>For the rest of you, for whom e-commerce is a strategic market, I have a question — have you built your total addressable market (TAM) and serviceable addressable market (SAM) estimates for 2021 considering how things evolved in 2020?</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			It&#8217;s important to understand the underlying business model dynamics of companies and visualize TAM from those perspectives.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>For most of us, research is a mind-numbing, repetitive exercise of clicking through links on Google until they all turn purple — at which point we start seeking the simplest possible explanation. For e-commerce, addressable market estimates come in the form of headlines from platforms like Shopify. The company quotes a merchant count number in its earnings calls and that becomes the basis for guesstimating the current TAM of e-commerce companies.</p>
<p>The other, rather simplistic approach is to look at the user-base count from several databases that publish tech platform-level user stats.</p>
<p>In reality, the simplest answer is not the right answer.</p>
<h2>Mind the gap</h2>
<p>Let&#8217;s take e-commerce shopping cart installations. Shopify, Magento, WooCommerce, BigCommerce and others publish installation numbers that run into millions.</p>
<p>Here is the dichotomy that should frame your TAM discussions.</p>
<p>E-commerce is long-tail heavy. Yes, there are millions of merchants, but e-commerce revenue is a fat-tail phenomenon — meaning, a disproportionate amount of e-commerce revenue comes from a few tens of thousands of companies.</p>
<p>PipeCandy publishes bottom-up <a href="https://pipecandy.com/RESEARCHer/">TAM estimates </a> with detailed data cuts by technology, logistics and payment system adoptions by firms across revenue tiers across all major markets. One of the common misconceptions we see in how firms misinterpret TAM estimates is that they equate revenue to spend potential.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/mind-the-gap-e-commerce-marketers-should-revise-their-tam-and-sam-estimates/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105600</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coinbase is going public via direct listing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/coinbase-is-going-public-via-direct-listing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/coinbase-is-going-public-via-direct-listing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 19:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joseph lubin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uniswap]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105647</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Coinbase plans to go public by way of a direct listing, the company announced in a blog post today. The cryptocurrency exchange was founded in 2012 and allows users to buy and trade decentralized tokens like bitcoin and ethereum. The company has raised over $540 million in funding as a private company. Last month, the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Coinbase plans to go public by way of a direct listing, the company <a href="https://blog.coinbase.com/coinbase-announces-proposed-direct-listing-3a52c4298ccc">announced</a> in a blog post today.</p>
<p>The cryptocurrency exchange was founded in 2012 and allows users to buy and trade decentralized tokens like bitcoin and ethereum. The company has <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/coinbase">raised over $540 million</a> in funding as a private company.</p>
<p>Last month, the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/coinbase-files-to-go-public-confidentially-and-were-hyped/">shared that it had confidentially filed an S-1 with the SEC</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The public has yet to see the company&#8217;s financials, but we now know that it has opted out of the traditional IPO process. Direct listings have been slowly gaining popularity. And given some outsized first day pops from recent tech IPOs, it&#8217;s not too surprising to see a company like Coinbase opt for this path to public markets.</p>
<p>The company is not alone in going this route. Roblox delayed its own offering after observing the late-2020 IPO market, opting <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/07/robloxs-raises-at-29-5-billion-valuation-as-it-readies-for-direct-listing/">instead for a direct listing of its own</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8QDAj4QpKY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/coinbase-files-to-go-public-confidentially-and-were-hyped/">Coinbase files to go public confidentially and we&#8217;re hyped</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Coinbase files to go public confidentially and we&#8217;re hyped&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/coinbase-files-to-go-public-confidentially-and-were-hyped/embed/#?secret=8QDAj4QpKY" data-secret="8QDAj4QpKY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Direct listings allow companies to skip elements of the traditional IPO by removing the need to price and sell a block of new equity. Instead, a company merely lists its shares, which then become available for trading. Of course, not every company has sufficient profile for the method to prove attractive, and the direct listing entity loses its ability to raise new primary capital; the best-known and richest companies may find direct listings the most attractive.</p>
<p>Recent months have been very friendly to tech IPOs, with investors racing to back technology companies that are primed to help with what&#8217;s been called the &#8220;digital transformation.&#8221; And with the cryptocurrency markets matching the public markets for froth, Coinbase could find itself in a pretty favorable spot when it begins to trade.</p>
<p>There is a general correlation between consumer interest in cryptocurrencies, trading volume and the price of bitcoin. As Coinbase generates incomes from users trading, it&#8217;s not a stretch to presume that a recent rally in the price of bitcoin and its peers has helped Coinbase&#8217;s own financial performance.</p>
<p>Coinbase&#8217;s announcement comes as Qualtrics, a software company, went public today. Its shares have rallied nearly 50% in today&#8217;s trading alone. More when the cryptocurrency company drops a public S-1 filing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/coinbase-is-going-public-via-direct-listing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105647</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Report: WeWork could be getting SPAC&#8217;d soon, too</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/report-wework-could-be-getting-spacd-soon-too/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/report-wework-could-be-getting-spacd-soon-too/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 19:22:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vivek ranadive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WeWork]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105617</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[According to a new report in the WSJ, WeWork, the co-working juggernaut that saw its attempt at a public offering blow up in spectacular fashion in the fall of 2019, might become a publicly traded company by merging with a blank-check company. Specifically, says the WSJ, the New York-based outfit has been &#8220;weighing offers from [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">According to a <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/wework-in-talks-to-combine-with-spac-or-raise-money-privately-11611857306">new report</a> in the WSJ, WeWork, the co-working juggernaut that saw its attempt at a public offering blow up in spectacular fashion in the fall of 2019, might become a publicly traded company by merging with a blank-check company.</p>
<p>Specifically, says the WSJ, the New York-based outfit has been &#8220;weighing offers from a SPAC affiliated with Bow Capital Management LLC and at least one other unidentified acquisition vehicle for several weeks&#8221; in a deal that could value WeWork at around $10 billion.</p>
<p>Asked for more information, a spokesperson for the company sent us the same statement that was sent to the Journal: &#8220;Over the past year, WeWork has remained focused on executing our plans for achieving profitability. Our significant progress combined with the increased market demand for flexible space, shows positive signs for our business. We will continue to explore opportunities that help us move closer toward our goals.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company is also contemplating inbound interest for more private funding, according to a person close to the company.</p>
<p>According to the WeWork spokesperson, WeWork currently has more than $3.6 billion of cash and unfunded cash commitments, including more than $875 million in available cash, and it believes this is &#8220;more than sufficient liquidity to weather a prolonged COVID environment.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s an understatement to say the company has had its ups and downs since outside investors took at look at WeWork&#8217;s S-1 in August 2019, which showed both massive losses as well as highlighted the enormous power wielded by its cofounder and then CEO, Adam Neumann.</p>
<p>After WeWork&#8217;s board first pressured Neumann&#8217;s to accept less shareholder power, then elbowed him out of the company, it was taken over by one of its biggest shareholders, SoftBank, which, by October of 2019 had plugged a massive <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/24/softbank-notes-it-has-now-invested-18-5-billion-in-wework-more-than-the-gdp-of-bolivia-which-has-11-5-million-people/">$18.5 billion</a> into the company, including as part of a rescue package, and was determined to find a way to avoid writing down the whole investment.</p>
<p>By February 2020, SoftBank had found a replacement for Neumann in Sandeep Mathrani, who stepped into the role of CEO after spending 1.5 years as the CEO of Brookfield Properties’ retail group and as a vice chairman of Brookfield Properties. (Before joining the Chicago-based company, Mathrani spent eight years as the CEO of General Growth Properties. It was one of the largest mall operators in the U.S. until Brookfield acquired it for $9.25 billion in cash in 2018.)</p>
<p>Of course, COVID-19 soon altered any plans Mathrani might have had for the company as the U.S. and elsewhere began to shut down, forcing people everywhere to work from home. WeWork, which had already begun conducting layoffs ahead of hiring him, would go on to part ways with 8,000 employees, representing one-third of its headcount.</p>
<p>Still, the company began staging a comeback as the year wore on and parents and others working from home &#8212; often in tight quarters with children and spouses and flat mates &#8212; began looking for alternative working spaces. Companies that had given up on the idea of returning to a full-time office environment also began contemplating co-working spaces</p>
<p>Indeed, by late October, Mathrani <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-10-29/wework-s-new-ceo-is-eyeing-an-ipo-again-after-he-turns-profit">told reporters</a> that WeWork was on track to turn profitable some time this year, and that after it hit &#8220;profitable growth first,&#8221; it would &#8220;revisit the IPO plan.&#8221;</p>
<p>Whether a traditional IPO was ever part of the strategy, it seems unlikely.</p>
<p>&#8220;There aren&#8217;t going to be a lot of bankers who are willing to go down the path of a roadshow again with WeWork; there&#8217;s too much historical baggage with the company,&#8221; says Zach Aarons, cofounder of the proptech-focused venture firm Metaprop in New York. &#8220;I just think the potential upside of running an IPO for WeWork isn&#8217;t that exciting,&#8221; he continues.</p>
<p>WeWork&#8217;s M&amp;A options, in the meantime, may be limited. Selling to a private equity firm might be a possibility, but the buyer for whom the company makes the most sense as an acquisition target &#8212; the rival business IWG &#8212; has a $3 billion market cap.</p>
<p>Put another way, if WeWork wants to be valued at $10 billion &#8212; and Aarons, who has come to own a stake in the company through some of WeWork&#8217;s past acquisitions, hopes it will &#8212; a SPAC is looking like its best option.</p>
<p>Bow Capital Management &#8212; reportedly one of the blank-check companies in pursuit of WeWork &#8212; is run by Vivek Ranadive, the founder of Tibco Software. In July, it registered plans for a $350 million blank-check company that would focus on acquiring a business in the technology, media and telecommunications industries.</p>
<p>Though there&#8217;s been <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-EKOV71m-PY">much discussion</a> over the years over whether WeWork is a tech company or much more of a pure real estate play, the company has long insisted it is the former.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bu49OsmAp0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/smart-lock-maker-latch-teams-with-real-estate-firm-to-go-public-via-spac/">Smart lock maker Latch teams with real estate firm to go public via SPAC</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Smart lock maker Latch teams with real estate firm to go public via SPAC&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/smart-lock-maker-latch-teams-with-real-estate-firm-to-go-public-via-spac/embed/#?secret=bu49OsmAp0" data-secret="bu49OsmAp0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/report-wework-could-be-getting-spacd-soon-too/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105617</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter is already working on integrating newsletters on its site, following Revue acquisition</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/twitter-is-already-working-on-integrating-newsletters-on-its-site-following-revue-acquisition/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/twitter-is-already-working-on-integrating-newsletters-on-its-site-following-revue-acquisition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 19:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105618</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter only announced its acquisition of newsletter platform Revue two days ago, but the company has already begun to integrate the product into the Twitter.com website. It appears &#8220;Newsletters&#8221; will soon be the newest addition to Twitter&#8217;s sidebar navigation, alongside Bookmarks, Moments, Twitter Ads and other options. The company is also readying a way to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitter-acquires-revue/">only announced</a> its acquisition of newsletter platform Revue two days ago, but the company has already begun to integrate the product into the Twitter.com website. It appears &#8220;Newsletters&#8221; will soon be the newest addition to Twitter&#8217;s sidebar navigation, alongside Bookmarks, Moments, Twitter Ads and other options. The company is also readying a way to promote the new product to Twitter users, promising them another way to reach their audience while getting paid for their work.</p>
<p>These findings and others were uncovered by noted reverse engineer <a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1354564523038924805">Jane Manchun Wong</a>, who dug into the Twitter.com website to see what the company may have in store for its newest acquisition.</p>
<p>According to a pop-up promotional message in development she found, Twitter will soon be pitching a handful of Revue benefits, like the ability to compose and schedule newsletters, embed tweets, import email lists, analyze engagement and earn money from paid followers. The messaging was clearly in early testing (it even had a typo!), but it hints at Twitter&#8217;s larger plans to tie Revue into the Twitter platform and serve as a way for prominent users to essentially monetize their reach.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Currently, the &#8220;Find Out More&#8221; button on pop-up message will redirect Twitter users to the Revue website Wong found.</p>
<p>In addition, Wong noted Twitter was making &#8220;Newsletters&#8221; a new navigation option on the Twitter sidebar menu. Unfortunately, it was not shown on the top-level menu where you today find options like Explore, Notifications, Messages or Bookmarks, but rather on the submenu you access from the three-dot &#8220;More&#8221; link.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Twitter is working to include the “<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f4f0.png" alt="📰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Newsletters” item in the menu in the web app, which shows the popup about <a href="https://twitter.com/revue?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@revue</a> above <a href="https://t.co/ATaXDGr0zc">pic.twitter.com/ATaXDGr0zc</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Jane Manchun Wong (@wongmjane) <a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1354566871740162049?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 27, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The tight integration between Revue and Twitter&#8217;s main platform could potentially give the company an interesting competitive advantage in the newsletters market &#8212; especially as Twitter has already dropped hints that its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/twitter-launches-its-voice-based-spaces-social-networking-feature-into-beta-testing/">new audio product, Twitter Spaces</a>, will also be used as a way to connect with newsletter subscribers.</p>
<p>In its <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/">announcement</a>, Twitter referred to &#8220;new settings for writers to host conversations&#8221; with their readers. That likely means Twitter users would be able to not just publish newsletters with the new Twitter product, but also monetize their existing follower base, find new readers through Twitter&#8217;s built-in features, and then engage their fans on an ongoing basis through audio chats in Spaces. Combined with its lowering of the paid newsletter fee to 5%, many authors are rightly considering the potential Twitter advantages. If anything at all is holding them back, it&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/will-this-time-be-any-different-for-twitter/">Twitter&#8217;s less-than-stellar reputation</a> when it comes to successfully capitalizing on some of its acquisitions.</p>
<p>Twitter declined to comment on Wong&#8217;s findings, but we understand these features are currently not live on the website. Wong told us she hasn&#8217;t found any indications of Revue integrations in the Twitter mobile apps just yet.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hFaCF77Nyx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/will-this-time-be-any-different-for-twitter/">Will this time be any different for Twitter?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Will this time be any different for Twitter?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/will-this-time-be-any-different-for-twitter/embed/#?secret=hFaCF77Nyx" data-secret="hFaCF77Nyx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/twitter-is-already-working-on-integrating-newsletters-on-its-site-following-revue-acquisition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105618</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Robinhood stops the games</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/robinhood-gamestop-this-is-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/robinhood-gamestop-this-is-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 19:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity Shot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gamestop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105530</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture-capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. This week the team — Natasha and Danny and Alex and Grace — recorded a bonus Equity Shot to help our listeners make sense out of the GameStop trading bonanza happening all over the internet. The story is fast-moving and news continues to break (twice [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/42e188ed-2b3a-4cdc-8eec-94792bf1efa5?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture-capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>This week the team — <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/DannyCrichton">Danny</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/gracedenhall">Grace</a> — recorded a bonus Equity Shot to help our listeners make sense out of the GameStop trading bonanza happening all over the internet. The story is fast-moving and news continues to break (twice during our recording, in fact) about how trading apps such as Robinhood are responding to the tear. Still, this type of story is worth a temperature check and timestamp because it feels like it&#8217;s a pivotal moment in many ways.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Here&#8217;s our coverage on the site so far for people playing catch up:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/how-trading-apps-are-responding-to-the-gamestop-fustercluck/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How Trading Apps are responding to the GameStop fustercluck</span></a> — <em>This piece from yesterday started our coverage of the response from trading apps concerning GameStop.</em></li>
<li><b></b><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/gamestop-memestocks-and-the-revenge-of-the-retail-trader/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">GameStop, meme stocks, and the revenge of the retail trader</span></a> — <em>This piece dug into what the initial story was about, with some jokes.</em></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/could-meme-stocks-like-gamestop-kill-bitcoins-rise/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Could meme stocks like GameStop kill Bitcoin’s rise?</span></a> — <em>This piece looks at what the other side of the stonk coin could be.</em></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/robinhood-users-say-its-restricting-trades-after-the-gamestop-brouhaha-shakes-markets/">Robinhood restricts trading in GameStop after retail brouhaha shakes markets</a> <em>—</em> <em>This piece looked into Robinhood&#8217;s moves from this morning, as the larger story went from huge to tectonic.</em></li>
<li> And, we gave a shout out to a good post by <a href="https://themargins.substack.com/p/game-stop">The Margins</a>, which gave perspective on how the unescapable GameStop stock crash will have tough and not meme-y consequences.</li>
</ul>
<p>Back later in the day with our usual weekly episode, which will not include any of the following phrases: stonks, retail traders, Robinhood or and r/Wallstreetbets. We promise. Talk soon!</p>
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST and Thursday afternoon as fast as we can get it out, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/robinhood-gamestop-this-is-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105530</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hear from Arlan Hamilton on finding the next big opportunities in tech at TC Sessions: Justice</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/hear-from-arlan-hamilton-on-finding-the-next-big-opportunities-in-tech-at-tc-sessions-justice/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/hear-from-arlan-hamilton-on-finding-the-next-big-opportunities-in-tech-at-tc-sessions-justice/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Megan Rose Dickey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 19:08:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arlan hamilton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backstage capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100864</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m very excited to announce Arlan Hamilton, founder and managing partner of Backstage Capital, will be joining us in a fireside chat at TC Sessions: Justice on March 3. Backstage Capital has raised more than $12 million to invest in more than 150 companies led by people of color, women and/or LGBTQ founders, including Spora [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">I&#8217;m very excited to announce Arlan Hamilton, founder and managing partner of Backstage Capital, will be joining us in a fireside chat at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/?utm_medium=editpost&amp;utm_campaign=justice2021&amp;utm_content=arlanhamilton&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=arlanhamiltonpost&amp;display=TRUE">TC Sessions: Justice</a> on March 3.</p>
<p>Backstage Capital has raised more than $12 million to invest in more than 150 companies led by people of color, women and/or LGBTQ founders, including Spora Health, Bitwise, Career Karma, Uncharted Power, Kairos and Zero Grocery. The venture firm is driven by the ethos that these founders represent the biggest opportunities in investment.</p>
<p>&#8220;I am into things that promote sustainability, that are clever,&#8221;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/07/8-black-investors-discuss-the-intersection-of-race-tech-and-vc/"> Hamilton said in an Extra Crunch survey in June</a>. &#8220;I like the senior care industry, but also pushing that a little further into senior activity and thriving entrepreneurship, et cetera. And media. I think media has a really interesting, exciting opportunity right now because of the way representation is so important, has always been, but it’s even more now. I’m seeing more and more interesting and unique media options rather than the status quo.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Backstage has gone on to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/05/backstage-capital-accelerator/">launch an accelerator in four cities to support underrepresented founders</a>, as well as a syndicate, <a href="https://www.backstagecrowd.com/faq">called Backstage Crowd</a>. Within the first three months of its relaunch in 2020, Backstage Crowd raised $1 million, <a href="https://backstagecapital.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Backstage-Capital-5-Year-Impact-Report-Final-1.pdf">according to the firm&#8217;s impact report</a>.</p>
<p>Hamilton is also the author of &#8220;It&#8217;s About Damn Time,&#8221; a book geared toward providing tactical advice for founders and aspiring investors.</p>
<p>At <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/?utm_medium=editpost&amp;utm_campaign=justice2021&amp;utm_content=arlanhamilton&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=arlanhamiltonpost&amp;display=TRUE">TC Sessions: Justice</a>, we&#8217;ll plan to chat with Hamilton about the state of venture capital, investing in underestimated and underfunded founders and more.</p>
<p>Be sure to snag your tickets here for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/?utm_medium=editpost&amp;utm_campaign=justice2021&amp;utm_content=arlanhamilton&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=arlanhamiltonpost&amp;display=TRUE">just $5 here</a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954"
			width="99%"
			height="500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/hear-from-arlan-hamilton-on-finding-the-next-big-opportunities-in-tech-at-tc-sessions-justice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100864</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple&#8217;s Tim Cook warns of adtech fuelling a &#8216;social catastrophe&#8217; as he defends app tracker opt-in</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/apples-tim-cook-warns-of-adtech-fuelling-a-social-catastrophe-as-he-defends-app-tracker-opt-in/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/apples-tim-cook-warns-of-adtech-fuelling-a-social-catastrophe-as-he-defends-app-tracker-opt-in/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 18:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antitrust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tim Cook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105303</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple&#8217;s CEO Tim Cook has urged Europe to step up privacy enforcement in a keynote speech to the CPDP conference today &#8212; echoing many of the points he made in Brussels in person two years ago when he hit out at the &#8216;data industrial complex&#8217; underpinning the adtech industry&#8217;s mass surveillance of Internet users. Reforming [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple&#8217;s CEO Tim Cook has urged Europe to step up privacy enforcement in a keynote speech to the <a href="https://www.cpdpconferences.org">CPDP</a> conference today &#8212; echoing many of the points he made in Brussels in person <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/24/apples-tim-cook-makes-blistering-attack-on-the-data-industrial-complex/">two years ago</a> when he hit out at the &#8216;data industrial complex&#8217; underpinning the adtech industry&#8217;s mass surveillance of Internet users.</p>
<p>Reforming current-gen adtech is now a humanitarian imperative, he argued in a speech that took a bunch of thinly-veiled swipes at Facebook.</p>
<p>&#8220;As I said in Brussels two years ago, it is certainly time, not only for a comprehensive privacy law here in the United States, but also for worldwide laws and new international agreements that enshrine the principles of data minimization, user knowledge, user access and data security across the globe,&#8221; said Cook.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div>&#8220;Together, we must send a universal, humanistic response to those who claim a right to users’ private information about what should not and will not be tolerated,&#8221; he added.</div>
<p>The message comes at a critical time for Apple as it prepares to flip a switch that will, for the first time, require developers to gain opt-in user consent to tracking.</p>
<p>Earlier today Apple <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/apple-app-tracking-transparency/">confirmed</a> it would be enabling the App Tracking Transparency (ATT) feature in the next beta release of iOS 14, which it said would roll out in early spring.</p>
<p>The tech giant had intended to debut the feature last year but <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/apple-delay-ios-14-privacy-ad-tracking/">delayed</a> to give developers more time to adapt.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RGTW9PadtY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/apple-app-tracking-transparency/">Apple&#8217;s App Tracking Transparency feature will be enabled by default and arrive in &#8216;early spring&#8217; on iOS</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple&#8217;s App Tracking Transparency feature will be enabled by default and arrive in &#8216;early spring&#8217; on iOS&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/apple-app-tracking-transparency/embed/#?secret=RGTW9PadtY" data-secret="RGTW9PadtY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Adtech giant Facebook has also been aggressively briefing against the shift, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/27/facebook-vs-apple-ad-tracking/">warning</a> of a major impact on publishers who use its ad network once Apple gives its users the ability to refuse third party tracking.</p>
<p>Reporting its Q4 earnings <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/facebook-q4-earnings-2/">yesterday</a>, Facebook also sounded a warning over “more significant advertising headwinds” impacting its own bottom line this year &#8212; naming Apple&#8217;s ATT as a risk (as well as what it couched as &#8220;the evolving regulatory landscape&#8221;).</p>
<p>In the speech to a data protection and privacy conference which is usually held in Brussels (but has been streamed online because of the pandemic), Cook made an aggressive defence of ATT and Apple&#8217;s pro-privacy stance in general, saying the forthcoming tracking opt-in is about &#8220;returning control to users&#8221; and linking adtech-fuelled surveilled of Internet users to a range of harms, including the spread of conspiracy theories, extremism and real-world violence.</p>
<p>&#8220;Users have asked for this feature for a long time,&#8221; he said of ATT. &#8220;We have worked closely with developers to give them the time and resources to implement it and we&#8217;re passionate about it because we think it has great potential to make things better for everybody.&#8221;</p>
<p>The move has attracted a competition challenge in France where four online advertising lobbies filed an antitrust complaint last <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/apple-advertisting-france-idUSL1N2HJ237">October</a> &#8212; arguing that Apple requiring developers ask app users for permission to track them is an abuse of market power by Apple. (A similar complaint has been lodged in the UK over Google&#8217;s move to depreciated third party tracking cookies in Chrome &#8212; and there the regulator has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/googles-plan-to-replace-tracking-cookies-goes-under-uk-antitrust-probe/">opened an investigation</a>.)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/facebook-looks-to-take-its-fight-with-apple-to-court">The Information</a> also reported today that Facebook is preparing to lodge an antitrust lawsuit against Apple &#8212; so the legal stakes are rising. (Though the social media giant is itself being <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2020/12/ftc-sues-facebook-illegal-monopolization">sued by the FTC</a> which alleges it has maintained a social networking monopoly via years of anti-competitive conduct&#8230; )</p>
<p>In the speech Cook highlighted another recent pro-privacy move made by Apple to require iOS developers to display &#8220;privacy nutrition&#8221; labels within the App Store &#8212; providing users with an overview of their data collection practices. Both the labels and the incoming ATT apply in the case of Apple&#8217;s own apps (not just third parties), as we reported earlier.</p>
<p>Cook said these moves align with Apple&#8217;s overarching philosophy: To make technology that &#8220;serves people and has their well-being in mind&#8221; &#8212; contrasting its approach with a rapacious &#8216;data industrial complex&#8217; that wants to aggregate information about everything people do online to use against them, as a tool of mass manipulation.</p>
<p>&#8220;It seems no piece of information is too private or personal to be surveilled, monetized and aggregated into a 360 degree view of your life,&#8221; Cook warned. &#8220;The end result of all of this is that you are no longer the customer; you are the product.</p>
<p>&#8220;When ATT is in full effect users will have a say over this kind of tracking. Some may well think that sharing this degree of information is worth it for more targeted ads. Many others, I suspect, will not. Just as most appreciated it when we built this similar functionality into <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/05/apple-adds-a-tracker-blocker-to-desktop-safari/">Safari limiting web trackers several years ago</a>,&#8221; he went on, adding that: &#8220;We see developing these kinds of privacy-centric features and innovations as a core responsibility of our work. We always have, we always will.&#8221;</p>
<p>Apple&#8217;s CEO pointed out that advertising has flourished in the past without the need for privacy-hostile mass surveillance, arguing: &#8220;Technology does not need vast troves of personal data stitched together across dozens of websites and apps in order to succeed. Advertising existed and thrived for decades without it. And we&#8217;re here today because the path of least resistance is rarely the path of wisdom.&#8221;</p>
<p>He also made some veiled sideswipes at Facebook &#8212; avoiding literally naming the adtech giant but hitting out at the notion of a business that&#8217;s built on &#8220;surveilling users&#8221;, on &#8220;data exploitation&#8221; and on &#8220;choices that are no choices at all&#8221;.</p>
<p>Such an entity &#8220;does not deserve our praise, it deserves reform&#8221;, he went on, having earlier heaped praise on Europe&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) for its role in furthering privacy rights &#8212; telling conference delegates that enforcement &#8220;must continue&#8221;. (The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/">GDPR&#8217;s weak spot to date has been exactly that</a>; but 2.5 years in there are signs the regime is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/grindr-on-the-hook-for-e10m-over-gdpr-consent-violations/">getting into a groove</a>.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BRftQ83KBE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/grindr-on-the-hook-for-e10m-over-gdpr-consent-violations/">Grindr on the hook for €10M over GDPR consent violations</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Grindr on the hook for €10M over GDPR consent violations&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/grindr-on-the-hook-for-e10m-over-gdpr-consent-violations/embed/#?secret=BRftQ83KBE" data-secret="BRftQ83KBE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In further sideswipes at Facebook, Cook attacked the role of data-gobbling, engagement-obsessed adtech in fuelling disinformation and conspiracy theories &#8212; arguing that the consequences of such an approach are simply too high for democratic societies to accept.</p>
<p>&#8220;We should not look away from the bigger picture,&#8221; he argued. &#8220;At a moment of rampant disinformation and conspiracy theories juiced by algorithms we can no longer turn a blind eye to a theory of technology that says all engagement is good engagement, the longer the better. And all with the goal of collecting as much data as possible.</p>
<p>&#8220;Too many are still asking the question how much can we get away with? When they need to be asking what are the consequences? What are the consequences of prioritizing conspiracy theories and violent incitement simply because of the high rates of engagement? What are the consequences of not just tolerating but rewarding content that undermines public trust in lifesaving vaccinations? What are consequences of seeing thousands of users join extremist groups and then perpetuating an algorithm that recommends even more,&#8221; he went on &#8212; sketching a number of scenarios of which Facebook&#8217;s business stands directly accused.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is long past time to stop pretending that this approach doesn&#8217;t come with a cost. Of polarization. Of lost trust. And &#8212; yes &#8212; of violence. A social dilemma cannot be allowed to become a social catastrophe,&#8221; he added, rebranding &#8216;The Social Network&#8217; at a stroke.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="F2lmlm63m1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/whatsapp-facebook-data-sharing-transparency-under-review-by-eu-dpas-after-ireland-sends-draft-decision/">WhatsApp-Facebook data-sharing transparency under review by EU DPAs after Ireland sends draft decision</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;WhatsApp-Facebook data-sharing transparency under review by EU DPAs after Ireland sends draft decision&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/whatsapp-facebook-data-sharing-transparency-under-review-by-eu-dpas-after-ireland-sends-draft-decision/embed/#?secret=F2lmlm63m1" data-secret="F2lmlm63m1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Apple has reason to appeal to a European audience of data protection experts to further its fight with adtech objectors to its ATT, as EU regulators have the power to take enforcement decisions that would align with and support its approach. Although they have been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/17/privacy-experts-slam-uks-disastrous-failure-to-tackle-unlawful-adtech/">shy to do so so far</a>.</p>
<p>Facebook&#8217;s lead data protection supervisor in Europe, Ireland&#8217;s Data Protection Commission (DPC), has a backlog of investigations into a number of aspects of its business &#8212; including its use of so-called &#8216;forced consent&#8217; (as users are not given any choice over being tracked for ad targeting if they wish to use its services).</p>
<p>That lack of choice stands in stark contrast to the change Apple is driving on its App Store, where all entities will be required to ask users if they want to be tracked. So Apple&#8217;s move aligns with the principles of European data protection law (which, for example, requires that consent for processing people&#8217;s data be freely given in order to be legally valid).</p>
<p>Equally, Facebook&#8217;s continued refusal to give users a choice stands in direct conflict with EU law and risks GDPR enforcement. (The kind Cook was urging in his speech.)</p>
<p>2021 looks like it could be a critical year on that front. A long running DPC investigation into the transparency of data-sharing between WhatsApp and Facebook is headed for enforcement this year &#8212; after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/whatsapp-facebook-data-sharing-transparency-under-review-by-eu-dpas-after-ireland-sends-draft-decision/">Ireland sent a draft decision to the other EU data protection agencies</a> at the back end of last year.</p>
<p>Last week <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/whatsapp-privacy-fine-data-protection-europe-50-million/">Politico</a> reported WhatsApp could be on the hook for a fine of between €30M and €50M in that single case. More pertinently for the tech giant &#8212; which paid a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/24/facebook-settles-with-ftc-5-billion-and-new-privacy-guarantees/">$5BN fine to the FTC in 2019 to settle charges related to privacy failings</a> (but was not required to make any material changes to how it operates its ad business) &#8212; WhatsApp could be ordered to change how it handles user data.</p>
<p>A regulatory order to stop processing certain types of user data &#8212; or mandating it ask users for consent before it can do so &#8212; could clearly have a far greater impact on Facebook&#8217;s business empire.</p>
<p>The tech giant is also facing a final verdict <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/facebooks-eu-us-data-transfers-face-their-final-countdown/">later this year</a> on whether it can continue to legally transfer European users&#8217; data out of the bloc.</p>
<p>If Facebook is ordered to suspend such data flows that would mean massive disruption to a sizeable chunk of its business (in <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/04/25/facebook-q1-2019-user-growth-in-europe-is-bouncing-back-despite-gdpr.html">2019</a> it reported 286M DAUs in the region in Q1).</p>
<p>So &#8212; in short &#8212; the regulatory conditions around Facebook&#8217;s business are certainly &#8216;evolving&#8217;.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="13TGekDYcB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/apple-takes-aim-at-adtech-hysteria-over-ios-app-tracking-change/">Apple takes aim at adtech hysteria over iOS app tracking change</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple takes aim at adtech hysteria over iOS app tracking change&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/apple-takes-aim-at-adtech-hysteria-over-ios-app-tracking-change/embed/#?secret=13TGekDYcB" data-secret="13TGekDYcB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The data industrial complex&#8217;s fight back against the looming privacy enforcement at Apple&#8217;s platform level involves ploughing legal resource into trying to claim such moves are anti-competitive. However EU lawmakers seem alive to this self-interested push to appropriate &#8216;antitrust&#8217; as a tool to stymie privacy enforcement.</p>
<p>(And it&#8217;s notable that Cook referred to privacy &#8220;innovation&#8221; in the speech. Including this ask: &#8220;Will the future belong to the innovations that make our lives better, more fulfilled and more human?&#8221; &#8212; which is really the key question in the privacy vs competition regulation &#8216;debate&#8217;.)</p>
<p>Last month Commission EVP and competition chief, Margrethe Vestager told the OECD Global Competition Forum that antitrust enforcers should be “vigilant so that privacy is not used as a shield against competition”. However her remarks had a sting in the tail for the data industrial complex &#8212; as she expressed support for a<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/23/antitrust-case-against-facebooks-super-profiling-back-on-track-after-german-federal-court-ruling/"> ‘superprofiling’ case against Facebook</a> in Germany.</p>
<p>That case (which is continuing to be litigated by the German FCO) combines privacy and competition in new and interesting ways. If the regulator prevails it could result in a structural separation of Facebook&#8217;s social empire at the data level &#8212; in a sort of regulatory equivalent of moving fast and breaking things.</p>
<p>So it&#8217;s notable Vestager dubbed that piece of regulatory innovation “inspiring and interesting”. Which sounds more of a vote of confidence than condemnation from Europe&#8217;s digital policy and competition chief.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rxz0eQkEwt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/23/antitrust-case-against-facebooks-super-profiling-back-on-track-after-german-federal-court-ruling/">Antitrust case against Facebook&#8217;s &#8216;super profiling&#8217; back on track after German federal court ruling</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Antitrust case against Facebook&#8217;s &#8216;super profiling&#8217; back on track after German federal court ruling&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/23/antitrust-case-against-facebooks-super-profiling-back-on-track-after-german-federal-court-ruling/embed/#?secret=rxz0eQkEwt" data-secret="rxz0eQkEwt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/apples-tim-cook-warns-of-adtech-fuelling-a-social-catastrophe-as-he-defends-app-tracker-opt-in/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105303</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
