<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 04:46:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Indian online insurer PolicyBazaar files for IPO, seeks to raise over $800 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/indian-online-insurer-policybazaar-files-for-ipo-seeks-to-raise-over-800-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/indian-online-insurer-policybazaar-files-for-ipo-seeks-to-raise-over-800-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 04:45:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[falcon edge capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PolicyBazaar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184430</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Indian online insurance aggregator PolicyBazaar has filed for an initial public offering in which it is seeking to raise $809 million, becoming the fourth startup in the past two months from the South Asian market to explore public markets. In papers submitted to the market regulator in India, PolicyBazaar said it is looking to raise [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Indian <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/17/softbank-backed-indian-insurance-platform-policybazaar-raises-75-million/">online insurance aggregator</a> PolicyBazaar has filed for an initial public offering in which it is seeking to raise $809 million, becoming the fourth startup in the past two months from the South Asian market to explore public markets.</p>
<p>In papers submitted to the market regulator in India, PolicyBazaar said it is looking to raise $504 million by issuing new shares while the rest will be driven by sale of shares by existing investors.</p>
<p>The 12-year-old startup &#8212; backed by SoftBank, Falcon Edge Capital, Tiger Global, and InfoEdge &#8212; said it may consider raising about $100 million in a pre-IPO round.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Policybazaar serves as an aggregator that allows users to compare and buy policies &#8212; across categories including life, health, travel, auto and property &#8212; from dozens of insurers on its website without having to go through conventional agents. It operates in India as well as the Middle East.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2126229" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2126229" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2126229 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/policybazaar-website.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="398" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/policybazaar-website.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/policybazaar-website.jpg?resize=150,88 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/policybazaar-website.jpg?resize=300,176 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/policybazaar-website.jpg?resize=768,450 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/policybazaar-website.jpg?resize=680,398 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/policybazaar-website.jpg?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2126229" class="wp-caption-text">PolicyBazaar website</p></div></p>
<p>In India only a fraction of the nation’s 1.3 billion people currently have access to insurance and some analysts say that digital firms could prove crucial in bringing these services to the masses. According to rating agency ICRA, insurance products had reached less than 3% of the population as of 2017.</p>
<p>An average Indian makes about $2,100 in a year, according to World Bank. ICRA estimated that of those Indians who had purchased an insurance product, they were spending less than $50 on it in 2017.</p>
<p>In a report early this year, analysts at Bernstein estimated that Policybazaar commands 90% of share in the online insurance distribution market. The platform also sells loans, credit cards and mutual funds. The startup says it sells over a million policies a month.</p>
<p>“India has an under-penetrated insurance market. Within the under-penetrated landscape, digital distribution through web-aggregators like Policybazaar forms &lt;1% of the industry. This offers a large headroom for growth,” Bernstein analysts wrote to clients.</p>
<p>Zomato, which had a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/23/food-delivery-firm-zomato-surges-in-key-india-debut/">stellar public debut last month</a>, as well as fintech firms Paytm and MobiKwik have filed for their initial public offerings in recent weeks.</p>
<p><em>More to follow&#8230;</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/indian-online-insurer-policybazaar-files-for-ipo-seeks-to-raise-over-800-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184430</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indian edtech Unacademy valued at $3.44 billion in $440 million fundraise</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/indian-edtech-unacademy-valued-at-3-44-billion-in-440-million-fundraise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/indian-edtech-unacademy-valued-at-3-44-billion-in-440-million-fundraise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 01:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mirae Asset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Vision Fund 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unacademy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184406</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Indian online learning platform Unacademy has raised $440 million in a new financing round as investors double down on the South Asian market and elsewhere following a widening series of regulatory crackdowns in China that wiped hundreds of billions of dollars last month. Temasek led the Bangalore-based startup’s new financing round while Mirae Asset and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Indian online learning platform Unacademy has raised $440 million in a new financing round as investors double down on the South Asian market and elsewhere following a widening series of regulatory crackdowns in China that wiped hundreds of billions of dollars last month.</p>
<p>Temasek led the Bangalore-based startup’s new financing round while Mirae Asset and existing investors including SoftBank Vision Fund 2, General Atlantic, Tiger Global as well as Zomato co-founder and chief executive Deepinder Goyal and Oyo founder Ritesh Agarwal participated in it, the startup said without disclosing the name of the new round (which should be Series G).</p>
<p>The new round values the six-year-old startup at $3.44 billion, up from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/tiger-global-invests-in-india-unacademy-at-2-billion-valuation/">$2 billion in November last year</a>. The investment brings Unacademy’s to-date raise to about $860 million.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The online learning platform, which began its journey on YouTube and still uses Google&#8217;s video platform to on-board educators, helps students prepare for competitive exams to get into college, as well as those who are pursuing graduate-level courses.</p>
<p>On its app, students watch live classes from educators and later engage in sessions to review topics in more detail. The startup has over 50,000 educators on its platform, many of whom are very popular on YouTube. These educators help Unacademy sell more subscriptions and in return get a commission, according to industry executives familiar with the business arrangement.</p>
<p>Unacademy has amassed over 6 million monthly active users (over 600,000 of whom pay for the service) in over 10,000 cities in India.</p>
<p>Gaurav Munjal, Unacademy co-founder and chief executive, said the startup will deploy the fresh capital to broaden its bets on new categories such as upskilling, jobs and hiring.</p>
<p>Relevel is &#8220;giving people a path to get their dream job irrespective of their educational background, while Graphy is &#8220;empowering creators to build their online businesses to sell digital goods including NFTs,&#8221; he said in a tweet.</p>
<p>In a recent conversation with TechCrunch, Munjal said he wants Unacademy to become a consumer internet tech giant &#8212; perhaps the &#8220;Tencent of India.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2078582" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2078582" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2078582 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/gs-online-education-spends.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="516" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/gs-online-education-spends.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/gs-online-education-spends.jpg?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/gs-online-education-spends.jpg?resize=300,151 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/gs-online-education-spends.jpg?resize=768,387 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/gs-online-education-spends.jpg?resize=680,343 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/gs-online-education-spends.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2078582" class="wp-caption-text">Spendings on education in India is among the highest globally (Source: A report from analysts at Goldman Sachs to clients last year.)</p></div></p>
<p>The startup competes with scores of firms including Byju&#8217;s, which is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/ubs-investment-makes-byjus-the-most-valuable-startup-in-india/">India&#8217;s most valuable startup</a> (at $16.5 billion valuation), TAL-backed Vedantu, Tiger Global-backed Classplus, and Lightspeed Venture-backed Teachmint. (TAL&#8217;s American depositary receipts have dropped to some 70% in recent days from $90 early this year as investors <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/chinas-regulatory-crackdown-is-good-news-for-startups-aligned-with-ccp-goals/">retreat following China&#8217;s crackdowns</a>.)</p>
<p>All these startups have reported growth in the past year as India &#8212; like most other countries &#8212; enforced lockdowns and closed schools to contain the spread of the coronavirus.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184424" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184424" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2184424 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/unacademy-app.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="281" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/unacademy-app.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/unacademy-app.jpg?resize=150,41 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/unacademy-app.jpg?resize=300,82 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/unacademy-app.jpg?resize=768,211 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/unacademy-app.jpg?resize=680,187 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/unacademy-app.jpg?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184424" class="wp-caption-text">Monthly active users of education learning firms&#8217; Android apps in India, according to mobile insight platform App Annie (sourced by TechCrunch from industry execs.)</p></div></p>
<p>At stake is India&#8217;s online education market, which is estimated to generate $5 billion in revenue by 2025 (up from about $1 billion last year), according to analysts at Goldman Sachs.</p>
<p>As of last year, there were about 6 million students in India who were paying for an online learning app, a figure Bernstein analysts expect to reach about 70 million by the end of the decade.</p>
<p>Unacademy said last week it was creating a $40 million fund for educators on its platform. &#8220;On Day One (which is today) we already have more than 300 Educators eligible for the Grant which they will get immediately. Over the next few years we will give Grants of over $40M to our Educators,&#8221; said Munjal in a tweet.</p>
<p>The new investment comes at a time when Indian startups are raising record capital and a handful of mature firms are beginning to explore the public markets. Business-to-business commerce and financing startup Ofbusiness said over the weekend it had raised $160 million in a new financing round (led by SoftBank Vision Fund 2) at a valuation of $1.5 billion, becoming the 18th Indian startup to attain the unicorn status, up from 11 last year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/indian-edtech-unacademy-valued-at-3-44-billion-in-440-million-fundraise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184406</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Square to buy &#8216;buy now, pay later&#8217; giant Afterpay in $29B deal</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/square-to-buy-buy-now-pay-later-giant-afterpay-in-29b-deal/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/square-to-buy-buy-now-pay-later-giant-afterpay-in-29b-deal/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AfterPay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buy Now]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cash app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Director]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jack dorsey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klarna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pay Later]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Square]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[up]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184395</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a blockbuster deal that rocks the fintech world, Square announced today that it is acquiring Australian buy now, pay later giant Afterpay in a $29 billion all-stock deal. The purchase price is based on the closing price of Square common stock on July 30, which was $247.26. The transaction is expected to close in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In a blockbuster deal that rocks the fintech world, Square announced today that it is acquiring Australian buy now, pay later giant Afterpay in a $29 billion all-stock deal.</p>
<p>The purchase price is based on the closing price of Square common stock on July 30, which was <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/SQ/history?fr=sycsrp_catchall">$247.26</a>. The transaction is expected to close in the first quarter of 2022, contingent upon certain closing conditions. It values Afterpay at more than 30% premium to its latest closing price of A$96.66.</p>
<p>Square co-founder and CEO Jack Dorsey said in a statement that the two fintech behemoths “have a shared purpose.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“We built our business to make the financial system more fair, accessible, and inclusive, and Afterpay has built a trusted brand aligned with those principles,” he said in the statement. “Together, we can better connect our Cash App and Seller ecosystems to deliver even more compelling products and services for merchants and consumers, putting the power back in their hands.”</p>
<p>The combination of the two companies would create a payments giant unlike any other. Over the past 18 months, the buy now, pay later space has essentially exploded, appealing especially to younger generations drawn to the idea of not using credit cards or paying interest and instead opting for the installment loans, which have become ubiquitous online and in retail stores.</p>
<p>As of June 30, Afterpay served more than 16 million consumers and nearly 100,000 merchants globally, including major retailers across industries such as fashion, homewares, beauty and sporting goods, among others.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dDVPBRlkvL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/as-bnpl-startups-raise-a-look-at-klarna-affirm-and-afterpay-earnings/">As BNPL startups raise, a look at Klarna, Affirm and Afterpay earnings</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As BNPL startups raise, a look at Klarna, Affirm and Afterpay earnings&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/as-bnpl-startups-raise-a-look-at-klarna-affirm-and-afterpay-earnings/embed/#?secret=dDVPBRlkvL" data-secret="dDVPBRlkvL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The addition of Afterpay, the companies’ statement said, will “accelerate Square’s strategic priorities” for its Seller and Cash App ecosystems. Square plans to integrate Afterpay into its existing Seller and Cash App business units, so that even “the smallest of merchants” can offer buy now, pay later at checkout. The integration will also give Afterpay consumers the ability to manage their installment payments directly in Cash App. Cash App customers will be able to find merchants and buy now, pay later (BNPL) offers directly within the app.</p>
<p>Afterpay&#8217;s co-founders and co-CEOs Anthony Eisen and Nick Molnar will join Square upon closure of the deal and help lead Afterpay’s respective merchant and consumer businesses. Square said it will appoint one Afterpay director to its board.</p>
<p>Shareholders of Afterpay will get 0.375 shares of Square Class A stock for every share they own. This implies a price of about A$126.21 per share based on Square&#8217;s Friday close, according to the companies.</p>
<p>Will there be more consolidation in the space? That remains to be seen, and Twitter is all certainly abuzz about what deals could be next. Here in the U.S., rival Affirm (founded by PayPal co-founder Max Levchin) <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/affirm-doubles-after-starting-to-trade-despite-strong-ipo-pricing/">went public earlier this year</a>. On July 30, shares closed at $56.32, <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/AFRM/?fr=sycsrp_catchall">significantly lower</a> than its opening price and 52-week-high of $146.90. Meanwhile, European competitor Klarna — which is growing rapidly in the U.S. — in June <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/fintech-giant-klarna-raises-639m-at-a-45-6b-valuation/">raised another $639 million</a> at a staggering post-money valuation of $45.6 billion.</p>
<p>No doubt the BNPL fight for the U.S. consumer is only heating up with this deal.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7LiNGozNts"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/fintech-giant-klarna-raises-639m-at-a-45-6b-valuation/">Fintech giant Klarna raises $639M at a $45.6B valuation amid &#8216;massive momentum&#8217; in the US</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fintech giant Klarna raises $639M at a $45.6B valuation amid &#8216;massive momentum&#8217; in the US&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/fintech-giant-klarna-raises-639m-at-a-45-6b-valuation/embed/#?secret=7LiNGozNts" data-secret="7LiNGozNts" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/square-to-buy-buy-now-pay-later-giant-afterpay-in-29b-deal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184395</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unicorns are ready for a haircut</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/unicorns-are-ready-for-a-haircut/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/unicorns-are-ready-for-a-haircut/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 18:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups Weekly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The digitization of your haircut may not have been on your 2020 bucket list, but 2021 has an even more surprising line item: Tech-powered barbershops are now a business proposition valued at nearly a billion dollars. Squire is a back-end barbershop management tool for independent businesses. I first covered it in the early months of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The digitization of your haircut may not have been on your 2020 bucket list, but 2021 has an even more surprising line item: Tech-powered barbershops are now a business proposition valued at nearly a billion dollars.</p>
<p>Squire is a back-end barbershop management tool for independent businesses. I first covered it in the early months of the COVID-19 pandemic. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/26/squire-haircuts-coronavirus-crv-34-million-series-b/">The startup raised millions of dollars</a> days before its key clientele — barber shops — were shut down across the country. The company eventually went from defense to offense in its growth strategy, finding itself as a key partner for any barbershop that needed to start offering contactless payments, digital appointment booking and a more seamless customer experience built for a generation used to doing everything online.</p>
<p>This week, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/squire-a-barbershop-tech-platform-triples-its-valuation-again-with-tiger-global/">Squire tripled its valuation thanks to a Tiger-Global-led round.</a> The company is now worth $750 million, after being valued at around $75 million when we first spoke to them.</p>
<p>When I spoke to co-founder Dave Salvant, who launched the company with Songe LaRon in 2016, he explained how the company is now in a spot to expand into other barbershop-specific value propositions — either through acquisitions or partnerships. This week, for example, Squire announced that it launched a payment processing arm with Bond, a venture-backed fintech infrastructure company. The company also partnered with Gusto to bring on HR services for its clientele. Salvant noted how the progress of tech, especially financial services, lets them offer up a strong product without needing to build everything in-house.</p>
<p>While these are partnerships for now, I wouldn’t be surprised if we see Squire begin to scoop up companies that can unlock value from its existing datasets of how barbershops function and what kind of capital comes in and out of those doors.</p>
<p><strong>Behind the numbers:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/growth-is-not-enough/">Growth is not enough</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/26/squire-haircuts-coronavirus-crv-34-million-series-b/">Squire balances clean fades with the coronavirus</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/04/heres-why-so-many-fintech-startups-are-loaning-to-small-businesses/">Here’s why so many fintech startups are loaning to small businesses</a></li>
</ul>
<p>It’s a company to watch that fits into the narrative of pandemic rocked, then proven startups looking to expand with fresh capitalization. Less common, though, is that Squire is now en route to becoming a historical and unfortunately still rare Black-led unicorn. More data points, the better.</p>
<p>In the rest of this newsletter, we’ll discuss Robinhood’s public debut and why a CEO thinks everyone needs to be them for a day. You can find me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">@nmasc_.</a></p>
<h2>Robinhood sells Robinhood</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2105946" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2105946" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2105946" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/robinhood-brick-wall.jpg" alt="illustration of robinhood feather logo spraypainted on a brick wall" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/robinhood-brick-wall.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/robinhood-brick-wall.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/robinhood-brick-wall.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/robinhood-brick-wall.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/robinhood-brick-wall.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/robinhood-brick-wall.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/robinhood-brick-wall.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/robinhood-brick-wall.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2105946" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>The long-awaited Robinhood IPO is no longer long-awaited. After <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/robinhood-targets-ipo-valuation-up-to-35b-amid-warning-that-crypto-incomes-are-slipping/">pricing at the lower end of its range</a>, the consumer investing and trading app’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/robinhoods-stock-drops-8-in-its-first-days-trading/">shares went down sharply</a>, teetering between 8% to 10%.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know: </strong>IPO expert and fellow Equity co-host Alex Wilhelm gave us two reasons as to why Robinhood’s stock went down. After all, we’re used to pops in the consumer-facing tech company world.</p>
<blockquote><p>Robinhood made a big chunk of its IPO available to its own users. Or, in practice, Robinhood curtailed early retail demand by offering its investors and traders shares at the same price and level of access that big investors were given. It’s a neat idea. But by doing so, Robinhood may have lowered unserved retail interest in its shares, perhaps reshaping its early supply/demand curve.</p></blockquote>
<p>Or maybe the company’s warnings that its trading volumes could decline in Q2 2021 scared off some bulls.</p>
<h2>You get to be a CEO, you get to be a CEO!</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2050300" style="width: 1010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2050300" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2050300" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/GettyImages-sb10063936j-001.jpg" alt="Burst balloons and party streamers on wooden floor" width="1000" height="665" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/GettyImages-sb10063936j-001.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/GettyImages-sb10063936j-001.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/GettyImages-sb10063936j-001.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/GettyImages-sb10063936j-001.jpg?resize=768,511 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/GettyImages-sb10063936j-001.jpg?resize=680,452 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/GettyImages-sb10063936j-001.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2050300" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Richard+Drury" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Richard Drury <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Now that free beer is no longer a company perk, the next best one may have emerged: Let <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/why-i-make-everyone-in-my-company-be-the-ceo-for-a-day/">anyone in your company become CEO for a day</a>. Vincit CEO Ville Houttu implemented this program at his company in 2018 and said that the initiative has paid off “tenfold.”</p>
<p><strong>Here’s how it works, per the company: </strong></p>
<blockquote><p>The program gives our employee the reins for 24 hours with an unlimited budget. The only requirement? The CEO must make one lasting decision that will help improve the working experience of Vincit employees. Whatever the CEO of the Day decides, the company sticks with. They can purchase something for the company, change a policy, update a tool we use … Really, anything that they come up with can be done.</p></blockquote>
<p>You can see the resulting policies <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/why-i-make-everyone-in-my-company-be-the-ceo-for-a-day/">in our story,</a> but in my humble opinion, the end result is definitely better than free beer.</p>
<h2>Around TC</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">The TechCrunch Disrupt Agenda just went live</a>. It’s a must-read line up and a must-attend event. Some standouts:
<ul>
<li>Pot, Pottery and Beyond with Seth Rogen (Houseplant), Haneen Davies (Houseplant) and Michael Mohr (Houseplant)</li>
<li>Breaking the Bank with Brian Armstrong (Coinbase)</li>
<li>Speaking SPAC with Chamath Palihapitiya (Social Capital)</li>
<li>Dogmatic Design with Melanie Perkins (Canva)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Shout out to <a href="https://twitter.com/asilbwrites">Amanda Silberling,</a> a recent addition to the TechCrunch team who has been absolutely crushing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/author/amanda-silberling/">her consumer tech beat. </a>Follow her <a href="https://twitter.com/asilbwrites">on Twitter</a> if you don’t already!</li>
</ul>
<h2>Across the week</h2>
<h3>Seen on TechCrunch</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/teslas-quarterly-profit-surpasses-1-billion/">Tesla’s quarterly profit surpasses $1 billion</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/microsoft-bests-earnings-estimates-as-azure-posts-51-growth-shares-fall/">Microsoft bests earnings estimates as Azure posts 51% growth; shares fall</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/robinhoods-stock-drops-8-in-its-first-days-trading/">Robinhood’s stock drops 8% in its first day’s trading</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/high-profile-entrepreneurs-launch-85-million-fund-to-back-indian-saas-startups/">High-profile entrepreneurs launch $85 million fund to back Indian SaaS startups</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/the-mmhmm-story-and-how-it-plans-to-spend-its-100m/">The mmhmm story and how it plans to spend its $100M</a></li>
</ul>
<p><em>For more public market news, subscribe to </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/the-exchange/"><em>The Exchange</em></a><em> by </em><a href="https://twitter.com/alex"><em>Alex Wilhelm</em></a><em> and </em><a href="https://twitter.com/abracarioca"><em>Anna Heim.  </em></a></p>
<h3>Seen on Extra Crunch</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/edtechs-venture-backed-globalization-pauses-at-china/">Edtech’s venture-backed globalization pauses at China</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/pilot-ceo-waseem-daher-tears-down-his-companys-60m-series-c-pitch-deck/">Pilot CEO Waseem Daher tears down his company’s $60M Series C pitch deck</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/financial-firms-should-leverage-machine-learning-to-make-anomaly-detection-easier/">Financial firms should leverage machine learning to make anomaly detection easier</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/what-ive-learned-after-5-years-of-buying-common-stock-in-startups/">What I’ve learned after 5 years of buying common stock in startups</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/why-latin-american-venture-capital-is-breaking-records-this-year/">Why Latin American venture capital is breaking records this year</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Talk soon,</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">N</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/unicorns-are-ready-for-a-haircut/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184270</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The pandemic effect is slowing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/2184325/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/2184325/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 17:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184325</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter for your weekend enjoyment.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome back to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter. It’s inspired by what the weekday </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/the-exchange/"><em>Exchange column</em></a><em> digs into, but free, and made for your weekend reading. </em><em>Want it in your inbox every Saturday? Sign up </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters"><em>here</em></a><em>. </em></p>
<p>Our work this week <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/as-china-shakes-up-regulations-tech-companies-suffer/">kicked off in China</a>, dug <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/african-startups-join-global-funding-boom-as-fintech-shines/">into African startup activity</a>, dealt <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/chinas-regulatory-crackdown-is-good-news-for-startups-aligned-with-ccp-goals/">with China once again</a>, took a very deep dive <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/why-latin-american-venture-capital-is-breaking-records-this-year/">into the Latin American startup ecosystem</a> and wrapped with a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/robinhoods-cfo-says-it-was-ready-to-go-public/">second look at the Robinhood IPO</a>. In other words, not much was really going on at all!</p>
<p>You may have been surprised to see Amazon’s stock fall off a cliff Friday. After all, the company <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/amazon-misses-q2-revenue-profit-201456091.html">posted huge revenue gains</a> to just over $113 billion during the quarter. And AWS, its public cloud business, seemed to tick along nicely.</p>
<p>But investors had expected more growth and had priced the Seattle-based e-commerce player accordingly. When Amazon missed revenue expectations and <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210729006106/en/Amazon.com-Announces-Second-Quarter-Results">projected Q3 2021 growth</a> of “between 10% and 16% compared with third quarter 2020,” investors let go of its stock.</p>
<p>But as some in the financial press are noting, it’s not just Amazon that’s taking stick from investors. <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/07/30/amazon-plunge-drags-down-ebay-etsy-and-wayfair-.html">Etsy and eBay also fell this week</a>. It appears that investors are anticipating that a period of turbocharged growth in e-commerce thanks to the COVID-19 pandemic is slowing at least, and may in fact be over. That means valuations are going to get reset at a host of companies, startups included.</p>
<p>Not that every company slowing down after the pandemic’s early phases is suffering, Duolingo <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/duolingos-ipo-pricing-is-great-news-for-edtech-startups/">managed a strong opening week as a public company</a> despite <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/duolingo-s-1/">slowing growth</a>. But delta variant or not, the investing classes are changing their market framing. We’d be smart to keep that in mind.</p>
<h2>It’s the products, stupid</h2>
<p>Something that is stuck in my teeth this week is how much Robinhood has changed the game regarding consumer investing. Sure, this week was mostly <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/robinhood-targets-ipo-valuation-up-to-35b-amid-warning-that-crypto-incomes-are-slipping/">about the company’s IPO</a> and its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/robinhoods-stock-drops-8-in-its-first-days-trading/">somewhat relaxed early trading performance</a>. But, buried in its final S-1/A filings is new evidence of Robinhood’s cultural impact.</p>
<p>At the top of the U.S. consumer investing unicorn’s <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001783879/000162828021014488/robinhoods-1a2.htm">filings</a> is a pair of statistics. They look like this:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184332" style="width: 522px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184332" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2184332" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/exchange_7_31.png" alt="" width="512" height="249" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/exchange_7_31.png 512w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/exchange_7_31.png?resize=150,73 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/exchange_7_31.png?resize=300,146 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/exchange_7_31.png?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184332" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Robinhood</p></div></p>
<p>Dang, you are thinking, that’s a lot of funded accounts and monthly active users. But then again, those are March 31, 2021, numbers. They are out of date. In the same filing, Robinhood indicated that its June 30 quarter saw its funded accounts tally grow to 22.5 million. That’s 25% growth in a single quarter!</p>
<p>Naturally, there were a few things going on in the second quarter of this year that won’t happen again, but it’s still a bonkers result.</p>
<p>Early Robinhood investor <a href="https://twitter.com/janatindex">Jan Hammer of Index</a> sent over a comment in the wake of his investment’s public offering, arguing that the company is part of work being done by tech companies to shake up financial services. Companies like Robinhood, he wrote, are “not just a fresh coat of paint for the same old financial products.”</p>
<p>I think that is correct. And the point is pretty damning of incumbent players still in the market with dated websites and medium-grade mobile experiences. Can you imagine getting a Gen Zer to swap out Robinhood or eToro or M1 Finance for, I don’t know, John Hancock? The toothpaste, as they say, is not going back into the tube.</p>
<p>How might Fidelity and Vanguard convince Robinhood users to move to their services? Will they be able to, or has an entire generation of investors skipped the traditional finance players entirely? Robinhood bulls must think so, and I can’t really find it in me to fight the perspective.</p>
<p>I do not know how Robinhood will perform in the coming quarters, but it does feel &#8212; given the MAU numbers from Robinhood, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/m1-finance-raises-150m-in-softbank-led-series-e-boosts-valuation-to-1-45b/">AUM figures from M1</a> and so forth &#8212; that fintech startups stole several marches on your trusty 401(k) provider. A market that I am sure the fintechs will soon dig more deeply into.</p>
<h2>More about Africa</h2>
<p>Circling back to Africa, how about some July data? Our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/african-startups-join-global-funding-boom-as-fintech-shines/">exploration of the continent’s strong H1 2021 performance</a> stopped in June, so let’s add some data. Per Africa-watching publication The Big Deal, African startups <a href="https://twitter.com/MaxBayen/status/1421037952583483392">raised $308 million across 71 deals</a> in the quarter. That’s a run rate of around $3.7 billion. Or in simpler terms, African startups are still on pace for their best year ever when it comes to raising venture capital.</p>
<p>Hugs, and get vaccinated.</p>
<p>Your friend,</p>
<p>&#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/2184325/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184325</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 lessons from Duolingo&#8217;s bellwether edtech IPO of the year</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/5-lessons-from-duolingos-bellwether-edtech-ipo-of-the-year/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/5-lessons-from-duolingos-bellwether-edtech-ipo-of-the-year/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 16:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[duolingo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Duolingo landed onto the public markets this week, rallying excitement and attention for the edtech sector and its founder cohort. The language learning business’ stock price soared when it began to trade, even after the unicorn raised its IPO price range, and priced above the raised interval. Duolingo’s IPO proves that public market investors can [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Duolingo landed onto the public markets this week, rallying excitement and attention for the edtech sector and its founder cohort. The language learning business’ stock price soared when it began to trade, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/duolingos-ipo-pricing-is-great-news-for-edtech-startups/">even after the unicorn raised its IPO price range</a>, and priced above the raised interval.</p>
<p>Duolingo’s IPO proves that public market investors can see the long-term value in a mission-driven, technology-powered education concern; the company’s IPO carries extra weight considering the historically few edtech companies that have listed.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Duolingo’s IPO proves that public market investors can see the long-term value in a mission-driven, technology-powered education concern; the company’s IPO carries extra weight considering the historically few edtech companies that have listed.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>For those that want the entire story of Duolingo, from origin to messy monetization to historical IPO, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/duolingo-ec1/">check out our EC-1</a>. It has dozens of interviews from executives, investors, linguists and competitors.</p>
<p>For today, though, we have fresh additions. We sat down with Duolingo CEO Luis von Ahn earlier in the week to discuss not only his company’s IPO, but also what impact the listing may have on startups. Duolingo’s IPO can be looked at as a case study into consumer startups, mission-driven companies that monetize a small base of users, or education companies that recently hit scale. Paraphrasing from von Ahn, Duolingo doesn’t see itself as just an edtech company with fresh branding. Instead, it believes its growth comes from being an engineering-first startup.</p>
<p>Selling motivation, it seems, versus selling the fluency in a language is a proposition that international consumers are willing to pay for, and an idea that investors think can continue to scale to software-like margins.</p>
<h2><strong>1. The IPO event will bring “more sophistication” to Duolingo’s core service</strong></h2>
<p>Duolingo has gone through three distinct phases: Growth, in which it prioritized getting as many users as it could to its app; monetization, in which it introduced a subscription tier for survival; and now, education, in which it is focusing on tacking on more sophisticated, smarter technology to its service.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/5-lessons-from-duolingos-bellwether-edtech-ipo-of-the-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184191</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>China roundup: Keep down internet upstarts, cultivate hard tech</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/china-roundup-keep-down-internet-upstarts-cultivate-hard-tech/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/china-roundup-keep-down-internet-upstarts-cultivate-hard-tech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 16:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[industrial robot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[made in china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northern Light Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semiconductor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semiconductors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xi jinping]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2181744</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to TechCrunch’s China roundup, a digest of recent events shaping the Chinese tech landscape and what they mean to people in the rest of the world. The tech industry in China has had quite a turbulent week. The government is upending its $100 billion private education sector, wiping billions from the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/china-roundup/">TechCrunch’s China roundup</a>, a digest of recent events shaping the Chinese tech landscape and what they mean to people in the rest of the world.</p>
<p>The tech industry in China has had quite a turbulent week. The government is upending its $100 billion private education sector, wiping billions from the market cap of the industry&#8217;s most lucrative players. Meanwhile, the assault on Chinese internet giants continued. Tech stocks tumbled after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/tencents-wechat-suspends-new-user-registration-in-china-to-comply-with-relevant-laws-and-regulations/">Tencent suspended user registration</a>, sparking fears over who will be the next target of Beijing&#8217;s wrath.</p>
<p>Incisive observers point out that the new wave of stringent regulations against China&#8217;s internet and education firms has long been on Beijing&#8217;s agenda and there&#8217;s nothing surprising. Indeed, the central government has been unabashed about its desires to <a href="https://twitter.com/ruima/status/1420109129847214084">boost manufacturing</a> and contain the unchecked powers of its service industry, which can include everything from internet platforms, film studios to after-school centers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A few weeks ago I had an informative conversation with a Chinese venture capitalist who has been investing in industrial robots for over a decade, so I&#8217;m including it in this issue as it provides useful context for what&#8217;s going on in the consumer tech industry this week.</p>
<h2>Automate the factories</h2>
<p>China is putting robots into factories at an aggressive pace. Huang He, a partner at Northern Light Venture Capital, sees three forces spurring the demand for industrial robots &#8212; particularly ones that are made in China.</p>
<p>Over the years, Beijing has advocated for &#8220;localization&#8221; in a broad range of technology sectors, from enterprise software to production line automation. One may start to see Chinese robots that can rival those of Schneider and Panasonic a few years down the road. CRP, an NLVC-backed industrial robot maker, is already selling across Southeast Asia, Russia and East Europe.</p>
<p>On top of tech localization, it&#8217;s also well acknowledged that China is facing a severe demographic crisis. The labor shortage in its manufacturing sector is further compounded by the reluctance of young people to do menial factory work. Factory robots could offer a hand.</p>
<p>&#8220;Youngsters these days would rather become food delivery riders than work in a factory. The work that robots replace is the low-skilled type, and those that still can&#8217;t be taken up by robots pay well and come with great benefits,&#8221; Huang observed.</p>
<p>Large corporations in China still lean toward imported robots due to the products&#8217; proven stability. The problem is that imported robots are not only expensive but also selective about their users.</p>
<p>&#8220;Companies need to have deep technical capabilities to be able to operate these [Western] robots, but such companies are rare in China,&#8221; said Huang, adding that the overwhelming majority of Chinese enterprises are small and medium size.</p>
<p>With the exceptions of the automotive and semiconductor industries, which still largely rely on sophisticated, imported robots, affordable, easy-to-use Chinese robots can already meet most of the local demand for industrial automation, Huang said.</p>
<p>China currently uses nearly one million six-axis robots a year but only manufactures 20% of them itself. The gap, coupled with a national plan for localization, has led to a frenzy of investments in industrial robotics startups.</p>
<p>The rush isn&#8217;t necessarily a good thing, said Huang. &#8220;There&#8217;s this bizarre phenomenon in China, where the most funded and valuable industrial robotic firms are generating less than 30 million yuan in annual revenue and not really heard of by real users in the industry.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;This isn&#8217;t an industry where giants can be created by burning through cash. It&#8217;s not the internet sector.&#8221;</p>
<p>Small-and-medium-size businesses are happily welcoming robots onto factory floors. Take welding for example. An average welder costs about 150,000 yuan ($23,200) a year. A typical welding robot, which is sold for 120,000 yuan, can replace up to three workers a year and &#8220;doesn&#8217;t complain at work,&#8221; said the investor. A quality robot can work continuously for six to eight years, so the financial incentive to automate is obvious.</p>
<p>Advanced manufacturing is not just helping local bosses. It will eventually increase foreign enterprises&#8217; dependence on China for its efficiency, making it hard to cut off Chinese supply chains despite efforts to avoid the geopolitical risks of manufacturing in China.</p>
<p>&#8220;In electronics, for example, most of the supply chains are in China, so factories outside China end up spending more on logistics to move parts around. Much of the 3C manufacturing is already highly automated, which relies heavily on electricity, but in most emerging economies, the power supply is still quite unstable, which disrupts production,&#8221; said Huang.</p>
<h2>War on internet titans</h2>
<p>The shock of antitrust regulations against Alibaba from last year is still reverberating, but another wave of scrutiny has already begun. Shortly after Didi&#8217;s blockbuster IPO in New York, the ride-hailing giant was asked to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/china-roundup-data-security-clampdown/">cease user registration</a> and work on protecting user information critical to national security.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Tencent stocks <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/international-investor-concerns-mount-over-chinas-tech-rout-2021-07-27/">fell the most in a decade</a> after it halted user signups on its WeChat messenger as it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/tencents-wechat-suspends-new-user-registration-in-china-to-comply-with-relevant-laws-and-regulations/">&#8220;upgrades&#8221; its security technology to align with relevant laws and regulations</a>. The gaming and social media giant is just the latest in a growing list of companies hit by Beijing&#8217;s tightening grip on the internet sector, which had been flourishing for two decades under laissez-faire policies.</p>
<p>Underlying the clampdowns is Beijing&#8217;s growing unease with the service industry&#8217;s unscrutinized accumulation of wealth and power. China is unequivocally determined to advance its tech sector, but the types of tech that Beijing wants are not so much the video games that bring myopia to children and algorithms that get adults hooked to their screens. China makes it clear in its <a href="https://www.uscc.gov/sites/default/files/2021-04/April_2021_Trade_Bulletin.pdf">five-year plan</a>, a series of social and economic initiatives, that it will go all-in on &#8220;hard tech&#8221; like semiconductors, renewable energy, agritech, biotech and industrial automation like factory robotics.</p>
<p>China has also vowed to fight inequality in education and wealth. In the authorities&#8217; eyes, expensive, for-profit after-schools dotting big cities are hindering education attainment for children from poorer areas, which eventually exacerbates the wealth gap. The new regulatory measures have restricted the<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/as-china-shakes-up-regulations-tech-companies-suffer/"> hours, content, profits and financing of private tutoring institutions</a>, tanking stocks of the industry&#8217;s top companies. Again, there have been clear indications from<a href="https://twitter.com/henrysgao/status/1420013465805094912"> President Xi Jinping&#8217;s writings</a> to bring off-campus tutoring &#8220;back on the educational track.&#8221; All China-focused investors and analysts are now poring over Xi&#8217;s thoughts and directives.</p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/china-roundup-keep-down-internet-upstarts-cultivate-hard-tech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2181744</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This Week in Apps: Instagram restricts teens&#8217; accounts, Elon Musk criticizes App Store fees, Google Play&#8217;s new policies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/this-week-in-apps-instagram-restricts-teens-accounts-elon-musk-criticizes-app-store-fees-google-plays-new-policies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/this-week-in-apps-instagram-restricts-teens-accounts-elon-musk-criticizes-app-store-fees-google-plays-new-policies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 14:40:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app stores]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[This Week In Apps]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184022</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to This Week in Apps, the weekly TechCrunch series that recaps the latest in mobile OS news, mobile applications and the overall app economy. The app industry continues to grow, with a record 218 billion downloads and $143 billion in global consumer spend in 2020. Consumers last year also spent 3.5 trillion minutes using apps on Android devices alone. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Welcome back to This Week in Apps, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/this-week-in-apps/">the weekly TechCrunch series</a> that recaps the latest in mobile OS news, mobile applications and the overall app economy.</p>
<p>The app industry continues to grow, with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a record</a> 218 billion downloads and $143 billion in global consumer spend in 2020. Consumers last year also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/">spent</a> 3.5 trillion minutes using apps on Android devices alone. And in the U.S., app usage surged ahead of the time spent watching live TV. Currently, the average American <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/">watches</a> 3.7 hours of live TV per day, but now spends four hours per day on their mobile devices.</p>
<p>Apps aren’t just a way to pass idle hours — they’re also a big business. In 2019, mobile-first companies had a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/app-stores-saw-record-204-billion-app-downloads-in-2019-consumer-spend-of-120-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">combined</a> $544 billion valuation, 6.5x higher than those without a mobile focus. In 2020, investors <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/">poured</a> $73 billion in capital into mobile companies — a figure that’s up 27% year over year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<blockquote><p><em><strong>This Week in Apps will finally be a newsletter! It will launch on August 7. <a href="http://techcrunch.com/newsletters">Sign up now! </a></strong></em></p></blockquote>
<h1>Top Stories</h1>
<h3>Google Play updates its policies</h3>
<p><strong>Did you hear the one about Google Play banning sugar daddy dating apps?</strong> Google this week updated its <a href="https://support.google.com/googleplay/android-developer/answer/9878810">terms to clarify that apps</a> where users offer sex acts in exchange for money, or &#8220;sugar dating,&#8221;<a href="https://support.google.com/googleplay/android-developer/answer/9934569?hl=en-GB"> as the new terms state,</a> are no longer allowed as of September 1, 2021.</p>
<p><strong>More interesting, perhaps, to the larger group of legitimate Android developers is this week&#8217;s unveiling of </strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/google-unveils-its-proposed-safety-section-for-apps-on-google-play"><strong>the UI for the upcoming Google Play safety section</strong></a> and the accompanying app labels. The labels will function as the Android counterpart to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/apple-launches-its-new-app-privacy-labels-across-all-its-app-stores/">app &#8220;nutrition labels&#8221;</a> the Apple App Store recently introduced. Google is giving developers plenty of time to get used to the idea of increased transparency and disclosure, by offering a detailed timeline of when it expects developers to have their privacy label submissions ready. By April 2022, all developers will need to declare specific info and have a privacy policy.</p>
<p>Developers will have to disclose to users whether their app uses security practices like data encryption, whether it follows Google Play’s Families policy for apps aimed at kids, whether users have a choice in data sharing, whether the app’s safety section had been verified by a third party, and if the app allowed users to request data deletion at the time of uninstalling, among other things.</p>
<p>Apps that don&#8217;t disclose won&#8217;t be able to list or update until the problems are fixed.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="STPJLAJRrp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/google-unveils-its-proposed-safety-section-for-apps-on-google-play/">Google unveils its proposed &#8216;safety section&#8217; for apps on Google Play</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google unveils its proposed &#8216;safety section&#8217; for apps on Google Play&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/google-unveils-its-proposed-safety-section-for-apps-on-google-play/embed/#?secret=STPJLAJRrp" data-secret="STPJLAJRrp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The safety section wasn&#8217;t the only Google Play policy news to be announced this week.</p>
<p><strong>Google also <a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2021/07/announcing-policy-updates-to-bolster.html">reminded developers</a> that it was making a technical change to how advertising IDs work.</strong> Now, when users opt out of interest-based advertising or ads personalization, their <a href="https://support.google.com/googleplay/android-developer/answer/6048248?hl=en&amp;ref_topic=2364761">advertising ID</a> is removed and replaced with a string of zeros. The change, however, is a phased rollout, affecting apps running on Android 12 devices starting late 2021 and expanding to all apps running on devices that support Google Play in early 2022.</p>
<p>Google also said it will test a new feature that notifies developers and ad/analytics service providers of user opt-out preferences and is prohibiting linking <a href="https://developer.android.com/training/articles/user-data-ids">persistent device identifiers</a> to personal and sensitive user data or resettable device identifiers. Kids apps will also not be able to transmit an ad ID.</p>
<p><strong>Another <a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2021/07/announcing-policy-updates-to-bolster.html">policy update includes</a> a plan to close dormant accounts</strong>. Google says if the account is inactive or abandoned after a year, it will be closed. This will include accounts where the developer has never uploaded an app or accessed Google Play Console in a year.</p>
<p>Tools to build accessible experiences will also be locked down, as Google is adding new requirements on how <a href="https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/ui/accessibility/service">AccessibilityService API</a> and <a href="https://developer.android.com/reference/kotlin/android/accessibilityservice/AccessibilityServiceInfo#isaccessibilitytool">IsAccessibilityTool</a> can be used.</p>
<h3>Apple tries to fix the Safari mess</h3>
<p>In response to feedback and complaints, Apple is clearly trying to fix some of the issues that arose from this change. It re-added a Share button to the tab bar and put additional controls under that menu. There’s also once again a reload button in the tab bar next to the domain name, though it’s a bit smaller, and a Reader Mode button will appear in the tab bar when Reader is available</p>
<p>On iPad, Safari also <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/07/27/ipados-15-macos-monterey-safari-interface/">reverted</a> back to the traditional separate row of tabs, instead of the new compact experience.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">The Refresh button is now permanently showing in the iOS 15 Safari address bar <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/iOS15DevBeta4?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#iOS15DevBeta4</a> <a href="https://t.co/v8AoRB68QI">pic.twitter.com/v8AoRB68QI</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Apple Software Updates (@AppleSWUpdates) <a href="https://twitter.com/AppleSWUpdates/status/1420078446726819842?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 27, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<h3>Elon Musk sides with Epic Games</h3>
<p>Elon Musk sided with Fortnite maker Epic Games in the Apple App Store antitrust lawsuit, as the Tesla CEO tweeted on Friday that Apple&#8217;s App Store fees were &#8220;a de facto global tax on the Internet.&#8221; The lawsuit alleges Apple is abusing its platform power with how it commissions apps and in-app purchases on its App Store platform &#8212; fees that add up to big numbers for a game like Fortnite, which arguably doesn&#8217;t need an App Store for discovery, marketing, payments and distribution. But there&#8217;s no other way to sell to iOS users today. On Android, apps can at least be sideloaded. It&#8217;s not currently clear why Musk has decided to take a stand on the issue, as none of his companies&#8217; apps are dramatically impacted by Apple&#8217;s fees at present.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="p1LmLgCrCx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/elon-musk-calls-app-store-fees-a-de-facto-global-tax-on-the-internet/">Elon Musk calls Apple&#8217;s App Store fees &#8216;a de facto global tax on the Internet&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Elon Musk calls Apple&#8217;s App Store fees &#8216;a de facto global tax on the Internet&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/elon-musk-calls-app-store-fees-a-de-facto-global-tax-on-the-internet/embed/#?secret=p1LmLgCrCx" data-secret="p1LmLgCrCx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h1>Weekly News</h1>
<h3>Other Platform News (Apple &amp; Google)</h3>
<p><strong>Apple <a href="https://developer.apple.com/support/deprecated-sirikit-intent-domains">announced</a> plans to <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/07/28/ios-15-limiting-siri-for-third-party-apps/">end support for a number</a> of SiriKit intents and commands</strong>, including those that could impact major apps &#8212; like ride-sharing app Uber. In total, there are over 20 SiriKit intent domains that will be deprecated and no longer supported in new and existing OS releases, Apple says.</p>
<p><strong>Apple <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/apple-tweaks-controversial-ios-15-safari-changes-in-latest-beta/">tweaked</a> the controversial iOS 15 Safari changes in the <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/07/27/apple-releases-ios-15-beta-4-and-ipados-15-beta-4-to-developers">latest betas</a></strong> (iOS 15 and iPadOS 15, beta 4). The new Safari design had moved the tab bar (URL bar) to the bottom of the screen — a fairly radical change for one of the iPhone’s most used apps. It was meant to make the controls easier to reach but critics said that the change made other often used features — like the reload button or Reader Mode — harder to find and use, impacting the overall usability of the browser itself.</p>
<p><strong>Google this week <a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2021/07/jetpack-compose-announcement.html">launched</a> version 1.0 of Jetpack Compose</strong>, Android&#8217;s new, native UI toolkit aimed at helping developers build better apps faster. The tool had been in beta since March. The new production release is built to integrate with the Jetpack libraries developers already use, and offers an implementation of Material Design components and theming. New <a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2021/07/jetpack-compose-announcement.html">features include</a> Compose Preview and Deploy Preview, which require Android Studio Arctic Fox, which is also out now in a stable release.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kLA1QwDjioc?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Google also <a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2021/07/accessing-car-hardware-apis-in-your-app.html">announced</a> the availability of the CarHardwareManager API</strong> via the Android for Cars App Library as part of Jetpack.</p>
<h3>E-commerce</h3>
<p><strong>Twitter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/twitter-launches-u-s-e-commerce-pilot-that-lets-users-shop-from-profiles/">launched a U.S. e-commerce pilot test</a> that will help determine the current appetite for online shopping on its platform.</strong> The test allows brands and businesses to feature a &#8220;Shop Module&#8221; with various products for sale at the top of their Professional Profile, a business-friendly version of a profile page with support for things like an address, hours, phone number and more. Users can click on the Shop Module to go to a retail website and transact. Early testers include Game Stop and Arden Cove. The feature itself is somewhat bare bones for now, as it&#8217;s really just an image that launches an in-app browser. That&#8217;s not enough to really compete with something like Instagram Shop or Shopify&#8217;s Shop and the integrated, native checkout experience those types of app offers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ql72pfY3Do"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/twitter-launches-u-s-e-commerce-pilot-that-lets-users-shop-from-profiles/">Twitter launches US e-commerce pilot that lets users shop from profiles</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter launches US e-commerce pilot that lets users shop from profiles&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/twitter-launches-u-s-e-commerce-pilot-that-lets-users-shop-from-profiles/embed/#?secret=ql72pfY3Do" data-secret="ql72pfY3Do" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Fintech</h3>
<p><strong>Fintech giant Robinhood <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/robinhood-gateway-meme-stocks-raises-21-billion-ipo-source-2021-07-28/">raised $2.1 billion</a> in its IPO this week</strong>. The IPO valued the trading app at $31.8 billion, making it larger that traditional rivals like Charles Schwab, even though the offering priced at the bottom of its range. The stock <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/robinhoods-stock-drops-8-in-its-first-days-trading/">dropped 8%</a> during its first day&#8217;s trading, however. Robinhood now has 21.3 million MAUs.</p>
<p><strong>PayPal during its second-quarter earnings call <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/paypals-new-super-app-is-ready-to-launch-will-also-include-messaging">announced</a> its new &#8220;super app&#8221; is now code-complete and ready to roll out.</strong> The app will feature early direct deposit, check cashing, high yield savings, budgeting tools, improved bill pay, crypto support, subscription management, buy now, pay later functionality, mobile commerce, and person-to-person messaging features. The latter hadn&#8217;t yet been announced and would allow users to chat outside of the payments process.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5wHHnZREbW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/paypals-new-super-app-is-ready-to-launch-will-also-include-messaging/">PayPal&#8217;s new &#8216;super app,&#8217; to include messaging, is ready to launch</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;PayPal&#8217;s new &#8216;super app,&#8217; to include messaging, is ready to launch&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/paypals-new-super-app-is-ready-to-launch-will-also-include-messaging/embed/#?secret=5wHHnZREbW" data-secret="5wHHnZREbW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Code found in Apple&#8217;s Wallet app indicates that iOS 15 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/spotifys-clubhouse-rival-greenroom-tops-140k-installs-on-ios-100k-on-android/">will require users</a> to verify their identities by taking a selfie</strong> when they add their driver&#8217;s license or other state identification card to the iPhone.</p>
<h3>Social</h3>
<p><strong>Instagram <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/instagram-to-default-young-teens-to-private-accounts-restrict-ads-and-unwanted-adult-contact/">announced</a> a series of significant changes to how it handles the accounts of younger teens</strong>. The company says it will now default users to private accounts at sign-up if they’re under the age of 16  — or under 18 in certain locales, including in the EU. It will also push existing users under 16 to switch their account to private if they have not already done so. In addition, Instagram is rolling out new technology aimed at reducing unwanted contact from adults — like those who have already been blocked or reported by other teens — and it will change how advertisers can reach its teenage audience. The changes give the company a way to argue to regulators that it&#8217;s capable of self-policing as it attempts to roll out a version of Instagram to younger users under the age of 13.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WutK5KWdxp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/instagram-to-default-young-teens-to-private-accounts-restrict-ads-and-unwanted-adult-contact/">Instagram to default young teens to private accounts, restrict ads and unwanted adult contact</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Instagram to default young teens to private accounts, restrict ads and unwanted adult contact&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/instagram-to-default-young-teens-to-private-accounts-restrict-ads-and-unwanted-adult-contact/embed/#?secret=WutK5KWdxp" data-secret="WutK5KWdxp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Twitter <a href="https://www.engadget.com/twitter-spaces-share-discover-195041240.html">rolls out an update</a> to its live audio platform, Twitter Spaces, that will make it easier to share the audio room with others</strong><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">. Users will be able to compose a tweet right from the Space that links to the room and includes any accompanying hashtags. iOS users also received new guest management controls for hosts.</span></p>
<p><strong>Snapchat <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22600902/snapchat-crashing-down-outage-issue-app-login">resolved an outage</a> that was stopping people from logging in on Thursday</strong>. Unlike other app blips, which fix themselves often without users&#8217; awareness, Snap told users to manually update their app if the issues continued.</p>
<p><strong>Snapchat also this week <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/snapchat-adds-my-places-feature-to-snap-map-connecting-users-to-businesses">added a &#8220;My Places&#8221; feature</a> to Snap Map, which allows users to log their favorite spots, share them with friends and find recommendations</strong>. The feature supports over 30 million businesses and allows Snap to differentiate its map from a utility like Google Maps or Apple Maps, because it&#8217;s about personal recommendations from people you know and trust: your friends.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BiIXTu7xIY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/snapchat-adds-my-places-feature-to-snap-map-connecting-users-to-businesses/">Snapchat adds My Places feature to Snap Map, recommending spots to visit</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Snapchat adds My Places feature to Snap Map, recommending spots to visit&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/snapchat-adds-my-places-feature-to-snap-map-connecting-users-to-businesses/embed/#?secret=BiIXTu7xIY" data-secret="BiIXTu7xIY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Instagram <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/instagram-now-supports-60-second-videos-on-reels-its-tiktok-clone/">added support</a> for 60-second videos to its TikTok clone, Reels.</strong> Previously, only Reels of up to 30 seconds were supported. Sixty seconds is in line with other platforms like YouTube Shorts and Snapchat&#8217;s Spotlight. But TikTok is now inching into YouTube territory, as it recently expanded to support three-minute videos.</p>
<p><strong>TikTok<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/tiktok-expands-live-platform-with-new-features-for-creators-and-fans/"> expanded its LIVE platform</a> with a huge lineup of new features</strong> including the ability to go live with others, host Q&amp;As, use moderators and improved keyword filters, and more. For viewers, TikTok is adding new discovery and viewing tools, including picture-in-picture mode and ways to jump to LIVE streams from the For You and Following feeds. Some markets, including the U.S. already had access to LIVE Events, but the feature is now expanding. Meanwhile, the co-host feature currently supports going live with one other creator, but TikTok says it&#8217;s now testing multiple hosts.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OX36h1X361"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/tiktok-expands-live-platform-with-new-features-for-creators-and-fans/">TikTok expands LIVE platform with new features, including events, co-hosts, Q&#038;As and more</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok expands LIVE platform with new features, including events, co-hosts, Q&#038;As and more&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/tiktok-expands-live-platform-with-new-features-for-creators-and-fans/embed/#?secret=OX36h1X361" data-secret="OX36h1X361" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Discord <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/discord-threads/">launched a new feature</a>, Threads, which will make it easier to read through longer conversations on busy servers.</strong> Now, any server with &#8220;Community&#8221; features enabled will be able to transform their messages into threaded conversations across mobile and desktop. The threads will be designated by their own subject name and can be created by selecting a new hashtag symbol that appears in the menu when hovering over messages or by pressing the + sign in the chat bar.</p>
<p><strong>Pinterest shares <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/pinterest-shares-drop-as-company-misses-on-user-growth-again">dropped</a> by more than 12% after the company reported its second-quarter earnings on Thursday</strong>. Despite beating on estimates with revenue of $613.2 million and earnings per share of 25 cents, investors were disappointed by the miss on user growth. The company reported monthly active user growth of just 9% to reach 454 million, when analysts were expecting 482 million. Pinterest blamed COVID impacts for the slowdown. The news follows <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/pinterest-rolls-out-new-features-that-let-creators-make-money-from-pins">Pinterest&#8217;s launch of new tools for creators to monetize their content,</a> with Ideas Pins &#8212; the recently launched video-first format that lets creators show off their work. Now, creators can make their pins &#8220;shoppable&#8221; and take commissions on those purchases.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CXGGtwCxPB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/pinterest-shares-drop-as-company-misses-on-user-growth-again/">Pinterest shares drop as company misses on user growth … again</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pinterest shares drop as company misses on user growth … again&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/pinterest-shares-drop-as-company-misses-on-user-growth-again/embed/#?secret=CXGGtwCxPB" data-secret="CXGGtwCxPB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Messaging</h3>
<p><strong>WhatsApp is <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/07/26/whatsapp-ios-testing-higher-image-upload-quality">testing support</a> for higher image upload quality on iOS devices.</strong> The feature was discovered on WhatsApp&#8217;s TestFlight version for iOS but is not yet public and offers three options: auto, best quality or data saver.</p>
<h3>Streaming &amp; Entertainment</h3>
<p><strong>Spotify&#8217;s Clubhouse clone, Greenroom, is off to a slow start.</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/spotifys-clubhouse-rival-greenroom-tops-140k-installs-on-ios-100k-on-android/">The app has only been downloaded</a> 140,000+ times on iOS and 100,000+ on Android, including installs from its earlier life as Locker Room, an app that Spotify acquired to move into live audio. Meanwhile, Spotify has 365 million monthly active users on its flagship streaming app.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ig7ROpW0bp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/spotifys-clubhouse-rival-greenroom-tops-140k-installs-on-ios-100k-on-android/">Spotify&#8217;s clone of Clubhouse tops 140K installs on iOS, 100K on Android</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Spotify&#8217;s clone of Clubhouse tops 140K installs on iOS, 100K on Android&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/spotifys-clubhouse-rival-greenroom-tops-140k-installs-on-ios-100k-on-android/embed/#?secret=ig7ROpW0bp" data-secret="ig7ROpW0bp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Spotify also reported its<a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/07/27/google-developing-switch-to-android-app-for-ios-to-copy-data-and-apps-from-your-iphone/"> Q2 earnings this week</a>, where it posted a $23.6 million loss and failed to reach its forecast for total MAUs, despite growing MAUs 22% YOY to 365 million</strong>. It now has 165 million paying subscribers, which is up 20% YOY.</p>
<p><strong>In a change to its app, Spotify <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/spotify-adds-an-attention-grabbing-whats-new-feed-to-addict-users-to-its-app/">added</a> an attention-grabbing &#8220;What&#8217;s New&#8221; feed that offers personalized updates about new releases and new podcast episodes</strong>. The feature is available through a notification bell icon and uses a blue dot to indicate when there&#8217;s something new to see. Dots like this are a psychological hacks popularized by social apps like Facebook and Instagram to addict users, which could impact user engagement time on Spotify&#8217;s app.</p>
<p><strong>Apple&#8217;s GarageBand app for iOS and iPadOS <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/07/garageband-features-new-sound-packs-from-dua-lipa-lady-gaga-and-top-producers/">now lets you remix tracks</a> from top artists and producers like</strong> Dua Lipa and Lady Gaga. There are also new Producer Packs with beats, loops and instruments created for GarageBand by top producers, including Boys Noize, Mark Lettieri, Oak Felder, Soulection, Take A Daytrip, Tom Misch and TRAKGIRL.</p>
<p><strong>Google TV&#8217;s mobile app was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/google-tv-mobile-app-redesign-adds-new-services-and-recommendations">updated</a> with new services and personalized recommendations, following last fall&#8217;s launch of the Google TV user experience for Chromecast devices</strong>. The app now sports 16:9 widescreen movie and show posters, and added new providers Discovery+, Viki, Cartoon Network, PBS Kids, Boomerang, plus on-demand content from live TV services, including YouTube TV, Philo and fuboTV.</p>
<h3>Gaming</h3>
<p><strong>Epic Games <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/fortnite-ariana-grande-rift-tour">announced</a> that Fortnite will host another in-game event it&#8217;s calling the &#8220;Rift Tour,&#8221;</strong> which kicks off Friday, August 6 and runs through Sunday, August 8. What it hasn&#8217;t yet said is what the Rift Tour is, beyond a &#8220;musical journey into magical new realities&#8221; that will feature a &#8220;record-breaking superstar.&#8221;</p>
<h3>Health &amp; Fitness</h3>
<p><strong>Facebook&#8217;s Oculus division is<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/technology?sref=gni836kR"> exploring an integration</a> of Oculus Workouts with Apple&#8217;s Health app</strong>, according to the app&#8217;s code. An integration would allow users to store their workout data in Health.</p>
<h3>Productivity</h3>
<p><strong>Usage of mobile video conferencing apps like Zoom grew by 150% in the first half of 2021</strong>, according to <a href="https://sensortower.com/blog/video-conferencing-apps-mau-growth">a report from Sensor Tower.</a> Zoom, Microsoft Teams and Google Meet saw a surge in usage, collectively climbing to nearly 21x higher than in H1 2019, the firm found.</p>
<p><strong>Google Voice&#8217;s app was <a href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2021/07/enhancements-to-google-voice.html">updated with a few refinements</a>, including a way to see the reason for a missed call or dropped call, and an easy way to redial</strong>. iOS users can now show their Google Voice number as their caller ID when they get a calling through a forwarding number. Another change will allow users to delete multiple SMS messages at once.</p>
<h3>Edtech</h3>
<p><strong>Language learning app Duolingo<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-07-28/language-app-duolingo-s-ipo-exceeds-goal-to-raise-521-million?sref=gni836kR"> raised $521 million</a> in its U.S. IPO,</strong> priced above the marketed range. The company priced 5.1 million shared at $102, after first marketing them at $95 to $100.</p>
<h3>Utilities</h3>
<p><strong>Amazon this week rolled out an update to its Alexa iOS app that allows users to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22600568/amazon-alexa-widget-ios-assign-reminders">add an Alexa widget to their iOS homescreen</a>.</strong> The widget lets you tap on a button to speak to the virtual assistant and issue commands. Watch out Siri! (Ha, just kidding.)</p>
<p><strong>Google Maps also updated its iOS app this week to <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/07/28/google-maps-widget-support/">add support for a homescreen widget</a>.</strong> There are two different widgets sizes to choose from &#8212; one that gives info like weather and traffic, while another is more of a shortcut to nearby places like gas stations, restaurants, work and home.</p>
<p><strong>Google is working on a&#8221;Switch to Android&#8221; app for iOS users</strong> that will copy over data and apps from an iPhone to bring them to a new Android device. Apple already offers a similar app, called &#8220;Move to iOS&#8221; for Android users.</p>
<h3>Transportation</h3>
<p><strong>Parking app usage has popped to pre-pandemic levels</strong>, <a href="https://blog.apptopia.com/parking-app-usage-is-above-pre-pandemic-levels">Apptopia reported</a>. Apps in this space help users find availability in lots and garages nearby and facilitate payments. Browsing time in apps was up 57% YOY in July, and overall parking app usage is now 6.2% above Jan. 2020 pre-pandemic levels.</p>
<p><strong>Moovit <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/moovit-integrates-lime-electric-scooters-bikes-mopeds-into-transit-planning-app">integrated</a> Lime&#8217;s electric scooters, bikes and mopeds into its transit-planning app</strong> that&#8217;s live in 117 cities across 20 countries and continents, including the United States, South America, Australia and Europe.</p>
<h3>Government &amp; Policy</h3>
<p><strong>Tencent&#8217;s WeChat <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/tencents-wechat-suspends-new-user-registration-in-china-to-comply-with-relevant-laws-and-regulations/">suspended</a> new user registrations in China to comply with &#8220;relevant laws and regulations</strong>.&#8221; The move comes amid a broad crackdown on tech companies by Chinese regulators, related to data collection and other harmful practices.</p>
<p><strong>Recently, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-07-28/china-targets-mobile-pop-ups-in-latest-tech-crackdown?sref=gni836kR">China ordered Tencent and 13 other developers</a> to fix problems related to pop-ups inside their apps, as part of the tech crackdown.</strong> The regulator also said it would tighten controls on misleading and explicit content used for marketing, and issued fines for offensive content to Tencent, Kuaishou and Alibaba.</p>
<h3>Security &amp; Privacy</h3>
<p><strong>Apple <a href="https://therecord.media/apple-releases-fix-for-ios-and-macos-zero-day-13th-this-year/">released patches</a> for iOS, iPadOS and macOS to address a zero-day vulnerability that had been exploited in the wild</strong>. Apple said the exploit could exploit the vulnerability known as CVE-2021-30807 to execute arbitrary code with kernel privileges on a vulnerable and unpatched device.</p>
<p>Google Play Protect failed an Android security test, according to a report from <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/google-play-protect-fails-android-security-tests-once-more/">Bleeping Computer</a>. The mobile threat protection solution ranked last out of 15 Android security apps tested over a span of six months, between January to June 2021.</p>
<h1>Funding and M&amp;A</h1>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Product insights and analytics startup Pendo <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-07-27/tiger-backed-startup-pendo-raises-funds-at-2-6-billion-value?sref=gni836kR">raised $150 million</a> at a $2.6 billion valuation</strong>, ahead of its expected IPO. The round was led by B Capital, the firm from Facebook co-founder Eduardo Saverin, and included new investor Silver Lake Waterman, alongside existing backers. Pendo&#8217;s platform helps companies gather data on how customers use their apps, including clients like Okta, Toast and others.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f91d.png" alt="🤝" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Twitter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/twitter-acqui-hires-the-team-from-subscription-news-app-brief/">&#8220;acqui-hired&#8221;</a> the team from subscription news app, Brief,</strong> who will now join Twitter&#8217;s Experience.org group, which works on Twitter Spaces and Explore. Brief had offered a non-biased news app that allowed you to get both sides of a story and all the necessary facts. Deal terms weren&#8217;t disclosed.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Delivery app Gopuff <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/gopuff-confirms-new-1b-cash-injection-at-a-15b-valuation-to-expand-its-instant-grocery-delivery-service/">confirmed its $1 billion fundraise</a> at a $15 billion valuation</strong>, aimed at expanding its instant delivery service. TechCrunch previously <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/filing-instant-grocery-startup-gopuff-is-raising-750m-more-at-a-13-5b-valuation/">reported</a> the news when the Series H was still being closed.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Indian travel app Ixigo <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/tech/startups/ixigo-raises-53-million-led-by-singapore-sovereign-wealth-fund-gic/articleshow/84800761.cms">raised $53 million</a> (Rs 395 crore)</strong>, prepping the business for a valuation of $750 million-$800 million for its upcoming IPO. The round was led by Singapore sovereign wealth fund GIC.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> </strong><strong>Mobile-first digital wallet Valora native to the Celo network <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/a16z-leads-20m-bet-that-celos-valora-becomes-a-global-gateway-to-crypto">raised $20 million</a></strong> in Series A funding led by Andreessen Horowitz (a16z), a Celo backer, to become a global gateway to crypto.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Crypto wallet company Eco, backed by a16z, </strong><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-07-27/a16z-backed-crypto-firm-eco-raises-60-million-in-funding-round?sref=gni836kR"><strong>raised $60 million</strong></a> in new funding led by Activant Capital and L Catterton. Eco offers a digital wallet with rewards and no fees, and has average deposits of around $6,000.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Search API startup Algolia, which lets developers integrate real-time search in apps or websites, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/search-api-startup-algolia-raises-150-million-at-2-25-billion-valuation">raised $150 million</a></strong> in Series D funding, valuing the business at $2.25 billion, post-money. The round was led by Lone Pine Capital. Algolia now has over 10,000 customers, including Slack, Stripe, Medium, Zendesk and Lacoste.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Brain Technologies <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/brain-technologies-raises-50m-for-the-launch-of-natural-a-natural-language-search-engine-and-super-app/">raised $50+ million</a> for Natural, a natural language search engine and super app for iOS</strong>, which wants users to stop switching between apps to order food, groceries or go shopping. Backers include Laurene Powell Jobs’ Emerson Collective, Goodwater Capital, Scott Cook and WTT Investment.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Messaging app Element, built on the decentralized Matrix protocol, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/element-a-messaging-app-built-on-the-decentralized-matrix-protocol-raises-30m/">r</a></strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/element-a-messaging-app-built-on-the-decentralized-matrix-protocol-raises-30m/"><strong>aised $30 million</strong></a> in a Series B round of funding. Investors include open-source R&amp;D lab Protocol Labs and Metaplanet. a fund from Skype co-founder Jaan Tallinn, as well as past investors Automattic and Notion.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Indonesia-based grocery app HappyFresh </strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/indonesia-based-grocery-app-happyfresh-reaps-65m-led-by-naver-financial-and-gafina/"><strong>raised $65 million</strong></a> in Series D funding in a round led by Naver Financial Corporation and Gafina B.V. The app offers an Instacart-like grocery delivery service for parts of Asia, which today operates in Indonesia, Malaysia and Thailand.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Indian D2C beauty brand MyGlamm, which sells products through an app and website, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/amazon-backed-indian-d2c-beauty-brand-myglamm-raises-71-million/">raised $71.3 million</a></strong> in Series C financing, from Amazon, Ascent Capital and Wipro.</p>
<h1>Downloads</h1>
<h3>Nanogram</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2184300" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184300" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2184300" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Nanogram.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="279" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Nanogram.png 1156w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Nanogram.png?resize=150,62 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Nanogram.png?resize=300,123 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Nanogram.png?resize=768,315 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Nanogram.png?resize=680,279 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Nanogram.png?resize=50,21 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184300" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nanogram</p></div></p>
<p>Developer Kosta Eleftheriou may have taken on Apple in legal battles and on Twitter, as he points out the numerous app scams on the App Store, but that hasn&#8217;t stopped him from building new apps.</p>
<p>This week, Eleftheriou introduced <a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/id1574130405">Nanogram</a>, a Telegram client app that works on the Apple Watch without needing an iPhone connection. Eleftheriou said he was inspired to build Nanogram because he wanted a Telegram app for his LTE Apple Watch and didn&#8217;t like the official version that didn&#8217;t provide &#8220;basic and reliable messaging functionality.&#8221; So he built his own app from scratch using the Telegram SDK, which allows you to send, receive and view all your messages and notifications right from your wrist &#8212; even if you don&#8217;t have your phone nearby. The app also supports Eleftheriou&#8217;s FlickType Swipe Keyboard for faster replies while on the go.</p>
<p>Eleftheriou notes the app doesn&#8217;t collect any personal information and requires an Apple Watch Series 3 or later, running watchOS 7 or later.</p>
<h3>Lightricks&#8217; Videoleap for Android</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2184307" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184307" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2184307" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-30-at-4.52.59-PM.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="344" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-30-at-4.52.59-PM.png 2208w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-30-at-4.52.59-PM.png?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-30-at-4.52.59-PM.png?resize=300,152 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-30-at-4.52.59-PM.png?resize=768,389 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-30-at-4.52.59-PM.png?resize=680,344 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-30-at-4.52.59-PM.png?resize=1536,778 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-30-at-4.52.59-PM.png?resize=2048,1037 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-30-at-4.52.59-PM.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184307" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Lightricks</p></div></p>
<p>After seeing a 70% yearly increase for its iOS version, Lightricks brought its <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.lightricks.videoleap">Videoleap app to the Google Play Store</a>. The app has grown popular with online creators for offering professional quality editing tools on mobile, including those that let you apply artistic effects, mix videos with images, add text and layer transformations and more. The company says Videoleap users are now creating 35 million pieces of content per month, and 47% of users are exporting their creations to TikTok in pursuit of monetizing their content further. The app, like others from Lightricks (which also makes FaceTune and others), monetizes by way of in-app subscriptions.</p>
<h1>Tweets</h1>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Apple app store fees are a de facto global tax on the Internet. Epic is right.</p>
<p>&mdash; Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1421152540394143746?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 30, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">There’s a total of *six* different touch targets in the iOS 15 beta 4 tab bar in Safari.</p>
<p>These exclude the ability to long-press the tab bar, swipe across it to change tabs, and swipe it up to open the Tabs view.</p>
<p>I’m…starting to think a single, small toolbar just won’t do. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f62c.png" alt="😬" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/EiD2mekVRL">pic.twitter.com/EiD2mekVRL</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Federico Viticci (@viticci) <a href="https://twitter.com/viticci/status/1420084637926363136?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 27, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Shortcuts has a new “Return to Home Screen” action in iOS 15 developer beta 4 – this has been long requested from the community and is great to see! <a href="https://t.co/8E3ZB7FIYX">pic.twitter.com/8E3ZB7FIYX</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Matthew Cassinelli (@mattcassinelli) <a href="https://twitter.com/mattcassinelli/status/1420078679854444547?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 27, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">I&#39;ve been fascinated to watch the reaction to Safari in iOS 15 because in 2016-2017, I worked on a similar redesign for mobile Chrome that we never launched. Finally decided to tell a bit of that story here: <a href="https://t.co/gF4hepQM5V">https://t.co/gF4hepQM5V</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Chris Lee (@cleerview) <a href="https://twitter.com/cleerview/status/1419336516040544264?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 25, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">something fun &amp; playful our team has been working on. what are *creative* ways we can utilize voice for more engaging convos on Spaces? how would you use these tools?</p>
<p>let’s have fun &amp; learn together<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f9cf-1f3fd-200d-2642-fe0f.png" alt="🧏🏽‍♂️" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://twitter.com/RichardPlom?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@RichardPlom</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/reedm?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@reedm</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/audgeyaudgey?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@audgeyaudgey</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/callmeparri?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@callmeparri</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/niw?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@niw</a> <a href="https://t.co/4ZBahxwkDN">pic.twitter.com/4ZBahxwkDN</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Danny Singh (@Mr_DannySingh) <a href="https://twitter.com/Mr_DannySingh/status/1418293516057329671?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 22, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/this-week-in-apps/"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1952542" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="93" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png 2047w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=150,21 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=300,41 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=768,105 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=680,93 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=1536,210 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=50,7 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/this-week-in-apps-instagram-restricts-teens-accounts-elon-musk-criticizes-app-store-fees-google-plays-new-policies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184022</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bring your own environment: The future of work</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/bring-your-own-environment-the-future-of-work/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/bring-your-own-environment-the-future-of-work/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 14:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accenture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consulting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Future of Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firewall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile device management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote working]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telecommunications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telecommuting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[working remotely]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184085</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A few years from now, the organizations that succeed will be the ones that resisted the urge to race everyone back to the office and instead rethought how their workforce operates.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Michael Biltz</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/mjbiltz">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Michael Biltz is managing director of <a href="https://www.accenture.com/us-en/insights/technology/technology-trends-2021">Accenture Technology Vision</a>, where he leads the enterprise's annual visioning process to focus on how technology will impact the way we work and live.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The world has just witnessed one of the fastest work transformations in history. COVID-19 saw businesses send people home en masse, leaning on technology to maintain business as usual. Working from home, once the exception rather than the rule, became responsible for <a href="https://siepr.stanford.edu/research/publications/how-working-home-works-out">two-thirds of economic activity</a> as an estimated <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/year-of-living-remotely-when-365-days-went-poof-into-the-cloud-11615575108">1.1 billion people</a> around the world were forced to perform their daily jobs remotely, up from 350 million in 2019.</p>
<p>As we explain in the <a href="https://www.accenture.com/us-en/insights/technology/technology-trends-2021?c=acn_us_technologyvisiogoogle_11975684&amp;n=psgs_0221&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwrsGCBhD1ARIsALILBYpxKZSC0pq2yWwtULPGZRbBi1Kky9cTy32DJQ8FY5mP_EJso51QRR4aAgXHEALw_wcB&amp;gclsrc=aw.ds">2021 Accenture Technology Vision</a> report, this transformation is just the beginning. Looking ahead, where and how people work will be much more flexible concepts with the potential to bring benefits to employees and employers alike. In fact, 87% of executives Accenture surveyed believe that the remote workforce opens up the market for difficult-to-find talent.</p>
<p>These benefits will only be fully realized if enterprises adopt a strategic approach to the future of work. Think back to a few years ago, when the bring your own device (BYOD) trend was in vogue. Faced with demand from workers to use their own devices in the enterprise setting, businesses had to think through new policies and controls to support this model.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Employers must now do the same thing, but on a much bigger scale. BYOD has become “BYOE”: Employees are bringing their entire <em>environments</em> to work. These environments include a broader range of worker-owned tech (smart speakers, home networks, gaming consoles, security cameras and more) and their work setting. One person may have a home office set up in a shed in their garden, another may be working from the kitchen table, surrounded by their family.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Businesses need to accept that their employees’ environments are a permanent part of their enterprise and adjust them accordingly.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<h2>The workplace reimagined</h2>
<p>Looking ahead, the BYOE-style of work won’t be limited to employees’ homes. People will be free to work from anywhere, and they will want to work in the environment that’s best for them — whether that’s the office, home or a hybrid mix of the two. This is something leaders must accommodate rather than fight.</p>
<p>Indeed, leaders can rethink the purpose of working at the warehouses, depots, factories, offices, labs and other locations that make up their businesses. They should consider carefully when it makes sense for people to be at certain sites and with certain people. They will thereby be able to optimize their operations.</p>
<p>A few years from now, the organizations that succeed will be the ones that resisted the urge to race everyone back to the office and instead rethought how their workforce operates. They will have put in place a robust strategy for change that includes the adoption of technology enablers like the cloud, AI, IoT and XR. But more importantly, this will outline how their reimagined workforce model can support and enable their people and how this can be reflected in the corporate culture.</p>
<h2>Enabling the new</h2>
<p>The first step toward this future requires gaining visibility into the employee experience. With BYOE, the employee experience has never been more important, but it has also never been harder to monitor. Workplace analytics will therefore be critical to understanding how employees’ environments are impacting their work and finding insights that can improve their experience and productivity.</p>
<p>Security is another primary enabler. Businesses need to accept that their employees’ environments are a permanent part of their enterprise and adjust them accordingly. IT security teams will have to do more than ensure that a worker’s laptop is secured with the latest firewall patches, and consider the worker’s network security and the security of all devices linked to that network, such as baby monitors and smart TVs.</p>
<p>Once the technology, analytics and security foundations are in place, businesses will be better positioned to unlock the full value of BYOE: operating model transformation. When companies go virtual-first, they have new opportunities to integrate emerging technologies into the workforce. With a virtual-first BYOE strategy, for example, businesses can have a warehouse full of robots doing the physical work, coupled with offsite employees safely monitoring and overseeing strategy.</p>
<h2>Cultural change is key</h2>
<p>Success in BYOE will also come down to culture. The enterprise must accept that the employee environment is now part of the &#8220;workplace&#8221; and accommodate people’s needs. This will be a large, slow-to-emerge cultural shift, but there will be quick wins, too.</p>
<p>Take the disconnect between in-person and remote workers as an example. So much is currently tied to geography, but the future will be all about balance. Workers in different roles will benefit from the work environment best suited to their needs. However, without careful implementation, the approach could lead to a divided workforce, where in-office and remote workers struggle to collaborate. Quora <a href="https://www.quora.com/q/quora/Remote-First-at-Quora">is already looking</a> to overcome this challenge by requiring all employees who are attending meetings, regardless of whether they’re home or in the office, to appear on their own video screen.</p>
<p>Reimagining the organization for BYOE is a moving target and best practices are still emerging. But one thing is already clear: You can’t afford to wait. To attract the best talent and keep employees engaged, start planning now.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OFAFaMJ2qG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/as-tech-offices-begin-to-reopen-the-workplace-could-look-very-different/">As tech offices begin to reopen, the workplace could look very different</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As tech offices begin to reopen, the workplace could look very different&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/as-tech-offices-begin-to-reopen-the-workplace-could-look-very-different/embed/#?secret=OFAFaMJ2qG" data-secret="OFAFaMJ2qG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/31/bring-your-own-environment-the-future-of-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184085</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TuSimple&#8217;s self-driving truck network takes shape with Ryder partnership</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/tusimples-self-driving-truck-network-takes-shape-with-ryder-partnership/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/tusimples-self-driving-truck-network-takes-shape-with-ryder-partnership/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving trucks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TuSimple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184089</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TuSimple, the self-driving truck company that went public earlier this year, has partnered with Ryder as part of its plan to build out a freight network that will support its autonomous trucking operations. Under the deal announced this week, Ryder&#8217;s fleet maintenance facilities will act as terminals for TuSimple&#8217;s freight network. TuSimple&#8217;s so-called AFN, or [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TuSimple, the self-driving truck company that went public earlier this year, has partnered with Ryder as part of its plan to build out a freight network that will support its autonomous trucking operations.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Under the deal announced this week, Ryder&#8217;s fleet maintenance facilities will act as terminals for TuSimple&#8217;s freight network. TuSimple&#8217;s so-called AFN, or autonomous freight network, is a collection of </span>shipping routes and terminals designed for autonomous trucking operations that will extend across the United States by 2024. UPS, which took a minority stake in TuSimple before it went public, carrier U.S. Xpress, Penske Truck Leasing and Berkshire Hathaway’s grocery and food service supply chain company McLane Inc. were the inaugural partners in the network.</p>
<p>TuSimple’s AFN involves four pieces that includes its self-driving trucks, digital mapped routes, freight terminals and a system that will let customers monitor autonomous trucking operations and track their shipments in real time.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Ryder&#8217;s facilities will primarily serve as strategic terminals where TuSimple trucks can receive maintenance and have sensors used in the self-driving system calibrated, if needed. In some cases, the terminals might be used as a transfer hub for a smaller operator that might want to pick up cargo. But this is not meant to be a hub-to-hub system where its customers would come and pick up freight, according to TuSimple President and CEO Cheng Lu.</p>
<p>&#8220;These trucks need to be serviceable and maintainable and they need to have higher uptime, which is what every carrier cares about regardless of whether it is autonomous or not,&#8221; Lu said.</p>
<p>Small shippers and carriers might use these terminals to pick up and drop off freight. However, Lu stressed that in most cases, especially for large-scale operators like UPS, TuSimple will take the freight directly to the customer&#8217;s distribution centers. The Ryder facilities work as nodes, or stops, on its network to allow TuSimple to reach more customers over a larger geographic area, Lu added.</p>
<p>The partnership will start gradually. TuSimple has 50 autonomous trucks in its fleet that — along with a human safety operator behind the wheel — transport freight for customers in Arizona, New Mexico and Texas. The partnership will initially use Ryder&#8217;s facilities in these areas and eventually expand to the company&#8217;s 500 maintenance facilities in the United States.</p>
<p>TuSimple said it expects to expand operations to the East Coast, carrying freight between Phoenix and Orlando later this year. TuSimple has about 25 new trucks on order, which will be added to the fleet once they become available.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wAsxKlZpTl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/kodiak-robotics-founder-says-tight-focus-on-autonomous-trucks-is-working/">Kodiak Robotics&#8217; founder says tight focus on autonomous trucks is working</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Kodiak Robotics&#8217; founder says tight focus on autonomous trucks is working&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/kodiak-robotics-founder-says-tight-focus-on-autonomous-trucks-is-working/embed/#?secret=wAsxKlZpTl" data-secret="wAsxKlZpTl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/tusimples-self-driving-truck-network-takes-shape-with-ryder-partnership/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184089</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pittsburgh Google contractors ratify deal with HCL</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/pittsburgh-google-contractors-ratify-deal-with-hcl/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/pittsburgh-google-contractors-ratify-deal-with-hcl/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 23:13:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pittsburgh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[union]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184346</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nearly two years ago, contractors for Google’s Pittsburgh operations voted to join the United Steelworkers union in a bid to secure more labor rights representation. It was an early example of a building union movement for tech workers across the spectrum. But as other hard-fought battles have been waged among blue and white collar workers [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Nearly two years ago, contractors for Google’s Pittsburgh operations voted to join the United Steelworkers union in a bid to secure more labor rights representation. It was an early example of a building union movement for tech workers across the spectrum. But as other hard-fought battles have been waged among blue and white collar workers alike, both sides have continued hashing out negotiations. This week, those have finally resulted in something more concrete.</p>
<p>The contract workers held out for what they believed to be similar treatment as others in the tech industry. At the time, it seemed Google was hoping to stay out of the fray with HCL Technologies, the consulting company that staffed the workers.</p>
<p>“We work with lots of partners, many of which have unionized workforces, and many of which don’t,” Google said following the initial union vote. “As with all our partners, whether HCL’s employees unionize or not is between them and their employer. We’ll continue to partner with HCL.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>According to the USW, the 65 Pittsburgh-based workers have ratified the contract with HCL. It’s a three-year-deal that covers working conditions, job security and wages, per a note from the union.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">USW Tech Workers Ratify Historic First Contract at HCL <a href="https://t.co/VY8XLGThUr">https://t.co/VY8XLGThUr</a></p>
<p>&mdash; United Steelworkers (@steelworkers) <a href="https://twitter.com/steelworkers/status/1421086925881028614?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 30, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>&#8220;After close to two years of hard work, patience and solidarity from our members at HCL, we are proud of what we achieved in this agreement,&#8221; USW President Tom Conway said in a release tied to the news. &#8220;More than ever, our struggle with HCL shows that all workers deserve the protections and benefits of a union contract.&#8221;</p>
<p>Last week, with the deal nearing completion, HCL said in a statement <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/23/22590357/google-pittsburgh-contractors-hcl-union-steelworkers">provided to The Verge</a>, “Throughout this process, HCL has been actively engaged in meaningful and fair discussions with the USW in good faith. We have been steadfast in our commitment to respect our employees’ right to pursue unionization should they choose to do so.”</p>
<p>In a release issued by USW, however, bargaining committee member Renata Nelson notes some clear tension in the process. “After ignoring our concerns, HCL tried to prevent us from forming a union, and when it failed, the company dragged out the negotiating process while sending our jobs overseas in retaliation,” Parks said in the release. “Now, with a strong union and contract in place, we’re confident that our voices will be heard.”</p>
<p>We’ve reached out to Google for comment.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EBTqT6T0Pt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/04/google-alphabet-employees-union/">Google, Alphabet employees unionize</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google, Alphabet employees unionize&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/04/google-alphabet-employees-union/embed/#?secret=EBTqT6T0Pt" data-secret="EBTqT6T0Pt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/pittsburgh-google-contractors-ratify-deal-with-hcl/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184346</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: European privacy regulators fine Amazon $887M over targeted advertising practices</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/daily-crunch-38/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/daily-crunch-38/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 22:10:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for July 30, 2021. What a week, my friends. It was packed full of IPOs and earnings and startup news and new venture funds. And today was no exception. Before we get into it, however, I am happy to report that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/calendly-ceo-tope-awotona-is-joining-us-at-disrupt-2021/">Calendly CEO Tope Awotona is coming to Disrupt</a>. It’s also the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/last-day-to-snag-early-bird-passes-to-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/">last day for early-bird passes</a>, which are cheap. See you there! &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IqKZLMa9vT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/last-day-to-snag-early-bird-passes-to-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/">Last day to snag early-bird passes to TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Last day to snag early-bird passes to TechCrunch Disrupt 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/last-day-to-snag-early-bird-passes-to-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/embed/#?secret=IqKZLMa9vT" data-secret="IqKZLMa9vT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/elon-musk-calls-app-store-fees-a-de-facto-global-tax-on-the-internet/"><strong>Elon vs. Tim Apple:</strong></a> Earnings season is usually replete with CEOs and other execs saying very few, usually boring things. That’s because there are rules about what CEOs and other corporate leaders can say when their companies are public. Then there’s Elon Musk, who took a <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/07/26/elon-musk-apple-sniping-tesla-call">poorly veiled potshot</a> at Apple during Tesla’s earnings call, and followed it up by tweeting that Apple’s App Store cut is a tax on the internet. Game on.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/robinhoods-cfo-says-it-was-ready-to-go-public/"><strong>Why Robinhood went public:</strong></a> TechCrunch spoke with the company’s CFO earlier this week about why this was the right time for the consumer trading service to go public. His answer? The company had done the work on exec talent, product work, safety and was ready. We also dug into why the company’s debut has been a bit staid.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/gopuff-confirms-new-1b-cash-injection-at-a-15b-valuation-to-expand-its-instant-grocery-delivery-service/"><strong>Gopuff confirms $100M investment:</strong></a> The on-demand delivery company is now worth $15 billion after the latest investment, meaning that the so-called “instant” delivery space is now better funded than ever. Who put the capital in? A raft of crossover funds and other capital pools. This is a win <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/gopuff-funding/">for SoftBank’s Vision Fund</a>, mind.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/yat-thinks-emoji-identities-can-be-a-thing-and-it-has-20m-in-sales-to-back-it-up/"><strong>A good day for startups starting with the letter “Y:”</strong></a> Remember <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/28/yik-yak-shuts-down-after-square-paid-1-million-for-its-engineers/">Yik Yak</a>? <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/24/yac-gets-backed-by-slack-to-bring-the-intimacy-of-voice-back-when-remote-co-workers-interact/">And Yac</a>? <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/hands-on-with-yo-the-absurdly-simple-messaging-app/">And Yo</a>? Well, now keep your mind wrapped around <em>Yat</em>, a startup that has sold tens of millions of dollars in emoji strings that can represent your person or personality. I would mock this but I thought Bitmoji were dumb, so what do I know.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/white-label-saas-shipping-startup-outvio-closes-3m-round-led-by-change-ventures/"><strong>Outvio closes $3M round for its white-label fulfillment service:</strong></a> Hailing from known startup hub Estonia, Outvio wants to build a SaaS business around its white-labelable “fulfillment solution for medium-sized and large online retailers in Spain and Estonia,” TechCrunch reports. Frankly given how big the e-commerce game is getting, the idea behind Outvio is not a surprise. Let’s see what it can get done with its new capital.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/varda-space-industries-closes-42m-series-a-for-off-planet-manufacturing/"><strong>Let’s build stuff in space:</strong></a> That’s what we presume Varda Space pitched when it was busy raising a $42 million Series A round. Why build stuff in space, which is hard to get to? Microgravity. Varda wants to have its first space-based manufacturing hub set up by 2023. My inner science fiction nerd is hyped.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/platform-as-a-service-startup-porter-aims-to-become-go-to-platform-for-deploying-managing-cloud-based-apps/"><strong>Porter wants to build a PaaS offering to make Kubernetes management better:</strong></a> The YC graduate just raised $1.5 million for its work to boot. In short, the founding team liked tech like Kubernetes, but didn’t like managing it. So they built a tool to make that work easier. Why Porter raised a 2012-era seed round is beyond us, but the company can surely access more funds if things go well.</li>
</ul>
<h2>The best way to grow your tech career? Treat it like an app</h2>
<p>Many technical workers aren&#8217;t extremely career focused; on average, they&#8217;re paid more than other startup employees, and the most talented often get to work on projects that interest them personally.</p>
<p>But the increasing demand for talent is offset by an ongoing shortage: Companies can&#8217;t hire developers and engineers fast enough, even though many still don&#8217;t see themselves as in-demand workers.</p>
<p>&#8220;To put it bluntly, many developers and engineers stink at managing their own careers,&#8221; says Raj Yavatkar, CTO of Juniper Networks.</p>
<p>Breaking away from traditional tech culture can be challenging, so Yavatkar recommends that developers and engineers &#8220;treat career advancement as you would a software project.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RnGv75BgmZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/the-best-way-to-grow-your-tech-career-treat-it-like-an-app/">The best way to grow your tech career? Treat it like an app</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The best way to grow your tech career? Treat it like an app&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/the-best-way-to-grow-your-tech-career-treat-it-like-an-app/embed/#?secret=RnGv75BgmZ" data-secret="RnGv75BgmZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>Fires, the moon and a European fine? We have it all for you today in our big technology watchlist:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/a-tesla-megapack-caught-fire-at-the-victorian-big-battery-facility-in-australia/"><strong>13 tons of Tesla batteries ignite:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Batteries sometimes catch fire. Samsung learned this back in the day. Tesla is the most recent victim. A 13-ton Tesla Megapack caught fire in southeast Australia recently, which made the news. No one was hurt.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/government-watchdog-rejects-blue-origins-protest-over-lunar-lander-contract/"><strong>Blue Origin won’t get a moon rover deal:</strong></a> After offering a heavily discounted project to the U.S. government, Blue Origin won’t get what it wanted after its request was turned down. A challenge to a SpaceX contract by Dynetics was also denied. So much for that.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/eu-hits-amazon-with-record-breaking-887m-gdpr-fine-over-data-misuse/"><strong>The EU fines Amazon its lunch money:</strong></a> Luxembourg’s National Commission for Data Protection, or CNPD, has assessed a mammoth fine worth €746 million in metric, or $887 million in furlongs per fortnight. Amazon was not pleased with the GDPR-derived fine. But still, the company generates tens of billions of dollars in operating cash flow each year. How much does this fine really hurt?</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/airtel-africa-gets-an-extra-200m-for-its-mobile-money-business-from-qia/"><strong>Airtel Africa’s mobile money arm raises another $200M:</strong></a> As TechCrunch has noted, there’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/african-startups-join-global-funding-boom-as-fintech-shines/">more and more capital flowing into all things digital in Africa</a>. And startups aren’t the only groups landing checks. African telco Airtel Africa’s mobile money unit has raised lots of capital in recent weeks, including a fresh $200 million from an affiliate of the Qatar Investment Authority. Mastercard and TPG are also investors.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>We’re reaching out to startup founders to tell us who they turn to when they want the most up-to-date growth marketing practices. <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">Fill out the survey here.</a></p>
<p>Read one of the testimonials we’ve received below!</p>
<p><strong>Marketer: </strong><a href="https://ascendant.uk/">Ascendant </a></p>
<p><strong>Recommended by: </strong>Robyn Weatherley<strong>, </strong><a href="https://www.thirdfort.com/">Thirdfort Limited</a></p>
<p><strong>Testimonial: </strong>“Beyond their knowledge and experience (which is in abundance!), they have a deep understanding and appreciation for the unique challenges early-stage businesses have. They are in tune with the particular hurdles at various stages of growth and are able to adapt their working style dependent on those. They haven&#8217;t just helped us execute vital growth tactics, but they&#8217;ve helped us set up the framework to keep executing on those whether we are 5, 50 or 500 people. This is incredibly important as we scale and to demonstrate to future investors. They are also exceptional mentors and are able to offer real-world advice and work flexibly to suit the ever-changing nature of a high-growth early-stage business.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/daily-crunch-38/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184287</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Argo AI can now offer the public rides in its autonomous vehicles in California</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/argo-ai-can-now-offer-the-public-rides-in-its-autonomous-vehicles-in-california/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/argo-ai-can-now-offer-the-public-rides-in-its-autonomous-vehicles-in-california/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 21:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Argo AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Argo AI, the autonomous vehicle technology startup backed by Ford and VW, has landed a permit in California that will allow the company to give people free rides in its self-driving vehicles on the state&#8217;s public roads. The California Public Utilities Commission issued the so-called Drivered AV pilot permit earlier this month, according to the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Argo AI, the autonomous vehicle technology startup backed by Ford and VW, has landed a permit in California that will allow the company to give people free rides in its self-driving vehicles on the state&#8217;s public roads.</p>
<p>The California Public Utilities Commission issued the so-called Drivered AV pilot permit earlier this month, according to the approved application. It was <a href="https://www.cpuc.ca.gov/regulatory-services/licensing/transportation-licensing-and-analysis-branch/autonomous-vehicle-carrier-pilot/autonomous-vehicle-pilot-permits-issued">posted on its website</a> Friday, a little more than a week after Argo and Ford announced plans to launch at least 1,000 self-driving vehicles on Lyft&#8217;s ride-hailing network in a number of cities over the next five years, starting with Miami and Austin.</p>
<p>The permit, which is part of the state&#8217;s Autonomous Vehicle Passenger Service pilot, puts Argo in small and growing group of companies seeking to expand beyond traditional AV testing — a signal that the industry, or at least some companies, are preparing for commercial operations. Argo has been testing its autonomous vehicle technology in Ford vehicles around Palo Alto since 2019. Today, the company&#8217;s test fleet in California is about one dozen self-driving test vehicles. It also has autonomous test vehicles in Miami, Austin, Washington D.C., Pittsburgh and Detroit.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Aurora, AutoX, Cruise, Deeproute, Pony.ai, Voyage, Zoox and Waymo have all received permits to participate in the CPUC&#8217;s Drivered Autonomous Vehicle Passenger Service Pilot program, which requires a human safety operator to be behind the wheel. Companies with this permit cannot charge for rides.</p>
<p>Cruise is the only company to have secured a driverless permit from the CPUC, which allows it to shuttle passengers in its test vehicles without a human safety operator behind the wheel.</p>
<p>Snagging the CPUC&#8217;s Drivered permit is just part of the journey to commercialization in California. The state requires companies to navigate a series of regulatory hurdles from the CPUC and the California Department of Motor Vehicles — each agency with its own tiered system of permits — before it can charge for rides in robotaxis without a human safety operator behind the wheel.</p>
<p>The DMV regulates and issues permits for testing autonomous vehicles on public roads. There are three levels of permits issued by the DMW, starting with one that allows companies to test AVs on public roads with a safety operator behind the wheel. More than 60 companies have this basic testing permit.</p>
<p>The next permit allows for driverless testing, followed by a deployment permit for commercial operations. Driverless testing permits, in which a human operator is not behind the wheel, have become the new milestone and a required step for companies that want to launch a commercial robotaxi or delivery service in the state. AutoX, Baidu, Cruise, Nuro, Pony.ai, Waymo, WeRide and Zoox have driverless permits with the DMV.</p>
<p>The final step with the DMV, which only Nuro has achieved, is a deployment permit. This permit allows Nuro to deploy at a commercial scale. Nuro&#8217;s vehicles can&#8217;t hold passengers, just cargo, which allows the company to bypass the CPUC permitting process.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the CPUC authorized in May 2018 two pilot programs for transporting passengers in autonomous vehicles. The Drivered Autonomous Vehicle Passenger Service Pilot program, which is what Argo just secured, allows companies to operate a ride-hailing service using autonomous vehicles as long as they follow specific rules. Companies are not allowed to charge for rides, a human safety driver must be behind the wheel and certain data must be reported quarterly.</p>
<p>The second CPUC pilot allows for driverless passenger service, which<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/cruise-can-now-give-passengers-rides-in-driverless-cars-in-california/"> Cruise secured in June 2021</a>.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s important to note that to reach the holy grail of commercial robotaxis requires the companies to secure all of these permits from the DMV and CPUC.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Gf9EBGd6mh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/argo-ford-to-launch-self-driving-vehicles-on-lyfts-ride-hailing-app/">Argo, Ford to launch self-driving vehicles on Lyft&#8217;s ride-hailing app</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Argo, Ford to launch self-driving vehicles on Lyft&#8217;s ride-hailing app&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/argo-ford-to-launch-self-driving-vehicles-on-lyfts-ride-hailing-app/embed/#?secret=Gf9EBGd6mh" data-secret="Gf9EBGd6mh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/argo-ai-can-now-offer-the-public-rides-in-its-autonomous-vehicles-in-california/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184276</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deliveroo could leave Spanish market ahead of on-demand labor reclassification</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/deliveroo-could-leave-spanish-market-ahead-of-on-demand-labor-reclassification/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/deliveroo-could-leave-spanish-market-ahead-of-on-demand-labor-reclassification/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 20:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deliveroo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Just-Eat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber Eats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184120</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Deliveroo said it is considering leaving the Spanish market, citing limited market share and a long road of investment with 'highly uncertain long-term potential returns' on the horizon.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Deliveroo <a href="https://www.investegate.co.uk/deliveroo-plc--roo-/rns/proposal-to-end-operations-in-spain/202107300908580582H/">announced today</a> that it is considering leaving the Spanish market, citing limited market share and a long road of investment with &#8220;highly uncertain long-term potential returns&#8221; on the horizon.</p>
<p>The company, an on-demand outfit based in the U.K., <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/deliveroo-prices-its-shares-on-the-lse-at-3-90-at-the-lower-end-of-the-range-with-a-market-cap-of-7-59b/">went public earlier in 2021</a>. Its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/what-to-make-of-deliveroos-rough-ipo-debut/">shares initially sagged</a>, drawing concern about both the value of on-demand companies and tech concerns listing in London more broadly. However, shares of Deliveroo have since recovered, and the company&#8217;s <a href="https://dpd-12774-s3.s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/assets/8316/2574/2996/Deliveroo_PLC_update_Q2_2021.pdf">second-quarter earnings report</a> saw it raise its expected gross order volume growth expectations &#8220;from between 30% to 40% to between 50% to 60%.&#8221;</p>
<p>Given its rising growth expectations and improving public-market valuation, you may be surprised that Deliveroo is willing to leave any of the 12 markets in which it currently operates. In the case of Spain, it appears that Deliveroo is concerned that changes to local labor laws will make its operations more expensive in the country, which, given its modest market share, is not palatable.</p>
<p>Recall that <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/spain-adopts-landmark-law-protect-gig-delivery-workers-77620461">Spain adopted a law</a> in May &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/spain-agrees-on-labor-reform-that-will-recognize-delivery-platform-riders-as-employees/">a law generally agreed to in March</a> &#8212; requiring on-demand companies to hire their couriers. This is the sort of arrangement that on-demand companies in food delivery and ride-hailing have long fought; many on-demand companies are unprofitable <em>without</em> hiring couriers, and doing so could raise their costs. The possibility of worsened economics makes such changes to labor laws in any market a worry for startups and public companies alike that lean on freelance delivery workers.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s parse the Deliveroo statement to better understand the company&#8217;s perspective. Here&#8217;s the introductory paragraph:</p>
<blockquote><p>Deliveroo today announces that it proposes to consult on ending its operations in Spain. Deliveroo currently operates across 12 markets worldwide, with the vast majority of the Company&#8217;s gross transaction value (GTV) coming from markets where Deliveroo holds a #1 or #2 market position.</p></blockquote>
<p>Translation: We&#8217;re probably leaving Spain. Most of our order volume comes from markets where we are in a leading position (the company competes with Uber Eats, Glovo and Just Eat in different markets). We are not in a leading position in Spain.</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="ad"><span class="r">Spain represents less than 2% of Deliveroo&#8217;s GTV in H1 2021. The Company has determined that achieving and sustaining a top-tier market position in Spain would require a disproportionate level of investment with highly uncertain long-term potential returns that could impact the economic viability of the market for the Company. </span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Translation: Spain is a very small market for Deliveroo. To gain lots of market share in Spain would be very costly, and the company isn&#8217;t sure about the long-term profitability of the country&#8217;s business. This is where labor issues like this come into play &#8212; investing to gain market share in a country where your business is less profitable is hard to pencil out.</p>
<p>And <a href="https://elpais.com/economia/2021-07-30/deliveroo-se-propone-cerrar-su-division-espanola.html">according to El Pais</a>, the decision by Deliveroo comes as it was up against a deadline regarding worker reclassification. That may have contributed to the timing of the announcement.</p>
<p>From this juncture, Deliveroo spends three paragraphs discussing how it will support workers in case it does leave the Spanish market. It closes with the following:</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="ae"><span class="o">This proposal does not impact previously communicated full-year guidance on Group annual GTV growth and gross profit margin.</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fair enough.</p>
<p>On-demand companies have made arguments over the years that changes to labor laws that would push more costs onto their plates in the form of hiring couriers &#8212; or simply paying them more &#8212; would make certain markets uneconomic and drive them away. Here, Deliveroo can follow through with an exit at essentially no cost, given how small its order volume is compared to its other 11 markets.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/deliveroo-could-leave-spanish-market-ahead-of-on-demand-labor-reclassification/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184120</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>For tech firms, the risk of not preparing for leadership changes is huge</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/for-tech-firms-the-risk-of-not-preparing-for-leadership-changes-is-huge/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/for-tech-firms-the-risk-of-not-preparing-for-leadership-changes-is-huge/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 20:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resource management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership tactics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satya Nadella]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tim Cook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184018</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A change of command is one of the most delicate moments in the life cycle of any organization. If mishandled, the transition from one CEO to the next can result in massive downsides.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jason Dressel</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/historyfactory">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jason Dressel is president of<a href="https://www.historyfactory.com/"> History Factory</a>, which helps companies use their history and heritage to enhance and transform strategy, positioning, marketing and communication.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Every week over the past three and a half years, an average of three CEOs have exited tech companies in the U.S. That tally is higher — in good times and bad — than in any of the other 26 for-profit sectors tracked by executive search firm <a href="https://www.challengergray.com/blog/ceo-turnover-cools-in-may-falling-26-from-april/">Challenger, Gray &amp; Christmas</a>. You&#8217;d think tech companies should be the paradigm of how to prep for leadership transitions, since they operate in such a constant state of flux.</p>
<p>They’re far from it.</p>
<p>A change of command is one of the most delicate moments in the life cycle of any organization. If mishandled, the transition from one CEO to the next can result in a loss of market valuation, momentum and focus, as well as key personnel, customers and partners. It may even become that turning point when an organization begins to slide toward irrelevance.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>With so much at stake, 84% of tech execs agree that succession planning is more important than ever because of today’s fast-changing business environment, according to <a href="https://www.historyfactory.com/the-succession-trap/">our new survey</a> of corporate America’s leaders. Seven out of 10 survey respondents agreed that tech companies face more scrutiny than other multinationals during a transition.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			84% of tech execs agree that succession planning is more important than ever because of today’s fast-changing business environment.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Yet we found that tech execs appear just as unprepared for C-suite transitions as their peers in other sectors. Three out of five respondents said their companies don’t have a documented plan to handle a leadership change, even though, by that same ratio, they acknowledge that a documented plan is the biggest determinant in seamless transitions.</p>
<p>The findings may not be troubling if these respondents were millennial startup founders, years from leaving their companies. The executives we polled, however, hail from 160 companies that have been in business for a minimum of 15 years — 35 are tech companies, the largest industry cohort in the survey.</p>
<p>The smallest companies have at least 1,500 employees and $500 million in annual revenue, while the largest have head counts of over 500,000 and revenue upward of $100 billion. They have been around long enough to understand — and put into place — risk management and crisis planning, including what happens should their leaders fall victim to the proverbial milk truck.</p>
<p>Tech execs should be more rigorous about succession planning for one important reason: institutional memory. Tech firms generally are younger than other companies of a similar size, which partly explains why the median age of S&amp;P 500 companies plunged to 33 years in 2018 from 85 years in 2000, according to <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/Industries/Electric%20Power%20and%20Natural%20Gas/Our%20Insights/Traditional%20company%20new%20businesses%20The%20pairing%20that%20can%20ensure%20an%20incumbents%20survival/Traditional-company-new-businesses-VF.ashx">McKinsey &amp; Co</a>.</p>
<p>These enterprises clearly have accomplished a lot in their short lives, but in their haste, most have not captured their history, unlike their longer-lived peers in other sectors. Less than half of these tech firms, in fact, have formally recorded their leader’s story for posterity. That puts them at a disadvantage when, inevitably, they will be required to onboard newcomers to their C-suites.</p>
<p>It’s best to record this history well before the intense swirl of a leadership transition begins. Crucially, it will help the incoming and future generations of leadership understand critical aspects of its track record, the lessons learned, culture and identity. It also explains why the organization has evolved as it has, what binds people together and what may trigger resistance based on previous experience. It’s as much about moving forward as looking back.</p>
<p>Most execs in our poll get it, with 85% saying a company’s history can be a playbook for new executives to learn and prepare for upcoming challenges and opportunities. “History is the mother of innovation for any type of company,” one respondent said. “History,&#8221; writes another, “includes the roadmap to failures as well as successes.”</p>
<p>But this documented history cannot be a hagiography of the departing CEO. Too often, outgoing execs spend their last years in office constructing their own trophy cases. Even as they conceded their own flat-footedness on transition planning, the majority of execs said they have already taken steps to create and reinforce their personal legacies — two-thirds said they have already completed their own formal legacy planning, many with the blessing of their boards.</p>
<p>It’s ironic, then, that three out of five also said that the legacy of a CEO or founder often overshadows the skill set and experience a successor brings. Two-thirds of tech execs believed that the longer a leader has been in office, the more it complicates a transition.</p>
<p>Tech leaders can do this right and have done so. Asked which five big-name CEO transitions was most successful, respondents’ No. 1 was <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2021-02-09/this-is-how-tim-cook-transformed-apple-aapl-after-steve-jobs?sref=MSHtM8dd">Apple’s handoff</a> from Steve Jobs to Tim Cook (38%), followed by Microsoft’s page-turn from Steve Ballmer to Satya Nadella (28%). The others, at General Electric, General Motors and Goldman Sachs, each netted no more than 13% of votes.</p>
<p>Apple&#8217;s apparent predominance in this survey might contradict the advice to play down the aggrandizement of an exiting CEO and highlight the compilation and transfer of an organization’s history to the next chief executive. Jobs, after all, painstakingly managed his legacy until the end. But even as he continued to take center-stage, he also made sure to pass along Apple’s institutional knowledge and ethos to Cook over the 13 years they shared space on Apple’s executive floor.</p>
<p>Sooner or later, everyone in the C-suite today — including startup founders — will depart. For the sake of everyone they’ll leave behind, they should begin prepping for that day now.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="r0pYmZuEwa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/why-i-make-everyone-in-my-company-be-the-ceo-for-a-day/">Why I make everyone in my company be the CEO for a day</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why I make everyone in my company be the CEO for a day&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/why-i-make-everyone-in-my-company-be-the-ceo-for-a-day/embed/#?secret=r0pYmZuEwa" data-secret="r0pYmZuEwa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/for-tech-firms-the-risk-of-not-preparing-for-leadership-changes-is-huge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184018</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Extra Crunch roundup: Livestream e-commerce, growth marketing interviews, CEO for a day</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/extra-crunch-roundup-livestream-e-commerce-growth-marketing-interviews-ceo-for-a-day/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/extra-crunch-roundup-livestream-e-commerce-growth-marketing-interviews-ceo-for-a-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 20:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[duolingo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184145</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thanks very much for reading Extra Crunch this week; have a great weekend.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This year, livestream viewers in China are projected to spend more than $60 billion on digital shopping experiences that let them interact with influencers in real time.</p>
<p>Promoting everything from cosmetics to food, social media stars use Taobao, TikTok and other platforms to livestream products and take questions from the audience.</p>
<p>On Taobao&#8217;s Singles Day in 2020, livestreams racked up $6 billion in sales, twice as much revenue as the year prior.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Sensing a trend, Western startups are getting in on the action, with companies like Whatnot and PopShop.Live raising rounds to build out their infrastructure. Looking forward, Alanna Gregory, senior global director at Afterpay, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/livestream-e-commerce-why-companies-and-brands-need-to-tune-in/">says she foresees four major trends</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Networks</li>
<li>SaaS streaming tools</li>
<li>Host discovery and outreach tools</li>
<li>Host marketplaces and agencies</li>
</ul>
<p>&#8220;For brands, SaaS streaming tools will be the most impactful way to take advantage of livestream commerce trends,&#8221; Gregory writes in an Extra Crunch guest post. &#8220;All of this will be incredibly transformative.&#8221;</p>
<hr />
<p>To help entrepreneurs take on the most fundamental challenge facing early-stage startups, our team is speaking to growth marketers to learn more about the advice they&#8217;re offering clients these days.</p>
<p>This week, Miranda Halpern and Anna Heim interviewed experts on growth marketing:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/the-mkt1-interview-growth-marketing-in-2021-hiring-versus-outsourcing-and-more/">The MKT1 interview: Growth marketing in 2021, hiring versus outsourcing and more</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/unmuted-founder-max-van-den-ingh-on-success-beyond-the-metrics/">Unmuted founder Max van den Ingh on success beyond the metrics</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/draft-dev-ceo-karl-hughes-on-the-importance-of-using-experts-in-developer-marketing/">Draft.dev CEO Karl Hughes on the importance of using experts in developer marketing</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Growth is an existential issue, so these stories are free to read and share. If you&#8217;ve worked with an individual or an agency who helped your startup find and keep new users,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/help-techcrunch-find-the-best-growth-marketers-for-startups/"> please let us know</a>.</p>
<p>Thanks very much for reading Extra Crunch this week; have a great weekend.</p>
<p>Walter Thompson</p>
<p>Senior Editor, TechCrunch</p>
<p><a href="https://www.twitter.com/yourprotagonist">@yourprotagonist</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Iqk824tp45"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/livestream-e-commerce-why-companies-and-brands-need-to-tune-in/">Livestream e-commerce: Why companies and brands need to tune in</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Livestream e-commerce: Why companies and brands need to tune in&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/livestream-e-commerce-why-companies-and-brands-need-to-tune-in/embed/#?secret=Iqk824tp45" data-secret="Iqk824tp45" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Why Latin American venture capital is breaking records this year</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996006" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996006" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996006" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996006" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Alex Wilhelm and Anna Heim’s global exploration of Q2 venture capital data wrapped up this week with an in-depth look at Latin America.</p>
<p>One investor told them that today’s LatAm startup market “is a story about talent, not about capital.”</p>
<p>“The union of talent and money is what startup markets need to thrive,” they write. “But there are other reasons why Latin American startups are so frequently in the news today, including structural factors, such as strong digital penetration and quick e-commerce growth.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uTiYd3XywG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/why-latin-american-venture-capital-is-breaking-records-this-year/">Why Latin American venture capital is breaking records this year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why Latin American venture capital is breaking records this year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/why-latin-american-venture-capital-is-breaking-records-this-year/embed/#?secret=uTiYd3XywG" data-secret="uTiYd3XywG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Dear Sophie: Should we sponsor international hires for H-1B transfers and green cards?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2099516" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2099516" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2099516" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg" alt="lone figure at entrance to maze hedge that has an American flag at the center" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2099516" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin/TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Dear Sophie,</strong></p>
<p><strong>My startup is desperately recruiting, and we see a lot of engineering candidates on H-1Bs. </strong></p>
<p><strong>They’re looking for H-1B transfers and green cards. What should we do?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Baffled in the Bay Area</strong></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="F8Pp1LQbjg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/dear-sophie-should-we-sponsor-international-hires-for-h-1b-transfers-and-green-cards/">Dear Sophie: Should we sponsor international hires for H-1B transfers and green cards? </a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Dear Sophie: Should we sponsor international hires for H-1B transfers and green cards? &#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/dear-sophie-should-we-sponsor-international-hires-for-h-1b-transfers-and-green-cards/embed/#?secret=F8Pp1LQbjg" data-secret="F8Pp1LQbjg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Why I make everyone in my company be the CEO for a day</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2182504" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2182504" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2182504" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-889233-001.jpg" alt="Vincit runs a CEO of the Day program once a month" width="1024" height="764" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-889233-001.jpg 2005w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-889233-001.jpg?resize=150,112 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-889233-001.jpg?resize=300,224 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-889233-001.jpg?resize=768,573 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-889233-001.jpg?resize=680,507 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-889233-001.jpg?resize=1536,1145 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-889233-001.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2182504" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Blake+Little" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blake Little <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>In the reality TV series &#8220;Undercover Boss,&#8221; high-powered executives disguise themselves so they can work alongside everyday employees, ostensibly to learn from them.</p>
<p>Flipping that script, software company Vincit USA has a “CEO of the Day” program where staffers move into a metaphorical corner office for 24 hours and receive a very real unlimited budget. There&#8217;s just one requirement.</p>
<p>&#8220;The CEO must make one lasting decision that will help improve the working experience of Vincit employees,&#8221; said Ville Houttu, Vincit&#8217;s founder and CEO.</p>
<p>Since instituting the program, Vincit USA has received multiple awards for its workplace culture and sees reduced staff turnover.</p>
<p>&#8220;Though it may seem crazy, the initiative has paid off tenfold,&#8221; said Houttu.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wQMtBZdso7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/why-i-make-everyone-in-my-company-be-the-ceo-for-a-day/">Why I make everyone in my company be the CEO for a day</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why I make everyone in my company be the CEO for a day&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/why-i-make-everyone-in-my-company-be-the-ceo-for-a-day/embed/#?secret=wQMtBZdso7" data-secret="wQMtBZdso7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>What I’ve learned after 5 years of buying common stock in startups</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2182461" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2182461" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2182461" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-103000219.jpg" alt="Buying common stock can help align investor and founder incentives" width="1024" height="751" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-103000219.jpg 2022w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-103000219.jpg?resize=150,110 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-103000219.jpg?resize=300,220 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-103000219.jpg?resize=768,563 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-103000219.jpg?resize=680,498 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-103000219.jpg?resize=1536,1126 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-103000219.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2182461" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Tim+Robberts" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tim Robberts <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Instead of giving founders standard term sheets, Boston-based seed-stage venture capital firm Pillar VC offers to buy common stock.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are many terms and conditions in a preferred term sheet that can misalign investors and founders,&#8221; says founding partner Jamie Goldstein.</p>
<p>&#8220;As with any experiment, we have learned a few things that have surprised us and faced challenges we’ve had to overcome.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TkD2xxzu19"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/what-ive-learned-after-5-years-of-buying-common-stock-in-startups/">What I&#8217;ve learned after 5 years of buying common stock in startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What I&#8217;ve learned after 5 years of buying common stock in startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/what-ive-learned-after-5-years-of-buying-common-stock-in-startups/embed/#?secret=TkD2xxzu19" data-secret="TkD2xxzu19" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>China’s regulatory crackdown is good news for startups aligned with CCP goals</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996007" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996007" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996007" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996007" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Alex Wilhelm takes stock of the wall of news out of China over the past week to see if there’s a silver lining for startups in the country as the Chinese Communist Party cracks down on everything from edtech companies to streaming platforms.</p>
<p>His take?</p>
<p>“The result may be concentrated effort and capital in sectors that Beijing favors and reduced capital and focus from entrepreneurs in sectors that have been deemed fit for strict control,” he writes. “Simply: Central planning is going to tilt business more toward centrally planned goals.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="61Euw8STQJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/chinas-regulatory-crackdown-is-good-news-for-startups-aligned-with-ccp-goals/">China&#8217;s regulatory crackdown is good news for startups aligned with CCP goals</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;China&#8217;s regulatory crackdown is good news for startups aligned with CCP goals&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/chinas-regulatory-crackdown-is-good-news-for-startups-aligned-with-ccp-goals/embed/#?secret=61Euw8STQJ" data-secret="61Euw8STQJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Duolingo’s IPO pricing is great news for edtech startups</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2146337" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2146337" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2146337" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="686" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg?resize=300,201 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg?resize=768,515 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg?resize=680,456 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg?resize=1536,1029 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg?resize=2048,1372 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Duolingo-Q4.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2146337" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>The Pittsburgh-based language-learning unicorn initially aimed for an $85 to $95 per share IPO price range, then bumped that up to $95 to $100 before it began to trade. It ultimately entered the public markets at $102 per share.</p>
<p>Alex Wilhelm notes that based on Duolingo’s expected Q2 revenues, the company has a run-rate multiple of nearly 16x. Compare that to the median multiple for public SaaS companies of 14x.</p>
<p>“Duolingo, a <em>consumer edtech company,</em> is now more valuable per revenue dollar than the median public enterprise SaaS business,” Alex writes.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aZhQLcRD3j"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/duolingos-ipo-pricing-is-great-news-for-edtech-startups/">Duolingo&#8217;s IPO pricing is great news for edtech startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Duolingo&#8217;s IPO pricing is great news for edtech startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/duolingos-ipo-pricing-is-great-news-for-edtech-startups/embed/#?secret=aZhQLcRD3j" data-secret="aZhQLcRD3j" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Financial firms should leverage machine learning to make anomaly detection easier</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2182155" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2182155" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2182155" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg" alt="Machine learning can make anolmaly detection easier" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg 2309w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1263395015.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2182155" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=GOCMEN" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GOCMEN <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>“Anomaly detection is one of the more difficult and underserved operational areas in the asset-servicing sector of financial institutions,” EZOPS CEO Bikram Singh writes in a guest column.</p>
<p>But it’s critical to detect these anomalies amid a sea of data. That’s where unsupervised learning can offer a solution.</p>
<p>​​”With all eyes on data, it’s crucial that financial institutions find solutions to detect anomalies upfront, thereby preventing bad data from infecting downstream processes,” Singh writes.</p>
<p>“Machine learning can be applied to detect the data anomalies as well as identify the reasons for them, effectively reducing the time spent researching and rectifying executions.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RfhvjtgA4y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/financial-firms-should-leverage-machine-learning-to-make-anomaly-detection-easier/">Financial firms should leverage machine learning to make anomaly detection easier</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Financial firms should leverage machine learning to make anomaly detection easier&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/financial-firms-should-leverage-machine-learning-to-make-anomaly-detection-easier/embed/#?secret=RfhvjtgA4y" data-secret="RfhvjtgA4y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>African startups join global funding boom as fintech shines</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996008" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996008" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996008" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-BLU.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996008" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Alex Wilhelm and Anna Heim continued their global tour of Q2 2021 venture capital data, this week focusing on Africa.</p>
<p>“Early data indicates that Africa is set to trounce historical records in terms of venture capital raised in the year and that the first half of 2021 saw roughly twice the funds raised by African startups as was recorded in the first half of 2020,” they write.</p>
<p>“Startups across Africa have never had more access to capital than they do right now.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PK5lu75PEt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/african-startups-join-global-funding-boom-as-fintech-shines/">African startups join global funding boom as fintech shines</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;African startups join global funding boom as fintech shines&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/african-startups-join-global-funding-boom-as-fintech-shines/embed/#?secret=PK5lu75PEt" data-secret="PK5lu75PEt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>True ‘shift left and extend right’ security requires empowered developers</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2183611" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2183611" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2183611" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg" alt="Empowered developers will change the nature of true shift left and extend right security" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg 2121w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-915777574.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2183611" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=kuritafsheen" target="_blank" rel="noopener">kuritafsheen <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>The intention of DevSecOps is to wedge security and compliance into DevOps. But that’s easier said than done, says Apiiro founder and CEO Idan Plotnik.</p>
<p>“Shifting left and extending right doesn’t mean that a scanning tool or security architect should detect a security risk earlier in the process — it means that a developer should have all the context to prevent the vulnerability before it even happens,” he writes.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uafTMAYn04"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/true-shift-left-and-extend-right-security-requires-empowered-developers/">True &#8216;shift left and extend right&#8217; security requires empowered developers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;True &#8216;shift left and extend right&#8217; security requires empowered developers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/true-shift-left-and-extend-right-security-requires-empowered-developers/embed/#?secret=uafTMAYn04" data-secret="uafTMAYn04" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>4 key areas SaaS startups must address to scale infrastructure for the enterprise</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2183726" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2183726" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2183726" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-83597636.jpg" alt="bonsai tree with miniature scaffolding" width="1024" height="809" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-83597636.jpg 1948w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-83597636.jpg?resize=150,119 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-83597636.jpg?resize=300,237 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-83597636.jpg?resize=768,607 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-83597636.jpg?resize=680,537 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-83597636.jpg?resize=1536,1214 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-83597636.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2183726" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Stewart+Sutton" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stewart Sutton <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Asana’s head of engineering, Prashant Pandey, rounds up four tips for SaaS startups looking to build up their infrastructure to meet customers&#8217; growing needs.</p>
<p>“Startups and SMBs are usually the first to adopt many SaaS products. But as these customers grow in size and complexity — and as you rope in larger organizations — scaling your infrastructure for the enterprise becomes critical for success,” he writes.</p>
<p>He offers four areas to focus on:</p>
<ul>
<li>Address your customers’ security and reliability needs</li>
<li>Give IT admins control over product usage</li>
<li>Build data isolation into your architecture</li>
<li>Support customers by interconnecting their data across applications</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="e3FaxxPSRU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/4-key-areas-saas-startups-must-address-to-scale-infrastructure-for-the-enterprise/">4 key areas SaaS startups must address to scale infrastructure for the enterprise</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;4 key areas SaaS startups must address to scale infrastructure for the enterprise&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/4-key-areas-saas-startups-must-address-to-scale-infrastructure-for-the-enterprise/embed/#?secret=e3FaxxPSRU" data-secret="e3FaxxPSRU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/extra-crunch-roundup-livestream-e-commerce-growth-marketing-interviews-ceo-for-a-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184145</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kodiak Robotics&#8217; founder says tight focus on autonomous trucks is working</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/kodiak-robotics-founder-says-tight-focus-on-autonomous-trucks-is-working/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/kodiak-robotics-founder-says-tight-focus-on-autonomous-trucks-is-working/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 20:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ADAS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Don Burnette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kodiak Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving truck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2181810</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["We will need to raise more money, as you pointed out, that's certainly no secret, but I think that we have multiple options to do that."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Kodiak Robotics is one of the last private autonomous vehicles companies focused on trucking that is still standing. Nearly all the rest have been wooed by the public marketplace and the capital it can provide. But co-founder and CEO Don Burnette says the three-year-old company&#8217;s strategy of staying focused and small(er) is paying off.</p>
<p>It will be able to deploy a commercial-scale operation for about $500 million in funding, he says in the interview below. To put those go-to-market costs in perspective, that&#8217;s 10% of what Waymo has raised in external fundraising and less than 25% of newly publicly traded company TuSimple&#8217;s total fundraise.</p>
<p>Kodiak&#8217;s strategy is to take a specialized, hyperfocused approach to autonomous trucking that outsources a lot of tech, like data labeling, lidar, radar and mapping, to existing companies. Burnette, who was one of four founders of the self-driving truck startup Otto that Uber acquired, thinks this is a faster, cheaper and more efficient path to commercialization versus building out your own systems and teams.</p>
<p>The company is moving freight for commercial customers, dipping its toes in the market by working with technology partners within the existing ecosystem. Burnette says Kodiak&#8217;s Driver technology has achieved a level of maturity where it can handle anything the highway throws at it. In December, the startup achieved “disengagement-free deliveries” between Dallas and Houston, meaning the autonomous system didn’t have to be switched off for safety reasons.</p>
<p><em>The following interview, part of an ongoing series with founders who are building transportation companies, has been edited for length and clarity. </em></p>
<p><strong>You previously told me that Kodiak would need about $500 million in total funding to get to commercial driverless. You also said you’ve had some undisclosed funding rounds, but publicly, you’ve only raised $40 million. Can you still execute on your vision this far off?</strong></p>
<p>Absolutely. We are always, as startups are, in fundraising mode. We&#8217;re always talking to investors. And there&#8217;s a lot of great things happening behind the scenes currently that we haven&#8217;t yet announced. We are growing, we&#8217;re hiring, if you can look to that as an indicator of the health of a company.</p>
<p>Our tech and our plan is really sound, and we are building up our commercialization efforts in a way that I think is going to be very exciting to the overall industry and to the market. We will need to raise more money, as you pointed out, that&#8217;s certainly no secret, but I think that we have multiple options to do that.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			&#8220;Kodiak is one of the only remaining serious AV trucking companies still in the private sector, and so I think that gives us some advantages in a lot of ways.&#8221;					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p><strong>How do you intend to close that gap? Are you looking at venture capital, or maybe going for an IPO or SPAC?</strong></p>
<p>We&#8217;re considering all of the above. It&#8217;s a constant conversation internally on what is the best path for Kodiak, what is the appetite of the various forms of investors and strategic relationships. Nothing is excluded.</p>
<p>The stock market is obviously very attractive and exciting. I think TuSimple has demonstrated that an IPO with the right set of metrics and the right set of momentum and partners is possible and can be successful. I think there&#8217;s also lots of opportunity within the VCs and the private markets. Kodiak is one of the only remaining serious AV trucking companies still in the private sector, and so I think that gives us some advantages in a lot of ways.</p>
<p><strong>What&#8217;s your sense of the venture funding environment right now in autonomous? Is it harder now than it was, say, four years ago?</strong></p>
<p>The appetite has changed. In particular, investors are more skeptical of timelines and promises. There is not this sense of Wild West excitement like there was four or five years ago, and that was the Golden Age of raising capital, certainly for earlier stage companies.</p>
<p>Kodiak was at the tail end of that age, and now the goalposts have changed, and the target investors have changed. It&#8217;s no longer the early-stage VCs that companies like Kodiak and others are talking to. It&#8217;s more of the growth-stage funds, and growth-stage funds look for different types of metrics. They look for commercial traction, product-market fit, users, efficiencies, etc.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/kodiak-robotics-founder-says-tight-focus-on-autonomous-trucks-is-working/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2181810</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Growth roundup: Investing in community, targeting developers, new marketer recs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/growth-roundup-investing-in-community-targeting-developers-new-marketer-recs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/growth-roundup-investing-in-community-targeting-developers-new-marketer-recs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Halpern]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 20:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183866</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;The best thing a startup can do, and I’m seeing it happen more and more, is investing in community early on,&#8221; growth marketing expert Max van den Ingh of Unmuted tells us. &#8220;When I was leading growth at MisterGreen, we created a community for the first thousand Tesla Model 3 owners in the Netherlands. Everyone [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">&#8220;The best thing a startup can do, and I’m seeing it happen more and more, is investing in community early on,&#8221; growth marketing expert Max van den Ingh of Unmuted tells us. &#8220;When I was leading growth at MisterGreen, we created a community for the first thousand Tesla Model 3 owners in the Netherlands. Everyone wanted to be a part of this founding tribe, learn from each other, get insights and so on.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;This group turned out to be our most effective marketing tool,&#8221; he explains in an interview we published this week. &#8220;Word-of-mouth went through the roof. We had all of these people talking about our community at birthday parties, in their office, you name it. This is a great example of investing in marketing you can’t really measure, but which you do strongly believe in.&#8221;</p>
<p>Elsewhere in this week’s growth marketing recap, you’ll find TechCrunch’s coverage of growth marketing, and related topics, from the past week. You’ll also find a few recommendations for growth marketers. If you’d like to recommend a great one you&#8217;ve worked with, please fill out our <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>Marketer: </strong><a href="https://scottgraham.io/">Scott Graham</a><br />
<strong>Recommended by: </strong>Heather Larrabee, CMO, <a href="https://www.form.com/">FORM</a><br />
<strong>Testimonial: </strong>“He was referred to us and blew our socks off from his initial analysis. He’s the rare growth adviser expert at strategy and execution. He’s a servant leader, a systems thinker, integrates with the team with empathy and curiosity like he’s an internal teammate, brings a wealth of cutting-edge knowledge, and a stable of incredible partners and resources. He runs with the best and the brightest, but he’s the first one on and the last one off for the day, putting in the time to make things great. He has an uncanny ability to communicate complex concepts and make them accessible for all audiences, and he’s been a foundational game changer for our business and many others.”</p>
<p><strong>Marketer: </strong><a href="https://ascendant.uk/">Ascendant </a><br />
<strong>Recommended by: </strong>Robyn Weatherley<strong>, </strong><a href="https://www.thirdfort.com/">Thirdfort Limited</a><br />
<strong>Testimonial: </strong>“Beyond their knowledge and experience (which is in abundance!), they have a deep understanding and appreciation for the unique challenges early-stage businesses have. They are in tune with the particular hurdles at various stages of growth and are able to adapt their working style dependent on those. They haven&#8217;t just helped us execute vital growth tactics, but they&#8217;ve helped us set up the framework to keep executing on those whether we are 5, 50 or 500 people. This is incredibly important as we scale and to demonstrate to future investors. They are also exceptional mentors and are able to offer real-world advice and work flexibly to suit the ever-changing nature of a high-growth early-stage business.”</p>
<p><strong>Marketer: </strong><a href="https://ferdinandgoetzen.com/">Ferdinand Goetzen</a><br />
<strong>Recommended by: </strong>Willem van Roosmalen, <a href="http://www.homerun.co">Homerun</a><br />
<strong>Testimonial: </strong>“Exceptional skills and experience in B2B SaaS, impressive track record, clear communicator, true leader, makes impact from day one, entrepreneur (actually launched his own start up, <a href="https://www.reveall.co/">Reveall</a>).”</p>
<p><strong>Marketer: </strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/adrianagrowth/">Adriana Ivascu</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/honeypotdigital/">HoneyPot Dgtl</a><br />
<strong>Recommended by: </strong>Mihaela Petre, <a href="https://www.beerproject.be/">Brussels Beer Project</a><br />
<strong>Testimonial: “</strong>Besides her solid experience in growth and digital, Adriana has a genuine interest in growing not only the company but its people. She is hands-on in digital transformation but on top of it, she is a coach who inspires and brings the best in teams. We are very happy to have benefited from a long-term strategic growth path and a skill playbook that we can pass on to our whole organization.”</p>
<p><strong>Marketer: </strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mariska-vroegindeweij/#">Mariska Vroegindeweij</a>, <a href="https://growthconfetti.nl/">Growth &amp; confetti</a><br />
<strong>Recommended by: </strong>Hugo Pereira, <a href="http://www.evbox.com">EVBox</a><br />
<strong>Testimonial: </strong>“[During our time working together] she was very young and bright. She started the Growth Marketing division on her own, built a team of developers, designers, advertisement specialists, product owners to drive conversion on the whole funnel from MQL to Opportunities. It&#8217;s hard to find a marketer that combines leadership skills with hardcore skills to drive growth. She was also very data-driven, challenged me a lot on assumptions and proved me wrong a few times by doing experiments and showcasing better ways to convert. And she was bold enough to start her own agency at a young age and doing well. Plus, she&#8217;s tons of fun.”</p>
<blockquote><p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Help TechCrunch find the best growth marketers for startups. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">this quick survey</a> and we&#8217;ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/the-mkt1-interview-growth-marketing-in-2021-hiring-versus-outsourcing-and-more/">The MKT1 interview: Growth marketing in 2021, hiring versus outsourcing and more</a>: We hosted a Twitter Spaces with strategic marketing firm MKT1 recently, following a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/mkt1-developer-marketing-is-what-startup-marketing-should-look-like/">popular interview</a> we published with them a few weeks ago. “The skill sets of growth marketers are in high demand,&#8221; co-founder Kathleen Estreich told host Danny Crichton during the event. &#8220;They always have been, but it feels pretty acute right now. Given that a lot of the companies are raising money earlier and starting to try and build that traction faster to grow into the valuations, we’re starting to see a huge need.” If you’re curious to see what skills are needed in growth marketing positions right now, take a look at the <a href="https://pallet.xyz/list/mkt1-jobs/jobs">job board</a> curated by MKT1.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/draft-dev-ceo-karl-hughes-on-the-importance-of-using-experts-in-developer-marketing/">Draft.dev CEO Karl Hughes on the importance of using experts in developer marketing</a>: Anna Heim interviewed Karl Hughes, founder of Daft.dev, which works with a large number of developer tool companies. Hughes&#8217; insights come from personal experience, “I’ve been a software developer, and then most recently was a CTO at a startup in Chicago, so I knew that there were lots of companies trying to reach developers [ … ] and that a lot of them were doing a poor job of it.” In this interview, Hughes addresses the mistakes made when targeting marketing toward developers, the steps that Draft.dev takes to mitigate them and more.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/unmuted-founder-max-van-den-ingh-on-success-beyond-the-metrics/">Unmuted founder Max van den Ingh on success beyond the metrics</a>: “At Unmuted, when we start working with a new client, we perform a series of exercises together,&#8221; he told us in the interview. &#8220;This helps us get a clear picture of where the client is now and where they could be when we’ve optimized marketing. Next, instead of fixed numbers, like a specific amount of new customers in a given period, we focus on growth levers, like month-over-month growth in certain conversion or activation areas. Focusing on growth levers makes our work more actionable.&#8221; Read the interview with him for more about Unmuted’s “modern” marketing approach, setting realistic goals and trends seen in growth marketing during the pandemic.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/dan-olsen-leads-a-product-market-fit-masterclass-for-the-startup-alley-cohort/">Dan Olsen leads a product-market fit masterclass for the Startup Alley+ cohort</a>: As part of Startup Alley+, TC Disrupt 2021 is offering a VIP experience where Dan Olsen will be holding a product-market fit masterclass. Olsen’s roster of clients includes Google, Facebook and Amazon.</p>
<p>Is there a startup growth marketing expert that you want us to know about? Let us know by filling out our <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/growth-roundup-investing-in-community-targeting-developers-new-marketer-recs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183866</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yat thinks emoji &#8216;identities&#8217; can be a thing, and it has $20M in sales to back it up</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/yat-thinks-emoji-identities-can-be-a-thing-and-it-has-20m-in-sales-to-back-it-up/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/yat-thinks-emoji-identities-can-be-a-thing-and-it-has-20m-in-sales-to-back-it-up/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 19:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emoji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ION]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysql]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[naveen jain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online identity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OpenSea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183855</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I learned about Yat in April, when a friend sent our group chat a link to a story about how the key emoji sold as an &#8220;internet identity&#8221; for $425,000. &#8220;I hate the universe,&#8221; she texted. Sure, the universe would be better if people with a spare $425,000 spent it on mutual aid or something, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">I learned about <a href="https://y.at/">Yat</a> in April, when a friend sent our group chat a link to a story about how <a href="https://thedefiant.io/emoji-based-username-project-yat-wants-to-become-universal-internet-identity-system/">the key emoji sold as an &#8220;internet identity&#8221; for $425,000</a>. &#8220;I hate the universe,&#8221; she texted.</p>
<p>Sure, the universe would be better if people with a spare $425,000 spent it on mutual aid or something, but minutes later, we were trying to figure out what this whole Yat thing was all about. And few more minutes later, I spent $5 (in U.S. dollars, not crypto) to buy <a href="https://y.at/%E2%98%95%F0%9F%91%89%F0%9F%92%A9%E2%9D%97"><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2615.png" alt="☕" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f449.png" alt="👉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4a9.png" alt="💩" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2757.png" alt="❗" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></a>, an emoji string that I think tells a moving story about my caffeine dependency and sensitive stomach. I didn&#8217;t think I would be writing about this when I made that choice.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184099" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184099" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2184099" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_7485.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="360" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_7485.jpg 750w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_7485.jpg?resize=150,79 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_7485.jpg?resize=300,159 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_7485.jpg?resize=680,360 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_7485.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184099" class="wp-caption-text">Kesha&#8217;s Yat URL on Twitter</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>On the surface, Yat is a platform that lets you buy a URL with emojis in it &#8212; even <a href="https://twitter.com/KeshaRose">Kesha</a> (y.at/<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f308.png" alt="🌈" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f680.png" alt="🚀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f47d.png" alt="👽" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />), <a href="https://twitter.com/LilTunechi">Lil Wayne</a> (y.at/<a class="css-4rbku5 css-18t94o4 css-901oao css-16my406 r-xfsgu1 r-1loqt21 r-4qtqp9 r-poiln3 r-1b7u577 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0" dir="ltr" role="link" href="https://t.co/hJ2L5cP0li?amp=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f47d.png" alt="👽" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f3b5.png" alt="🎵" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></a>), and <a href="https://twitter.com/disclosure">Disclosure</a> (y.at/<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f60e.png" alt="😎" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f3b5.png" alt="🎵" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f60e.png" alt="😎" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />) are using them in their Twitter bios. Like any URL on the internet, Yats can redirect to another website, or they can function like a more <a href="https://y.at/%F0%9F%8C%88%F0%9F%9A%80%F0%9F%91%BD">eye-catching Linktree</a>. While users could purchase their own domain name that supports emojis and use it instead of a Yat, many people don&#8217;t have the technical expertise or time to do so. Instead, they can make a one-time purchase from Yat, which owns the Y.at domain, and the company will provide you with your own y.at link for you.</p>
<p>This convenience, however, comes at a premium. Yat uses an algorithm to determine your Yat&#8217;s &#8220;rhythm score,&#8221; its metric for determining how to price your emoji combo based on its rarity. Yats with one or two emojis are so expensive that you have to contact the company directly to buy them, but you can easily find a four- or five-emoji identity that&#8217;ll only put you out $4.</p>
<p>Beyond that, CEO Naveen Jain &#8212; a Y Combinator alumnus, founder of digital marketing company Sparkart and angel investor &#8212; thinks that Yat is ultimately an internet privacy product. Jain wants people to be able to use their Yats in any way they&#8217;re able to use an online identity now, whether that&#8217;s to make payments, send messages, host a website or log in to a platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;Objectively, it&#8217;s a strange norm. You go on the internet, you register accounts with ad-supported platforms, and your username isn&#8217;t universal. You have many accounts, many usernames,&#8221; Jain said. &#8220;And you don&#8217;t control them. If an account wants to shut you down, they shut you down. How many stories are there of people trying to email some social network, and they don&#8217;t respond because they don&#8217;t have to?&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184101" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184101" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2184101" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Yat-4-copy.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="616" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Yat-4-copy.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Yat-4-copy.jpg?resize=150,136 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Yat-4-copy.jpg?resize=300,272 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Yat-4-copy.jpg?resize=768,696 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Yat-4-copy.jpg?resize=680,616 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Yat-4-copy.jpg?resize=1536,1392 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Yat-4-copy.jpg?resize=50,45 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184101" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://y.at" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Yat <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Yat doesn&#8217;t plan to fuel itself with ad money, since users pay for the product when they purchase their Yat, whether they get it for $4 or $400,000.</p>
<p>In the long run, Yat&#8217;s CEO says the company plans to use blockchain technology as a way to become self-sovereign. Yats would become assets issued on decentralized, distributed databases. Today, there are several projects working to create <a href="https://blog.nameshield.com/blog/2020/04/08/dns-on-blockchain-the-next-evolution-of-domain-names/">a decentralized alternative</a> to the current domain name system (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_Name_System">DNS</a>), which is managed by internet regulatory authority <a href="https://www.icann.org/">ICANN</a>.  DNS is how you find things on the internet, but uses a centralized, hierarchical system. A blockchain domain name system would have no central authority, and some believe this could be the foundation of a next-gen web, or &#8220;Web 3.0.&#8221;</p>
<p>Today, words like &#8220;blockchain&#8221; and &#8220;cryptocurrency&#8221; don&#8217;t appear on the Yat website. Jain doesn&#8217;t think that&#8217;s compelling to average consumers &#8212; he believes in progressive decentralization, which explains why Yats are currently purchased with dollars, not ethereum.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;Something we think is really funny about the cryptocurrency world is that anyone who&#8217;s a part of it spends a lot of time talking about databases,&#8221; Jain said. &#8220;People don&#8217;t care about databases. When&#8217;s the last time you went to a website and it said &#8216;powered by MySQL&#8217;?&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Y.at, however, was registered at a <a href="https://www.101domain.com/at.htm">traditional internet registrar</a>, not on the blockchain.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is laying the foundation &#8212; there are certain elements of the vision that are certainly more of a social contract than actual implementation at this point in time,&#8221; says Jain. &#8220;But this is the vision that we&#8217;ve set forth, and we&#8217;re working continuously towards that goal.&#8221;</p>
<p>Still, until Yat becomes more decentralized, it can&#8217;t yet give users the complete control it aspires to. At present, the <a href="https://y.at/terms">Terms &amp; Conditions</a> give Yat the authority to terminate or suspend users at its discretion, but the company claims it hasn&#8217;t yet booted anyone from the system.</p>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">As Yat becomes more decentralized, our terms and conditions won&#8217;t be important,&#8221; Jain said. &#8220;This is the nature of pursuing a progressive decentralization strategy.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>In its &#8220;generation zero&#8221; phase (an open beta), Yat claims to have sold almost $20 million worth of emoji identities. Now, as the waitlist to get a Yat ends, Yat is posting some rare emoji identities on <a href="https://opensea.io/">OpenSea</a>, the NFT marketplace that recently reached a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/nft-market-opensea-hits-1-5-billion-valuation/">valuation of $1.5 billion</a>.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184092" style="width: 526px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184092" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2184092" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?w=680" alt="" width="516" height="516" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png 720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/210729102850_42061966-5491-454a-9ef6-ca79a13503fb.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 516px) 100vw, 516px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184092" class="wp-caption-text">A still image of a Yat visualizer creation</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;For the first time ever, we&#8217;re going to be auctioning some Yats on OpenSea, and we&#8217;re going to be launching minting of Yats on Ethereum,&#8221; Jain said. Before minting Yats as NFTs, users can create a digital art landscape for their Yats through a Visualizer. These features, as well as new emojis in the Yat emoji set, will launch this evening at a virtual event called <a href="https://yativerse.y.at/pages/yat-horizon">Yat Horizon</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">Yat Creators will now have more rights,&#8221; Jain said about the new ability to mint Yats as NFTs. &#8220;We are going to continue to pursue progressive decentralization until we achieve our ultimate goal: making Yat the best self-directed, self-sovereign identity system for all.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Consumers have a demonstrated interest in retaining greater privacy on the internet &#8212; data shows that in iOS 14.5, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/05/96-of-us-users-opt-out-of-app-tracking-in-ios-14-5-analytics-find/">96% of users</a> opted out of ad tracking. But the decentralization movement hasn&#8217;t yet been able to market its privacy advantages to the mainstream. Yat helps solve this problem because even if you don&#8217;t understand what blockchain means, you understand that having a personal string of emojis is pretty fun. But, before you spend $425,000 on a single-emoji username, keep in mind that Yat&#8217;s vision will only completely materialize with the advent of Web 3.0, and we don&#8217;t yet know when or if that will happen.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gfF0hDrq1d"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/building-customer-first-relationships-in-a-privacy-first-world-is-critical/">Building customer-first relationships in a privacy-first world is critical</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Building customer-first relationships in a privacy-first world is critical&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/building-customer-first-relationships-in-a-privacy-first-world-is-critical/embed/#?secret=gfF0hDrq1d" data-secret="gfF0hDrq1d" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/yat-thinks-emoji-identities-can-be-a-thing-and-it-has-20m-in-sales-to-back-it-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183855</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calendly CEO Tope Awotona is joining us at Disrupt 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/calendly-ceo-tope-awotona-is-joining-us-at-disrupt-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/calendly-ceo-tope-awotona-is-joining-us-at-disrupt-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 18:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brynn Putnam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chamath Palihapitiya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pete buttigieg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewart butterfield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tope Awotona]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184066</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Early Bird Tickets to Disrupt end today, Friday, July 30. Book your tickets now! ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It all seems so simple. Instead of the dreaded back-and-forth on email, what if there was a solution that helped two parties (or multiple parties) schedule a call or a hangout?</p>
<p>Calendly was born out of that question. Today, the company is worth more than $3 billion, according to reports, and has more than 10 million users. The growth of the product is insane, with more than 1,000% growth from last year.</p>
<p>But that kind of success doesn&#8217;t come without hard work and dedication.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>To hear more about the journey from bootstrapped to billions, Calendly founder and CEO Tope Awotona will <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?utm_medium=editorialpost&amp;utm_campaign=disrupt2021&amp;utm_content=topespeakerpost&amp;utm_source=tcwebsite&amp;promo=topespeakerpost&amp;display=TRUE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">join us at Disrupt this September</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?utm_medium=editorialpost&amp;utm_campaign=disrupt2021&amp;utm_content=topespeakerpost&amp;utm_source=tcwebsite&amp;promo=topespeakerpost&amp;display=TRUE" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient"><strong>P.S. Early Bird Tickets to Disrupt end today, Friday, July 30. Book your tickets now! </strong></span></a></p>
<p>Awotona put his entire life savings into Calendly and managed to bootstrap it for years before taking a $350 million funding round led by OpenView and Iconiq.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aFprKzAjzI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/how-atlantas-calendly-turned-a-scheduling-nightmare-into-a-3b-startup/">How Atlanta&#8217;s Calendly turned a scheduling nightmare into a $3B startup</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How Atlanta&#8217;s Calendly turned a scheduling nightmare into a $3B startup&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/how-atlantas-calendly-turned-a-scheduling-nightmare-into-a-3b-startup/embed/#?secret=aFprKzAjzI" data-secret="aFprKzAjzI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>We&#8217;ll chat with Awotona about the early days of Calendly, how he navigated the hypergrowth phase, what made him choose to finally take institutional funding, his thoughts on pricing and packaging, and much more.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MS2WQJVTdH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/08/bootstrapping-managing-product-led-growth-and-knowing-when-to-fundraise/">Bootstrapping, managing product-led growth and knowing when to fundraise</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bootstrapping, managing product-led growth and knowing when to fundraise&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/08/bootstrapping-managing-product-led-growth-and-knowing-when-to-fundraise/embed/#?secret=MS2WQJVTdH" data-secret="MS2WQJVTdH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Awotona joins an incredible roster of speakers, including Secretary of Transportation Pete Buttigieg, Mirror&#8217;s Brynn Putnam, Chamath Palihapitiya, Slack CEO Stewart Butterfield <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/#0affacde-e0ed-4a3c-abc4-988cb1c0eb3e" target="_blank" rel="noopener">and more</a>. Plus, Disrupt features the legendary Startup Battlefield competition, where startups from across the globe compete for $100,000 and eternal glory.</p>
<p>Disrupt’s virtual format provides plenty of opportunity for questions, so come prepared to ask the experts about the issues that keep you up at night.</p>
<p>One post can’t possibly contain all of Disrupt&#8217;s events. Don’t miss the epic Startup Battlefield competition, hundreds of early-stage startups exhibiting in the Startup Alley expo area, special breakout sessions — like the Pitch Deck Teardown — and so much more.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?utm_medium=editorialpost&amp;utm_campaign=disrupt2021&amp;utm_content=topespeakerpost&amp;utm_source=tcwebsite&amp;promo=topespeakerpost&amp;display=TRUE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> offers tons of opportunities. Don’t miss out on the first one — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?utm_medium=editorialpost&amp;utm_campaign=disrupt2021&amp;utm_content=topespeakerpost&amp;utm_source=tcwebsite&amp;promo=topespeakerpost&amp;display=TRUE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">buy your Disrupt pass</a> today, <strong>July 30, by 11:59 p.m. (PDT)</strong> for less than $100. It’s a sweet deal!</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at Disrupt 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-c8cece2948fb67f4dcb74c1c2da58b16"
			width="99%"
			height="1300"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/c8cece2948fb67f4dcb74c1c2da58b16"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-c8cece2948fb67f4dcb74c1c2da58b16')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-c8cece2948fb67f4dcb74c1c2da58b16'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/calendly-ceo-tope-awotona-is-joining-us-at-disrupt-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184066</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
