<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 06:17:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>RepairSmith raises $42M Series B to bring auto repair to customers&#8217; doorsteps</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/repairsmith-raises-42m-series-b-to-bring-auto-repair-to-customers-doorsteps/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/repairsmith-raises-42m-series-b-to-bring-auto-repair-to-customers-doorsteps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 10:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[auto repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repairsmith]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191277</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Needing to get your car fixed is like having a toothache: It’s painful, hard to ignore and likely means someone messing around under the hood. RepairSmith, launched in 2019, wants to make that process a little smoother through its mobile auto repair service that sends a mechanic right to the driver’s home. The startup is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Needing to get your car fixed is like having a toothache: It’s painful, hard to ignore and likely means someone messing around under the hood. RepairSmith, launched in 2019, wants to make that process a little smoother through its mobile auto repair service that sends a mechanic right to the driver’s home.</p>
<p>The startup is already in seven states and now, with a new round of $42 million funding, is looking to grow its operations to encompass every major metropolitan area in the U.S. by the end of 2022.</p>
<p>“Fundamentally what we&#8217;re doing here is e-commerce plus logistics,” Milne said. “We&#8217;re trying to disrupt probably the biggest retail industry that&#8217;s untouched by tech.” RepairSmith aims to do so by letting customers book an appointment online and have a mechanic perform an inspection or repair from their driveway, a far cry from the conventional auto repair process.</p>
<p>RepairSmith was incepted at Mercedes-Benz’ incubator program, and the company’s first few funding rounds were furnished solely by the automaker. Now that RepairSmith has a solid footing in multiple metros, with the data to show it’s an attractive business, the company decided to bring in new investors TI Capital, Porsche Ventures and Spring Mountain Capital to the latest Series B, in addition to Mercedes.</p>
<p>“We built this business from the beginning to be multibrand as an industry solution,” RepairSmith CEO Joel Milne told TechCrunch in an interview. “While [Mercedes] seeded it, it was never meant to be a Mercedes solution. That was always the intent.”</p>
<p>Depending on the market, users can have a repair technician at their home in as little as one or two days. Milne said around 90% of appointments can be completed on-site. For those remaining 10% or so, the customer can either drive their car (or if it’s not drivable) have it towed to a network of auto body shops that have partnered with RepairSmith.</p>
<p>In some cases, the customer knows what is wrong with their car in advance, but when they don’t, RepairSmith schedules an inspection visit and generates a quote for the service after.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company launched focusing on the consumer market, but it’s also expanded to working with fleets, rental car agencies and dealerships. A little over a quarter of the company’s services are now B2B. “They’re both equally big markets and very attractive opportunities for us,” Milne said. “It&#8217;s really a function of, we focused on consumer first, but part of this capital raise [is] we&#8217;re aggressively growing out our B2B services.”</p>
<p>All RepairSmith technicians are also employees, rather than contractors, a decision that ultimately came down to wanting to attract top talent.</p>
<p>“We didn&#8217;t feel that we could be competitive in recruiting the quality of technicians we were looking for, not giving them standard employment terms. All technicians at repair shops are employees today, and that&#8217;s the market that we compete in for labor,” Milne said. He added that the company also didn’t want to have to deal with legal issues over what counts as a contractor versus employee.</p>
<p>The startup has big goals — entering all major metro markets by the end of next year, which doesn’t just include hiring more auto technicians but also continuing to improve the company’s software and logistics platform, which it built from the ground up. Milne demurred on whether it might need additional capital to get there. “Ultimately, if the market is good, we&#8217;ll be looking for further investment to grow, whether it&#8217;s internationally, whether it&#8217;s to grow our service offering. But this raise gets us a long way on the way there, depending on how fast we want to go.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rFlruxFo1k"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/how-to-make-the-math-work-for-todays-sky-high-startup-valuations/">How to make the math work for today&#8217;s sky-high startup valuations</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to make the math work for today&#8217;s sky-high startup valuations&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/how-to-make-the-math-work-for-todays-sky-high-startup-valuations/embed/#?secret=rFlruxFo1k" data-secret="rFlruxFo1k" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/repairsmith-raises-42m-series-b-to-bring-auto-repair-to-customers-doorsteps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191277</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon rolls out India&#8217;s first celebrity voice on Alexa with Amitabh Bachchan</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/amazon-rolls-out-indias-first-celebrity-voice-on-alexa-with-amitabh-bachchan/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/amazon-rolls-out-indias-first-celebrity-voice-on-alexa-with-amitabh-bachchan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 05:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alexa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon India]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191490</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon has rolled out India’s first celebrity voice feature on Alexa with the nation’s biggest movie star Amitabh Bachchan as the company makes a push to lure more users in the world’s second-most populated nation. The company, which rolled out the voice of Samuel Jackson on Alexa in the U.S. in 2019, said users in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Amazon has rolled out India’s first celebrity voice feature on Alexa with the nation’s biggest movie star Amitabh Bachchan as the company makes a push to lure more users in the world’s second-most populated nation.</p>
<p>The company, which rolled out the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/25/alexa-gets-an-improved-voice-and-can-now-sound-like-samuel-l-jackson-too/">voice of Samuel Jackson on Alexa in the U.S. in 2019</a>, said users in India can add the Bollywood legend’s voice to their Echo devices or Amazon shopping app for an introductory price of 149 Indian rupees ($2) for the first year. (Starting second year, the annual price will move to $4.)</p>
<p>The 78-year-old actor is providing Amazon with stories from his life, a selection of poems from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harivansh_Rai_Bachchan">his father</a>, tongue twisters, and motivational quotes. Amazon customers can also ask Alexa to play music, set alarms, get weather updates and get answers in Bachchan’s signature style.</p>
<p>And the company said it is also applying neural speech technology to make Alexa sound like Bachchan even if there&#8217;s no direct pre-recording. (Amit ji, remind me to ask you about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/13/india-orders-investigation-into-alleged-anti-competitive-practices-by-amazon-and-walmarts-flipkart/">Amazon&#8217;s antitrust situation in India</a> later today.)</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2191491" style="width: 1510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2191491" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2191491 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/amitabh-bachchan-alexa-amazon.jpg" alt="" width="1500" height="1473" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/amitabh-bachchan-alexa-amazon.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/amitabh-bachchan-alexa-amazon.jpg?resize=150,147 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/amitabh-bachchan-alexa-amazon.jpg?resize=300,295 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/amitabh-bachchan-alexa-amazon.jpg?resize=768,754 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/amitabh-bachchan-alexa-amazon.jpg?resize=680,668 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/amitabh-bachchan-alexa-amazon.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/amitabh-bachchan-alexa-amazon.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/amitabh-bachchan-alexa-amazon.jpg?resize=64,64 64w" sizes="(max-width: 1500px) 100vw, 1500px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2191491" class="wp-caption-text">Image credits: Amazon</p></div></p>
<p>“Working with Amazon to introduce my voice on Alexa was a new experience in bringing together the magic of voice technology and artistic creativity. I am excited that my well-wishers can now interact with me via this new medium, and looking forward to hear how they feel about this,” said Bachchan in a statement.</p>
<p>A household name, Bachchan emerged as Bollywood’s top star in the 1970s playing characters who battled corruption and social injustice. He has also done scores of advertisements for brands and initiatives from everything including hair oil, biscuits, cold drinks, jewelry, state tourism, banks to UNICEF-backed polio vaccination campaign.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company announced its collaboration with Bollywood legend last year. But the pandemic forced Amazon&#8217;s engineering teams to work remotely for this project. There were also additional complications. Globally, users can trigger Alexa with one-word wake alert. Alexa, do this, for instance. But in case of Bachchan, Amazon has introduce a two-word wake system to Alexa. &#8220;Amit ji.&#8221; (Where &#8216;ji&#8217; is a Hindi word to pay respect.)</p>
<p>“At Amazon &amp; Alexa, we consistently innovate on behalf of our customers and building the Amitabh Bachchan celebrity voice experience with one of India’s most iconic voices has been a labor of love. Creating the world’s first bi-lingual celebrity voice required us to invent &amp; re-invent across almost every element of speech science – wake word, speech recognition, neural text-to-speech and more,” said Puneesh Kumar, Country Leader for Alexa, Amazon India, in a statement.</p>
<p>“While we are proud of the many India-first innovations and desi-delighters in this, it’s still Day 1 and we will continue to enrich this experience as science evolves.”</p>
<p>India is a key overseas market for Amazon, which has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/14/amazon-to-invest-1-billion-to-digitize-small-businesses-in-india/">deployed over $6.5 billion</a> and is increasingly <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/amazon-backs-indian-wealth-management-service-smallcase-in-40-million-funding/">making investment in startups</a>. This isn&#8217;t the first time the company has signed up Bachchan for one of its businesses. The company last year acquired Bachchan&#8217;s &#8220;Gulabo Sitabo&#8221; movie rights for streaming globally on Prime Video.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/amazon-rolls-out-indias-first-celebrity-voice-on-alexa-with-amitabh-bachchan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191490</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple is changing Mail Privacy Protection and email marketers must prepare</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apple-is-changing-mail-privacy-protection-and-email-marketers-must-prepare/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apple-is-changing-mail-privacy-protection-and-email-marketers-must-prepare/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 23:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Ecommerce and D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online privacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191327</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Effectively leveraging email analytics and data to inform future emails and multichannel campaigns requires marketers to start preparing now.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Melissa Sargeant</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/mhsargeant">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Melissa Sargeant is CMO at <a href="https://www.litmus.com/">Litmus</a>, where she runs worldwide marketing initiatives including corporate and product branding, demand generation, product marketing, public relations and event management. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The most critical phase in a marketing team’s mix and overall multichannel strategy happens after you press send on an email campaign: the post-send and performance pillars of email marketing.</p>
<p>During this phase, marketers should gather metrics and data to guide insights impacting future emails and entire marketing campaigns. Email metrics can influence ad messaging and social posts and guide the design, content and product marketing teams. When used strategically, these metrics increase email programs’ ROI while raising marketing channel and workflow efficiency and effectiveness.</p>
<p>As one of the most lucrative channels for reaching target audiences — for every dollar invested in email marketing, brands <a href="https://www.litmus.com/2020StateofEmail">receive $36 in return</a> — email enables brands to reach their core consumer base: email subscribers.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Just as they adjusted to accommodate the evolution from print to digital, marketers must pivot and accommodate this new disruption to remain competitive — and successful.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>They have opted-in to email touch points because they <em>want</em> to hear from the brand. By applying these insights via analytics, marketers optimize marketing spend and messaging to hit business goals.</p>
<p>Email impacts marketing strategy and enables better overall business success. It’s the lifeblood of an effective multichannel campaign. However, Apple’s Mail Privacy Protection — announced earlier this summer with its iOS 15 update — attempts to eliminate metrics and data associated with email.</p>
<p>According to the <a href="https://emailclientmarketshare.com/">Litmus Email Client Market Share</a>, in 2020, Apple iPhone, Apple Mail and Apple iPad accounted for nearly half of all email opens. Lacking these insights will create marketing roadblocks for segmented and personalized touch points. Marketers and businesses must prepare by adjusting email strategy and processes before the update occurs.</p>
<p>Companies and consumers have talked about privacy quite a bit lately. Companies fearing breaches, reputation damage and potentially lost revenue want to protect consumer data. Consumer awareness of privacy concerns has grown, too.</p>
<p>In a 2021 survey, <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1228234/online-privacy-concerns-us/">over half the respondents</a> expressed more concern about online privacy than in 2020. Consumers expect brands to demonstrate trustworthiness before they willingly share sensitive personal information.</p>
<p>Recognizing an increased desire for better privacy control, Apple revealed new privacy protections in its iOS 15 update, including its Mail Privacy Protection. Apple Mail users may hide their IP addresses, locations and additional data from senders, preventing brands from pulling information like open rates and location. <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/06/apple-advances-its-privacy-leadership-with-ios-15-ipados-15-macos-monterey-and-watchos-8/">Apple said that</a> “Mail Privacy Protection stops senders from using invisible pixels to collect information about the user.”</p>
<p>What does this update mean for marketers? The potential disappearance of a critical phase in the marketing mix and multichannel strategy: the post-send and performance pillars of email marketing. No open-rate-specific data &#8212; the brand will appear to have a 100% open rate.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apple-is-changing-mail-privacy-protection-and-email-marketers-must-prepare/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191327</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook releases a glimpse of its most popular posts, but we don&#8217;t learn much</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/facebook-widely-viewed-content-reports/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/facebook-widely-viewed-content-reports/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 22:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[misinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New-York-Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news feed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The New York Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191406</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook is out with a new report collecting the most popular posts on the platform, responding to critics who believe the company is deliberately opaque about its top-performing content. Facebook&#8217;s new &#8220;widely viewed content reports&#8221; will come out quarterly, reflecting most viewed top News Feed posts in the U.S. every three months — not exactly [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook is out with a new report collecting the most popular posts on the platform, responding to critics who believe the company is deliberately opaque about its top-performing content.</p>
<p>Facebook&#8217;s new &#8220;<a href="https://transparency.fb.com/data/widely-viewed-content-report/">widely viewed content reports</a>&#8221; will come out quarterly, reflecting most viewed top News Feed posts in the U.S. every three months — not exactly the kind of real-time data monitoring that might prove useful for observing emerging trends.</p>
<p>With the new data set, Facebook hopes to push back against criticism that its algorithms operate within a black box. But like its often misleading blogged rebuttals and the other sets of cherry-picked data it shares, the company&#8217;s latest gesture at transparency is better than nothing, but not particularly useful.</p>
<p>So what <em>do</em> we learn? According to the new data set, 87% of posts that people viewed in the U.S. during Q2 of this year didn&#8217;t include an outside link. That&#8217;s notable but not very telling since Facebook still has an incredibly massive swath of people sharing and seeing links on a daily basis.</p>
<p>YouTube is predictably the top domain by Facebook&#8217;s chosen metric of &#8220;content viewers,&#8221; which it defines as any account that saw a piece of content on the News Feed, though we don&#8217;t get anything in the way of potentially helpful granular data there. Amazon, Gofundme, TikTok and others also in the top 10, no surprises there either.</p>
<p>Things get weirder when Facebook starts breaking down its most viewed links. The top five links include a website for alumni of the Green Bay Packers football team, a random online CBD marketplace and reppnforchrist.com, an apparently prominent portal for Christianity-themed graphic T-shirts. The subscription <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/09/technology/epoch-media-right-wing-disinformation.html">page for the Epoch Times</a>, a site well known for spreading pro-Trump conspiracies and other disinformation, comes in at No 10, though it was beaten by a Tumblr link to two cats walking with their tails intertwined.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2191434" style="width: 1802px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2191434" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2191434 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fb-top-10.jpeg" alt="" width="1792" height="856" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fb-top-10.jpeg 1792w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fb-top-10.jpeg?resize=150,72 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fb-top-10.jpeg?resize=300,143 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fb-top-10.jpeg?resize=768,367 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fb-top-10.jpeg?resize=680,325 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fb-top-10.jpeg?resize=1536,734 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fb-top-10.jpeg?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1792px) 100vw, 1792px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2191434" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Yahoo and ABC News are the only prominent national media outlets that make the top 20 when the data is sliced and diced in this particular way. Facebook also breaks down which posts the most people viewed during the period with a list of mostly benign if odd memes, including one that reads &#8220;If your VAGINA [cat emoji] or PENIS [eggplant emoji] was named after the last TV show/Move u watched what would it be.&#8221;</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re wondering why Facebook chose to collect and present this set of data in this specific way, it&#8217;s because the company is desperately trying to prove a point: That its platform isn&#8217;t overrun by the political conspiracies and controversial right-wing personalities that make headlines.</p>
<p>The dataset is Facebook&#8217;s latest argument in its long feud with New York Times reporter Kevin Roose, who created a Twitter account that surfaces Facebook&#8217;s most engaging posts on a daily basis, as measured through the Facebook-owned social monitoring tool CrowdTangle.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">The top-performing link posts by U.S. Facebook pages in the last 24 hours are from:</p>
<p>1. Dan Rather<br />2. Ben Shapiro<br />3. Love Meow<br />4. Ben Shapiro<br />5. Dinesh D&#39;Souza<br />6. Ben Shapiro<br />7. Ben Shapiro<br />8. Sean Hannity<br />9. Fox News<br />10. Steven Crowder</p>
<p>&mdash; Facebook&#39;s Top 10 (@FacebooksTop10) <a href="https://twitter.com/FacebooksTop10/status/1425095560776667136?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 10, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>By the metric of engagement, Facebook&#8217;s list of top-performing posts in the U.S. are regularly dominated by far-right personalities and sites like <a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/7/28/22594550/newsmax-ratings-dive-explained">Newsmax</a>, which pushes election conspiracies that Facebook would prefer to distance itself from.</p>
<p>The company argues that Facebook posts with the most interactions don&#8217;t accurately represent the top content on the platform. Facebook insists that reach data, which measures how many people see a given post, is a superior metric, but there&#8217;s no reason that engagement data isn&#8217;t just as relevant if not more so.</p>
<p>&#8220;The content that’s seen by the most people isn’t necessarily the content that also gets the most engagement,&#8221; Facebook wrote, in a dig clearly aimed at Roose.</p>
<p>The platform wants to de-emphasize political content across the board, which isn&#8217;t surprising given its track record of amplifying Russian disinformation, violent far-right militias and the Stop the Steal movement, which culminated in deadly violence at the U.S. Capitol in January.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="M4PYxgd6cD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/facebook-capitol-riot-zuckerberg-sandberg-comments-hearing/">Zuckerberg blames Trump, not Facebook, for the Capitol attack</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Zuckerberg blames Trump, not Facebook, for the Capitol attack&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/facebook-capitol-riot-zuckerberg-sandberg-comments-hearing/embed/#?secret=M4PYxgd6cD" data-secret="M4PYxgd6cD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/14/technology/facebook-data.html">The New York Times previously reported</a>, Facebook actually scrapped plans to make its reach data widely available through a public dashboard over fears that even <em>that</em> version of its top-performing posts wouldn&#8217;t reflect well on the company.</p>
<p>Instead, the company opted to offer a taste of that data in a confusingly condensed quarterly report. The result shows plenty of inexplicable junk content (no really, what&#8217;s with the Packers site?), but less in the way of politics. Facebook&#8217;s cursory gesture of transparency notwithstanding, it&#8217;s worth remembering that nothing is stopping the company from letting people see a deeper, broader leaderboard of its most popular content. This isn&#8217;t that.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JiSiO6hlIv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/15/extra-crunch-members-save-money-with-partner-perks-and-event-discounts/">Extra Crunch members save money with Partner Perks and event discounts</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Extra Crunch members save money with Partner Perks and event discounts&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/15/extra-crunch-members-save-money-with-partner-perks-and-event-discounts/embed/#?secret=JiSiO6hlIv" data-secret="JiSiO6hlIv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HX4Kqn2fAT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/facebook-ad-observatory-nyu-researchers/">Facebook cuts off NYU researcher access, prompting rebuke from lawmakers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook cuts off NYU researcher access, prompting rebuke from lawmakers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/facebook-ad-observatory-nyu-researchers/embed/#?secret=HX4Kqn2fAT" data-secret="HX4Kqn2fAT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="19hun5hqWE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/02/2020-election-social-media-facebook-twitter-policies/">What social networks have learned since the 2016 election</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What social networks have learned since the 2016 election&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/02/2020-election-social-media-facebook-twitter-policies/embed/#?secret=19hun5hqWE" data-secret="19hun5hqWE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/facebook-widely-viewed-content-reports/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191406</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The hottest fintech market you aren&#8217;t paying attention to</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/the-hottest-fintech-market-you-arent-paying-attention-to/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/the-hottest-fintech-market-you-arent-paying-attention-to/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 22:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[african startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191079</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture-capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. For our Wednesday show this week, Natasha and Alex and Danny had colleague Tage Kene-Okafor on the show to chat about the burgeoning African startup scene. Tage has become TechCrunch&#8217;s key correspondent in the area, chronicling the continent&#8217;s expanding venture capital totals, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/3543f286-8568-406a-ace2-2164b697f54d?dark=false" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/equity/id1215439780">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture-capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>For our Wednesday show this week, <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/dannycrichton">Danny</a> had colleague <a href="https://twitter.com/ulonnaya">Tage Kene-Okafor</a> on the show to chat about the burgeoning African startup scene. Tage has become TechCrunch&#8217;s key correspondent in the area, chronicling the continent&#8217;s expanding venture capital totals, public company performance and startup ecosystem.</p>
<p>Given that we&#8217;ve paid attention to just how much money African startups are raising, we wanted to have Tage on to give us a better, deeper understanding of the continent&#8217;s technology activity. Here&#8217;s what we got into:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>The power of Y Combinator in Africa:</strong> Is the well-known American accelerator a kingmaker in Africa? Or are we merely seeing more of its activity thanks to our own information biases?</li>
<li><strong>Fintech as core focus:</strong> As in many markets, fintech investment and startup activity stand out in Africa. We wanted to better understand why that&#8217;s the case in Africa, and what startups are building in the realm of financial technology.</li>
<li><strong>African e-commerce:</strong> The continent&#8217;s e-commerce market is perhaps best known through the lens of Jumia, a public tech company that works in the sale of goods online, and their delivery. How quickly is e-commerce growing in Africa, and which startups could be the next breakouts? We asked Tage.</li>
</ul>
<p>Equity is back on Friday with our weekly news roundup!</p>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content"><em>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PDT, Wednesday, and Friday morning at 7:00 a.m. PDT, so subscribe to us on <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity">Overcast</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ">Spotify</a> and all the casts.</em></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="piano-recirculation-article-footer"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/the-hottest-fintech-market-you-arent-paying-attention-to/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191079</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: T-Mobile confirms &#8216;highly sophisticated cyberattack&#8217; affecting 47M customer accounts</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/daily-crunch-49/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/daily-crunch-49/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 22:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191325</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for August 18, 2021! Good news up top: A big welcome to Kate Park, who recently <a href="https://twitter.com/kateparknews/status/1427767529598976002">joined the TechCrunch family</a>. She’s helping expand our coverage of Asia, with a special eye on South Korea. Make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/kateparknews">follow her on Twitter</a> and say hello.</p>
<p>Now let’s talk Apple and crypto and startups! &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Apple under fire:</strong> Apple’s not having the world’s best day, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apple-walks-back-controversial-safari-changes-with-ios-15-beta-6-update/">retreating on a controversial browser design choice</a> while also coming under fresh criticism for its anti-CSAM system that, it turns out, suffers from hash collisions. Not sure what that means? Our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apples-csam-detection-tech-is-under-fire-again/">own Zack Whittaker has you covered</a>.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/crypto-world-shows-signs-of-being-rather-bullish/">Good news from crypto:</a></strong> In the wake of Coinbase’s direct listing, we’ve seen global venture capitalists invest in a number of crypto exchanges. Raising money is never a bad sign for any technology niche. But the good news from cryptoland is more extensive than just venture activity. TechCrunch explores.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/t-mobile-says-at-least-47m-current-and-former-customers-affected-by-data-breach/">T-Mobile hacked:</a></strong> The possible T-Mobile hack that we shared in Daily Crunch recently is real &#8212; and impacts tens of millions of customers. As TechCrunch notes, this is the “fifth time that T-Mobile was hacked in recent years.” Not good.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>Our newest TechCruncher has been hard at work, which means we can highlight some of her reporting already. Here’s Park on South Korean secondhand marketplace Danggeun Market and its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/17/south-korean-online-secondhand-marketplace-danggeun-market-raises-162m-at-a-2-7b-valuation/">recent $162 million round that values the company at $2.7 billion</a>.</p>
<p>Before we dive into the funding round rundown, Mayfield investor <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/what-is-happening-to-risk-taking-in-venture-capital/">Navin Chaddha wants to know what happened</a> to risky venture capital bets. His essay is a response to a particular piece from The Information. We’ve explored the concept before, but Chaddha’s notes are well worth reading.</p>
<p>Now, the rest of today’s key startup news:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/api-platform-postman-valued-at-5-6-billion-in-225-million-fundraise/"><strong>APIs are big business:</strong></a><strong> </strong>So big in fact, that API-delivered startups aren’t the only companies raising money off the model of building developer-friendly services. Postman just raised $225 million at a $5.6 billion valuation to help other developers build APIs. So that <em>other</em> developers can more easily plug into technology products. Postman competes with Stoplight and Kong, among others.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/mealworm-farming-company-beta-hatch-raises-10m/"><strong>Worm protein cometh:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Food tech is neat. Who doesn’t like that startups are working on all sorts of alternative proteins, right? Raising cows is trash for the environment, and we all know it. But what about insects? Beta Hatch just raised $10 million for its insect-focused protein work. Perhaps the future is crunchy.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/kaipod-learning-thinks-learning-pods-are-here-to-stay/"><strong>KaiPod bets on tiny schools:</strong></a><strong> </strong>One piece of the 2020 and 2021 boom in edtech startup activity involves pods, or “micro-schools.” Per our own Natasha Mascarenhas, Boston-based KaiPod is betting that the model is here to stay and is focusing on the homeschool market to start.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/one-banks-40m-to-offer-all-in-one-financial-services-to-the-middle-class/"><strong>Middle-income fintech?</strong></a><strong> </strong>One neat element of the world of fintech has been the use of financial technology to reduce the cost of financial services and bring more money-management tooling to underserved communities. One is not doing that. Instead, the company is building fintech for the middle class. The startup wants to build an “all-in-one” solution, Mary Ann Azevedo reports.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/floodmapp-climate-change-flooding/"><strong>Planning for a wet future:</strong></a> That’s what FloodMapp is doing, per Danny Crichton. The startup, based in Australia, “is aiming to wash out the old approaches to hydrology and predictive analytics and put in place a much more modern approach to help emergency managers and citizens know when the floods are coming.” Once you know what is coming, you can prepare, goes the idea.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/stacker-raises-20m-series-a-for-no-code-software-tool-for-business-units/"><strong>More venture wagers on no-code:</strong></a> The latest service hoping to take no-code app development mainstream is Stacker. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/stacker-raises-1-7m-to-help-nocoders-build-apps-from-spreadsheets/">You may have heard of them</a>. Ron Miller reports that the company just landed $20 million from a16z in its Series A round. As with some other services, Stacker lets users turn spreadsheets into apps. (Some startups are <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/spreadsheet-com-wants-to-put-apps-in-your-spreadsheet/">taking the opposite approach</a>, notably.)</li>
<li>Today in great startup names, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/17/rara-delivery-gets-3-25m-for-its-ambitious-on-demand-delivery-plans-in-indonesia/"><strong>RaRa Delivery just raised $3.25 million</strong></a>. The Indonesian startup wants to bring same-day delivery to its home market. Sequoia Capital India’s Surge program and East Ventures led the round.</li>
</ul>
<h2>How to establish a health tech startup advisory board</h2>
<p>Most startups could use an advisory board, but in health tech, it&#8217;s a core requirement.</p>
<p>Founders seeking to innovate in this area have a unique need for mentors who have experience navigating regulations, raising capital and managing R&amp;D, to name just a few areas.</p>
<p>Based on his own experience, Patrick Frank, co-founder and COO of PatientPartner, shared some very specific ideas about who to recruit, where to find them and how to fit them into your cap table.</p>
<p>&#8220;You want to leverage these individuals so you are able to focus on the full view of the company to ensure it is something that both the market and investors want at scale,&#8221; says Frank.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="o6WCjqjD0M"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/how-to-establish-a-health-tech-startup-advisory-board/">How to establish a health tech startup advisory board</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to establish a health tech startup advisory board&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/how-to-establish-a-health-tech-startup-advisory-board/embed/#?secret=o6WCjqjD0M" data-secret="o6WCjqjD0M" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/twitter-adds-support-for-twitter-spaces-to-its-rebuilt-api/"><strong>Twitter wants developers to build for its live-audio product:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Twitter Spaces is no passing fad at the social media giant, it appears. Twitter is adding Spaces to its recently rebuilt API, allowing external developers to extend its capabilities. Frankly, we think Twitter Spaces are pretty neat, so this is a welcome piece of news.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/amazon-backs-indian-wealth-management-service-smallcase-in-40-million-funding/"><strong>Amazon invests in India:</strong></a><strong> </strong>In the form of a $40 million Series C for Bangalore-based financial services startup smallcase. When we think about tech megacompanies that are active investors, Amazon isn’t high on the list, making this transaction more notable than most corporate venture deals.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend growth marketers who have expertise in SEO, social, content writing and more! If you’re a growth marketer, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re curious about how these surveys are shaping our coverage, check out this interview Anna Heim did with Ascendant co-founder Gus Ferguson and partner Alyssa Crankshaw, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/17/for-british-agency-ascendant-growth-marketing-is-much-more-than-a-set-of-tactics/">“For British agency Ascendant, growth marketing is much more than a set of tactics.”</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QN5sfI0r8G"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/17/for-british-agency-ascendant-growth-marketing-is-much-more-than-a-set-of-tactics/">For British agency Ascendant, growth marketing is much more than a set of tactics</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;For British agency Ascendant, growth marketing is much more than a set of tactics&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/17/for-british-agency-ascendant-growth-marketing-is-much-more-than-a-set-of-tactics/embed/#?secret=QN5sfI0r8G" data-secret="QN5sfI0r8G" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Community</h2>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/i/spaces/1yoKMAwakYnKQ?s=20"><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter wp-image-2189749 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/choose_poss.jpg?w=199" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/choose_poss.jpg 1838w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/choose_poss.jpg?resize=99,150 99w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/choose_poss.jpg?resize=199,300 199w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/choose_poss.jpg?resize=768,1160 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/choose_poss.jpg?resize=450,680 450w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/choose_poss.jpg?resize=1017,1536 1017w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/choose_poss.jpg?resize=1356,2048 1356w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/choose_poss.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" /></a></p>
<p>Join Danny Crichton on Thursday, August 19, at 2 p.m. PDT/5 p.m. EDT for a <a href="https://twitter.com/i/spaces/1yoKMAwakYnKQ?s=20">Twitter Spaces</a> interview with Sukhinder Singh Cassidy, author of <a href="https://www.choosepossibility.com/">“Choose Possibility: Take Risks and Thrive (Even When You Fail).”</a></p>
<h2>TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021?display=true&amp;promo=dailycrunchfree"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2127639 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TC_Disrupt_21_WebOverviewCard_2000x1155-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="591" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TC_Disrupt_21_WebOverviewCard_2000x1155-1.png 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TC_Disrupt_21_WebOverviewCard_2000x1155-1.png?resize=150,87 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TC_Disrupt_21_WebOverviewCard_2000x1155-1.png?resize=300,173 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TC_Disrupt_21_WebOverviewCard_2000x1155-1.png?resize=768,444 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TC_Disrupt_21_WebOverviewCard_2000x1155-1.png?resize=680,393 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TC_Disrupt_21_WebOverviewCard_2000x1155-1.png?resize=1536,887 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TC_Disrupt_21_WebOverviewCard_2000x1155-1.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>It’s almost that time when startup followers from around the world gather at our annual conference, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021?display=true&amp;promo=dailycrunchfree">Disrupt</a>, which will be held virtually again this year. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021?display=true&amp;promo=dailycrunchfree">Join the community</a> September 21-23 to expand your horizons and your network with founders and CEOs of Coinbase, Dapper Labs, GitLab, Canva and more. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021?display=true&amp;promo=dailycrunchfree">Attend for less than $100</a>, or you can get a free Innovator Pass if you are one of the first 10 people to register with promo code <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021?display=true&amp;promo=dailycrunchfree">DAILYCRUNCHFREE</a>. But you’ll want to hurry &#8212; it’s first come, first served, and once they’re gone, they’re gone!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/daily-crunch-49/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191325</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Would the math work if Databricks were valued at $38B?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/would-the-math-work-if-databricks-were-valued-at-38b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/would-the-math-work-if-databricks-were-valued-at-38b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 21:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data lakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Databricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rumors]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191330</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Databricks, the open-source data lake and data management powerhouse has been on quite a financial run lately. Today Bloomberg reported the company could be raising a new round worth at least $1.5 billion at an otherworldly $38 billion valuation. That price tag is up $10 billion from its last fundraise in February when it snagged [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://databricks.com">Databricks</a>, the open-source data lake and data management powerhouse has been on quite a financial run lately. Today <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-08-18/databricks-funding-will-bring-valuation-to-38-billion?srnd=technology-vp">Bloomberg reported</a> the company could be raising a new round worth at least $1.5 billion at an otherworldly $38 billion valuation. That price tag is up $10 billion from its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/databricks-raises-1b-at-28b-valuation-as-it-reaches-425m-arr/">last fundraise in February</a> when it snagged $1 billion at a $28 billion valuation.</p>
<p>Databricks declined to comment on the Bloomberg post and its possible new valuation.</p>
<p>The company has been growing like gangbusters, giving credence to the investor thesis that the more your startup makes, the more it is likely to make. Consider that Databricks closed 2020 with $425 million in annual recurring revenue, which in itself was up 75% from the previous year.</p>
<p>As revenue goes up so does valuation, and Databricks is a great example of that rule in action. In October 2019,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/22/databricks-announces-400m-round-on-6-2b-valuation-as-analytics-platform-continues-to-grow/"> the company raised $400 million</a> at a seemingly modest $6.2 billion valuation (if a valuation like that can be called modest). By February 2021, that had ballooned to $28 billion, and today it could be up to $38 billion if that rumor turns out to be true.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="H0C0O91lUx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/databricks-raises-1b-at-28b-valuation-as-it-reaches-425m-arr/">Databricks raises $1B at $28B valuation as it reaches $425M ARR</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Databricks raises $1B at $28B valuation as it reaches $425M ARR&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/databricks-raises-1b-at-28b-valuation-as-it-reaches-425m-arr/embed/#?secret=H0C0O91lUx" data-secret="H0C0O91lUx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>One of the reasons that Databricks is doing so well is it operates on a consumption model. The more data you move through the Databricks product family, the more money it makes, and with data exploding, it&#8217;s doing quite well, thank you very much.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that Databricks&#8217;s primary competitor, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/snowflakes-ipo-could-value-it-as-high-as-24b-salesforce-and-berkshire-to-invest/">Snowflake went public last year</a> and has a market cap of almost $83 billion. In that context, the new figure doesn&#8217;t feel quite so outrageous, But what does it mean in terms of revenue to warrant a valuation like that. Let&#8217;s find out.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>Valuation math</h2>
<p>Let’s rewind the clock and observe the company’s recent valuation marks and various revenue results at different points in time:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/22/databricks-announces-400m-round-on-6-2b-valuation-as-analytics-platform-continues-to-grow/">Q3 2019</a>: $200 million run rate, $6.2 billion valuation.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/14/databricks-crossed-350m-run-rate-in-q3-up-from-200m-one-year-ago/">Q3 2020</a>: $350 million run rate, no known valuation change.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/databricks-raises-1b-at-28b-valuation-as-it-reaches-425m-arr/">EoY 2020</a>: $425 million run rate, $28 billion valuation (Q1 valuation).</li>
<li>Q3 2021: Unclear run rate, possible $38 billion valuation.</li>
</ul>
<p>The company’s 2019 venture round gave Databricks a 31x run rate multiple. By the first quarter of 2021, that had swelled to a roughly 66x multiple if we compare its final 2020 revenue pace to its then-fresh valuation. Certainly software multiples were higher at the start of 2021 than they were in late 2019, but Databricks’s $28 billion valuation was still more than impressive; investors were betting on the company like it was going to be a key breakout winner, and a technology company that would go public eventually in a big way.</p>
<p>To see the company possibly raise more funds would therefore not be surprising. Presumably the company has had a good few quarters since its last round, given its history of revenue accretion. And there’s only more money available today for growing software companies than before.</p>
<p>But what to make of the $38 billion figure? If Databricks merely held onto its early 2021 run rate multiple, the company would need to have reached a roughly $575 million run rate, give or take. That would work out to around 36% growth in the last two-and-a-bit quarters. That works out to less than $75 million in new run rate per quarter since the end of 2020.</p>
<p>Is that possible? Yeah. The company added $75 million in run rate between Q3 2020 and the end of the year. So you can back-of-the-envelope the company’s growth to make a $38 billion valuation somewhat reasonable at a flat multiple. (There’s some fuzz in all of our numbers, as we are discussing rough timelines from the company; we’ll be able to go back and do more precise math once we get the Databricks S-1 filing in due time.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kxOaFOrQZf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/databricks-co-founder-and-ceo-ali-ghodsi-is-coming-to-tc-sessions-saas/">Databricks co-founder and CEO Ali Ghodsi is coming to TC Sessions: SaaS</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Databricks co-founder and CEO Ali Ghodsi is coming to TC Sessions: SaaS&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/databricks-co-founder-and-ceo-ali-ghodsi-is-coming-to-tc-sessions-saas/embed/#?secret=kxOaFOrQZf" data-secret="kxOaFOrQZf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>All this raises the question of whether Databricks should be able to command such a high multiple. There’s some precedent. Recently, public software company <a href="https://twitter.com/alex/status/1428004906133336074">Monday.com has a run rate multiple north of 50x,</a> for example. It earned that mark on the back of a strong first quarter as a public company.</p>
<p>Databricks securing a higher multiple while private is not crazy, though we wonder if the data-focused company is managing a similar growth rate. Monday.com grew 94% on a year-over-year basis in its most recent quarter.</p>
<p>All this is to say that you can make the math shake out for Databricks to raise at a $38 billion valuation, but built into that price is quite a lot of anticipated growth. Top quartile public software companies today trade for around 23x their forward revenues, and around 27x their present-day revenues, <a href="https://cloudindex.bvp.com/">per Bessemer</a>. To defend its possible new valuation when public, then, leaves quite a lot of work ahead of Databricks.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/databricks-co-founder-and-ceo-ali-ghodsi-is-coming-to-tc-sessions-saas/">company’s CEO, Ali Ghodsi</a>, will join us at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/">TC Sessions: SaaS on October 27th</a>, and we should know by then if this rumor is, indeed true. Either way, you can be sure we are going to ask him about it.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rGRf7ASW7O"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/why-one-databricks-investor-thinks-the-company-may-be-undervalued/">Why one Databricks investor thinks the company may be undervalued</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why one Databricks investor thinks the company may be undervalued&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/why-one-databricks-investor-thinks-the-company-may-be-undervalued/embed/#?secret=rGRf7ASW7O" data-secret="rGRf7ASW7O" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/would-the-math-work-if-databricks-were-valued-at-38b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191330</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Two senators urge the FTC to investigate Tesla over &#8216;Full Self-Driving&#8217; statements</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/two-senators-urge-the-ftc-to-investigate-tesla-over-full-self-driving-statements/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/two-senators-urge-the-ftc-to-investigate-tesla-over-full-self-driving-statements/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 20:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Autopilot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Trade Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[full self driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Highway Traffic and Safety Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191349</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two Democratic senators have asked the new chair of the Federal Trade Commission to investigate Tesla’s statements about the autonomous capabilities of its Autopilot and Full Self-Driving systems. The senators, Edward Markey (D-Mass.) and Richard Blumenthal (D-Conn.), expressed particular concern over Tesla misleading customers into thinking their vehicles are capable of fully autonomous driving. “Tesla’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Two Democratic senators have asked the new chair of the Federal Trade Commission to investigate Tesla’s statements about the autonomous capabilities of its Autopilot and Full Self-Driving systems. The senators, Edward Markey (D-Mass.) and Richard Blumenthal (D-Conn.), expressed particular concern over Tesla misleading customers into thinking their vehicles are capable of fully autonomous driving.</p>
<p>“Tesla’s marketing has repeatedly overstated the capabilities of its vehicles, and these statements increasingly pose a threat to motorists and other users of the road,” they said. “Accordingly, we urge you to open an investigation into potentially deceptive and unfair practices in Tesla’s advertising and marketing of its driving automation systems and take appropriate enforcement action to ensure the safety of all drivers on the road.”</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.blumenthal.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/2021.08.18%20-%20FTC%20-%20Tesla.pdf">their letter to new FTC Chair Lina Khan</a>, they point to a 2019 YouTube video Tesla posted to its channel, which shows a Tesla driving autonomously. The roughly two-minute video is titled “Full Self-Driving” and has been viewed more than 18 million times.</p>
<p><iframe title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tlThdr3O5Qo" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>&#8220;Their claims put Tesla drivers – and all of the travelling public – at risk of serious injury or death,” the senators wrote.</p>
<p>When it comes to Tesla and formal investigations, when it rains, it pours. The letter was published just two days after the National Highway Transportation Safety Administration said it had opened a preliminary investigation into incidents involving Teslas crashing into parked emergency vehicles.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ujpkrfI10f"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/u-s-safety-regulator-opens-investigation-into-tesla-autopilot-following-crashes-with-parked-emergency-vehicles/">US safety regulator opens investigation into Tesla Autopilot following crashes with parked emergency vehicles</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;US safety regulator opens investigation into Tesla Autopilot following crashes with parked emergency vehicles&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/u-s-safety-regulator-opens-investigation-into-tesla-autopilot-following-crashes-with-parked-emergency-vehicles/embed/#?secret=ujpkrfI10f" data-secret="ujpkrfI10f" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Lina Khan is the youngest person to ever chair the FTC. She’s widely considered the most progressive appointment in recent history, particularly for her scholarship on antitrust law. But should the FTC choose to investigate Tesla, the case would likely have nothing to do with antitrust law and instead fall under the purview of consumer protection. The FTC has the authority to investigate false or misleading claims from companies regarding their products.</p>
<p>This is not the first time prominent figures have called on the FTC to open an investigation into Tesla’s claims. The Center for Auto Safety and Consumer Watchdog, two special interest groups, also <a href="https://www.autosafety.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/CAS-and-CW-Letter-to-FTC-on-Tesla-Deceptive-Advertising.pdf">sent a letter</a> in 2018 to the commission over the marketing of Autopilot features. The following year, the NHTSA urged the FTC to investigate whether claims made by Tesla CEO Elon Musk on the Model 3’s safety “constitute[d] unfair or deceptive acts or practices.”</p>
<p>Tesla charges $10,000 for access to a “Full Self-Driving” option at the point of sale, or as a subscription. The company is currently testing beta version 9 of FSD with a few thousand drivers, but the senators take aim at the beta version, too. “After the [beta 9] update, drivers have posted videos online showing their updated Tesla vehicles making unexpected maneuvers that require human intervention to prevent a crash,” they write. “Mr. Musk’s tepid precautions tucked away on social media are no excuse for misleading drivers and endangering the lives of everyone on the road.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="i4CVNh4Tmt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/crypto-world-shows-signs-of-being-rather-bullish/">Crypto world shows signs of being rather bullish</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Crypto world shows signs of being rather bullish&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/crypto-world-shows-signs-of-being-rather-bullish/embed/#?secret=i4CVNh4Tmt" data-secret="i4CVNh4Tmt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/two-senators-urge-the-ftc-to-investigate-tesla-over-full-self-driving-statements/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191349</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to establish a health tech startup advisory board</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/how-to-establish-a-health-tech-startup-advisory-board/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/how-to-establish-a-health-tech-startup-advisory-board/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 19:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advisory board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[board member]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate governance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Consumer Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191113</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Three to five people is an ideal starting point for an advisory board, depending on the size and stage of your company.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Patrick Frank</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/itspatrickfrank">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Patrick Frank is the co-founder and COO of <a href="https://www.patientpartner.com/">PatientPartner</a>, a platform that connects pre-surgical patients with fully recovered patients who went through the same surgery. Frank has worked in consumer technology across industries including retail banking, law, real estate and healthcare. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">When you enter the health tech industry as a new startup, an advisory board is a crucial foundational step. A board can guide you through industry-specific nuances, help you make important decisions and prove your legitimacy to investors looking for a strong industry background.</p>
<p>An advisory board will be able to give you strategic insights about both your company and the wider healthcare and technology industries.</p>
<p>In my experience of raising capital, the unpredictable financial situation at the beginning of the pandemic meant we nearly lost our $2 million round, but came through with a committed $250,000, which we used to bring in about $500,000 in revenue.</p>
<p>Something that helped this process was building our advisory board and starting small — we didn’t go for all of healthcare but instead focused on two healthcare verticals. This allowed us to prove our concept, build case studies and win contracts with specific teams in our customers&#8217; companies.</p>
<p>It pays off to stay focused and prove your worth so that your advisory board members can champion you in niche markets, with the potential to expand in the future. For this reason, it’s important to identify the main intention behind your board, and exactly who should be on it.</p>
<h2>Who to recruit</h2>
<p>Three to five people is an ideal starting point for an advisory board, depending on the size and stage of your company. In health tech, you need more than just the healthcare perspective — you also need the insight of those who have already grown technology companies, perhaps outside of the industry. Our company’s board is an even split of two healthcare and two technology advisers, and, ideally, you want to find a fifth who is well versed in both industries.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			It pays off to stay focused and prove your worth so that your advisory board members can champion you in niche markets, with the potential to expand in the future.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>An M.D., a Ph.D. from a respected institution or a thought leader in your relevant field of healthcare is the most important asset to an advisory board. These are the highly decorated physicians who have strong connections and act as a reference for their peers.</p>
<p>They provide instant credibility for your company, help you get into the minds of both patients and healthcare providers, and can outline how various health systems work.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/how-to-establish-a-health-tech-startup-advisory-board/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191113</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter adds support for Twitter Spaces to its rebuilt API</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/twitter-adds-support-for-twitter-spaces-to-its-rebuilt-api/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/twitter-adds-support-for-twitter-spaces-to-its-rebuilt-api/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 18:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real time Web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Speaker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[text messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter Spaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191186</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter is rolling out changes to its newly rebuilt API that will allow third-party developers to build tools and other solutions specifically for its audio chatroom product, Twitter Spaces. The company today announced it&#8217;s shipping new endpoints to support Spaces on the Twitter API v2, with the initial focus on enabling discovery of live or [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter is rolling out changes to its newly rebuilt API that will allow third-party developers to build tools and other solutions specifically for its audio chatroom product, Twitter Spaces. The company today <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/developer/en_us/topics/tools/2021/shape-the-future-of-twitter-spaces">announced</a> it&#8217;s shipping new <a href="https://twittercommunity.com/t/introducing-new-spaces-endpoints-on-the-twitter-api-v2/158213">endpoints</a> to support Spaces on the Twitter API v2, with the initial focus on enabling discovery of live or scheduled Spaces. This may later be followed by an API update that will make it possible for developers to build out more tools for Spaces&#8217; hosts.</p>
<p>The company<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/16/twitter-introduces-a-new-fully-rebuilt-developer-api-launching-next-week/"> first introduced its fully rebuilt API</a> last year, with the goal of modernizing its developer platform while also making it easier to add support for Twitter&#8217;s newer features at a faster pace. The new support for Twitter Spaces in the API is one example of that plan now being put into action.</p>
<p>With the current API update, Twitter hopes developers will build new products that enable users &#8212; both on and off Twitter &#8212; to find Twitter Spaces more easily, the company says. This could potentially broaden the reach of Spaces and introduce its audio chats to more people, which could give Twitter a leg up in the increasingly competitive landscape for audio-based social networking. Today, Twitter Spaces isn&#8217;t only taking on Clubhouse, but also the audio chat experiences being offered by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/facebook-officially-launches-live-audio-rooms-and-podcasts-in-the-u-s/">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/BobbyAllyn/status/1376974352994856961">Discord</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/reddit-unveils-its-clubhouse-clone-reddit-talk/">Reddit</a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22451481/public-app-trading-stocks-live-audio">Public.com</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/spotify-launches-its-live-audio-app-and-clubhouse-rival-spotify-greenroom/">Spotify</a> and smaller social apps.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6iIJEdB7qF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/spotify-launches-its-live-audio-app-and-clubhouse-rival-spotify-greenroom/">Spotify launches its live audio app and Clubhouse rival, Spotify Greenroom</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Spotify launches its live audio app and Clubhouse rival, Spotify Greenroom&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/spotify-launches-its-live-audio-app-and-clubhouse-rival-spotify-greenroom/embed/#?secret=6iIJEdB7qF" data-secret="6iIJEdB7qF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>According to Twitter, developers will gain access to two new endpoints, Spaces lookup and Spaces search, which allow them to lookup live and scheduled Spaces using specific criteria &#8212; like the Spaces ID, user ID or keywords. The Spaces lookup endpoint also offers a way to begin to understand the public metadata and metrics associated with a Space, like the participant count, speaker count, host profile information, detected language being used, start time, scheduled start time, creation time, status and whether the Space is ticketed or not, Twitter tells us.</p>
<p>To chose which Spaces functionality to build into its API first, Twitter says it spoke to developers who told the company they wanted functionality that could help people discover Spaces they may find interesting and set reminders for attending. Developers said they also want to build tools that would allow Spaces hosts to better understand how well their audio chats are performing. But most of these options aren&#8217;t yet available with today&#8217;s API update. Twitter only said it&#8217;s &#8220;exploring&#8221; other functionality &#8212; like tools that would allow developers to integrate reminders into their products, as well as those that would be able to surface certain metrics fields available in the API or allow developers to build analytics dashboards.</p>
<p>These ideas for other endpoints haven&#8217;t yet gained a spot on Twitter&#8217;s Developer Platform <a href="https://trello.com/b/myf7rKwV/twitter-developer-platform-roadmap">Roadmap</a>, either.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Twitter also told us it&#8217;s not working on any API endpoints that would allow developers to build standalone client apps for Twitter Spaces, as that&#8217;s not something in which its developer community expressed interest.</p>
<p>Several developers have been participating in a weekly Spaces hosted by Daniele Bernardi from Twitter&#8217;s Spaces team, and were already clued in to coming updates. Developers with access to the v2 API will be able to begin building with the new endpoints starting today, but none have new experiences ready to launch at this time. Twitter notes Bernardi will also host <a href="https://twitter.com/i/spaces/1djxXqNqWNNKZ">another Spaces event</a> today at 12 PM PT to talk in more detail about the API update and what&#8217;s still to come.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BA5PytJeGW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/01/twitters-acquisition-strategy-eat-the-public-conversation/">Twitter&#8217;s acquisition strategy: Eat the public conversation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter&#8217;s acquisition strategy: Eat the public conversation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/01/twitters-acquisition-strategy-eat-the-public-conversation/embed/#?secret=BA5PytJeGW" data-secret="BA5PytJeGW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/twitter-adds-support-for-twitter-spaces-to-its-rebuilt-api/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191186</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple&#8217;s CSAM detection tech is under fire — again</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apples-csam-detection-tech-is-under-fire-again/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apples-csam-detection-tech-is-under-fire-again/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 18:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[algorithms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitHub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iCloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law enforcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Password]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Python]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sha-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tim Cook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191246</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple has encountered monumental backlash to a new child sexual abuse material (CSAM) detection technology it announced earlier this month. The system, which Apple calls NeuralHash, has yet to be activated for its billion-plus users, but the technology is already facing heat from security researchers who say the algorithm is producing flawed results. NeuralHash is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple has encountered monumental backlash to a new child sexual abuse material (CSAM) detection technology it announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/apple-icloud-photos-scanning/">earlier this month</a>. The system, which Apple calls NeuralHash, has yet to be activated for its billion-plus users, but the technology is already facing heat from security researchers who say the algorithm is producing flawed results.</p>
<p>NeuralHash is designed to identify known CSAM on a user&#8217;s device without having to possess the image or knowing the contents of the image. Because a user&#8217;s photos stored in iCloud are end-to-end encrypted so that even Apple can&#8217;t access the data, NeuralHash instead scans for known CSAM on a user&#8217;s device, which Apple <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/interview-apples-head-of-privacy-details-child-abuse-detection-and-messages-safety-features/?tpcc=ECTW2020">claims is more privacy friendly</a>, as it limits the scanning to just photos rather than other companies which scan all of a user&#8217;s file.</p>
<p>Apple does this by looking for images on a user&#8217;s device that have the same hash — a string of letters and numbers that can uniquely identify an image — that are provided by child protection organizations like <a href="https://www.missingkids.org/HOME">NCMEC</a>. If NeuralHash finds 30 or more matching hashes, the images are flagged to Apple for a manual review before the account owner is reported to law enforcement. Apple says the chance of a false positive is about one in one trillion accounts.</p>
<p>But security experts and privacy advocates have expressed concern that the system <a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2021/08/apples-plan-think-different-about-encryption-opens-backdoor-your-private-life">could be abused</a> by highly resourced actors, like governments, to implicate innocent victims or to manipulate the system to detect other materials that authoritarian nation states find objectionable. NCMEC called critics the &#8220;screeching voices of the minority,&#8221; according to a leaked memo distributed internally to Apple staff.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NJAAzospVB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/apple-icloud-photos-scanning/">Apple confirms it will begin scanning iCloud Photos for child abuse images</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple confirms it will begin scanning iCloud Photos for child abuse images&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/apple-icloud-photos-scanning/embed/#?secret=NJAAzospVB" data-secret="NJAAzospVB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Last night, Asuhariet Ygvar reverse-engineered Apple&#8217;s NeuralHash into a Python script and <a href="https://github.com/AsuharietYgvar/AppleNeuralHash2ONNX">published code to GitHub</a>, allowing anyone to test the technology regardless of whether they have an Apple device to test. In <a href="https://old.reddit.com//r/MachineLearning/comments/p6hsoh/p_appleneuralhash2onnx_reverseengineered_apple/">a Reddit post</a>, Ygvar said NeuralHash &#8220;already exists&#8221; in iOS 14.3 as obfuscated code, but was able to reconstruct the technology to help other security researchers understand the algorithm better before it&#8217;s rolled out to iOS and macOS devices later this year.</p>
<p>It didn&#8217;t take long before others tinkered with the published code and soon came the first <a href="https://github.com/AsuharietYgvar/AppleNeuralHash2ONNX/issues/1">reported</a> case of a &#8220;hash collision,&#8221; which in NeuralHash&#8217;s case is where two entirely different images produce the same hash. <a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/research/researchers/cory-cornelius.html">Cory Cornelius</a>, a well-known research scientist at Intel Labs, <a href="https://github.com/AsuharietYgvar/AppleNeuralHash2ONNX/issues/1#issue-973388387">discovered</a> the hash collision. Ygvar confirmed the collision a short time later.</p>
<p>Hash collisions can be a death knell to systems that rely on cryptography to keep them secure, such as encryption. Over the years several well-known password hashing algorithms, like MD5 and SHA-1, were <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/23/security-researchers-announce-first-practical-sha-1-collision-attack/">retired after collision attacks</a> rendered them ineffective.</p>
<p>Kenneth White, a cryptography expert and founder of the Open Crypto Audit Project, said <a href="https://twitter.com/kennwhite/status/1428035349155024903">in a tweet</a>: &#8220;I think some people aren&#8217;t grasping that the time between the iOS NeuralHash code being found and [the] first collision was not months or days, but a couple of hours.&#8221;</p>
<p>When reached, an Apple spokesperson declined to comment on the record. But in a background call where reporters were not allowed to quote executives directly or by name, Apple downplayed the hash collision and argued that the protections it puts in place — such as a manual review of photos before they are reported to law enforcement — are designed to prevent abuses. Apple also said that the version of NeuralHash that was reverse-engineered is a generic version, and not the complete version that will roll out later this year.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not just civil liberties groups and security experts that are expressing concern about the technology. A senior lawmaker in the German parliament <a href="https://appleinsider.com/articles/21/08/17/germany-writes-to-tim-cook-to-reconsider-csam-plans#:~:text=and%20confidential%20communication%2C%22-,according%20to,-Heise%20Online.%20The">sent a letter</a> to Apple chief executive Tim Cook this week saying that the company is walking down a &#8220;dangerous path&#8221; and urged Apple not to implement the system.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PrMze43qFi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/interview-apples-head-of-privacy-details-child-abuse-detection-and-messages-safety-features/">Interview: Apple’s head of Privacy details child abuse detection and Messages safety features</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Interview: Apple’s head of Privacy details child abuse detection and Messages safety features&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/interview-apples-head-of-privacy-details-child-abuse-detection-and-messages-safety-features/embed/#?secret=PrMze43qFi" data-secret="PrMze43qFi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apples-csam-detection-tech-is-under-fire-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191246</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is happening to risk-taking in venture capital?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/what-is-happening-to-risk-taking-in-venture-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/what-is-happening-to-risk-taking-in-venture-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 18:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national venture capital association]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PitchBook Data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sam Lessin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191164</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The irony is that there’s never been a better time to be an inception investor given lower capital needs of getting from idea to Series A milestones.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Navin Chaddha</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/navinchaddha">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Navin Chaddha is managing partner at <a href="https://www.mayfield.com/">Mayfield</a>, an inception and early-stage investor with more than 50 years of a people-first investing philosophy.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/17/biology-as-technology-will-reinvent-trillion-dollar-industries/">Biology as technology will reinvent trillion-dollar industries</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/15/the-renaissance-of-silicon-will-create-industry-giants/">The renaissance of silicon will create industry giants</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Sam Lessin’s <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/the-end-of-venture-capital-as-we-know-it">post</a> in The Information, “The End of Venture Capital as We Know It,” prompted heated debate in Silicon Valley. He argued that the arrival of new players with large amounts of capital is changing the landscape of late-stage investing for venture capitalists and forcing VCs to “enter the bigger pond as a fairly small fish, or go find another small pond.”</p>
<p>But there’s another important trend developing in venture capital that has even more significant consequences than whether VCs are being forced to fight with bigger, deeper pockets for late-stage investment opportunities. And that is the move away from what has always defined venture capital: taking risks on the earliest-stage companies.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			The VC industry at large, instead of taking risks at inception and in the early stages, is investing in later-stage companies where the concept is proven and companies have momentum.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>The data indicates investing in early-stage companies is decreasing rapidly. According to data from PitchBook and the National Venture Capital Association, as a percentage of total U.S. venture capital dollars invested, angel/seed stage has reduced from 10.6% to 4.9% over the last three years, early-stage has reduced from 36.5% to 26.1% during the same time period, while late-stage has drastically increased from 52.9% to 69%, coming (as Lessin pointed out) from new players such as hedge funds and mutual funds.</p>
<p>This is happening at a time when there has been a record rate of new business creation. According to the U.S. Census Bureau, seasonally adjusted monthly business applications have been around 500,000 per month from the second half of 2020 to June 2021, compared with 300,000 per month in the year preceding the pandemic.</p>
<p>This data should be a red flag. Venture capital is about investing in risk to help the most innovative, transformative ideas get from concept to a flourishing enterprise. But the VC industry at large, instead of taking risks at inception and in the early stages, is investing in later-stage companies where the concept is proven and companies have momentum.</p>
<p>Here, the skill is more about finance to determine how much to invest and at what valuation to hit a certain return threshold rather than having the ability to spot a promising founder with a breakthrough idea. There’s an important role for late-stage investing, but if that’s where too much of the industry’s focus is applied, we’ll stifle innovation and limit the pipeline of companies to invest in Series B and beyond in the future.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The irony is that there’s never been a better time to be an inception investor given lower capital needs of getting from idea to Series A milestones. Startup costs have been driven down with access to cloud, social, mobile and open-source technologies, allowing entrepreneurs to test ideas and build momentum with small pools of capital.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xzIKO9q1lv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/how-first-time-fund-managers-are-de-risking/">How first-time fund managers are de-risking</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How first-time fund managers are de-risking&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/how-first-time-fund-managers-are-de-risking/embed/#?secret=xzIKO9q1lv" data-secret="xzIKO9q1lv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This has spawned a golden age of innovation and many new trends are emerging, creating a large pool of companies that need money and support to take an idea and turn it into a flourishing business.</p>
<p>It’s also ironic that when we are judged for our prowess as VC investors, the only question that has ever mattered is who was the earliest investor, who had the genius to recognize a brilliant idea. It is not who led the last round(s) before an IPO.</p>
<p>This is not some esoteric argument about venture capital; there will be real consequences for our ability to innovate and invest in areas such as the renaissance of silicon, biology as technology, human-centered AI, unleashing the power of data, climate-friendly investing, saving lives, re-humanization of social media, blockchain and quantum computing.</p>
<p>The VC industry cannot forget its roots. In its early days, it served as the catalyst for the success of iconic companies such as Genentech, Apple, Microsoft, Netscape, Google, Salesforce, Amazon and Facebook. Without these companies, we would not have a biotech industry, the internet, the cloud, social media and mobile computing, all of which have dramatically changed how we live, play and work.</p>
<p>We can’t know the future, but with AI, machine learning and a new generation of semiconductors and materials, we certainly know profound change lies ahead. But it won’t happen if venture capital doesn’t play a major role at a company’s inception. We have to step up and do more to change the discouraging statistics above.</p>
<p>And it’s not just about individual firm glory: If we want the U.S. to maintain its leadership as the innovation engine of the world, the venture industry has to do more to support bold ideas at the earliest stages to give them a shot at succeeding. Maybe it’s time, as Lessin suggested, for VCs to “go find another small pond” or rather swim deeper in the one some of us are already in: the one that is full of inception-stage companies looking for investors who will partner with them throughout their journey.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HWQW1eBY4L"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/06/venture-capital-probably-isnt-dead/">Venture capital probably isn’t dead</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Venture capital probably isn’t dead&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/06/venture-capital-probably-isnt-dead/embed/#?secret=HWQW1eBY4L" data-secret="HWQW1eBY4L" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/what-is-happening-to-risk-taking-in-venture-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191164</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Waze with &#8216;PAW Patrol&#8217; voices sounds like a chill car ride</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/waze-with-paw-patrol-voices-sounds-like-a-chill-car-ride/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/waze-with-paw-patrol-voices-sounds-like-a-chill-car-ride/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 17:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waze]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191202</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Waze might have a way to keep your kids entertained during a drive without handing them a tablet: distract them with your navigation app. The company has added a PAW Patrol experience.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jon Fingas</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jon Fingas is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/17/ikea-will-sell-clean-energy-to-swedish-homes/">IKEA will sell clean energy to Swedish homes</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/uber-will-offer-free-rosetta-stone-language-courses-to-drivers/">Uber will offer free Rosetta Stone language courses to drivers</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Waze might have a way to keep your kids entertained during a drive without <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-new-fire-hd-10-tablets-plus-kids-pro-130029307.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1">handing them a tablet</a>: distract them with your navigation app. The company has <a href="https://medium.com/waze/ride-into-adventure-with-paw-patrol-a1972a0b23c8" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="22" data-v9y="1">added</a> a <em>PAW Patrol</em> experience to Waze that has the TV show&#8217;s Ryder guide you to your destination with help from Chase, Marshall and Skye. You can also switch your <a href="https://www.engadget.com/waze-design-brand-refresh-moods-130054677.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="23" data-v9y="1">Waze Mood</a> to replace the usual icon with Chase&#8217;s police car, Marshall&#8217;s fire truck or Skye&#8217;s aircraft.</p>
<p>The feature is available for a &#8220;limited time&#8221; to English users through the My Waze section in the app. It&#8217;s available on both Android and iOS.</p>
<p>This is a not-so-subtle plug for the upcoming <em>PAW Patrol</em> movie, but it could be helpful for keeping your young ones engaged. It might even encourage them to take an interest in the drive and the world outside the car window. Of course, it&#8217;s also easy to see this going very badly — the last thing you want is to have your kids shouting at the phone while you&#8217;re listening for directions. This might be best for children who tend to watch the show in raptured silence.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This post originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/waze-paw-patrol-navigation-164613580.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/waze-with-paw-patrol-voices-sounds-like-a-chill-car-ride/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191202</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Planet Labs and Google Cloud join forces in data analysis agreement</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/planet-labs-and-google-cloud-join-forces-in-data-analysis-agreement/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/planet-labs-and-google-cloud-join-forces-in-data-analysis-agreement/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 16:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Planet Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite constellation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite imagery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191196</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Satellite operator Planet Labs is beefing up its existing partnership with Google Cloud. Under a new agreement, Planet customers can use Google Cloud to store and process data, and access Google’s other products such as its data analytics warehouse BigQuery. The two companies’ collaboration stretches back to 2017, when Google sold its satellite imaging business, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Satellite operator Planet Labs is beefing up its existing partnership with Google Cloud. Under a new agreement, Planet customers can use Google Cloud to store and process data, and access Google’s other products such as its data analytics warehouse BigQuery.</p>
<p>The two companies’ collaboration stretches back to 2017, when <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/03/google-selling-terra-bella-satellite-imaging-business-to-planet/">Google sold</a> its satellite imaging business, Terra Bella, to Planet. As part of the sale agreement, Google also signed a multiyear contract with Planet to license Earth imaging for its use. Planet also uses Google Cloud for its own internal data processing and hosting.</p>
<p>This latest agreement will let <a href="https://www.planet.com/">Planet</a> customers use products like BigQuery to analyze large volumes of satellite imaging data, reflecting “a growing demand for planetary-scale satellite data analysis, powered by the cloud,” Planet said in a news release.</p>
<p>“Planet customers want scalable compute and storage,” Kevin Weil, Planet’s president of product and business, said. “Google Cloud customers want broader access to satellite data and analytics. This partnership is a win-win for both, as it helps customers transform their operations and compete in a digital-first world, powered by Planet’s unique data set.”</p>
<p>Planet operates a network of around 200 satellites &#8212; more than any government &#8212; and provides analytics services on the data it gathers. Last month, the company joined a slew of other space companies by announcing it was going public via a $2.8 billion merger with blank-check firm dMY Technology Group IV. The deal is anticipated to inject Planet with $545 million in cash, including a $200 million private-investment-in-public-equity from BlackRock-managed funds, Koch Strategic Platforms, Marc Benioff’s TIME Ventures and Google.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1kMbK0ekxy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/satellite-operator-planet-to-go-public-in-2-8b-spac-merger/">Satellite operator Planet to go public in $2.8B SPAC merger</a></p></bl<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>ockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Satellite operator Planet to go public in $2.8B SPAC merger&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/satellite-operator-planet-to-go-public-in-2-8b-spac-merger/embed/#?secret=1kMbK0ekxy" data-secret="1kMbK0ekxy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/planet-labs-and-google-cloud-join-forces-in-data-analysis-agreement/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191196</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: Tips on EB-1A and EB-2 NIW?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/dear-sophie-tips-on-eb-1a-and-eb-2-niw/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/dear-sophie-tips-on-eb-1a-and-eb-2-niw/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 16:06:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Future of Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B visa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2190702</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m on an H-1B in the U.S. I’ve been looking at the EB-1A and EB-2 NIW. I’m not sure if I would qualify for an EB-1A, but since I was born in India, I face a longer wait for an EB-2 NIW. Any tips?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/dear-sophie-can-i-hire-an-engineer-whose-green-card-is-being-sponsored-by-another-company/">Dear Sophie: Can I hire an engineer whose green card is being sponsored by another company?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/dear-sophie-which-immigration-options-allow-me-to-launch-my-own-startup/">Dear Sophie: Which immigration options allow me to launch my own startup?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>Extra Crunch members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Dear Sophie,</strong></p>
<p><strong>I’m on an H-1B living and working in the U.S. I want to apply for a green card on my own. I’m concerned about only relying on my current employer and I want to be able to easily change jobs or create a startup. I’ve been looking at the EB-1A and EB-2 NIW. </strong></p>
<p><strong>I’m not sure if I would qualify for an EB-1A, but since I was born in India, I face a much longer wait for an EB-2 NIW. Any tips on how to proceed?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Inventive from India</strong></p>
<p>Dear Inventive,</p>
<p>Thanks for your question. Take a listen to my <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/084-back-to-school-extraordinary-ability-bootcamp-part-1/">podcast episode</a> in which I discuss the latest tech immigration news and delve into the benefits and requirements of the <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/eb-1a-green-card/">EB-1A</a> green card for individuals of extraordinary ability and the <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/eb-1a-green-card/">EB-2 NIW</a> (National Interest Waiver) green card, which as you know are the main employment-based green cards for which individuals can self-sponsor.</p>
<p>I recommend you consult an experienced immigration attorney who can evaluate your abilities and accomplishments and assess your prospects for each green card. After an initial consultation with new clients, we’re able to provide a lot more detail to folks on their specific options since these are such individualized pathways.</p>
<p>There are some groups of people who might need every advantage. Those can include folks born in India or China, who might face long green card backlogs. Another such group includes people whose skills and accomplishments might be borderline for an EB-1A green card for extraordinary ability. In some cases &#8212; if eligible and to have every opportunity for green card security and to mitigate wait times as much as possible &#8212; our clients choose to file both the EB-1A and EB-2 NIW in parallel.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100312" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100312" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2100312" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg" alt="A composite image of immigration law attorney Sophie Alcorn in front of a background with a TechCrunch logo." width="1024" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=1536,1013 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Joanna Buniak / <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sophie Alcorn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>The EB-1A is the highest priority green card and the standard for qualifying is much higher than for the EB-2 NIW. And that means an EB-1A is typically quicker to get, which is particularly the case now: According to the <a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/legal/visa-law0/visa-bulletin/2021/visa-bulletin-for-august-2021.html">August 2021 Visa Bulletin</a>, there is no wait for an EB-1A green card regardless of country of birth, while only individuals who were born in India and have a <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/028-all-about-priority-dates/">priority date</a> of June 1, 2011 or earlier can proceed with their EB-2 NIW petition.</p>
<p>Please remember that the Visa Bulletin fluctuates and changes every month. Also, the EB-1A is currently eligible for premium processing on the I-140. Although there is talk to add this option to the EB-2 NIW one day, premium processing is not available for EB-2 NIW I-140s yet.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/dear-sophie-tips-on-eb-1a-and-eb-2-niw/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2190702</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Waymo Via is scaling up autonomous trucking operations in Texas, Arizona and California</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/waymo-via-is-scaling-up-autonomous-trucking-operations-in-texas-arizona-california/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/waymo-via-is-scaling-up-autonomous-trucking-operations-in-texas-arizona-california/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 16:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous trucking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo driver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo via]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2190828</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Waymo, Alphabet&#8217;s self-driving arm, is building a dedicated trucking hub in Dallas and partnering with Ryder for fleet management services in a two-pronged move to seriously scale up its autonomous trucking operations across Texas, Arizona and California. This news comes just a couple of months after Waymo announced a $2.5 billion raise that it would [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Waymo, Alphabet&#8217;s self-driving arm, is building a dedicated trucking hub in Dallas and partnering with Ryder for fleet management services in a two-pronged move to seriously scale up its autonomous trucking operations across Texas, Arizona and California.</p>
<p>This news comes just a couple of months after Waymo announced a<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/waymo-alphabets-self-driving-arm-raises-2-5b-in-second-external-investment-round/"> $2.5 billion raise</a> that it would use to continue growing its autonomous driving platform, the Waymo Driver, as well as its team. Waymo has been ramping up testing on the fifth generation of the Driver on Class 8 trucks, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/waymo-and-jb-hunt-partner-to-bring-autonomous-trucks-to-texas-in-new-pilot/">hauling freight for carriers like J.B. Hunt</a> along Interstate 45 between Houston and Fort Worth, Texas and working with<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/27/daimler-trucks-partners-with-waymo-to-build-self-driving-semi-trucks/"> Daimler Trucks</a> to develop a robust level 4 redundant vehicle platform, according to a spokesperson for the company. According to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/27/daimler-trucks-partners-with-waymo-to-build-self-driving-semi-trucks/">Society of Automotive Engineers</a>, level 4 autonomy means the vehicle can drive itself without a human but only in predefined areas.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TVnBDNwaK1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/waymo-and-jb-hunt-partner-to-bring-autonomous-trucks-to-texas-in-new-pilot/">Waymo and J.B. Hunt partner to bring autonomous trucks to Texas in new pilot</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Waymo and J.B. Hunt partner to bring autonomous trucks to Texas in new pilot&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/waymo-and-jb-hunt-partner-to-bring-autonomous-trucks-to-texas-in-new-pilot/embed/#?secret=TVnBDNwaK1" data-secret="TVnBDNwaK1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Waymo has already broken ground on the new 9-acre trucking hub, which will be built specifically for Waymo Via, the company&#8217;s autonomous trucking operations, in Dallas-Forth Worth to service one of the busiest corridors in the country. Designed for commercial use, the hub is expected to accommodate hundreds of trucks as the company scales in the region and amplifies larger and more complex autonomous testing. Waymo says it will help the company spread out operations in Texas beyond the I-45 and across the I-10 and I-20. The location is well situated to support long-haul routes across state borders and connect with Waymo&#8217;s Phoenix operations center. Waymo said it plans to move into the facility during the first half of next year.</p>
<p>This is where the Ryder partnership comes in. The Dallas hub will be a central launch point for testing not only the Waymo Driver, but also its transfer hub model, which is a mix of automated and manual trucking that optimizes transfer hubs near highways to ensure the Waymo Driver is sticking to main thoroughfares and human drivers are handling first and last mile deliveries. Scaling this model will require a high level of organization, and Ryder&#8217;s fleet management services and standardized fleet maintenance across over 500 facilities should be up to the job.</p>
<p>The partnership includes fleet maintenance, inspections and roadside assistance across all of the Waymo Via hubs and testing sites, including the new Dallas facility. Given Ryder&#8217;s size and influence and Waymo&#8217;s access to AV fleet data, the two companies will also work on a blueprint for autonomous truck maintenance and optimized performance.</p>
<p>“While this partnership initially focuses on fleet maintenance, we see many opportunities to collaborate on autonomous trucking operations in order to successfully deploy these trucks at scale,” said Karen Jones, chief marketing officer and head of new product development for Ryder, in a statement. “Already, we’ve collaborated on the layout and design of Waymo’s new Dallas facility to ensure it’s optimized for serviceability of trucks and for the transfer hub model they plan to pursue in the near future. Autonomous Class 8 technology is quickly taking hold, and Ryder is poised to become a leader — not only in servicing trucks but also in managing the unique logistics of autonomous operations.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aBCWnL1Kr9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-origin/">How Google&#8217;s self-driving car project accidentally spawned its robotic delivery rival</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How Google&#8217;s self-driving car project accidentally spawned its robotic delivery rival&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/nuro-ec1-origin/embed/#?secret=aBCWnL1Kr9" data-secret="aBCWnL1Kr9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/waymo-via-is-scaling-up-autonomous-trucking-operations-in-texas-arizona-california/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2190828</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple walks back controversial Safari changes with iOS 15 beta 6 update</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apple-walks-back-controversial-safari-changes-with-ios-15-beta-6-update/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apple-walks-back-controversial-safari-changes-with-ios-15-beta-6-update/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 16:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ios 7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191091</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple is slowly walking back its controversial decision to redesign mobile Safari in iOS 15 to show the address bar at the bottom of the screen, floating atop the page&#8217;s content. The revamp, which was largely meant to make it easier to reach Safari&#8217;s controls with one hand, has met with criticism as Apple&#8217;s other [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple is slowly walking back its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/apple-tweaks-controversial-ios-15-safari-changes-in-latest-beta/">controversial decision</a> to redesign mobile Safari in iOS 15 to show the address bar at the bottom of the screen, floating atop the page&#8217;s content. The revamp, which was largely meant to make it easier to reach Safari&#8217;s controls with one hand, has <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2021/07/safari_15_public_betas_for_mac_and_ios">met with criticism</a> as Apple&#8217;s other design choices actually made the new experience less usable than before. With the latest release of iOS 15 beta 6, Apple is responding to user feedback and complaints with the <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/ios-ipados-release-notes/ios-ipados-15-beta-release-notes">introduction</a> of yet another design that now shows the bottom tab bar below the page content, offering a more standardized experience for those who would have otherwise liked the update. More importantly, perhaps, Apple is no longer forcing the bottom tab bar on users.</p>
<p>With the new release, there&#8217;s now an option to show the address bar at the top of the page, as before. For all those who truly hated the update, this means they can set things back to &#8220;normal.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2191155" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2191155" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2191155" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/safari-changes.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/safari-changes.jpg 2778w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/safari-changes.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/safari-changes.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/safari-changes.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/safari-changes.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/safari-changes.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/safari-changes.jpg?resize=2048,2048 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/safari-changes.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/safari-changes.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/safari-changes.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/safari-changes.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/safari-changes.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2191155" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Screenshots, tab bar before and after</p></div></p>
<p>One significant complaint with the floating tab bar was that it <a href="https://twitter.com/viticci/status/1418297985398624258">made some websites nearly unusable</a>, as the bar would block out elements you needed to click. (To get to these unreachable parts of the page, you&#8217;d have to swipe the bar down &#8212; a less-than-ideal experience).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Just another day being unable to order takeout because iOS 15 Safari’s bottom bar makes this checkout button untappable.</p>
<p>thanks Safari for not letting me have that bruschetta <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f622.png" alt="😢" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/e23YTYzGM6">pic.twitter.com/e23YTYzGM6</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Federico Viticci (@viticci) <a href="https://twitter.com/viticci/status/1418297985398624258?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 22, 2021</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>In iOS 15 beta 6, these and other issues are addressed. Essentially, the tab bar looks much like it used to &#8212; with a familiar row of buttons, like it had before when it had been available at the top of the screen. And the bar will no longer get in the way of website content.</p>
<p>Testers had also pointed out that Apple&#8217;s original decision to hide often-used features &#8212; like the reload button or Reader Mode &#8212; under the three-dot &#8220;more&#8221; menu made Safari more difficult to use than in the past. With the release of iOS 15 beta 4, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/apple-tweaks-controversial-ios-15-safari-changes-in-latest-beta/">Apple had tried to solve this problem</a> by bringing back the reload and share buttons, and making Reader Mode appear when available. But the buttons were still small and harder to tap than before.</p>
<p>The new tab bar and the return to normal it offers &#8212; regardless of its placement at the top or bottom of the screen &#8212; is an admission from Apple that users&#8217; complaints on this matter were, in fact, valid. And it&#8217;s a demonstration of what beta testing is meant to be about: trying out new ideas and fixing what doesn&#8217;t work.</p>
<p>Separately, beta 6 users can now restore the tab bar to the top of the page, if that&#8217;s your preference. You can now find an option under <em>Settings &#8211;&gt; Safari</em> to choose between the Tab Bar default and the Single Tab option &#8212; the latter which relocates the address bar to the top of the screen. (Doing so means you&#8217;ll lose the option to swipe through your open tabs, as you could with the Tab Bar, however.)</p>
<p>It&#8217;s fairly common for Apple to offer alternatives to its default settings &#8212; like how it allows users to configure how gestures and clicks work on the Mac&#8217;s trackpad, for example, or how it allows users to turn off the <a href="https://heresthethingblog.com/2014/07/23/mac-tip-natural-scrolling-feels/">once</a>&#8211;<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/apple/comments/1p7gm2/who_here_actually_uses_natural_scrolling/">debated</a> &#8220;natural&#8221; scroll direction option. But adding the option to return the tab at the top is an admission that some good portion of Safari users didn&#8217;t want to relearn how to use one of the iPhone&#8217;s most frequently accessed apps. And if forced to do so, they may have switched browsers instead.</p>
<p>As Apple typically releases the latest version of its iOS software in the fall, this update may represent one of the final changes to Safari we&#8217;ll see ahead of the public release.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Em6Kh8uPKa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/apple-tweaks-controversial-ios-15-safari-changes-in-latest-beta/">Apple tweaks controversial iOS 15 Safari changes in latest beta</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple tweaks controversial iOS 15 Safari changes in latest beta&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/apple-tweaks-controversial-ios-15-safari-changes-in-latest-beta/embed/#?secret=Em6Kh8uPKa" data-secret="Em6Kh8uPKa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/apple-walks-back-controversial-safari-changes-with-ios-15-beta-6-update/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191091</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mealworm farming company Beta Hatch raises $10M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/mealworm-farming-company-beta-hatch-raises-10m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/mealworm-farming-company-beta-hatch-raises-10m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 16:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beta hatch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lewis & Clark AgriFood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mealworms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[protein]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191119</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last time I was in Hong Kong, a startup gave me a jar of mealworms as a snack. They were crunchy and a bit odd looking (as one might expect from a jar full of baked larvae). They really didn’t offer much in the way of flavor, though, so maybe supply your own seasoning. For [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last time I was in Hong Kong, a startup gave me a jar of mealworms as a snack. They were crunchy and a bit odd looking (as one might expect from a jar full of baked larvae). They really didn’t offer much in the way of flavor, though, so maybe supply your own seasoning.</p>
<p>For all sorts of sustainability reasons, there’s been a good deal of interest in these sorts of alternative protein sources &#8212; for humans and otherwise. <a href="http://betahatch.com/">Beta Hatch’s</a> farming efforts are squarely focused on the latter, citing livestock and pets as primary targets for a farming process it says is “virtually zero-waste.”</p>
<p>Today the St. Louis-based firm announced $10 million in funding in a round led by Lewis &amp; Clark AgriFood, with participation from Cavallo Ventures and Innova Memphis, which are both signed on as existing investors. The money comes as Beta Hatch is eyeing the expansion of its flagship farm in Cashmere, Washington.</p>
<p>“We are proud to be a part of building the future of farming as a member of the Washington agricultural community,” founder and CEO Virginia Emery said in a release. “We are excited for our presence in rural America to grow, as we employ and partner with the people in those communities to feed a growing global population.”</p>
<p>The company says the new facility will be the largest of its kind in North America, helping to push Beta Hatch to 10x its current output over the next year. The location is currently powered by renewably sourced energy.</p>
<p>Mealworms have proven intriguing as food sources for food sources, as evidenced by Ÿnsect’s $125 million raise way back in 2019.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WHfMhL9W2h"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/21/a-bugs-life-brings-billions/">Tech investors see bugs as a big business as Ÿnsect raises $125 million</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tech investors see bugs as a big business as Ÿnsect raises $125 million&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/21/a-bugs-life-brings-billions/embed/#?secret=WHfMhL9W2h" data-secret="WHfMhL9W2h" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/mealworm-farming-company-beta-hatch-raises-10m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191119</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>B2B sales platform Accord adds $1M to seed round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/b2b-sales-platform-accord-adds-1m-to-seed-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/b2b-sales-platform-accord-adds-1m-to-seed-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 16:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lead generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Murchison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ross Rich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ryan Rich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stephanie Schatz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wayne Pan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2190751</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Accord’s application provides shared next steps and milestones for buying and selling teams to align on so that the right people are looped in at the right time.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://inaccord.com/">Accord</a> opened up its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/accord-launches-b2b-sales-platform-with-6m-seed/">previously announced $6 million seed round</a> to accept over $1 million from a group of CEOs and sales leads at companies they are working with to officially launch its business-to-business sales platform.</p>
<p>Brothers Ross and Ryan Rich co-founded the San Francisco-based company in 2019 with Wayne Pan to create a customer collaboration platform that, in the words of CEO Ross Rich, “makes the process of buying and selling suck less.”</p>
<p>The average sales deal can involve 14 people, just on the buyer side, which means teams do a lot of “herding cats” in order to drive consensus on sales, he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yZsP98HzN5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/accord-launches-b2b-sales-platform-with-6m-seed/">Accord launches B2B sales platform with $6M seed</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Accord launches B2B sales platform with $6M seed&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/accord-launches-b2b-sales-platform-with-6m-seed/embed/#?secret=yZsP98HzN5" data-secret="yZsP98HzN5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Instead, Accord’s application provides shared next steps and milestones for buying and selling teams to align on so that the right people are looped in at the right time.</p>
<p>“Our unique approach is helping management and sales, but also helping the buyer, which is how you build a relationship,” Ross Rich explained. “Before COVID, you could go onsite, but now you can’t do that. You also have to adjust to the buyer’s expectations, and with business-to-consumer, everything is ‘now and immediate.’ ”</p>
<p>The company’s target market is technology startups, but Ross Rich said Accord is now attracting interest from medical device companies and others where there is no software that bridges the gap between external parties.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Over the past six months, Accord doubled its team and was approached by multiple companies with acquisition offers. However, just a year-and-a-half into the company Rich said he is not entertaining those kinds of offers just yet.</p>
<p>“We have barely scratched the surface and would be selling ourselves short not having had a swing at it,” he added.</p>
<p>The company decided to focus on non-institutional investors when it raised this uncapped round, opting not to grow the board, Rich said.</p>
<p>Instead, it gathered a group of CEOs and sales leads from companies it works with — people who were getting it and seeing the value, including Mike Murchison, co-founder and CEO of Ada Support, who said via email that Ada’s B2B growth “exploded in part because of our focus on being a true partner — not simply a vendor — to our clients.” He added that Accord made it easy for Ada’s sales teams to offer a collaborative buying process.</p>
<p>Another investor, Stephanie Schatz, one of Accord’s advisors, said via email she got in on the round due to Ross Rich having “all the right ingredients for a successful founder,” and the product, which she said was taking into account how people want to buy.</p>
<p>“Ross has intelligence, drive, passion, vision and charisma, but on top of that, I have found that he has excellent instincts for leading a team and building a generational company,” she added. “Accord offers CEOs and sales leaders the opportunity to build a high-performing sales team from the very beginning that truly puts customers at the center.”</p>
<p>The new funding will go toward the general launch of the platform and adding to its team of 13. Rich expects a Series A round to quickly follow.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WFDVsR6bdQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/17/how-startups-close-their-first-big-sales/">How startups close their first big sales</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How startups close their first big sales&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/17/how-startups-close-their-first-big-sales/embed/#?secret=WFDVsR6bdQ" data-secret="WFDVsR6bdQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/b2b-sales-platform-accord-adds-1m-to-seed-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2190751</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pokémon Unite is coming to iOS and Android on September 22</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/pokemon-unite-is-coming-to-ios-and-android-on-september-22/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/pokemon-unite-is-coming-to-ios-and-android-on-september-22/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 15:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile devices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo DS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pokemon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pokemon company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RPG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Switch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During today&#8217;s Pokémon Presents livestream, The Pokémon Company announced that Pokémon Unite will become available for iOS and Android on September 22. The strategic battle game came out for Nintendo Switch in late July, but its arrival on mobile devices will expand the game&#8217;s potential user base. For users already playing on Nintendo Switch, fear [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">During today&#8217;s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kdja9m4YlT4&amp;">Pokémon Presents</a> livestream, The Pokémon Company announced that Pokémon Unite will become available for <a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/id1512321575">iOS</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=jp.pokemon.pokemonunite">Android</a> on September 22. The strategic battle game came out for Nintendo Switch in late July, but its arrival on mobile devices will expand the game&#8217;s potential user base.</p>
<p>For users already playing on Nintendo Switch, fear not &#8212; the game allows cross-platform play, which means you can play on your Switch, then pick up where you left off on mobile. All users can play together regardless of which device they&#8217;re using, and it&#8217;s not necessary to have a Switch to get the mobile game. Pokémon Unite is free-to-start with microtransactions &#8212; you can purchase in-game currency to get certain items or Pokémon.</p>
<p>The presentation also unveiled new gameplay footage and feature news for upcoming Nintendo Switch releases: <a href="https://diamondpearl.pokemon.com/en-gb/">Pokémon Brilliant Diamond and Shining Pearl</a> (November 19, 2021), remakes of the Nintendo DS games from 2006 and <a href="https://legends.pokemon.com/en-us/">Pokémon Legends: Arceus</a> (January 28, 2022), the first open-world RPG in the Pokémon universe.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2191120" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2191120" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2191120" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/BDSP_Screen_EN_25.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/BDSP_Screen_EN_25.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/BDSP_Screen_EN_25.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/BDSP_Screen_EN_25.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/BDSP_Screen_EN_25.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/BDSP_Screen_EN_25.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/BDSP_Screen_EN_25.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/BDSP_Screen_EN_25.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2191120" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Pokémon Brilliant Diamond and Shining Pearl</p></div></p>
<p>Like previous main series game remakes, Brilliant Diamond and Shining Pearl will expand upon the original games&#8217; foundation and introduce features that appeared in later games, like Following Pokémon, Secret Bases and &#8212; very importantly &#8212; changing your trainer&#8217;s outfit. The game will also include re-designed features from its original release, like designing Poké Ball capsules and competing in Pokémon Contests.</p>
<p>But for the first time in a Pokémon Game, Brilliant Diamond and Shining Pearl will introduce a new aspect of gameplay called the Sinnoh Underground. Players can collect statues of Pokémon for their Secret Base, and depending on which statues are on display, different Pokémon will appear in Pokémon Hideaways within the Sinnoh Underground. To commemorate the 15-year-old games&#8217; remakes, on November 5, 2021, Nintendo will release a &#8220;Dialga and Palkia Edition&#8221; of the Nintendo Switch Lite, which features the legendary Pokémon in gold and silver on a grey console.</p>
<p>Then, the Pokémon Company shared more information about Pokémon Legends: Arceus, a first-of-its-kind release for the iconic franchise. Fans have compared its open-world design to The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild, which is the fourth-best-selling Nintendo Switch game with <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2021/210805_3e.pdf">23.2 million copies</a> sold, but others say it&#8217;s more <a href="https://kotaku.com/heres-what-youll-actually-do-in-pokemon-legends-arceus-1847097025">similar to Monster Hunter</a>. The new game introduces the Hisui Region (an ancient version of the Sinnoh Region), along with new Pokémon like a <a href="https://twitter.com/SerebiiNet/status/1427983460887633928">grandpa-esque Growlithe</a>, and an evolution of Basculin called <a href="https://twitter.com/SerebiiNet/status/1427985426166566912">Basculegion</a>, which can evolve when &#8220;possessed by the souls of other Basculin from their school that could not withstand the harsh journey upstream&#8221;&#8230; Yes, this is a children&#8217;s franchise.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Welcome to the Hisui region, Trainers.</p>
<p>Newly discovered Pokémon, newly discovered regional forms, and new gameplay features are coming to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/PokemonLegendsArceus?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#PokemonLegendsArceus</a>! <a href="https://t.co/h08CvKToSf">pic.twitter.com/h08CvKToSf</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Pokémon (@Pokemon) <a href="https://twitter.com/Pokemon/status/1427986250494005254?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 18, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Nightmare-inducing new Pokémon aside, the livestream revealed more information about how exactly this new type of Pokémon game will work.</p>
<p>Like standard Pokémon games, players will set out on a mission to complete a Pokédex, but rather than training to become &#8220;the best like no one ever was,&#8221; they will be part of an expedition team, conducting survey work to learn more about the nature of Pokémon and the secrets they hold. In between field assignments, players can heal their party, craft items, and buy supplies at outposts (ancient Pokémon Centers?). Pokémon Legends: Arceus will also introduce a new battle style &#8212; like Pokémon Unite, it won&#8217;t simply repurpose the turn-based gameplay we&#8217;ve been accustomed to since the first Pokémon games were released in 1998.</p>
<p>Anyway, these games seem promising, but just try your best not to think about Basculegion.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Xy0ujEYwuX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/28/how-niantic-evolved-pokemon-go-for-the-year-no-one-could-go-anywhere/">How Niantic evolved Pokémon GO for the year no one could go anywhere</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How Niantic evolved Pokémon GO for the year no one could go anywhere&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/28/how-niantic-evolved-pokemon-go-for-the-year-no-one-could-go-anywhere/embed/#?secret=Xy0ujEYwuX" data-secret="Xy0ujEYwuX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/pokemon-unite-is-coming-to-ios-and-android-on-september-22/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191064</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
