<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 18:06:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Spotify Group Session UX teardown: The fails and their fixes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/ux-teardown-spotify-group-sessions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/ux-teardown-spotify-group-sessions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 18:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Consumer Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ux]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2106350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We highlight some of Spotify Group Sessions user experience failings and offer ways to fix them, as well as a number of UX features that are done right. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In July last year, Spotify extended its shared-queue feature, Group Session, to support remote usage. Essentially a “party mode,” the feature offers a way for participants to contribute to a collaborative playlist in real-time and control what’s playing across everyone’s devices.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/28/spotifys-new-party-mode-feature-group-session-goes-remote/">As TechCrunch&#8217;s Sarah Perez explained</a>, Premium users are able to tune into the same playlist or podcast together at the same time, even if they’re not in the same place. Prompted by the coronavirus pandemic, Spotify, like a spew of other tech companies, is trying to create more shared online experiences that are lockdown-proof, and as people are being forced to spend more time indoors and online.</p>
<p>In our latest UX teardown, with the help of <a href="https://builtformars.co.uk/">Built for Mars</a> founder and UX expert Peter Ramsey, we highlight some of Spotify Group Sessions user experience failings and offer ways to fix them, as well as a number of UX features that are done right. Many of these lessons can be applied to other existing digital products or ones you are currently building, including the need to remember the difference between usernames and display names, when it makes sense to combine common actions into one, and how to use &#8220;react and explain&#8221; on-boarding.</p>
<h2>Usernames and display names</h2>
<p>Always remember the difference between user names and displays.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2106366" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2106366" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2106366" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CompareNames.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="287" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CompareNames.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CompareNames.jpg?resize=150,63 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CompareNames.jpg?resize=300,127 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CompareNames.jpg?resize=768,324 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CompareNames.jpg?resize=680,287 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CompareNames.jpg?resize=50,21 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2106366" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Built For Mars</p></div></p>
<p>The fail<span style="font-weight: 400;">: If you created a Spotify account using Facebook, then you’re arbitrarily assigned an 11-digit display name. This is then shown to everyone you invite and is totally meaningless.</span></p>
<p>The fix<span style="font-weight: 400;">: Prompt the user to set a real display name when they create their first session. It avoids confusion and creates a more real experience.</span></p>
<p><strong>Steve O&#8217;Hear: This looks really sloppy and unprofessional, as well as being useless from a usability point of view. However, I’m guessing this is technical debt of some kind; any idea what’s going on here?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Peter Ramsey:</strong> Yes, it happens when usernames go from being irrelevant (i.e., Spotify) to suddenly relevant (i.e. when they add social features). But by that point, the database/infrastructure is already in motion.</p>
<p><strong>Can you think of an example where this has been done right?</strong></p>
<p>Twitter is the perfect example of this done right. There can only be one @jack, but loads of people with the display name Jack. Otherwise basically every tweet would be by some obscure name and the world would feel like Reddit (i.e., anonymous).</p>
<h2>Combining common actions into one<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/ux-teardown-spotify-group-sessions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2106350</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok will recheck the age of every user in Italy after DPA order</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-will-recheck-the-age-of-every-user-in-italy-after-dpa-order/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-will-recheck-the-age-of-every-user-in-italy-after-dpa-order/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 17:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107857</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TikTok has agreed to re-verify the age of every user in Italy and block access to users who state they are under 13, the country&#8217;s data protection agency said today. The video sharing social network confirmed that from February 9 every user in Italy will be required to go through its age gate process again [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TikTok has agreed to re-verify the age of every user in Italy and block access to users who state they are under 13, the country&#8217;s data protection agency <a href="https://www.garanteprivacy.it/web/guest/home/docweb/-/docweb-display/docweb/9533424#english_version">said today</a>.</p>
<p>The video sharing social network confirmed that from February 9 every user in Italy will be required to go through its age gate process again &#8212; and only those users aged 13 and above will be allowed to continue using the app.</p>
<p>Accounts of those who say they are under 13 will be deleted.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The move to required all users in Italy to go through TikTok&#8217;s age-verification process again follows an emergency <a href="https://www.garanteprivacy.it/web/guest/home/docweb/-/docweb-display/docweb/9524224">order</a> by Italy&#8217;s GPDP on January 22 after the death of a 10-year-old girl from Palermo who died of asphyxiation after participating in a “blackout challenge” on the social network, according to reports in local media.</p>
<p>TikTok was given a deadline of January 29 to respond to the GPDP&#8217;s order, as we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/tiktok-has-until-friday-to-respond-to-italys-order-to-block-users-it-cant-age-verify-after-girls-death/">reported earlier</a>. Today the agency confirmed the measures TikTok has agreed to take.</p>
<p>As well as asking all users in the country to re-enter their date of birth to continue using the app, the GPDP said TikTok will &#8220;consider deploying AI-based systems for age verification purposes&#8221;.</p>
<p>The Italian watchdog added that it will be monitoring the effectiveness of TikTok&#8217;s age verification process.</p>
<p>The basic age-check TikTok conducts when users sign-up &#8212; which it will be pushing out again to all users in Italian in a few days &#8212; simply requires users to enter a date of birth so is very easy to circumvent. But it&#8217;s also clear that age verification online remains a hard problem.</p>
<p>Robust identity checks to determine age beyond doubt threaten a &#8216;sledgehammer to crack a nut&#8217; scenario &#8212; potentially limiting service access in a way that&#8217;s unfair and risking harm to online anonymity and privacy, with potential knock on impacts on other considerations like freedom of expression and data security.</p>
<p>On the flip side are growing public concerns that underage users are being exposed to inappropriate and even harmful content online.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5NWeoXLaGM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/tiktok-has-until-friday-to-respond-to-italys-order-to-block-users-it-cant-age-verify-after-girls-death/">TikTok has until Friday to respond to Italy&#8217;s order to block users it can&#8217;t age-verify after girl&#8217;s death</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok has until Friday to respond to Italy&#8217;s order to block users it can&#8217;t age-verify after girl&#8217;s death&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/tiktok-has-until-friday-to-respond-to-italys-order-to-block-users-it-cant-age-verify-after-girls-death/embed/#?secret=5NWeoXLaGM" data-secret="5NWeoXLaGM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>While TikTok&#8217;s lead data supervisor in the European Union is Ireland&#8217;s Data Protection Commission (DPC), the EU&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) includes a provision that allows national DPAs to take emergency interventions to protect users &#8212; which is the route the GPDP has used here.</p>
<p>&#8220;In order to identify users below 13 years with reasonable certainty following this initial check, the company undertook to further consider the deployment of AI-based systems,&#8221; the agency said today.</p>
<p>&#8220;Since the implementation of such systems requires balancing the need for accurate verification against the children’s right to data protection, the company committed to starting a dialogue with the Irish Data Protection Commission (DPC) on the use of AI for age verification purposes. Ireland is where TikTok set its main establishment in the EU,&#8221; it added.</p>
<p>Reached for comment, the Irish Data Protection Commission told TechCrunch: &#8220;The DPC is engaging with TikTok to review, in the context of the processing of personal data, the measures implemented by the company to ensure it has effective means of identifying child users on the platform and, more generally, the measures and protections to protect the most vulnerable of users in terms of risks arising from the processing of their personal data.&#8221; So it remains to be seen whether the regulator will push for more robust age checks.</p>
<p>In another change triggered by the GPDP&#8217;s intervention TikTok has implemented an in-app button to enable users to &#8220;quickly and easily&#8221; report other users that may seem to be below 13 years of age.</p>
<p>Per TikTok, these reports are reviewed by moderators and &#8220;removed as necessary&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;All the above measures supplement those already in place,&#8221; the GPDP said, adding: &#8220;TikTok undertook to also double the number of Italian moderators of platform contents.&#8221;</p>
<p>Commenting in a statement, Alexandra Evans, TikTok&#8217;s head of child safety, added: &#8220;Keeping people on TikTok safe is our top priority. We&#8217;ve reached an agreement with the Garante and today, we&#8217;re taking additional steps to support our community in Italy. From February 9, we&#8217;ll be sending every user in Italy through our age gate process again and only users aged 13 and over will be able to continue using the app after going through this process. We&#8217;re also rolling out a new, dedicated in-app reporting button to allow users to flag an account they believe may be under the age of 13, which will then be reviewed by our team and removed as necessary.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is no finish line when it comes to protecting our users, especially our younger ones, and our work in this important area doesn&#8217;t stop. That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re continuing to invest in the people, processes and technologies that help to keep our community a safe space for positive, creative expression.&#8221;</p>
<p>TikTok&#8217;s reissued age check in Italy will also be accompanied by a local information campaign in which TikTok will aim to raise parents’ and children’s awareness of the age checks and other child-safety-related features &#8212; both via its app and in the media.</p>
<p>&#8220;An information campaign will be launched by TikTok starting on February 4 both via the app and through other channels. The company will send push alerts to users on the app before blocking their access and will inform them on the need to enter their age. Banners will also be published containing links to information on security tools and on how to change profile settings from ‘public’ to ‘private’. The information campaign both via the web and through the press will be addressed to parents and the age threshold for registration will be specifically highlighted, among other things,&#8221; the GPDP said.</p>
<p>The agency also noted that TikTok has agreed to improve the wording of the short privacy notice intended for users aged under 18 years &#8212; &#8220;to explain what data are collected and how those data are processed in an easily understandable and user-oriented manner&#8221;.</p>
<p>In addition to TikTok&#8217;s impending information campaign, the GPDP is launching a child safety awareness-raising campaign of its own on national TV channels, in cooperation with a child protection charity called Telefono Azzurro. It said this will be targeted at parents to encourage them to supervise their kids&#8217; use of the app.</p>
<p>&#8220;The campaign is aimed at calling upon parents to actively supervise and pay special attention to the situations where their children are requested to enter their age in order to access TikTok,&#8221; it said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3eN2fS3eFK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-to-flag-and-downrank-unsubstantiated-claims-fact-checkers-cant-verify/">TikTok to flag and downrank &#8216;unsubstantiated&#8217; claims fact checkers can&#8217;t verify</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok to flag and downrank &#8216;unsubstantiated&#8217; claims fact checkers can&#8217;t verify&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-to-flag-and-downrank-unsubstantiated-claims-fact-checkers-cant-verify/embed/#?secret=3eN2fS3eFK" data-secret="3eN2fS3eFK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-will-recheck-the-age-of-every-user-in-italy-after-dpa-order/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107857</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clearview AI ruled &#8216;illegal&#8217; by Canadian privacy authorities</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/clearview-ai-ruled-illegal-by-canadian-privacy-authorities/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/clearview-ai-ruled-illegal-by-canadian-privacy-authorities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 17:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clearview ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facial recognition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facial recognition software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illinois]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law enforcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mass surveillance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terms of service]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107913</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Controversial facial recognition startup Clearview AI violated Canadian privacy laws when it collected photos of Canadians without their knowledge or permission, the country&#8217;s top privacy watchdog has ruled. The New York-based company made its splashy newspaper debut a year ago by claiming it had collected over 3 billion photos of people&#8217;s faces and touting its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Controversial facial recognition startup Clearview AI violated Canadian privacy laws when it collected photos of Canadians without their knowledge or permission, the country&#8217;s top privacy watchdog has ruled.</p>
<p>The New York-based company made its splashy newspaper debut a year ago by claiming it had <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/18/technology/clearview-privacy-facial-recognition.html">collected over 3 billion photos</a> of people&#8217;s faces and touting its connections to law enforcement and police departments. But the startup has faced a slew of criticism for scraping social media sites also without their permission, prompting Facebook, LinkedIn and Twitter to send cease and desist letters to demand it stops.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.priv.gc.ca/en/opc-news/news-and-announcements/2021/nr-c_210203/?=february-2-2021">a statement</a>, Canada&#8217;s Office of the Privacy Commissioner said its investigation found Clearview had &#8220;collected highly sensitive biometric information without the knowledge or consent of individuals,&#8221; and that the startup &#8220;collected, used and disclosed Canadians&#8217; personal information for inappropriate purposes, which cannot be rendered appropriate via consent.&#8221;</p>
<p>Clearview rebuffed the allegations, claiming Canada&#8217;s privacy laws do not apply because the company doesn&#8217;t have a &#8220;real and substantial connection&#8221; to the country, and that consent was not required because the images it scraped were publicly available.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s a challenge the company continues to face in court, as it faces <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/27/clearview-facial-recognition-private-companies/">a class action suit</a> citing Illinois&#8217; biometric protection laws that last year dinged Facebook to the tune of $550 million for violating the same law.</p>
<p>The Canadian privacy watchdog rejected Clearview&#8217;s arguments, and said it would &#8220;pursue other actions&#8221; if the company does not follow its recommendations, which included stopping the collection on Canadians and deleting all previously collected images. Clearview said in July that it <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-clearview-ai-canada/clearview-ai-stops-offering-facial-recognition-technology-in-canada-idUSKBN2472RA">stopped providing</a> its technology to Canadian customers after the Royal Canadian Mounted Police and the Toronto Police Service were using the startup&#8217;s technology.</p>
<p>&#8220;What Clearview does is mass surveillance and it is illegal,&#8221; said Daniel Therrien, Canada&#8217;s privacy commissioner. &#8220;It is an affront to individuals&#8217; privacy rights and inflicts broad-based harm on all members of society, who find themselves continually in a police lineup. This is completely unacceptable.&#8221;</p>
<p>A spokesperson for Clearview AI did not immediately return a request for comment.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mtQ3uVabCy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/clearview-source-code-lapse/">Security lapse exposed Clearview AI source code</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Security lapse exposed Clearview AI source code&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/clearview-source-code-lapse/embed/#?secret=mtQ3uVabCy" data-secret="mtQ3uVabCy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/clearview-ai-ruled-illegal-by-canadian-privacy-authorities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107913</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Instagram confirms it&#8217;s working on a &#8220;Vertical Stories&#8221; feed</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/instagram-confirms-its-working-on-a-vertical-stories-feed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/instagram-confirms-its-working-on-a-vertical-stories-feed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 17:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Instagram is developing a new feature that could give its app more of a TikTok-like feel: Vertical Instagram Stories. Today, users browse through Stories through taps and horizontal swipes &#8212; a feature Instagram adopted from Snapchat. But now, Stories are passé. Even Snapchat is borrowing ideas from TikTok. Its recent launch of Spotlight, for example, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Instagram is developing a new feature that could give its app more of a TikTok-like feel: Vertical Instagram Stories. Today, users browse through Stories through taps and horizontal swipes &#8212; a feature Instagram adopted from Snapchat. But now, Stories are passé. Even Snapchat is borrowing ideas from TikTok. Its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/snapchat-launches-a-tiktok-like-feed-called-spotlight-kick-started-by-paying-creators/">recent launch of Spotlight</a>, for example, is its own TikTok clone.</p>
<p>In many ways, vertical swiping feels more natural than taps and horizontal flicks. It is, after all, how users navigate much of the mobile web, as well as other key features across a variety of social apps, like Facebook&#8217;s News Feed or YouTube&#8217;s home page.</p>
<p>That said, turning Instagram Stories into a vertical feed would be a notable change, and one that could potentially set the stage from a shift away from more static content &#8212; like the photos and reshared Feed posts that still often fill the Stories section today. In a &#8220;Vertical Stories&#8221; feed, on the other hand, Instagram would likely prioritize video posts over images to better compete with TikTok, just as it&#8217;s currently tweaking its algorithms and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/instagram-redesign-puts-reels-and-shop-tabs-on-the-home-screen/">overall design</a> to prioritize Reels. (A turn of the dials that has already been leveraged by <a href="https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMeJfAChp/">indie</a> <a href="https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMeJf5mxV/">creators</a> to <a href="https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMeJfXGjT/">significantly</a> <a href="https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMeJf5udh/">grow</a> their followings, in fact).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The &#8220;Vertical Stories&#8221; feature was spotted under development by <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1356574935024599040">Alessandro Paluzzi</a> who shared the discovery on his Twitter account.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Instagram?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Instagram</a> is working on Vertical Stories <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f440.png" alt="👀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br />Swipe up and down to browse stories. <a href="https://t.co/LDJje8l137">pic.twitter.com/LDJje8l137</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Alessandro Paluzzi (@alex193a) <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1356574935024599040?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 2, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>His screenshot shows a simple user interface with text that reads: <em>&#8220;Now you can swipe up and down to browse stories&#8221;</em> and then a big, blue button labeled &#8220;Vertical Stories.&#8221;</p>
<p>Paluzzi tells TechCrunch that the feature is not yet live. Instead, he dug it up from Instagram&#8217;s code.</p>
<p>Instagram confirmed to TechCrunch the feature is being built but is not out to the public at this time.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is an early prototype and is not currently testing on Instagram,&#8221; a company spokesperson told us.</p>
<p>A prototype may never actually make it to a public launch, of course, but its existence does say something about what sort of ideas Instagram is considering as a means of offering a better challenge to TikTok.</p>
<p>Today, the company&#8217;s TikTok rival, Reels, has been shoehorned into the platform via the Instagram Explore page, where Reels sits in the top position. When you click on the Reels video here, you&#8217;re taken to a new user interface where you then vertically swipe through videos, similar to TikTok.</p>
<p>This doesn&#8217;t feel right, and the launch of the new format has added to Instagram&#8217;s clutter. Today, the app has all sorts of places users can publish their videos, including in the Feed, as Stories, as longer-form IGTV content, and now Reels. It&#8217;s too much.</p>
<p>Instagram knows this arrangement isn&#8217;t quite working. As Instagram head Adam Mosseri <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22238513/instagram-adam-mosseri-reels-decoder-interview-podcast">recently told The Verge</a>, most people probably don&#8217;t even understand the difference between IGTV content and videos posted to Instagram, for example. He said the company was looking at ways to simplify and consolidate its ideas, too.</p>
<p>While his comments were focused on the confusion between Instagram&#8217;s normal video posts and IGTV, there&#8217;s also significant overlap between Instagram&#8217;s Stories&#8217; vertical video content and Reels. A &#8220;Vertical Stories&#8221; feed could allow for an eventual combination of those formats &#8212; Stories videos and Reels, perhaps.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not clear that&#8217;s at all what Instagram has in mind, though. The social network could just be looking to transition another part of its app to the more modern vertical feed, as the demand for the traditional Stories format declines.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/instagram-confirms-its-working-on-a-vertical-stories-feed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107819</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google&#8217;s new subsea cable between the U.S. and Europe is now online</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/googles-new-subsea-cable-between-the-u-s-and-europe-is-now-online/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/googles-new-subsea-cable-between-the-u-s-and-europe-is-now-online/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 17:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subcom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subsea cable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virginia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107855</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google, together with its partner SubCom, today announced that the company&#8217;s privately owned Dunant subsea cable between Virginia Beach, Virginia and Saint-Hilaire-de-Riez on the French Atlantic coast is now operational. Google first announced this project, which was named after the first Noble Peach Price winner and founder of the Red Cross, Henry Dunant, back in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google, together with its partner <a href="https://www.subcom.com/">SubCom</a>, today<a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/infrastructure/googles-dunant-subsea-cable-is-now-ready-for-service"> announced</a> that the company&#8217;s privately owned Dunant subsea cable between Virginia Beach, Virginia and Saint-Hilaire-de-Riez on the French Atlantic coast is now operational.</p>
<p>Google first announced this project, which was named after the first Noble Peach Price winner and founder of the Red Cross, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henry_Dunant">Henry Dunant,</a> back in the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/17/google-builds-its-own-subsea-cable-from-the-us-to-france/">middle of 2018</a>. At the time it expected the project to go live in 2020, but besides dealing with the complications of spanning a long cable between continents, the project leaders probably didn&#8217;t budget for a global pandemic at the time.</p>
<p>The almost 4,000-mile cable has a total capacity of 250 terabits per second &#8212; or enough to transmit the &#8220;entire digitized Library of Congress three times every second&#8221; (though maybe using Library of Congress data size references is starting to <a href="https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/2011/07/transferring-libraries-of-congress-of-data/">feel a bit antiquated at this point</a>?). Unlike some older cables, Dunant uses 12 fiber pairs, coupled with a number of <a href="https://www.submarinenetworks.com/en/insights/submarine-sdm-cable">technical innovations around maximizing its bandwidth</a>, to achieve these numbers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Google is dedicated to meeting the exploding demand for cloud services and online content that continues unabated,&#8221; said Mark Sokol, senior director of Infrastructure, Google Cloud. &#8220;With record-breaking capacity and transmission speeds, Dunant will help users access content wherever they may be and supplement one of the busiest routes on the internet to support the growth of Google Cloud. Dunant is a remarkable achievement that would not have been possible without the dedication of both SubCom and Google’s employees, partners, and suppliers, who overcame multiple challenges this year to make this system a reality.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107858" style="width: 1010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gcp_subsea_cable.max-1000x1000-1.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107858" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2107858" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gcp_subsea_cable.max-1000x1000-1.png" alt="" width="1000" height="502" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gcp_subsea_cable.max-1000x1000-1.png 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gcp_subsea_cable.max-1000x1000-1.png?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gcp_subsea_cable.max-1000x1000-1.png?resize=300,151 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gcp_subsea_cable.max-1000x1000-1.png?resize=768,386 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gcp_subsea_cable.max-1000x1000-1.png?resize=680,341 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gcp_subsea_cable.max-1000x1000-1.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2107858" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>With Dunant now being operational, the next Google cable to go live will be the Grace Hopper cable between New York and Europe, with landing sites in Bilbao, Spain and Bude, UK. Google first announced this new cable, which it is also building in partnership with SubCom, last July. It&#8217;s expected to go online in 2022 and will feature a total of 16 fiber pairs.</p>
<p>In addition, Google is also building the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/infrastructure/introducing-equiano-a-subsea-cable-from-portugal-to-south-africa">Equiano cable</a> from South Africa to Portugal. This cable is supposed to go online later this year.</p>
<p>In addition to its privately-owned cables, Google is also a partner in a <a href="https://www.submarinenetworks.com/en/insights/complete-list-of-google-s-subsea-cable-investments">number of consortiums</a> that band together to build cable systems.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/edgepoint.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2107878" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/edgepoint.png" alt="" width="1024" height="330" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/edgepoint.png 1438w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/edgepoint.png?resize=150,48 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/edgepoint.png?resize=300,97 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/edgepoint.png?resize=768,248 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/edgepoint.png?resize=680,219 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/edgepoint.png?resize=50,16 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/googles-new-subsea-cable-between-the-u-s-and-europe-is-now-online/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107855</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple Music, Books, iTunes, App Store and more are experiencing outages</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/apple-music-books-itunes-app-store-and-more-are-experiencing-outages/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/apple-music-books-itunes-app-store-and-more-are-experiencing-outages/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 16:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iTunes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[services]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107844</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Several high-level Apple services are experiencing issues and outages on Wednesday morning, Apple has confirmed. These issues are impacting a number of consumer-facing services including Apple Music and Radio, Apple Books, and the App Store platforms across both iOS devices and Mac. For some users, the services are down. For example, there were reports circulating [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Several high-level Apple services are experiencing issues and outages on Wednesday morning, Apple has confirmed. These issues are impacting a number of consumer-facing services including Apple Music and Radio, Apple Books, and the App Store platforms across both iOS devices and Mac.</p>
<p>For some users, the services are down. For example, there were reports circulating this morning that users were having problems <a href="https://www.imore.com/apple-music-experiencing-outage">streaming music through Apple Music</a> or using iTunes. Other have noticed strange problems cropping up on the App Store &#8212; like app search results that only returned a small handful of top apps related to the search term.</p>
<p>Even when the services are partially up, they&#8217;re sometimes much slower to load than usual &#8212; meaning users may see blank pages for several seconds before the page is populated with its usual content.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2107847" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107847" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2107847" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-03-at-11.20.56-AM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="568" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-03-at-11.20.56-AM.jpg 1924w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-03-at-11.20.56-AM.jpg?resize=150,125 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-03-at-11.20.56-AM.jpg?resize=300,251 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-03-at-11.20.56-AM.jpg?resize=768,642 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-03-at-11.20.56-AM.jpg?resize=680,568 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-03-at-11.20.56-AM.jpg?resize=1536,1284 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-03-at-11.20.56-AM.jpg?resize=50,42 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2107847" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>At the time of the initial reports, <a href="https://www.apple.com/support/systemstatus/">Apple&#8217;s Status page</a> didn&#8217;t reflect these issues, as it showed all services as being available. That has since changed. Now, the page displays outages are occurring across the App Store, Apple Book, Apple Music, Apple Music Radio, iTunes Store, Mac App Store, and Radio.</p>
<p>The Apple Support Twitter account has also posted about the outage, but has yet to provide details about what has happened or when it might be resolved.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s concerning is that the account replied to a tweet with a complaint from a user who said they couldn&#8217;t reset their password &#8212; an indication that the outages could be impacting other types of backend services, as well.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Some services are currently experiencing an outage. Hang tight and keep checking back: <a href="https://t.co/waNYZdXpJm">https://t.co/waNYZdXpJm</a> If you’d like to connect with us in DM, we can look further. <a href="https://t.co/GDrqU22YpT">https://t.co/GDrqU22YpT</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Apple Support (@AppleSupport) <a href="https://twitter.com/AppleSupport/status/1356996642931675137?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 3, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Apple says it&#8217;s working to provide us with more information on this, and we&#8217;ll update when the company has more to share.</p>
<p><em>Update, 12:38 PM ET: The status page shows the outages as resolved. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/apple-music-books-itunes-app-store-and-more-are-experiencing-outages/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107844</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Techstars Los Angeles names Matt Kozlov as its new managing director</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/techstars-los-angeles-names-matt-kozlov-as-its-new-managing-director/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/techstars-los-angeles-names-matt-kozlov-as-its-new-managing-director/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 16:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anna Barber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Cohen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[head]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Louisiana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M13]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[matt kozlov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mentorships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[premier]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SINAI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spencer rascoff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup Accelerator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechStars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107813</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Techstars Los Angeles, the local Los Angeles-focused branch of the global accelerator network, has named Matt Kozlov as its new managing director. Kozlov, a longtime Techstars network fixture, has previously served as the head of the organization&#8217;s healthcare accelerator through a partnership with Cedars-Sinai and as the head of the Techstars Starburst Space Accelerator, which [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.techstars.com/accelerators/los-angeles">Techstars Los Angeles</a>, the local Los Angeles-focused branch of the global accelerator network, has named Matt Kozlov as its new managing director.</p>
<p>Kozlov, a longtime <a href="https://www.techstars.com">Techstars</a> network fixture, has previously served as the head of the organization&#8217;s healthcare accelerator through a partnership with Cedars-Sinai and as the head of the Techstars Starburst Space Accelerator, which was focused on space and aerospace startups.</p>
<p>Now, Kozlov turns his attention to the Los Angeles ecosystem broadly.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;I’m humbled to have the opportunity each day to support incredible founders who are solving some of humanity’s greatest challenges,&#8221; said Kozlov, in a statement. &#8220;As I begin this new role, my goal is to continue to leverage my experience to help generate opportunities for future Techstars LA companies to make meaningful, long-term impact.&#8221;</p>
<p>Kozlov&#8217;s appointment comes as the Los Angeles tech ecosystem is having something of a moment. As the diaspora out of Silicon Valley continues, the Southern California tech world has proven to be a tempting landing pad during the COVID-19 pandemic. And remote work means that Los Angeles could be a fixture for more investors looking to escape the Bay.</p>
<p>Beyond Southern California&#8217;s coastal appeal is a vibrant technology ecosystem that encompasses enterprise software, financial services, healthcare, aerospace and defense, robotics, ecommerce and social media. It&#8217;s the home of social networking favorites Snap and TikTok&#8217;s U.S. base of operations and SpaceX&#8217;s significant presence has born a number of talented hardware and engineering startups.</p>
<p>LA is truly having a moment and Kozlov&#8217;s experience with some of the less-well-known corners of the city&#8217;s tech ecosystem could be a boon for the Techstars program.</p>
<p>“I’m thrilled by the selection of Matt as the new Managing Director for Techstars LA,” said Anna Barber, former Managing Director, Techstars LA, who stepped down from the role in November to join venture firm M13 as Partner, in a statement. “He is a talented investor and longstanding leader in LA’s Techstars community, and has been an essential and valued mentor for the program for the past four years. He embodies the Techstars values of #givefirst and I have every confidence that he is the right leader to continue building on what we’ve established in the LA community.”</p>
<p>Collectively, the 40 alumni companies who have participated in Techstars Los Angeles accelerator program have raised over $126 million and have a combined market cap of $328.6 million.</p>
<p>“Techstars LA plays a critical role in the Los Angeles tech ecosystem as the premier startup accelerator, providing valuable mentorship and funding for dozens of companies a year,” said Spencer Rascoff, Chair of dot.LA and Los Angeles angel investor. “I’m very excited that Matt will be the new Managing Director of Techstars LA. He brings extensive experience in healthcare and aerospace investing and has been an incredible mentor and leader to the companies of the Techstars Starburst Space Accelerator over the last several years.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/techstars-los-angeles-names-matt-kozlov-as-its-new-managing-director/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107813</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Electric moped startup Revel launches an EV charging business</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/electric-moped-startup-revel-launches-an-ev-charging-business/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/electric-moped-startup-revel-launches-an-ev-charging-business/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 15:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107830</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Revel, the shared electric moped startup, is building a DC fast-charging station for electric vehicles in New York City, the first in a new business venture that will eventually spread to other cities. The company said Wednesday that this new &#8220;Superhub,&#8221; which is located at the former Pfizer building in Brooklyn, will contain 30 chargers [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Revel, the shared electric moped startup, is building a DC fast-charging station for electric vehicles in New York City, the first in a new business venture that will eventually spread to other cities.</p>
<p>The company said Wednesday that this new &#8220;Superhub,&#8221; which is located at the former Pfizer building in Brooklyn, will contain 30 chargers and be open to the public 24 hours a day. This will be the first in a network of Superhubs opened by Revel across New York City, the company said.</p>
<p>Revel didn&#8217;t build the EV charging infrastructure in house. Instead, it is using Tritium&#8217;s new RTM75 model for the first 10 chargers at its Brooklyn site, which will go live this spring. These chargers are designed to delivery with 100 additional miles of charge to an electric vehicle in about 20 minutes, according to Revel.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The EV charging business has been couched by Revel as a mission to electrify cities. The move comes as a growing number of automakers, including legacy companies like GM, Ford and VW Group along with new entrant Rivian and EV leader Tesla add more electric vehicles to their portfolios.</p>
<p>Revel&#8217;s expansion into charging marks its first new product line since launching a shared fleet of electric mopeds in 2018. Revel, founded by Frank Reig and Paul Suhey, started with a pilot program in Brooklyn and later expanded to Queens, the Bronx and sections of Manhattan. It has been on a fast-paced growth track thanks to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/10/electric-moped-startup-revel-raises-27-6-million-as-it-eyes-new-markets/">$27.6 million in capital</a> raised October 2019 in a Series A round led by Ibex Investors. The equity round included newcomer Toyota AI Ventures and further investments from Blue Collective, Launch Capital and Maniv Mobility.</p>
<p>Several thousands mopeds are available to rent in New York City today. Revel expanded its shared moped business to other cities such as Austin, Miami and Washington, D.C in its first 18 months of operation. Last year, the company launched in Oakland and received a permit in July 2020 to operate in San Francisco.</p>
<p>Shared mopeds haven&#8217;t been successful everywhere. Revel <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/revel-pulls-electric-mopeds-after-failing-to-make-a-dent-in-austins-car-culture/">pulled out of Austin</a> in December. Reig said at the time that the COVID-19 pandemic, which has caused ridership to fall across shared micromobility services, along with the city&#8217;s deep-rooted car culture was proven difficult to penetrate.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/electric-moped-startup-revel-launches-an-ev-charging-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107830</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Venture capital is going to get even bigger, faster and more expensive this year</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/venture-capital-is-going-to-get-even-bigger-faster-and-more-expensive-this-year/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/venture-capital-is-going-to-get-even-bigger-faster-and-more-expensive-this-year/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 15:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insight Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107792</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The venture capital market has skewed later and larger in recent quarters, something you might have felt in the rapid recent pace of new unicorn formation. December was a hot month for new unicorns, for example. So was January. February likely will be more of the same. Powering those unicorn births are huge rounds led [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The venture capital market has skewed later and larger in recent quarters, something you might have felt in the rapid recent pace of new unicorn formation. December was a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/as-2020-ends-new-unicorn-formation-continues-to-impress/">hot month</a> for new unicorns, for example. So <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/07/with-5-new-unicorns-in-first-week-of-2021-are-we-in-for-a-stampede-this-year/">was January</a>. February likely will be more of the same.</p>
<p>Powering those unicorn births are huge rounds led by large funds. In 2020, for example, there were <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/whats-going-on-with-fintech-venture-capital-investment/">at least 97 global fintech rounds worth $100 million</a> or more. That number was up from 92 in 2019 and 66 in 2018. Each preceding year was a prior record.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a>, or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>It&#8217;s possible to see how venture is trending toward bigger, later-stage rounds in other pieces of private market data. Venture capital in Europe during Q4 2020 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/22/how-vcs-invested-in-asia-and-europe-in-2020/">set a record for dollars invested</a>, some $14.3 billion, for example. But that money was spread against the continent&#8217;s lowest deal count since Q4 2019.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995214 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>The result of that divergence has been rising deal sizes in Europe. A median Series B on the continent saw its value double from $10 million in 2016 to $20 million in 2020, for example.</p>
<p>Adding to the pile of numbers, the U.S. startup industry <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/19/late-stage-deals-made-q3-2020-a-standout-vc-quarter-for-us-based-startups/">raised around 90 rounds worth $100 million or more in Q3 2020 alone</a>.</p>
<p>The data goes on and on. If you read <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/20/fintech-startups-and-unicorns-had-a-stellar-q4-2020/">essentially any recent TechCrunch piece</a> concerning the state of venture capital, private rounds are getting bigger as unicorns propagate, and the pace at which the market manages to find exits for the largest startups lags their aggregate value creation.</p>
<p>2021 could be more than just more of the same; this year could set fresh records for private investment results.</p>
<p>Parsing data from Silicon Valley Bank&#8217;s <a href="https://www.svb.com/trends-insights/reports/state-of-the-markets-2021-q1-report">most recent markets&#8217; report</a>, I&#8217;ve pulled a few trends that help illustrate where the startup and private capital markets are heading this year. And, for flavor, I&#8217;ve also collected some data from <a href="https://www2.insightpartners.com/scale-up-report">an Insight Partners&#8217; dive</a> into the impact that middle-aged startups have on job creation. That final set of data will illustrate how quickly the startup market has bounced back from COVID-19 lows to near-record numbers and what that rebound could mean for 2021.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s going to be one hell of a year. Let&#8217;s talk about why.</p>
<h2>2020&#8217;s venture capital market</h2>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/venture-capital-is-going-to-get-even-bigger-faster-and-more-expensive-this-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107792</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Global smartphone shipments expected to rebound 11% this year</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/global-smartphones-shipments-expected-to-rebound-11-this-year/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/global-smartphones-shipments-expected-to-rebound-11-this-year/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 15:31:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5g]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gartner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107823</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Like countless other industries, mobile phone sales got hit hard in 2020. The industry hit a 10.5% decline for the year, as Covid-19 first decimated the supply and later consumer demand for devices. It was the latest in a rough couple of years for manufacturers, but 2020 hit significantly harder than most. New numbers from [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Like countless other industries, mobile phone sales got hit hard in 2020. The industry hit a 10.5% decline for the year, as Covid-19 first decimated the supply and later consumer demand for devices. It was the latest in a rough couple of years for manufacturers, but 2020 hit significantly harder than most.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2021-02-03-gartner-says-worldwide-smartphone-sales-to-grow-11-percent-in-2021">New numbers from Gartner</a> point to a rebound to pre-2020 levels. The firm is forecasting 1.5 billion devices shipped globally for 2021, amounting to an 11.4% increase across the board. We certainly saw the beginnings of that rebound arrive in Q4 for last year, as declines continued to slow, thanks in no small part to a record quarter for iPhone sales.</p>
<p>That points to the beginnings of a so-called “supercycle” for Apple, which hits a sort of perfect storm. The last few years have seen consumers slow down upgrades, as device prices increased, features were generally less compelling and their existing devices were perfectly fine so as not to warrant a standard two to three year upgrade pattern.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3fbi9mxkZs"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/will-apples-spectacular-iphone-12-sales-figures-boost-the-smartphone-industry-in-2021/">Will Apple&#8217;s spectacular iPhone 12 sales figures boost the smartphone industry in 2021?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Will Apple&#8217;s spectacular iPhone 12 sales figures boost the smartphone industry in 2021?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/will-apples-spectacular-iphone-12-sales-figures-boost-the-smartphone-industry-in-2021/embed/#?secret=3fbi9mxkZs" data-secret="3fbi9mxkZs" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Analysts pointed to 5G a clear conduit for righting slipping sales numbers early last year, but a global pandemic very much threw a wrench in all of that. If anything, however, the iPhone’s Covid-19 related delay actually contributed to a stellar quarter for the company, both in time for holiday sales and the arrival of multiple vaccines that pointed to some potential return to normalcy.</p>
<p>The long awaited 5G bump will continue in 2021, according to the new numbers, coupled with a quick push to offer next-gen wireless at an accessible price.</p>
<p>“The growing availability of 5G networks coupled with a higher variety of 5G smartphones starting at $200 will steer demand in mature markets and China,” the firm notes. “Demand in emerging countries will be driven by buyers looking for a smartphone with better specifications and a 5G connectivity as an optional feature. Gartner forecasts sales of 5G smartphones will total 539 million units worldwide in 2021, which will represent 35% of total smartphone sales in that year.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2ZkzEYIGOT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/smartphone-sales-slowed-decline-in-q4-with-a-big-assist-from-apple/">Smartphone sales decline in Q4, with a big assist from Apple</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Smartphone sales decline in Q4, with a big assist from Apple&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/smartphone-sales-slowed-decline-in-q4-with-a-big-assist-from-apple/embed/#?secret=2ZkzEYIGOT" data-secret="2ZkzEYIGOT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/global-smartphones-shipments-expected-to-rebound-11-this-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107823</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Box acquires eSignature startup SignRequest for new content workflows</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/box-acquires-esignature-startup-signrequest-for-new-content-workflows/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/box-acquires-esignature-startup-signrequest-for-new-content-workflows/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 15:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aaron Levie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Box]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SignRequest]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107806</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Box announced this morning that it has agreed to acquire eSignature startup SignRequest for $55 million.The acquisition gives the company a native signature component it has been lacking and opens up new workflows for the company. Box CEO Aaron Levie says the company has seen increased demand from customers to digitize more of their workflows, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://box.com">Box</a> announced this morning that it has agreed to acquire eSignature startup <a href="http://signrequest.com">SignRequest</a> for $55 million.The acquisition gives the company a native signature component it has been lacking and opens up new workflows for the company.</p>
<p>Box CEO Aaron Levie says the company has seen increased demand from customers to digitize more of their workflows, and this acquisition is about giving them a signature component right inside Box that will be known as Box Sign moving forward. &#8220;With Box Sign, customers can have a seamless esignature experience right where their content already lives,&#8221; Levie told me.</p>
<p>While Box has partnerships with other eSignature vendors, this gives it one to call its own, one that will be built into Box starting this summer. As we have learned during this pandemic, the more work we can do remotely, the safer it is. Even after the pandemic ends and we get back to more face-to-face interactions, being able to do things fully in the cloud and removing paper from the workflow will speed up everything.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;The massive push to remote work effectively instantly highlighted for every enterprise where their digital workflows were breaking down. And eSignature was a major part of that — too many industries still rely on paper based processes,&#8221; he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hPUhxrNXZs"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/29/aaron-levie-we-have-way-too-many-manual-processes-in-businesses/">Aaron Levie: &#8216;We have way too many manual processes in businesses&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Aaron Levie: &#8216;We have way too many manual processes in businesses&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/29/aaron-levie-we-have-way-too-many-manual-processes-in-businesses/embed/#?secret=hPUhxrNXZs" data-secret="hPUhxrNXZs" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Levie says that the signature component has been a key missing piece from the platform. &#8220;As for our platform, when you look at Snowflake, they’re the data cloud. Salesforce is the sales cloud. Adobe is the marketing cloud. We want to build the content cloud. Imagine one platform that can power the entire lifecycle of content. eSignature has been a major missing link for critical workflows,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>He believes this will open up the platform for a number of scenarios, that while possible before, could not flow as easily between Box components. &#8220;Having SignRequest gets us more natively into mission critical workflows like customer contracts, vendor onboarding, healthcare onboarding and supply chain collaboration,&#8221; Levie explained.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/28/dropbox-snares-hellosign-for-230m-gets-workflow-and-esignature/">Dropbox acquired HelloSign for $230 million</a> two years ago to provide it with a similar kind of functionality and workflow capability, but analyst Alan Pelz-Sharpe from Deep Analysis, a firm that follows the content management market, says this wasn&#8217;t really in reaction to that.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think what is interesting here is that Box is going to integrate SignRequest and bundle it as part of the standard service. That’s what really caught my eye as the challenge with eSig is that it&#8217;s typically a separate product and so gets limited use. They bought it partly in response to Dropbox, but it was a hole that needed fixing regardless so would have done so anyway,&#8221; Pelz-Sharpe explained.</p>
<p>As for SignRequest, the company was founded in the Netherlands in 2014. Neither Pitchbook nor Crunchbase has a record of it raising funds. The plan is for the company&#8217;s employees to join Box and help build the signature component that will become Box Sign. According to a<a href="https://signrequest.com/en/signrequest-is-joining-box"> message to customers on the company website</a>, existing customers will have the opportunity over the next year to move to Box Sign, and get all of the other components of the Box platform.</p>
<p>Levie says the basic Box Sign function will be built into the platform at no additional charge, but there will be more advanced features coming that they could charge for. The deal is expected to close soon with the SignRequest team remaining in The Netherlands.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KpBH49ILMP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/22/boxs-aaron-levie-says-it-will-take-creativity-and-focus-to-get-through-this-crisis/">Box&#8217;s Aaron Levie says it will take creativity and focus to get through this crisis</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Box&#8217;s Aaron Levie says it will take creativity and focus to get through this crisis&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/22/boxs-aaron-levie-says-it-will-take-creativity-and-focus-to-get-through-this-crisis/embed/#?secret=KpBH49ILMP" data-secret="KpBH49ILMP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/box-acquires-esignature-startup-signrequest-for-new-content-workflows/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107806</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lightspeed&#8217;s Gaurav Gupta and Grafana Labs&#8217; Raj Dutt will tell us why they financially tied the knot (twice!)</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/lightspeeds-gaurav-gupta-and-grafana-labs-raj-dutt-will-tell-us-why-they-got-financially-married-twice/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/lightspeeds-gaurav-gupta-and-grafana-labs-raj-dutt-will-tell-us-why-they-got-financially-married-twice/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 15:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch live announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaurav Gupta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grafana Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed venture partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2106507</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many founders only know their own experience fundraising and don&#8217;t hear much about what other founders went through. On Extra Crunch Live today, we&#8217;re going to remedy that. Grafana Labs has raised upward of $75 million since it launched in 2014. Lightspeed Venture Partners, and partner Gaurav Gupta to be specific, led both the startup&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Many founders only know their own experience fundraising and don&#8217;t hear much about what other founders went through. On <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/check-out-the-amazing-speakers-joining-us-on-extra-crunch-live-in-february/?tpcc=ECTW2020">Extra Crunch Live</a> today, we&#8217;re going to remedy that.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/grafana/">Grafana Labs</a> has raised upward of $75 million since it launched in 2014. Lightspeed Venture Partners, and partner Gaurav Gupta to be specific, led both the startup&#8217;s Series A and Series B rounds. As far as commitments go, that&#8217;s a pretty significant one.</p>
<p>The new and improved Extra Crunch Live pairs founders and the investors who led their earlier rounds to talk about how the deal went down, from the moment they met to the conversations they had (including some disagreements) to the relationship as it exists today. Hell, we may even take a peek at the original pitch deck that made it all happen.</p>
<p>Then, we&#8217;ll turn our eyes back to you, the audience. That same founder/investor duo (in this case, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/radutt">Grafana Labs CEO Raj Dutt</a> and <a href="https://lsvp.com/team/gaurav-gupta/">LVP&#8217;s Gaurav Gupta</a>) will take a look at your pitch decks and give their own feedback. (If you haven&#8217;t yet submitted a pitch deck to be torn down on Extra Crunch Live, <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/Lutrgz8Q">you can do so here</a>.)</p>
<p>The hour-long episode is sandwiched between two 30-minute rounds of networking. From start to finish, it goes from 11:30 a.m. PST/2:30 p.m. EST to 1:30 p.m. PST/4:30 p.m. EST. And Extra Crunch Live will come to you at the same time, every week, with a new pair of speakers.</p>
<p>So let&#8217;s learn a little bit more about Gupta and Dutt.</p>
<p>Before becoming an investor, Gupta enjoyed a rich career in the product development sphere, holding positions at Elastic (where he led product management), Splunk (VP of Products), as well as Google, Gateway and the McKenna Group. He joined Lightspeed in 2019 as a partner, focusing primarily on enterprise software. He&#8217;s led investments in Impira, Blameless, Hasura and Panther, and of course, Grafana. He sits on the board of the last three companies in that list.</p>
<p>Dutt is the co-founder and CEO at Grafana Labs, but the fast-growing company isn&#8217;t his first go at entrepreneurialism. Dutt also founded and led Voxel, a cloud-hosting startup that was acquired by Internap for $30 million in 2012.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re absolutely thrilled to have Gupta and Dutt join us on our first episode of Extra Crunch Live in 2021. As a reminder, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=lightspeedgrafana">Extra Crunch Live is for Extra Crunch members only</a>. We&#8217;re coming to you with a new pair of speakers every week, and you can catch everything you missed on-demand if you can&#8217;t join us live. It&#8217;s worth the cost of the subscription on its own, but EC members also get access to our premium content, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ec-market-map/">market maps</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ec-investor-survey/">investor surveys</a>. Long story short? <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=lightspeedgrafana">Subscribe, smarty.</a> You won&#8217;t regret it.</p>
<p>Oh, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/check-out-the-amazing-speakers-joining-us-on-extra-crunch-live-in-february/?tpcc=ECTW2020">here&#8217;s a look at other speakers you can expect to see on Extra Crunch Live</a>:</p>
<p>Aydin Senkut (Felicis) + Kevin Busque (Guideline) — February 10<br />
Steve Loughlin (Accel) + Jason Boehmig (Ironclad) — February 17<br />
Matt Harris (Bain Capital Ventures) + Isaac Oates (Justworks) — February 24</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s just the February slate!</p>
<p>All the details to register for this upcoming episode (and more) are available below. Can&#8217;t wait to see you there!</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/lightspeeds-gaurav-gupta-and-grafana-labs-raj-dutt-will-tell-us-why-they-got-financially-married-twice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2106507</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Evinced raises $17M to speed up accessibility testing for the web</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/evinced-raises-17m-to-speed-up-accessibility-testing-for-the-web/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/evinced-raises-17m-to-speed-up-accessibility-testing-for-the-web/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 15:02:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accessibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evinced]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2106786</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Making and keeping the web accessible is a full-time job, and like any other development role, accessibility tools need to evolve to keep up with the times. Evinced is a startup that promises both richer and faster checks of websites in production or in progress, and it just raised $17M to take its tools to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Making and keeping the web accessible is a full-time job, and like any other development role, accessibility tools need to evolve to keep up with the times. <a href="https://www.evinced.com/">Evinced</a> is a startup that promises both richer and faster checks of websites in production or in progress, and it just raised $17M to take its tools to the next level.</p>
<p>Because accessibility problems can happy in so many ways, it often takes a lot of manual code review to catch the errors. Even a team thinking about making their site fully accessible from the start — which should be everyone — can miss that this script doesn&#8217;t hook into that variable right if this menu is opened, and so on.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s automated code review, but it can be slow and bulky. Evinced is making a powerful, streamlined tool that checks a website in a fraction of a second while you&#8217;re using it, presenting the problems in a way that&#8217;s easy for devs to share and address. It also doesn&#8217;t trip up on the fancy, javascript-heavy web apps that millions use today.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s an example of a modern website that looks fine but is obviously (for demo purposes) riddled with accessibility issues. The video gives a good breakdown of what this part of the Evinced product does:</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/50sG_BozlMI?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Honestly, that&#8217;s how it feels like it ought to look, but existing enterprise-level tools probably aren&#8217;t quite so efficient. And as you can see, the tool responds instantly while the user (that is to say, the developer) proceeds through the various actions the site enables. It could be, after all, that auditing the site before anyone fills in a form or pulls down any menus could give a misleading green light.</p>
<p>The inspector also brings in a bit of AI in the form of smart rules and computer vision, so if an element <em>looks</em> like a menu or button but isn&#8217;t labeled correctly, it isn&#8217;t fooled. Those elements do have distinct styles and roles: if something can be clicked and turns into a list that the user chooses from, well, it&#8217;s a pulldown menu whether it&#8217;s called that or not.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107061" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/evinced-demo.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107061" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2107061" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/evinced-demo.jpg" alt="Image of Evinced's tool pointing out accessibility problems on a webpage." width="1024" height="530" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/evinced-demo.jpg 1915w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/evinced-demo.jpg?resize=150,78 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/evinced-demo.jpg?resize=300,155 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/evinced-demo.jpg?resize=768,398 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/evinced-demo.jpg?resize=680,352 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/evinced-demo.jpg?resize=1536,796 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/evinced-demo.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2107061" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Evinced</p></div></p>
<p>Naturally there are also quick fixes suggested and the ability to easily export the issues for formal inspection by the boss, as well as other expected features for a web development tool. It&#8217;s available as a Chrome extension, or as an API or automated part of other analysis or commit actions, throwing its list of errors in with the rest.</p>
<p>The company formed back in 2018, when they started development. The next year they hooked up with a few large enterprises to see about integrating and testing within their ecosystems. Capitol One became their biggest customer and is now an investor.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have since deployed our products in production at Capital One (means they are used every day &#8211; and power their end-to-end accessibility operations &#8211; see the Capital One blog) and others. These are paying customers that have an enterprise license,&#8221; said Founder and CEO, Navin Thandani.</p>
<p>Indeed, as Capitol One explains:</p>
<p>Capital One partnered with Evinced early, to guide their development with a particular focus on: helping developers release accessible code integrating multiple automated testing steps through the build and deployment lifecycle building products that can automatically scan for accessibility across a full web property (including through logins and internal repositories), and do this fast.</p>
<blockquote><p>Capital One partnered with Evinced early, to guide their development with a particular focus on: helping developers release accessible code integrating multiple automated testing steps through the build and deployment lifecycle building products that can automatically scan for accessibility across a full web property (including through logins and internal repositories), and do this fast.</p>
<p>We’ve seen Evinced discover as much as 10x more critical accessibility issues than we were previously finding through automated testing alone. An even greater number of issues are discovered when a site is more interactive, including keyboard and screen reader usability issues.</p>
<p>Automated testing on a large enterprise scale can be an extremely complex and time consuming effort. Evinced is speedy and reliable, with 40x faster execution, enabling us to cut our processing time in some cases from 4-5 days down to less than 3 hours (and is being further optimized).</p></blockquote>
<p>Glowing words, even if they are from an investor (technically Capital One Ventures, but still).</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s $17M series A was co-led by M12 BGV, and Capital One Ventures and included previous investors Engineering Capital.</p>
<p>As a sort of debut celebration present, Evinced is announcing its free tiers of service, including an iOS app accessibility debugger, which should be helpful to all the folks making apps who don&#8217;t know a thing about WCAG guidelines and ARIA roles. There&#8217;s also a free &#8220;community edition&#8221; site scanner that admins can sign up to be approved for, and a free trial for enterprises that want to give it a shot.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/evinced-raises-17m-to-speed-up-accessibility-testing-for-the-web/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2106786</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: What’s the recipe for an H-1B?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/dear-sophie-whats-the-recipe-for-an-h-1b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/dear-sophie-whats-the-recipe-for-an-h-1b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 14:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dear Sophie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107560</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What goes into an H-1B petition? How has it changed in recent weeks? Is the lottery going to be wage-based or random?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/dear-sophie-how-can-i-sponsor-my-mom-and-stepdad-for-green-cards/">Dear Sophie: How can I sponsor my mom and stepdad for green cards?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/20/dear-sophie-what-are-bidens-immigration-changes/">Dear Sophie: What are Biden’s immigration changes?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>Extra Crunch members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<hr />
<p><strong>Dear Sophie: </strong></p>
<p><strong>I want to sponsor a potential employee for an H-1B but the process for an H-1B petition seems pretty complex. </strong></p>
<p><strong>What goes into an H-1B petition? How has it changed in recent weeks? Is the lottery going to be wage-based or random?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Hungry to Learn in Hillsborough</strong></p>
<p>Dear Hungry:</p>
<p>This is a great time to get started on the H-1B lottery process &#8212; the time is fast approaching. In my most recent podcast episode about <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/055-h-1b-lottery-planning-part-1/">H-1Bs</a> on Immigration Law for Tech Startups, we covered planning for the H-1B lottery.</p>
<p>For all those foodies out there, in this column, I include a recipe for making your very first H-1B, plus the latest on lottery timing, whether the lottery will be wage-based and pay-to-play, the end of Buy American, Hire American, and changes in how H-1B wage levels are calculated.</p>
<h2><strong>New to the H-1B?</strong></h2>
<p>To get started, if you’re a newbie looking to whet your appetite with what’s involved in the H-1B process, there’s no need for the H-1B lottery season to feel complex or daunting. In fact, I wrote out a recipe so you can easily understand how to cook up an H-1B petition. ;)</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100312" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100312" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2100312" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg" alt="A composite image of immigration law attorney Sophie Alcorn in front of a background with a TechCrunch logo." width="1024" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=1536,1013 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Composite image credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Joanna Buniak <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sophie Alcorn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<h2><strong>Alcorn H-1B Petition Recipe</strong></h2>
<h3>Ingredients</h3>
<ul>
<li>1 hungry employer seeking top global talent</li>
<li>&gt; 1 motivated job seeker(s) from around the world</li>
<li>&gt; 1 experienced business immigration attorney</li>
<li>&gt; 1 compassionate business immigration paralegal</li>
<li>1 package clear communication</li>
<li>1 gallon legal strategy; add more to taste</li>
<li>1 gallon hard work, divided</li>
<li>4 cups enthusiasm and dedication</li>
<li>2 questionnaires</li>
<li>1 Labor Condition Application (LCA)</li>
<li>4 forms for USCIS, 5 if you want to broil the case and eat sooner</li>
<li>1 robust letter of support from the company</li>
<li>To taste: Job seekers’ supporting documents, as needed</li>
<li>For startup flavor: sprinkling of company formation documents</li>
</ul>
<h3>Directions</h3>
<ol>
<li>It’s important to start off the H-1B with a solid legal strategy. Start by combining the employer and job seeker with at least one business immigration attorney and at least one business immigration paralegal. Add communication, half gallon of legal strategy and 1 cup of enthusiasm and dedication.</li>
<li>After the legal strategy has been prepped, separate the rest of the ingredients into separate containers (there will be some overlap).</li>
<li>Take the two questionnaires and distribute evenly between the employer and job seeker. Add to pan over medium-low heat or high heat depending on how soon everyone wants to eat.</li>
<li>Once the questionnaires are evenly browned, remove from heat and examine to make sure everything is cooked properly.</li>
<li>Once the questionnaires are reviewed, use some of the flavors to prepare the Labor Condition Application (LCA). Add in 1 cup of legal strategy and 1 quart of hard work. Let simmer for 7-10 days.</li>
<li>While the LCA is simmering, prep your forms one at a time. Add ½ cup of legal strategy and 2 cups of hard work.</li>
<li>After the forms are prepped, use the remaining legal strategy (more if necessary), 2 quarts of hard work, and 1 cup of enthusiasm and dedication to prepare the letter of support.</li>
<li>Once that’s ready, and the LCA is fully cooked, use ½ quart of hard work to add the glazed forms, LCA and letter of support into a bowl (preferably Adobe Acrobat). After adding the letter of support, fold in the job seekers’ supporting documents. Add 1 cup of enthusiasm and dedication. Add startup sprinkles if desired.</li>
<li>Finally, use the remaining 2 cups of enthusiasm and dedication to bake the case with USCIS!</li>
<li>Allow to cool for 15 calendar days if famished, or 4-6 months if you’re not that hungry.</li>
<li>Enjoy!</li>
</ol>
<p>For those experts out there hungering for the latest H-1B updates, here’s a rundown of what we’ve been seeing over the last two weeks since the Biden Administration took office:</p>
<h2>Lottery timing</h2>
<p>We expect an imminent announcement regarding the details of the upcoming FY2022 H-1B lottery registration process for cap-subject nonimmigrant visa petitions. The electronic registration period lasts at least 14 days, and the latest possible start date will be March 18, 2021. We’re also awaiting details on when the initial registration period will begin; last year it lasted from March 1 to 20. Feel free to listen back to <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/046-get-ready-for-h-1b-fy2022-lottery/">Get Ready for the H-1B FY2022 Lottery</a> for more details on how this worked last year and please stay tuned if you’re planning on filing an H-1Bs this year: Following these dates is crucial.</p>
<h2>Will the lottery be pay-to-play?</h2>
<p>A final rule called “Modification of Registration Requirement for Petitioners Seeking To File Cap-Subject H–1B Petitions” issued under Trump is currently scheduled to take effect on March 9, 2021. It would change the lottery from being random to being allocated based on highest to lowest relative wage. On January 20 the Biden administration instructed all agencies to consider delaying the effective date of certain rules not yet in effect, such as this one.</p>
<p>We’re all waiting with bated breath to see if this new change will go through. So far USCIS has not published any rule in the Federal Register indicating that the wage-based H-1B lottery will be delayed until after the scheduled start date. Also, over the past few days, there are some preliminary indications that the system will go forward as Trump planned, even under the Biden administration. This includes changes to the H-1B registration online tool and the form.</p>
<p>Although a wage-based allocation might make H-1B salaries more expensive for some employers, it would also dramatically increase immigrant security and employer predictability. As we all wait to see what USCIS will decide to do here, you can also access our <a href="https://witty-author-184.ck.page/22abd76a87">free H-1B guide</a> for more information on H-1Bs.</p>
<h2><strong>The end of Buy American, Hire American</strong></h2>
<p>On January 25, President Biden issued Executive Order 14005, “Ensuring the Future Is Made in All of America by All of America’s Workers.” This ends Trump’s “Buy American and Hire American” Executive Order and ensures a broader focus of helping American businesses “compete in strategic industries” and helping “America’s workers thrive.” We anticipate that this change will probably lead to higher rates of U.S.-business-based visas and green cards being approved in the future.</p>
<h2>Changes in wage-level calculations</h2>
<p>There are changes to the way that prevailing wages are calculated for visas such as H-1Bs and the PERM portion of the green card process. White House Chief of Staff Ron Klain indicated that new rules may be withdrawn or delayed. We’ve already seen the Department of Labor withdraw the Office of Foreign Labor Certification H-1B Program Bulletin and a Wage and Hour Division Field Assistance Bulletin (FAB) on LCAs, so it is no longer in effect. Additionally, DOL announced this week that it will delay the rule regarding prevailing wage levels, to not take effect until May 14, 2021.</p>
<p>We’re tracking all the major H-1B changes here, so stay tuned to Dear Sophie for all the latest!</p>
<p>All my best,</p>
<p>Sophie</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">Have a question? Ask it here.</a> We reserve the right to edit your submission for clarity and/or space. The information provided in “Dear Sophie” is general information and not legal advice. For more information on the limitations of “Dear Sophie,” please view our full disclaimer <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/attorney-advertising">here</a>. You can contact Sophie directly at Alcorn Immigration Law.</p>
<p>Sophie&#8217;s podcast, <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/immigration-law-for-tech-startups/id1497746915">Immigration Law for Tech Startups</a>, is available on all major podcast platforms. If you&#8217;d like to be a guest, <a href="https://forms.gle/TsCtSJabKStwiUk88">she&#8217;s accepting applications!</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/dear-sophie-whats-the-recipe-for-an-h-1b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107560</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Edtech valuations aren&#8217;t skyrocketing, but investors see more exit opportunities</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/edtech-valuations-arent-skyrocketing-but-investors-see-more-exit-opportunities/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/edtech-valuations-arent-skyrocketing-but-investors-see-more-exit-opportunities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 14:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101325</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Despite the pandemic, investors don't seem to value remote learning as much as they do tech sectors like e-commerce and fintech.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Less than a year after we put out an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/09/12-major-league-edtech-vcs-discuss-top-trends-opportunities/">initial temperature check survey</a>, it&#8217;s clear that specialist investors are even more bullish on edtech. Bears are hard to find right now: the sector, once undercapitalized, has brought in $10 billion in venture capital funding globally in 2020.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/12-investors-say-lifelong-learning-is-taking-edtech-mainstream/">As investors told us last week</a>, the biggest consumer opportunity in 2021 and beyond is lifelong learning (and portfolio companies have the profits to prove it).</p>
<p>But despite edtech&#8217;s noise, the second installment of our edtech survey shows that VCs think startups haven&#8217;t enjoyed parallel gains from a valuation perspective. The sentiment suggests that despite an apparent revitalization, edtech isn&#8217;t at the same level of &#8220;value&#8221; in investor eyes like sectors such as e-commerce, consumer and fintech.</p>
<p>As Mercedes Bent of Lightspeed Venture Partners said, &#8220;edtech didn&#8217;t tend to have heady valuations before the pandemic, and through 2020 I&#8217;m seeing edtech companies raise at valuations that are reasonable for Silicon Valley; still nothing like what we see in fintech.&#8221;</p>
<p>Now, valuations aren&#8217;t everything — but they aren&#8217;t nothing, either. Where edtech lacks in impressive valuations, investors see it gaining in exit opportunities. Many investors think that the exit environment is set to dramatically change in the next few years.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve already seen Nerdy and Skillsoft, two edtech companies, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/nerdy-varsity-tutors-spac/?tpcc=ECTW2020">go public via SPACs in the past few months.</a> Private equity ownership is an interesting dynamic to be aware of here, especially as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/vistas-3-5b-purchase-of-pluralsight-signals-a-maturing-edtech-market/">Vista recently scooped up PluralSight for $3.5 billion.</a></p>
<p>Here are the investors we spoke to, along with their areas of interest and expertise:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Deborah Quazzo</strong>, managing partner, GSV Ventures<em> (an education fund backing ClassDojo, Degreed, Clever)</em></li>
<li><strong>Ashley Bittner,</strong> founding partner, Firework Ventures <em>(a future-of-work fund with portfolio companies LearnIn and TransfrVR)</em></li>
<li><strong>Jomayra Herrera,</strong> principal, <a href="https://www.cowboy.vc/team">Cowboy Ventures</a> <em>(a generalist fund with portfolio companies Hone and Guild Education)</em></li>
<li><strong>John Danner</strong>, managing partner, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/dunce-capital">Dunce Capital</a> <em>(an edtech and future-of-work fund with portfolio companies Lambda School and Outschool)</em></li>
<li><strong>Mercedes Bent and Bradley Twohig</strong>, partners, <a href="https://lsvp.com/team/">Lightspeed Venture Partners</a> <em>(a multistage generalist fund with investments including Forage, Clever and Outschool)</em></li>
<li><strong>Ian Chiu,</strong> managing director, <a href="https://owlvc.com/ian.php">Owl Ventures</a> <em>(a large edtech-focused fund backing highly valued companies including BYJU’s, Newsela and Masterclass) </em></li>
<li><strong>Jan Lynn-Matern</strong>, founder and partner, <a href="https://emerge.education/team/">Emerge Education</a> <em>(a leading edtech seed fund in Europe with portfolio companies like Aula, Unibuddy and BibliU) </em></li>
<li><strong>Benoit Wirz</strong>, partner, <a href="https://www.brighteyevc.com/">Brighteye Ventures</a> <em>(an active edtech-focused venture capital fund in Europe that backs YouSchool, Lightneer, and Aula)</em></li>
<li><strong>Charles Birnbaum</strong>, partner, <a href="https://www.bvp.com/team/charles-birnbaum">Bessemer Venture Partners</a> <em>(a generalist fund with portfolio companies including Guild Education and Brightwheel)</em></li>
<li><strong>Daniel Pianko</strong>, co-founder and managing director, <a href="https://universityventures.com/team.php">University Ventures</a> <em>(a higher-ed and future-of-work fund that is backing Imbellus and Admithub)</em></li>
<li><strong>Rebecca Kaden</strong>, managing partner, <a href="https://www.usv.com/people/rebecca-kaden/">Union Square Ventures</a><em> (a generalist fund with portfolio companies including TopHat, Quizlet, Duolingo)</em></li>
<li><strong>Andreata Muforo</strong>, partner, <a href="https://tlcomcapital.com/team">TLCom Capital</a> <em>(a generalist fund backing uLesson)</em></li>
</ul>
<h2>Deborah Quazzo, managing partner, GSV</h2>
<p><strong>How has edtech’s boom impacted your deal-making? Has the new interest from generalist investors made valuations too bubbly, or is the market growth helping everyone?</strong></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">We met on Zoom with over 800 founding teams in COVID all over the world. We invested in 14 new companies and are just finishing rounds in two more. Valuation pressures are across tech sectors. I&#8217;d argue that education still lags average tech. The question for edtech is whether there is potential for a $100 billion company in the sector — will TAMs support it.</p>
<p><strong>Edtech has traditionally had few exits. When do you expect to see that change? Are you optimistic about the boom in funding lately? On the other hand, what consolidation do you expect to see?</strong></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Exit volume is rising already with a wide range of strategic and financial buyers of edtech companies — something that didn’t exist before. You will see numerous high-value exits in the first half of 2021. It’s the public market “exits” that have really lagged and that I hope turns around in 2021 and 2022. There are numerous global companies that could go public and the addition of SPAC IPOs creates another positive dynamic.</p>
<h2>Ashley Bittner, founding partner, Firework Ventures</h2>
<p><strong>How has edtech’s boom impacted your deal-making? Has the new interest from generalist investors made valuations too bubbly, or is the market growth helping everyone?</strong></p>
<p>The boom has not directly impacted my deal-making. We tend to work with CEOs looking for category expertise and track record in the space. I do worry about overexuberance creating disappointing returns that sour interest in the sector. There are important TAM, business model, pedagogical and regulatory factors to consider in valuation.</p>
<p><strong>Edtech has traditionally had few exits. When do you expect to see that change? Are you optimistic about the boom in funding lately? On the other hand, what consolidation do you expect to see? </strong></p>
<p>I think that will change shortly … I suspect many of the notable exits will come in future of work/human capital, consumer and in international markets for early education and K-12.</p>
<h2>Jomayra Herrera, principal, Cowboy Ventures</h2>
<p><strong>How has edtech’s boom impacted your deal-making? Has the new interest from generalist investors made valuations too bubbly, or is the market growth helping everyone?</strong><br />
Edtech has a history of going in booms (when investors find new excitement for the sector) and busts (when investors realize the difficulties in scaling companies in the space). We happen to be going through a boom right now, which I think is an overall good thing for market innovation. While valuations across all sectors are expensive right now, I think more capital going toward innovating a sector that has an impact on everyone’s life will result in a net positive. We have a history of investing in the sector and will continue to do so as we see new, category-defining companies arise.</p>
<p><strong>Edtech has traditionally had few exits. When do you expect to see that change? Are you optimistic about the boom in funding lately? On the other hand, what consolidation do you expect to see?</strong><br />
Edtech has had plenty of exits, but they are usually smaller and typically to PE firms or companies that have large distribution channels. There are very few large IPOs. I think we will start to see larger exits for three primary reasons: (I) accelerated consumer adoption of online and hybrid learning will increase market sizes, (II) as educators and institutions get more comfortable with leveraging technology in their practice we may see shorter sales cycle and more budget available, (III) many larger exits tend to be platforms as opposed to content providers (e.g., Canvas, 2U, Instructure) and with a higher standard for infrastructure there is a space for new competitors.<br />
I expect even more consolidation in the bootcamp space. We’re already seeing it with Flatiron, Thinkful, General Assembly, Bloc and many others having already been acquired.</p>
<h2>John Danner, managing partner, Dunce Capital<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/edtech-valuations-arent-skyrocketing-but-investors-see-more-exit-opportunities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101325</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Granulate nabs $30M for software to optimize workloads and latency</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/granulate-nabs-30m-for-software-to-optimize-workloads-and-latency/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/granulate-nabs-30m-for-software-to-optimize-workloads-and-latency/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 14:35:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Granulate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107753</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Services like video streaming, gaming, media-intensive advertising and marketing technology are putting more strain on bandwidth and backend latency than ever before due to the surge of online traffic in the last year. But for most organizations in today&#8217;s usage-based cloud world, that can represent a huge cost in compute power &#8212; or a major [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Services like video streaming, gaming, media-intensive advertising and marketing technology are putting more strain on bandwidth and backend latency than ever before due to the surge of online traffic in the last year. But for most organizations in today&#8217;s usage-based cloud world, that can represent a huge cost in compute power &#8212; or a major investment in a company&#8217;s own latency technology &#8212; to try to address that.</p>
<p>This has created an opportunity for startups building optimization tools. Today, one called <a href="https://granulate.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Granulate</a> &#8212; which has built software for organizations to handle those loads more intelligently and cost-effectively &#8212; is announcing a round of funding after seeing a huge boost in business in the last 10 months, with customer growth up 360% and revenues growing 570%.</p>
<p>The Tel Aviv startup has picked up $30 million, a Series B, led by Red Dot Capital Partners, with previous backers Insight Partners, TLV Partners, and Hetz Ventures, and new backer Dawn Capital also participating.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The timing of this Series B speaks to the demand in the market right now: it comes on the back of Granulate <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/22/granulate-announces-12m-series-a-to-optimize-infrastructure-performance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">closing a $12 million Series A</a> only in April last year. Investors say that its business growth is what prompted them to re-up so soon.</span></p>
<p>“Granulate’s unique technology and impressive growth since their last funding round reflects a rising market demand for their game-changing optimization solution,” said Yaniv Stern, Managing Partner at Red Dot Capital Partners, in a statement. “For companies facing rising infrastructure costs or focusing on operating cost reduction, Granulate offers a solution that can drive additional improvement regardless of any other solutions already deployed by their clients.”</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Granulate is not disclosing its valuation with this latest round, which brings the total raised by the startup to $45 million. </span></p>
<p>The opportunity in the market that Granulate is targeting is the fact that media-heavy content, and services like e-commerce that rely on efficient responsiveness on sites and apps to keep people from abandoning their shopping carts, are all on the rise.</p>
<p>But as companies look to keep customers happy with better quality services, they are also trying to keep an eye on margins and therefore want to keep infrastructure and computing costs low.</p>
<p>Granulate&#8217;s solution is software that sits at the server layer &#8212; either in the cloud or on-premises, as a customer prefers &#8212; that uses AI to detect workloads that a customer tags as important and prioritize them so that they work more efficiently. Granulate said that its software can improve response times by up to 40%, and throughput up to five times, while reducing costs by up to 60%. The company today has partnerships with AWS and Microsoft&#8217;s Azure and is in the &#8220;early stages&#8221; of talks with Google Cloud Platform.</p>
<p>Bigger tech companies like Netflix, Google and Amazon typically invest huge sums to build their own optimization technology, but it&#8217;s an area that smaller organizations (and you can still be huge while still being smaller than companies like Google) will not have the bandwith &#8212; pun intended &#8212; to address in the same way.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are aware of similar things going on inside of Netflix as what we have built,&#8221; Asaf Ezra, co-founder and CEO of Granulate, said in an interview. &#8220;But to us, it&#8217;s a testament of how large you need to be to address this issue and the talent you need to hire to address the lowest level issues.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s customers include at least one major retailer (which it can&#8217;t name), AppsFlyer, Period and PicsArt.</p>
<p>What will be interesting to watch is how the growth of 5G will affect the bigger problem: as Ezra notes, it will undoubtedly improve front-end latency.</p>
<p>&#8220;5g will not cannibalize Granulate,&#8221; he said. &#8220;In fact, when it becomes standard, the round trip time will be reduced for data, but the front end will be less of the ratio of the time, while the back-end latency will become more of the problem. 5g would solve only the access to your server, but not latency at the server itself.&#8221;</p>
<p>Longer term, it&#8217;s likely that Granulate will add more optimization and management solutions around those it already offers for latency, Ezra said, while also looking for ways to stand out apart from others in the same space. Competitors are in the process of some consolidation &#8212; witness <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/03/netapp-to-acquire-spot-formerly-spotinst-to-gain-cloud-infrastructure-management-tools/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spot acquired by NetApp</a> last June &#8212; so features based around a wider platform will likely be a key way to keep customers interested.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/granulate-nabs-30m-for-software-to-optimize-workloads-and-latency/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107753</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon begins testing customer deliveries using Rivian electric vans</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/amazon-begins-testing-customer-deliveries-using-rivian-electric-vans/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/amazon-begins-testing-customer-deliveries-using-rivian-electric-vans/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 14:05:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rivian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107767</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon has started making deliveries to customers in Los Angeles using electric vans designed and built by Rivian. The electric vans, which are part of Amazon&#8217;s 2040 climate pledge, won&#8217;t go into series production until the end of the year, according to an update Wednesday by the company. Amazon declined to reveal how many electric [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Amazon has started making deliveries to customers in Los Angeles using electric vans designed and built by Rivian.</p>
<p>The electric vans, which are part of Amazon&#8217;s 2040 climate pledge, won&#8217;t go into series production until the end of the year, <a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/transportation/amazons-custom-electric-delivery-vehicles-are-starting-to-hit-the-road">according to an update</a> Wednesday by the company. Amazon declined to reveal how many electric vans were in the test fleet.</p>
<p>The customer deliveries are part of continuous testing being conducted by Amazon and Rivian to measure performance as well as safety durability in various climates and geographies. Road tests first started more than four months ago. The current fleet of vehicles was built at Rivian&#8217;s headquarters in Plymouth, Michigan and can drive up to 150 miles on a single charge. Rivian engineers will continue to refine the vehicles for the start of production at its Normal, Illinois factory.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2107782" style="width: 5589px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107782" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2107782 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg" alt="amazon vans-2" width="5579" height="3719" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg 5579w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/amazon-vans-2.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 5579px) 100vw, 5579px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2107782" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Amazon</p></div></p>
<p>In the meantime, these electric vehicles will continue to pop up on delivery routes in up to 15 additional cities in 2021. Eventually, Amazon plans to deploy at least 100,000 electric vans — the size of its order with Rivian — over the next several years.</p>
<p>Amazon and Rivian began testing vehicles four months prior to making customer deliveries, as part of the testing and development process. Amazon is also starting to modify its buildings to accommodate the new fleet of vehicles and has installed thousands of electric vehicle charging stations at its delivery stations across North America and Europe, the company said.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re loving the enthusiasm from customers so far&#8211;from the photos we see online to the car fans who stop our drivers for a first-hand look at the vehicle,&#8221; Ross Rachey, director of Amazon&#8217;s global Fleet and products, said in a statement. &#8220;From what we&#8217;ve seen, this is one of the fastest modern commercial electrification programs, and we&#8217;re incredibly proud of that.&#8221;</p>
<p>The exterior of Rivian-built electric vans share some the same design features found in today&#8217;s gas-powered versions. There are a few more rounded edges and an overall sleeker look to the electric vans.</p>
<p>The real difference is in the electric architecture and the custom features that have been integrated into the vans, including, highway driving and traffic assist features; exterior cameras that can provide a 360-degree view for the driver via a digital display, a larger interior floor space in the cabin to help with drivers getting to and from the cabin compartment, surround tail lights for better braking visibility and three-level shelving and a bulkhead cargo compartment separating door. Amazon&#8217;s Alexa voice assistant is also an embedded feature.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kmhWQVHQ5N"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/amazon-debuts-its-first-fully-electric-delivery-vehicle-created-in-partnership-with-rivian/">Amazon debuts its first fully electric delivery vehicle, created in partnership with Rivian</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon debuts its first fully electric delivery vehicle, created in partnership with Rivian&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/amazon-debuts-its-first-fully-electric-delivery-vehicle-created-in-partnership-with-rivian/embed/#?secret=kmhWQVHQ5N" data-secret="kmhWQVHQ5N" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/amazon-begins-testing-customer-deliveries-using-rivian-electric-vans/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107767</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scratchpad snags $13M Series A to simplify Salesforce data entry</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/scratchpad-snags-13m-series-a-to-simplify-salesforce-data-entry/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/scratchpad-snags-13m-series-a-to-simplify-salesforce-data-entry/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 14:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Craft Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david sacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scratchpad]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107761</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Scratchpad is an early stage startup that wants to make it easier for sales people to get information into Salesforce by placing a notation layer on top of it. Today, it announced a $13 million Series A led by Craft Ventures with participation from Accel. The company has now raised a total of $16.6 million [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://scratchpad.com/">Scratchpad</a> is an early stage startup that wants to make it easier for sales people to get information into Salesforce by placing a notation layer on top of it. Today, it announced a $13 million Series A led by Craft Ventures with participation from Accel.</p>
<p>The company has now raised a total of $16.6 million including<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/scratchpad-announces-3-6m-seed-to-put-work-space-on-top-of-salesforce/"> the $3.6 million seed round</a> we covered in October. Co-founder and CEO Pouyan Salehi says that he wasn&#8217;t really looking to add capital, but the investors understood his vision and the money will help accelerate the product roadmap.</p>
<p>&#8220;To be honest, it actually wasn&#8217;t on our radar to raise again so soon after we raised what I consider a substantial seed. We had plenty of runway, but we started to see a lot of bottom-up user growth, this bottom-up motion just really started to take hold,&#8221; Salehi told me.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He says that lead investor David Sacks, who has built some successful startups himself, really got what they were trying to do, and the deal came together fairly easily. In fact, the company caught the attention of Craft because they were hearing about Scratchpad from their portfolio companies.</p>
<p>The bottoms up approach is certainly something we have seen with developer tools and with software for knowledge workers, but companies often take aim at sales through the sales manager, rather than trying directly to get salespeople to use a particular tool. This approach of getting the end users involved early allows them to gain traction with members of the sales team before approaching management about paid versions.</p>
<p>Traditionally, sales teams don&#8217;t like the tools that are thrust upon them. They are essentially databases and even with a visual interface, it doesn&#8217;t really match up with the way they work. Scratchpad gives them an interface like a spreadsheet or notes application that they are typically using to hack together a workflow, but with a direct connection to Salesforce.</p>
<p>What the paid tiers provide is a way to bring all this data together and get a bigger picture view of what&#8217;s happening on the sales team, and it helps ensure that people are using Salesforce because the data in Scratchpad links to the Salesforce database automatically.</p>
<p>The company has completed the initial work of building the individual salesperson&#8217;s workspace, but the next phase, and part of what this capital is going to fund, is building the team workspace and seeing how this data can flow from individuals to a team view to give management more insight into what their individual reps are doing. This includes notes, which usually don&#8217;t make it into Salesforce, but provide a lot of context about interactions with customers.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s resonating with thousands of users (although Salehi didn&#8217;t want to share an exact customer number just yet). Customers include Autodesk, Brex, Lacework, Snowflake and Twilio.</p>
<p>Sacks says that he liked the viral way the product has been spreading. &#8220;Once a rep starts using Scratchpad, two things tend to happen: it becomes a daily habit, and they share it with their teammates. This phenomena of viral spread is rare and indicates a very strong product-market fit,&#8221; he said in a statement.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jnRYoCkB2f"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/scratchpad-announces-3-6m-seed-to-put-work-space-on-top-of-salesforce/">Scratchpad announces $3.6M seed to put workspace on top of Salesforce</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Scratchpad announces $3.6M seed to put workspace on top of Salesforce&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/scratchpad-announces-3-6m-seed-to-put-work-space-on-top-of-salesforce/embed/#?secret=jnRYoCkB2f" data-secret="jnRYoCkB2f" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/scratchpad-snags-13m-series-a-to-simplify-salesforce-data-entry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107761</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Duality scores $14M DARPA contract for hardware-accelerated homomorphic encryption</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/duality-scores-14m-darpa-contract-for-hardware-accelerated-homomorphic-encryption/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/duality-scores-14m-darpa-contract-for-hardware-accelerated-homomorphic-encryption/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 14:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DARPA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Duality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[duality technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fully homomorphic encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homomorphic encryption]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107583</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Training AIs is essential to today&#8217;s tech sector, but handling the amount of data needed to do so is intrinsically dangerous. DARPA hopes to change that by tapping the encryption experts at Duality to create a hardware-accelerated method of using large quantities of data without decrypting it — a $14.5 million contract. Duality specializes in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Training AIs is essential to today&#8217;s tech sector, but handling the amount of data needed to do so is intrinsically dangerous. DARPA hopes to change that by tapping the encryption experts at <a href="https://dualitytech.com/">Duality</a> to create a hardware-accelerated method of using large quantities of data without decrypting it — a $14.5 million contract.</p>
<p>Duality specializes in what&#8217;s called fully homomorphic encryption. Without descending into the technical details, the main issue with everyday encryption methods — though it&#8217;s also sort of the point of them — is that they render the encrypted data totally unreadable, essentially noise unless you have the key to reverse the process. Doing that is computationally expensive with large datasets, and of course once the data is in the clear, it&#8217;s vulnerable to hackers, abuse, and other dangers.</p>
<p>There are methods, however, of encrypting data such that it can be analyzed and manipulated without decrypting it, and one of those is fully homomorphic encryption. Unfortunately FHE is even more computationally intense than ordinary encryption, ruling it out for applications where gigabytes or terabytes of data are called for. There are other methods of accomplishing the same ends but no one would cry if FHE suddenly became ten times easier.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="myHUquFwXj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/26/datafleets-keeps-private-data-useful-and-useful-data-private-with-federated-learning-and-4-5m-seed/">DataFleets keeps private data useful and useful data private with federated learning and $4.5M seed</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;DataFleets keeps private data useful and useful data private with federated learning and $4.5M seed&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/26/datafleets-keeps-private-data-useful-and-useful-data-private-with-federated-learning-and-4-5m-seed/embed/#?secret=myHUquFwXj" data-secret="myHUquFwXj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>DARPA is as interested as anyone else in this field, though it has considerably deeper pockets than your garden variety encryption wonk. This contract is part of a <a href="https://www.darpa.mil/news-events/2020-03-02">broader effort called DPRIVE</a>, or Data Protection in Virtual Environments, and the stated goal is to develop a special purpose chip — an ASIC pre-assigned the code name TREBUCHET — to accelerate FHE by, hopefully, an order of magnitude or more.</p>
<p>The Duality team will bring in experts from USC, NYU, CMU, SpiralGen, Drexel University, and TwoSix Labs. The company has been in the game for a long time and has actually worked with DARPA before, so this is not new territory for them.</p>
<p>&#8220;<span lang="en-IL">Duality team members have been supporting DARPA-funded innovation and application of FHE for over a decade. Some members of our team developed the first ever prototype HE hardware accelerators under the DARPA PROCEED program starting in 2010 and are lead developers for the PALISADE open source FHE library, first developed for the DARPA SAFEWARE program in 2015,&#8221; said Duality Labs director and principal investigator for the contract, David Bruce Cousins, in a press release.</span></p>
<p>As you can see, they&#8217;re not short on acronyms either.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not totally clear what the timeline is on this, but considering the state of the technologies involved I wouldn&#8217;t expect results before at least two or three years from now.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/duality-scores-14m-darpa-contract-for-hardware-accelerated-homomorphic-encryption/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107583</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple urged to root out rating scams as developer highlights ugly cost of enforcement failure</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/apple-urged-to-root-out-rating-scams-as-developer-highlights-ugly-cost-of-enforcement-failure/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/apple-urged-to-root-out-rating-scams-as-developer-highlights-ugly-cost-of-enforcement-failure/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 14:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Watch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fake reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FlickType]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107704</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple is facing calls to beef up enforcement against fake reviews and rating scams after a developer took to social media to shine a light on unfair practices he&#8217;s forced to compete with as a result of fraudulent activity on the App Store not being rooted out by the tech giant. Kosta Eleftheriou, one of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple is facing calls to beef up enforcement against fake reviews and rating scams after a developer took to <a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1356011069395755009">social media</a> to shine a light on unfair practices he&#8217;s forced to compete with as a result of fraudulent activity on the App Store not being rooted out by the tech giant.</p>
<p>Kosta Eleftheriou, one of the founders of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/fleksy/">Fleksy</a> keyboard app (who was acquihired by Pinterest in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/06/15/pinterest-acquires-the-team-behind-fleksy-a-custom-ios-and-android-keyboard/">2016</a>), has &#8212; since March 2018 &#8212; been applying his expertise in autocorrect algorithms to make typing on the Apple Watch&#8217;s tiny screen not only possible but &#8220;simple, enjoyable and highly effective&#8221;, as <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/davidphelan/2019/03/02/apple-watch-flicktype-gesture-keyboard-app-makes-typing-a-breeze-is-it-any-good/">Forbes&#8217; reviewer put it</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">The App Store has a big problem<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f447.png" alt="👇" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>You: an honest developer, working hard to improve your IAP conversions.<br />Your competitor: a $2M/year scam running rampant.</p>
<p>1/<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f9f5.png" alt="🧵" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>&mdash; Kosta Eleftheriou (@keleftheriou) <a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1356011069395755009?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 31, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>His app, FlickType, has also been described by app reviewers as &#8220;astonishingly accurate&#8221;, a &#8220;fundamentally better keyboard&#8221; and &#8220;way faster&#8221; than the letter-by-letter scribble method Apple supports natively.</p>
<p>User reviews also include a large amount of glowing five-star ratings. The overall rating from users currently is 3.5 because a number of lower scores have pulled down the average. But if you take the time to dig in the developer can be seen responding consistently and constructively to issues being raised by users who leave lower scores.</p>
<p>Sometimes complaints are related to Watch platform issues outside his control (as Apple limits how third party text input can be accessed). Missing features are another common issue &#8212; and in many responses Eleftheriou responds by saying he&#8217;s added the setting the person was after (such as the ability to disable Auto-Correction) or highlighting a &#8220;brand new look &amp; feel to make typing even easier&#8221;. Other times he thanks users for raising bugs that he says have now been fixed.</p>
<p>Anyone reading how specifically each complaint is addressed would be confident the developer of FlickType is working hard to make sure the app meets customers expectations. Even though the overall rating means other Watch keyboard apps are &#8216;rated&#8217; higher overall.</p>
<p>The problem for Eleftheriou is all his genuine hard work is being undercut by copycat app makers who are able to leverage weak App Store enforcement to profit unfairly and at his expense.</p>
<p>The scam goes like this: A bunch of Watch keyboard apps are published that purport to have the same slick features as FlickType but instead lock users into paying eye-wateringly high subscription fees for what is, at best, a pale imitation.</p>
<p>You might expect quality to float to the top of the App Store but the trick is sustained by the clones being accompanied by scores of fake reviews/ratings which crowd out any genuine crowdsourced assessment of what&#8217;s being sold.</p>
<p>Fake reviews outnumber the real deal. It&#8217;s only if you take the time to read through the comments that alarm bells might start ringing&#8230;</p>
<p>&#8220;Wish I read the reviews before buying. I can&#8217;t even get it to work on my watch,&#8221; runs a one-star review of WatchKey, one of the rival apps Eleftheriou has complained about &#8212; which nonetheless has a higher overall rating than his app owing to also having a very large proportion of five-star reviews.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are so sorry for any inconvenienced caused. Please kindly email us to describe more about your scenario so that we can support you as soon as possible,&#8221; is WatchKey&#8217;s generic response to the one-star review.</p>
<p>&#8220;Terrible,&#8221; writes another one-star reviewer. &#8220;I bought this app to use T9 on my watch. I haven’t been able to get T9 to work on my watch, I’ve also reached out to the customer service email that’s listed on the app. But I haven’t gotten a response, I would advise to find a different app.&#8221;</p>
<p>WatchKey&#8217;s response to another abysmal verdict on its software? More platitudes: &#8220;Thank you for your feedback. Unfortunately, we haven&#8217;t received your email yet. Please kindly email us once more via support@vulcanlabs.co to describe more your scenario so we can support you as soon as possible.&#8221;</p>
<p>The pattern repeats across negative reviews. Even one of the &#8216;five&#8217; star reviews warns: &#8220;You need to pay if you want to use the T9. They make you write a review to &#8216;unlock&#8217; and then they ask for a payment.&#8221;</p>
<p>One component of the manipulation involves posting generic platitudes to do the bare minimum required by Apple to manage (genuine) negative reviews. The other is flooding listings with fake five star reviews to ensure the app&#8217;s overall rating remains high. Step 3: Profit.</p>
<p>Eleftheriou&#8217;s Twitter thread highlights some of what he says are &#8220;hundreds&#8221; of fake five star reviews which are being used to drive Watch owners toward downloading the malicious clones &#8212; using wording that refers to non-existent features or references things you&#8217;d be doing on other types of devices (suggesting the text may have been cut and pasted from genuine reviews elsewhere).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Then their glowing 5-star reviews start rolling in:</p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br />&quot;Very happy with it has control alt delete what&#39;s your two of my favorite Keys even though they don&#39;t work&quot; says user Munim Flynn, delighted to be able to invoke the Windows task manager on their Apple Watch. Huh?</p>
<p>&mdash; Kosta Eleftheriou (@keleftheriou) <a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1356011086265237504?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 31, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">There are hundreds of these. And then, there&#39;s hundreds of *real* ones too: <br /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br />&quot;SCAM. What shady business. Downloaded this app on concept. It doesn’t even work. There is no free version AT ALL. You are tricked into downloading and then asked to pay $7.99 per FREAKING WEEK. Wow.&quot;</p>
<p>&mdash; Kosta Eleftheriou (@keleftheriou) <a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1356011094070841348?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 31, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>A quick Google search for &#8216;buy ios reviews&#8217; returns a staggering 643M results &#8212; including ads for companies touting &#8220;app reviews, installs and ratings [as] the best way to improve the rank of your apps at Appstore and Google Play&#8221; and selling &#8220;high quality iOS app reviews with ratings for $2.5&#8230; from 100% Real Users&#8221;.</p>
<p>Clearly selling fake reviews is a booming business &#8212; which in turn speaks to the woeful lack of effective enforcement.</p>
<p>In an extra fake kicker, Eleftheriou found that one of the scammy competitors had even ripped off his own app promo video &#8212; which was demoing the features offered by FlickType &#8212; and used it in ads targeting app consumers on Facebook and Instagram.</p>
<p>Facebook does have policies against third-party infringement (under section 4 of its prohibited content policy) &#8212; but you might as well whistle for pro-active enforcement from the adtech giant. It only acts when it gets a complaint of infringement so preventing abuse of his marketing materials would require Eleftheriou to spend even more of his time hunting for and reporting the malicious ads ripping off his stuff. (&#8220;I did report and Facebook did eventually take it down. But&#8230; I knew this was not going to be any sort of lasting relief,&#8221; he confirms.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">First, they made an app that appeared to fulfill the promise of a watch keyboard &#8211; but was practically unusable. Then, they started heavily advertising on FB &amp; Instagram, using my own promo video, of my own app, with my actual name on it: <a href="https://t.co/knnO6Mbiyb">https://t.co/knnO6Mbiyb</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Kosta Eleftheriou (@keleftheriou) <a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1356011076127625217?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 31, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Of course the really big kicker here is that Apple&#8217;s rules for developers clearly stipulate that submitting fraudulent reviews is a violation of the developer program licence agreement.</p>
<p>Its App Store review guidelines also warn that developers who attempt to cheat the system (such as by manipulating ratings) may only have their apps removed from the App Store &#8212; and could be expelled from Apple&#8217;s developer program entirely.</p>
<p>So &#8212; to put it politely &#8212; it&#8217;s not a good look for Apple that an indie developer with proven expertise and reputation is having to spend so much resource fighting App Store scams because its own enforcement has failed to stamp them out. To the point where he feels the only path forward is to resort to a public call out on social media to highlight systematic enforcement failures.</p>
<p>Eleftheriou tells TechCrunch he decided to raise the complaint on social media after what he describes as &#8220;simply depressing results&#8221; from engaging with Apple&#8217;s official &#8216;app dispute&#8217; channel.</p>
<p>&#8220;They put you in contact with the other developer in question, and oversee the thread while they hope you will resolve the issue with the other party directly,&#8221; he explains. &#8220;The scammers I complained about in that dispute weren&#8217;t even the bigger scammers I mention in my Twitter thread. Yet, the complaint I had with them barely got addressed, and there was no response from Apple whatsoever on the issue of the fake ratings and reviews. Simply a &#8216;if we don&#8217;t hear back from you very soon we consider the matter resolved&#8217;. We even reached out to Apple privately after that but got no response.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;What was most impressive to me, was that in the presence of the Apple legal team, the scammers did not feel threatened one bit &#8212; almost as if they know Apple is unlikely to do anything,&#8221; he adds. &#8220;In my view, Apple simply does not devote enough resources on this area.&#8221;</p>
<p>Since raising the issue on Twitter, Eleftheriou has reported a partial win &#8212; in that some of the apps he had complained about have been taken down from the App Store. (At the time of writing Apple has not made any public statement confirming any action.)</p>
<p>However the developer accounts do not appear to have been banned at this time. &#8220;It&#8217;s astounding that even pulling a scam like that, doesn&#8217;t get your developer account revoked!&#8221; Eleftheriou told us. &#8220;I mean if that didn&#8217;t do it, what would??&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">While the “KeyWatch” $300k/month scam was removed, Apple did *not* take down their developer account. </p>
<p>Not only that, but their other scam, “GPS Speedometer”, remains on the App Store stealing $200k/month from unsuspecting people, with $416/year subscriptions.<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f631.png" alt="😱" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>UNREAL! <a href="https://t.co/gU3R45LskO">pic.twitter.com/gU3R45LskO</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Kosta Eleftheriou (@keleftheriou) <a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1356725679102943232?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 2, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>We reached out to Apple about this issue and it provided some background information related to its developer policies &#8212; which forbid attempts to cheat the system (such as by trying to trick the review process, steal user data, copy another developer’s work, or manipulate ratings or App Store discovery), among other relevant provisions.</p>
<p>We also asked Apple if it&#8217;s considering any policy changes in light of the issues raised by Eleftheriou &#8212; and will update this post with any response.</p>
<p>&#8220;The main issue in my view is not the cloning here. I didn&#8217;t even care that they were using my name, or made their screenshots similar to mine etc. If only there was a system to better prevent fake ratings and reviews, none if this would matter,&#8221; Eleftheriou also told us. &#8220;People would be able to collectively protect themselves through their 1-star &#8216;votes&#8217; but when that system is allowed to get rigged, everything else goes out the window.</p>
<p>&#8220;The promise of ratings and reviews you can trust does not exist any more which erodes consumer trust at an ever accelerating pace,&#8221; he adds. &#8220;I did a Google search to see what those &#8216;companies&#8217; look like, if you want to buy ratings and reviews. These are proper, full blown companies, with support systems, and claims that their ratings won&#8217;t get deleted by Apple, unlike their competitors. It was shocking to see that this is an industry that is thriving.&#8221;</p>
<p>The issue of fake reviews certainly goes far beyond Apple&#8217;s App Store. And is a <a href="https://www.webretailer.com/b/amazon-fake-reviews/">very insidious one</a>.</p>
<p>Fake reviews are pretty much a universal experience across the Internet &#8212; whether you&#8217;re trying to buy stuff on Amazon, looking at places to visit on Tripadvisor or trying to find a local dentist with the help of reviews on Google Maps (in short; don&#8217;t) &#8212; given how many platforms now incorporate user reviews.</p>
<p>But the issue does look especially toxic for Apple.</p>
<p>A core part of the USP for its App Store is the claim that Apple&#8217;s review process sums to a higher quality, more trustworthy experience than alternative marketplaces that aren&#8217;t so carefully overseen.</p>
<p>So a failure to do more to enforce against review scams and rating manipulations risks taking a lot more shine off Apple&#8217;s brand than Cupertino should be comfortable with.</p>
<p>Simply put: Consumers expect a higher standard from Apple. That&#8217;s why they&#8217;re willing to pay a premium for its products. Under-resourcing App Store review and enforcement thus looks like a false economy &#8212; not least because it risks driving quality developers like Eleftheriou away.</p>
<p>If a developer with so much pedigree can&#8217;t reliably sell his wares on the App Store what does that say about Apple&#8217;s &#8216;premium&#8217; marketplace?</p>
<p>The issue is also likely to be increasingly on the radar of consumer watchdogs and regulators in the coming years. The European Union, for example, is planning to bake binding transparency and reporting requirements into <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">incoming platform regulations</a> &#8212; as it seeks to promote <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/14/europe-agrees-platform-rules-to-tackle-unfair-business-practices/">fairness and accountability</a> in digital businesses.</p>
<p>While an <a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/eli/dir/2019/2161/oj">EU Omnibus Directive</a> that came into force at the start of last year &#8212; with a two year deadline for Member States to transpose it &#8212; aims to beef up consumer rights through enhanced enforcement and transparency requirements &#8212; including directly addressing the issue of fake reviews by placing an obligation on traders to take &#8216;reasonable and proportionate&#8217; steps to ensure reviews are genuine, among other measures.</p>
<p>In the EU platforms will soon start being required to &#8216;justify&#8217; their enforcement failures vis-a-vis fake reviews. And if they can&#8217;t, well, the regime includes tough &#8216;GDPR-level&#8217; fines for breaches of consumer protection law. So the costs won&#8217;t only be reputational, as currently.</p>
<p>The UK&#8217;s Competition and Markets Authority, meanwhile, has also been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/08/facebook-and-ebay-pledge-to-do-more-to-tackle-trade-in-fake-reviews-after-pressure-from-uk-regulator/">cracking down</a> on the trade in fake reviews &#8212; specifically targeting Facebook, Instagram and eBay in recent years. Further attention to the issue from UK oversight bodies, which are now operating independently of the EU, also seems likely.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LbgUoOgn8I"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/08/facebook-and-ebay-pledge-to-do-more-to-tackle-trade-in-fake-reviews-after-pressure-from-uk-regulator/">Facebook and eBay pledge to do more to tackle trade in fake reviews after pressure from UK regulator</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook and eBay pledge to do more to tackle trade in fake reviews after pressure from UK regulator&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/08/facebook-and-ebay-pledge-to-do-more-to-tackle-trade-in-fake-reviews-after-pressure-from-uk-regulator/embed/#?secret=LbgUoOgn8I" data-secret="LbgUoOgn8I" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/apple-urged-to-root-out-rating-scams-as-developer-highlights-ugly-cost-of-enforcement-failure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107704</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
