<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 12:01:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Payments giant Stripe launches Stripe Tax to integrate sales tax calculations for 30+ countries</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/payments-giant-stripe-launches-stripe-tax-to-integrate-sales-tax-calculations-for-30-countries/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/payments-giant-stripe-launches-stripe-tax-to-integrate-sales-tax-calculations-for-30-countries/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 12:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164272</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the heels of acquiring sales tax specialist TaxJar in April, today Stripe is making another big move in the area of tax. The $95 billion payments behemoth is launching a new product called Stripe Tax, which will provide automatic, updated sales tax calculations (covering sales tax, VAT, and GST) and related accounting services to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">On the heels of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/stripe-acquires-taxjar-to-add-cloud-based-automated-sales-tax-tools-into-its-payments-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquiring sales tax specialist TaxJar in April</a>, today Stripe is making another big move in the area of tax. The $95 billion payments behemoth is launching a new product called Stripe Tax, which will provide automatic, updated sales tax calculations (covering sales tax, VAT, and GST) and related accounting services to Stripe payments customers initially in some 30 countries and across the U.S.</p>
<p>Stripe Tax is a separate service from TaxJar, but the two are not unconnected: as Stripe Tax was being built out of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/04/stripe-will-establish-an-engineering-hub-in-dublin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stripe&#8217;s offices in Dublin</a> over the last several months, Stripe&#8217;s business lead for EMEA Matt Henderson told me that the team had identified TaxJar as a strong company in the field, and that ultimately led to M&amp;A between them.</p>
<p>Sales tax &#8212; and specifically a more seamless way to deal with charging and tracking sales tax &#8212; is a painful issue for people doing business online. Digital and physical goods are taxed in over 130 countries, Stripe said, and within that there can be a huge amount of variation and compliance complexity, since codes get updated all the time, too. Mishandled sales tax, meanwhile, can result in pretty hefty fines, sometimes up to 30% interest on past-due amounts.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Unsurprisingly, a sales tax tool has been the most requested feature from Stripe&#8217;s customers, Henderson said, a request that presumably only got louder in the last year, as e-commerce and digital transactions went through the roof with Covid-19.</p>
<p>Arguably, that makes Stripe Tax one of the company&#8217;s more significant product launches, not to mention the first since announcing its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/14/stripe-closes-600m-round-at-a-95b-valuation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">monster funding round earlier this year</a>.</p>
<p>Previously, Stripe customers would have resorted to using a third-party service (like TaxJar) to work out sales tax, or more typically those Stripe customers would have opted to limit the number of places they sold goods and services, in order to minimize the pain of dealing with multiple, complex, and usually quite localized tax codes.</p>
<p>Stripe said that a survey of its customers found that two-thirds of respondents said that the challenge of implementing sales tax actually limited their growth.</p>
<p>TaxJar has built a strong system for handling that, but the company &#8212; based out of Massachusetts &#8212; is primarily focused on the U.S. market, which has sales tax that is complicated enough (there are 11,000 different tax jurisdictions in the country).</p>
<p>That leaves a lot on the table for building out sales tax tools for the rest of the world: the wider geographical focus of Stripe Tax thus fills a particular geographical gap for the company, regardless of how well TaxJar and Stripe integrate over time.</p>
<p>There are some other differences worth noting between the two.</p>
<p>TaxJar came to Stripe&#8217;s attention with an established business &#8212; 15,000 customers at the time of the announcement. Stripe (wisely) bolted that on as a standalone business, so new and existing customers that use TaxJar can continue to use it as is. That is to say, at least for now, they do not need to be Stripe payments customers in order to use TaxJar, even if the integration between the two platforms will only improve over time.</p>
<p>Stripe Tax, on the other hand, is being built from the ground up as a product aimed specifically at increasing touchpoints and stickiness with Stripe customers specifically.</p>
<p>Stripe Tax provides real-time tax calculation based on customer location and product sold; transparent itemizing for customers; tax ID management in areas (like Europe) where business customers can provide their code and get a reverse charge on tax if they are under a certain turnover threshold themselves; and reconciliation and reporting across all transactions to make filing and remittance easier.</p>
<p>But, there is for now no way to use Stripe Tax outside of Stripe itself.</p>
<p>This could pose some problems for some customers &#8212; these days many of the strongest retailers will take an &#8216;omnichannel&#8217; approach that might cover selling through marketplaces, selling through websites, selling through social media and more &#8212; and not all of those storefronts might be powered by Stripe. It will be worth watching whether future iterations of Stripe Tax can account for that.</p>
<p>“No one leaps out of bed in the morning excited to deal with taxes,” said John Collison, co-founder and president of Stripe in a statement. “For most businesses, managing tax compliance is a painful distraction. We simplify everything about calculating and collecting sales taxes, VAT, and GST, so our users can focus on building their businesses.”</p>
<p>Stripe&#8217; most significant product launch prior to Stripe Tax &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/03/stripe-announces-embedded-business-banking-service-stripe-treasury/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stripe Treasury</a> &#8212; underscores how the company is currently very focused on diversifying outside of their basic payments business and opening the platform to much wider, more scaled transactions. Treasury, which is still in invite-only mode, saw Stripe partner with established banks to provide a business banking service, providing a way for its customers to handle money that they generate from their Stripe-powered businesses.</p>
<p>The full country list where Stripe Tax is launching is Australia, Austria, Belgium, Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Czech Republic, Denmark, Estonia, Finland, France, Germany, Greece, Hungary, Ireland, Italy, Latvia, Lithuania, Luxembourg, Malta, New Zealand, the Netherlands, Norway, Poland, Portugal, Romania, Slovakia, Slovenia, Spain, Sweden, Switzerland, the United States, and the United Kingdom.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/payments-giant-stripe-launches-stripe-tax-to-integrate-sales-tax-calculations-for-30-countries/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164272</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New South African partnership gets $3M, launches telehealth product</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/new-south-african-partnership-gets-3m-launches-telehealth-product/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/new-south-african-partnership-gets-3m-launches-telehealth-product/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 11:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doktor.se]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthforce.io]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quro Medical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telehealth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telemedicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Webrock Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2163915</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For the early detection and treatment of health conditions, easy access to primary healthcare is crucial. Primary healthcare is best delivered by teams of primary care clinicians coordinating care between them. However, ubiquitous access to such care is scant across Sub-Saharan Africa. There is a real opportunity for digital healthcare platforms to scale access to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the early detection and treatment of health conditions, easy access to primary healthcare is crucial</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Primary healthcare is best delivered by teams of primary care clinicians coordinating care between them</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, ubiquitous access to such care is scant across Sub-Saharan Africa.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is a real opportunity for digital healthcare platforms to scale access to team-based care across the region</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">They can reduce the cost of quality care while improving health outcomes, reach patients in remote areas and reduce the pressure on the traditional medical support systems</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pandemic has seen such platforms scale globally, and Africa is not exempt. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">A new platform (without a name yet) is launching out of South Africa and it wants to provide accessible quality care for Africans with its telehealth service. Today, it has closed a $3 million pre-Series A round to that end</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes, you&#8217;re wondering why the platform doesn&#8217;t have a name (I am too), but what&#8217;s interesting is the fact that a VC firm (Webrock Ventures) and two health tech companies (Healthforce.io and Doktor.se) joined forces to launch this new venture</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here&#8217;s summarized information on the trio.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://webrockventures.com/en/">Webrock Ventures</a> is a Sweden-based investment company that employs a venture-building model. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">So </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">essentially,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the firm partners with tech companies in Sweden and combines its cash with the company&#8217;s business models to create portfolio businesses</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It does this while maintaining a sizeable stake in the company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://healthforce.io/">Healthforce</a> is a South Africa-based health tech company that tries to improve healthcare through multidisciplinary clinical teams</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">So far, it has set up nurses in over 450 clinics across the country while conducting more than 1 million nurse consultations</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Healthforce also has a telemedicine play with over 110,000 consultations since launching the service last year</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a Sweden-based telehealth company, <a href="https://doktor.se/">Doktor.se</a> allows patients to contact healthcare professionals through their smartphones across the whole spectrum of primary care</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Most of its customers are in Europe, as well as in Latin America.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So why form a partnership to launch a telehealth product in South Africa with a plan for further roll-out in other African countries down the line</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Globally, telehealth investments have skyrocketed and increased by more than 50% since the start of the pandemic</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">With many of the fastest-growing economies globally, investors and companies (in this case, Webrock and Doktor.se) are now turning to Africa as a major growth region for such high-demand services</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2164287" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164287" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2164287" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Saul-Kornik-CEO-Co-Founder.jpg?w=680" alt="South African telehealth" width="680" height="606" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Saul-Kornik-CEO-Co-Founder.jpg 1780w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Saul-Kornik-CEO-Co-Founder.jpg?resize=150,134 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Saul-Kornik-CEO-Co-Founder.jpg?resize=300,267 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Saul-Kornik-CEO-Co-Founder.jpg?resize=768,684 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Saul-Kornik-CEO-Co-Founder.jpg?resize=680,606 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Saul-Kornik-CEO-Co-Founder.jpg?resize=1536,1369 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Saul-Kornik-CEO-Co-Founder.jpg?resize=50,45 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164287" class="wp-caption-text">Saul Kornik (CEO &amp; Co-Founder of Healthforce and CEO of the new venture)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, Doktor.se has two models for commercialising its telemedicine application. The first is to use its technology to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">personally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> deliver healthcare services. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The second model licenses the core technology to third parties in markets in which Doktor.se has no intention of expanding</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Doktor.se achieved this with Brazilian health tech startup ViBe Saúde (via Webrock), and last year, the platform had over 1.2 million patient consultations</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It plans to do the same by licensing its technology to deliver care through Healthforce across Africa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By forming a new partnership, a completely new opportunity is set up. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Healthforce can leverage its current position to take core tech from Doktor.se to a new direct-to-patient market</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. In the background is Webrock, a willing investment machine set up to scale the platform.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The new venture will focus on the uninsured, B2C segment through a freemium-type offering</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The platform offers on-demand and scheduled consultations with nurses, general practitioners and mental health professionals</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It also provides chronic care management and will </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be integrated</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with Healthforce’s broader primary care offering</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://za.linkedin.com/in/saulkornik">Saul Kornik</a>, co-founder and CEO at Healthforce, will resume a new role at the newly formed company</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to him, the partnership gives Healthforce an </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">additional</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> product to add to its healthcare product stack</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, it gives Doktor.se the ability to generate license fee revenue from a new market, while Webrock has an opportunity to invest in yet another large developing market</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Webrock and Healthforce partnered to bring funding and strategic/operational capacity to this new pan-African direct-to-patient play, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">respectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">,&#8221; he said to TechCrunch</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. &#8220;All existing independent operations will continue. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, under the NewCo, Healthforce as a major shareholder will expand its primary care product stack and Doktor.se will generate revenue off license fees earned</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sub-Saharan Africa has a healthcare market of about $90 billion. But health insurance coverage is in single-digit (percentage-wise) across countries in Sub-Saharan Africa except for South Africa with 16% coverage. Kornik says the three parties want to tackle a large portion of this challenge and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are aligned</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> about how the healthcare system in Africa could look if it were functioning </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">optimally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;This is a pure-play provider-of-healthcare venture. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Through this pan-African venture, we will deliver high-quality healthcare at low cost to 75 million people through telemedicine, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">literally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> putting healthcare in the palm of their hands,&#8221; he said</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Partner at Webrock Ventures <a href="https://webrockventures.com/en/about/team/#:~:text=Joshin%20Raghubar&amp;text=He%20is%20the%20founder%20of,and%20a%20Yale%20World%20Fellow.">Joshin Raghubar</a> and co-founder and CEO of Doktor, <a href="https://se.linkedin.com/in/martin-lindman-304b4438">Martin Lindman</a>, are enthusiastic about the opportunity Africa presents due to its large population and increasing smartphone penetration</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p>This new venture, which should hopefully have a name soon, is one of the few health tech platforms based in South Africa that have raised seven-figure sums in a fintech-dominated year. In February, <a href="https://hearxgroup.com/">hearX Group, a company that specializes in making hearing healthcare technologies</a>, raised $8.3 million Series A to expand into the U.S. April saw Quro Medical <a href="https://www.quromedical.co.za/">close a $1.1 million seed round</a> to scale its service that manages ill patients in the comfort of their homes. Judging by the spacing between each fundraise, we should see more from the country before the year runs out.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JYr8T62Nhk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/south-africas-quro-medical-comes-out-of-stealth-with-1-1m-to-expand-its-hospital-at-home-service/">South Africa&#8217;s Quro Medical comes out of stealth with $1.1M to expand its hospital-at-home service</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;South Africa&#8217;s Quro Medical comes out of stealth with $1.1M to expand its hospital-at-home service&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/south-africas-quro-medical-comes-out-of-stealth-with-1-1m-to-expand-its-hospital-at-home-service/embed/#?secret=JYr8T62Nhk" data-secret="JYr8T62Nhk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/new-south-african-partnership-gets-3m-launches-telehealth-product/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2163915</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI startup Eightfold valued at $2.1B in SoftBank-led $220M funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/ai-startup-eightfold-valued-at-2-1b-in-softbank-led-220m-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/ai-startup-eightfold-valued-at-2-1b-in-softbank-led-220m-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 11:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Capital One Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foundation capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Catalyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IVP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Vision Fund 2]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164273</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Eightfold AI, a startup which uses deep learning and artificial intelligence to help companies find, recruit and retain workers, said on Thursday it has raised $220 million in a new round as it looks to accelerate its growth. SoftBank Vision Fund 2 led the Series E round of the five-year-old startup, which is now valued [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Eightfold AI, a startup which uses deep learning and artificial intelligence to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/17/two-facebook-and-google-geniuses-are-combining-search-and-ai-to-transform-hr/">help companies find, recruit and retain workers</a>, said on Thursday it has raised $220 million in a new round as it looks to accelerate its growth.</p>
<p>SoftBank Vision Fund 2 led the Series E round of the five-year-old startup, which is now valued at $2.1 billion, up from $1 billion in Series E last October, <a href="http://eightfold.ai">Eightfold AI</a> founder and chief executive <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashutoshgarg893/">Ashutosh Garg</a> told TechCrunch in an interview.</p>
<p>Existing investors General Catalyst, Capital One Ventures, Foundation Capital, IVP and Lightspeed Venture Partners also participated in the new round, which brings the startup’s all-time raise to over $410 million.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Mountain View-based startup provides its clients with a talent acquisition platform that helps them identify suitable candidates and import and filter thousands of resumes. One of Eightfold AI&#8217;s missions is to help companies reduce biases in their hirings, so it masks candidates&#8217; personal information during evaluation.</p>
<p>&#8220;Instead of searching for a job, a candidate can upload their resume and the system will tell the most relevant job for that candidate in real-time,&#8221; explained Garg. &#8220;What this does is, it reduces the drop-off rate. And our clients see more applications &#8212; and field more diverse applications.&#8221;</p>
<p>The startup, which has amassed clients in over 100 countries and offers its platform in over a dozen languages, also enables employers to deploy the Eightfold platform internally and help employees discover promotions and new role opportunities within their organizations.</p>
<p>&#8220;This has helped businesses almost double their internal mobility,&#8221; said Garg, who previously worked at IBM Research, where he filed patents on understanding people behavior, and Google, where he worked on the company&#8217;s user personalization efforts.</p>
<p>Recruiting remains a big global problem and an untapped opportunity. Garg said solving this requires expertise with sifting through a plethora of data points and right talent. Eightfold itself analyzes data it sources from a range of places including employers&#8217; sales, customer management and human resources as well as public sources such as patent sites and publications.</p>
<p>&#8220;Transforming HR and global talent further unlocks trillions of dollars&#8217; worth of human potential. SoftBank shares our bold vision, and we are excited to welcome them as our partner,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>In the state of Indiana, Eightfold maintains partnership for people applying for unemployment insurance to build up their resumes and find job opportunities instantly. The startup also has a program for veterans in the U.S. to help them find opportunities relevant to their skills, said Garg.</p>
<p>&#8220;Powered by AI and machine learning, Eightfold&#8217;s platform provides global enterprises with a single solution for managing the entire talent lifecycle, including hiring, retaining, and growing a diverse global workforce,&#8221; said Deep Nishar, Senior Managing Partner at SoftBank Investment Advisers and who previously worked for nearly six years at LinkedIn. &#8220;We are pleased to partner with Ashutosh and the Eightfold team to support their ambition of transforming how enterprises manage talent and how people build their careers.&#8221;</p>
<p>Eightfold will deploy the fresh capital to accelerate its expansion efforts and invest in hiring more data scientists and engineers, Garg said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/ai-startup-eightfold-valued-at-2-1b-in-softbank-led-220m-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164273</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Corporate services &#8220;super app&#8221; Osome lands $16M Series A</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/corporate-services-super-app-osome-lands-16m-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/corporate-services-super-app-osome-lands-16m-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 11:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accounting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Osome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMEs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164241</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Osome, a startup that combines multiple corporate services for SMEs into one “super app,” has raised a $16 million Series A. The round included returning investors Target Global, AltaIR Capital and Phystech Ventures, and new backers S16VC and venture capitalist Peng T. Ong, who joined as an angel investor. The Singapore-based startup’s last funding round [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://osome.com/">Osome</a>, a startup that combines multiple corporate services for SMEs into one “super app,” has raised a $16 million Series A. The round included returning investors Target Global, AltaIR Capital and Phystech Ventures, and new backers S16VC and venture capitalist Peng T. Ong, who joined as an angel investor.</p>
<p>The Singapore-based startup’s last funding round was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/singapore-based-digital-business-assistant-osome-raises-3-million/">$3 million announced in November</a>. Its Series A brings Osome’s total funding since it was founded in 2017 to $24.5 million. It now claims to be used by 6,000 companies in Singapore, the United Kingdom and Hong Kong, giving it $9.5 million in annual recurring revenue and 100% year-over-year revenue growth.</p>
<p>Its Series A will be used on international expansion and product integrations. Osome, which employs a total of 200 people, has seen fast adoption by e-commerce companies in particular, and plans to launch more products and apps for the sector over the next 18 months.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sAhuCxOBjE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/singapore-based-digital-business-assistant-osome-raises-3-million/">Singapore-based digital business assistant Osome raises $3 million</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Singapore-based digital business assistant Osome raises $3 million&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/singapore-based-digital-business-assistant-osome-raises-3-million/embed/#?secret=sAhuCxOBjE" data-secret="sAhuCxOBjE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Co-founder and chief executive officer Victor Lysenko told TechCrunch that the company started “looking at the e-commerce segment some time ago, but wanted to be confident that our product can handle the increased complexity and transaction volume of e-commerce businesses before launching marketing. The pandemic has caused the e-commerce industry to grow significantly faster and that was also a factor for us.”</p>
<p>He added that Osome will add integrations with multiple e-commerce platforms and administrative services, with the goal of cutting hours out of the time e-commerce company owners spend on accounting each week.</p>
<p>Osome’s flagship product is online accounting services for SMEs, connecting companies with chartered accountants. It also offers corporate secretary services, including business registration, compliance and taxation. The platform uses machine learning tech to automate many tasks—for example, it categorizes, tags and stores documents, creates management reports and tax returns and files paperwork on time.</p>
<p>Lysenko said entrepreneurs on average spend 68% of their time dealing with back-office tasks, instead of strategizing their company’s goals. Osome is meant to reduce the burden of administrative work on small businesses and demand for its services grew during the pandemic as companies moved more of their operations online.</p>
<p>Singapore makes it relatively easy to incorporate businesses online, so several other startups in the same space are based there. These include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/03/sleek/">Sleek</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/07/lanturn-a-singaporean-tech-enabled-corporate-services-provider-raises-3-million-seed-round/">Lanturn</a> and BlueMeg, all focused on automating accounting and other time-consuming tasks for SMEs.</p>
<p>In a statement about the funding, S16VC co-founder Aleks Shamis said, “I’ve done business with small and medium e-commerce in 10 countries and see the same inefficiencies in manual accounting across all of them. It is a real problem that will definitely be solved, and Osome is technologically and traction-wise among the few companies in the world in getting there.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WgdzpcFBOa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/28/once-a-buzzword-digital-transformation-is-reshaping-markets/">Once a buzzword, digital transformation is reshaping markets</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Once a buzzword, digital transformation is reshaping markets&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/28/once-a-buzzword-digital-transformation-is-reshaping-markets/embed/#?secret=WgdzpcFBOa" data-secret="WgdzpcFBOa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/corporate-services-super-app-osome-lands-16m-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164241</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nexford University lands $10.8M pre-Series A to scale its flexible remote learning platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/nexford-university-lands-10-8m-pre-series-a-to-scale-its-flexible-remote-learning-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/nexford-university-lands-10-8m-pre-series-a-to-scale-its-flexible-remote-learning-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 08:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Future Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[higher education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IBM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Massive Open Online Course]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nexford University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tech startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[university]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164226</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two profound problems face the higher education sector globally &#8212; affordability and relevance. Whether you live in Africa, Europe, or the U.S., a major reason why people don&#8217;t go to university or college or even drop out because they cannot afford tuition fees. On the other hand, relevance shows the huge gap between what traditional [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Two profound problems face the higher education sector globally &#8212; affordability and relevance. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whether you live in Africa, Europe, or the U.S., a major reason why people don&#8217;t go to university or college or even drop out because they cannot afford tuition fees</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the other hand</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, relevance shows the huge gap between what traditional universities teach and what global employers actually look for. It&#8217;s not a secret that universities focus a bit too much on theory.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the past few years, there has been the emergence of </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">a number of</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> alternative credential providers trying to provide students with the necessary skills to earn and make a living. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nexford University is one of such platforms, and today, it has a closed $10.8 million pre-Series A funding round</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dubai-based VC Global Ventures led the new round</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other investors include Future Africa&#8217;s new thematic fund (focused on education), angel investors, and family offices. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unnamed VCs from 10 countries, including the U.S., U.K., France, Dubai, Switzerland, Qatar, Nigeria, Egypt and Saudi Arabia, also took part</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To date, Nexford has raised $15.3 million, following the first tranche of $4.5 million in seed funding raised two years ago.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://uk.linkedin.com/in/ftarzi">Fadl Al Tarzi</a> launched <a href="https://www.nexford.org/">Nexford University</a> in 2019. The tech-enabled university is filling affordability and relevance gaps by providing access to quality and affordable education.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;That way, you get the best of both worlds,&#8221; CEO Al Tarzi said to TechCrunch. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;You get practical skills that you can put to work immediately or for your future career while </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">actively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> keeping a job</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. So the whole experience </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is designed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as a learning as a service model.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nexford Unversity lets students study at their own pace. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once they apply and get admitted into either a degree program or a course program, they choose how fast or slow they want the program to be</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2164258" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164258" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2164258" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-Headshot_Fadl.jpg?w=680" alt="Nexford University" width="680" height="646" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-Headshot_Fadl.jpg 2362w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-Headshot_Fadl.jpg?resize=150,143 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-Headshot_Fadl.jpg?resize=300,285 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-Headshot_Fadl.jpg?resize=768,730 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-Headshot_Fadl.jpg?resize=680,646 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-Headshot_Fadl.jpg?resize=1536,1459 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-Headshot_Fadl.jpg?resize=2048,1946 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Copy-of-Headshot_Fadl.jpg?resize=50,48 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164258" class="wp-caption-text">Fadl Al Tarzi (CEO, Nexford University)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The CEO says whatever students learn on the platform is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">directly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> applicable to their jobs</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Currently, Nexford offers undergraduate degrees in business administration; 360</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">°</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> marketing; AI &amp; automation; building a tech startup; business analytics; business in emerging markets; digital transformation; e-commerce; and product management. Its graduate degrees are business administration, advanced AI, e-commerce, hyperconnectivity, sustainability, and world business.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nexford&#8217;s tuition structure is very different from traditional universities because it&#8217;s modelled monthly. Its accredited degrees cost between $3,000 to $4,000 paid in monthly instalments. In Nigeria, for instance, an MBA costs about $160 a month, while a bachelor degree costs $80 a month. But the catch for the monthly instalment structure means the faster a learner graduates, the less they pay.</span></p>
<h2>What&#8217;s it like learning with Nexford University?</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nexford University doesn&#8217;t offer standardized and theoretical tests or assignments as most traditional universities do. Al Tarzi says the company employs what he calls a competency-based education model where students prove mastery by working on practical projects.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For instance, a student working on an accounting course will most likely need to create a P&amp;L statement, analyze balance sheets and identify where the error is to correct it. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The platform then gives the student different scenarios showing companies with different revenues and expense levels. The task? </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">To analyse and extract certain ratios to help make sense of which company is profitable and the other unit economics involved</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though Nexford plays in the edtech space, Al Tarzi doesn&#8217;t think the company is an edtech company. As a licensed and accredited online university, Nexford has a huge amount of automation across the organization and provides students with support from faculty and career advisors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After offering degrees, Nexford puts on its placement hats by fixing its graduates with partner employers</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There&#8217;s a big shortage of jobs in Nigeria, and despite the high unemployment, it&#8217;s actually difficult to find </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">extremely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> qualified entry-level graduates. So Nexford has carried out </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">several</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> partnerships where employers sponsor their employees or soon-to-be employees for upskilling and rescaling purposes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An illustration is with Sterling Bank, a local bank in the country. Most Nigerian banks</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> have yearly routines where they hire graduates and put them on weeks-long training programs</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Sterling Bank employs any candidate it feels did great after</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the capital intensive (eight weeks in most cases) programs</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So what Nexford has done is to partner with Sterling to fund the tuition for high school leavers. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">When these students go through Nexford&#8217;s programs for the first year, they begin to get part-time placements at Sterling</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Upon graduation, they get a job in the bank.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;That saves Sterling the training cost and our tuition fee is almost equal to the training that they provided for students</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Also, students start paying back once they get placed, so it&#8217;s a win-win.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2164263 aligncenter" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screenshot-151.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="290" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screenshot-151.png 1349w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screenshot-151.png?resize=150,64 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screenshot-151.png?resize=300,128 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screenshot-151.png?resize=768,328 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screenshot-151.png?resize=680,290 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screenshot-151.png?resize=50,21 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nexford University has learners from 70 countries, with Nigeria its biggest market yet</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Nexford also has blue-chip partnerships with Microsoft, LinkedIn Learning, and IBM </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">to provide access to tools, courses and programmes to improve the learning experience.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the major gains of this learning experience is how it prepares people for remote jobs. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nexford is bullish on its virtual skills grid, where people will get jobs </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">remotely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> regardless of their location on the platform</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Across Sub Saharan Africa by the year 2026, there&#8217;s gonna be a shortage of about 100 million university seats as a result of huge growth in youth population not met by growth and supply. Even if you want to build universities fast, you wouldn&#8217;t be able to meet the demand. And that spirals down to the job market. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We don&#8217;t think</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the local economy will produce enough jobs in Nigeria, for instance. But we want to enable people to get remote jobs across the world and not </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">necessarily</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> have to migrate.&#8221; </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last year, Nexford&#8217;s revenues grew by 300%. This year, the company hopes to triple the size of its enrollment from last year, the CEO said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nexford is big on designing students&#8217; curriculum based on analysis of what their employer needs</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Al Tarzi tells me that the company always follow the Big Data approach, asking themselves, &#8220;how do we find out what employers worldwide are looking for and keep our curriculum alive and relevant?&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We develop proprietary technology that enables us to analyze job vacancies as well as </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">several</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> other data sources; use AI to understand how those data sets and build a curriculum based on those findings. So, in short, we start with the end in mind,&#8221; he answers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company is keen on improving its technology regardless. It wants to analyse skills more accurately and automate more functions to enhance user experience. That&#8217;s what the funding will be used for in addition to fuelling its regional expansion plans (particularly in Asia) and investing in growth and product development. Per the latter,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the online university says it will be launching partner programs with more employers globally to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">facilitate</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> both placement and upskilling and rescaling. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Merging both worlds of tech and the traditional university model is no easy feat. The former is about efficiency, user-centricity, product, among others. The latter embodies rigidity and continues to lag behind fast-paced innovation. And while t</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">here&#8217;s been a boom in edtech, most startups try to circumvent the industry&#8217;s bureaucracy by launching an app or a MOOC</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Nexford&#8217;s model of running a degree-granting, licensed, accredited, and regulated university is more challenging but in it lies so much opportunity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/eaboyeji">Iyin Aboyeji</a>, Future Africa general partner CEO, understands this. It&#8217;s one reason why the company is the first investment out of Future Africa&#8217;s soon-to-be-launched fund focused on the future of learning and why he believes the company is a game-changer for higher education in Africa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“During the pandemic, while many universities in Nigeria </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">were shut</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> down due to labour disputes, Nexford was already delivering an innovative and affordable new model of online higher education designed for a skills-based economy.&#8221;  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For general partner at Global Ventures <a href="https://ae.linkedin.com/in/noor-sweid-4b5233">Noor Sweid</a>, Nexford University is redressing the mismatch between the supply of talent and the demands of today&#8217;s digital economy. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are thrilled</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to partner with Fadl and the Nexford team on their journey toward expanding access to universal quality higher education in emerging markets,” she said.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/nexford-university-lands-10-8m-pre-series-a-to-scale-its-flexible-remote-learning-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164226</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yousign raises $36.6 million to build a European alternative to DocuSign</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/yousign-raises-36-6-million-to-build-a-european-alternative-to-docusign/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/yousign-raises-36-6-million-to-build-a-european-alternative-to-docusign/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contract]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-signature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yousign]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2163963</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup Yousign has raised a $36.6 million Series A funding round (€30 million). Lead Edge Capital is leading the round and eFounders is investing once again in the company. Yousign, as the name suggests, is an e-signature provider that complies with European regulation on digital signatures. While the company was originally founded in 2013, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://yousign.com">Yousign</a> has raised a $36.6 million Series A funding round (€30 million). <a href="https://leadedge.com">Lead Edge Capital</a> is leading the round and eFounders is investing once again in the company. Yousign, as the name suggests, is an e-signature provider that complies with European regulation on digital signatures.</p>
<p>While the company was originally founded in 2013, Yousign teamed up with startup studio <a href="https://www.efounders.com">eFounders</a> in 2019. Following this deal, eFounders has become a key shareholders and a strategic partner.</p>
<p>Things have changed quite a lot since then as the e-signature market has grown tremendously. You may be familiar with DocuSign, Adobe Sign, SignNow, HelloSign and a bunch of other players. But none of them have been designed for the European market from the ground up.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Yousign wants to become the European alternative to these American companies. More specifically, the startup thinks it can convince small and medium companies that aren’t using an e-signature solution yet. Instead of asking DocuSign customers to switch, Yousign wants to convert new customers to e-signatures.</p>
<p>“Faced with American giants with large scopes and complex products, we have built a solution that is accessible and easy to use, allowing SMBs to sign their first documents within the hour, and not a month” Yousign co-founder and CEO Luc Pallavidino said in a statement.</p>
<p>Yousign is a certification authority and complies with eIDAS — a European framework for e-signatures. It means that signatures are legally binding and the service archives your documents in partnership with <a href="https://arkhineo.com">Arkhineo</a>.</p>
<p>Like other e-signature services, you can create document templates, approval workflows and reminders. Yousign makes sure the right person is signing the document with strong authentication processes and all events are timestamped. It’s a SaaS product, which means you have to pay a subscription fee to access the service.</p>
<p>With today’s funding round, Yousign wants to reach 50,000 European SMBs by 2024 — it has 6,000 clients today. That would represent an annual recurring revenue of $85 million (€70 million). In 2020 alone, the company grew drastically from 35 to 120 employees. The startup now plans to hire 150 additional employees over the next 18 months.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hE59wtKF5G"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/23/efounders-backs-yousign-to-build-a-european-esignature-company/">eFounders backs Yousign to build a European e-signature company</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;eFounders backs Yousign to build a European e-signature company&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/23/efounders-backs-yousign-to-build-a-european-esignature-company/embed/#?secret=hE59wtKF5G" data-secret="hE59wtKF5G" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/yousign-raises-36-6-million-to-build-a-european-alternative-to-docusign/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2163963</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tata Digital to acquire majority stake in online pharmacy 1mg</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/tata-digital-to-acquire-majority-stake-in-online-pharmacy-1mg/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/tata-digital-to-acquire-majority-stake-in-online-pharmacy-1mg/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 06:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1mg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tata Digital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164235</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tata Digital, the subsidiary of Tata Sons, said on Thursday it is acquiring a majority stake in digital health startup 1mg, the latest in a series of investments as the salt-to-steel Indian conglomerate enters the digital consumer space. The firms didn&#8217;t share the financial details of the deal, but a person familiar with the matter [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tata Digital, the subsidiary of Tata Sons, said on Thursday it is acquiring a majority stake in digital health startup 1mg, the latest in a series of investments as the salt-to-steel Indian conglomerate <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/tata-digital-to-invest-75-million-in-curefit/">enters the digital consumer space</a>.</p>
<p>The firms didn&#8217;t share the financial details of the deal, but a person familiar with the matter told TechCrunch that 1mg has received over $220 million in primary and secondary investments &#8212; with participation from some existing investors &#8212; and is being valued at around $450 million. Tata Digital has acquired about 55% stake in the Indian startup, the person said, requesting anonymity as the specifics of the deal are private.</p>
<p>A spokesperson for Tata Digital declined to comment. 1mg didn&#8217;t immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>According to insight firm Tracxn, 1mg had raised $156 million prior to Thursday&#8217;s announcement and was last valued at $242 million. 1mg counts Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation and Sequoia Capital India among its investors.</p>
<p>1mg is one of the largest players in the health space in India, where it competes with Prosus Ventures-backed PharmEasy, which leads the market. 1mg operates diagnostics labs, has a supply chain that covers over 20,000 Indian zipcodes, and is a major business-to-business distributor of medicines in the South Asian nation.</p>
<p>Tata Digital said its investment in 1mg is in line with the giant&#8217;s &#8220;vision of creating a digital ecosystem which addresses the consumer needs across categories in a unified manner.&#8221; The giant, which announced plans to invest in fitness startup CureFit earlier this week, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/tata-group-reaches-agreement-to-buy-majority-stake-in-bigbasket/">acquired a majority stake in online grocer BigBasket</a> earlier this year.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are delighted to join hands with one of India&#8217;s most iconic and respected conglomerates,&#8221; said Prashant Tandon, co-founder and chief executive of 1mg, in a statement. &#8220;This marks a significant milestone in 1mg&#8217;s journey to make high quality healthcare products and services accessible to customers across India.&#8221;</p>
<p>Tata, which owns consumer brands including Tata Tea, Tetley, Vitax, Eight O’Clock Coffee, Himalayan Natural Mineral Water, Tata Coffee Grand and Joekels, reaches over 200 million households in India and has an &#8220;unparalleled ability to leverage the Tata brand in consumer products,&#8221; wrote analysts at HDFC Bank last month.</p>
<p><em>The story was updated throughout with additional details. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/tata-digital-to-acquire-majority-stake-in-online-pharmacy-1mg/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164235</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dracula Technologies turns ambient light into energy with printed solar cells</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/dracula-technologies-turns-ambient-light-into-energy-with-printed-solar-cells/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/dracula-technologies-turns-ambient-light-into-energy-with-printed-solar-cells/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 06:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clean tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dracula Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[organic photovoltaic technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar cells]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solar Power]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164236</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Internet of Things devices are proliferating, making daily tasks more convenient for many people—but that comes at cost. The United Nations expects the amount of e-waste created globally to reach 52.2 million metric tons this year, and a sizable portion of that are dead batteries. Dracula Technologies, a French startup that is currently exhibiting virtually [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2164237" style="width: 774px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/dracos.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164237" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2164237 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/dracos.png" alt="A bat-shaped organic photovoltaic module from Dracula Technologies" width="764" height="510" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/dracos.png 764w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/dracos.png?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/dracos.png?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/dracos.png?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/dracos.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 764px) 100vw, 764px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2164237" class="wp-caption-text">A bat-shaped organic photovoltaic module from Dracula Technologies</p></div></p>
<p>Internet of Things devices are proliferating, making daily tasks more convenient for many people—but that comes at cost. The United Nations expects the amount of e-waste created globally <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/telecom/internet/the-internet-of-trash-iot-has-a-looming-ewaste-problem">to reach 52.2 million metric tons</a> this year, and a sizable portion of that are dead batteries.</p>
<p><a href="https://dracula-technologies.com/">Dracula Technologies</a>, a French startup that is currently <a href="https://virtual.computextaipei.com.tw/index">exhibiting virtually at Computex</a>, wants to help with its inkjet-printed organic photovoltaic (OPV, or organic solar cells) technology. Called LAYER (or Light As Your Energetic Response), Dracula Technologies’ OPV modules run indoors on natural or artificial ambient light, and can be used to power low-consumption indoor devices. Because they are printed and not made of silicon, the OPV modules&#8217; shape is more customizable and, unlike many batteries, it does not use rare earths or heavy metals. Instead, the modules are created from carbon-based material.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In addition to being better for the environment, LAYER is also more economical—the company claims it can reduce the total cost of ownership by four times compared to batteries.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="11SAcCNMTh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/exeger-takes-38m-to-ramp-up-production-of-its-flexible-solar-cells-for-self-powered-gadgets/">Exeger takes $38M to ramp up production of its flexible solar cells for self-powered gadgets</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Exeger takes $38M to ramp up production of its flexible solar cells for self-powered gadgets&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/exeger-takes-38m-to-ramp-up-production-of-its-flexible-solar-cells-for-self-powered-gadgets/embed/#?secret=11SAcCNMTh" data-secret="11SAcCNMTh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Dracula Technologies is currently working with manufacturers, including a partnership with Japanese semiconductor company Renesas Electronics and AND Technology Research (ANDtr) to <a href="https://andtr.com/renesas-electronics-and-dracula-technologies-press-release">create a self-powering, battery-less IoT device</a> that can send messages through BLE to a mobile app.</p>
<p>Dracula Technologies was founded in 2011, after a project in collaboration with the CEA (Commissariat à l&#8217;énergie atomique et aux énergies alternatives, or the French Alternative Energies and Atomic Energy Commission), a public research organization. Chief executive officer Brice Cruchon saw the tech’s commercial potential and after six years of research and development, LAYER was launched through the <a href="https://hello-tomorrow.org/">Hello Tomorrow program</a> for deep tech startups</p>
<p>So far, Dracula Technologies has raised a total of 4.4 million euros (about $5.4 million USD), including a 2 million euros round in 2016 from angel investors for a pilot line, and 2.4 million euros raised last year from MGI Digital and ISRA Cards, which Dracula Technologies is using to increase the production of its photovoltaic modules during its pre-industrialization stage. The company plans to move to its industrial phase in 2024, with the goal of producing millions of modules per year.</p>
<p>MGI Digital, a digital printing and finishing tech company, and ISRA Cards, which makes high-value electronic cards (like licenses or gift and loyalty cards), are Dracula Technologies’ industrial partners. It is also part of the Solar Impulse Foundation’s #1000 Solutions, a guide to green energy solutions that can be implemented on a large scale.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="c1l2crQhvm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/18/despite-pandemic-setbacks-the-clean-energy-future-is-underway/">Despite pandemic setbacks, the clean energy future is underway</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Despite pandemic setbacks, the clean energy future is underway&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/18/despite-pandemic-setbacks-the-clean-energy-future-is-underway/embed/#?secret=c1l2crQhvm" data-secret="c1l2crQhvm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/dracula-technologies-turns-ambient-light-into-energy-with-printed-solar-cells/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164236</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BukuWarung, a fintech for Indonesian MSMEs, scores $60M Series A led by Valar and Goodwater</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/bukuwarung-a-fintech-for-indonesian-msmes-scores-60m-series-a-led-by-valar-and-goodwater/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/bukuwarung-a-fintech-for-indonesian-msmes-scores-60m-series-a-led-by-valar-and-goodwater/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BukuWarung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital bookkeeping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MSMEs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2163590</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BukuWarung, a fintech focused on Indonesia’s micro, small and medium enterprises (MSMEs), announced today it has raised a $60 million Series A. The oversubscribed round was led by Valar Ventures, marking the firm’s first investment in Indonesia, and Goodwater Capital. The Jakarta-based startup claims this is the largest Series A round ever raised by a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://bukuwarung.com/">BukuWarung</a>, a fintech focused on Indonesia’s micro, small and medium enterprises (MSMEs), announced today it has raised a $60 million Series A. The oversubscribed round was led by Valar Ventures, marking the firm’s first investment in Indonesia, and Goodwater Capital. The Jakarta-based startup claims this is the largest Series A round ever raised by a startup focused on services for MSMEs. BukuWarung did not disclose its valuation, but sources tell TechCrunch it is estimated to be between $225 million to $250 million.</p>
<p>Other participants included returning backers and angel investors like Aldi Haryopratomo, former chief executive officer of payment gateway GoPay, Klarna co-founder Victor Jacobsson and partners from SoftBank and Trihill Capital.</p>
<p>Founded in 2019, BukuWarung’s target market is the more than 60 million MSMEs in Indonesia, <a href="https://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/sites/67ce6854-en/index.html?itemId=/content/component/67ce6854-en">according to data</a> from the Ministry of Cooperatives and SMEs. These businesses <a href="https://www.asia-pacific.undp.org/content/rbap/en/home/presscenter/articles/2021/MSMEs-bear-the-brunt.html">contribute</a> about 61% of the country&#8217;s gross domestic product and employ 97% of its workforce.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>BukuWarung’s services, including digital payments, inventory management, bulk transactions and a Shopify-like e-commerce platform called Tokoko, are designed to digitize merchants that previously did most of their business offline (many of its clients started taking online orders during the COVID-19 pandemic). It is building what it describes as an “operating system” for MSMEs and currently claims more than 6.5 million registered merchant in 750 Indonesian cities, with most in Tier 2 and Tier 3 areas. It says it has processed about $1.4 billion in annualized payments so far, and is on track to process over $10 billion in annualized payments by 2022.</p>
<p>BukuWarung’s new round brings its total funding to $80 million. The company says its growth in users and payment volumes has been capital efficient, and that more than 90% of its funds raised have not been spent. It plans to add more MSME-focused financial services, including lending, savings and insurance, to its platform.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HYruIjV0QA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/02/meet-bukuwarung-the-bookkeeping-app-built-for-indonesias-60-million-micro-merchants/">Meet BukuWarung, the bookkeeping app built for Indonesia&#8217;s 60 million &#8220;micromerchants&#8221;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Meet BukuWarung, the bookkeeping app built for Indonesia&#8217;s 60 million &#8220;micromerchants&#8221;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/02/meet-bukuwarung-the-bookkeeping-app-built-for-indonesias-60-million-micro-merchants/embed/#?secret=HYruIjV0QA" data-secret="HYruIjV0QA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>BukuWarung’s new funding announcement comes four months after its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/bukuwarung-a-startup-digitizing-indonesias-smes-raises-new-funding-from-rocketship-vc/">previous one</a>, and less than a month after competitor BukuKas disclosed it had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/bukukas-gets-50m-from-investors-including-doordashs-gokul-rajaram-and-transferwise-co-founder-taavet-hinrikus/">raised a $50 million Series B.</a> Both started out as digital bookkeeping apps for MSMEs before expanding into financial services and e-commerce tools.</p>
<p>When asked how BukuWarung plans to continue differentiating from BukuKas, co-founder and CEO Abhinay Peddisetty told TechCrunch, “We don’t see this space as a winner takes all, our focus is on building the best products for MSMEs as proven by our execution on our payments and accounting, shown by massive growth in payments TPV as we’re 10x bigger than the nearest player in this space.”</p>
<p>He added, “We have already run successful lending experiments with partners in fintech and banks and are on track to monetize our merchants backed by our deep payments, accounting and other data that we collect.”</p>
<p>BukuWarung’s new funding will be used to double its current workforce of 150, located in Indonesia, Singapore and India, to 300 and develop BukuWarung’s accounting, digital payments and commerce products, including a payments infrastructure that will include QR payments and other services.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Owz8ciTLpz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/bukukas-gets-50m-from-investors-including-doordashs-gokul-rajaram-and-transferwise-co-founder-taavet-hinrikus/">BukuKas gets $50M from investors including DoorDash&#8217;s Gokul Rajaram and TransferWise founder Taavet Hinrikus</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BukuKas gets $50M from investors including DoorDash&#8217;s Gokul Rajaram and TransferWise founder Taavet Hinrikus&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/bukukas-gets-50m-from-investors-including-doordashs-gokul-rajaram-and-transferwise-co-founder-taavet-hinrikus/embed/#?secret=Owz8ciTLpz" data-secret="Owz8ciTLpz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/bukuwarung-a-fintech-for-indonesian-msmes-scores-60m-series-a-led-by-valar-and-goodwater/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2163590</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Motional CEO hints at an autonomous future in logistics</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/motional-ceo-hints-at-an-autonomous-future-in-logistics/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/motional-ceo-hints-at-an-autonomous-future-in-logistics/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 23:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aurora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motional]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164118</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Motional, the $4 billion joint venture between Aptiv and Hyundai, is exploring the company&#8217;s potential involvement in autonomous trucking or logistics, its CEO said today during a live session at TechCrunch&#8217;s 2021 Mobility Event. &#8220;The beauty of what&#8217;s on the other side of the coin is that the same core technology can of course apply [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Motional, the $4 billion joint venture between Aptiv and Hyundai, is exploring the company&#8217;s potential involvement in autonomous trucking or logistics, its CEO said today during a live session at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/07/autonomous-vehicle-pioneers-karl-iagnemma-and-chris-urmson-are-coming-to-tc-sessions-mobility-2021/">TechCrunch&#8217;s 2021 Mobility Event</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;The beauty of what&#8217;s on the other side of the coin is that the same core technology can of course apply to multiple use cases,&#8221; said Karl Iagnemma on the panel led by TechCrunch transportation editor Kirsten Korosec, who asked about Motional&#8217;s intention to expand its business model into trucking. &#8220;It&#8217;s similar, it&#8217;s not the same, but it&#8217;s similar. And so we are actively exploring other use cases. We will have additional activity in this area. We don&#8217;t have anything to announce today. But more to come.&#8221;</p>
<p>While Motional still believes the biggest economic opportunity comes from solving the hard technological problems of autonomy in the service of moving people, AKA <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/motional-and-lyft-target-2023-to-deploy-driverless-robotaxi-services-in-major-u-s-cities/">the robotaxi model</a>, Iagnemma recognized the same hard problems &#8212; perception, planning, decision making, localization &#8212; lie at the core of autonomy, whether that&#8217;s moving people or parcels.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re looking for a great business opportunity that has the closest adjacency from a technical perspective to the stack that we&#8217;re currently developing,&#8221; said Iagnemma, responding to what is most appealing in the delivery and logistics model. &#8220;That&#8217;s really what it boils down to. These different use cases have, in some cases, quite dramatically different business cases around them, the opportunity looks quite different. And so that helps us score rank order internally. What presents an interesting opportunity? And then again, we tried to align that toward our current technology development path to say, hey, this would be the least incremental effort for the biggest incremental opportunity. That&#8217;s how we sort of guide our strategy, internally at Motional.&#8221;</p>
<p>For his part, Chris Urmson, co-founder and CEO of autonomous vehicle company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/autonomous-vehicle-startup-aurora-in-final-talks-to-merge-with-reid-hoffmans-newest-spac/">Aurora</a>, and the other panelist on the session, admitted that ride-hailing and moving people with automated vehicles will ultimately be both a transformational business and one that surpasses trucking in the long term. Aurora is currently focused on freight applications, rather than robotaxi, for a number of reasons, including the ability to scale now.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HsDjj73joF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/uber-sells-self-driving-unit-uber-atg-in-deal-that-will-push-auroras-valuation-to-10b/">Uber sells self-driving unit Uber ATG in deal that will push Aurora&#8217;s valuation to $10B</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Uber sells self-driving unit Uber ATG in deal that will push Aurora&#8217;s valuation to $10B&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/uber-sells-self-driving-unit-uber-atg-in-deal-that-will-push-auroras-valuation-to-10b/embed/#?secret=HsDjj73joF" data-secret="HsDjj73joF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;[The robotaxi] market will take time to evolve, whereas the freight and trucking market is here today,&#8221; said Urmson.</p>
<p>Both panelists agreed that there&#8217;s no low-hanging fruit in the autonomous world. The problem of self-driving vehicles is difficult to solve, but Urmson argues it&#8217;s perhaps a bit easier to solve with trucking, where you don&#8217;t have to reckon with the amount of variability in the road network of a city. Building an autonomous stack to drive on freeways is easier due to their mostly uniform nature.</p>
<p>&#8220;So once you crack the initial nut of having the technology working in that operational defined design domain, the rollout moves from a technological expansion to an operational expansion,&#8221; said Urmson. &#8220;And that looks more like kind of a conventional business. So we think that’s a way to be scaling the business and operations and generating the revenue stream that allows us to then go and really take that core technology and apply it into ride hailing and build an exciting business in that space as well.&#8221;</p>
<div class="c-message_actions__container c-message__actions" role="group"></div>
<div role="group"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/motional-ceo-hints-at-an-autonomous-future-in-logistics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164118</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Does what happens at YC stay at YC?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/does-what-happens-at-yc-stay-at-yc/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/does-what-happens-at-yc-stay-at-yc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 22:52:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164006</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Community has never felt louder in startupland. Bringing people together over a shared interest is innate to human nature, and coming out of a lonely, draining pandemic, every startup is looking to cultivate community, conversation and camaraderie. Last week, though, the outside world got a look at how Y Combinator, one of Silicon Valley’s most [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Community has never felt louder in startupland. Bringing people together over a shared interest is innate to human nature, and coming out of a lonely, draining pandemic, every startup is looking to cultivate community, conversation and camaraderie.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last week, though, the outside world got a look at how Y Combinator, one of Silicon Valley’s most famed and feared accelerators, deals with the intricacies of a scaled, yet still ultra-exclusive, community after the accelerator kicked out two founders from its internal messaging board, Bookface.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The two founders,</span><a href="https://darklang.com/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Dark</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> CEO</span><a href="https://twitter.com/paulbiggar"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Paul Biggar</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and</span><a href="https://www.prolific.co/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Prolific</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> CEO and co-founder</span><a href="https://twitter.com/ekadamer"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Katia Damer</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, say they were removed from YC after publicly critiquing YC &#8212; for very different reasons. Biggar had noted on social media back in March that another YC founder was tipping off people on how to cut the vaccine lines to get an early jab, while Damer expressed worry and frustration more recently about the alumni community’s support of a now-controversial alum, Antonio García Martínez.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Y Combinator says that the two founders were removed from Bookface because they broke community guidelines, namely the rule to never externally post any internal information from Bookface.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The now-public ousting of Biggar and Damer, who turned to Twitter to first explain their experiences, is a nuanced situation. Y Combinator says that it has only removed a “dozen or so” founders in its 16 year history for violating YC ethics and Bookface forum guidelines.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still, YC’s decision to remove these founders, especially in light of a broader reckoning around free speech and dissent within startups, has triggered a series of questions &#8212; some by YC founders themselves &#8212; around how the accelerator moderates its community, handles negative publicity and draws its own line around what can be openly said by its alumni base without consequence.</span></p>
<h2><b>Privacy first</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best curated communities allow participants to safely, and freely, share personal experiences, debate, and even disagree. Part of that safety comes from what some see as a common rule within communities: don’t share private information publicly.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Per YC, respecting privacy is a key rule for anyone who joins Bookface, an internal messaging forum that includes some 6,000 founders of the YC community, from alumni to management to current batch companies. Founders log in daily, asking for introductions to a crypto accountant or bringing up a recent job posting for crowdsourced suggestions, among other topics.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We ask that founders don’t share anything from the forum with anyone outside of YC, as this is a community built on trust and privacy,” </span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lindsaywiese/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lindsay Wiese-Amos</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Y Combinator head of communications, tells TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s more than a polite request. Amos said that when a company is accepted into YC, the founders must sign investment documents, one of which is its founder ethics policy. Within the policy, there are guidelines around the Bookface forum, including the language: “Don&#8217;t share anything in the Forum, or any links to the content posted to it, with anyone outside of YC.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">YC claims that when a founder breaks the rules, it reaches out to them with a warning, and if the rule is broken multiple times, that individual is removed from the community.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When a startup is removed from the YC community, YC “generally” returns the shares to the company, though it says there are exceptions. In Damer’s case, says Amos, her “co-founder is still actively working on Prolific, and both he and Prolific remain part of the YC community.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, Biggar’s YC startup closed eight months after graduating from the accelerator, so YC didn’t have to sever financial ties.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/garrytan"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Garry Tan</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, co-founder of Initialized Capital, and a former YC partner who has stakes in alumni companies including Coinbase, thinks there is a difference between a critical discussion and breaking community rules. Tan tells TechCrunch that discussions are fine, but that these “founders violated privacy expectations of other people within the community.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ifRtRtDUQb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/09/brian-armstrongs-new-problem-60-plus/">Brian Armstrong&#8217;s new problem: 60-plus free agents</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Brian Armstrong&#8217;s new problem: 60-plus free agents&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/09/brian-armstrongs-new-problem-60-plus/embed/#?secret=ifRtRtDUQb" data-secret="ifRtRtDUQb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I think YC has become an institution, and institutions are viewed with high scrutiny,” he said. “That’s not a bad thing, it’s probably how it should be.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The &#8220;‘too far’ moment is when people try to ascribe specific political viewpoints to an institution when that institution is A) a lot of people not just a few and B) probably innocent of specifically pushing one viewpoint or another,” Tan continues.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">YC’s Bookface rules are seemingly cut and dried. However, in light of the actions it took against Biggar and Damer, it’s fair to wonder what happens if someone in the community disparages YC publicly, but not having to do with Bookface. Is that also an offense that would get them kicked out of the organization? And would the organization make an exception for especially promising founders?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Amos suggests that all founders are treated equally and that dissent is welcome. “We believe strongly in free speech and are open to criticism. People are allowed to criticize YC and would not get kicked out of the community for doing so,” she said.</span></p>
<h2><b>‘I had no faith in Y Combinator doing the right thing’</b></h2>
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/paulbiggar/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Biggar</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> went through Y Combinator in 2010. “I was like a Paul Graham acolyte,&#8221; he says. &#8220;I have a signed copy of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hackers and Painters</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, read every essay that he put out, and as soon as I finished my PhD, I applied to Y Combinator.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For over a decade, Biggar says, he has been an active participant in Bookface, recently helping multiple companies with financial and relationship advice on co-founder break-ups.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When the Black Lives Matter movement was growing last summer, Biggar noticed that Bookface was relatively quiet and, as he describes it, “apolitical, but in a derogatory way” around issues such as diversity and police brutality. He compared the tone of Bookface to that of Coinbase, after CEO Brian Armstrong</span><a href="https://blog.coinbase.com/coinbase-is-a-mission-focused-company-af882df8804"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">published a memo that banned political discussions at work.</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Biggar’s frustration grew, hitting a tipping point in March when he spotted a founder bragging on the forum that he had skipped a vaccine queue and offering tips to help other founders do the same.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Soon after, Biggar tweeted: “For the second time, a @ycombinator founder has posted to the internal YC forum about how they lied to skip the vaccine queue in Oakland, with instructions for other founders to do the same. Absolutely fucking disgusted.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Biggar left out screenshots of the founder’s post or any identifying material to protect the individual’s anonymity. But within hours of publishing the tweet, Biggar received a direct message on Twitter from Y Combinator co-founder Jessica Livingston, asking him to alert a partner at YC about inappropriate content on Bookface. She added: “You may get a faster and more thorough response than posting to all of Twitter.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">His response to her: “Hey Jessica! Truth be told, I’m so disillusioned with YC that it never even occurred to me.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Biggar decided to leave up the tweet. Meanwhile, because Biggar was apparently not alone in his view of the content on Bookface &#8212; Amos says that “the community made its perspective quite clear in the comments: they were not in agreement with this founder” offering vaccination hacks  &#8212; YC says it deleted the post less than 24 hours after it appeared on Bookface.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The episode wasn&#8217;t even on his mind, Biggar says, when he received an email from</span><a href="https://blog.ycombinator.com/author/jon-levy/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Jon Levy</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the managing director of partnerships at YC, asking to chat last week. To Biggar&#8217;s surprise, Levy told him that he was being removed from the YC community. That meant he was being removed not just from Bookface, says Biggar, but he is no longer invited to Demo Day or allowed on YC Slack.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">lol just got kicked out of <a href="https://twitter.com/ycombinator?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@ycombinator</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Paul Biggar (@paulbiggar) <a href="https://twitter.com/paulbiggar/status/1400904600421535744?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 4, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Notably, Biggar says that YC didn’t give him a warning or the option to take down any posts before ushering him out of the broader YC community, though he suspected it was becoming stricter about its community rules. A week before he was booted, Biggar says that Y Combinator reminded founders about a “no leak” policy within Bookface.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">YC offers a different recounting of the events, saying it was only “recently” notified of Biggar’s tweet through someone in the YC community and that all founders are given a warning. YC also states that a founder is removed only after violating its terms “multiple” times, while Biggar maintains that he only once tweeted about Bookface. Asked about other examples of Biggar violating its terms, YC declined to comment further.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Says Biggar now of these recent events: &#8220;I got criticized for not posting it internally, which I think is kind of bullshit. But, you know, the reason I didn&#8217;t post it internally is just that I had no faith in Y Combinator doing the right thing. I didn&#8217;t think that going public would do anything, either. I mean, I’m not someone who actually matters here.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This is the smallest way that one could possibly call out YC,” Biggar continues. “A couple of community members did a shitty thing, which I think is reflective of the community. That for them is, like, too much dissent &#8212; shut it all down.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are not “the people who have been elevated to part-time partners [or are] tight with the people that matter,” no one “cares what you think. No one ever asks what you think . . .You can’t have dissent internally. There are just too many disciples.”</span></p>
<h2><b>‘YC is not soul-searching’</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Damer’s own removal from Bookface might not have been publicized if not for Biggar sharing on Twitter last week that he’d just been “kicked out.” Soon after, she</span><a href="https://twitter.com/ekadamer/status/1400956227501318146"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">came forward,</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> tweeting to him that “2 weeks ago, YC kicked me out as well” for her public critique. Specifically, says Damer, she was thrown off Bookface because she called out misogyny and the lack of diversity within the accelerator community.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It began with a memo on Bookface with the title: “Is YC an inclusive organization? If we continue like this, YC will lose its great reputation.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In her post, Damer explained that she noticed many people defending Antonio García Martínez, the author of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chaos Monkeys</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> who recently was invited to join Apple, then asked to</span><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/05/13/tech/apple-antonio-garcia-martinez/index.html"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">leave Apple</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, after a</span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/12/22432909/apple-petition-hiring-antonio-garcia-martinez-chaos-monkeys-facebook"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">petition</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to investigate his hiring was signed by more than 2,000 Apple employees. They were concerned about specific book passages, including one that reads: “[M]ost women in the Bay Area are soft and weak, cosseted and naive despite their claims of worldliness, and generally full of shit.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like the Apple employees who circulated the petition, Damer believes the book is proof that García Martínez is a “misogynist,” writing on Bookface about how “disconcerting” she found the outpouring of support for him on the internal platform.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I care about YC and that’s why I am writing this,” Damer said. “What is happening right now is not normal, and it looks like YC is soul searching. If this doesn’t get under control, YC will start missing out on some of the best deal flow, especially from women and underrepresented founders.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Livingston soon responded.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“YC is not ‘soul-searching’,” Livingston wrote. “Antonio participated in YC a decade ago, and I remember him as a decent person&#8230;I think if anything the YC community should be the ones defending Antonio, because many of us have first-hand knowledge of him, instead of just cherry picked quotes from a book. And we know from being in the startup world how often people are criticized unfairly by the press and in social media.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Livingston’s post received hundreds of upvotes, while Damer’s post received a handful. Aggravated, Damer soon went to LinkedIn and Twitter to post </span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/katia-damer_dear-founders-id-like-to-apologize-to-activity-6799970875278925824-990_/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">screenshots of the interaction,</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> “retracting” any previous praise she’d given to YC’s founders, and advising founders not to give up equity before VCs earn their trust.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Soon, a YC partner e-mailed Damer with an invitation to reach out to group partners or this partner directly about any YC concerns, according to a document shared with TechCrunch by the accelerator. The partner also explained that one of the community rules at Bookface was not to share anything from the forum with anyone outside of YC. The partner asked Damer to take down the Bookface screenshots. Damer did not respond to the email and did not take down the screenshots. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Less than two weeks later, Damer received a second email from the partner, this time with a clear message: Because she did not delete her posts, Damer had been removed from Bookface and could reach out if she wished to re-engage.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The communication was extensive compared with the organization’s handling of Biggar’s tweet, and suggests that YC did a far better job in following its own protocols in Damer’s case.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Either way, Damer thinks that YC’s guidelines encourage complacency, especially around issues of diversity, and suggests her waning enthusiasm for the organization ties directly to its not “stepping up” for “women when given the chance.” Adds Damer, “I don&#8217;t think any one of [the partners] is malicious, I actually think they are good people. It&#8217;s more about the complacency &#8212; that is what bothers me so much,” she said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As for whether she regrets airing her exasperation publicly, she suggests she didn’t have a choice. “People use rules when they don&#8217;t know what else to do. This is about courage, this is about actually standing up for what is right.”</span></p>
<h2><b>Community rules can be clear, but enforcement muddy</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is plainly an argument for and against Y Combinator’s deciding to remove founders from its forum. It’s typical of investors to ask portfolio companies to agree to certain terms and conditions. In this case, YC specifically alerts those who join its organization that the privilege of using Bookface comes with its own, additional, terms and conditions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still, whether the terms and conditions around its community are fair or reasonable could become a question mark in the minds of founders who haven’t yet applied to the program &#8212; as could YC’s different handling of two founders who broke the rules.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Broadly speaking, people within communities who feel like they are not being heard internally &#8212; yet who are also being asked not to express their disdain publicly &#8212; are pushing back on such limits. Coinbase saw at least 60 employees leave last fall after being told that the company would no longer tolerate internal political dissent or debate. In late May, the company Basecamp reportedly lost a third of its staff following disagreements over the company&#8217;s attitude toward internal political debates. Most recently, Medium lost half its staff in July</span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/medium-exodus-culture-memo/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">after a strategy shift and an internally criticized culture memo.</span></a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lDB1ZC48Jw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/medium-exodus-culture-memo/">Medium sees more employee exits after CEO publishes ‘culture memo’</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Medium sees more employee exits after CEO publishes ‘culture memo’&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/medium-exodus-culture-memo/embed/#?secret=lDB1ZC48Jw" data-secret="lDB1ZC48Jw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Because of its successful track record, YC may be more powerful as an institution than any one company, but rivals are always looking for weaknesses, and asking members not to air their grievances outside of YC could ultimately impair the outfit. A generation of founders and operators is showing it is less and less willing to suppress a viewpoint in the service of others, and the most talented of these individuals have no shortage of options when it comes to both mentorship and capital.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">YC, with its extensive network &#8212; perhaps even because of it &#8212;  may increasingly find it isn&#8217;t immune to the trend.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/does-what-happens-at-yc-stay-at-yc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164006</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: A crowded market for exits and acquisitions forecasts a hot AI summer</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/daily-crunch-a-crowded-market-for-exits-and-acquisitions-forecasts-a-hot-ai-summer/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/daily-crunch-a-crowded-market-for-exits-and-acquisitions-forecasts-a-hot-ai-summer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 22:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for June 9, 2021. Today was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/">TC Sessions: Mobility</a>, a rollicking good time and one that we hoped you enjoyed. Looking ahead, we’re starting to announce some speakers for Disrupt &#8212; including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/join-accels-arun-mathew-at-techcrunch-disrupt-in-our-debate-around-alt-financing/">Accel’s Arun Mathew</a>. Mark your calendars, Disrupt is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">going to be epic this year</a>. &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2142930 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Generic-WP-Header.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Generic-WP-Header.png 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Generic-WP-Header.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Generic-WP-Header.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Generic-WP-Header.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Generic-WP-Header.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Generic-WP-Header.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/biden-revokes-and-replace-trump-actions-targeting-tiktok-and-wechat-report/"><strong>Biden tears down Trump’s Chinese app wall</strong></a><strong>: </strong>After a very confusing episode in which the former U.S. president demanded that TikTok sell to an American company and that the U.S. government get a cut, things are mostly back to normal today after President Biden “signed an executive order revoking actions targeting TikTok and WeChat,” TechCrunch reports. Biden also signed a “new order requiring the Commerce Department to review apps with ties to ‘jurisdiction of foreign adversaries,’” so this story is not yet finished.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/swedish-company-northvolt-raises-2-75b-to-accelerate-european-battery-production/"><strong>Billions for battery tech</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Northvolt has raised a $2.75 billion round to build its in-Europe battery manufacturing capacity to 150 GWh by 2030. While 2030 may sound far away, it’s under a decade from now. The news of Northvolt’s round underscores how many regions want to ensure that they can build core technology products like batteries, chips and AI on their own as a way to limit geopolitical risk.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/ai-startup-investment-is-on-pace-for-a-record-year/"><strong>Everyone wants to fund AI startups</strong></a><strong>: </strong>The era in which every startup claimed to be an AI company is behind us, leaving us with the era in which every VC wants to fund AI startups. That’s the gist of a recent TechCrunch dig into the hot and busy fundraising market for startups leveraging artificial intelligence.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups and VC</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/branch-raises-50m-to-offer-bundled-auto-home-insurance-via-an-api/"><strong>Branch finds more backers for its insurtech service</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Bundled home-and-auto insurtech startup Branch has raised a $50 million round led by Anthemis Group. The company’s pitch is that it starts customers off with a bundle, meaning that it doesn’t have to cross-sell them later on. VCs are still more than willing to pour capital into neo-insurance providers, despite some struggles from unicorns in the space after they went public.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/shelflife-a-marketplace-for-raw-materials-raises-3-million-seed-round/"><strong>ShelfLife wants to help you source raw materials</strong></a><strong>:</strong> Ever wanted to produce and sell your own version of White Claw? Lillian Cartwright and some fellow Harvard Business School folks had that idea, but ran into supply issues. Cartwright built ShelfLife, which helps brands by providing “a directory and marketplace of raw material suppliers based on what brands actually, specifically need, allowing them to secure quotes quickly.”</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/mythical-games-raises-75m-to-build-an-nft-game-engine/"><strong>If you are tired of insurtech rounds, how about an NFT round</strong></a><strong>? </strong>Mythical Games announced a $75 million round despite fading near-term momentum in the market for blockchain-specific digital ownership writs. Regardless of what you think about NFTs, it’s clear that VCs are bullish and are willing to pay up to not miss a possible trend.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/stacey-abrams-cofounded-fintech-company-now-raises-9-5m/"><strong>American political luminary Stacey Abrams’ Now raises $9.5M</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Now is a fintech company that buys corporate invoices for a fee, allowing companies to unlock revenue before they get paid. Provided that it can properly assess nonpayment risk, it’s a pretty business-friendly model.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/contentstack-raises-57-5m-for-its-headless-content-management-system/"><strong>Behead your CMS</strong></a><strong>: </strong>If you are not hip to headless CMS tools, imagine WordPress but without the bits that make it render in your browser. The headless model has attracted backers in a more fractured end-user device world, where users might access content on everything from smartwatches to tablets to desktops to VR helmets. And now Contentstack’s headless CMS service is $57.5 million richer after an investment led by Insight Partners.</li>
</ul>
<p>To round out our startup news today, two things: The first is that Superhuman CEO Rahul Vohra and his buddy Todd Goldberg, the founder of Eventjoy, have formalized their investing partnership in a new fund <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/todd-and-rahuls-angel-fund-closes-new-24-million-fund/">called Todd and Rahul’s Angel Fund</a>. That name has big “Bill and Ted’s Excellent Adventure” vibes, albeit with a larger, $24 million budget.</p>
<p>And fresh on the heels of the Equity Podcast diving into hormonal health and the huge startup opportunity that it presents, there’s a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/allara-pcos-ro-rachel-blank/">new startup working on PCOS on the market</a>. Check out our look at its early form.</p>
<h2>Don’t panic: ‘Algorithm updates’ aren’t the end of the world for SEO managers</h2>
<p>SEO expert and consultant Eli Schwartz will join Managing Editor Danny Crichton tomorrow to share his advice for everyone who gets nervous each time Google updates its algorithm.</p>
<p>To set a foundation for <a href="https://twitter.com/i/spaces/1MnxnlQMVajGO">tomorrow&#8217;s chat on Twitter Spaces</a>, Eli shared a guest post that should deflate some myths. For starters: A drop in search traffic isn&#8217;t necessarily hurting you.</p>
<p>Instead of chasing the algorithm, he advises companies that rely on organic search results to focus on the user experience instead: &#8220;If you are helpful to the user, you have nothing to fear.&#8221;</p>
<p>Just like you release product updates based on feedback and analytics, Google’s improving its products to offer a better user experience.</p>
<p>“If you see a drop, in many cases, your site might not have even lost real traffic,” says Eli. “Often, the losses represent only lost impressions already not converting into clicks.”</p>
<p>Tomorrow&#8217;s discussion is the latest in a series of chats with top Extra Crunch guest contributors. If you&#8217;ve worked with a talented growth marketer, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/help-techcrunch-find-the-best-growth-marketers-for-startups/">please share a brief recommendation</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JImxMO12Cg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/dont-panic-algorithm-updates-arent-the-end-of-the-world-for-seo-managers/">Don&#8217;t panic: &#8216;Algorithm updates&#8217; aren&#8217;t the end of the world for SEO managers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Don&#8217;t panic: &#8216;Algorithm updates&#8217; aren&#8217;t the end of the world for SEO managers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/dont-panic-algorithm-updates-arent-the-end-of-the-world-for-seo-managers/embed/#?secret=JImxMO12Cg" data-secret="JImxMO12Cg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> <em>You can sign up here</em></a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/google-announces-the-firmina-subsea-cable-between-the-u-s-to-argentina/"><strong>Google is building a huge fiber trunk to Argentina</strong></a><strong>:</strong> Imagine you were a megacorp. And the internet was a bit slow between your headquarters, and, say, Argentina. Do you curse your luck? Stamp your feet? Or do you announce that you are going to “build a new subsea cable that will connect the East Coast of the U.S. and Las Toninas, Argentina — with additional landings in Brazil and Uruguay” as Google did? We hope it’s the final option.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/instagram-adds-affiliate-and-shop-features-for-creators/"><strong>Did you know that it’s Facebook’s creator week</strong></a><strong>?</strong> It is, as it turns out. Big Blue announced a “native affiliate tool” for Instagram that will allow “creators to recommend products available on checkout, share them with followers and earn commissions for sales their posts drive.” The idea may prove annoying for non-influencers, but for the folks with large followings it could be a boon.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/carlyle-acquires-1e-com-an-endpoint-and-hybrid-working-specialist-in-270m-deal/"><strong>$270M for end-point security shop 1E</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Rising acceptance of remote work means more and more end points for companies to secure. To see Carlyle pick up 1E for a quarter-billion, then, is not a surprise in substance. Crunchbase has no funding data from the London-based company, so perhaps this was a pretty big exit for its team.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Introducing TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2159841 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1500" height="942" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1500px) 100vw, 1500px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch is back with our next category for our Experts project: We’re reaching out to startup founders to tell us who they turn to when they want the most up-to-date growth marketing practices.</p>
<p><a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">Fill out the survey here.</a></p>
<p>We’re excited to share the results we collect in the form of a database. The more responses we receive from our readers, the more robust our editorial coverage will be moving forward. To learn more, visit<a href="https://techcrunch.com/experts/"> techcrunch.com/experts</a>.</p>
<h2>Community</h2>
<p>Join us for a <a href="https://twitter.com/i/spaces/1MnxnlQMVajGO">conversation tomorrow at 12:30 p.m. PDT / 3:30 p.m. EDT on Twitter Spaces</a>. Our own <a href="https://twitter.com/dannycrichton?lang=en">Danny Crichton</a> will be discussing growth marketer <a href="https://twitter.com/5le">Eli Schwartz</a>’s guest column <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/dont-panic-algorithm-updates-arent-the-end-of-the-world-for-seo-managers/">Don’t panic: ‘Algorithm updates’ aren’t the end of the world for SEO managers</a>. Bring your questions and comments!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/daily-crunch-a-crowded-market-for-exits-and-acquisitions-forecasts-a-hot-ai-summer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164105</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Health clouds are set to play a key role in healthcare innovation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/health-clouds-are-set-to-play-a-key-role-in-healthcare-innovation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/health-clouds-are-set-to-play-a-key-role-in-healthcare-innovation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 21:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chronic disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2163775</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. healthcare industry is amidst one of the biggest transformations any industry has seen since the dot-com boom of the late 1990s.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Abhinav Shashank</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/abhinavshashank">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Innovaccer founder and CEO Abhinav Shashank has written more than 300 articles for various international media outlets and has also been listed in Forbes’ “30 Under 30 Asia 2017: Enterprise Tech” and among the "Top 60 rising leaders in U.S. healthcare under 40” in the 2019 Becker's Hospital Review. 	</div>
	
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Mike Sutten</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/mikesutten">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Mike Sutten, CTO at Innovaccer, has over two decades of prior IT leadership experience with Fortune 500 organizations, including Kaiser Permanente, Royal Caribbean Cruises, and General Electric, and has also served as the CTO and Deputy CIO at the CIA.
	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The U.S. healthcare industry is amidst one of the biggest transformations any industry has seen since the dot-com boom of the late 1990s. This massive change is being stimulated by federal mandates, technological innovation and the need to improve clinical outcomes and communication between providers, patients and payers.</p>
<p>An aging population, increase in chronic diseases, lower reimbursement rates and a shift to value-based payments — plus the COVID-19 pandemic — have added pressure and highlighted the need for new technology to enhance virtual and value-based care.</p>
<p>Improving medical outcomes now requires processing massive amounts of healthcare data, and the cloud plays a pivotal role in meeting the current needs of healthcare organizations.</p>
<h2>Challenges in healthcare</h2>
<p>Most of today’s healthcare challenges fall into two broad categories: rapidly rising costs and an increased burden on resources. Rising costs — and the resulting inadequacy of healthcare resources — can stem from:</p>
<p><strong>An aging population: </strong>As people age and live longer, healthcare gets more expensive. As medicine improves, people aged 65 and above are expected to account for 20% of the U.S. population by 2030, per the U.S. Census Bureau. And as older people spend more on healthcare, an aging population is <a href="https://www.pgpf.org/blog/2020/04/why-are-americans-paying-more-for-healthcare">expected</a> to contribute to increasing healthcare costs over time.</p>
<p><strong>Prevalence of chronic illnesses: </strong>According to a National Center for Biotechnology Information <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7077778/#:~:text=Today%2C%20chronic%20disease%20affects%2050,of%20health%20care%20costs%203.">report</a>, chronic disease treatment makes up 85% of healthcare costs, and more than half of all Americans have a chronic illness (diabetes, high blood pressure, depression, lower back and neck pain, etc.)</p>
<p><strong>Higher ambulatory costs: </strong>The cost of ambulatory care, including outpatient hospital services and emergency room care, increased the most of all treatment categories covered in a 2017 study in the <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2661579">Journal of the American Medical Association</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Rising healthcare premiums, out-of-pocket costs, and Medicare and Medicaid: </strong>Healthcare premiums rose by an <a href="https://www.kff.org/report-section/ehbs-2019-summary-of-findings/attachment/figure-a-36/">estimated 54% between 2009 and 2019</a>. The COVID-19 pandemic has spurred enrollment into government programs like Medicaid and Medicare, which has increased the overall demand for medical services, contributing to rising costs. A <a href="https://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-drop/rp-20-32.pdf">2021 IRS report</a> highlighted that a shift to high-deductible health plans — with out-of-pocket costs of up to $14,000 per family — has also increased the cost of healthcare.</p>
<p><strong>Delayed care and surgeries due to COVID-19: </strong>A poll by the Kaiser Family Foundation (KFF) in May 2020 indicated that up to 48% people have avoided or postponed medical care due to concerns about the COVID-19 pandemic. About 11% of those people reported that their medical condition worsened after skipping or postponing care. Non-emergency surgeries were frequently postponed, as resources were set aside for COVID-19 patients. These delays make treatable conditions more costly and increase overall costs.</p>
<p><strong>A lack of pricing transparency:</strong> Without transparency, it’s difficult to know the actual cost of healthcare. The fragmented data landscape fails to capture complete details and complex medical bills, and does not give patients a complete view of payments.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Digital transformation across the system can help healthcare organizations connect and aggregate data from disparate sources to support a healthcare intelligence layer.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<h2>The need to modernize</h2>
<p>To mitigate the impact of increased costs and inadequate resources, healthcare organizations need to replace legacy IT programs and adopt modern systems designed to support rapid innovation for site-agnostic, collaborative, whole-person care — all while being affordable and accessible.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/health-clouds-are-set-to-play-a-key-role-in-healthcare-innovation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2163775</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Seoul-based Ringle raises $18M Series A for its one-on-one English tutoring platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/seoul-based-ringle-raises-18m-series-a-for-its-one-on-one-english-tutoring-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/seoul-based-ringle-raises-18m-series-a-for-its-one-on-one-english-tutoring-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 21:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Must Asset Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ringle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2163629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many of the highest-profile English tutoring platforms focus on children, including VIPKID and Magic Ears. Ringle created a niche for itself by focusing on adults first, with courses like business English and interview preparation. The South Korea-based startup announced today it has raised an $18 million Series A led by returning investor Must Asset Management, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Many of the highest-profile English tutoring platforms focus on children, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/vipkid/">VIPKID</a> and Magic Ears. <a href="https://www.ringleplus.com/en/student/landing/home">Ringle</a> created a niche for itself by focusing on adults first, with courses like business English and interview preparation. The South Korea-based startup announced today it has raised an $18 million Series A led by returning investor Must Asset Management, at a valuation of $90 million. Ringle is preparing to launch a program for school kids later this year, and also has plans to open offline educational spaces in South Korea and the United States.</p>
<p>Other participants in the round, which brings Ringle’s total raised to $20 million, include returning investors One Asset Management and MoCA Ventures, along with new backer Xolon Invest. Ringle claims its revenue has grown three times every year since it was founded in 2015, and that bookings for lessons have increased by 390% compared to the previous year.</p>
<p>Ringle currently has 700 tutors, who are pre-screened by the company, and 100,000 users. About 30% of its students, who learn through one-on-one live video sessions, are based outside of Korea, including in the U.S., the United Kingdom, Japan, Australia and Singapore.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Ringle’s co-founders are Seunghoon Lee and Sungpah Lee, who both earned MBAs from the Stanford University Graduate School of Business. They developed Ringle based on the challenges they faced as non-native English speakers and graduate students in the U.S. The startup was first created to serve professionals who are already established in their careers or in academia. Its students include people who have worked for companies like Google, Amazon, BCG, McKinsey and Samsung Electronics.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yrMXu14AXt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/21/chinas-vipkid-which-links-native-english-speakers-with-online-learners-raises-another-500m-reportedly-at-3b-valuation/">China&#8217;s VIPKID, which links English tutors with online learners, raises $500M at $3B+ valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;China&#8217;s VIPKID, which links English tutors with online learners, raises $500M at $3B+ valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/21/chinas-vipkid-which-links-native-english-speakers-with-online-learners-raises-another-500m-reportedly-at-3b-valuation/embed/#?secret=yrMXu14AXt" data-secret="yrMXu14AXt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Seunghoon Lee told TechCrunch that Ringle creates <a href="https://www.ringleplus.com/en/student/landing/english-learning-materials">proprietary learning materials</a> based on current events to keep its students interested. For example, recent topics have included blockchain NFT tech, how the movie “Parasite” portrayed class conflict and global inequalities in vaccine access.</p>
<p>Ringle’s tutors are recruited from top universities and need to submit proof of education and verify their school emails. The company’s vetting process also includes a mock session with Ringle staff. Lee said applicants are asked to familiarize themselves with some of Ringle’s learning materials and lead a full lesson based on its guidance. Ringle assesses candidates on their teaching skills and ability to lead engaging discussions that also hone their students’ language skills.</p>
<p>Part of Ringle’s new funding is earmarked for its tech platform. It is currently developing a language diagnostics system that tracks the complexity and accuracy of students’ spoken English with researchers at KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology).</p>
<p>The company already has an AI-based analytics system that uses speech-to-text and measures speech pacing (or words spoken per minute), the amount of filler words and range of words and expressions in lessons. It delivers feedback that allows students to compare their performance with the top 20% of Ringle users in different metrics.</p>
<p>The new language diagnostics system that is currently under development with KAIST will start releasing features over the next few months, including speech fluency scoring, a personalized dictionary and auto-paraphrasing suggestions.</p>
<p>The funding will also be used to create more original learning content, and hire for Ringle’s offices in Seoul and San Mateo, California. Ringle also plans to diversify its revenue sources by providing premium content on a subscription basis, and will launch its junior program for students aged 10 and above later this year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zdRsJiS4TY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/31/english-learning-app-elsa-lands-15-million-series-b-for-international-growth-and-its-b2b-platform/">English learning app ELSA lands $15 million Series B for international growth and its B2B platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;English learning app ELSA lands $15 million Series B for international growth and its B2B platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/31/english-learning-app-elsa-lands-15-million-series-b-for-international-growth-and-its-b2b-platform/embed/#?secret=zdRsJiS4TY" data-secret="zdRsJiS4TY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WTrEx4MjVq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/to-win-post-pandemic-edtech-needs-to-start-thinking-big/">To win post-pandemic, edtech needs to start thinking big</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;To win post-pandemic, edtech needs to start thinking big&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/to-win-post-pandemic-edtech-needs-to-start-thinking-big/embed/#?secret=WTrEx4MjVq" data-secret="WTrEx4MjVq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/seoul-based-ringle-raises-18m-series-a-for-its-one-on-one-english-tutoring-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2163629</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A revival at the intersection of open source and open standards</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/a-revival-at-the-intersection-of-open-source-and-open-standards/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/a-revival-at-the-intersection-of-open-source-and-open-standards/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 20:45:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interoperability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[standards]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tremendous technological innovation and transformative power are possible for the future if we re-energize the spirit of collaboration between the open-standards and open-source communities.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Guy Martin</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/guyma">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.oasis-open.org/people/staff/guy-martin/">Guy Martin</a> is the executive director of OASIS Open, one of the most respected nonprofit standards organizations in the world. He brings more than 25 years of experience as both a software engineer and an open-source strategist to OASIS Open, where he helps the organization realize the tremendous advantage in integrating the best of open-standards and open-source communities.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Our world has big problems to solve, and something desperately needed in that pursuit is the open-source and open-standards communities working together.</p>
<p>Let me give you a stark example, taken from the harsh realities of 2020. Last year, the United States experienced nearly <a href="https://fas.org/sgp/crs/misc/IF10244.pdf">60,000 wildland fires</a> that burned more than 10 million acres, resulting in more than 9,500 homes destroyed and at least <a href="https://yaleclimateconnections.org/2021/01/reviewing-the-horrid-global-2020-wildfire-season/">43 lives</a> lost.</p>
<p>I served as a volunteer firefighter in California for 10 years and witnessed firsthand the critical importance of technology in helping firefighters communicate efficiently and deliver safety-critical information quickly. Typically, multiple agencies show up to fight these fires, bringing with them radios made by different manufacturers that each use proprietary software to set radio frequencies. As a result, reprogramming these radios so that teams could communicate with one another is an unnecessarily slow — and potentially life-threatening — process.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>If the radio manufacturers had instead all contributed to an open-source implementation conforming to a standard, the radios could have been quickly aligned to the same frequencies. Radio manufacturers could have provided a valuable, life-saving tool rather than a time-wasting obstacle, and they could have shared the cost of developing such software. In this situation, like so many others, there is no competitive advantage to be gained from proprietary radio-programming software and many priceless benefits to gain by standardizing.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Open source and open standards are obviously different, but the objectives of these communities are the same: interoperability, innovation and choice.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>The benefit of coherent standards and corresponding open-source implementations is not unique to safety-critical situations like wildfires. There are many areas of our lives that could significantly benefit from a better integration of standards and open source.</p>
<h2>Open source and open standards: What’s the difference?</h2>
<p>“Open source” describes software that is publicly accessible and free for anyone to use, modify and share. It also describes a collaborative, community-oriented software development philosophy, with an open exchange of ideas, open participation, rapid prototyping, and open governance and transparency.</p>
<p>By contrast, the term “standard” refers to agreed-upon definitions of functionality. These requirements, specifications and guidelines ensure that products, services and systems perform in an interoperable way with quality, safety and efficiency.</p>
<p>Dozens of organizations exist for the purpose of establishing and maintaining standards. Examples include the International Organization for Standardization (ISO), the European Telecommunications Standards Institute (ETSI), and the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C). <a href="https://www.oasis-open.org/">OASIS Open</a> belongs in this category as well. A standard is “open” when it is developed via a consensus-building process, guided by organizations that are open, fair and transparent. Most people would agree that the standard-building process is careful and deliberate, ensuring consensus through compromise and resulting in long-lasting specifications and technical boundaries.</p>
<h2>Where’s the common ground?</h2>
<p>Open source and open standards are obviously different, but the objectives of these communities are the same: interoperability, innovation and choice. The main difference is how they accomplish those goals, and by that I’m referring primarily to culture and pace.</p>
<p>Chris Ferris, an IBM fellow and CTO of Open Technology, recently told me that with standards organizations, it often seems the whole point is to slow things down. Sometimes it’s with good reason, but I’ve seen competition get the best of people, too. Open source seems to be much more collaborative and less contentious or competitive. That doesn’t mean that there aren’t competitive projects out there that are tackling the same domain.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UigwbeJGjz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/09/the-human-focused-startups-of-the-hellfire/">The human-focused startups of the hellfire</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The human-focused startups of the hellfire&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/09/the-human-focused-startups-of-the-hellfire/embed/#?secret=UigwbeJGjz" data-secret="UigwbeJGjz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Another culture characteristic that affects pace is that open source is about writing code and standards organizations are about writing prose. Words outlive code with respect to long-term interoperability, so the standards culture is much more deliberate and thoughtful as it develops the prose that defines standards. Although standards are not technically static, the intent with a standard is to arrive at something that will serve without significant change for the long term. Conversely, the open-source community writes code with an iterative mindset, and the code is essentially in a state of continuous evolution. These two cultures sometimes clash when the communities try to move in concert.</p>
<p>If that’s the case, why try to find harmony?</p>
<h2>Collaboration between open source and open standards will fuel innovation</h2>
<p>The internet is a perfect example of what harmony between the open-source and open-standards communities can achieve. When the internet began as ARPANET, it relied on common shared communications standards that predated TCP/IP. With time, standards and open-source implementations brought us TCP/IP, HTTP, NTP, XML, SAML, JSON and many others, and also enabled the creation of additional key global systems implemented in open standards and code, like disaster warnings (OASIS CAP) and standardized global trade invoicing (OASIS UBL).</p>
<p>The internet has literally transformed our world. That level of technological innovation and transformative power is possible for the future, too, if we re-energize the spirit of collaboration between the open-standards and open-source communities.</p>
<h2>Finding harmony and a natural path of integration</h2>
<p>With all of the critical open-source projects residing in repositories today, there are many opportunities for collaboration on associated standards to ensure the long-term operability of that software. Part of our mission at OASIS Open is identifying those open-source projects and giving them a collaborative environment and all the scaffolding they need to build a standard without it becoming a difficult process.</p>
<p>Another point Ferris shared with me is the necessity for this path of integration to grow. For instance, this need is particularly prevalent if you want your technology to be used in Asia: If you don’t have an international standard, Asian enterprises don’t even want to hear from you. We’re seeing the European community asserting a strong preference for standards as well. That is certainly a driver for open-source projects that want to play with some of the heavy hitters in the ecosystem.</p>
<p>Another area where you can see a growing need for integration is when an open-source project becomes bigger than itself, meaning it begins to impact a whole lot of other systems, and alignment is needed between them. An example would be a standard for telemetry data, which is now being used for so many different purposes, from observability to security. Another example is the software bill of materials, or SBOM. I know some things are being done in the open-source world to address the challenge of tracking the provenance of software. This is another case where, if we’re going to be successful at all, we need a standard to emerge.</p>
<h2>It’s going to take a team effort</h2>
<p>Fortunately, the ultimate goals of the open-source and open-standards communities are the same: interoperability, innovation and choice. We also have excellent proof points of how and why we need to work together, from the internet to Topology and Orchestration Specification for Cloud Applications (TOSCA) and more. In addition, major stakeholders are carrying the banner, acknowledging that for certain open-source projects we need to take a strategic, longer-term view that includes standards.</p>
<p>That’s a great start to a team effort. Now it&#8217;s time for foundations to step up to the plate and collaborate with each other and with those stakeholders.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iFRlXbPY56"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/where-top-vcs-are-investing-in-open-source-and-dev-tools-part-1-of-2/">Where top VCs are investing in open source and dev tools (Part 1 of 2)</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Where top VCs are investing in open source and dev tools (Part 1 of 2)&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/where-top-vcs-are-investing-in-open-source-and-dev-tools-part-1-of-2/embed/#?secret=iFRlXbPY56" data-secret="iFRlXbPY56" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/a-revival-at-the-intersection-of-open-source-and-open-standards/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162333</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Alzheimer&#8217;s is open for business:&#8221; Controversial FDA approval could pave the way for future drugs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/alzheimers-is-open-for-business-controversial-fda-approval-could-pave-the-way-for-future-drugs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/alzheimers-is-open-for-business-controversial-fda-approval-could-pave-the-way-for-future-drugs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Betuel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 20:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dementia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drug development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drug discovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life Sciences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[therapeutics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164092</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Monday, a 17-year drought in the world of Alzheimer’s drugs ended with the FDA approval of Biogen’s Aduhlem (aducanumab). The controversy behind the FDA’s decision was considerable, but it doesn’t seem to be spooking drug developers who are now narrowing in on the degenerative brain disease.  In a nutshell, the approval of Aduhelm came [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Monday, a 17-year drought in the world of Alzheimer’s drugs ended with the FDA approval of Biogen’s Aduhlem (aducanumab). The controversy behind the FDA’s decision was considerable, but it doesn’t seem to be spooking drug developers who are now narrowing in on the degenerative brain disease. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a nutshell, the approval of Aduhelm came after conflicting results from clinical trials. In </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/06/health/aducanumab-alzheimers-drug-fda-panel.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">November 2020 </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">an independent FDA advisory board did not recommend that the agency endorse the drug, but in June, the agency approved the drug anyway via an Accelerated Approval Program. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aduhelm is now the first novel treatment to address one underlying cause of Alzheimer’s – beta-amyloid plaques that accumulate in the brain. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The drug received support from </span><a href="https://www.alz.org/news/2021/alzheimers-association-fda-approval-aducanumab"><span style="font-weight: 400;">patient and industry groups</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (the FDA also </span><a href="https://www.fda.gov/drugs/news-events-human-drugs/fdas-decision-approve-new-treatment-alzheimers-disease"><span style="font-weight: 400;">noted</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that the “need for treatment is urgent”, in a statement explaining the agency’s choice). Still, there have been a number of doctors who have expressed concern. One member of the expert committee that voted not to recommend the approval of Aduhelm back in November has </span><a href="https://www.statnews.com/2021/06/08/fda-expert-panel-resigns-alzheimers-approval/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">resigned</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> since the announcement.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the inconsistency of the science and highly public debate around the approval of Aduhelm doesn’t seem to have halted enthusiasm within the pharmaceutical industry. Rather, it may signal a new wave of additional treatments in the next few years, which will piggyback off of the approval of Aduhelm (however controversial that approval may be).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This is great news for investors and for drug companies that are working towards new drugs,” says </span><a href="https://healthpolicy.usc.edu/staff/alison-sexton-ward-phd/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alison Ward</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a research scientist at the USC Schaeffer Center for Health Policy and Economics. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Historically there have been a few factors that have made the development of a drug for Alzheimer’s an uphill battle. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first, is a 17-year history of failure to bring a drug through clinical trials. Even Biogen’s clinical trials for Aduhelm were halted in 2019 because it wasn’t clear that they would reach their clinical endpoints (effectively, the target outcomes of the trial). In fact, Aduhlem was approved based on a “surrogate endpoint,” the decline of beta-amyloid, not the primary endpoint, cognitive function. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Trials for Alzheimer’s drugs have also historically been expensive. A 2018 paper in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alzheimer’s and Dementia: Translational Research and Clinical Interventions </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">(a journal run by the Alzheimer’s Association)</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">estimated that the cost of developing an Alzheimer’s drug was about </span><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S235287371830026X"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$5.6 billion</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. By comparison, the mean investment needed to bring a new drug to market is about </span><a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2762311"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$1.3 billion</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> according to analysis of SEC filings for companies that applied for FDA approval between 2009 and 2018 (though the median cost was about $985 million). Older estimates have put the costs of bringing a drug to market at </span><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S235287371830026X"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$2.8 billion</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Alzheimer’s specifically, Phase 3 trials are still largely sponsored by industry, but over the past five years, trials sponsored solely by the industry have </span><a href="https://alz-journals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/trc2.12185"><span style="font-weight: 400;">decreased</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Government grants and funding via public-private partnerships have made up an i</span><a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/health-news/articles/2021-05-27/theres-been-a-shift-in-whos-funding-alzheimers-research"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ncreasing share</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of available funds.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Martin Tolar, the founder CEO of </span><a href="https://alzheon.com/medicines-alzheimers-disease/alzheon-management-team/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alzheon</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, another company pursuing an oral treatment for Alzheimer’s (currently in a phase 3 clinical trial), says that attracting other forms of funding was a challenge. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bQtZfxLcUu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/2021-should-be-a-banner-year-for-biotech-startups-that-make-smart-choices-early/">2021 should be a banner year for biotech startups that make smart choices early</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;2021 should be a banner year for biotech startups that make smart choices early&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/2021-should-be-a-banner-year-for-biotech-startups-that-make-smart-choices-early/embed/#?secret=bQtZfxLcUu" data-secret="bQtZfxLcUu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It was impossible to finance anything,” he says. “It was impossible to get Wall Street interested because everything was failing one after the other after the other.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He expects this recent approval of Aduhelm to change that outlook considerably. Already, we are seeing some increased interest in companies already in phase 3 clinical trials: After the FDA announcement, </span><a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=eli+lilly+stock&amp;oq=eli+lilly+stock+&amp;aqs=chrome.0.0i131i433l2j0l8.6233j0j7&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8"><span style="font-weight: 400;">shares of Eli Lilly</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, also running a phase 3 clinical trial, </span><a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/why-eli-lilly-stock-soared-today-2021-06-07"><span style="font-weight: 400;">surged by 10 percent</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I’ve had probably hundreds of discussions, of calls, from bankers, investors, collaborators, pharma, you name it,” Tolar says. “Alzheimer’s is open for business.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With renewed interest and what appears like a pathway to approval at the FDA, the environment for the next generation of Alzheimer’s drugs seems to be ripening. Right now, there are about </span><a href="https://www.clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/results/map?recrs=adef&amp;cond=Alzheimer%27s+Disease&amp;phase=2&amp;map="><span style="font-weight: 400;">130</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> phase 3 clinical trials on Alzheimer’s drugs that are either completed, active or recruiting. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tolar sees the FDA decision, based on imperfect data, as a “signal of urgency” to approve new treatments that are imminent arrivals. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As Ward pointed out in a </span><a href="https://healthpolicy.usc.edu/research/impacts-of-first-in-class-drug-approvals-on-future-in-class-innovation/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">white paper</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on in-class drug innovation, “follow on” drugs go on to become leaders in the industry, especially if they demonstrate better safety or efficacy than the drug that was first to market.  That, the paper argues, suggests drug approval may “pave the way” for more effective drugs in the future. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the case of Alzheimer’s, it might not be one drug that dominates, even as more get approved, she notes. Rather, a cadre of new, approved drugs may go on to compliment one another.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The way that the medical community is thinking of AD [Alzheimer’s Disease] now is that it’s likely going to be a combination of drugs or a cocktail of drugs that comes together to have true success at delaying progression,” she says.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“If we’re looking to treat AD with a cocktail of drugs, history suggests it’s individually approved drugs that come together to make those drug cocktails.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are still some potential pitfalls for future drugs to consider. </span><a href="https://www.statnews.com/2021/05/30/if-the-fda-approves-biogens-alzheimers-treatment-i-wont-prescribe-it/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">One argument is</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that with an approved drug available, it may be more difficult to recruit participants in clinical trials, slowing the pace of drug discovery. In that respect, Ward argues that this will ultimately be dwarfed by patients who will now look into a potential diagnosis for Alzheimer’s now that there’s something to treat it with. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There’s also the fact that Aduhelm’s costs are high (about </span><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/08/biogen-faces-tough-questions-over-56k-a-year-price-of-newly-approved-alzheimers-drug.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$56,000</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for a year’s supply, the brunt of which will be </span><a href="https://www.axios.com/aduhelm-biogen-drug-price-medicare-44628fff-6564-453f-9e01-2b04e80ff8f2.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">borne by Medicare</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">), and the data remains questionable. Those factors may push patients towards other drugs, even if they’re in clinical trials. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, there is the question of how well Aduhelm actually performs during the critical followup study mandated by the FDA as a condition of the drug’s approval. Whether Aduhelm can truly slow cognitive decline, as well as help address levels of beta-amyloid from the brain, remains questionable based on current data. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still, Tolar doesn’t see the results of that study as particularly relevant because the industry will have moved on. Biogen CEO Michel Vounatsos has said it may not share results of this trial for as many as </span><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/07/first-on-cnbc-cnbc-transcript-biogen-ceo-michel-vounatsos-speaks-with-cnbcs-power-lunch-today.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">nine years</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, though he noted the company would try to deliver data sooner. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> “There will be better drugs by then,” Tolar predicts. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tolar’s phase 3 clinical trial just began dosing this week, and is scheduled to </span><a href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04770220"><span style="font-weight: 400;">end by 2024</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Biogen and Esai will likely </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">also </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">have another drug ready for evaluation by then, as two phase 3 clinical trials for another beta-amyloid antibody treatment called lecanemab are scheduled for completion </span><a href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03887455?term=ban2401&amp;draw=2&amp;rank=3"><span style="font-weight: 400;">by 2024</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and</span><a href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04468659?term=ban2401&amp;draw=2&amp;rank=4"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 2027</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The signal sent by Monday’s approval may be a pathway for future drugs, rather than an end itself. The data is imperfect, the costs high, and the controversy considerable, but the band-aid has been ripped off. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rnE1lP69Ya"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/19/risks-and-rewards-of-digital-therapeutics-in-treating-mental-disorders/">Risks and rewards of digital therapeutics in treating mental disorders</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Risks and rewards of digital therapeutics in treating mental disorders&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/19/risks-and-rewards-of-digital-therapeutics-in-treating-mental-disorders/embed/#?secret=rnE1lP69Ya" data-secret="rnE1lP69Ya" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/alzheimers-is-open-for-business-controversial-fda-approval-could-pave-the-way-for-future-drugs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164092</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joby Aviation eyes Asia and Europe as early markets alongside North America</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/joby-aviation-eyes-asia-and-europe-as-early-markets-alongside-north-america/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/joby-aviation-eyes-asia-and-europe-as-early-markets-alongside-north-america/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 20:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eVTOL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joby Aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban air mobility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2163996</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While electric vertical take-off and landing passenger aircraft startup Joby Aviation is targeting North America for its initial commercial launch, founder and CEO JoeBen Bevirt expects the company to have an early presence in Asia and Europe as well. Bevirt, who joined the TC Sessions: Mobility 2021 on June 9, didn&#8217;t give away the first [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">While electric vertical take-off and landing passenger aircraft startup Joby Aviation is targeting North America for its initial commercial launch, founder and CEO JoeBen Bevirt expects the company to have an early presence in Asia and Europe as well.</p>
<p>Bevirt, who joined the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021?promo=leftrail&amp;display=true">TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</a> on June 9, didn&#8217;t give away the first location; although recent announcements suggest it is narrowed down to Los Angeles, Miami, New York and the San Francisco Bay Area. But he did weigh in on what those first cities will look like.</p>
<p>&#8220;I imagine that we will have early markets in each of the three regions,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Our initial launch market will be in North America just for proximity to the nexus of where most of our team is currently. But there are incredible opportunities and cities around the world and we want to provide as much benefit to as many people as quickly as we possibly can. And so that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re so focused on scaling manufacturing.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Joby Aviation<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> is expected to </span>begin construction on a 450,000-square-foot manufacturing facility, designed in conjunction with Toyota, later this year. The company has completed a pilot manufacturing facility already.</p>
<p>Joby, once a secretive startup, has had a far more public six months of late. The company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/joby-aviation-takes-flight-into-the-public-markets-via-a-spac-merger/">reached a deal to</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> merge with special purpose acquisition company Reinvent Technology Partners, formed by</span> well-known investor and LinkedIn co-founder Reid Hoffman, Michael Thompson and Zynga founder Mark Pincus. Hoffman also joined Bevirt at the TC Sessions: Mobility event.</p>
<p>Prior to its SPAC deal, Joby had gained attention and investors over the years as it developed its eVTOL. Toyota became an important backer and partner, leading a $620 million Series C round of funding in January 2020. Nearly a year later, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/uber-sells-air-taxi-business-elevate-to-joby-aviation-shedding-its-last-moonshot/">Joby acquired Uber’s air taxi moonshot Elevate</a> as part of a complex deal.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jjAOTEGTWv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/uber-sells-air-taxi-business-elevate-to-joby-aviation-shedding-its-last-moonshot/">Uber sells air taxi business Elevate to Joby Aviation, shedding its last moonshot</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Uber sells air taxi business Elevate to Joby Aviation, shedding its last moonshot&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/uber-sells-air-taxi-business-elevate-to-joby-aviation-shedding-its-last-moonshot/embed/#?secret=jjAOTEGTWv" data-secret="jjAOTEGTWv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Today, Joby is focused on certification, which it has been working on with the FAA since 2018, as well manufacturing its eVTOL aircraft. The company is also starting to put the pieces together for how and where it will operate. And that&#8217;s adding to its size. In the past year, Joby has doubled its workforce, which now sits at about 800.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Joby Aviation announced a partnership with REEF Technology, one of the country&#8217;s largest parking garage operators, and real estate acquisition company Neighborhood Property Group to build out its network of vertiports, with an initial focus on Los Angeles, Miami, New York and the San Francisco Bay Area.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">When 2024 arrives, Bevirt anticipates launching in one to two cities in that first year of operation. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;We do want to provide sufficient depth of coverage that consumers get to experience the transformative experience,&#8221; Bevirt said. &#8220;There have been cases where if a new service launches, and there&#8217;s not enough supply, consumers can be frustrated, right. And so we want to make sure we can, that we can really service, at least a portion of the demand and provide a really gratifying experience to our customers. I think that that&#8217;s the piece that we really care about as a company, is making customers into raving fans.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TG3n4Fz0Wu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/joby-aviation-takes-flight-into-the-public-markets-via-a-spac-merger/">Joby Aviation takes flight into the public markets via a SPAC merger</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Joby Aviation takes flight into the public markets via a SPAC merger&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/joby-aviation-takes-flight-into-the-public-markets-via-a-spac-merger/embed/#?secret=TG3n4Fz0Wu" data-secret="TG3n4Fz0Wu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/joby-aviation-eyes-asia-and-europe-as-early-markets-alongside-north-america/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2163996</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spotlight gets more powerful in iOS 15, even lets you install apps</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/spotlight-gets-more-powerful-in-ios-15-even-lets-you-install-apps/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/spotlight-gets-more-powerful-in-ios-15-even-lets-you-install-apps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 19:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Craig Federighi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imdb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS 15]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile devices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search results]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siri]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spotlight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WWDC 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2163990</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the upcoming release of iOS 15 for Apple mobile devices, Apple&#8217;s built-in search feature known as Spotlight will become a lot more functional. In what may be one of its bigger updates since it introduced Siri Suggestions, the new version of Spotlight is becoming an alternative to Google for several key queries, including web [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With the upcoming release of<a href="https://www.apple.com/ios/ios-15-preview/features/"> iOS 15</a> for Apple mobile devices, Apple&#8217;s built-in search feature known as Spotlight will become a lot more functional. In what may be one of its bigger updates since it <a href="https://tidbits.com/2015/09/16/explaining-siri-suggestions-and-spotlight-search-in-ios-9/">introduced</a> <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT210658">Siri Suggestions</a>, the new version of Spotlight is becoming an alternative to Google for several key queries, including web images and information about actors, musicians, TV shows and movies. It will also now be able to search across your photo library, deliver richer results for contacts, and connect you more directly with apps and the information they contain. It even allows you to install apps from the App Store without leaving Spotlight itself.</p>
<p>Spotlight is also more accessible than ever before.</p>
<p>Years ago, Spotlight moved from its location to the left of the Home screen to become available with a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/09/18/a-few-tricks-all-the-new-ios-7-users-should-know/">swipe down in the middle of any screen</a> in iOS 7, which helped grow user adoption. Now, it&#8217;s available with the same swipe-down gesture on the iPhone&#8217;s Lock Screen, too.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">You can access spotlight from the lock screen <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/iOS15?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#iOS15</a> (locked or unlocked) <a href="https://t.co/rVC1DqvBkA">pic.twitter.com/rVC1DqvBkA</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Alex Fife (@alextfife) <a href="https://twitter.com/alextfife/status/1402682130979823616?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 9, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Apple showed off a few of Spotlight&#8217;s improvements during its keynote address at its Worldwide Developers Conference, including the search feature&#8217;s new cards for looking up information on actors, movies and shows, as well as musicians. This change alone could redirect a good portion of web searches away from Google or dedicated apps like IMDb.</p>
<p>For years, Google has been offering quick access to common searches through its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Knowledge_Graph">Knowledge Graph</a>, a knowledge base that allows it to gather information from across sources and then use that to add informational panels above and the side of its standard search results. Panels on actors, musicians, shows and movies are available as part of that effort.</p>
<p>But now, iPhone users can just pull up this info on their home screen.</p>
<p>The new cards include more than the typical Wikipedia bio and background information you may expect &#8212; they also showcase links to where you can listen or watch content from the artist or actor or movie or show in question. They include news articles, social media links, official websites and even direct you to where the searched person or topic may be found inside your own apps (e.g. a search for &#8220;Billie Eilish&#8221; may direct you to her tour tickets inside SeatGeek, or a podcast where she&#8217;s a guest).</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2164042" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164042" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2164042" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.43-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="378" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.43-PM.jpg 3312w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.43-PM.jpg?resize=150,83 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.43-PM.jpg?resize=300,167 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.43-PM.jpg?resize=768,427 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.43-PM.jpg?resize=680,378 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.43-PM.jpg?resize=1536,854 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.43-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1139 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.43-PM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164042" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>For web image searches, Spotlight also now allows you to search for people, places, animals and more from the web &#8212; eating into another search vertical Google today provides.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2164070" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164070" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2164070" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_9609.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="571" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_9609.jpg 1284w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_9609.jpg?resize=150,126 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_9609.jpg?resize=300,252 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_9609.jpg?resize=768,645 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_9609.jpg?resize=680,571 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_9609.jpg?resize=50,42 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164070" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> iOS 15 screenshot</p></div></p>
<p>Your personal searches have been upgraded with richer results, too, in iOS 15.</p>
<p>When you search for a contact, you&#8217;ll be taken to a card that does more than show their name and how to reach them. You&#8217;ll also see their current status (thanks to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-refines-ios-15-notifications-with-focus-summary-features/">another iOS 15 feature</a>), as well as their location from FindMy, your recent conversations on Messages, your shared photos, calendar appointments, emails, notes and files. It&#8217;s almost like a personal CRM system.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2164045" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164045" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2164045" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.25-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="380" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.25-PM.jpg 3354w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.25-PM.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.25-PM.jpg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.25-PM.jpg?resize=768,429 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.25-PM.jpg?resize=680,380 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.25-PM.jpg?resize=1536,858 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.25-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1144 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.25-PM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164045" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>Personal photo searches have also been improved. Spotlight now uses Siri intelligence to allow you to search your photos by the people, scenes and elements in your photos, as well as by location. And it&#8217;s able to leverage the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apples-live-text-lets-you-interact-with-text-in-your-photos/">new Live Text feature in iOS 15</a> to find the text in your photos to return relevant results.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="V66CqWLYK9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apples-live-text-lets-you-interact-with-text-in-your-photos/">Apple&#8217;s Live Text lets you interact with text in your photos</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple&#8217;s Live Text lets you interact with text in your photos&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apples-live-text-lets-you-interact-with-text-in-your-photos/embed/#?secret=V66CqWLYK9" data-secret="V66CqWLYK9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This could make it easier to pull up photos where you&#8217;ve screenshot a recipe, a store receipt, or even a handwritten note, Apple said.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2164046" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164046" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2164046" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.16-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="381" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.16-PM.jpg 3330w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.16-PM.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.16-PM.jpg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.16-PM.jpg?resize=768,430 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.16-PM.jpg?resize=680,381 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.16-PM.jpg?resize=1536,860 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.16-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1146 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-3.11.16-PM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164046" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>A couple of features related to Spotlight&#8217;s integration with apps weren&#8217;t mentioned during the keynote.</p>
<p>Spotlight will now display action buttons on the Maps results for businesses that will prompt users to engage with that business&#8217;s app. In this case, the feature is leveraging <a href="https://developer.apple.com/app-clips/">App Clips</a>, which are small parts of a developer&#8217;s app that let you quickly perform a task even without downloading or installing the app in question. For example, from Spotlight you may be prompted to pull up a restaurant&#8217;s menu, buy tickets, make an appointment, order takeout, join a waitlist, see showtimes, pay for parking, check prices and more.</p>
<p>The feature will require the business to support App Clips in order to work.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2164054" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164054" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2164054" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_9606.png?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_9606.png 1284w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_9606.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_9606.png?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_9606.png?resize=768,1662 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_9606.png?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_9606.png?resize=710,1536 710w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_9606.png?resize=947,2048 947w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/IMG_9606.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164054" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> iOS 15 screenshot</p></div></p>
<p>Another under-the-radar change &#8212; but a significant one &#8212; is the new ability to install apps from the App Store directly from Spotlight.</p>
<p>This could prompt more app installs, as it reduces the steps from a search to a download, and makes querying the App Store more broadly available across the operating system.</p>
<p>Developers can additionally choose to insert a few lines of code to their app to make data from the <a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2021/10098/">app discoverable within Spotlight</a> and customize how it&#8217;s presented to users. This means Spotlight can work as a tool for searching content from inside apps &#8212; another way Apple is redirecting users away from traditional web searches in favor of apps.</p>
<p>However, unlike Google&#8217;s search engine, which relies on crawlers that browse the web to index the data it contains, Spotlight&#8217;s in-app search requires developer adoption.</p>
<p>Still, it&#8217;s clear Apple sees Spotlight as a potential rival to web search engines, including Google&#8217;s.</p>
<p>&#8220;Spotlight is the universal place to start <em>all</em> your searches,&#8221; said Apple SVP of Software Engineering Craig Federighi during the keynote event.</p>
<p>Spotlight, of course, can&#8217;t handle &#8220;all&#8221; your searches just yet, but it appears to be steadily working towards that goal.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/WWDC-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/wwdc-2021-banner.jpg" alt="read more about Apple's WWDC 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/spotlight-gets-more-powerful-in-ios-15-even-lets-you-install-apps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2163990</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Decades-old ASCII adventure NetHack may hint at the future of AI</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/decades-old-ascii-adventure-nethack-may-hint-at-the-future-of-ai/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/decades-old-ascii-adventure-nethack-may-hint-at-the-future-of-ai/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 19:09:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ascii]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook AI Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nethack]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2163929</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Machine learning models have already mastered Chess, Go, Atari games and more, but in order for it to ascend to the next level, researchers at Facebook intend for AI to take on a different kind of game: the notoriously difficult and infinitely complex NetHack. &#8220;We wanted to construct what we think is the most accessible &#8216;grand [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Machine learning models have already mastered Chess, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/05/24/alphago-beats-planets-best-human-go-player-ke-jie/">Go</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/01/deepminds-agent57-ai-agent-can-best-human-players-across-a-suite-of-57-atari-games/">Atari games</a> and more, but in order for it to ascend to the next level, researchers at Facebook intend for AI to <a href="https://ai.facebook.com/blog/launching-the-nethack-challenge-at-neurips-2021/">take on a different kind of game</a>: the notoriously difficult and infinitely complex NetHack.</p>
<p>&#8220;We wanted to construct what we think is <a href="https://nethackchallenge.com/">the most accessible &#8216;grand challenge&#8217;</a> with this game. It won&#8217;t <em>solve</em> AI, but it will unlock pathways towards <em>better</em> AI,&#8221; said Facebook AI Research&#8217;s Edward Grefenstette. &#8220;Games are a good domain to find our assumptions about what makes machines intelligent and break them.&#8221;</p>
<p>You may not be familiar with NetHack, but it&#8217;s one of the most influential games of all time. You&#8217;re an adventurer in a fantasy world, delving through the increasingly dangerous depths of a dungeon that&#8217;s different every time. You must battle monsters, navigate traps and other hazards, and meanwhile stay on good terms with your god. It&#8217;s the first &#8220;roguelike&#8221; (after Rogue, its immediate and much simpler predecessor) and arguably still the best — almost certainly the hardest.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>(It&#8217;s free, by the way, and you can <a href="http://nethack.org/">download and play it on nearly any platform.</a>)</p>
<p>Its simple ASCII graphics, using a g for a goblin, an @ for the player, lines and dots for the level&#8217;s architecture, and so on, belie its incredible complexity. Because Nethack, which made its debut in 1987, has been under active development ever since, with its shifting team of developers expanding its roster of objects and creatures, rules, and the countless, countless interactions between them all.</p>
<p>And this is part of what makes NetHack such a difficult and interesting challenge for AI: It&#8217;s so open-ended. Not only is the world different every time, but every object and creature can interact in new ways, most of them hand-coded over decades to cover every possible player choice.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2164028" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NetHack_level2.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164028" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2164028" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NetHack_level2.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="272" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NetHack_level2.jpg 1264w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NetHack_level2.jpg?resize=150,40 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NetHack_level2.jpg?resize=300,80 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NetHack_level2.jpg?resize=768,204 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NetHack_level2.jpg?resize=680,181 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NetHack_level2.jpg?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2164028" class="wp-caption-text">NetHack with a tile-based graphics update &#8211; all the information is still available via text.</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Atari, Dota 2, StarCraft 2&#8230; the solutions we&#8217;ve had to make progress there are very interesting. NetHack just presents different challenges. You have to rely on human knowledge to play the game as a human,&#8221; said Grefenstette.</p>
<p>In these other games, there&#8217;s a more or less obvious strategy to winning. Of course it&#8217;s more complex in a game like Dota 2 than in an Atari 800 game, but the idea is the same — there are pieces the player controls, a game board of environment, and win conditions to pursue. That&#8217;s kind of the case in NetHack, but it&#8217;s weirder than that. For one thing, the game is different every time, and not just in the details.</p>
<p>&#8220;New dungeon, new world, new monsters and items, you don&#8217;t have a save point. If you make a mistake and die you don&#8217;t get a second shot. It&#8217;s a bit like real life,&#8221; said Grefenstette. &#8220;You have to learn from mistakes and come to new situations armed with that knowledge.&#8221;</p>
<p>Drinking a corrosive potion is a bad idea, of course, but what about throwing it at a monster? Coating your weapon with it? Pouring it on the lock of a treasure chest? Diluting it with water? We have intuitive ideas about these actions, but a game-playing AI doesn&#8217;t think the way we do.</p>
<p>The depth and complexity of the systems in NetHack are difficult to explain, but that diversity and difficulty make the game a perfect candidate for a competition, according to Grefenstette. &#8220;You have to rely on human knowledge to play the game,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>People have been designing bots to play NetHack for many years that rely not on neural networks but decision trees as complex as the game itself. The team at Facebook Research hopes to engender a new approach by building a training environment that people can test machine learning-based game-playing algorithms on.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2164029" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/nethack-logic.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164029" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2164029" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/nethack-logic.png" alt="" width="1024" height="336" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/nethack-logic.png 1129w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/nethack-logic.png?resize=150,49 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/nethack-logic.png?resize=300,99 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/nethack-logic.png?resize=768,252 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/nethack-logic.png?resize=680,223 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/nethack-logic.png?resize=50,16 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2164029" class="wp-caption-text">NetHack screens with labels showing what the AI is aware of.</p></div></p>
<p>The <a href="https://github.com/facebookresearch/nle">NetHack Learning Environment</a> was actually put together last year, but the NetHack Challenge is only just now getting started. The NLE is basically a version of the game embedded in a dedicated computing environment that lets an AI interact with it through text commands (directions, actions like attack or quaff)</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a tempting target for ambitious AI designers. While games like StarCraft 2 may enjoy a higher profile in some ways, NetHack is legendary and the idea of building a model on completely different lines from those used to dominate other games is an interesting challenge.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also, as Grefenstette explained, a more accessible one than many in the past. If you wanted to build an AI for StarCraft 2, you needed a lot of computing power available to run visual recognition engines on the imagery from the game. But in this case the entire game is transmitted via text, making it extremely efficient to work with. It can be played thousands of times faster than any human could with even the most basic computing setup. That leaves the challenge wide open to individuals and groups who don&#8217;t have access to the kind of high-power setups necessary to power other machine learning methods.</p>
<p>&#8220;We wanted to create a research environment that had a lot of challenges for the AI community, but not restrict it to only large academic labs,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>For the next few months, NLE will be available for people to test on, and competitors can basically build their bot or AI by whatever means they choose. But when the competition itself starts in earnest on October 15, they&#8217;ll be limited to interacting with the game in its controlled environment through standard commands — no special access, no inspecting RAM, etc.</p>
<p>The goal of the competition will be to complete the game, and the Facebook team will track how many times the agent &#8220;ascends,&#8221; as it&#8217;s called in NetHack, in a set amount of time. But &#8220;we&#8217;re assuming this is going to be zero for everyone,&#8221; Grefenstette admitted. After all, this is one of the hardest games ever made, and even humans who have played it for years have trouble winning even once in a lifetime, let alone several times in a row. There will be other scoring metrics to judge winners in a number of categories.</p>
<p>The hope is that this challenge provides the seed of a new approach to AI, one that more fundamentally resembles actual human thinking. Shortcuts, trial and error, score-hacking, and zerging won&#8217;t work here — the agent needs to learn systems of logic and apply them flexibly and intelligently, or die horribly at the hands of an enraged centaur or owlbear.</p>
<p>You can check out the rules and other <a href="https://nethackchallenge.com/">specifics of the NetHack Challenge here</a>. Results will be announced at the NeurIPS conference later this year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Z73wE748dx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/ai-startup-investment-is-on-pace-for-a-record-year/">AI startup investment is on pace for a record year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;AI startup investment is on pace for a record year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/ai-startup-investment-is-on-pace-for-a-record-year/embed/#?secret=Z73wE748dx" data-secret="Z73wE748dx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/decades-old-ascii-adventure-nethack-may-hint-at-the-future-of-ai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2163929</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Todd and Rahul&#8217;s Angel Fund closes new $24 million fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/todd-and-rahuls-angel-fund-closes-new-24-million-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/todd-and-rahuls-angel-fund-closes-new-24-million-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 19:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[angel fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Angel Investor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[behance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dapper Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eventjoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[First Round Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jack Altman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lattice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Levels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national basketball association]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rahul Vohra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scott Belsky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shahed Khan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[superhuman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TicketMaster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Todd Goldberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2163947</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After making investments in 57 startups together, Superhuman CEO Rahul Vohra and Eventjoy founder Todd Goldberg are back at it with a new $24 million fund and big ambitions amid a venture capital renaissance with fast-moving deals aplenty. &#8220;Todd and Rahul&#8217;s Angel Fund&#8221; announced their first $7.3 million fund just weeks before the pandemic hit [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After making investments in 57 startups together, Superhuman CEO Rahul Vohra and Eventjoy founder Todd Goldberg are back at it with a new $24 million fund and big ambitions amid a venture capital renaissance with fast-moving deals aplenty.</p>
<p>&#8220;<a href="https://www.toddandrahulangelfund.com/">Todd and Rahul&#8217;s Angel Fund</a>&#8221; announced their first $7.3 million fund just weeks before the pandemic hit stateside last year and they were soon left with more access to deals than they had funding to support; they went on to raise $3.5 million in a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/angellist-pioneers-rolling-vc-funds-in-pivot-to-saas/">rolling fund</a> designed around making investments in later-stage deals beyond seed and Series A rounds.</p>
<p class="p1">&#8220;We closed right before COVID hit and we had one plan, but then everything accelerated,&#8221; Goldberg tells TechCrunch. &#8220;A lot of our companies started raising additional rounds.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>With their latest raise, Vohra and Goldberg are looking to maintain their wide outlook with a single fund, saying they plan to invest three-quarters of the fund in early-stage deals while saving a quarter of the $24 million for later-stage opportunities. Still, the duo know they likely could&#8217;ve chosen to raise more.</p>
<p>&#8220;A lot of our peers were scaling up into much larger funds,&#8221; Vohra says. &#8220;For us, we wanted to stay small and collaborative.&#8221;</p>
<p>Some of the firm&#8217;s investments from their first fund include NBA Top Shot creator <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/nba-top-shot-maker-dapper-labs-is-now-worth-2-6-billion-thanks-to-half-of-hollywood-the-nba-and-michael-jordan/">Dapper Labs</a>, open source Firebase alternative <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/supabase-raises-6m-for-its-open-source-firebase-alternative/">Supabase</a>, D2C liquor brand <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/30/haus-raises-4-5-million-to-replace-your-wine-club-membership/">Haus</a>, alternative asset platform <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/sports-trading-card-platform-alt-launches-with-31-million-in-funding-and-plenty-of-market-hype/">Alt</a>, biowearable maker <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/levels-raises-12m-from-a16z-and-others-to-bring-its-biowearable-to-market/">Levels</a> and location analytics startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/location-data-analytics-startup-placer-ai-raises-50m-series-b/">Placer</a>. Their biggest hit was an early investment in audio chat app Clubhouse before Andreessen Horowitz led its buzzy seed round at a $100 million valuation. Clubhouse most recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/clubhouse/">raised at $4 billion</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Gavup6Nwdi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/superhuman-and-eventjoy-founders-announce-7-million-angel-fund/">Superhuman and Eventjoy founders announce $7 million angel fund</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Superhuman and Eventjoy founders announce $7 million angel fund&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/superhuman-and-eventjoy-founders-announce-7-million-angel-fund/embed/#?secret=Gavup6Nwdi" data-secret="Gavup6Nwdi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The pair say they&#8217;ve learned a ton through the past year of navigating increasingly competitive rounds and that fighting for those deals has helped the duo hone how they market themselves to founders.</p>
<p>&#8220;You never want to be a passive check,&#8221; Goldberg says. &#8220;We do three things: we help companies find product/market fit, we help them super-charge distribution&#8230; and we help them find the best investors.&#8221;</p>
<p>A big part of the firm&#8217;s appeal to founders has been the &#8220;operator&#8221; status of its founders. Goldberg&#8217;s startup Eventjoy was acquired by Ticketmaster and Vohra&#8217;s Rapportive was bought by LinkedIn while his current startup Superhuman has maintained buzz for its premium email service and has raised $33 million from investors, including Andreessen Horowitz and First Round Capital.</p>
<p>Their new fund has an unusual LP base that&#8217;s made up of more than 110 entrepreneurs and investors, including 40 founders that Vohra and Goldberg have previously backed themselves. Backers of their second fund include Plaid&#8217;s William Hockey, Behance&#8217;s Scott Belsky, Haus&#8217;s Helena Price Hambrecht, Lattice&#8217;s Jack Altman and Loom&#8217;s Shahed Khan.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="e3gOUL1yNv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/superhuman-ceo-rahul-vohra-is-coming-to-techcrunch-early-stage-in-july/">Superhuman CEO Rahul Vohra is coming to TechCrunch Early Stage in July</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Superhuman CEO Rahul Vohra is coming to TechCrunch Early Stage in July&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/superhuman-ceo-rahul-vohra-is-coming-to-techcrunch-early-stage-in-july/embed/#?secret=e3gOUL1yNv" data-secret="e3gOUL1yNv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/todd-and-rahuls-angel-fund-closes-new-24-million-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2163947</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
