<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 16:57:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>For the love of the loot: Blockchain, the metaverse and gaming&#8217;s blind spot</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/for-the-love-of-the-loot-blockchain-the-metaverse-and-gamings-blind-spot/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/for-the-love-of-the-loot-blockchain-the-metaverse-and-gamings-blind-spot/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 16:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Loot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metaverse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roblox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203754</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The way NFTs are currently being discussed in relation to gaming are very much in danger of Killing the core gameplay loop via a financial fast track.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jonathan Stringfield</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/jdstringfield">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonathanstringfield/">Jonathan Stringfield</a>, PhD, is VP and Global Head of Business Marketing, Measurement and Insights at Activision Blizzard Media and Esports.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The speed at which gaming has proliferated is matched only by the pace of new buzzwords inundating the ecosystem. Marketers and decision makers, already suffering from FOMO about opportunities within gaming, have latched onto buzzy trends like the applications of blockchain in gaming and the “metaverse” in an effort to get ahead of the trend rather than constantly play catch-up.</p>
<p>The allure is obvious, as the relationship between the blockchain, metaverse, and gaming makes sense. Gaming has always been on the forefront of digital ownership (one can credit gaming platform Steam for normalizing the concept for games, and arguably other media such as movies), and most agreed upon visions of the metaverse rely upon virtual environments common in games with decentralized digital ownership.</p>
<p>Whatever your opinion of either, I believe they both have an interrelated future in gaming. However, the success or relevance of either of these buzzy topics is dependent upon a crucial step that is being skipped at this point.</p>
<p>Let’s start with the example of blockchain and, more specifically, NFTs. Collecting items of varying rarities and often random distribution form some of the core “loops” in many games (i.e. kill monster, get better weapon, kill tougher monster, get even better weapon, etc.), and collecting “skins” (e.g. different outfits/permutation of game character) is one of the most embraced paradigms of micro-transactions in games.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			The way NFTs are currently being discussed in relation to gaming are very much in danger of falling into this very trap: Killing the core gameplay loop via a financial fast track.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Now, NFTs are positioned to be a natural fit with various rare items having permanent, trackable, and open value. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/03/loot-games-the-crypto-world/">Recent releases</a> such as <a href="https://decrypt.co/80108/what-is-loot-ethereum-nft-role-playing-phenonemon">“Loot (for Adventurers)”</a> have introduced a novel approach wherein the NFTs are simply descriptions of fantasy-inspired gear and offered in a way that <a href="https://www.lootproject.com/resources">other creators can use them as tools to build worlds around</a>. It’s not hard to imagine a game built around NFT items, à la Loot.</p>
<p>But that’s been done before… kind of. Developers of games with a “loot loop” like the one described above have long had a problem with “farmers”, who acquire game currencies and items to sell to players for real money, against the terms of service of the game. The solution was to implement in-game “auction houses” where players could instead use real money to purchase items from one another.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Unfortunately, this had an unwanted side-effect. As noted by renowned game psychologist Jamie Madigan, our brains are evolved to pay special attention to rewards that are both unexpected and beneficial. When much of the joy in some games comes from an unexpected or randomized reward, being able to easily acquire a known reward with real money robbed the game of what made it fun.</p>
<p>The way NFTs are currently being discussed in relation to gaming are very much in danger of falling into this very trap: Killing the core gameplay loop via a financial fast track. The most extreme examples of this phenomena commit the biggest cardinal sin in gaming — a game that is “pay to win,” where a player with a big bankroll can acquire a material advantage in a competitive game.</p>
<p>Blockchain games such as <a href="https://axieinfinity.com/">Axie Infinity</a> have rapidly increased enthusiasm around the concept of &#8220;play to earn,&#8221; where players can potentially earn money by selling tokenized resources or characters earned within a blockchain game environment. If this sounds like a scenario that can come dangerously close to &#8220;pay to win,&#8221; that&#8217;s because it is.</p>
<p>What is less clear is whether it matters in this context. Does anyone care enough about the core game itself rather than the potential market value of NFTs or earning potential through playing? More fundamentally, if real-world earnings are the point, is it truly a game or just a gamified micro-economy, where “farming” as described above is not an illicit activity, but rather the core game mechanic?</p>
<p>The technology culture around blockchain has elevated solving for very hard problems that very few people care about. The solution (like many problems in tech) involves reevaluation from a more humanist approach. In the case of gaming, there are some fundamental gameplay and game psychology issues to be tackled before these technologies can gain mainstream traction.</p>
<p>We can turn to the metaverse for a related example. Even if you aren’t particularly interested in gaming, you’ve almost certainly heard of the concept after <a href="https://www.theverge.com/22588022/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-ceo-metaverse-interview">Mark Zuckerberg staked the future of Facebook upon it</a>. For all the excitement, the fundamental issue is that it simply doesn’t exist, and the closest analogs are massive digital game spaces (such as Fortnite) or sandboxes (such as Roblox). Yet, many brands and marketers who haven’t really done the work to understand gaming are trying to fast-track to an opportunity that isn’t likely to materialize for a long time.</p>
<p>Gaming can be seen as the training wheels for the metaverse — the ways we communicate within, navigate, and think about virtual spaces are all based upon mechanics and systems with foundations in gaming. I’d go so far as to predict the first adopters of any “metaverse” will indeed be gamers who have honed these skills and find themselves comfortable within virtual environments.</p>
<p>By now, you might be seeing a pattern: We’re far more interested in the “future” applications of gaming without having much of a perspective on the “now” of gaming. Game scholarship has proliferated since the early aughts due to a recognition of how games were influencing thought in fields ranging from sociology to medicine, and yet the business world hasn’t paid it much attention until recently.</p>
<p>The result is that marketers and decision makers are doing what they do best (chasing the next big thing) without the usual history of why said thing should be big, or what to do with it when they get there. The growth of gaming has yielded an immense opportunity, but the sophistication of the conversations around these possibilities remains stunted, due in part to our misdirected attention.</p>
<p>There is no “pay to win” fast track out of this blind spot. We have to put in the work to win.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/for-the-love-of-the-loot-blockchain-the-metaverse-and-gamings-blind-spot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203754</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto&#8217;s networked collaboration will drive Web 3.0</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/cryptos-networked-collaboration-will-drive-web-3-0/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/cryptos-networked-collaboration-will-drive-web-3-0/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 16:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proof of stake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203598</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Web 1.0 was the static web, and Web 2.0 is the social web, but Web 3.0 will be the decentralized web. It will move us from a world where communities contribute but don’t profit, to one where they can.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Harry Alford</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/HarryAlford3">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Harry Alford is a business development manager at Coinbase Cloud, formerly Bison Trails, where he leads sales and business development efforts for key protocols and engagements with major financial institutions, funds, exchanges and custodians. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Web 1.0 was the static web, and Web 2.0 is the social web, but Web 3.0 will be the decentralized web. It will move us from a world in which communities contribute but don’t own or profit, to one where they can through collaboration.</p>
<p>By breaking away from traditional business models centered around benefiting large corporations, Web3 brings the possibility of community-centered economies of scale. This collaborative spirit and its associated incentive mechanisms are attracting some of the most talented and ambitious developers today, unlocking projects that were previously not possible.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Web3 might not be the final answer, but it&#8217;s the current iteration, and innovation isn&#8217;t always obvious in the beginning.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Web3, as <a href="https://decrypt.co/resources/what-is-web-3">Ki Chong Tran</a> once said, is &#8220;The next major iteration of the internet, which promises to wrest control from the centralized corporations that today dominate the web.&#8221; Web3-enabled collaboration is made possible by decentralized networks that no single entity controls.</p>
<p>In closed-source business models, users trust a business to manage funds and execute services. With open source projects, users trust the technology to perform these tasks. In Web2, the bigger network wins. In Web3, whoever builds the biggest network together wins.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">web2: we work in a zero-sum environment where everything is a competition (who can build the biggest network)</p>
<p>web3: we work in a positive-sum environment where collaboration wins (how can we build the biggest network together)</p>
<p>&mdash; jessepollak.eth (@jessepollak) <a href="https://twitter.com/jessepollak/status/1427723477772034051?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 17, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>In a decentralized world, not only is participation open to all, the incentive structure is designed so that the greater the number of participants, the more everybody succeeds.</p>
<h2>Learning from Linux</h2>
<p>Linux, which is behind a majority of Web2&#8217;s websites, changed the paradigm for how the internet was developed and provides a clear example of how collaborative processes can drive the future of technology. Linux wasn&#8217;t developed by an incumbent tech giant, but by a group of volunteer programmers who used networked collaboration, which is when people freely share information without central control.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Cathedral-Bazaar-Musings-Accidental-Revolutionary/dp/0596001088">&#8220;The Cathedral &amp; The Bazaar,&#8221;</a> author Eric S. Raymond shares his observations of the Linux kernel development process and his experiences managing open source projects. Raymond depicts a time when the popular mindset was to develop complex operating systems carefully coordinated by a small, exclusionary group of people — “cathedrals,” which are corporations and financial institutions.</p>
<p>Linux evolved in a completely different way. Raymond explains, &#8220;Quality was maintained not by rigid standards or autocracy, but by the naively simple strategy of releasing every week and getting feedback from hundreds of users within days, creating a sort of Darwinian selection on the mutations introduced by developers. To the amazement of almost everyone, this worked quite well.&#8221; This <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux_kernel#Development_model">Linux development model</a>, or “bazaar” model as Raymond puts it, assumes that &#8220;bugs are generally shallow phenomena&#8221; when exposed to an army of hackers without significant coordination.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/cryptos-networked-collaboration-will-drive-web-3-0/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203598</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Confluent CEO Jay Kreps is coming to TC Sessions: SaaS for a fireside chat</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/confluent-ceo-jay-kreps-is-coming-to-tc-sessions-saas-for-a-fireside-chat/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/confluent-ceo-jay-kreps-is-coming-to-tc-sessions-saas-for-a-fireside-chat/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 16:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apache Kafka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Casey Aylward]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Confluent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[event streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Javier Soltero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jay Kreps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kobie Fuller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software as a service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions: SaaS 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203267</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As companies process ever-increasing amounts of data, moving it in real time is a huge challenge for organizations. Confluent is a streaming data platform built on top of the open source Apache Kafka project that&#8217;s been designed to process massive numbers of events. To discuss this, and more, Confluent CEO and co-founder Jay Kreps will [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As companies process ever-increasing amounts of data, moving it in real time is a huge challenge for organizations. <a href="https://www.confluent.io/">Confluent</a> is a streaming data platform built on top of the open source <a href="https://kafka.apache.org/">Apache Kafka</a> project that&#8217;s been designed to process massive numbers of events. To discuss this, and more, Confluent CEO and co-founder Jay Kreps will be joining us at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=jaycrepspost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=jaycrepspost&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TC Sessions: SaaS on Oct 27th</a> for a fireside chat.</p>
<p>Data is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/10/datarobot-ceo-dan-wright-coming-to-tc-sessions-saas-to-discuss-role-of-data-in-machine-learning/">a big part of the story</a> we are telling at the SaaS event, as it has such a critical role in every business. Kreps has said in the past the data streams are at the core of every business, from sales to orders to customer experiences. As he wrote in <a href="https://www.confluent.io/blog/series-e-round-metamorphosis/">a company blog post</a> announcing the company&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/21/confluent-lands-another-big-round-with-250m-series-e-on-4-2b-valuation/">$250 million Series E</a> in April 2020, Confluent is working to process all of this data in real time &#8212; and that was a big reason why investors were willing to pour so much money into the company.</p>
<p>&#8220;The reason is simple: though new data technologies come and go, event streaming is emerging as a major new category that is on a path to be as important and foundational in the architecture of a modern digital company as databases have been,&#8221; Kreps wrote at the time.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s streaming data platform takes a multi-faceted approach to streaming and builds on the open source Kafka project. While anyone can download and use Kafka, as with many open source projects, companies may lack the resources or expertise to deal with the raw open source code. Many a startup have been built on open source to help simplify whatever the project does, and Confluent and Kafka are no different.</p>
<p>Kreps <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/07/confluent-raises-50m-to-continue-growing-commercial-arm-of-apache-kafka/">told us in 2017</a> that companies using Kafka as a core technology include Netflix, Uber, Cisco and Goldman Sachs. But those companies have the resources to manage complex software like this. Mere mortal companies can pay Confluent to access a managed cloud version or they can manage it themselves and install it in the cloud infrastructure provider of choice.</p>
<p>The project was actually born at LinkedIn in 2011 when their engineers were tasked with building a tool to process the enormous number of events flowing through the platform. The company eventually open sourced the technology it had created and Apache Kafka was born.</p>
<p>Confluent launched in 2014 and raised over $450 million along the way. In its last private round in April 2020, the company scored a $4.5 billion valuation on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/21/confluent-lands-another-big-round-with-250m-series-e-on-4-2b-valuation/">a $250 million investment</a>. As of today, it has a market cap of over $17 billion.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In addition to our discussion with Kreps, the conference will also include Google&#8217;s Javier Soltero, Amplitude’s Olivia Rose, as well as investors Kobie Fuller and Casey Aylward, among others. We hope you’ll join us. It’s going to be a thought-provoking lineup.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=jaycrepspost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=jaycrepspost&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Buy your pass now to save up to $100 when you book by October 1</a>. We can’t wait to see you in October!</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-65d304c03160136b94a019a397c502b4"
			width="99%"
			height="1000"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/65d304c03160136b94a019a397c502b4"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-65d304c03160136b94a019a397c502b4')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-65d304c03160136b94a019a397c502b4'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/confluent-ceo-jay-kreps-is-coming-to-tc-sessions-saas-for-a-fireside-chat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203267</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Whatnot raises another $150M for its livestream shopping platform, evolves into a unicorn</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/whatnot-raises-another-150m-for-its-livestream-shopping-platform-evolves-into-a-unicorn/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/whatnot-raises-another-150m-for-its-livestream-shopping-platform-evolves-into-a-unicorn/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 16:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whatnot]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whatnot, a live streaming shopping platform for collectors to buy and sell things like rare Pokémon cards and Funko Pops, has closed a $150M Series C — its third round of fundraising in 2021 alone. This round pins Whatnot&#8217;s valuation at $1.5B, earning it a spot on the ever-growing list of unicorns. So what&#8217;s a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.whatnot.com">Whatnot</a>, a live streaming shopping platform for collectors to buy and sell things like rare Pokémon cards and Funko Pops, has closed a $150M Series C — its third round of fundraising in 2021 alone. This round pins Whatnot&#8217;s valuation at $1.5B, earning it a spot on the ever-growing list of unicorns.</p>
<p>So what&#8217;s a Whatnot? The app captures a trend that had been growing popular on platforms like Instagram in the US (and was already hugely popular in China): live shopping. Verified sellers can go on the air at any time, hosting on-the-fly video auctions for their goods. Sometimes buyers know exactly what they&#8217;re getting. Other times it&#8217;s more of a mystery bag; with the popular &#8220;card break&#8221; concept, for example, users buy assigned portions of an unopened (and often itself rare) box of Pokémon or sports cards and watch its contents revealed live.</p>
<p>This round was funded by return investors A16Z and Y Combinator&#8217;s Continuity fund, along with one new firm joining them: CapitalG (which was known as Google Capital <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/11/04/google-capital-changes-its-name-to-capitalg/">before the Google/Alphabet name change</a>.) They&#8217;ve also added a few well-known names to their list of angel investors, including Andre Iguodala of the Golden State Warriors, Zion Williamson of the New Orleans Pelicans, and Logan Paul of the YouTubes. Initial word of this round broke last week, via <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/live-shopping-startup-whatnot-raising-at-1-5-billion-valuation">TheInformation.</a></p>
<p>Whatnot originally started out as a more standard (less live) resale platform, at first focused on authenticating just one kind of collectable: Funko Pops. As the pandemic took over and everyone was suddenly stuck at home, they leaned hard into live shopping — and grew rapidly as a result.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GVdEe3JryL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/whatnot-wants-to-be-the-goat-of-collectible-toys-starting-with-funko-pop-figurines/">Whatnot wants to be the GOAT of collectible toys, starting with Funko Pops</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Whatnot wants to be the GOAT of collectible toys, starting with Funko Pops&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/whatnot-wants-to-be-the-goat-of-collectible-toys-starting-with-funko-pop-figurines/embed/#?secret=GVdEe3JryL" data-secret="GVdEe3JryL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Meanwhile, the company has been quickly expanding its scope; it grew from just Funko Pops to all sorts of other collectables, including Pokémon cards, pins, vintage clothing, sneakers, and more. Whatnot co-founder Grant Lafontaine tells me that its biggest driver is sports cards, followed by Pokémon and Funko Pops. With each category it dives into, Whatnot focuses on onboarding sellers that are already known and trusted in their respective community; each streamer on the platform is currently vetted by the company before they can go live, helping them keep fraud to a minimum. Doing anything sketchy just means getting booted off the platform and burning your own reputation in the process.</p>
<p>A few other key bits from my conversation with Lafontaine:</p>
<ul>
<li>He sees &#8220;thousands&#8221; of potential categories they can expand into. One they&#8217;re working on right now: NFTs. Streamers would be able to import their NFTs into Whatnot, displaying them on screen and bringing them in as (static or animated) overlays in the livestream. Users could tap an onscreen NFT to reveal its metadata and learn more about it.</li>
<li>He says there are &#8220;a couple thousand active livestream sellers&#8221; on the platform right now.</li>
<li>The company&#8217;s GMV (the total value of everything sold on the platform) is up 30x since its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/whatnot-raises-20m-for-its-live-streaming-platform-built-for-selling-pokemon-cards-and-other-collectibles/">Series A back in the beginning of this year</a>. Whatnot takes an 8% cut on each sale.</li>
<li>They&#8217;re in the middle of rolling out a &#8220;pre-bidding&#8221; feature, which will allow users to bid on items they know they want ahead of a livestream — if, for example, the user knows they want a certain thing and want a shot at it, but won&#8217;t be able to watch live. Others could still out bid them, of course.</li>
<li>The company is soon rolling out a complete rebuild of both its iOS and Android apps, with a new UI meant to make the entire process smoother and easier for both buyers and sellers. Lafontaine expects it to ship to everyone in &#8220;the next week or two.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<p>This round brings the company&#8217;s total funds raised to $225M — pretty much all of that in the last year. Meanwhile, competition in the space is heating up; Competitors like <a href="https://popshop.live/discovery">Popshop</a> have<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/popshop-live-raises-around-20m-at-a-100m-valuation-for-its-livestream-shopping-platform-for-hipsters/"> been raising millions</a> for their platforms, and Miami&#8217;s <a href="https://loupetheapp.com">Loupe</a> raised $12M back in June (and is opening a physical retail space soon) with its focus laser locked on sports cards live sales. Existing giants want in on it too: YouTube is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/youtube-to-pilot-test-shopping-from-livestreams-with-select-creators/">playing with the live shopping concept</a>, and Amazon has been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/livestream-e-commerce-why-companies-and-brands-need-to-tune-in/">bringing in influencers to host live sessions</a>. In other words: watch this space. Maybe watch it via livestream.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GxCQcTswBC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/whatnot-raises-50m-to-let-people-sell-pokemon-cards-funko-pops-and-more-via-livestream/">Whatnot raises $50M to let people sell Pokémon cards, Funko Pops and more via livestream</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Whatnot raises $50M to let people sell Pokémon cards, Funko Pops and more via livestream&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/whatnot-raises-50m-to-let-people-sell-pokemon-cards-funko-pops-and-more-via-livestream/embed/#?secret=GxCQcTswBC" data-secret="GxCQcTswBC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/whatnot-raises-another-150m-for-its-livestream-shopping-platform-evolves-into-a-unicorn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203814</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook revamps its business tool lineup following threats to its ad targeting business</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/facebook-revamps-its-business-tool-lineup-following-threats-to-its-ad-targeting-business/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/facebook-revamps-its-business-tool-lineup-following-threats-to-its-ad-targeting-business/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 15:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malaysia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messenger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philippines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private message]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203784</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook today is announcing the launch of new products and features for business owners, following the threat to its ad targeting business driven by Apple&#8217;s new privacy features, which now allow mobile users to opt out of being tracked across their iOS apps. The social networking giant has repeatedly argued that Apple&#8217;s changes would impact [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook today is <a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/news/introducing-products-for-the-next-era-of-personalized-experiences">announcing</a> the launch of new products and features for business owners, following the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-facebook-clash-over-ads-small-businesses-fear-theyll-be-impacted-11618009627">threat</a> to its ad targeting business driven by <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/apptrackingtransparency">Apple&#8217;s new privacy features</a>, which now allow mobile users to opt out of being tracked across their iOS apps. The social networking giant <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/facebook-apple-small-business/">has repeatedly argued that Apple&#8217;s changes</a> would impact small businesses that relied on Facebook ads to reach their customers. But it was not successful in getting any of Apple&#8217;s changes halted. Instead, the market is shifting to a new era focused more on user privacy, where personalization and targeting are more of an opt-in experience. That&#8217;s required Facebook to address its business advertiser base in new ways.</p>
<p>As the ability to track consumers declines &#8212; very few consumers are opting into tracking, <a href="https://www.flurry.com/blog/ios-14-5-opt-in-rate-att-restricted-app-tracking-transparency-worldwide-us-daily-latest-update/">studies find</a> &#8212; Facebook is rolling out new features that will allow businesses to better position themselves in front of relevant audiences. This includes updates that will let them reach customers, advertise to customers, chat with customers across Facebook apps, generate leads, acquire customers and more.</p>
<p>The company <a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/news/new-facebook-tools-for-online-marketing">earlier this year began testing a way</a> for customers to explore businesses from underneath News Feed posts by tapping on topics they were interested in &#8212; like beauty, fitness, and clothing, and explore content from other related businesses. The feature <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/facebook-to-test-new-business-discovery-features-in-u-s-news-feed/">allows people to come across new businesses</a> that may also like, and would allow Facebook to create its own data set of users who like certain types of content. Over time, it could possibly even turn the feature into an ad unit, where businesses could pay for higher placement.</p>
<p>But for the time being, Facebook will expand this feature to more users across the U.S., and launch it in Australia, Canada, Ireland, Malaysia, New Zealand, Philippines, Singapore, South Africa, and the U.K.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2139153" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2139153" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2139153" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-15-at-10.23.44-AM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="579" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-15-at-10.23.44-AM.jpg 2360w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-15-at-10.23.44-AM.jpg?resize=150,128 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-15-at-10.23.44-AM.jpg?resize=300,255 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-15-at-10.23.44-AM.jpg?resize=768,653 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-15-at-10.23.44-AM.jpg?resize=680,579 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-15-at-10.23.44-AM.jpg?resize=1536,1307 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-15-at-10.23.44-AM.jpg?resize=2048,1743 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-15-at-10.23.44-AM.jpg?resize=50,43 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2139153" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>Facebook is also making it easier for businesses to chat with customers. They&#8217;re already able to buy ads that encourage people to message them on Facebook&#8217;s various chat platforms &#8212; Messenger, Instagram Direct, or WhatsApp. Now, they&#8217;ll be able to choose all the messaging platforms where they&#8217;re available, and Facebook will default the chat app showcased in the ad based on where the conversation is most likely to happen.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203842" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203842" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2203842" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242183806_387010036350622_8333505588434282386_n.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="397" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242183806_387010036350622_8333505588434282386_n.jpg 4096w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242183806_387010036350622_8333505588434282386_n.jpg?resize=150,88 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242183806_387010036350622_8333505588434282386_n.jpg?resize=300,175 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242183806_387010036350622_8333505588434282386_n.jpg?resize=768,448 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242183806_387010036350622_8333505588434282386_n.jpg?resize=680,397 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242183806_387010036350622_8333505588434282386_n.jpg?resize=1536,896 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242183806_387010036350622_8333505588434282386_n.jpg?resize=2048,1195 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242183806_387010036350622_8333505588434282386_n.jpg?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203842" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company will tie WhatsApp to Instagram, as well, as part of this effort. Facebook explains that many businesses market themselves or run shops across Instagram, but rely on WhatsApp to communicate with customers and answer questions. So, Facebook will now allow businesses to add a WhatsApp click-to-chat button to their Instagram profiles.</p>
<p>This change, in particular, represents another move that ties Facebook&#8217;s separate apps more closely together, at a time when <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/08/19/tech/ftc-facebook-antitrust/index.html">regulators are considering</a> breaking up Facebook over antitrust concerns. Already, Facebook interconnected Facebook&#8217;s<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/facebook-introduces-cross-app-communication-between-messenger-and-instagram-plus-other-features/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/facebook-introduces-cross-app-communication-between-messenger-and-instagram-plus-other-features/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1631832022380000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEwiqhJ8za71NRnQ9rygzO2Td7FYQ"> Messenger and Instagram messaging services,</a> which would make such a disassembly more complicated. And more recently, it&#8217;s begun <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-08-23/facebook-retools-messaging-again-by-adding-calling-to-main-app?sref=gni836kR" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-08-23/facebook-retools-messaging-again-by-adding-calling-to-main-app?sref%3Dgni836kR&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1631832022380000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEMQrrClPG5e5iUh2nwYDsCtUpE2w">integrating</a> Messenger directly into Facebook&#8217;s platform itself.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203843" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203843" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2203843" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242123185_1221084118303928_6191054780633679594_n.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="350" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242123185_1221084118303928_6191054780633679594_n.jpg 4096w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242123185_1221084118303928_6191054780633679594_n.jpg?resize=150,77 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242123185_1221084118303928_6191054780633679594_n.jpg?resize=300,155 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242123185_1221084118303928_6191054780633679594_n.jpg?resize=768,396 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242123185_1221084118303928_6191054780633679594_n.jpg?resize=680,350 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242123185_1221084118303928_6191054780633679594_n.jpg?resize=1536,792 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242123185_1221084118303928_6191054780633679594_n.jpg?resize=2048,1056 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242123185_1221084118303928_6191054780633679594_n.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203843" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>In a related change, soon businesses will be able to create ads that send users directly to WhatsApp from the Instagram app. (Facebook also already offers ads like this.)</p>
<p>Separately from this news, Facebook<a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/whatsapp-business/whatsapp-launches-test-of-in-app-business-directory-idUKL1N2QH0U1"> announced the launch of a new business directory on WhatsApp</a>, allowing consumers to find shops and services on the chat platform, as well.</p>
<p>Another set of changes being introduced involve an update to <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2020/09/a-faster-and-easier-way-to-manage-your-business-on-facebook-and-instagram/">Facebook Business Suite</a>. Businesses will be able to manage emails through Inbox and sending remarketing emails; use a new File Manager for creating, managing, and posting content; and access a feature that will allow businesses to test different versions of a post to see which one is most effective.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203829" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203829" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2203829" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/facebook-business-suite.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/facebook-business-suite.png 3502w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/facebook-business-suite.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/facebook-business-suite.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/facebook-business-suite.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/facebook-business-suite.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/facebook-business-suite.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/facebook-business-suite.png?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/facebook-business-suite.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203829" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>Other new products include tests of paid and organic lead generation tools on Instagram; quote requests on Messenger, where customers answer a few questions prior to their conversations; and a way for small businesses to access a bundle of tools to get started with Facebook ads, which includes a Facebook ad coupon along with free access to QuickBooks for 3 months or free access to Canva Pro for 3 months.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203845" style="width: 341px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203845" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2203845" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242082022_193945919502671_1399180330540229658_n.jpg?w=331" alt="" width="331" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242082022_193945919502671_1399180330540229658_n.jpg 1195w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242082022_193945919502671_1399180330540229658_n.jpg?resize=73,150 73w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242082022_193945919502671_1399180330540229658_n.jpg?resize=146,300 146w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242082022_193945919502671_1399180330540229658_n.jpg?resize=768,1578 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242082022_193945919502671_1399180330540229658_n.jpg?resize=331,680 331w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242082022_193945919502671_1399180330540229658_n.jpg?resize=748,1536 748w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242082022_193945919502671_1399180330540229658_n.jpg?resize=997,2048 997w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/242082022_193945919502671_1399180330540229658_n.jpg?resize=24,50 24w" sizes="(max-width: 331px) 100vw, 331px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203845" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>Facebook will also begin testing something called &#8220;Work Accounts,&#8221; which will allow business owners to access their business products, like Business Manager, separately from their personal Facebook account. They&#8217;ll be able to manage these accounts on behalf of employees and use single-sign-on integrations.</p>
<p>Work Accounts will be tested through the remainder of the year with a small group of businesses, and Facebook says it expects to expand availability in 2022.</p>
<p>Other efforts it has in store include plans to incorporate more content from creators and local businesses and new features that let users control the content they see, but these changes were not detailed at this time.</p>
<p>Most of the products being announced are either rolling out today or will begin to show up soon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/facebook-revamps-its-business-tool-lineup-following-threats-to-its-ad-targeting-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203784</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ford boosts spending to increase production capacity of its F-150 Lightning electric truck</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/ford-boosts-spending-to-increase-production-capacity-of-its-f-150-lightning-electric-truck/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/ford-boosts-spending-to-increase-production-capacity-of-its-f-150-lightning-electric-truck/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 15:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[f-150 lightning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203802</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ford said Thursday it will invest another $250 million and add 450 jobs to increase production capacity of its upcoming F-150 Lightning to 80,000 all-electric trucks annually. The announcement comes after receiving more than 150,000 pre-orders for the all-electric pickup truck. The additional funds and jobs will be spread out across its new Rouge Electric [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Ford said Thursday it will invest another $250 million and add 450 jobs to increase production capacity of its upcoming F-150 Lightning to 80,000 all-electric trucks annually. The announcement comes after receiving more than 150,000 pre-orders for the all-electric pickup truck.</p>
<p>The additional funds and jobs will be spread out across its new Rouge Electric Vehicle Center in Dearborn, Michigan, Van Dyke Electric Powertrain Center and Rawsonville Components Plant, Ford said.</p>
<p>The announcement was made during an event at the Rouge Electric Vehicle Center, a 500,000-square-foot facility expansion that was part of Ford&#8217;s $700 million investment in its Rouge Complex. Gas-powered F-Series trucks are also assembled at the Rouge Complex.</p>
<p>Ford also announced that has started pre-production of the Lightning trucks. These prototypes will be used for real-world testing. The truck will be available to customers in spring 2022.</p>
<p>The all-electric pickup truck is a critical piece of the company&#8217;s $30 billion investment into electrification and one of a trifecta of Ford EV debuts and launches in the 18 months, including the Mustang Mach-E. The Lightning may be the most meaningful in terms of the bottom line. The Ford F-150 Lightning follows the introduction of the all-electric Mustang Mach-E and the E-Transit, a configurable all-electric cargo van focused on commercial customers.</p>
<p>The F-150 Lightning will be offered in four trims, which includes the base, XLT, Lariat and Platinum series, and two battery options. The truck, which has an aluminum alloy body, is powered by two in-board electric motors, comes standard with four-wheel drive and has an independent rear suspension. The base version will be priced at $39,974 before any federal or state tax credits, while the midseries XLT model will start at $52,974. All of these prices exclude the destination fees and taxes.</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/ford-boosts-spending-to-increase-production-capacity-of-its-f-150-lightning-electric-truck/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203802</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Submit your pitch deck now for live feedback at TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 next week</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/submit-your-pitch-deck-now-for-live-feedback-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2021-next-week/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/submit-your-pitch-deck-now-for-live-feedback-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2021-next-week/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 15:33:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pitch Deck Teardown]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203804</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The art of pitching is perhaps the most important art that a founder learns on their journey to unicorn status and beyond. And like any art, it helps to get some critical feedback along the way from the judges on the other side of the table. That’s why every Disrupt, we host Pitch Deck Teardown, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The art of pitching is perhaps the most important art that a founder learns on their journey to unicorn status and beyond. And like any art, it helps to get some critical feedback along the way from the judges on the other side of the table.</p>
<p>That’s why every Disrupt, we host Pitch Deck Teardown, a panel of VCs who read and critique several pitch decks in a row to offer feedback on everything from the overarching narrative and story to the mundane details of format, typography and colors.</p>
<p>At TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 next week, I’m excited to be hosting Maren Bannon of January Ventures, Bling Capital’s Ben Ling and Vanessa Larco of NEA for our next iteration of this popular workshopping panel.</p>
<p>If you’re a founder and want to submit your deck for consideration, <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSe6unxbSjKe2dVQxoDyNs95En1R3mzPc6I5D5Gdi7YhgDJPnA/viewform"><strong>head on over to this trusty Google Form</strong></a> and upload a copy of your pitch deck in PDF format. Remember that this will be presented publicly, so make sure it’s appropriate for a live studio audience. We’ll be selecting roughly six of them for inclusion in the event, and we’ll notify the founders selected by email.</p>
<p>Come join us next week! And if you need tickets to Disrupt, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021?promo=rightrail">we still have some available</a> for all the virtual excitement across two stages and dozens of fireside chats and panels.</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/submit-your-pitch-deck-now-for-live-feedback-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2021-next-week/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203804</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fiberplane nabs € 7.5M seed to bring Google Docs-like collaboration to incident response</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/fiberplane-nabs-e-7-5m-seed-to-bring-google-docs-like-collaboration-to-incident-response/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/fiberplane-nabs-e-7-5m-seed-to-bring-google-docs-like-collaboration-to-incident-response/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 15:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EU startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiberplane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[incident response]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SREs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203755</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fiberplane, an Amsterdam-based early stage startup that is building collaborative notebooks for SREs (site reliability engineers)  to collaborate around an incident in a similar manner to group editing in a Google Doc, announced a ​​€ 7.5M (approximately $8.8 million USD) seed round today. The round was co-led by Crane Venture Partners and Notion Capital with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://fiberplane.dev">Fiberplane</a>, an Amsterdam-based early stage startup that is building collaborative notebooks for SREs (site reliability engineers)  to collaborate around an incident in a similar manner to group editing in a Google Doc, announced a ​​€ 7.5M (approximately $8.8 million USD) seed round today.</p>
<p>The round was co-led by Crane Venture Partners and Notion Capital with participation from Northzone, System.One and Basecase Capital.</p>
<p>Micha Hernandez van Leuffen (known as Mies) is founder and CEO at Fiberplane. When his previous startup, Werker <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/17/developer-tools-startup-wrecker-has-been-acquired-by-oracle/">was sold to Oracle</a> in 2017, Hernandez van Leuffen became part of a much larger company where he saw people struggling to deal with outages (which happen at every company).</p>
<p>&#8220;We were always going back and forth between metrics, logs and traces, what I always call this sort of treasure hunt, and figuring out what was the underlying root cause of an outage or downtime,&#8221; Hernandez van Leuffen told me.</p>
<p>He said that this experience led to a couple of key insights about incident response: First, you needed a centralized place to pull all the incident data together, and secondly that as a distributed team managing a distributed system you needed to collaborate in real time, often across different time zones.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2j6uuBnH6n"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/31/how-you-react-when-your-systems-fail-may-define-your-business/">How you react when your systems fail may define your business</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How you react when your systems fail may define your business&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/31/how-you-react-when-your-systems-fail-may-define-your-business/embed/#?secret=2j6uuBnH6n" data-secret="2j6uuBnH6n" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>When he left Oracle in August 2020, he began thinking about the idea of giving DevOps teams and SREs the same kind of group editing capabilities that other teams inside an organization have with tools like Google Docs or Notion and an idea for his new company began to take shape.</p>
<p>What he created with Fiberplane is a collaborative notebook for SRE&#8217;s to pull in the various data types and begin to work together to resolve the incident, while having a natural audit trail of what happened and how they resolved the issue. Different people can participate in this notebook, just as multiple people can edit a Google Doc, fulfilling that original vision.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203799" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203799" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2203799" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screenshot-2-1.jpg?w=680" alt="Fiberplane incident response notebook with various types of data about the incident." width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screenshot-2-1.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screenshot-2-1.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screenshot-2-1.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screenshot-2-1.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screenshot-2-1.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screenshot-2-1.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screenshot-2-1.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screenshot-2-1.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203799" class="wp-caption-text">Fiberplane collaborative notebook example with multiple people involved. <strong>Image Credit:</strong> Fiberplane</p></div></p>
<p>He doesn&#8217;t plan to stop there though. The longer term vision is an operational platform for SREs and DevOps teams to deal with every aspect of an outage. &#8220;This is our starting point, but we are planning to expand from there as more I would say an SRE workbench, where you&#8217;re also able to command and control your infrastructure,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Today the company has 13 employees and is growing, and as they do, they are exploring ways to make sure they are building a diverse company, looking at concrete strategies to find more diverse candidates.</p>
<p>&#8220;To hire diversely, we’re re-examining our top of the funnel processes. Our efforts include posting our jobs in communities of underrepresented people, running our job descriptions through a gender decoder and facilitating a larger time frame for jobs to remain open,&#8221; Elena Boroda, marketing manager at Fiberplane said.</p>
<p>While Hernandez van Leuffen is based in Amsterdam, the company has been hiring people in the UK, Berlin, Copenhagen and the US, he said. The plan is to have Amsterdam as a central hub when offices reopen as the majority of employees are located there.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/fiberplane-nabs-e-7-5m-seed-to-bring-google-docs-like-collaboration-to-incident-response/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203755</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Don’t miss the Startup Alley Crawls at Disrupt next week</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/dont-miss-the-startup-alley-crawls-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/dont-miss-the-startup-alley-crawls-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 15:13:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup Alley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2195506</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s coming down to the wire folks. TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 — our flagship global event — takes over the internet on September 21-23. More than 10,000 people will attend to learn about the latest tech and investment trends from iconic leaders, founders and VCs. They’ll network and connect to build game-changing startups. Time to get [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It’s coming down to the wire folks. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> — our flagship global event — takes over the internet on September 21-23. More than 10,000 people will attend to learn about the latest tech and investment trends from iconic leaders, founders and VCs. They’ll network and connect to build game-changing startups.</p>
<p><strong>Time to get on board:</strong> It costs less than $100 to attend TechCrunch Disrupt until this Monday. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/tickets/">Purchase your pass</a> now to save yourself some money. You can check out <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/#0affacde-e0ed-4a3c-abc4-988cb1c0eb3e">the Disrupt agenda</a> here and then go grab your ticket.</p>
<p>The heart of every Disrupt — even our virtual incarnations — is Startup Alley. It’s where hundreds of innovative startups exhibit their products, platforms and services. It’s where investors look for portfolio potential, founders find new customers, tech journalists hunt for stories and everyone finds inspiration.</p>
<p>We’ve created a special series of events to focus on the wide range of talent in Startup Alley. It’s the Startup Alley Crawl — think pub crawl without the remorse. We group exhibitors in Startup Alley by business category, and each business category will have its own dedicated, hour-long crawl.</p>
<p>You might even see some of these exhibitors interviewed live during a Disrupt Desk segment. Sit back in the comfort of your secure, undisclosed location and tune in to learn more about what these companies have to offer.</p>
<p>All Startup Alley exhibitors have their own virtual booth where you can check out their pitch deck, strike up a conversation, schedule a product demo or connect with them via CrunchMatch to set up 1:1 video meetings.</p>
<p>Here’s what Jessica McLean, the director of marketing and communications for Infinite-Compute, a Startup Alley exhibitor at Disrupt 2020, had to say about networking during a virtual conference:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<blockquote><p>The virtual platform made networking easy. We sent quick introductions, scheduled meetings with investors and other smart people who could add value to our company. A person we connected with at Disrupt is currently helping us with marketing, which is fantastic.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> takes place on September 21-30. If you haven’t done so yet, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/tickets/">buy your pass now</a>. Pop some corn, pop a pint and join the Startup Alley Crawl — and check out all the other exhibitors, too. You never know what opportunities are waiting there just for you.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			width="99%"
			height="1300"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/dont-miss-the-startup-alley-crawls-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2195506</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tyk raises $35M for its open source, open-ended approach to enterprise API management</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/tyk-raises-35m-for-its-open-source-open-ended-approach-to-enterprise-api-management/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/tyk-raises-35m-for-its-open-source-open-ended-approach-to-enterprise-api-management/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 15:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apigee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[APIs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GraphQL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IBM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microservices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MMC Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulesoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scottish equity partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Société Générale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starbucks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tyk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[APIs are the grease turning the gears and wheels for many organizations&#8217; IT systems today, but as APIs grow in number and use, tracking how they work (or don&#8217;t work) together can become complex and potentially critical if something goes awry. Now, a startup that has built an innovative way to help with this is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">APIs are the grease turning the gears and wheels for many organizations&#8217; IT systems today, but as APIs grow in number and use, tracking how they work (or don&#8217;t work) together can become complex and potentially critical if something goes awry. Now, a startup that has built an innovative way to help with this is announcing some funding after getting traction with big enterprises adopting its approach.</p>
<p><a href="https://tyk.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tyk</a>, which has built a way for users to access and manage multiple internal enterprise APIs through a universal interface by way of GraphQL, has picked up $35 million, an investment that it will be using both for hiring and to continue enhancing and expanding the tools that it provides to users. Tyk has coined a term describing its approach to managing APIs and the data they produce &#8212; &#8220;<a href="https://tyk.io/docs/universal-data-graph/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">universal data graph</a>&#8221; &#8212; and today its tools are being used to manage APIs by some 10,000 businesses, including large enterprises like Starbucks, Societe Generale and Domino’s.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.sep.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span class="s4">Scottish Equity Partners</span></a> led the round, with participation also from <a href="https://mmc.vc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MMC Ventures</a> &#8212; its sole previous investor from a round in 2019 after boostrapping for its first five years. The startup is based out of London but works in a very distributed way &#8212; one of the co-founders is living in New Zealand currently &#8212; and it will be hiring and growing based on that principle, too. It has raised just over $40 million to date.</p>
<p>Tyk (pronounced like &#8220;tyke&#8221;, meaning small/lively child) got its start as an open source side project first for co-founder Martin Buhr, who is now the company&#8217;s CEO, while he was working elsewhere, as a &#8220;load testing thing,&#8221; in his words.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sVbrCUOB4i"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/corporate-venture-capital-follows-the-same-trend-as-other-vc-markets-up/">Corporate venture capital follows the same trend as other VC markets: Up</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Corporate venture capital follows the same trend as other VC markets: Up&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/corporate-venture-capital-follows-the-same-trend-as-other-vc-markets-up/embed/#?secret=sVbrCUOB4i" data-secret="sVbrCUOB4i" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The shifts in IT toward service-oriented architectures, and building and using APIs to connect internal apps, led him to rethink the code and consider how it could be used to control APIs. Added to that was the fact that as far as Buhr could see, the API management platforms that were in the market at the time &#8212; some of the big names today include Kong, Apigee (now a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/08/google-will-acquire-apigee-for-625-million/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">part of Google</a>), 3scale (now a <a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/about/press-releases/red-hat-acquire-api-management-leader-3scale" target="_blank" rel="noopener">part of RedHat</a> and thus IBM), MuleSoft (now a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/20/salesforce-is-buying-mulesoft-at-enterprise-value-of-6-5-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">part of Salesforce</a>) &#8212; were not as flexible as his needs were. &#8220;So I built my own,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>It was built as an open source tool, and some engineers at other companies started to use it. As it got more attention, some of the bigger companies interested in using it started to ask why he wasn&#8217;t charging for anything &#8212; a sure sign as any that there was probably a business to be built here, and more credibility to come if he charged for it.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;So we made the gateway open source, and the management part went into a licensing model,&#8221; he said. And Tyk was born as a startup co-founded with James Hirst, who is now the COO, who worked with Buhr at a digital agency some years before.</p>
<p>The key motivation behind building Tyk has stayed as its unique selling point for customers working in increasingly complex environments.</p>
<p>&#8220;What sparked interest in Tyk was that companies were unhappy with API management as it exists today,&#8221; Buhr noted, citing architectures using multiple clouds and multiple containers, creating more complexity that needed better management. &#8220;It was just the right time when containerization, Kubernetes and microservices were on the rise&#8230; The way we approach the multi-data and multi-vendor cloud model is super flexible and resilient to partitions, in a way that others have not been able to do.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;You engage developers and deliver real value and it’s up to them to make the choice,&#8221; added Hirst. &#8220;We are responding to a clear shift in the market.&#8221;</p>
<p>One of the next frontiers that Tyk will tackle will be what happens within the management layer, specifically when there are potential conflicts with APIs.</p>
<p class="p9">&#8220;When a team using a microservice makes a breaking change, we want to bring that up and report that to the system,&#8221; Buhr said. &#8220;The plan is to flag the issue and test against it, and be able to say that a schema won&#8217;t work, and to identify why.&#8221;</p>
<p>Even before that is rolled out, though, Tyk&#8217;s customer list and its growth speak to a business on the cusp of a lot more.</p>
<p>“Martin and James have built a world-class team and the addition of this new capital will enable Tyk to accelerate the growth of its API management platform, particularly around the GraphQL focused Universal Data Graph product that launched earlier this year,&#8221; said Martin Brennan, a director at SEP, in a statement. &#8220;We are pleased to be supporting the team to achieve their global ambitions.”</p>
<p>Keith Davidson, a partner at SEP, is joining the Tyk board as a non-executive director with this round.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/tyk-raises-35m-for-its-open-source-open-ended-approach-to-enterprise-api-management/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203688</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tiger’s bullish robotic investments</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/actuator-5/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/actuator-5/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 15:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Actuator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ambi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[berkshire grey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Locus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203434</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday, Tiger Global led not one but two big funding rounds, announcing its role in a $26 million Series A for Ambi and an additional $50 million for Locus Robotics. The firm has been so active in investing of late, that neither one of these companies cracked Alex’s coveted “Today’s Tiger round” in our [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">On Tuesday, Tiger Global led not one but two big funding rounds, announcing its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/logistics-robotics-startup-ambi-raises-26m/">role in a $26 million Series A for Ambi</a> and an additional <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/locus-robotics-just-raised-another-50m/">$50 million for Locus Robotics</a>. The firm has been so active in investing of late, that neither one of these companies cracked Alex’s coveted “Today’s Tiger round” in our daily newsletter (that honor went to a $150 million round for Indonesian fintech company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/indonesian-fintech-xendit-is-now-a-unicorn-with-150m-in-fresh-funding-led-by-tiger-global/">Xendit</a>).</p>
<p>It’s fair to say that Tiger is bullish about robotics as a category. Other rounds in recent months include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/rapid-robotics-raises-another-36-7m/">$36.7 million for Rapid Robotics</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/path-robotics-raises-another-100m/">$100 million for Path</a> &#8212; both Series B. All of the rounds are head-turning in the robotics world, and they represent a broad scope under the larger robotics umbrella. Ambi and Locus both operate (though address different problems) in the logistics/fulfillment spaces, while Path and Rapid deal with construction and manufacturing, respectively.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2191371" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2191371" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2191371" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2191371" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin/TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p><em>Don’t forget to sign up to get the upcoming <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">free newsletter version</a> of Actuator delivered to your inbox.</em></p>
<p>Certainly that last bit speaks to how diversified interest has been in the category. All of the above industries no doubt saw enough impact during the pandemic to significantly accelerate interest in automation.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2114223" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2114223" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2114223" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Locus-Robotics-Pickers-2.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Locus-Robotics-Pickers-2.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Locus-Robotics-Pickers-2.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Locus-Robotics-Pickers-2.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Locus-Robotics-Pickers-2.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Locus-Robotics-Pickers-2.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Locus-Robotics-Pickers-2.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Locus-Robotics-Pickers-2.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Locus-Robotics-Pickers-2.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2114223" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Locus Robotics</p></div></p>
<p>It’s also telling that the warehouse/fulfillment side of things gets a bit of extra love. In addition to the general strains of the pandemic, there’s the fact that everyone is looking for a way to compete with Amazon. The retailer already has a massive stranglehold on these categories and gave itself a big head start in terms of automation through a series of acquisitions. It’s an industry where any competitive advantage means a lot, and companies like Locus are hoping to crack that code.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In February, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/locus-robotics-has-raised-a-150m-series-e/">company raised a hefty $150 million</a>, with Tiger on as co-lead. And this week, the firm returned with another $50 million. Locus’ approach to the category offers more flexibility than those companies that require a kind of ground-up rebuild. It’s an appealing option in terms of pricing and time frame, and makes a lot more sense for organizations looking for seasonable robotic help &#8212; ditto for the company’s robotics-as-a-service pricing model.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2201880" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2201880" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2201880" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Ambi-Robotics_Founders-1.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Ambi-Robotics_Founders-1.jpg 8256w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Ambi-Robotics_Founders-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Ambi-Robotics_Founders-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Ambi-Robotics_Founders-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Ambi-Robotics_Founders-1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Ambi-Robotics_Founders-1.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Ambi-Robotics_Founders-1.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Ambi-Robotics_Founders-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2201880" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Ambi Robotics</p></div></p>
<p>Ambi, which got its first TechCrunch mention in one of these columns several months back, specializes in pick and place/sorting robots. The company came out of stealth is April and is already seeing solid adoption.</p>
<p>“Ambi Robotics combines cutting-edge AI technology with engaging user interfaces to transform the role of ‘item handlers’ to ‘robot handlers,’ ” CEO Jim Liefer said in a release. “With our Series A funding, we will be able to empower more companies to help their associates work harmoniously alongside robots.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203696" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203696" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2203696" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/download-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="763" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/download-1.png 1323w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/download-1.png?resize=150,112 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/download-1.png?resize=300,224 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/download-1.png?resize=768,572 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/download-1.png?resize=680,507 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/download-1.png?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203696" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Berkshire Grey</p></div></p>
<p>On the aforementioned ground-up approach to warehouse automation, <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2021/09/15/2297513/0/en/Berkshire-Grey-Announces-Global-Availability-of-its-AI-Enabled-Robotic-Pick-and-Pack-RPP-Solutions-for-e-Commerce-Fulfillment-Following-Successful-Customer-Deployments.html">Berkshire Grey this week announced</a> its own Robotic Pick and Pack (RPP) system, designed to pack goods into shipping packages. The system has already been deployed at SoftBank Logistics’ flagship location in Ichikawa, Japan.</p>
<p>Here’s COO Steve Johnson:</p>
<blockquote><p>We believe our RPP system is the first robotic eCommerce fulfillment solution capable of completely automating the picking and packing process of direct-to-consumer orders for apparel, cosmetics, health and beauty, sporting equipment, food and general merchandise &#8212; it will transform the speed and efficiencies of warehouses and fulfillment centers around the globe. Berkshire Grey RPP excels in handling orders – the AI handles a wide range of SKUs and does so carefully – meeting even the exacting quality standards of Japanese consumers.</p></blockquote>
<p><div id="attachment_2203694" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203694" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2203694" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Spot-3.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="538" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Spot-3.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Spot-3.jpg?resize=150,79 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Spot-3.jpg?resize=300,158 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Spot-3.jpg?resize=768,403 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Spot-3.jpg?resize=680,357 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Spot-3.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203694" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Boston Dynamics</p></div></p>
<p>Boston Dynamics, meanwhile,<a href="https://blog.bostondynamics.com/spot-release-3.0-flexible-autonomy-and-repeatable-data-capture"> announced an update for Spot</a> that brings additional autonomous features to the four-legged robot. Specifically, the Spot Release 3.0 update is designed to improve the robot’s data collection capabilities. Per BD:</p>
<blockquote><p>Schedule missions for Spot to collect photos, thermal images, point clouds, and other critical data; process that data into valuable signals at the edge with computer vision models; and create custom uploads to send those signals to your existing systems, so it’s easy to keep all of your data in one place for analysis and review. Spot Release 3.0 makes dynamic sensing available to everyone.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/actuator-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203434</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>As offices come back, ATMO launches air monitoring device claiming to give COVID-risk score</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/as-offices-come-back-atmo-launches-air-monitoring-device-claiming-to-give-covid-risk-score/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/as-offices-come-back-atmo-launches-air-monitoring-device-claiming-to-give-covid-risk-score/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 14:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airthings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ATMO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atmotube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[player]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vera kozyr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world health organization]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203766</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Way back in 2015 we covered the launch of the Atmotube, a small, innovative, portable air quality monitor which went on to receive a number of awards after its CES debut. Since rebranding as ATMO, the company, co-founded by Vera Kozyr, is now launching the Atmocube, an indoor air quality monitoring system for businesses and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Way back in 2015 we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/11/16/atmotube-is-a-tiny-pollution-sensor-that-clears-up-whats-in-the-air-you-breathe/">covered</a> the launch of the Atmotube, a small, innovative, portable air quality monitor which went on to receive a number of awards after its CES debut.</p>
<p>Since rebranding as <a href="https://atmotube.com">ATMO</a>, the company, co-founded by <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/vera-kozyr">Vera Kozyr</a>, is now launching the <a href="https://atmotube.com/pages/atmocube">Atmocube</a>, an indoor air quality monitoring system for businesses and enterprises. This new product is positioned far more for the post-COVID era, where air quality inside offices is going to be vital, and this time, instead of being small and portable (although that earlier product is still sold), the Atmocube will be prominent and visible in order to give office workers peace of mind that their air quality is good.</p>
<p>The key to this is measuring CO2 levels, which the Atmocube displays on its screen along with other metrics.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KP1R2cWlin"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/11/16/atmotube-is-a-tiny-pollution-sensor-that-clears-up-whats-in-the-air-you-breathe/">Atmotube Is A Tiny Pollution Sensor That Clears Up What&#8217;s In The Air You Breathe</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Atmotube Is A Tiny Pollution Sensor That Clears Up What&#8217;s In The Air You Breathe&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2015/11/16/atmotube-is-a-tiny-pollution-sensor-that-clears-up-whats-in-the-air-you-breathe/embed/#?secret=KP1R2cWlin" data-secret="KP1R2cWlin" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The device has up to 14 sensors measuring various environmental parameters such as CO2, formaldehyde NO2, PM1 (small airborne particles), PM2.5, ozone and others, and other environmental parameters, such as relative humidity, temperature, atmospheric pressure, ambient noise, light levels and color temperature.</p>
<p>The company says this new device also calculates the Airborne Virus Transmission Score — based on the levels of particulate matter, humidity and CO2, and says it comes up with a “score” that estimates the probability of transferring virus diseases in closed spaces. Obviously, that’s probably something that would need independent testing to verify, but it is the case that the WHO <a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/q-a-detail/coronavirus-disease-covid-19-how-is-it-transmitted">advises</a> that COVID-19 can be transmitted in poorly ventilated and/or crowded indoor settings.</p>
<p>Kozyr said: “Air pollution is dangerous because it can affect you and your health even if you don’t notice it. We aim to help people know what they’re breathing and make changes as a result. As businesses return to the office, they need a tool to make information about indoor air quality transparent and accessible to their employees. Most air quality monitors are designed to be hidden away, so we set out to create a device with a more transparent interface that would highlight HVAC performance safety and create trust between occupants and building owners”.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>ATMO is by no means the only player in the space of course, as it’s joined by <a href="https://www.airthings.com/en/">AirThings</a>, <a href="https://uk.getawair.com/">Awair Omni</a> and <a href="https://www.kaiterra.com/en/index/">Kaiterra</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/as-offices-come-back-atmo-launches-air-monitoring-device-claiming-to-give-covid-risk-score/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203766</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Open Mineral raises $33M Series C funding for its &#8216;eBay for commodities trading&#8217; platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/open-mineral-raises-33m-series-c-funding-for-its-ebay-for-commodities-trading-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/open-mineral-raises-33m-series-c-funding-for-its-ebay-for-commodities-trading-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 14:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commodities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mubadala Investment Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Open Mineral]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203753</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Back in 2018 we covered how Open Mineral (OM), a startup aiming to leverage greater transparency in commodities trading, had raised $2.25 million. Well, they’ve come a long way, and now the Zug, Switzerland-based, company has raised a $33 million Series C funding round led by Mubadala Investment Company. Existing investors Xploration Capital and Emerald [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Back in 2018 we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/19/open-mineral-plans-to-disrupt-commodities-trading-with-blockchain/">covered</a> how <a href="https://openmineral.com/">Open Mineral</a> (OM), a startup aiming to leverage greater transparency in commodities trading, had raised $2.25 million. Well, they’ve come a long way, and now the Zug, Switzerland-based, company has raised a $33 million Series C funding round led by <a href="https://www.mubadala.com/">Mubadala Investment Company</a>. Existing investors Xploration Capital and Emerald Technology Ventures were joined by new investors Statkraft and Lingfeng Capital.</p>
<p>The company says it will use the capital to solidify its physical supply chain merchant activities. The commodities trading market is worth $200 billion and even today there’s still a lot of paper flying around, so digitization is continuing apace.</p>
<p>Open Mineral says its platform has registered more than 900 metals and mining companies across the world, using its pricing algorithms across the commodity supply chain.</p>
<p>As well as digitizing aspects of the industry, OM says it’s also working with third-party providers to incorporate &#8220;green&#8221; ESG metrics across the sell-side and buy-side.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rLEBt6sBhu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/19/open-mineral-plans-to-disrupt-commodities-trading-with-blockchain/">Open Mineral plans to disrupt commodities trading with blockchain</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Open Mineral plans to disrupt commodities trading with blockchain&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/19/open-mineral-plans-to-disrupt-commodities-trading-with-blockchain/embed/#?secret=rLEBt6sBhu" data-secret="rLEBt6sBhu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>It also claims to have developed automated blending/smelter material optimization solutions “enabling more efficient, informed, and profitable trade of physical metal raw commodities.” These have an impact on transitioning to a lower carbon footprint, says the company.</p>
<p>Boris Eykher, CEO and co-founder of Open Mineral, said in a statement: “The metal trading industry’s future is in digital data and analytics, enabling market participants to communicate faster and make quicker, and more data-driven decisions. Just as eBay revolutionized retail purchasing by bringing more choices to buyers and sellers, we aim to do the same for physical commodity producers in a curated, trusted environment of the Open Mineral platform.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Faris Al Mazrui, head of Russia and CIS Investments at Mubadala, said: “Open Mineral is disrupting the commodity trading business by leveraging data analytics technology. Buyers and sellers of base metal commodities can tap into a unique and proprietary data hub to trade more efficiently and capture upside.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/open-mineral-raises-33m-series-c-funding-for-its-ebay-for-commodities-trading-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203753</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What could stop the startup boom?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/what-could-stop-the-startup-boom/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/what-could-stop-the-startup-boom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 14:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlantico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taiwan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unicorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital funds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203712</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Similar to how certain macroeconomic conditions have provided a long-term boost, a reversal of those conditions could do the opposite.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We’ve spent so long staring at record venture capital results around the world from Q2 that it’s nearly Q3.</p>
<p>We’ve seen record results from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/bostons-startup-market-is-more-than-setting-records-in-scorching-start-to-year/">cities</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/16/india-poised-for-record-vc-year-as-unicorns-head-for-decisive-ipos/">countries</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/the-european-vc-market-is-so-hot-it-may-skip-its-summer-holiday/">regions</a>. There’s so much money sloshing around the venture capital and startup worlds that it’s hard to recall what they were like in leaner times. We’ve been in a bull market for tech upstarts for so long that it feels like the only possible state of affairs.</p>
<p>It’s not.</p>
<p>Digging back through our notes from the last few months from data sources, investors and founders, it’s clear that there are macroeconomic factors bolstering the startup economy. And there are changes to the economy that are providing additional lift. Secular tailwinds, if you will.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>But as the market giveth, it can also taketh away.</p>
<p>What might slow the startup boom? Similar to how certain macroeconomic conditions have provided a long-term boost, a reversal of those conditions could do the opposite. The secular trends powering startups — often on the demand side due to more rapid digitalization of global business — may be unconnected to the larger economy, a view underscored by software’s outsized performance during COVID-19 induced economic mess of mid-2020.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995212 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>This morning, let’s talk about what’s fueling startups and their backers, and what could change. Because no bull market lasts forever.</p>
<h2>Driving forces</h2>
<p>Prominent among the macroeconomic conditions that have helped startups’ fundraising totals rise are globally low interest rates. Money is cheap around the world at the moment.</p>
<p>It doesn’t cost much to borrow money today, compared to historical norms. The result of that dynamic is that lending money doesn’t earn as much either. Bank yields are negative in real terms, and bond yields aren’t impressive.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.readmargins.com/p/zirp-explains-the-world">Money always skates towards yield</a>, so the low interest rate environment has led to lots of capital moving toward more lucrative investing options. This dynamic is partially responsible for the seemingly ever-rising stock market, for example. It’s also a partial explanation of why there is so much capital flowing into venture capital funds and other vehicles that push money into high-growth private companies. The money is looking for yield.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/what-could-stop-the-startup-boom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203712</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Avalanche raises $230 million from private sale of AVAX tokens</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/avalanche-raises-230-million-from-private-sale-of-avax-tokens/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/avalanche-raises-230-million-from-private-sale-of-avax-tokens/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avalanche]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Polychain Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Three Arrows Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203736</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Avalanche, a relatively new blockchain with a focus on speed and low transactions costs, has completed a $230 million private sale of AVAX tokens to some well-known crypto funds. Polychain and Three Arrows Capital are leading the investment. The Avalanche Foundation completed the private sale back in June 2021 and is disclosing it today. Other [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.avax.network">Avalanche</a>, a relatively new blockchain with a focus on speed and low transactions costs, has completed a $230 million private sale of AVAX tokens to some well-known crypto funds. Polychain and Three Arrows Capital are leading the investment.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.avalabs.org">Avalanche Foundation</a> completed the private sale back in June 2021 and is disclosing it today. Other participants in the private sale include R/Crypto Fund, Dragonfly, CMS Holdings, Collab+Currency and Lvna Capital.</p>
<p>Proceeds from the private sale will be used to support the Avalanche ecosystem, which is relatively nascent when you compare it to the Ethereum blockchain, for instance. Among other things, the foundation plans to support DeFi (decentralized finance) projects as well as enterprise applications through grants, token purchases and other forms of investments.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YKFyft9vS0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/everyone-wants-to-fund-the-next-coinbase/">Everyone wants to fund the next Coinbase</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Everyone wants to fund the next Coinbase&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/everyone-wants-to-fund-the-next-coinbase/embed/#?secret=YKFyft9vS0" data-secret="YKFyft9vS0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Like <a href="https://solana.com">Solana</a> and other newer blockchains, Avalanche wants to solve the scalability issues that older blockchains face. For instance, if you’ve recently tried to buy an NFT on the Ethereum blockchain, you probably paid $50 or $100 in transaction fees, or gas fees.</p>
<p>The Avalanche Foundation positions its blockchain as a solid alternative to Ethereum. You can run Dapps (decentralized apps) for a fraction of the costs with a much faster time-to-finality. Avalanche supports smart contracts, which is a key feature to enable DeFi projects.</p>
<p>Here’s what Avalanche’s official website says about its blockchain performance:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203737" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203737" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2203737" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-16-at-3.46.47-PM.png" alt="" width="1024" height="668" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-16-at-3.46.47-PM.png 2434w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-16-at-3.46.47-PM.png?resize=150,98 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-16-at-3.46.47-PM.png?resize=300,196 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-16-at-3.46.47-PM.png?resize=768,501 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-16-at-3.46.47-PM.png?resize=680,444 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-16-at-3.46.47-PM.png?resize=1536,1002 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-16-at-3.46.47-PM.png?resize=2048,1336 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-16-at-3.46.47-PM.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203737" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Avalanche</p></div></p>
<p>Having better performance is just part of the problem when you’re competing with Ethereum and other blockchains. Avalanche also needs to attract developers and build a strong developer community so that it becomes the infrastructure of other crypto projects.</p>
<p>That’s why Avalanche wants to make it as easy as possible to port your Ethereum Dapp to Avalanche. Avalanche’s smart contract chain executes Ethereum Virtual Machine contracts, which means that you can reuse part of your codebase if you’re already active on the Ethereum blockchain.</p>
<p>Similarly, applications that query the Ethereum network can be adapted to support Avalanche by changing API endpoints and adding support for a new network. The Avalanche team has also been working on <a href="https://medium.com/avalancheavax/new-avalanche-bridge-builds-on-intel-sgx-technology-in-breakthrough-for-cross-chain-8f854e0e72e0">a bridge</a> to transfer Ethereum assets to the Avalanche blockchain. The equivalent of $1.3 billion in crypto assets have been transferred using this bridge.</p>
<p>Those are technical incentives. As for financial incentives, private sales and grants could help bootstrap developer interest. The Avalanche Foundation says that 225 projects currently support the platform, including popular crypto projects that already run on other blockchains, such as Tether, SushiSwap, Chainlink, Circle and The Graph. <a href="https://toppsnfts.com">Topps</a>, an NFT-based game with partnerships with the MLB and Bundesliga, is also using Avalanche.</p>
<p>Avalanche and its underlying token AVAX is currently the 14th cryptocurrency by total market capitalization according to <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com">CoinMarketCap</a>. With a current market cap of $13 billion, Avalanche is ahead of Algorand or Polygon, but behind Polkadot and Solana. Solana also suffered from a <a href="https://decrypt.co/80917/solana-down-for-hours-resource-exhaustion">major outage</a> earlier this week, raising questions about Solana&#8217;s ability to scale. It’s going to be interesting to see whether one of these blockchains can catch up with Ethereum or even surpass Ethereum in usage and value.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/avalanche-raises-230-million-from-private-sale-of-avax-tokens/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203736</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CodeSignal secures $50M for its tech hiring platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/codesignal-secures-50m-for-its-tech-hiring-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/codesignal-secures-50m-for-its-tech-hiring-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 14:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A.Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CodeSignal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HR tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Index Venture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[menlo ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nina Achadjian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tigran Sloyan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upwork]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203426</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The company’s technical assessment technology is a “flight simulator for developers,” that gives candidates a score based on a simulated evaluation of their skills.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In less than a year after raising <a href="https://codesignal.com/blog/codesignal-news/codesignal-announces-25m-series-b-funding/">$25 million in Series B funding</a>, technical assessment company <a href="https://codesignal.com/">CodeSignal</a> announced a $50 million in Series C funding to offer new features for its platform that helps companies make data-driven hiring decisions to find and test engineering talent.</p>
<p>Similar to attracting a big investor lead for its B round — Menlo Ventures — it has partnered with Index Ventures to lead the C round. Menlo participated again and was joined by Headline and A Capital. This round brings CodeSignal’s total fundraising to $87.5 million.</p>
<p>Co-founder and CEO Tigran Sloyan got the idea for the company from an experience his co-founder and friend Aram Shatakhtsyan had while trying to find an engineering job. Both from Armenia, the two went in different paths for college, with Shatakhtsyan staying in Armenia and Sloyan coming to the U.S. to study at MIT. He then went on to work at Google.</p>
<p>“As companies were recruiting myself and my classmates, Aram was trying to get his resume picked up, but wasn’t getting attention because of where he went to college, even though he was the greatest programmer I had ever known,” Sloyan told TechCrunch. “Hiring talent is the No. 1 problem companies say they have, but here was the best engineer, and no one would bring him in.”</p>
<p>They, along with Sophia Baik, started CodeSignal in 2015 to act as a self-driving interview platform that directly measures skills regardless of a person’s background. Like people needing to take a driver’s test in order to get a license, Sloyan calls the company’s technical assessment technology a “flight simulator for developers,” that gives candidates a simulated evaluation of their skills and comes back with a score and highlighted strengths.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The need by companies to hire engineers has led to CodeSignal growing 3.5 times in revenue year over year and to gather a customer list that includes Brex, Databricks, Facebook, Instacart, Robinhood, Upwork and Zoom.</p>
<p>Sloyan said the company has not yet touched the money it received in its Series B, but wanted to jump at the opportunity to work with Nina Achadjian, partner at Index Ventures, whom he had known for many years since their time together at Google. To work together and for Achadjian to join the company’s board was something “I couldn’t pass up,” Sloyan said.</p>
<p>When Achadjian moved over to venture capital, she helped Sloyan connect to mentors and angel investors while keeping an eye on the company. Hiring engineers is “mission critical” for technology companies, but what became more obvious to her was that engineering functions have become necessary for all companies, Achadjian explained.</p>
<p>While performing due diligence on the space, she saw traditional engineering cultures utilizing CodeSignal, but then would also see nontraditional companies like banks and insurance companies.</p>
<p>“Their traction was undeniable, and many of our portfolio companies were using CodeSignal,” she added. “It is rare to see a company accelerate growth at the stage they are at.”</p>
<p>U.S. Department of Labor statistics estimate there is already a <a href="https://www.daxx.com/blog/development-trends/software-developer-shortage-us#The%20US%20Tech%20Talent%20Shortage%20Statistics%20in%202020">global talent labor shortage of 40 million workers</a>, and that number will grow to over 85 million by 2030. Achadjian says engineering jobs are also expected to increase during that time, and with all of those roles and applicants, vetting candidates will be more important than ever, as will the ability for candidates to apply from wherever they are.</p>
<p>The new funding enabled the company to launch its Integrated Development Environment for candidates to interact with relevant assessment experiences like codes, files and a terminal on a machine that is familiar with them, so that they can showcase their skills, while also being able to preview their application. At the same time, employers are able to assign each candidate the same coding task based on the open position.</p>
<p>In addition, Sloyan intends to triple the company’s headcount over the next couple of months and expand into other use cases for skills assessment.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EDWxNA0rlW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/14/how-to-hire-your-first-engineer-a-guide-for-nontechnical-founders/">How to hire your first engineer: A guide for nontechnical founders</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to hire your first engineer: A guide for nontechnical founders&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/14/how-to-hire-your-first-engineer-a-guide-for-nontechnical-founders/embed/#?secret=EDWxNA0rlW" data-secret="EDWxNA0rlW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/codesignal-secures-50m-for-its-tech-hiring-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203426</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google&#8217;s R&#038;D division experiments with newsletters powered by Google Drive</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/googles-rd-division-experiments-with-newsletters-powered-by-google-drive/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/googles-rd-division-experiments-with-newsletters-powered-by-google-drive/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 13:52:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Area 120]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Slides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google-docs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google-Drive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Museletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[publishers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[R&D]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Substack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203705</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Following entries into the newsletter market from tech companies like Facebook and Twitter, Google is now experimenting with newsletters, too. The company&#8217;s internal R&#38;D division, Area 120, has a new project called Museletter, which allows anyone to publish a Google Drive file as a blog or newsletter to their Museletter public profile or to an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Following entries into the newsletter market from tech companies like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/facebooks-newsletter-platform-bulletin-is-now-live/">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/twitter-is-testing-a-feature-that-puts-users-revue-newsletters-on-their-profiles/">Twitter</a>, Google is now experimenting with newsletters, too. The company&#8217;s internal R&amp;D division, Area 120, has a new project called <a href="https://museletter.area120.google.com/">Museletter</a>, which allows anyone to publish a Google Drive file as a blog or newsletter to their Museletter public profile or to an email list.</p>
<p>The effort would essentially repurpose Google&#8217;s existing document-creation tools as a means of competing with other newsletter platforms, like Substack, Ghost, Revue and others, which are today attracting a <a href="https://whatsnewinpublishing.com/one-of-the-most-important-tools-available-to-publishers-email-newsletters-are-resurging-says-reuters-institute/">growing</a> audience.</p>
<p>Google&#8217;s experiment was spotted this week by sites including <a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/09/14/google-area-120-museletter/">9to5Google</a> and <a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/09/15/googles-latest-area-120-experiment-wants-to-help-you-start-a-newsletter/">Android Police</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RC0JD7GriF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/twitter-is-testing-a-feature-that-puts-users-revue-newsletters-on-their-profiles/">Twitter is testing a feature that puts users&#8217; Revue newsletters on their profiles</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter is testing a feature that puts users&#8217; Revue newsletters on their profiles&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/twitter-is-testing-a-feature-that-puts-users-revue-newsletters-on-their-profiles/embed/#?secret=RC0JD7GriF" data-secret="RC0JD7GriF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Reached for comment, an Area 120 spokesperson declined to share further details about Museletter, saying only that it was &#8220;one of the many experiments&#8221; within the R&amp;D group and that &#8220;it&#8217;s still very early.&#8221;</p>
<p>From the Museletter website, however, there is already much that can be learned about the project. The site explains how Google Drive could be monetized by creators in a way that would allow Google&#8217;s newsletter project to differentiate itself from the competition. Not only could newsletters be written in a Google Doc, other productivity apps could also be used to share information with readers. For example, a newsletter creator could offer a paid subscription plan that would allow readers to access their Google Slides. A creator who writes about finance could publish helpful spreadsheets to Google Sheets, which would be available to their subscribers.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2203725" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2203725" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2203725" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/museletter2.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" /><p id="caption-attachment-2203725" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>To make this possible, Museletter publishers would create a public profile on their Google Drive, then publish any Google Drive file directly to it. This provides them with a landing page where they can market their subscriptions and showcase how many different Drive files they&#8217;ve made publicly available across Docs, Sheets and Slides.</p>
<p>Creators can also optionally publish to an email list &#8212; including a list brought in from other platforms. The newsletter subscriptions can be free or paid, depending on the creator&#8217;s preferences, but using Museletter itself will be free. Instead, the project aims to monetize with premium features like custom domains, welcome emails and more.</p>
<p>The platform also promises tools and analytics to engage audiences and track the newsletter&#8217;s performance.</p>
<p>While the site doesn&#8217;t mention any plans for advertising, a success in this space could provide Google with a new<a href="https://thefix.media/2021/04/06/newsletters-help-grow-subscriptions-generate-ad-revenue-and-gear-up-for-a-cookie-less-world/"> ad revenue</a> stream &#8212; and one that arrives at a time when the tech giant&#8217;s multibillion-dollar advertising market has a new challenger in the form of Amazon, whose own ad business could <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90631969/amazon-ad-business-growth">eventually challenge</a> the Facebook-Google duopoly.</p>
<p>Google didn&#8217;t say when it plans to launch Museletter, but the website is offering <a href="https://museletter.area120.google.com/signup">a link to a form</a> where users can request early access.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/googles-rd-division-experiments-with-newsletters-powered-by-google-drive/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203705</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FTC says health apps must notify consumers about data breaches — or face fines</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/ftc-says-health-apps-must-notify-consumers-if-their-data-is-breached-or-face-fines/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/ftc-says-health-apps-must-notify-consumers-if-their-data-is-breached-or-face-fines/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 13:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Babylon Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FLO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[identity management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lina Khan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpyFone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terms of service]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203695</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Federal Trade Commission (FTC) has warned apps and devices that collect personal health information must notify consumers if their data is breached or shared with third parties without their permission. In a 3-2 vote on Wednesday, the FTC agreed on a new policy statement to clarify a decade-old 2009 Health Breach Notification Rule, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The U.S. Federal Trade Commission (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ftc/">FTC</a>) has warned apps and devices that collect personal health information must notify consumers if their data is breached or shared with third parties without their permission.</p>
<p>In a 3-2 vote on Wednesday, the FTC agreed on a <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2021/09/ftc-warns-health-apps-connected-device-companies-comply-health">new policy statement</a> to clarify a decade-old 2009 Health Breach Notification Rule, which requires companies handling health records to notify consumers if their data is accessed without permission, such as the result of a breach. This has now been extended to apply to health apps and devices — specifically calling out apps that track fertility data, fitness and blood glucose — which “too often fail to invest in adequate privacy and data security,” according to FTC chair Lina Khan.</p>
<p>“Digital apps are routinely caught playing fast and loose with user data, leaving users&#8217; sensitive health information susceptible to hacks and breaches,&#8221; said Khan in a statement, pointing to a study published this year in the British Medical Journal that found health apps suffer from “serious problems” ranging from the insecure transmission of user data to the unauthorized sharing of data with advertisers.</p>
<p>There have also been a number of recent high-profile breaches involving health apps in recent years. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/babylon-health/">Babylon Health</a>, a U.K. AI chatbot and telehealth startup, last year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/10/babylon-health-admits-software-error-led-to-patient-data-breach/">suffered a data breach</a> after a “software error” allowed users to access other patients’ video consultations, while period tracking app <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/flo-gets-ftc-slap-for-sharing-user-data-when-it-promised-privacy/">Flo was recently found to be sharing users’ health data</a> with third-party analytics and marketing services.</p>
<p>Under the new rule, any company offering health apps or connected fitness devices that collect personal health data must notify consumers if their data has been compromised. However, the rule doesn&#8217;t define a &#8220;data breach&#8221; as just a cybersecurity intrusion; unauthorized access to personal data, including the sharing of information without an individual&#8217;s permission, can also trigger notification obligations.</p>
<p>&#8220;While this rule imposes some measure of accountability on tech firms that abuse our personal information, a more fundamental problem is the commodification of sensitive health information, where companies can use this data to feed behavioral ads or power user analytics,” Khan said.</p>
<p>If companies don&#8217;t comply with the rule, the FTC said it will &#8220;vigorously&#8221; enforce fines of $43,792 per violation per day.</p>
<p>The FTC has been cracking down on privacy violations in recent weeks. Earlier this month, the agency <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/spyfone-ftc-stalkerware/">unanimously voted to ban spyware maker SpyFone</a> and its chief executive Scott Zuckerman from the surveillance industry for harvesting mobile data on thousands of people and leaving it on the open internet.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PwvSJdNQBb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/opioid-addiction-treatment-apps-found-sharing-sensitive-data-with-third-parties/">Opioid addiction treatment apps found sharing sensitive data with third parties</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Opioid addiction treatment apps found sharing sensitive data with third parties&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/opioid-addiction-treatment-apps-found-sharing-sensitive-data-with-third-parties/embed/#?secret=PwvSJdNQBb" data-secret="PwvSJdNQBb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/ftc-says-health-apps-must-notify-consumers-if-their-data-is-breached-or-face-fines/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203695</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lucid Air snags the longest range EV title, surpassing Tesla</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/lucid-air-snags-the-longest-range-ev-title-surpassing-tesla/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/lucid-air-snags-the-longest-range-ev-title-surpassing-tesla/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 13:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lucid Air]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lucid group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucid Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203721</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lucid Group, the all-electric automaker slated to go public this year, said Thursday that one variant of its upcoming luxury Air sedan has an EPA range of more than 520 miles. The official rating of the Lucid Air Dream Edition Range variant pushes Lucid past Tesla, a company that has long dominated in this category. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Lucid Group, the all-electric automaker <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/22/lucid-motors-strikes-spac-deal-to-go-public-with-24-billion-valuation/">slated to go public</a> this year, said Thursday that one variant of its upcoming luxury Air sedan has an EPA range of more than 520 miles. The official rating of the Lucid Air Dream Edition Range variant pushes Lucid past Tesla, a company that has long dominated in this category.</p>
<p>The official EPA range of the Lucid Air — and its many editions — have been expected to be as high or higher than some of Tesla&#8217;s models. This announcement not only gives Lucid bragging rights, it reveals a bit about the company&#8217;s strategy to offer a variety of versions of the Air sedan with prices ranging between $169,000 and $77,400.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ISl7e7aKjh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/arrivals-denis-sverdlov-on-the-new-era-of-car-manufacturing/">Arrival&#8217;s Denis Sverdlov on the new era of car manufacturing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Arrival&#8217;s Denis Sverdlov on the new era of car manufacturing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/arrivals-denis-sverdlov-on-the-new-era-of-car-manufacturing/embed/#?secret=ISl7e7aKjh" data-secret="ISl7e7aKjh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Lucid initially planned to sell one version of Lucid Air Dream Edition, essentially its first and flagship model of the sedan. There are now two versions: the Lucid Air Dream Edition Range, which has 520 miles of range when equipped with 19-inch tires and 933 horsepower, and the Lucid Air Dream Edition Performance, a more powerful version with 1,111 horsepower that can travel 471 miles on a single charge when equipped with 19-inch tires. The range on the Dream Edition Range drops to 481 and the Dream Edition Performance to 451 miles when the vehicles have 21 inch tires.</p>
<p>Lucid Group CTO and CEO Peter Rawlinson credits the range figure on a combination of its 900V battery and battery management system, smaller drive units and its electric drive train technology. Rawlinson noted that he believed this is a new record for any EV.</p>
<p>Lucid plans to produce and sell other variants of the Air, including a Grand Touring version that received a 516-mile EPA range rating. The Grand Touring variant has a starting price of $139,000, while the longest-range Dream Edition has a base price of $169,000. The automaker plans to sell two other, less expensive versions: the Air Touring that starts at $95,000 and the Air Pure with a $77,400 base price.</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/lucid-air-snags-the-longest-range-ev-title-surpassing-tesla/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203721</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SOSV is building a New Jersey HAX facility for industrial, healthcare and climate startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/sosv-is-building-a-new-jersey-hax-facility-for-industrial-healthcare-and-climate-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/sosv-is-building-a-new-jersey-hax-facility-for-industrial-healthcare-and-climate-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 13:26:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accelerator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sosv]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2203698</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SOSV this morning announced work on a $50 million HAX facility in Newark, New Jersey focused on growing industrial, healthcare and climate startups. The five-year development plan utilizes $25 million from the New Jersey Economic Development Authority. The facility is set to open in June of 2022, with an eye on early-stage U.S. companies working [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">SOSV this morning announced work on a $50 million HAX facility in Newark, New Jersey focused on growing industrial, healthcare and climate startups. The five-year development plan utilizes $25 million from the New Jersey Economic Development Authority.</p>
<p>The facility is set to open in June of 2022, with an eye on early-stage U.S. companies working toward their seed round. SOSV notes that, while HAX&#8217;s earliest focus was on wearables, in more recent years, the accelerator has largely shifted to industrial and healthcare, which currently comprise 70% and 20% of its portfolio, respectively.</p>
<p>“Since 2015, HAX started investing in more industrial &amp; health startups and today make up 90% of our new investments,” HAX partner Garrett Winther told TechCrunch. “These hard tech startups, at their earliest stages, tend to rely on more deep science R&amp;D, high-precision prototyping, and only require one to two of their first product before raising funding. These companies also take up a lot of space, easily filling a room with their equipment and prototypes.”</p>
<p>Newark was chosen for myriad reasons, including proximity to New York City and universities like Princeton and Rutgers. It also, frankly, has more space than, say, Manhattan &#8212; which is a clear necessity for industrial startups. That’s a big part of the reason companies like AeroFarms and Bowery have looked toward to the area to host their massive vertical farming facilities.</p>
<p>The fact that the state was willing to put up around half the cost of the project likely didn’t hurt, either. New Jersey no doubt has a vested interest in welcoming hardware startups with open arms. It will be interesting to see what sort of incentives the local governments can offer to help keep them there to avoid the allure of nearby NYC.</p>
<p>“Growing New Jersey’s innovation economy both creates high-quality jobs today and generates opportunities for exponential returns in the future,” NJEDA CEO Tim Sullivan said in a release. “As startups become successful and scale-up in New Jersey, they build buildings, hire more employees, and become anchors for vibrant communities and small-business supply-chains.”</p>
<p>SOSV says the Newark location will effectively operate as a U.S. equivalent to its offices in Shenzhen, China, which afford easy access to the global supply chain. HAX also operates satellites in San Francisco, Tokyo and New York.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/sosv-is-building-a-new-jersey-hax-facility-for-industrial-healthcare-and-climate-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203698</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
