<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 15:20:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Twitter relaunches test that asks users to revise harmful replies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/twitter-relaunches-test-that-asks-users-to-revise-harmful-replies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/twitter-relaunches-test-that-asks-users-to-revise-harmful-replies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 15:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bullying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tweet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter is running a new test that will ask users to pause and think before they tweet. According to the company&#8217;s announcement, when Twitter detects what appears to be a potentially harmful or offensive reply to someone else&#8217;s tweet, it will prompt you to consider revising your text instead of tweeting. Users whose tweets are [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter is running a new test that will ask users to pause and think before they tweet. According to the company&#8217;s <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1363956974824550400">announcement</a>, when Twitter detects what appears to be a potentially harmful or offensive reply to someone else&#8217;s tweet, it will prompt you to consider revising your text instead of tweeting.</p>
<p>Users whose tweets are flagged in this way will see a pop-up message appear on their screen, which asks, &#8220;Want to review this before Tweeting?&#8221; There are three buttons to then choose from: one to tweet the reply anyway, an Edit button (this is as close as we&#8217;ll get, apparently), and a delete button to discard the tweet entirely. There is also a small link to report if the system got things wrong.</p>
<p>This is not the first time Twitter has run a test like this.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/05/twitter-harmful-replies-prompt-harassment-test-feature/">May 2020</a> and again in <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1292883957164281861">August 2020</a>, Twitter ran variations on this same experiment. In those cases, the text on the pop-up screen was largely the same, but the layout of the three buttons looked different and were less colorful.</p>
<p>The earlier tests ran on Android, iOS and web, but this current iteration is only on iOS, for the time being.</p>
<p>At the time of the initial test, Twitter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/05/twitter-harmful-replies-prompt-harassment-test-feature/">explained</a> its systems were able to detect harmful language based on the kind of language that had been used in other tweets that had been reported in the past.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Say something in the moment you might regret? <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f62c.png" alt="😬" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> We&#39;ve relaunched this experiment on iOS that asks you to review a reply that&#39;s potentially harmful or offensive. </p>
<p>Think you&#39;ve received a prompt by mistake? Share your feedback with us so we can improve. <a href="https://t.co/t68az8vlYN">pic.twitter.com/t68az8vlYN</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Twitter Support (@TwitterSupport) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1363956974824550400?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 22, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>It&#8217;s been shown that these sorts of built-in small nudges can have an impact.</p>
<p>For example, when Twitter began <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/twitter-read-before-retweet/">prompting users to read the article</a> linked in a tweet before retweeting it, the company found that users would open the articles 40% more often than without the nudge. Twitter has also built similar experiments to try to slow down the pace of online conversation on its platform, by doing things like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/09/twitter-retweet-changes-quote-tweet-election-misinformation/">discouraging retweets without commentary</a> or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/twitter-may-slow-down-users-ability-to-like-tweets-containing-misinformation/">slow down &#8220;Likes&#8221;</a> on tweets containing misinformation.</p>
<p>Other social networks use small nudges like this, too, to influence their users&#8217; behavior. Instagram back in 2019 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/08/instagram-anti-bullying-features/">launched</a> a feature that would flag potentially offensive comments before they were posted, and later <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/16/instagram-to-now-flag-potentially-offensive-captions-in-addition-to-comments/">expanded</a> this to captions. TikTok more recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-to-flag-and-downrank-unsubstantiated-claims-fact-checkers-cant-verify/">launched a banner</a> that would ask users if they were sure they wanted to share a video that contains &#8220;unverified content.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s unclear why Twitter hasn&#8217;t simply rolled out the pop-up to combat online abuse &#8212; still a serious issue on its platform &#8212; and then iterated on the design and style of the message box, as needed.</p>
<p>Compared with the much larger engineering and design efforts the company has had underway &#8212; including its newer Stories feature known as Fleets and a Clubhouse rival called Spaces &#8212; a box asking users to pause and think seems like something that could have graduated to a full product by now.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/twitter-relaunches-test-that-asks-users-to-revise-harmful-replies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116508</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>RIBS: The messaging framework for every company and product</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/ribs-the-messaging-framework-for-every-company-and-product/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/ribs-the-messaging-framework-for-every-company-and-product/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 15:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2115904</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Relevant. Inevitable. Believable. Simple. Behind most successful companies is a story that checks every one of those boxes.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Caryn Marooney</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/carynm650">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Caryn Marooney is general partner at <a href="https://www.coatue.com/">Coatue Management</a> and sits on the boards of Zendesk and Elastic. In prior roles she oversaw communications for Facebook, Instagram, WhatsApp and Oculus and co-founded The OutCast Agency, which served clients like Salesforce.com and Amazon.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/bottom-up-saas-a-framework-for-mapping-pricing-to-customer-value/">Bottom-up SaaS: A framework for mapping pricing to customer value</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/27/onboarding-employees-and-maintaining-culture-in-a-remote-work-environment/">Onboarding employees and maintaining culture in a remote work environment </a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Over more than two decades of advising founders, I’ve heard all kinds of stories &#8212; good, bad and everything in between. While everyone is different, I’ve noticed that the very best stories have something in common: They pass the RIBS test. I’ve<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/14/facebooks-former-pr-chief-explains-why-no-one-is-paying-attention-to-your-startup/"> talked a lot</a> about this over the years, and it’s stood the test of time and trends.</p>
<p>The test is designed to tell you if your story is memorable (will it “stick to your ribs?”) so you can turn it into a compelling message. It looks something like this:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>R</strong>elevant</li>
<li><strong>I</strong>nevitable</li>
<li><strong>B</strong>elievable</li>
<li><strong>S</strong>imple</li>
</ul>
<h2>Relevant</h2>
<p>Before you can come up with a good story, you need to think about the audience. Who are you trying to reach? Are you solving a problem they care about? What matters to them about that problem? Why does your solution deserve attention?</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			The test is designed to tell you if your story is memorable (will it “stick to your ribs?”) so you can turn it into a compelling message.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Marc Benioff could have launched Salesforce by describing it as an online way for companies to manage relationships with their customers. It’s true and it would have been interesting, at least to some people. But instead, Marc went bigger: He ran a campaign that described Salesforce as the “end of software.”</p>
<p>At the time, software was everywhere and it was creating all kinds of problems: It was massively expensive, time consuming and prone to failure. By taking on those issues, Marc made the company instantly more relevant to a bigger market and audience. The conversation went from a discussion of feature checklists, contacts and leads, to how an entire industry would change. Marc looked like a visionary — and Salesforce seemed revolutionary.</p>
<h2>Inevitable</h2>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/ribs-the-messaging-framework-for-every-company-and-product/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2115904</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shippo raises $45M more at $495M valuation as ecommerce booms</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/shippo-raises-45m-more-at-495m-valuation-as-ecommerce-booms/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/shippo-raises-45m-more-at-495m-valuation-as-ecommerce-booms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 15:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shippo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116243</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning Shippo, a software company that provides shipping-related services to ecommerce companies, announced a new $45 million investment. The new capital values the startup at $495 million. TechCrunch is calling the new funding a Series D as it is a priced round that followed its Series C; the company did not award the round [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a href="https://goshippo.com/">Shippo</a>, a software company that provides <a href="https://goshippo.com/products/shipping/">shipping-related services</a> to ecommerce companies, announced a new $45 million investment. The new capital values the startup at $495 million. TechCrunch is calling the new funding a Series D as it is a priced round that followed its Series C; the company did not award the round a moniker.</p>
<p>Shippo&#8217;s 2020 Series C, a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/07/shippo-raises-a-30m-series-c-after-posting-rapid-2019-growth/">$30 million transaction</a> that was announced last April, valued the company at around $220 million. D1 Capital led both Shippo&#8217;s Series C and D rounds, implying that it was content to pay around twice as much for the company&#8217;s equity in 2021 than it was in 2020. (Recall that investors doubling-down on previous bets as lead investor in successive rounds is no longer considered to be a negative signal concerning startup quality, but a <em>positive</em> indicator.)</p>
<p>Why raise more money so soon after its last round? According to Shippo CEO and founder <a href="https://twitter.com/LauraBehrensWu">Laura Behrens Wu</a>, her company made material progress on customer acquisition and partnerships last year. That led to a decision around the time of Shippo&#8217;s Q4 board meeting with her investors that it was a good time to put more capital into the company.</p>
<p>In a sense the timing is reasonable. As Shippo scales its customer base, it can negotiate better shipping deals with various providers, which, in turn, help it continue to attract new customers. Behrens Wu noted in an interview with TechCrunch that when her company was helping its early customers ship just a few packages, shipping companies it supports on its platform didn&#8217;t want to meet with the startup. Now armed with more volume, Shippo can recycle customer demand into partner leverage, improving its total customer offering.</p>
<p>Behrens Wu said that Shippo had secured such a partnership with UPS before it raised its new round.</p>
<p>Turning to growth, Shippo doubled its platform spend, or &#8220;GPV&#8221; last year. GPV is the company&#8217;s acronym for <em>gross postage volume</em>. It roughly tracks with revenue, TechCrunch confirmed. So Shippo likely doubled its top-line last year. That&#8217;s good. Shippo wants to do that again this year, Behrens Wu told TechCrunch. The startup will also double its headcount this year, adding around 150 people.</p>
<p>Now flush with more capital, what&#8217;s next for Shippo? Per its CEO, the startup wants to invest more in platforms (where Shippo is baked into a marketplace, for example), international expansion (Shippo only does a &#8220;little bit&#8221; of international shipping, per Behrens Wu), and double-down on what it considers its core customer base.</p>
<p>TechCrunch was curious about how broad Shippo might take its product from its original home in shipping labels. The startup said that there&#8217;s lots of room in the journey of a packaged, from pre-purchase on, where her company might expand into. However, Behrens Wu cautioned that such a broadening of product work is not an immediate focus at her company.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s see how long the current ecommerce boom lasts and how far this new capital can take Shippo. If it doubles in size again this year we&#8217;ll have to start its IPO countdown sometime in mid-2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/shippo-raises-45m-more-at-495m-valuation-as-ecommerce-booms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116243</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wisetack raises $19M as its buy-now-pay-later service for IRL services scales</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/wisetack-raises-19m-as-its-buy-now-pay-later-service-for-irl-services-scales/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/wisetack-raises-19m-as-its-buy-now-pay-later-service-for-irl-services-scales/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 15:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affirm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnpl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greylock]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116172</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning Wisetack, a startup that provides buy-now-pay-later services to in-person business transactions, announced that is has closed a total of $19 million across two rounds, a seed investment and a Series A. Greylock led both rounds, with the seed round clocking in at $4 million and the Series A at $15 million. Bain Capital [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a href="https://www.wisetack.com/">Wisetack</a>, a startup that provides buy-now-pay-later services to in-person business transactions, announced that is has closed a total of $19 million across two rounds, a seed investment and a Series A.</p>
<p><a href="https://greylock.com/">Greylock</a> led both rounds, with the seed round clocking in at $4 million and the Series A at $15 million. <a href="https://www.baincapitalventures.com/">Bain Capital Ventures</a> also took part in the company&#8217;s fundraising.</p>
<p>Notably both rounds were closed in 2019, making these amongst the more aged rounds that we&#8217;ve heard of in recent quarters. However, as much venture reporting was delayed last year due to the pandemic and political unsettlement, I am still willing to cover the occasional antique deal.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Wisetack caught our eye not only due to its fundraising activity, but also thanks the buy-now-pay-later (BNPL) space becoming all the more interesting in the wake of Affirm&#8217;s direct listing. Affirm is perhaps the best-known service of its type, making its liquidity moment &#8212; and post-IPO performance &#8212; impactful for its broader business category.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Z4qDjRXNLo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/wall-street-hugs-affirm-as-it-starts-life-as-a-public-company/">Wall Street hugs Affirm as it starts life as a public company</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Wall Street hugs Affirm as it starts life as a public company&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/wall-street-hugs-affirm-as-it-starts-life-as-a-public-company/embed/#?secret=Z4qDjRXNLo" data-secret="Z4qDjRXNLo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But while Affirm wants to offer point-of-sale BNPL services to online merchants, Wisetack is taking a different approach. It focuses on the in-person business world, helping finance consumer transactions involving things like home improvement and car repair; the sort of big transactions that your average family might not have the cash to cover but also doesn&#8217;t want to put on a credit card.</p>
<p>Wisetack partners with vertical SaaS players in different areas. Say, plumbing. This allows users of those vertical SaaS applications &#8212; the plumbers, sticking to the same example &#8212; to offer Wisetack&#8217;s BNPL service to their customers.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s well known that vertical SaaS has wide application. A <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/23/atlantas-singleops-raises-6m-for-its-outdoor-care-focused-software-business/">favorite recent example is SingleOps</a>, which provides software for the so-called &#8220;green industry,&#8221; the world of lawns and landscaping. There&#8217;s SaaS for all sorts of IRL work, which could mean that Wisetack has a good number of software providers to sell into.</p>
<p>The model appears to be working, at least thus far. Wisetack shared with TechCrunch that its loan volume rose 20x between January of 2020 and January of 2021. As the company generates revenues from merchants (loan processing costs), and consumer interest, it&#8217;s likely that its revenue scales with loan volume. If the relationship is even closer to direct, Wisetack grew quite a lot last year.</p>
<p>The startup also said that the number of businesses using Wisetack grew 25-fold last year to a number in the &#8220;thousands.&#8221;</p>
<p>Wisetack fits neatly into a number of recent trends. The first is its work with vertical SaaS, a notable slice of the software market. The second is that Wisetack is another example of an API-led business, offering its service as a tech-powered add-on to other bits of code. And, third, that Wisetack had the same lead investor twice in sequential rounds. This sort of doubling-down from the venture community has become common in recent quarters as the signaling risk of having the lead twice in a row has been zeroed out by general investor enthusiasm for more equity in what appear to be winning startups.</p>
<p>Finally, the Wisetack round is interesting as it is nearly a sort of vertical BNPL, or at least a vertically focused BNPL. The company was reticent to share notes on how it comes to credit decisions, but we presume that all BNPL players that do focus on a particular niche or segment.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/wisetack-raises-19m-as-its-buy-now-pay-later-service-for-irl-services-scales/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116172</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rode&#8217;s Wireless Go II delivers key upgrades to the best mobile mic for creators</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/rodes-wireless-go-ii-delivers-key-upgrades-to-the-best-mobile-mic-for-creators/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/rodes-wireless-go-ii-delivers-key-upgrades-to-the-best-mobile-mic-for-creators/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 15:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RØDE Microphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telecommunications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transmitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wireless]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116185</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rode Microphones has a new and improved version of its much-loved Go portable mic, the Wireless Go II, which uses the same form factor as the original but adds a list of new and improved features. Most notably, the Go II offers two transmitter packs that can simultaneously talk to a single receiver, letting you [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Rode Microphones has a new and improved version of its much-loved Go portable mic, the Wireless Go II, which uses the same form factor as the original but adds a list of new and improved features. Most notably, the Go II offers two transmitter packs that can simultaneously talk to a single receiver, letting you record two individual speakers to the same camera or connected device.</p>
<h2>Basics</h2>
<p>The <a href="http://www.rode.com/wirelessgoii​">Rode Wireless Go II</a> ($299) ships with everything you need to begin recording high-quality audio to a camera or anything else that can connect to a 3.5mm jack. The transmitter packs – there are two of them in the box – have built-in microphones that offer great sound on their own, or you can use them with any 3.5mm-equipped lavalier mic depending on your needs.</p>
<p>The receiver pack can output to 3.5mm TRS, but it can also transmit using USB Type-C (which is also for charging). This is new for this generation, and Rode also sells USB-C to USB-C and USB-C to Lightning cables so that you can use them with modern Android devices, iPhones, iPads, Macs and PCs.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2116238" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2116238" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2116238" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Rode-Wireless-Go-II-2.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Rode-Wireless-Go-II-2.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Rode-Wireless-Go-II-2.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Rode-Wireless-Go-II-2.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Rode-Wireless-Go-II-2.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Rode-Wireless-Go-II-2.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Rode-Wireless-Go-II-2.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Rode-Wireless-Go-II-2.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2116238" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Rode</p></div></p>
<p>Each of the three packs has a built-in rechargeable battery that can provide up to 7 hours of operating time on a single charge. You can independently adjust the gain on each of the transmitters, and mute each individually or both from the receiver pack. You can also swap between mono recording with each transmitter as a channel, and stereo recording modes.</p>
<p>The transmitters can operate at a range of 200 meters (roughly 650 feet) from the receiver, provided they have line-of-sight, and the receiver has a display to show you input levels, battery status, connectivity and more. The transmitters each have two LEDs that provide visual feedback for connectivity and gain. Each also automatically records locally, with the ability to store more than 24 hours of audio on built-in storage in case of dropouts in connectivity.</p>
<h2>Design and performance</h2>
<p>With this update, it really feels like Rode has thought of everything. You can get started immediately, for one, since the transmitter packs and receiver come pre-paired and assigned to left and right channels by default. They&#8217;re incredibly user-friendly, and while Rode has introduced a new Windows and Mac app for centralized control of them called Rode Central, you don&#8217;t actually need any additional software to get started recording with them.</p>
<p>This updated version also uses a new RF transmission tech that has 128-bit encryption built in, with a much farther line-of-site range for their use. This is designed to make them much more reliable in areas where there&#8217;s a lot of RF traffic happening already – like a busy shopping mall (once COVID times are behind us), conference halls, or other public areas with lots of people and smartphones around.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/990857365%3Fsecret_token%3Ds-7HHfwU3NeR8&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true" width="100%" height="166" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<div style="font-size: 10px; color: #cccccc; line-break: anywhere; word-break: normal; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; text-overflow: ellipsis; font-family: Interstate,Lucida Grande,Lucida Sans Unicode,Lucida Sans,Garuda,Verdana,Tahoma,sans-serif; font-weight: 100;"><a style="color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;" title="Darrell Etherington" href="https://soundcloud.com/darrell-etherington-343558619" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Darrell Etherington</a> · <a style="color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;" title="Rode Wireless Go II Sample" href="https://soundcloud.com/darrell-etherington-343558619/rode-wireless-go-ii-sample/s-7HHfwU3NeR8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rode Wireless Go II Sample</a></div>
<p>The onboard memory is also new, and means you&#8217;ll never have to worry about any potential dropped connections since you&#8217;ll always have a local file to rely on on the transmitter packs themselves. A similar peace-of-mind feature is a safety channel that records a back-up track at -20db, so that if you encounter any overloud sounds that cause peaking in your primary recording, you&#8217;ll have another option. Both of these features have to be turned on proactively in the Rode Central app, which Rode will also use to deliver future firmware updates for the Go II, but they&#8217;re very welcome additions.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2116240" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2116240" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2116240" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Rode-Wireless-Go-II-DSC00089.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Rode-Wireless-Go-II-DSC00089.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Rode-Wireless-Go-II-DSC00089.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Rode-Wireless-Go-II-DSC00089.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Rode-Wireless-Go-II-DSC00089.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Rode-Wireless-Go-II-DSC00089.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Rode-Wireless-Go-II-DSC00089.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Rode-Wireless-Go-II-DSC00089.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2116240" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Darrell Etherington</p></div></p>
<p>Meanwhile, the best new feature might be that you get all these improvements in the same great package. Rode&#8217;s original Go was remarkable in large part because it came in such a small, portable package, with transmitters that featured built-in mics as well as being great body packs. The size here is exactly the same, and these use the same integrated clips that make them compatible with all of Rode&#8217;s existing Go accessories.</p>
<h2>Bottom line</h2>
<p>There&#8217;s a concept of &#8216;lapping&#8217; in racing, where you&#8217;re so far ahead of a competitor that you overtake them again. That&#8217;s basically what Rode has done with the Go II, which pads the lead for the best mobile video/field podcasting mic on the market, with smart features that address the few downsides of the original.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/rodes-wireless-go-ii-delivers-key-upgrades-to-the-best-mobile-mic-for-creators/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116185</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FarmWise plans to add autonomous crop dusting to its suite of robotic services</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/farmwise-plans-to-add-autonomous-crop-dusting-to-its-suite-of-robotic-services/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/farmwise-plans-to-add-autonomous-crop-dusting-to-its-suite-of-robotic-services/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 14:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116504</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The robotics revolution in farming is set to continue as the autonomous crop cultivation company FarmWise looks to add new capabilities to its autonomous farming equipment. The San Francisco-based company is currently testing the application of fungicides and insecticides to row crops as an additional capability for its weed-killing robots, according to company chief executive [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The robotics revolution in farming is set to continue as the autonomous crop cultivation company <a href="https://farmwise.io/">FarmWise</a> looks to add new capabilities to its autonomous farming equipment.</p>
<p>The San Francisco-based company is currently testing the application of fungicides and insecticides to row crops as an additional capability for its weed-killing robots, according to company chief executive Sébastien Boyer.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the latest advancement in robotics for the farm &#8212; a market that&#8217;s becoming increasingly crowded with the launch of new companies like <a href="https://www.futureacres.co/">Future Acres</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/future-acres-launches-with-the-arrival-of-crop-transporting-robot-carry/">which launched its support robot Carry today</a>, and Mineral, the spinout from Alphabet (Google&#8217;s parent company)<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/12/alphabets-latest-moonshot-is-a-field-roving-plant-inspecting-robo-buggy/"> that provides crop analysis</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SaIPRfsA6M"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/12/alphabets-latest-moonshot-is-a-field-roving-plant-inspecting-robo-buggy/">Alphabet&#8217;s latest moonshot is a field-roving, plant-inspecting robo-buggy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Alphabet&#8217;s latest moonshot is a field-roving, plant-inspecting robo-buggy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/12/alphabets-latest-moonshot-is-a-field-roving-plant-inspecting-robo-buggy/embed/#?secret=SaIPRfsA6M" data-secret="SaIPRfsA6M" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Rather than sell robots directly to farmers, FarmWise sells its robotics services to farms, and charges farms roughly $200 per acre inspected and weeded. &#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">We show up on farmers’ fields with our own operators and our own equipment,&#8221; Boyer said.</span></p>
<p>It&#8217;s a business model that has attracted <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/17/farmwise-and-its-weed-pulling-agribot-harvest-14-5m-in-funding/">$24 million in outside funding</a> from firm&#8217;s including <a href="https://playground.global/portfolio">Playground Global</a> and the company is likely going to raise another round, targeted at $20 million, later this year, according to Boyer.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0D9HKeVEw0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/17/farmwise-and-its-weed-pulling-agribot-harvest-14-5m-in-funding/">FarmWise and its weed-pulling agribot harvest $14.5M in funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;FarmWise and its weed-pulling agribot harvest $14.5M in funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/17/farmwise-and-its-weed-pulling-agribot-harvest-14-5m-in-funding/embed/#?secret=0D9HKeVEw0" data-secret="0D9HKeVEw0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Boyer says the company already counts half of the largest growers in Salinas, Calif. among the company&#8217;s customers. These are farms for big consumer vegetable companies like Dole.</p>
<p>What FarmWise hopes to do is fill gaps of missing labor, according to Boyer. Along with co-founder Thomas Palomares, Boyer said he identified a need for farms to keep up with their output while dealing with a shrinking workforce. &#8220;It&#8217;s about helping farmers keep up with work while the pool of people willing to do these jobs is shrinking,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Using the robots isn&#8217;t just good for farms&#8217; bottom lines, Boyer said. It also helps reduce the amount of fertilizer and chemicals used on the farm, which is good for the environment and creates a more sustainable food chain, he said.</p>
<p>&#8220;I was attracted by working on a large-scale sustainability problem,&#8221; Boyer said.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/farmwise-plans-to-add-autonomous-crop-dusting-to-its-suite-of-robotic-services/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116504</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ChargeLab raises seed capital to be the software provider powering EV charging infrastructure</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/chargelab-raises-seed-capital-to-be-the-software-provider-powering-ev-charging-infrastructure/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/chargelab-raises-seed-capital-to-be-the-software-provider-powering-ev-charging-infrastructure/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 14:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ABB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ChargeLab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ChargePoint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charging stations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Construct Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayna grayson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electrical engineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Electrify America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inductive charging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[notation capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rachel Holt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reef]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Root Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siemens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116486</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As money floods into the electric vehicle market a number of small companies are trying to stake their claim as the go-to provider of charging infrastructure. These companies are developing proprietary ecosystems that work for their own equipment but don&#8217;t interoperate. ChargeLab, which has raised $4.3 million in seed financing led by Construct Capital and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As money floods into the electric vehicle market a number of small companies are trying to stake their claim as the go-to provider of charging infrastructure. These companies are developing proprietary ecosystems that work for their own equipment but don&#8217;t interoperate.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.chargelab.co/">ChargeLab</a>, which has raised $4.3 million in seed financing led by Construct Capital and Root Ventures, is looking to be the software provider providing the chargers built by everyone else.</p>
<p>&#8220;You&#8217;ll find everyone in every niche and corner,&#8221; says ChargeLab chief executive Zachary Lefevre. Lefevre likens Tesla to Apple with its closed ecosystem and compares Chargepoint and Blink, two other electric vehicle charging companies to Blackberry &#8212; the once dominant smartphone maker. &#8220;What we&#8217;re trying to do is be android,&#8221; Lefevre said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That means being the software provider for manufacturers like ABB, Schneider Electric and Siemens. &#8220;These guys are hardware makers up and down the value stack,&#8221; Lefevre said.</p>
<p>ChargeLab already has an agreement with ABB to be their default software provider as they go to market. The big industrial manufacturer is getting ready to launch their next charging product in North America.</p>
<p>As companies like REEF and Metropolis revamp garages and parking lots to service the next generation of vehicles, ChargeLab&#8217;s chief executive thinks that his software can power their EV charging services as they begin to roll that functionality out across the lots they own.</p>
<p>Lefevre got to know the electric vehicle charging market first as a reseller of everyone else&#8217;s equipment, he said. The company had raised a pre-seed round of $1.1 million from investors including Urban.us and Notation Capital and has now added to that bank account with another capital infusion from Construct Capital, the new fund led by Dayna Grayson and Rachel Holt, and Root Ventures, Lefevre said.</p>
<p>Eventually the company wants to integrate with the back end of companies like Chargepoint and Electrify America to make the charging process as efficient for everyone, according to ChargeLab&#8217;s chief executive.</p>
<p>As more service providers get into the market, Lefevre sees the opportunity set for his business expanding exponentially. &#8220;Super open platforms are not going to be building an EV charging system any more than they would be building their own hardware,&#8221; he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/chargelab-raises-seed-capital-to-be-the-software-provider-powering-ev-charging-infrastructure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116486</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>3D model provider CGTrader raises $9.5M Series B led by Evli Growth Partners</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/3d-model-provider-cgtrader-raises-9-5m-series-b-led-by-evli-growth-partners/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/3d-model-provider-cgtrader-raises-9-5m-series-b-led-by-evli-growth-partners/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 14:29:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3d]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3D modeling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arsenal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cgtrader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer graphics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crate & barrel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[designer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graphics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[image-processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Karma Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Made.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Practica Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rovio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shutterstock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[staples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visual effects]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[3D model provider CGTrader, has raised $9.5M in a Series B funding led by Finnish VC fund Evli Growth Partners, alongside previous investors Karma Ventures and LVV Group. Ex-Rovio CEO Mikael Hed also invested and joins as Board Chairman. We first covered the Vilnius-based company when it raised 200,000 euro from Practica Capital. Founded in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">3D model provider <a href="https://www.cgtrader.com/">CGTrader</a>, has raised $9.5M in a Series B funding led by Finnish VC fund Evli Growth Partners, alongside previous investors Karma Ventures and LVV Group. Ex-Rovio CEO Mikael Hed also invested and joins as Board Chairman. We first covered the Vilnius-based company when it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/02/21/cgtrader-an-online-marketplace-for-3d-models-raises-185k-euro-from-practica/">raised</a> 200,000 euro from Practica Capital.</p>
<p>Founded in 2011 by 3D designer Marius Kalytis (now COO), CGTrader has become a signifiant 3D content provider &#8211; it even claims to be the world’s largest. In its marketplace are 1.1M 3D models and 3.5M 3D designers, service 370,000 businesses including Nike, Microsoft, Made.com, Crate &amp; Barrel, and Staples.</p>
<p>Unlike photos, 3D models can also be used to create both static images as well as AR experiences, so that users can see how a product might fit in their home. The company is also looking to invest in automating 3D modeling, QA, and asset management processes with AI. </p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Dalia Lasaite, CEO and co-founder of CGTrader said in a statement: “3D models are not only widely used in professional 3D industries, but have become a more convenient and cost-effective way of generating amazing product visuals for e-commerce as well. With our ARsenal enterprise platform, it is up to ten times cheaper to produce photorealistic 3D visuals that are indistinguishable from photographs.”</p>
<p>CGTrader now plans to consolidate its position and further develop its platform.</p>
<p>The company competes with TurboSquid (which was recently <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90597548/shutterstock-makes-a-75-million-bet-that-the-future-of-photography-doesnt-involve-cameras">acquired</a> for $75 million by Shutterstock) and Threekit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/3d-model-provider-cgtrader-raises-9-5m-series-b-led-by-evli-growth-partners/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116495</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Electric raises $40M Series C to put small-business IT in the cloud</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/electric-raises-40m-series-c-to-put-small-business-it-in-the-cloud/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/electric-raises-40m-series-c-to-put-small-business-it-in-the-cloud/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 14:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric.ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ryan denehy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116453</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It would be an understatement to say that enterprise-focused startups have fared well during the pandemic. As organizations look to go remote, and the way we work has been flipped on its head, quickly-growing tech companies that simplify this transition are in high demand. One such startup has, in fact, raised $61.5 million in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It would be an understatement to say that enterprise-focused startups have fared well during the pandemic. As organizations look to go remote, and the way we work has been flipped on its head, quickly-growing tech companies that simplify this transition are in high demand.</p>
<p>One such startup has, in fact, raised $61.5 million in the last 12 months alone. <a href="https://www.electric.ai/">Electric</a>, a company looking to put IT departments in the cloud, just announced the close of a $40 million Series C round. This comes after an extension of its Series B in March of 2020, when it raised $14.5 million, and then an additional $7 million from 01 Advisors in May of 2020.</p>
<p>This Series C round was led by Greenspring Associates, with participation from existing investors Bessemer Venture Partners, GGV Capital, 01 Advisors, Primary Venture Partners as well as new investors including Atreides Management and Vintage Investment Partners.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xHmgY2QfL8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/18/electric-gets-another-7-million-in-funding-from-01-advisors-and-the-slack-fund/">Electric gets another $7 million in funding from 01 Advisors and the Slack Fund</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Electric gets another $7 million in funding from 01 Advisors and the Slack Fund&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/18/electric-gets-another-7-million-in-funding-from-01-advisors-and-the-slack-fund/embed/#?secret=xHmgY2QfL8" data-secret="xHmgY2QfL8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Electric launched in 2016 with a mission to make IT much simpler for small and medium-sized businesses. Rather than bringing on a dedicated IT department, or contracting out high-priced local service providers, Electric&#8217;s software allows one admin to manage devices, software subscriptions, permissions and more.</p>
<p>According to founder Ryan Denehy, the vast majority of IT&#8217;s work is administration, distribution, and maintenance of the broad variety of software programs at any given company. Electric does most of that job on behalf of IT, meaning that a smaller business only needs to worry about desk-side troubleshooting when it comes up, rather than the whole kit and caboodle.</p>
<p>Electric charges a flat price per seat per month, and Denehy says the company more than doubled its customer base in the last year. It now supports around 25,000 users across more than 400 individual customer organizations, which puts Electric just shy of $20 million ARR.</p>
<p>This is the first time Denehy has come anywhere close to sharing revenue numbers publicly, but it&#8217;s a good time to flex. The company has recently introduced a new lighter-weight offering that includes all of the same functionality as its more expensive product, but without access to chat functionality.</p>
<p>&#8220;The name of the game is just simplicity, simplicity, simplicity,&#8221; said Denehy. &#8220;Part of this is in response to the fact that people are realizing the permanence of hybrid work. During the pandemic, people stopped paying their landlords but they didn&#8217;t stop paying us. So in the summer, we started to focus on how we can create more offerings that we can get in the hands of more businesses and let them start their journey with us.&#8221;</p>
<p>Denehy says that a little less than half of Electric&#8217;s client base are tech startups, which makes sense considering the company launched in New York in a tech and media-centric ecosystem. As a way to expand into other verticals, Electric acquired Sinu, an IT service provider who happened to have an impressive roster of clients outside of Electric&#8217;s comfort zone, such as legal, accounting and non-profit.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s what Denehy said at the time:</p>
<blockquote><p>Organic market entry, even in adjacent markets can be extremely time consuming and expensive. Sinu&#8217;s team has done an excellent job winning and pleasing customers in a lot of industries where we currently don&#8217;t play but probably should. The combination of our two companies is a massive shot in the arm to our national expansion strategy.</p></blockquote>
<p>Alongside growth, both of the Electric team and its customer base, the company is also investing in expanding its diversity programs and philanthropic efforts.</p>
<p>The Electric team is currently made up of just under 250 full-time employees, with 32.5 percent women and around 30 percent of employees being non-white. Specifically, nearly 12 percent of employees are Black and 10 percent are Latinx.</p>
<p>Denehy explained that he thinks of the company&#8217;s payroll, which is in the tens of millions of dollars, as one of the biggest ways he can make a change in the world.</p>
<p>&#8220;We will wait longer to fill a role to make sure that we have the most diverse pipeline of candidates possible,&#8221; said Denehy. &#8220;A lot of founders will say that nobody applied. Well, the reality is you didn&#8217;t look hard enough. We&#8217;ve just accepted that like it may take us longer to fill certain roles.&#8221;</p>
<p>This latest round brings Electric&#8217;s total funding to more than $100 million.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/electric-raises-40m-series-c-to-put-small-business-it-in-the-cloud/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116453</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ag monitoring startup Flurostat merges with soil carbon expert Dagan to form Regrow</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/ag-monitoring-startup-flurostat-merges-with-soil-carbon-expert-dagan-to-form-regrow/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/ag-monitoring-startup-flurostat-merges-with-soil-carbon-expert-dagan-to-form-regrow/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 14:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon sequestration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116475</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Flurostat and Dagan, two startups that both are tackling the monitoring and management of agricultural inputs and outputs for a better understanding of the role sustainable agriculture can play in reducing greenhouse gas emissions, have merged and are launching a package of services under a new brand, Regrow. The merge, announced yesterday, will create a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Flurostat and Dagan, two startups that both are tackling the monitoring and management of agricultural inputs and outputs for a better understanding of the role sustainable agriculture can play in reducing greenhouse gas emissions, have merged and are launching a package of services under a new brand,<a href="https://www.regrow.ag/"> Regrow</a>.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The merge, announced yesterday, will create a company that combines Flurostat&#8217;s data driven agriculture management services with Dagan&#8217;s soil biogeochemical modeling technology, the companies said in a joint statement. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The combined companies will have the ability to provide satellite collected data to optimize crop management and adoption of conservation practices along with site-specific analysis and custom interventions for different crops, fields, farms, and regions. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dagan co-founder Dr. William Salas said that the combined companies will be able to have a better handle on the market for carbon emissions &#8212; thanks in no small part to Dagan&#8217;s work on soil carbon. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Soil carbon sequestration is finally emerging as a globally relevant strategy for drawing down excess </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">atmospheric carbon dioxide. Shortcuts, misconceptions and over-hyping have the potential to stunt the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">tremendous potential of soil carbon,” Salas said in a statement. “But the merger of FluroSat and Dagan will give the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">industry the confidence and integrity it needs with best-in-class soil health data that can prescribe site-</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">specific strategies and provide accuracy and transparency that will help companies succeed in carbon markets.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Terms of the merger were not disclosed, but FluroSat had previously raised roughly $8.6 million in equity and grant funding led by Microsoft&#8217;s M12 venture fund, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/flurosat/company_financials">according to data from Crunchbase</a>.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Over the next decade, we need to grow and produce enough food to nourish 10 billion people around </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">the world in a way that protects our land and stems climate change,” says Ranveer Chandra, Chief </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Scientist, Azure Global at Microsoft. “Regrow’s computational agriculture, using machine learning and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">scientific modeling, will help improve the accuracy of accounting for soil carbon, and bring farmers </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">closer to benefitting from carbon markets.”</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/ag-monitoring-startup-flurostat-merges-with-soil-carbon-expert-dagan-to-form-regrow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116475</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Midwest Fund launches, brings The Fund&#8217;s innovative investment strategy to a fifth market</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/the-midwest-fund-launches-brings-the-funds-innovative-investment-strategy-to-a-fifth-market/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/the-midwest-fund-launches-brings-the-funds-innovative-investment-strategy-to-a-fifth-market/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 14:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cincinnati]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[detroit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Midwest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pittsburgh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Fund]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116458</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new investment fund is coming to Midwest cities, and it&#8217;s lead by names familiar to the local scenes. The aptly-named Midwest Fund targets early-stage startups from Pittsburgh to Chicago, from Detroit to Cincinnati, and everywhere in between. Unlike traditional venture capital funds, this one gets its funding from successful entrepreneurs looking for ways to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A new investment fund is coming to Midwest cities, and it&#8217;s lead by names familiar to the local scenes. The aptly-named Midwest Fund targets early-stage startups from Pittsburgh to Chicago, from Detroit to Cincinnati, and everywhere in between. Unlike traditional venture capital funds, this one gets its funding from successful entrepreneurs looking for ways to reinvest in their regions.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.thefund.vc/community/midwest/">The Midwest Fund</a> was born from <a href="https://www.thefund.vc">The Fund</a>, an NYC-based venture capital group. Founded in 2018 by an all-star cast of Jenny Fielding, Scott Hartley, Katie Hunt, Adam Carver, and Matthew Brimer, The Fund has since expanded with micro-funds in Los Angeles, London, and the Boulder/Denver region. And with each expansion, local founders and investors are tapped to lead each region.</p>
<p>The Midwest Fund&#8217;s founding general partners are familiar names to the Midwest. This includes Ted Serbinski and Tops Kataria of Detroit, Chris Bergman of Cincinnati, Lynsie Campbell of Pittsburgh, Jennifer Fried of Chicago. With this diverse team, The Midwest Fund follows the example set-out by The Fund of having equal gender representation on investment committees.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;The Fund has always set out to have equal gender representation on the investment committee,&#8221; said Ted Serbinski, a GP at The Midwest Fund, &#8220;and believed that this composition, not an explicit mandate, would lead to more balanced investing. Three years in and across the other geographies, The Fund has invested in over 40 percent female founders. We think the same will be true in The Midwest, and we&#8217;re excited to advance this mission.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Midwest area has long been a foundry of notable industries and startups, with more popping up every day. Nearly eight years ago, Ted Serbinki, then a partner at Detroit Venture Partners, mapped this area, calling it a diamond with key cities at each point. Now with The Midwest Fund, he&#8217;s part of a team ready to write seed-stage checks to young companies.</p>
<p>Serbinski tells TechCrunch this fund is unique to this area because of its speed. He explains the fund intends to invest in two Midwest companies a month for two years, which he believes would make it the most active in the region.</p>
<p>The Midwest Fund&#8217;s limited partners come from the local areas in which the fund operates including Chicago&#8217;s Amanda Lannert, CEO of Jellyvision, Pittsburgh&#8217;s Patrick Colletti, founder of Newthealth, and Cincinnati&#8217;s Charlie Key, founder of Losant. Across all six funds ran by The Fund, notable LPs come from Zillow, ClassPass, Soundcloud, Casper, Quartz, and InVision.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/the-midwest-fund-launches-brings-the-funds-innovative-investment-strategy-to-a-fifth-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116458</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Maple launches with $3.5 million in funding to become the SaaS backoffice for the family</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/maple-launches-with-3-5-million-in-funding-to-become-the-saas-backoffice-for-the-family/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/maple-launches-with-3-5-million-in-funding-to-become-the-saas-backoffice-for-the-family/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 14:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evelyn Rusli]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspired Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Publishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yumi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116443</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Much of our daily lives have been transformed in one way or another by technology – and often through intentional efforts to innovate thanks to the advent of new technology. Now more than ever, we rely on shared collaboration platforms and digital workspaces in our professional lives, and yet most of the changes wrought by [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Much of our daily lives have been transformed in one way or another by technology – and often through intentional efforts to innovate thanks to the advent of new technology. Now more than ever, we rely on shared collaboration platforms and digital workspaces in our professional lives, and yet most of the changes wrought by tech on our home and family lives seem like the accidental effects of broader trends, rather than intentional shifts. <a href="https://www.growmaple.com">Maple</a>, a new startup launching today, aims to change that.</p>
<p>Founded by former Shopify product director and Kit (which was acquired by Shopify in 2016) co-founder Michael Perry, Maple is billed as &#8220;the family tech platform,&#8221; and hopes to ease the burden of parenting, freeing up parents, aunts, uncles, grandparents and kids to spend more quality time together. The startup, which is launching its app on iPhone and Android for all and onboarding new users from its waitlist over the next few weeks, has raised $3.5 million in seed funding – an impressive round for a company just about seven months into its existence. The round was led by Inspired Capital, and includes participation by Box Group, but is also supported by a number of angels who were Perry&#8217;s former colleagues at Shopify, including Shopify President Harley Finkelstein.</p>
<p>Perry and his co-founder Mike Taylor, who also co-founded Kit, decided to leave Shopify in order to pursue Perry&#8217;s vision of a platform that can help parents better manage their family lives – a platform made up of a social layer, a task-focused list of shared responsibilities, and a bourgeoning service marketplace that looks and feels a lot like the ecosystem Shopify has built for empowering e-commerce entrepreneurs. That&#8217;s by design, Perry says.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;I think you&#8217;re gonna see a lot of Shopify inspiration in this product – we think we&#8217;re the back office of every family,&#8221; Perry told me in an interview. &#8220;And we think we&#8217;re building the app ecosystem of apps, services, all kinds of things that are going to live on this platform that&#8217;s going to revolutionize parenting.&#8221;</p>
<p>In its current early incarnation, Maple&#8217;s primary interface for parents is a list of various tasks they need to take care of during the day. During onboarding, Maple asks parents what they&#8217;re typically responsible for in the household, and then uses some basic machine learning behind the scenes to build a customized schedule for getting those things done. Maple has signed on three initial partners to assist with accomplishing some of these tasks, including Evelyn Rusli&#8217;s Yumi food and nutrition brand for infants; Lalo, a DTC baby and toddler furniture and gear brand; and Haus, which will be providing date night packages for parents to enjoy for some getaway time.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2116461" style="width: 520px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2116461" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2116461" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Michael_headshot.jpg?w=510" alt="" width="510" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Michael_headshot.jpg 3024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Michael_headshot.jpg?resize=113,150 113w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Michael_headshot.jpg?resize=225,300 225w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Michael_headshot.jpg?resize=768,1024 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Michael_headshot.jpg?resize=510,680 510w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Michael_headshot.jpg?resize=1152,1536 1152w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Michael_headshot.jpg?resize=1536,2048 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Michael_headshot.jpg?resize=38,50 38w" sizes="(max-width: 510px) 100vw, 510px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2116461" class="wp-caption-text">Maple co-founder Micheal Perry with his son.</p></div></p>
<p>The platform will offer users the ability to tap others for help with tasks – these could be other family members added to the household, or the partners mentioned above (the plan is to bring on more, but to gate admittance initially while developing API endpoints that any company can potentially tap into). When interacting with family members, Maple also encourages smalls social interactions, like thanking someone for their help on a particular task or just showing general appreciation. Perry says this is a key ingredient he prioritized in product design.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have this cool thing that every day at eight o&#8217;clock, we give you an end of the day recap with your family,&#8221; Perry said. &#8220;So you click on it, and it will show me that, for example, Alex [Perry&#8217;s wife] completed three responsibilities for our family today, and how many I did for my family today, and how much help I received from other people today. And directly in app, you can send these cool little &#8216;Thank you &#8216;messages and say, you know, I love you, I appreciate you – we&#8217;re a great team. And Alex will get those messages. We believe in a world where this can be incredibly dynamic, in many different ways kto kind of bring some love and appreciation and make parenting feel more rewarding and easier.&#8221;</p>
<p>Perry is quick to note that what Maple offers today is only the beginning, and it&#8217;s clear he has bold ambitions for the platform. He talked about building &#8220;the family graph,&#8221; or a trove of data that can be used to not only build intelligent recommendations and develop ever more advanced machine learning to optimize family management, but also to provide partners with the tools they need to build products to best serve families. I asked Perry what that means for privacy, given that people are likely to be far more reluctant to share info around their families than they are about their work lives. He said the they team plans to go slow in terms of what it exposes to partners, when, and how, and that they&#8217;ll have user privacy in mind at each step – since, after all, Perry himself is a father and a husband and is wary of any incursions on his own private life.</p>
<p>For now, partners like Yumi only receive what users share with them through their own account creation and login mechanism, and they only pass back a basic attribution token – essentially letting Maple know the task was completed so it can mark it off in a user&#8217;s list.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2116460" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2116460" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2116460" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Help-What-To-Cook.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="786" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Help-What-To-Cook.jpg 3650w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Help-What-To-Cook.jpg?resize=150,115 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Help-What-To-Cook.jpg?resize=300,230 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Help-What-To-Cook.jpg?resize=768,589 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Help-What-To-Cook.jpg?resize=680,522 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Help-What-To-Cook.jpg?resize=1536,1178 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Help-What-To-Cook.jpg?resize=2048,1571 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Help-What-To-Cook.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2116460" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Maple</p></div></p>
<p>Maple&#8217;s partners today are representative of the kind of businesses that might make use of the platform in future, but Perry has a much broader vision. He hopes that Maple can ultimately help parents handle their responsibilities across a wide range of needs and income levels. Right now, Perry points out, a lot of what&#8217;s available to parents in terms of support is only available to higher income brackets – ie., nannies and dedicated caregivers. Perry says that his experience growing up relatively poor with a young mother supporting the family while his father worked long hours led him to want to provide something better.</p>
<p>&#8220;You have 125 million households in America, you have 3 million children being born every year, you have 30% of the households in America being single parent-run households,&#8221; Perry said. &#8220;It&#8217;s hard. Some people are working one two jobs, most couples are working couples. Every industry that&#8217;s changed has been about making things more accessible. In the case of Shopify, at one point building, an online store required hundreds of thousands of dollars and a bunch of skilled people. Now you can start a store for $20 in five minutes – 20 years ago, that was unfathomable.&#8221;</p>
<p>For Perry, Maple represents a path to that kind of shift in the economics of parenting and a network of family services, including goods, care, leisure and more. The startup has plans to eventually enlist other parents to provide services, which Perry says will unlock part-time income generation for full-time parents, allowing parents to help each other at the same time.</p>
<p>I asked him if he thought people would be reluctant to treat their family lives with the same kind of optimization approach favored by enterprise and commercial platform tools, but he suggested that in fact, not taking advantage of those same technologies in our personal lives is a missed opportunity.</p>
<p>&#8220;We believe that, uniquely, we&#8217;re living through a generation where we can start creating more time for people,&#8221; Perry said. &#8220;I think what makes Maple so unique is that no company has approached this by asking &#8216;How do we create more time for you so that you can spend more time with your kids?&#8217; in the consolidated way that we have.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>Disclosure: I worked at Shopify from 2018 to 2019 while Perry was employed there, but we did not work together directly.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/maple-launches-with-3-5-million-in-funding-to-become-the-saas-backoffice-for-the-family/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116443</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Furniture startup Burrow raises $25M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/furniture-startup-burrow-raises-25m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/furniture-startup-burrow-raises-25m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 14:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Burrow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[furniture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parkway Venture Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Burrow, a startup that first launched with a modular sofa, eventually aims to sell you furniture for every room in your home. Today, it&#8217;s announcing that it&#8217;s raised $25 million in Series C funding. Burrow participated in the Y Combinator accelerator in 2016 with an initial aim of building sofas that, by virtue of being [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://burrow.com">Burrow</a>, a startup that first launched with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/04/burrow-wants-to-bring-caspers-mattress-concept-to-couches/">a modular sofa</a>, eventually aims to sell you furniture for every room in your home. Today, it&#8217;s announcing that it&#8217;s raised $25 million in Series C funding.</p>
<p>Burrow participated in the Y Combinator accelerator in 2016 with an initial aim of building sofas that, by virtue of being modular, were easier to move and adapt to a variety of living spaces. Now its product lineup also includes armchairs, ottomans, tables, rugs, lights and other accessories. In fact, the company says it launched 19 new products last year, including a modular shelving system.</p>
<p>When I asked via email about this expansion, co-founder and CEO Stephen Kuhl told me that the company follows &#8220;a very rigorous research process&#8221; involving customer surveys, focus groups, online search data and more.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;The goal is to match the largest customer needs with the biggest market opportunities,&#8221; Kuhl said. &#8220;Once it’s clear what category to enter, we use our research to define how we’re going to develop the best version(s) of each product for our customer base, and how we’re going to build the best end-to-end customer experience around that product. I’m probably going to jinx it, but every single product we’ve ever launched has exceeded projections, a testament to our customer-centric, research-driven design process.&#8221;</p>
<p>Burrow says it saw triple-digit revenue growth last year, a trend it anticipates continuing in 2021. Kuhl suggested that the startup is also benefitting from broader trends accelerated during the pandemic, including the shift to e-commerce, an increased focus on the home and people moving to the suburbs (and buying more furniture in the process).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NIatQsV7wD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/21/burrow-series-a/">Modular sofa startup Burrow raises $14M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Modular sofa startup Burrow raises $14M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/21/burrow-series-a/embed/#?secret=NIatQsV7wD" data-secret="NIatQsV7wD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;Over the last 18 months, we launched innovative new products in every category of living room furniture,&#8221; he said. &#8220;In 2021, we’ll continue that expansion into every room of the home.&#8221;</p>
<p>The startup has now raised a total fo $55 million. Its Series C was led by Parkway Venture Capital, with Managing Partner Gregg Hill joining Burrow&#8217;s board of directors. NEA, Red &amp; Blue Ventures, Winklevoss Capital and Michael Seibel also participated in the new round.</p>
<p>Burrow says it will use the new funding to launch new products while also investing in operations and building out its international supply chain.</p>
<p>&#8220;Parkway looks for brands that are changing how we live today as well as innovating to stay ahead,&#8221; Hill said in a statement. &#8220;We believed in Burrow’s business model from the beginning, having invested in their Series B round, and recognize all their future potential.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gDuJRE7n3L"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/olive-launch/">Jet co-founder Nate Faust is building a more sustainable e-commerce experience with Olive</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Jet co-founder Nate Faust is building a more sustainable e-commerce experience with Olive&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/olive-launch/embed/#?secret=gDuJRE7n3L" data-secret="gDuJRE7n3L" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/furniture-startup-burrow-raises-25m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116456</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rokk3r acquires AdMobilize and Matrix Labs for $19.5M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/rokk3r-acquires-admobilize-and-matrix-labs-for-19-5m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/rokk3r-acquires-admobilize-and-matrix-labs-for-19-5m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Riggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 14:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AdMobilize]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rokk3r]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116288</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Miami-based AdMobilize and its spin-off, Matrix Labs, announced this morning that they are being acquired for $19.5 million. The buyer is Rokk3r, a Miami-based holding company that invests in creating, acquiring and integrating companies. AdMobilize quantifies digital advertising in the physical world, so marketers can better reach their target audiences. “If you’re walking on 5th [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Miami-based </span><a href="https://www.admobilize.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">AdMobilize</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and its spin-off, </span><a href="https://www.matrix.one/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Matrix Labs</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, announced this morning that they are being acquired for $19.5 million. The buyer is <a href="https://www.rokk3r.com/">Rokk3r</a>, a Miami-based </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">holding company that invests in creating, acquiring and integrating companies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">AdMobilize quantifies digital advertising in the physical world, so marketers can better reach their target audiences.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“If you’re walking on 5th Avenue and you pass by a bus shelter that has a digital screen, AdMobilize analyzes [peoples’] age, gender, emotion and even how long the person was looking at the ad. We created a platform that mimics the click-through rate. So we kind of created Google Analytics for the outside world,” said Rodolfo Saccoman, CEO and founder of AdMobilize.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company, which has raised $13 million since its launch in 2012, also has offices in Saccoman’s native Brazil, as well as Colombia and London. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">AdMobilize operates as a SaaS with an average monthly subscription fee of $50 per screen or billboard. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VrCeef3F8c"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/subscription-based-pricing-is-dead-smart-saas-companies-are-shifting-to-usage-based-models/">Subscription-based pricing is dead: Smart SaaS companies are shifting to usage-based models</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Subscription-based pricing is dead: Smart SaaS companies are shifting to usage-based models&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/subscription-based-pricing-is-dead-smart-saas-companies-are-shifting-to-usage-based-models/embed/#?secret=VrCeef3F8c" data-secret="VrCeef3F8c" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our tech is 95% accurate, and it’s based on undeniable computer vision data,” Saccoman said. If a digital ad screen doesn’t have a camera built-in, AdMobilize can provide one. But Saccoman made it very clear that the company doesn’t do any facial recognition and really is only interested in the data in a broader sense.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Matrix Labs, on the other hand, is a hardware company with products that look similar to Raspberry Pi, but with a lot more oomph.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our Matrix Labs development boards give the Raspberry Pi superpowers. It transforms the Pi to be AI-ready for computer vision, sensor fusion, voice recognition and more. It democratizes AI at the edge by removing barriers to entry, shortening the learning curve, and increases adaptability,” Saccoman said.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2116294" style="width: 435px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2116294" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2116294" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image0-1.jpeg?w=300" alt="" width="425" height="422" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image0-1.jpeg 3201w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image0-1.jpeg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image0-1.jpeg?resize=300,297 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image0-1.jpeg?resize=768,761 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image0-1.jpeg?resize=680,674 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image0-1.jpeg?resize=1536,1523 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image0-1.jpeg?resize=2048,2030 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image0-1.jpeg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image0-1.jpeg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image0-1.jpeg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image0-1.jpeg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image0-1.jpeg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 425px) 100vw, 425px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2116294" class="wp-caption-text">Rodolfo Saccoman <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Saccoman</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company offers two boards. One is called the Matrix Creator and sells for $99, while the other is the Matrix Voice which goes for $75.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It [Matrix boards] enables people to not spend millions of dollars making a piece of hardware,” Saccoman said. In fact, it levels the playing field for developers, he added. “It allows them to create solutions in the physical world with inexpensive edge AI hardware.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rokk3r was an early investor in AdMobilize, along with Azoic Ventures, Fuel Venture Capital, VAS Ventures and Axel Springer.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Rokk3r has always believed in the potential of artificial intelligence, Internet of Things, and computer vision, hence it seeded and helped build AdMobilize. Where we stand today with what AdMobilize/Matrix Labs has achieved, it is clear that the technology created is critical to the future of AI/IOT/CV, and with Rokk3r’s focus on AI/IOT and IP creation, the fit was clear,” said Nabyl Charania, chairman and CEO of Rokk3r.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Saccoman is a Brazilian-born serial entrepreneur who moved to the U.S. to attend college at Cornell in 1995 and never left. He made his way down to South Florida with his first job out of college, where he was head of Digital Innovation at the ultra-lux Breakers Hotel in Palm Beach. While the AdMobilize/Matrix Labs deal is his first exit, his first “venture” was when he was just 13 years old. It was called the PiPi bag. São Paulo, the financial capital of Brazil, is notorious for awful traffic. It can often take people three hours to get to the airport, and when you’re trying to catch a flight, stopping to use the restroom isn’t usually an option. As the name suggests, the Pipi bag was a handheld portable toilet of sorts for those moments when nature calls.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8C7r9IoS4P"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/29/the-martix-voice-is-an-alexa-for-your-raspberry-pi/">The Matrix Voice is an Alexa for your Raspberry Pi</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Matrix Voice is an Alexa for your Raspberry Pi&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/29/the-martix-voice-is-an-alexa-for-your-raspberry-pi/embed/#?secret=8C7r9IoS4P" data-secret="8C7r9IoS4P" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Years later, in 2007, Saccoman also founded a company with his brother who has a PhD in psychology. It was called MyTherapyJournal.com and was the first online journaling platform with cognitive behavior therapy. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It would measure your varying emotions when you answered key questions. For example, people could start to understand what would trigger their anxiety. It had early traces of AI,” Saccoman said. MyTherapyJournal closed in 2012.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of his various ventures, he said, “My mind was always running to find problems.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Saccoman will stay on board and lead Rokk3r’s AI and IoT division.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/rokk3r-acquires-admobilize-and-matrix-labs-for-19-5m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116288</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Codecademy eyes the enterprise with $40 million in new capital</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/codecademy-series-d/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/codecademy-series-d/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 14:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[codecademy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Owl Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zach sims]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116154</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After going over four years without raising any capital, coding class platform Codecademy has raised a new tranche of money: a $40 million Series D round led by Owl Ventures, with participation from Prosus and Union Square Ventures. The startup is the latest edtech business to bring on capital after years without it, a list [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After going over four years without raising any capital, coding class platform<a href="https://www.codecademy.com/"> Codecademy</a> has raised a new tranche of money: a $40 million Series D round led by Owl Ventures, with participation from Prosus and Union Square Ventures.</p>
<p>The startup is the latest edtech business to bring on capital after years without it, a list that includes <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/classdojos-second-act-comes-with-first-profits/">ClassDojo</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/26/course-hero-a-profitable-edtech-unicorn-raises-rare-cash/">CourseHero</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/13/quizlet-valued-at-1-billion-as-it-raises-millions-during-a-global-pandemic/">Quizlet</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/03/udacity-raises-75m-in-debt-says-its-tech-education-business-is-profitable-after-enterprise-pivot/">Udacity</a>. But founder <a href="https://twitter.com/zsims?lang=en">Zach Sims</a>, who began the company in 2011 as a Columbia student, says that Codecademy’s growth, and hunger for new capital, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/12-investors-say-lifelong-learning-is-taking-edtech-mainstream/">isn’t due to a pandemic bump.</a></p>
<p>“A lot of that edtech bump came in K-12 and college solutions, or in leisure educational things like MasterClass,” Sims said. “Ours was less pandemic-induced.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The business, which helps students and employees learn how to code in an interactive environment, is currently bringing in $50 million in annual recurring revenue. That figure is on track with Codecademy’s normal growth trajectory, which has been doubling since 2018. The startup has still seen some areas of growth. It took Codecademy four years to reach their first 100,000 users; however, they added 50,000 more paying users in their fifth year alone.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YBUUxYrDxf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/03/udacity-raises-75m-in-debt-says-its-tech-education-business-is-profitable-after-enterprise-pivot/">Udacity raises $75M in debt, says its tech education business is profitable after enterprise pivot</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Udacity raises $75M in debt, says its tech education business is profitable after enterprise pivot&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/03/udacity-raises-75m-in-debt-says-its-tech-education-business-is-profitable-after-enterprise-pivot/embed/#?secret=YBUUxYrDxf" data-secret="YBUUxYrDxf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Codecademy’s funding signals that investors aren’t just looking for exponential growth, they are looking for sustainable, historical growth. The startup has been cash-flow positive for years, and has $20 million of its $30 million Series C, closed in 2016, still in the bank. Two-thirds of today’s capital is going straight to the bank, Sims says.</p>
<p>Still, raising itself costs money in the form of equity for founders and a startup. So why raise if you still have cash and aren’t struggling to keep up demand?</p>
<p>Sims says that the new cash will be used to acquire businesses, grow internationally in India and other countries, and hire. He also wants to “invest deeply” in a paid product it launched in the wake of the pandemic, Codecademy For Business. The product is Codecademy’s foray into selling coding classes for the enterprise, a shift from its direct-to-consumer route.</p>
<p>Codecademy For Business launched in beta last year and grew to 600 paying clients. Half of those customers are non-technology companies like banks, consulting firms and small businesses that want to train employees in data literacy and tech-specific programing. Sims says that the product was launched due to customer demand, and piggybacks on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/12-investors-say-lifelong-learning-is-taking-edtech-mainstream/">what investors see</a> as an awakening among companies that it is necessary to train and reskill employees.</p>
<p>The growth mirrors the gains recently enjoyed by Udemy. The re-skilling company similarly has an enterprise and consumer product, but is seeing more monetary gains in the former. We scooped last month that Udemy for Business has secured 7,000 customers, and is bringing in roughly $200 million in ARR.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7wzfzNqplc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/udemys-new-president-discusses-the-reskilling-companys-future/">Udemy&#8217;s new president discusses the reskilling company&#8217;s future</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Udemy&#8217;s new president discusses the reskilling company&#8217;s future&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/udemys-new-president-discusses-the-reskilling-companys-future/embed/#?secret=7wzfzNqplc" data-secret="7wzfzNqplc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Sims says that its enterprise operation, which competes with products like Udemy or Coursera, requires upfront research and development “before it starts to pay itself back.” He thinks that building a bottoms-up enterprise product, fueled by tens of millions of Codecademy users, will be both the big opportunity and a big challenge for the company. The end goal here for Codecademy is to have a 50% split between its consumer and enterprise business.</p>
<p>“The number one biggest differentiator has been interactivity,” Sims said. “<a href=" https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/edtech-zoom-university/ ">Everyone is tired of Zoom</a>, and our thesis since the beginning is that video is not the best way to learn, and that learning by doing is.”</p>
<p>While the startup wouldn’t disclose valuation, Codecademy’s growth <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/21/edtech-startups-flirt-with-unicorn-style-growth/">feels mature and unicorn-like. </a>The startup is diversifying revenue, adding offensive cash to its bank, and even not-so-subtly added a CFO from Chegg to its ranks. IPOs are in the air.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="t92KTlwTY5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/12-investors-say-lifelong-learning-is-taking-edtech-mainstream/">13 investors say lifelong learning is taking edtech mainstream</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;13 investors say lifelong learning is taking edtech mainstream&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/12-investors-say-lifelong-learning-is-taking-edtech-mainstream/embed/#?secret=t92KTlwTY5" data-secret="t92KTlwTY5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/codecademy-series-d/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116154</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Y Combinator company Axle Health is bringing on-demand home testing services to telehealth providers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/y-combinator-company-axle-health-is-bringing-on-demand-home-testing-services-to-telehealth-providers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/y-combinator-company-axle-health-is-bringing-on-demand-home-testing-services-to-telehealth-providers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 13:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telehealth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telemedicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ZocDoc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116451</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While usage of telehealth services have surged during the COVID-19 epidemic, there are some times when health professionals need to be around in person to conduct diagnostics tests. To help those telehealth companies bridge that gap is Axle Health, a company currently enrolled in the latest cohort from the Y Combinator accelerator. &#8220;In terms of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">While usage of telehealth services have surged during the COVID-19 epidemic, there are some times when health professionals need to be around in person to conduct diagnostics tests. To help those telehealth companies bridge that gap is <a href="https://www.axlehealth.com/">Axle Health</a>, a company currently enrolled in the latest cohort from the Y Combinator accelerator.</p>
<p>&#8220;In terms of the professionals that we send in home, they&#8217;re phlebotomists, MAs, LVNs, and RNs as well,&#8221; said Axle co-founder Connor Hailey.</p>
<p>In a sad reflection of the times, most of the calls the company&#8217;s getting are COVID-19 related, Hailey said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>And while the company currently doesn&#8217;t accept insurance, many of the companies on the platform choose a price they want to charge their patients and then seek reimbursement from insurers from those costs, according to Hailey.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;There are very few patients that are paying cash. Our services in the home are what would come out of pocket,&#8221; Hailey said. Those fees vary by the licensure level of the visiting health care worker. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company&#8217;s largest partner, Sameday Health, is charging $250 for an at-home PCR test and that&#8217;s self-pay, not covered by insurance, according to Hailey. Hailey said Sameday plans on offering an insurance-covered, at-home PCR test soon which would come with a $100 house-call fee. </span></p>
<p>Axle Health launched its service at the end of January and is seeking to expand its treatment options to more than just COVID-19 testing, but for now, it&#8217;s simply responding to market demand.</p>
<p>Hailey <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/announcing-axle-health-next-generation-in-home-connor-hailey/">launched the business</a> after spending a few years working at ZocDoc and then spending some time at Uber. What motivates Hailey and company co-founder Adam Stansell is providing similar concierge services at lower costs for a broader base of patients, Hailey said.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;The rich have access to in-home care can we make it economical enough so that we can bring it to everyone,&#8221; he said. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/y-combinator-company-axle-health-is-bringing-on-demand-home-testing-services-to-telehealth-providers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116451</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Plume picks up $270M at a $1.35B valuation to power smart home WiFi for broadband providers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/plume-picks-up-270m-at-a-1-35b-valuation-to-power-smart-home-wifi-for-broadband-providers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/plume-picks-up-270m-at-a-1-35b-valuation-to-power-smart-home-wifi-for-broadband-providers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 13:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116414</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The last year of life under a global health pandemic has seen a massive surge of people working from home &#8212; a shift that has thrown a stark light on the iffy quality of our broadband networks. Today a startup called Plume &#8212; which has built a mesh-WiFi platform that helps optimize broadband connectivity and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The last year of life under a global health pandemic has seen a massive surge of people working from home &#8212; a shift that has thrown a stark light on the iffy quality of our broadband networks. Today a startup called <a href="http://plume.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Plume</a> &#8212; which has built a mesh-WiFi platform that helps optimize broadband connectivity and then uses it to deliver a range of smarter home services to some 22 million homes globally &#8212; is announcing a major funding round of $270 million that underscores the opportunity to fix that, and more.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’re the best at optimizing WiFi connectivity in the home, but that is not what we’re about,&#8221; said Fahri Diner, Plume&#8217;s co-founder and CEO, in an interview with TechCrunch. &#8220;We see it as the foundation. We cut our teeth on it but have gone way beyond that to services like advanced parental controls, secure access controls, which devices can access networks and what passwords they use. We focus on sophisticated security, which we believe will be the next big area that consumers will start paying attention to.</p>
<p>&#8220;The ultimate product for Plume is a comprehensive, cloud-driven platform that enables consumers to curate, manage and deliver these services. That’s what the company is about.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The investment, a Series E, is coming from a single investor, Insight Partners, and values the company at $1.35 billion. This is a significant step up for the company, which almost exactly a year ago <a href="https://www.prnewswire.co.uk/news-releases/plume-r-secures-85-million-in-financing-852091305.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised $85 million</a> in a combination of equity and debt at a valuation of $510 million.</p>
<p>Unless you have been following the business of home broadband networking, you may not be familiar with the name Plume. But if you are not already be using it, chances are that you may be getting pitched a service using its technology, or will be soon.</p>
<p>The company, based out of Palo Alto, has deals in place with some 170 carriers around the globe that provide residential broadband services, reselling Plume&#8217;s mesh technology as a way to improve home WiFi connectivity &#8212; especially critical in older or bigger homes, and dwellings where you have many people connecting to and straining your broadband network &#8212; providing Plume-powered services like network security, parental access controls and motion awareness on top of that.</p>
<p>Plume brands those added services as HomePass, and on top of this it also provides a cloud-based operations tools to carriers, Haystack and Harvest, which help them with customer support, to manage their networks, glean better performance analytics and provide insights on customer usage and churn.</p>
<p>Plume also works with a number of big and less well-known hardware makers who design the routing devices and the processors and related software that power them.</p>
<p>Some of its customers, like Comcast, Charter, Qualcomm, Belkin, Cablevision, Liberty Global and Shaw Communications have become <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/05/08/comcast-invests-in-mesh-router-maker-plume-launches-xfinity-xfi-for-managing-your-homes-wireless-network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">strategic investors</a> in the company over the years, which speaks to its traction with the big players in the market. (It has raised $397 million to date.)</p>
<p>There have been a number of efforts over the years to improve WiFi in the home, from faster networks through to better routers and WiFi extenders.</p>
<p>Plume&#8217;s technology is based on one of those alternatives, mesh architecture &#8212; also used by others like Google in its Nest WiFi system &#8212; which uses a single router and then a series of nodes that operate as if they are a single device on the network (extenders by contrast use different SSIDs and passwords).</p>
<p>On top of the mesh architecture, Plume then runs a software-defined network to identify and better measure the traffic, using automation to, for example, then detect and fix when a device is on the network, may need more power to work properly, and so on.</p>
<p>In all, it appears that Plume has some <a href="https://patents.google.com/?assignee=Plume+Design+Inc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">170 patents and patent applications</a> in play to underpin what it has built.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s interesting to note that at one time Plume was compared to Eero, the mesh-based wifi router startup that was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/11/amazon-is-buying-home-mesh-router-startup-eero/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">eventually acquired by Amazon</a>, which now resells its routers as part of its own mesh WiFi solution.</p>
<p>But the two have some critical differences, based mainly on the business premise behind the two. As Diner points out, Plume&#8217;s service stack is based not around a router (as Eero&#8217;s primarily was) but on mesh technology that plus an open source silicon-to-cloud framework platform for building services to run on the mesh network that it calls <a href="http://opensync.io">OpenSync</a>. This essentially allows service providers to build their own services on top of Plume&#8217;s mesh architecture.</p>
<p>(Diner, I should point out, has a pretty long-standing and deep understanding of what carriers need, what they actually use and also how they think. He himself trained as an engineer and worked in increasingly senior roles at a number of vendors at the cusp of when carriers were making their switch from legacy copper to fiber and optic networks. In the heyday of telecoms capital expenditures, he sold a previous company that he founded, Qtera, a pioneer in long-haul photonic networking solutions, to now-defunct Nortel for $3.2 billion. He&#8217;s also a long-standing investor and board member at a range of major next-generation communications vendors.)</p>
<p>In a telecoms world that has long fretted over the idea of being cannibalized and relegated to the role of a &#8220;dumb pipe&#8221;, it provides a way for those carriers to build services &#8212; apps, as it were &#8212; on top of that WiFi connectivity.</p>
<p>That existential crisis has been even more compounded as the promise of &#8220;triple play&#8221; &#8212; carriers selling voice, broadband and video services to their customers &#8212; has failed to deliver not least because no one is particularly interested in using or keeping their fixed landlines, and carriers have been completely outplayed on content by the giant rush of tech and media companies building their own, more attractive alternatives for consumers.</p>
<p>That has left carriers with a focus on broadband, which itself then gets commoditized on price, with everyone more or less offering the same speeds and reliability.</p>
<p>&#8220;How to differentiate?&#8221; is the question they all ask now, said Diner. Plume&#8217;s answer: &#8220;We differentiate inside the home, with a new bundle of services.&#8221;</p>
<p>Realistically, however, Diner points out that only the very biggest carriers (and not even all of them) might have the resources and appetite to do so. Of the 170 customers it has today, only five are building their own customized services on top of the platform, he said.</p>
<p>This is why Plume builds services that it white-labels and resells to carriers to sell on to consumers, and why those services have seen a lot of traction among those service providers. OpenSync, Plume says, now covers some 26 million access points and is seeing a sharp rise as more people fill out their homes with more equipment that they use throughout the day.</p>
<p>You might argue that those home services will also start to look too similar to each other as well, and so frankly the hope is that the open platform will eventually lead to more companies and services innovating around it.</p>
<p>In the meantime, it&#8217;s a win-win for Plume.</p>
<p>“Growth in the smart home category is exploding, but the quality of consumer experience has fallen short,” said Insight Partners Managing Director Ryan Hinkle, in a statement. “We are convinced that Plume, with its scalable cloud data platform approach, highly efficient go-to-market strategy, strong momentum, top-quartile financial performance across all SaaS KPIs – including revenue, growth rates, gross margin, efficiency and retention metrics – and world class team is transforming this category. We’re delighted to join and support this exciting journey.” Hinkle is joining Plume&#8217;s board with this round.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/plume-picks-up-270m-at-a-1-35b-valuation-to-power-smart-home-wifi-for-broadband-providers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116414</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anuvia raises $103 million to commercialize its novel fertilizer</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/anuvia-raises-103-million-to-commercialize-its-novel-fertilizer/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/anuvia-raises-103-million-to-commercialize-its-novel-fertilizer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 13:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agriculture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[board member]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chemicals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indigo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managing partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michigan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Anuvia Plant Nutrients has raised $103 million to commercialize its novel fertilizer technology. The company, backed by investors like TPG ART, Pontifax Global Food and Agriculture Technology Fund, Generate Capital andPiva Capital, is now ready to roll out its tech, which is already used on roughly 1200 farms and is projected to be on 20 million [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.anuviaplantnutrients.com/">Anuvia Plant Nutrients</a> has raised $103 million to commercialize its novel fertilizer technology.</p>
<p>The company, backed by investors like <a href="https://www.tpg.com/platforms/tpgart"><span style="font-weight: 400;">TPG ART,</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> <a href="https://www.pontifaxagtech.com/">Pontifax Global Food and Agriculture Technology Fund</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">,</span> <a href="https://generatecapital.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Generate Capital</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">and</span><a href="http://www.piva.vc/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Piva</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Capital</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, is now ready to roll out its tech, which is already used on roughly 1200 farms and is projected to be on 20 million acres of farmland by 2025. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now led by longtime agriculture executive Amy Yoder, who represents the sixth generation of a Michigan farm family, Anuvia pitches its tech as a supplement for crops that can boost productivity by taking excrement, food waste and agricultural processing waste and converting that into useful fertilizer using a proprietary catalytic process. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>By treating the waste with a specific blend of chemicals Yoder said Anuvia&#8217;s technology can control the release of nutrients as plants grow to make more productive crops and reduce leaching into soil, protecting groundwater and restoring carbon to the soil.</p>
<p>Anuvia is one of a growing number of agriculture technology companies trying to juice crop productivity and capture carbon to provide additional revenues from more abundant crops and carbon capture and storage. Other startups, including Pivot Bio, Indigo Agriculture, AgBiome, and Agrinos, are all developing other crop treatments that can purportedly boost agricultural production.</p>
<p>&#8220;M<span style="font-weight: 400;">ost of what I see would be very complimentary to us,&#8221; said Yoder. &#8220;Because we put the carbon back into the soil, because the nutrients are held in different way. You could utilize the pivot technology and the Anuvia technology. Those things when they could piggyback together could make really nice solutions in the longterm.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>The Winter Garden, Fla.-based company has a 1.2 million ton facility for production, but the company wants to build out additional capacity and continue developing new fertilizers to take to market, Yoder said.</p>
<p>Farmers using the product see increased yields of around five times their previous production levels and the product can be used on all the main row crops, according to Yoder.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That claim has been verified by Environmental Resources Management (ERM), a leading global environmental consulting firm, versus traditional fertilizer on corn, rice, and cotton.</span></p>
<p>Anuvia&#8217;s treatment can also reduce greenhouse gases on production by up to 32% compared to commercial fertilizers. Anuvia estimates that its products could provide emissions reductions equivalent to removing 30,000 cars from roads. If the company can get farmers to apply its treatment to the 90 million acres of corn in the U.s. that would reduce the equivalent emissions of 1.8 million cars, according to a statement.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“With the world’s population expected to hit 10 billion by 2050, we need technology-enabled, large-scale agriculture to meet this growing demand,” says Dr. Geoff Duyk, Founder and Managing Partner of Circularis and Anuvia Board Member. “Anuvia’s technology will help farms continue to feed the world, while also advancing the circular economy, increasing sustainability, and enhancing resource efficiency.” </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/anuvia-raises-103-million-to-commercialize-its-novel-fertilizer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116345</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>IronSource acquires video and playable ad platform Luna Labs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/ironsource-acquires-luna-labs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/ironsource-acquires-luna-labs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 13:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IronSource]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Luna Labs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mobile advertising company ironSource is announcing its second acquisition of the year — Luna Labs, a startup that that&#8217;s built a platform allowing app developers to create and manage video and playable ads. When I first wrote about the startup in 2019, its main selling point was the ability to create those ads directly from [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Mobile advertising company <a href="http://ironsource.com">ironSource</a> is announcing its second acquisition of the year — <a href="https://lunalabs.io">Luna Labs</a>, a startup that that&#8217;s built a platform allowing app developers to create and manage video and playable ads.</p>
<p>When I <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/31/luna-labs-creates-playable-ads-directly-from-unity/">first wrote about the startup in 2019</a>, its main selling point was the ability to create those ads directly from from the Unity game engine used by many developers. Since then, it has expanded its platform to support the creation of both playable and video ads (including unlimited variations of a gameplay video), manage their entire ad library, analyze their performance and even automatically optimize them based on install data. Its customers include Crazy Labs, Supersonic Studios, Lion Studios, Kwalee and Voodoo.</p>
<p>IronSource, meanwhile, has built a platform for mobile user growth and monetization. It was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/03/ironsource-a-mobile-adtech-startup-confirms-400m-raise-at-1-valuation/">valued at more than $1 billion</a> in its most recent funding round of more than $400 million, and in January it announced <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2021/01/11/ironsource-acquires-ad-measurement-firm-soomla/">the acquisition of ad measurement company Soomla</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In a statement, ironSource&#8217;s co-founder and chief revenue officer Omer Kaplan said:</p>
<blockquote><p>Our vision at ironSource is to build the most comprehensive growth platform for app developers, allowing them to focus on content creation and on building a great user experience, while we provide the infrastructure for their business expansion. Creatives are a key part of that and have only become more important as competition for user attention grows. But ad creative development and testing at scale is incredibly difficult and costly. Luna Labs solves that by bringing high quality end-to-end ad creation management to app developers, and we’re excited to be able to add that capability into the ironSource platform.</p></blockquote>
<p>The financial terms of the acquisition were not disclosed. IronSource says that the Luna Labs team (currently based in the United Kingdom) will remain in its current offices, where it will continue developing its technology &#8220;under the ironSource umbrella.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QKbNvNNO9K"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/31/luna-labs-creates-playable-ads-directly-from-unity/">Luna Labs creates playable ads, directly from Unity</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Luna Labs creates playable ads, directly from Unity&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/31/luna-labs-creates-playable-ads-directly-from-unity/embed/#?secret=QKbNvNNO9K" data-secret="QKbNvNNO9K" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/ironsource-acquires-luna-labs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116182</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SpaceTech startup ConstellR, that can monitor land surface temperatures, raises €1M pre-seed round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/spacetech-startup-constellr-that-can-monitor-land-surface-temperatures-raises-e1m-pre-seed-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/spacetech-startup-constellr-that-can-monitor-land-surface-temperatures-raises-e1m-pre-seed-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 11:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cubesat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food supply]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[infrared]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managing partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monitoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology Partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ConstellR, a SpaceTech startup with a technology that can monitors land surface temperatures from space, has raised a €1m pre-seed round led by FTTF, with the participation of strategic investor OHB Venture Capital, Baden-Württemberg’s state bank L-Bank and an undisclosed investor. The first system is due to go into orbit in December 2021. The company [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://constellr.space/">ConstellR</a>, a SpaceTech startup with a technology that can monitors land surface temperatures from space, has raised a €1m pre-seed round led by FTTF, with the participation of strategic investor OHB Venture Capital, Baden-Württemberg’s state bank L-Bank and an undisclosed investor. The first system is due to go into orbit in December 2021. The company was a finalist for Hottest Ag/FoodTech Startup at the prestigious <a href="http://theeuropas.com">Europas Awards 2020</a>.</p>
<p>The Freiburg, Germany-based startup monitors the land via a constellation of 30 CubeSats with thermal infrared payloads. The data generated is used by farmers to reduce water and fertilizer usage, and could help them reduce existing monitoring costs by 97%, says the company. ConstellR has a patent-pending miniaturization architecture with ‘free-form optics’ and claims to be able to make it much cheaper to monitor the infrared part of the spectrum than traditional satellite systems.</p>
<p>Dr. Max Gulde, CEO, ConstellR, said: “Our mission is to monitor every single field on the planet every single day of the year and provide precision farming companies with highly accurate temperature data to safeguard the world’s food supply. With our strong financial and technology partners on board, I am looking forward to a time of quantum leaps in our constellation development to change agriculture on the global planetary scale.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Tobias Schwind, Managing Partner at FTTF, Fraunhofer’s Technology Transfer Fund, said: “ConstellR’s unique technology and business case as well as its passionate team convinced us to make this exciting pre-seed investment.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/spacetech-startup-constellr-that-can-monitor-land-surface-temperatures-raises-e1m-pre-seed-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116417</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
