<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 16:04:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Atlassian launches a Jira for every team</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/atlassian-launches-jira-work-management-a-jira-for-every-team/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/atlassian-launches-jira-work-management-a-jira-for-every-team/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 16:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlassian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JIRA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144745</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Atlassian today announced a new edition of its Jira project management tool, Jira Work Management. The company has long been on a journey of bringing Jira to teams beyond the software development groups it started out with. With Jira Service Management, it is successfully doing that with IT teams. With Jira Core, it also moved [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Atlassian today <a href="https://www.atlassian.com/blog/announcements/introducing-jira-work-management">announced</a> a new edition of its Jira project management tool, Jira Work Management. The company has long been on a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/13/atlassian-expands-jira-service-desk-beyond-it-teams/">journey</a> of bringing Jira to teams beyond the software development groups it started out with. With <a href="https://www.atlassian.com/software/jira/service-management">Jira Service Management</a>, it is successfully doing that with IT teams. With <a href="https://www.atlassian.com/software/jira/core/">Jira Core</a>, it also moved further in this direction, but Jira Work Management takes this a step further (and will replace Jira Core). The idea here is to offer a version of Jira that enables teams across marketing, HR, finance, design and other groups to manage their work and &#8212; if needed &#8212; connect it to that of a company&#8217;s development teams.</p>
<p>&#8220;JIRA Software&#8217;s this de-facto standard,&#8221; Atlassian&#8217;s VP of Product Noah Wasmer told me. &#8220;We&#8217;re making just huge inroads with JIRA Service Management right now, bringing IT teams into that loop. We have over 100,000 customers now on those two products. So it&#8217;s really doing incredibly well. But one of the things that CIOs say is that it&#8217;s really tough to put JIRA Software in front of an HR team and the legal team. They often ask, what is code? What is a pull request?&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2145028" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-1.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2145028" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2145028" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-1.png 1552w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-1.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-1.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-1.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-1.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-1.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-1.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2145028" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Atlassian</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Wasmer also noted that even though Jira Software is specifically meant for developers, about half of its users are already in other teams that work with these development teams. &#8220;We think that [Jira Work Management] gives them the more contextually relevant tool &#8212; a tool that actually helps them accelerate and move faster,&#8221; Wasmer said.</p>
<p>With Jira Work Management, the company is looking at making it easier for any team to track and manage their work in what Wasmer described as a &#8220;universal system and family of product.&#8221; As company&#8217;s look at how to do remote and hybrid work, Atlassian believes that they&#8217;ll need this kind of core product to keep track of the work that is being done. But it&#8217;s also about the simple fact that every business is now a software business and while every team&#8217;s work touches upon this, marketing and design teams often still work in their own silos.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2145016" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/JWM-Timeline-View.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2145016" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2145016" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/JWM-Timeline-View.gif" alt="" width="800" height="473" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2145016" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Atlassian</p></div></p>
<p>These different teams, though, also have quite different expectations of the user interface they need to manage their work most effectively. So while Jira Work Management features all of the automation features and privacy controls of its brethren, it is based around a slightly different and simplified user interface than Jira Software, for example.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s even more important, though, is that Jira Work Management offers a variety of views for teams to enter and manipulate their data. To get new users onboarded quickly, Atlassian built a set of templates for some of the most common use cases it expects, though users are obviously free to customize all these different views to their hearts&#8217; &#8212; and business needs&#8217; &#8212; content.</p>
<p>Atlassian also changed some of the language around Jira tickets. There are no &#8216;stories&#8217; and &#8216;bugs&#8217; in Jira Work Management (unless you add them yourself) and instead, these templates use words like &#8216;tasks,&#8217; &#8216;assets&#8217; (for design use cases) or &#8216;candidates&#8217; (for HR).</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2145017" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/JWM-List-View.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2145017" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2145017" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/JWM-List-View.gif" alt="" width="800" height="473" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2145017" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Atlassian</p></div></p>
<p>Given the fact that spreadsheets are the universal language of business, it&#8217;s maybe no surprise that the List view is core here, with an Excel/Airtable-like experience that should immediately feel familiar to any business user. It&#8217;s in-line editable and completely abstracts away the usual Jira ticket, even though underneath, it&#8217;s the same taxonomy and infrastructure.</p>
<p>&#8220;We really wanted people to walk into this product and just understand that there is work that needs to be done,&#8221; Chase Wilson, the head of product marketing for Jira Work Management, said. He noted that the team worked on making the experience feel snappy.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2145089" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-2.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2145089" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2145089" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="538" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-2.png 1552w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-2.png?resize=150,79 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-2.png?resize=300,158 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-2.png?resize=768,404 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-2.png?resize=680,358 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-2.png?resize=1536,808 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/pasted-image-0-2.png?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2145089" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Atlassian</p></div></p>
<p>The other view available are pretty straightforward a calendar and Gantt chart-like timeline view, as well as the traditional Kanban board that has long been at the core of Jira (and Agile in general).</p>
<p>Jira Work Management also lets users build forms, using a drag and drop editor that makes it easy for anybody inside an organization to build forms and collect requests that way. Only a few weeks ago, Atlassian announced the acquisition of ThinkTilt, the company behind the popular no-code from builder <a href="https://www.thinktilt.com/proforma/forms-for-jira-service-management">ProForma</a> and it looks like it is already putting this acquisition to work here.</p>
<p>As Wasmer stressed, Jira Work Management is meant to help different teams get work done in a way that works best for them. But because Jira is now a family of products, it also enables a lot more cross-team collaboration. That means a development team that is working on implementing a GDPR requirement can now build a workflow that ties in with the project board for a legal team that then allows legal to hold up a software release until it approves this new feature.</p>
<p>&#8220;We hear about this all the time today,&#8221; he said. &#8220;They just stick the legal team into JIRA Software &#8212; and it over-inundates them with information that&#8217;s not relevant to what they&#8217;re trying to get done. Now we can expose them. And we also then get that legal team, that marketing team, exposed to different templates for different work. What they&#8217;re finding is that once they get used to it for that must-do use case, they start saying: Well, hey, why don&#8217;t I use this for contract approvals at the end of the quarter?'&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2145101" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/JWM-Board-View.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2145101" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2145101" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/JWM-Board-View.gif" alt="" width="800" height="431" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2145101" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Atlassian</p></div></p>
<p>As for pricing, Atlassian follows its same standard template here, offering a free tier for teams with up to 10 users and then the paid tiers start at $5/user/month, with discounts for larger teams.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, Atlassian plans to add more reporting capabilities, native approvals for faster signoffs and more advanced functionality across the new work views.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that Jira Work Management is the first product to come out of Point A, Atlassian&#8217;s new innovation program &#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">dedicated to connecting early adopter customers with product teams to build the next generation of teamwork tools.&#8221;</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vnWHeLfL4w"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/atlassian-acquires-thinktilt/">Atlassian acquires ThinkTilt</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Atlassian acquires ThinkTilt&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/atlassian-acquires-thinktilt/embed/#?secret=vnWHeLfL4w" data-secret="vnWHeLfL4w" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/atlassian-launches-jira-work-management-a-jira-for-every-team/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144745</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Uber adds vaccine booking, car rental delivery in new product push</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/uber-adds-vaccine-booking-car-rental-delivery-in-new-product-push/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/uber-adds-vaccine-booking-car-rental-delivery-in-new-product-push/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 15:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rideshare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber Eats]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144777</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Uber is launching more than a half-dozen new features, including one that will let users book vaccine appointments at Walgreens and reserve a ride to get their jab, as the company homes in on a business model that will finally deliver profitability. The features, announced Wednesday, fall under what Uber is describing as its &#8220;go [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Uber is launching more than a half-dozen new features, including one that will let users book vaccine appointments at Walgreens and reserve a ride to get their jab, as the company homes in on a business model that will finally deliver profitability.</p>
<p>The features, announced Wednesday, fall under what Uber is describing as its &#8220;go get&#8221; strategy. It&#8217;s also meant to mark a return to more &#8220;normal&#8221; business operations following 14 months of shutdowns caused by the COVID-19 pandemic. The numerous features that include vaccine booking, a valet service that will drop off a rental car, reserved rides at airports that off up a an hour of wait time and options to pick up food during a rideshare route are all centered around Uber&#8217;s core services of delivery and ride-hailing.</p>
<p>In early 2020, Uber looked like a different business with a web of pursuits that covered air taxis and self-driving cars, delivery, ridesharing, a freight booking platform and shared ebike and scooter rentals. In the past year, Uber has dumped shared micromobility unit Jump, offloaded its autonomous air taxi business Uber Elevate, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/uber-sells-self-driving-unit-uber-atg-in-deal-that-will-push-auroras-valuation-to-10b/">sold off its Uber ATG self-driving unit</a> and sold a stake in its growing but still unprofitable logistics arm, Uber Freight. (Uber has maintained equity in all of these businesses).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This wasn&#8217;t just about riding itself of businesses. During this same period, Uber also doubled down on rideshare and delivery — acquiring Postmates and Drizly in the process — in a bet that these two areas would be the best path to profitability. Uner&#8217;s Go Get initiative is a continuation of that strategy. Meanwhile, COVID-19 decimated its rideshare — along with competitors — business as delivery exploded.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2145116" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Valet-Delivery-and-Pickup.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2145116" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2145116 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Valet-Delivery-and-Pickup.gif?w=680" alt="Uber Valet - Delivery and Pickup" width="680" height="680" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2145116" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Uber</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Over the last year, the company has evolved into a platform where we&#8217;re doing two things with incredible focus and incredible intensity,&#8221; Uber CPO Sundeep Jain said in a recent interview. &#8220;And those are helping users &#8216;go&#8217; and helping users &#8216;get.&#8217; We really have evolved this platform where you can go anywhere, get anything.&#8221;</p>
<p>For Uber, this means building products that let people &#8220;go&#8221; somewhere using a variety of different modes from cars and scooters to buses and other forms of public transit or &#8220;get&#8221; anything such as prepared food from restaurants and more recently expanding into groceries, prescriptions and alcohol. This &#8220;go&#8221; and &#8220;get&#8221; directive is influencing the company&#8217;s product development and even acquisition strategy. With Uber&#8217;s acquisition of Postmates, the company even deliver iPhones, Jain noted as one example.</p>
<p>Among the new features is Uber Rent with Valet, which lets users in the U.S. rent a car directly in the Uber app. The vehicle is then delivered to the user, whether it&#8217;s at their home or airport. The company&#8217;s Uber Reserve feature is now being rolled out across the U.S. as well, and includes flight tracking, 60 minutes of wait time and curbside pickup.</p>
<p>On the &#8220;get&#8221; front of this strategy, Uber has launched &#8220;Pick Up and Go&#8221; which lets a rideshare user place an order for pickup and add a stop to pick up the order while en route to their final destination. Uber also rolled out a new &#8216;schedule&#8217; button that includes an option to order from merchants, even when they&#8217;re closed. There&#8217;s also new capability to add on items from a second merchant at check out for no additional delivery fee.</p>
<p>Uber has also added a savings hub that will highlight every eligible offer, deal and discount available to users, a new feature that gives delivery reminders via in-app notifications and an extension of its Eats Pass membership.</p>
<p>All of this, is of course, aimed at the holy &#8220;profitability&#8221; grail. And it appears to be closer than it was a year ago. Earlier this month, Uber released a SEC filing that maintained it still expects quarterly Adjusted EBITDA profitability in 2021. Uber also reported its gross bookings<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> in March reached the highest monthly level in the company&#8217;s nearly 12-year history. The company&#8217;s mobility business posted its best month since March 2020, crossing a $30 billion annualized Gross Bookings run-rate, with average daily Gross Bookings up 9% month-over-month. The company&#8217;s delivery business set another all-time record, crossing a $52 billion annualized Gross Bookings run-rate in March, growing more than 150% year-over-year, the filing said. </span></p>
<p>The upshot: March was Uber&#8217;s best in its history in terms of gross sales on its platform. However, as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/12/ride-hailings-profitability-promise-is-in-its-final-countdown/">TechCrunch&#8217;s Alex Wilhelm noted</a> recently, while Uber&#8217;s delivery business has scaled, it is still less profitable than its main rideshare business. The company has reached a new total platform spend record, but it&#8217;s made up of less profitable revenue than before.</p>
<p>This Go Get program appears to be aimed finding new ways to build out its ridehailing business — which in previous quarters generated the superior result, generating positive adjusted EBITDA — while expanding delivery without adding costs.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/uber-adds-vaccine-booking-car-rental-delivery-in-new-product-push/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144777</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zomato juice: Indian unicorn&#8217;s proposed IPO could drive regional startup liquidity</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/zomato-juice-indian-unicorns-proposed-ipo-could-drive-regional-startup-liquidity/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/zomato-juice-indian-unicorns-proposed-ipo-could-drive-regional-startup-liquidity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 15:26:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Food Climate and Sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zomato]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144948</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The IPO parade that has continued in 2021 is not a strictly domestic affair. Other countries are getting in on the unicorn liquidity rush. This week, India-based food-delivery unicorn Zomato filed to go public. As TechCrunch reported, the company intends to list &#8220;on Indian stock exchanges NSE and BSE.&#8221; The Zomato IPO is incredibly important. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/after-going-public-once-hot-startups-are-riding-a-valuation-roller-coaster/">IPO parade</a> that has continued in 2021 is not a strictly domestic affair. Other countries are getting in on the unicorn liquidity rush.</p>
<p>This week, India-based food-delivery unicorn Zomato <a href="https://www.sebi.gov.in/filings/public-issues/apr-2021/zomato-limited-drhp_49956.html">filed to go public</a>. As <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/indian-food-delivery-startup-zomato-files-for-an-ipo/">TechCrunch reported</a>, the company intends to list &#8220;on Indian stock exchanges NSE and BSE.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Zomato IPO is incredibly important. As our own <a href="https://twitter.com/refsrc?lang=en">Manish Singh</a> reported when the company&#8217;s numbers became public, a &#8220;successful listing [could be] poised to encourage nearly a dozen other unicorn Indian startups to accelerate their efforts to tap the public markets.&#8221; So, Zomato&#8217;s debut is not only notable because its impending listing gives us a look into its economics, but because it could lead to a liquidity rush in the country if its flotation goes well.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>At this point, we&#8217;ll pause and note that India is currently enduring a COVID-19 surge that may be without precedent. You can <a href="https://impact.publicgood.com/campaign/4240db93-7334-499d-8ee5-0ed938563b31">provide help here</a>. May the pandemic abate quickly and with as little pain as possible.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995214 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p>Back to Zomato: The company&#8217;s IPO filing paints the picture of a quickly growing company derailed by the pandemic. However, the unicorn has posted rapid recovery in recent quarters, and its economics are maturing to the point when it can begin to craft a path to long-term profitability. This morning, let&#8217;s dig into its numbers and try to sort out why the company is going public now and how investors may vet its recent performance.</p>
<h2>Zomato&#8217;s business</h2>
<p>Zomato was last valued at around $5.4 billion in a February 2021 round that <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/funding_round/zomato-series-unknown--920293a6">put $250 million</a> into its operations. The unicorn has raised more than $2 billion to date, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/zomato/company_financials">per Crunchbase data</a>.</p>
<p>In business terms, Zomato offers more than merely food delivery. Per its IPO filing, the company&#8217;s food delivery business is supplemented by its &#8220;dining-out&#8221; capability that facilitates in-person eating, a raw materials business called &#8220;Hyperpure,&#8221; and Zomato Pro, a consumer offering that provides food discounts to its 1.4 million subscribers.</p>
<p>So we can&#8217;t merely compare the firm to, say, Uber Eats &#8212; the India operations of which Zomato bought back in the day &#8212; on a one-to-one basis.</p>
<p>But what we can track is the company&#8217;s aggregate financial performance through the end of 2020. The Zomato filing does not appear to include information regarding the company&#8217;s calendar Q1 2021 performance; that period, for reference, is the fourth quarter of the company&#8217;s fiscal 2021.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s start from a very high level:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fiscal year ending March 31, 2019: $187.4 million in total revenue, and a loss before exceptional items of $296.3 million.</li>
<li>Fiscal year ending March 31, 2020: $367.8 million in total revenue, and a loss before exceptional items of $303.5 million</li>
<li>Nine-month period ending December 31, 2020: $183.4 million in total revenue, and a loss before exceptional items of $47.8 million<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/zomato-juice-indian-unicorns-proposed-ipo-could-drive-regional-startup-liquidity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144948</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>3D printing marketplace Shapeways set for SPAC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/3d-printing-marketplace-shapeways-set-for-spac/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/3d-printing-marketplace-shapeways-set-for-spac/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 15:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3d printer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3d printing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shapeways]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145063</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shapeways this morning confirmed earlier reports that it has entered into a deal to go public via SPAC. The model, which has become increasingly popular among tech companies in the past year, has already been taking up by a number of fellow 3D printing companies, including Markforged and Desktop Metal. “Our vision to enable anyone [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Shapeways this morning confirmed <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-galileo-acqsn-m-a-shapeways/shapeways-nears-deal-to-go-public-through-galileo-spac-merger-sources-idUSKBN2CE2O3">earlier reports</a> that it has<a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210428005322/en/Shapeways-a-leader-in-Digital-Manufacturing-to-List-on-NYSE-via-Merger-with-Galileo-Acquisition-Corp."> entered into a deal to go public via SPAC</a>. The model, which has become increasingly popular among tech companies in the past year, has already been taking up by a number of fellow 3D printing companies, including Markforged and Desktop Metal.</p>
<p>“Our vision to enable anyone to rapidly transform digital designs to physical products is reaching a significant milestone today as we transition Shapeways into a public company,” CEO Greg Kress said in a release tied to the news. “We have been successfully executing on our vision, and this capital will allow us to empower digital manufacturing at scale, accelerating Shapeways’ additive manufacturing capabilities while expanding the Company’s material and technology offerings to more markets and industries.”</p>
<p>Founded back in 2007, the New York-based company (with Dutch roots) offers 3D printing as a service. Specifically, it lets users outsource the printing of 3D printing objects to its own army of industrial units. Included in its services is a marketplace where users can buy and sell 3D printed objects.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company, which has raised north of $107 million <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/shapeways">per Crunchbase</a>, will enter into a reverse merge with blank firm, Galileo Acquisition Corp. The deal would value Shapeways at $410 million and provide upwards of $195 million in proceeds. The money will go toward, “accelerat[ing] Shapeways’ metal additive manufacturing capabilities, expand[ind] the company’s material and technology offerings to extend market reach and grow customer share of wallet as well as to provid[ing] additional working capital.”</p>
<p>The deal, which is subject to the standard regulatory scrutiny, would list the company as “SHPW” in the NYSE. It’s expected to close this summer.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jTBfdyitWt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/metal-3d-printing-company-markforged-announces-plans-to-go-public-via-spac/">Metal 3D printing company Markforged announces plans to go public via SPAC</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Metal 3D printing company Markforged announces plans to go public via SPAC&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/metal-3d-printing-company-markforged-announces-plans-to-go-public-via-spac/embed/#?secret=jTBfdyitWt" data-secret="jTBfdyitWt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/3d-printing-marketplace-shapeways-set-for-spac/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145063</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Splitwise raises $20M Series A to help everyone in the world divvy expenses</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/splitwise-raises-20m-series-a-to-help-everyone-in-the-world-divvy-expenses/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/splitwise-raises-20m-series-a-to-help-everyone-in-the-world-divvy-expenses/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 15:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insight Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Providence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[splitwise]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145011</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning Splitwise, a Providence, Rhode Island-based startup announced that it has closed a $20 million Series A. The company builds consumer fintech software that helps users split expenses. But Splitwise isn&#8217;t a Venmo or Paytm clone. Instead of helping users wire money to their pals, the company leaves the transference of money to others. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a href="https://www.splitwise.com/">Splitwise</a>, a Providence, Rhode Island-based startup announced that it has closed a $20 million Series A.</p>
<p>The company builds consumer fintech software that helps users split expenses. But Splitwise isn&#8217;t a Venmo or Paytm clone. Instead of helping users wire money to their pals, the company leaves the transference of money to others. Splitwise simply wants to help reduce the stress and awkwardness that money puts on relationships of all sorts, CEO <a href="https://twitter.com/jonbittner?lang=en">Jon Bittner</a> told TechCrunch in an interview.</p>
<p>Roommates, partners, married couples with distinct finances, or just friends going on skiing trips all have to deal with shared expenses. And tracking down your friends or spouse or roomie for their cut of a cost is zero fun. Splitwise&#8217;s software makes it easier to track and come to terms with shared expenses. By keeping those costs in the open, and whom owes who, the app wants to keep debts clear so that folks don&#8217;t have to trip over each other when it comes to money.</p>
<p>The product concept has found a global audience. Per Bittner, Splitwise has attracted tens of millions of registered user who have shared or managed what it calculates to be $90 billion since 2011. The startup declined to share <em>active</em> user numbers, but as it is merely raising a Series A we gave it an early-stage pass on more concrete usage metrics.</p>
<p>Since Splitwise leaves the transference of monies amongst its users to others, it doesn&#8217;t make money off of transaction fees or stored consumer funds.<strong> </strong>So how does it make cash? By charging users $3 per month for its Pro service. Or more simply, Splitwise offers a consumer subscription to users who need more powerful cost-sharing software.</p>
<p>We lack metrics to illustrate how Splitwise&#8217;s subscription user-base looks, but Bittner said that the company&#8217;s conversion rate from free to paid has not declined as Splitwise&#8217;s free user base has scaled. We can infer, however, that as Insight Partners was willing to lead a $20 million investment into the company, its paid subscriber base is growing at at least a reasonable clip.</p>
<p>Before its Series A, Bittner told TechCrunch that his company had raised around $9 million.</p>
<p>Splitwise has long grown organically. As it was able to attract new users without paid spend, it managed to keep its costs low. That meant that it didn&#8217;t need to raise venture capital at the same velocity as some other consumer fintech companies. But by keeping its fundraising to a minimum, the company had to be somewhat careful in where it pointed its resources.</p>
<p>Its CEO said that Splitwise said that the new capital will allow the company to boost its product cadence.</p>
<p>But don&#8217;t expect all the money to go to making paid-only features. Splitwise was clear to TechCrunch that it wants its free experience to be sufficiently useful that users are willing to invite their friends to the service without risking bringing them into an overly-pushy commercial digital environment.</p>
<p>Its investors seem aligned with the thinking, with Insight Partners&#8217; Boris Treskunov saying in a statement that he&#8217;s &#8220;excited to see the app become the go-to platform for easy cost-splitting among friends and family.&#8221; Mass adoption of that sort will require a robust free experience. Which means continued spend on the free-side of the startup&#8217;s freemium product work.</p>
<p>Splitwise is perhaps Providence&#8217;s best-known startup, though the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/05/yc-backed-pangea-discusses-growth-fundraising-ahead-of-demo-day/">recent Y Combinator graduate</a> <a href="https://pangea.app/">Pangea</a> is giving it a run for its money lately when it comes to local notoriety. Regardless, the two companies are evidence that it&#8217;s possible to build growing tech companies outside of the handful of American cities most associated with startup work. Let&#8217;s see what Splitwise can do with its new capital, and what percent of its future hiring winds up being remote, versus local to its main hub.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fhsXO01AQj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/internal-rates-of-return-in-emerging-us-tech-hubs-are-starting-to-overtake-silicon-valley/">Internal rates of return in emerging US tech hubs are starting to overtake Silicon Valley</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Internal rates of return in emerging US tech hubs are starting to overtake Silicon Valley&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/internal-rates-of-return-in-emerging-us-tech-hubs-are-starting-to-overtake-silicon-valley/embed/#?secret=fhsXO01AQj" data-secret="fhsXO01AQj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/splitwise-raises-20m-series-a-to-help-everyone-in-the-world-divvy-expenses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145011</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Shopify aims to level the playing field with its machine learning-driven model of lending</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/how-shopify-aims-to-level-the-playing-field-with-its-machine-learning-driven-model-of-lending/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/how-shopify-aims-to-level-the-playing-field-with-its-machine-learning-driven-model-of-lending/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 15:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online lending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Merchant Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online lending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Publishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145029</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shopify is widely known for giving independent merchants a platform to start, run, market and manage their businesses. But over the past 5 years, the company has been steadily growing another part of its own business: Shopify Capital. Through this arm, the Canadian commerce giant revealed today that it has provided $2 billion in funding [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shopify is widely known for giving independent merchants a platform to start, run, market and manage their businesses.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But over the past 5 years, the company has been steadily growing another part of its own business: Shopify Capital. Through this arm, the Canadian commerce giant revealed today that it has provided $2 billion in funding to tens of thousands of entrepreneurs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Besides being a cool milestone, how it works is interesting. Merchants don’t necessarily have to apply for loans. Shopify’s machine learning models identify eligible merchants based on their previous sales history and store performance, according to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Solmaz Shahalizadeh, vice president of data science and engineering, commerce intelligence at Shopify.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> If a merchant accepts a pre-approved offer, they can generally receive funding in 2 to 5 business days.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the milestone is significant, I was especially intrigued by the model by which Shopify lends money to its merchants. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is intentional about using machine learning and AI “to make sure offers are based on factors different from any other in the financial industry,” Shahalizadeh said. “We don’t ask for a business plan. Our models see the business performance and it’s potential and makes an offer based on that.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We use 70 million data points to understand larger trends across the platform for merchants, and can see they are growing before they even can so we can preemptively offer them,” she added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kaz Nejatian, vice president of merchant services at Shopify, emphasizes that Shopify Capital does not lend in the manner of traditional banks by charging interest on loans.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our funding is designed to work off sales. If you don’t sell anything, we don’t get paid back until you make sales,” N</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ejatian said. “It’s</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a highly merchant aligned form of funding designed to fund the type of people banks and VCs won’t fund.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company’s model also aims to eliminate any biases that exist in the current financial system, when it comes to educational background, ethnicity, race or gender, he added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For N</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ejatian, it’s also personal. His mother is a Shopify merchant who herself struggled with getting capital herself last year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our goal is to reduce barriers to entrepreneurship by offering access to funds,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As part of that effort, Shopify </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Capital has increased the maximum amount of funding to $2 million. Previously, it granted funds ranging from $200 to $1 million.</span></p>
<p>Shopify offers two types of funding &#8211; merchant cash advances and loans. Shopify Capital charges a fixed fee (factor rate) on its financings.</p>
<p>On a merchant cash advance for example, it purchases $10,000 of a merchant’s future receivables in exchange for a promise to remit $10,900 of their future sales. The $900 is the amount it charges for the financing, and is repaid by a merchant’s daily remittances on days they make sales.</p>
<p>On its loans, it also applies a similar fixed fee to get a total repayment number, which is repaid via daily payments and milestone payments.</p>
<p>Simply put, the fixed fee that it charges is how Shopify earns money in exchange for funding our merchants. This fee, plus the amount advanced, are returned to the company over the life of a financing via daily remittance payments.</p>
<p>Says the company: &#8220;By charging a fixed fee, a merchant is able to understand exactly how much they’ll be expected to repay, before they take financing from Shopify Capital. These amounts don’t change over the life of a financing.”</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over time, Shopify plans to continually improve the machine learning algorithm behind Capital, making its predictive model “even smarter,” Shahalizadeh said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our model allows us to predict merchants&#8217; minimum sales with 90% accuracy while helping us make more proactive, pre-qualified offers as quickly as possible,” she added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shopify merchant Steven Borrelli, Founder of CUTS, says that when he was looking for funding as a newer business, he ran into the challenge of most traditional banks and lenders wanting to see that he had been in business for several years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CUTS started with getting $2,000 in funding from Shopify Capital. Over the last three years, it has grown into a business with sales “in the tens of millions.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We found Shopify Capital to be so valuable that we’ve returned for 10 rounds of funding. Our most recent round of Shopify Capital was $1 million,” he said. “So far we’ve used the funding for expanding our product line and growing our inventory.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/how-shopify-aims-to-level-the-playing-field-with-its-machine-learning-driven-model-of-lending/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145029</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revel launches an all-electric, rideshare service with a fleet of 50 Teslas</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/revel-launches-an-all-electric-rideshare-service-with-a-fleet-of-50-teslas/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/revel-launches-an-all-electric-rideshare-service-with-a-fleet-of-50-teslas/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:36:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rideshare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla Model Y]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Revel started out in 2018 with shared, dockless e-mopeds in Brooklyn, which later expanded to  Queens, Manhattan, the Bronx and a handful of other U.S. cities. This year, the company launched a monthly e-bike subscription in New York City and announced plans to build an electric vehicle charging hub in Bed-Stuy. Now, Revel is introducing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Revel started out in 2018 with shared, dockless e-mopeds in Brooklyn, which later expanded to  Queens, Manhattan, the Bronx and a handful of other U.S. cities. This year, the company launched a monthly e-bike subscription in New York City and announced plans to build an electric vehicle charging hub in Bed-Stuy. Now, Revel is introducing an all-electric — and all-Tesla — rideshare service in Manhattan.</p>
<p class="p1">What once seemed like a company with an identity crisis dabbling at random with different forms of mobility is starting to come together as a calculated strategy to own the electrification infrastructure of cities, starting with NYC. This has been founder and CEO Frank Reig’s war cry from the start.</p>
<p class="p1">“From day one, our mission has been to electrify cities,” Reig told TechCrunch. “We do that by providing electric transportation options needed in cities, as well as building the electric vehicle infrastructure needed to make that happen.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p class="p1">The new rideshare venture, which will launch in late May with a fleet of 50 Revel-branded Tesla Model Ys, is the natural next step in the process of working towards “electrifying every single trip in a city,” says Reig. Customers will be able to access ride-hailing services with the same app used to book e-mopeds. The launch will begin in a zone below 42nd Street, and will expand to additional neighborhoods based on demand and data from the initial phase, according to the company.</p>
<p class="p1">Revel’s rideshare launch is taking a similar approach to its initial moped launch three years ago, starting in a small area and slowly growing towards an overall goal of serving the entire city, according to co-founder Paul Suhey.</p>
<p class="p1">The company is still in the application process to become an approved operator with NYC’s Taxi &amp; Limousine Commission. Revel’s initial application was approved, but there are a few more steps to acquiring a fully issued license.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">“I think one reason we’re even coming out with this right now instead of waiting until everything is officially licensed and ready to go is because we’re employing drivers,” Suhey told TechCrunch. “When it comes to employing drivers, we need to get the word out. We need to be able to recruit and retain drivers now.”</p>
<p class="p1">Revel’s customer rates will be on par with competitors like Uber and Lyft, Reig says, but rather than relying on gig economy workers, the company intends to hire all of its drivers.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">“For the same price, you’re able to get into a fully electric vehicle with a company that actually employs New Yorkers and doesn’t push all the insurance risk and asset depreciation onto New York City residents just trying to make a living,” said Reig.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2KXXQ0el6i"><p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/micromobilitys-next-big-business-is-software-not-vehicles/">Micromobility&#8217;s next big business is software, not vehicles</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Micromobility&#8217;s next big business is software, not vehicles&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/micromobilitys-next-big-business-is-software-not-vehicles/embed/#?secret=2KXXQ0el6i" data-secret="2KXXQ0el6i" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p class="p1">Paying workers is not just altruism for Revel. It makes more sense to employ drivers because the company needs to own the Teslas, in large part so they can be built to Revel&#8217;s specifications. The Model Ys will be painted &#8220;Revel-blue&#8221; and will include a touchscreen to control cabin conditions like temperature and music. The front passenger seat of the vehicles will be removed to both adhere to Covid-19 distancing guidelines and to allow riders to stretch their legs.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">But more importantly, Revel learned a valuable lesson from the $200 million PR campaign from the likes of Uber, Lyft and Postmates to lobby Californians to vote for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/07/human-capital-the-gig-economy-in-a-post-prop-22-world/"><span class="s1">Proposition 22</span></a>, a ballot initiative which would make the app-based companies exempt from treating workers as employees with benefits. The initiative passed, but Reig is of the opinion that that money could have gone towards attracting and maintaining a solid workforce, rather than constantly trying to fill the funnel of drivers with a disillusioned labor pool. <span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">“There’s also a safety piece when you’re talking about a fleet,” said Reig. “Because it’s our fleet, we’re able to understand exactly the acceleration, the speed and the braking of the car at all times. Every single driver that we employ and train will be getting safety scores at the end of every shift so they can improve their driving. So now, we’re able to lower insurance costs and liabilities.”</p>
<p class="p1">As cities electrify, Revel wants to be the one scaffolding the business models going forward. Offering up a ride-hail is not just about building out a new business line. It’s also about accelerating the production of the company’s charging business. Revel&#8217;s trying to establish an electric monopoly while solving for the chicken-and-egg problem of prospective EV buyers who would buy electric if only there were charging stations and planners who would build EV infrastructure if only more people were buying EVs.</p>
<p class="p1">“Everything that we do as a company is about trying to drive EV adoption and access to electric mobility in cities,” said Suhey. “People think about that in terms of access to a different mode, whether that’s an electric car, an electric bike, a moped — we’re thinking more broadly about electrification in cities.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6EyQKdh5KU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/tamika-butler-remixs-tiffany-chu-and-revels-frank-reig-to-discuss-how-to-balance-equitability-and-profitability-at-tc-sessions-mobility/">Tamika Butler, Remix&#8217;s Tiffany Chu and Revel&#8217;s Frank Reig to discuss how to balance equitability and profitability at TC Sessions: Mobility</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tamika Butler, Remix&#8217;s Tiffany Chu and Revel&#8217;s Frank Reig to discuss how to balance equitability and profitability at TC Sessions: Mobility&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/tamika-butler-remixs-tiffany-chu-and-revels-frank-reig-to-discuss-how-to-balance-equitability-and-profitability-at-tc-sessions-mobility/embed/#?secret=6EyQKdh5KU" data-secret="6EyQKdh5KU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/revel-launches-an-all-electric-rideshare-service-with-a-fleet-of-50-teslas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144791</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: What’s the latest on DACA?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/dear-sophie-whats-the-latest-on-daca/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/dear-sophie-whats-the-latest-on-daca/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daca]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Labor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144761</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My company is looking to hire a very talented data infrastructure engineer who is undocumented. She has never applied for DACA before. What is the latest on DACA? What can we do to support her?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/dear-sophie-how-can-i-get-my-startup-off-the-ground-and-visit-the-us/">Dear Sophie: How can I get my startup off the ground and visit the US?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/dear-sophie-how-can-i-get-an-h-1b-without-the-lottery/">Dear Sophie: How can I get an H-1B without the lottery?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>Extra Crunch members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Dear Sophie,</strong></p>
<p><strong>My company is looking to hire a very talented data infrastructure engineer who is undocumented. </strong><strong>She has never applied for DACA before. </strong></p>
<p><strong>What is the latest on DACA? What can we do to support her?</strong></p>
<p><strong>—Multicultural in Milpitas</strong></p>
<p>Dear Multicultural,</p>
<p>Thank you for your questions and for supporting your prospective new Dreamer hire in her effort to obtain Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA). Take a listen to the <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/068-update-on-daca/">podcast episode</a> in which my colleagues Anita Koumriqian, my law partner who is an expert in family immigration law, and Cori Farooqi, an associate attorney in our family immigration team, provide an update on all things DACA.</p>
<h2>What’s the latest on DACA?</h2>
<p>In good news for many in the United States, the DACA program has largely returned to what it was when the Obama administration created it through an executive order in 2012. At the end of last year, a federal judge ordered U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) to accept and adjudicate new DACA applications, which had stopped in September 2017 when the previous administration announced it was ending DACA.</p>
<p>Moreover, President Joe Biden issued a memorandum on his first day in office stating that the secretary of Homeland Security, who oversees USCIS, should “fortify and preserve DACA.”</p>
<p>Your company can support an undocumented engineer by offering to pay for the services of an immigration attorney to assist her with filing applications for DACA and an <a href="https://www.uscis.gov/green-card/green-card-processes-and-procedures/employment-authorization-document">employment authorization document</a> (EAD), also known as a work permit. It may take several months for her applications to be processed. The approvals will allow her to be legally hired in the United States.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100312" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100312" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2100312" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg" alt="A composite image of immigration law attorney Sophie Alcorn in front of a background with a TechCrunch logo." width="1024" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=1536,1013 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Joanna Buniak / <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sophie Alcorn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<h2>What are the DACA requirements?<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/dear-sophie-whats-the-latest-on-daca/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144761</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Botpress nabs $15M Series A to help developers build conversational apps</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/botpress-nabs-15m-series-a-to-help-developers-build-conversational-apps/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/botpress-nabs-15m-series-a-to-help-developers-build-conversational-apps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Botpress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chat bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conversational AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Decibel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145002</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Botpress, a Montreal-based early stage startup, wants to make it easier for developers to build conversational-based apps, meaning humans interact with the app by speaking instead of typing, clicking or tapping. Today it announced an $15 million Series A from Decibel and Inovia Capital. &#8220;We&#8217;re trying to bring human-level digital assistance to the masses, and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://botpress.com/">Botpress</a>, a Montreal-based early stage startup, wants to make it easier for developers to build conversational-based apps, meaning humans interact with the app by speaking instead of typing, clicking or tapping. Today it announced an $15 million Series A from Decibel and Inovia Capital.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re trying to bring human-level digital assistance to the masses, and we do that by giving developers the tools they need to build conversational AI applications, so essentially conversational AI. [&#8230;] It&#8217;s a new way to build and consume software by using human language as a user interface instead of using traditional graphical user interfaces,&#8221; Botpress founder and CEO Sylvain Perron told me.</p>
<p>The company has created an open source toolkit to help developers remove some of the complexity associated with creating these applications. &#8220;Developers choose us because we provide the right tools to build conversational AI without changing the normal workflow of building software,&#8221; Perron explained.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Several years ago, Perron was trying to create a bot application and he just couldn&#8217;t find any good guidance to help him, so he decided to build a solution. He released the first version of that tool in 2017 and today he has more than 100,000 developers using the open source tool kit worldwide including a bunch of Fortune 500 companies.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jliG6EGsHY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/moveworks-expands-it-chatbot-platform-to-encompass-entire-organization/">Moveworks expands IT chatbot platform to encompass entire organization</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Moveworks expands IT chatbot platform to encompass entire organization&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/moveworks-expands-it-chatbot-platform-to-encompass-entire-organization/embed/#?secret=jliG6EGsHY" data-secret="jliG6EGsHY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Jon Sakoda who is leading the investment at Decibel says that the company is turning some of that enterprise interest into a business supporting those companies. &#8220;Today, we do have a commercial open source offering, which a lot of companies already pay for, but as I think you&#8217;ve seen in this current wave of successful open source companies, there&#8217;s always a lot of demand for a cloud product. And I think that this financing clearly allows Botpress to invest in building a turnkey cloud offering,&#8221; Sakoda says.</p>
<p>He says that what impresses him about Botpress is that developers can build a bot in less than an hour on a laptop, but having a cloud product will remove one more layer of complexity around deploying and scaling the bot in production.</p>
<p>The company, which has offices in Montreal and Quebec City (when they actually go to the office again), currently has 25 employees. The plan is to triple the team size over the next year as they put the investment to work. As they do this, Perron says that diversity and inclusion is a key goal in hiring.</p>
<p>&#8220;In our discussions, we want to make sure that we are a very inclusive company as we scale, especially scaling at this pace it&#8217;s very easy to [&#8230;] fall into non inclusive ways, so that&#8217;s very top of mind for us, and we&#8217;re putting significant effort into making sure that we&#8217;re doing this right,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The company has been remote from its early days, and had just opened an office in Quebec City when the pandemic hit so they haven&#8217;t had much opportunity to use it. He expects to have a hybrid approach when they are allowed back in the office, but it will be up to employees whether they come in or not.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TKTNxvikIh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/12/chatbots-spotlight-machine-learnings-trillion-dollar-potential/">Chatbots spotlight machine learning&#8217;s trillion-dollar potential</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chatbots spotlight machine learning&#8217;s trillion-dollar potential&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/12/chatbots-spotlight-machine-learnings-trillion-dollar-potential/embed/#?secret=TKTNxvikIh" data-secret="TKTNxvikIh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/botpress-nabs-15m-series-a-to-help-developers-build-conversational-apps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145002</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alchemy raises $80M at a $505M valuation to be the ‘AWS for blockchain’</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/alchemy-raises-80m-at-a-505m-valuation-to-be-the-aws-for-blockchain/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/alchemy-raises-80m-at-a-505m-valuation-to-be-the-aws-for-blockchain/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alchemy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Web Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chairman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charles schwab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CTO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dfj growth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[driver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emilie choi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jared Leto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jerry Yang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manchester united]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nikil Viswanathan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pantera capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reid Hoffman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stanford University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yahoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144727</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Blockchain developer platform Alchemy announced today it has raised $80 million in a Series B round of funding led by Coatue and Addition, Lee Fixel’s new fund. The company previously raised a total of $15.5 million, so the latest financing brings its total raised to $95.5 million since it launched in 2017. The latest round caught [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Blockchain developer platform <a href="https://www.alchemy.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alchemy</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> announced today it has raised $80 million in a Series B round of funding led by Coatue and Addition, </span><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/alexkonrad/2020/07/01/lee-fixel-raises-1-billion-fund-addition/?sh=15ddca7719a1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lee Fixel’s</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> new fund. The company previously raised a total of $15.5 million, so the latest financing brings its total raised to $95.5 million since it launched in 2017.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The latest round caught our attention for a few reasons. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">First, the company, which describes itself as the backend technology behind the blockchain industry, went from public launch to a $505 million valuation in a matter of just eight months. During that time, Alchemy says it powered over $30 billion in transactions for tens of millions of users all over the world. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">S</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">econd, the startup says it also already powering the </span><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-21/nfts-mushroom-into-billion-dollar-market-with-help-from-alchemy?srnd=premium"><span style="font-weight: 400;">majority of the NFT industry</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And finally, its investors in the round include a </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">high-profile mix of institutions and individuals such as DFJ Growth, K5 Global, the Chainsmokers, actor Jared Leto and the Glazer family (owners of the Tampa Bay Buccaneers and Manchester United). </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">They joined existing backers including Yahoo co-founder and former CEO Jerry Yang, Pantera Capital, Coinbase, SignalFire, Samsung, Stanford University, Google chairman and Stanford University President John L. Hennessy, Charles Schwab, LinkedIn co-founder Reid Hoffman and others.</span></p>
<p>Sources with inside knowledge of Alchemy’s operations tell TechCrunch that the company has already grown its business more than eightfold since it signed the Series B term sheet. They also said Alchemy had over $300 million of investor demand wanting to enter the round and is being inbounded to do another financing at &#8220;many times&#8221; the current valuation.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TechCrunch talked with Alchemy co-founders Nikil Viswanathan (CEO) and Joe </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lau (CTO) about the raise and their passion for the startup’s mission was clear. As is its explosive growth.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We realized that in order for space to thrive and build to its full potential, we needed to build a developer platform layer for blockchain,” Viswanathan told TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alchemy&#8217;s goal is to be the starting place for developers considering to build a product on top of a blockchain or mainstream blockchain applications. Its developer platform aims to remove the complexity and costs of building infrastructure while improving applications through “necessary” developer tools.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The startup powers a range of transactions across nearly every blockchain vertical, including financial institutions, exchanges, billion-dollar decentralized finance projects and multinational organizations such as UNICEF. It</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has also quickly become the technology behind every major NFT platform, including Makersplace, OpenSea, Nifty Gateway, SuperRare and CryptoPunks.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Every time you open DoorDash, you’re using Amazon’s infrastructure,” Lau said. “Every time you interact with an NFT, you’re using Alchemy. It’s being powered by Alchemy underneath the hood.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2144734 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Alchemy-Product-Centered-e1619565568800.png" alt="" width="3840" height="1977" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the pair would not provide hard revenue figures, the company – which operates as a SaaS business – says it increased its revenue by 600% in 2020.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For inside players, Alchemy’s efforts are paving the way for the whole industry.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The cryptoeconomy is innovating faster than any technological movement that came before it, and Alchemy has been a key driver of that,” said Coinbase President and COO Emilie Choi. “Alchemy enables developers to build the rich ecosystem of applications necessary for mainstream blockchain adoption.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pantera Capital’s Paul Veradittakit describes Alchemy as “the Amazon Web Services (AWS) of the blockchain industry” that is “enabling the vision of a decentralized web.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“While in Web 2.0, Microsoft, Apple and AWS are three of the most valuable companies in the world because they are the developer platform powering the computer and internet industries, Alchemy is primed to do the same for the blockchain,” he said.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OWncrpRmUe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/is-rising-usage-driving-cryptos-recent-price-boom/">Is rising usage driving crypto&#8217;s recent price boom?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Is rising usage driving crypto&#8217;s recent price boom?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/is-rising-usage-driving-cryptos-recent-price-boom/embed/#?secret=OWncrpRmUe" data-secret="OWncrpRmUe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company believes the comparison to AWS is fair, noting that: “Just as AWS provides the platform that powers Uber, Netflix and much of the technology industry, Alchemy powers infrastructure for many large players in the blockchain industry.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alchemy plans to use its new capital to expand its developer platform to new blockchains, fuel global expansion and to open new offices in the U.S. and globally. The startup is based in San Francisco and is planning to open an office in New York.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are going to use the funds</span> to support new chains with our developer platform,<span style="font-weight: 400;">” Viswanathan said. “We also expect to 5x the team this year.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But to be clear, Alchemy prides itself on being lean and mean.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We just went from 14 to 22 employees,” Lau said. “We have intentionally wanted to keep the team as small as possible.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The blockchain space has been the subject of increased investor interest as of late. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In March, </span><a href="http://www.blockfi.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">BlockFi</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which describes itself a financial services company for crypto market investors, announced it had closed on a massive </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/blockfi-lands-a-350m-series-d-at-3b-valuation-for-its-fast-growing-crypto-lending-platform/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$350 million Series D funding </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">that valued it at $3 billion. Also last month, </span><a href="https://www.chainalysis.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chainalysis</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a blockchain analysis company, revealed the close of $100 million in Series D financing, which doubled its valuation to over $2 billion.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8KlslIVLye"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/chainalysis-raises-100m-doubles-valuation-to-over-2b/">Crypto boom continues as Chainalysis raises $100M, doubles valuation to over $2B</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Crypto boom continues as Chainalysis raises $100M, doubles valuation to over $2B&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/chainalysis-raises-100m-doubles-valuation-to-over-2b/embed/#?secret=8KlslIVLye" data-secret="8KlslIVLye" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/alchemy-raises-80m-at-a-505m-valuation-to-be-the-aws-for-blockchain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144727</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here’s Samsung’s new flagship laptop series, the Galaxy Book Pro</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/heres-samsungs-new-flagship-laptop-the-galaxy-book-pro/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/heres-samsungs-new-flagship-laptop-the-galaxy-book-pro/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[galaxy book pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laptops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[samsung galaxy s iii]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144626</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Following the customary weeks of leaks, Samsung just announced a couple of new additions to its laptop line. The Galaxy Book Pro and Galaxy Book Pro 360 joined the hardware giant’s wide range of devices toward the high end &#8212; offering what can reasonably be categorized as the company’s take on the MacBook Pro. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Following the customary weeks of leaks, Samsung just announced a couple of new additions to its laptop line. The Galaxy Book Pro and Galaxy Book Pro 360 joined the hardware giant’s wide range of devices toward the high end &#8212; offering what can reasonably be categorized as the company’s take on the MacBook Pro.</p>
<p>The Windows machines continue the company’s push to blur some of the productivity lines between its Galaxy PC and mobile offerings, including a number of cross-device software offerings and, naturally, the inclusion of the S-Pen, which ships in the box with the Pro 360. As the name implies, the 360’s lid hinges in either direction, so it can double as a writing surface.</p>
<p>The thin and light design is probably the headline feature for Samsung. The Pro and Pro 360 measure 11.2 and 11.9 millimeters, respectively. Both feature an option of a 13.3 and 15.6-inch Super AMOLEDs. With a 1920 x 1080 resolution. That’s all powered by either a Core i5 or i7 11th-gen Intel processor, 8 or 16GB of RAM and up to 1TB of storage (512GB max on the Pro).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2144635" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2144635" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2144635" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Galaxy_Book_Pro_360_13inch_MysticBronze_WiFi_D9_S_Pen_210416093710.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Galaxy_Book_Pro_360_13inch_MysticBronze_WiFi_D9_S_Pen_210416093710.jpg 4000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Galaxy_Book_Pro_360_13inch_MysticBronze_WiFi_D9_S_Pen_210416093710.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Galaxy_Book_Pro_360_13inch_MysticBronze_WiFi_D9_S_Pen_210416093710.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Galaxy_Book_Pro_360_13inch_MysticBronze_WiFi_D9_S_Pen_210416093710.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Galaxy_Book_Pro_360_13inch_MysticBronze_WiFi_D9_S_Pen_210416093710.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Galaxy_Book_Pro_360_13inch_MysticBronze_WiFi_D9_S_Pen_210416093710.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Galaxy_Book_Pro_360_13inch_MysticBronze_WiFi_D9_S_Pen_210416093710.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Galaxy_Book_Pro_360_13inch_MysticBronze_WiFi_D9_S_Pen_210416093710.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2144635" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Samsung</p></div></p>
<p>There are also options for LTE and 5G versions (depending on market availability). That will almost certainly have a direct impact on the battery, which the company rates as “all-day.” Both models sport 65W fast charging by way of the USB-C port. The keyboard mechanisms have been upgraded over previous models and the track pad is now 23% larger.</p>
<p>The systems go up for preorder today and start shipping May 14. The 13 and 15-inch versions of the Pro start at $1,000 and $1,100, respectively and the 360 runs $1,200 and $1,300.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mNWWhfPfS4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/15/extra-crunch-members-save-money-with-partner-perks-and-event-discounts/">Extra Crunch members save money with Partner Perks and event discounts</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Extra Crunch members save money with Partner Perks and event discounts&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/15/extra-crunch-members-save-money-with-partner-perks-and-event-discounts/embed/#?secret=mNWWhfPfS4" data-secret="mNWWhfPfS4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/heres-samsungs-new-flagship-laptop-the-galaxy-book-pro/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144626</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Netflix launches its shuffle feature, now called &#8216;Play Something,&#8217; to users worldwide</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/netflix-launches-its-shuffle-feature-now-called-play-something-to-users-worldwide/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/netflix-launches-its-shuffle-feature-now-called-play-something-to-users-worldwide/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144920</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Netflix today is officially launching a feature that will make it easier to find something to watch when you&#8217;re stuck browsing and unable to make a decision. The service is introducing a tool called &#8220;Play Something&#8221; to users worldwide &#8212; the final iteration that &#8220;shuffle&#8221; feature you may have already seen during Netflix&#8217;s tests over [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Netflix today is officially launching a feature that will make it easier to find something to watch when you&#8217;re stuck browsing and unable to make a decision. The service is introducing a tool called &#8220;Play Something&#8221; to users worldwide &#8212; the final iteration that &#8220;shuffle&#8221; feature you may have already seen during Netflix&#8217;s tests over the past year. When selected, Netflix will play another show or movie it thinks you&#8217;ll like, based on your interests and prior viewing behavior.</p>
<p>In other words, it won&#8217;t play random content, but will instead bring up either a movie or show you&#8217;re already watching, a series or movie on your list, an unfinished series or movie you may want to revisit, or a brand new series or film that Netflix&#8217;s personalization algorithms suggest.</p>
<p>The feature has been in testing under various names and styles for some time. A year ago, the feature was called <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/18/netflix-test-puts-a-shuffle-play-button-right-on-your-home-screen/">Shuffle Play</a>, for example. During its Q4 earnings, Netflix said the shuffle feature <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/netflixs-shuffle-play-feature-will-roll-out-to-all-users-worldwide-this-year/">would roll out</a> to its worldwide users sometime in the first half of 2021, describing it as a way for users to &#8220;instantly watch a title chosen just for them.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For today&#8217;s launch, not much has changed beyond the feature&#8217;s name and style.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2144938" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2144938" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2144938" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US_NETFLIX_TV_Comp_00003-1.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US_NETFLIX_TV_Comp_00003-1.png 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US_NETFLIX_TV_Comp_00003-1.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US_NETFLIX_TV_Comp_00003-1.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US_NETFLIX_TV_Comp_00003-1.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US_NETFLIX_TV_Comp_00003-1.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US_NETFLIX_TV_Comp_00003-1.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US_NETFLIX_TV_Comp_00003-1.png?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US_NETFLIX_TV_Comp_00003-1.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2144938" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Netflix</p></div></p>
<p>The new option can be found on Netflix&#8217;s TV app underneath your profile name, on the navigation menu to the left of your screen and on the tenth row on your Netflix homepage &#8212; a location that hopes to find users after they&#8217;ve been scrolling for some time without landing on anything they want to watch.</p>
<p>Netflix users with screen-readers can use Text-to-Speech (TTS) to use Play Something, the company notes.</p>
<p>While Netflix is always testing features that make it easier for users to jump from browsing to watching, this feature in particular comes at a time when Netflix is seeing slower subscriber growth &#8212; something <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/netflix-q1-2021/">it&#8217;s blaming on the lighter content slate</a> due to COVID. But the reality is that Netflix is no longer the only streamer in town. And some of the content it has shipped has been weak, as evident in the growing list of <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/netflix-cancelations-2021-canceled-shows-tv-series-1558429">cancellations</a>. It has also lost t<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/nielsen-says-the-office-was-the-most-popular-streaming-series-of-2020/">op titles like &#8220;The Office&#8221;</a> to rivals as rights&#8217; holders have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/25/the-office-leaving-netflix-why-are-you-the-way-that-you-are/">pulled their content</a> back to their own new services.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2144940" style="width: 456px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2144940" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2144940" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US-Play-Something-Android-2.png?w=446" alt="" width="446" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US-Play-Something-Android-2.png 5829w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US-Play-Something-Android-2.png?resize=98,150 98w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US-Play-Something-Android-2.png?resize=197,300 197w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US-Play-Something-Android-2.png?resize=768,1171 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US-Play-Something-Android-2.png?resize=446,680 446w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US-Play-Something-Android-2.png?resize=1008,1536 1008w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US-Play-Something-Android-2.png?resize=1343,2048 1343w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/US-Play-Something-Android-2.png?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 446px) 100vw, 446px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2144940" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Netflix</p></div></p>
<p>For those reasons, too, Netflix needs a way to addict its current user base to what&#8217;s available in its existing catalog before they churn out.</p>
<p>The new Play Something feature is available today on Netflix on TVs, and will soon begin testing on mobile devices, starting with Android.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/netflix-launches-its-shuffle-feature-now-called-play-something-to-users-worldwide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144920</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In a room with no smart speaker, Alexa can&#8217;t hear you scream</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/in-a-room-with-no-smart-speaker-alexa-cant-hear-you-scream/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/in-a-room-with-no-smart-speaker-alexa-cant-hear-you-scream/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reddit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144614</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. For this week’s deep dive Natasha and Alex and Danny and Chris dove into the world of audio. Sure, you&#8217;ve heard of Clubhouse, but there&#8217;s lots more going on than just a single app&#8217;s cultural rise. So from the biggest companies to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/bffbe21b-426c-4274-8d5a-04c508a294fd?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>For this week’s deep dive <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> and<a href="https://twitter.com/alex"> Alex</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/dannycrichton">Danny</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/cgates123">Chris</a> dove into the world of audio. Sure, you&#8217;ve heard of Clubhouse, but there&#8217;s lots more going on than just a single app&#8217;s cultural rise. So from the biggest companies to niche startups, we compiled all the recent audio news into a single show for all our delectation.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the rundown:</p>
<ul>
<li>Facebook is building a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/facebook-invests-in-audio-with-short-form-soundbites-feature-podcast-support-and-a-clubhouse-clone/">number of audio products</a>, including a Clubhouse clone and a short-form audio service that we think could be neat.</li>
<li>Reddit is also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/reddit-unveils-its-clubhouse-clone-reddit-talk/">building a Clubhouse-like service</a>, and Alex is excited about it.</li>
<li>It&#8217;s not just the established social networks that are trying out live audio. Peanut, a social networking app for women, added live audio &#8220;Pods&#8221; to its platform. It kicked off a conversation on what it takes to win this market, and what&#8217;s a smart versus silly bet.</li>
<li>While a drop in downloads doesn&#8217;t necessarily mean a drop in active users, it&#8217;s worth pointing out that Clubhouse&#8217;s monthly downloads dropped 72% in March. Where is that gosh darn Android app?</li>
<li>And Alex explained <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/25/22402183/clubhouse-partnering-nfl-draft-week-programming">why the Clubhouse-NFL deal</a> matters for the company, as it could molt into something more akin to a platform over time.</li>
<li>Danny explained how Apple and Spotify are building paid podcast services &#8212; more <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/apple-unveils-podcast-subscriptions-and-a-redesigned-apple-podcasts-app/">here</a>, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/spotify-launches-paid-podcasts-through-new-anchor-feature/">here</a>, respectively &#8212; and we have thoughts about which service is being more fair with the money. Natasha tied in how sentiment around the creator economy might be driving some of these individual-friendly business models.</li>
<li>Alex brought up TWiT&#8217;s <a href="https://twit.tv/subscribe">new business model</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>All told there&#8217;s quite a lot of excitement around the spoken word. Which is good as Equity is a podcast? Right?</p>
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 AM PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts!</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/in-a-room-with-no-smart-speaker-alexa-cant-hear-you-scream/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144614</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gamified connecting rowing machine maker Ergatta raises $30M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/gamified-connecting-rowing-machine-maker-ergatta-raises-30m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/gamified-connecting-rowing-machine-maker-ergatta-raises-30m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advanced Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[connected fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ergatta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exercise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144372</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the world takes its first steps back to relative normalcy, there remains a major question mark around how profoundly our day-to-day is going to be changed for good. Nowhere does that question loom larger than fitness. Connected home machines have undergone a seismic shift over the past year, but once gyms safely reopen, how [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As the world takes its first steps back to relative normalcy, there remains a major question mark around how profoundly our day-to-day is going to be changed for good. Nowhere does that question loom larger than fitness. Connected home machines have undergone a seismic shift over the past year, but once gyms safely reopen, how much will that industry peter out?</p>
<p>The likeliest answer is that there will be some leveling off in the long run. However, investors still see a lot of growth potential in the category, extending beyond now-major players like Peloton, Mirror and Tonal. New York-based <a href="https://ergatta.com/">Ergatta</a> is the latest to receive some of that windfall, announcing a $30 million Series A this morning.</p>
<p>This latest round &#8212; led by Advanced Venture Partners with participation from Greycroft, Fifth Wall, Gaingels and Hans Tung (GGV) &#8212; brings the company’s total funding up to $35 million, including a $5 million seed round raised in July of last year. Ergatta says the funding will go toward developing new content, competition and social features for its platform.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company’s primary hardware is a rowing machine. Built out of cherry wood in the U.S., the machine certainly offers a warmer aesthetic than a lot of home workout equipment. It’s a nice touch for people who don’t want a big, industrial-looking piece of equipment in their bedroom. Content-wise, the platform is built around a gamified exercise content. It’s a similar approach to the one we’ve seen from the earlier-stage, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/pivoting-to-home-fitness-aviron-offers-gamified-rowing-machines/">YC-backed Aviron</a>.</p>
<p>“We are creating a new paradigm for digital fitness content that leverages games and competition, rather than instructors,” co-founder and CEO Tom Aulet said in a press release tied to the news. “Our mission is to bring daily fitness within reach for our members by putting the individual in control and creating compelling, personalized programming that adapts to their fitness level, driving consistent fitness behavior over time.”</p>
<p>The $2,200 Ergatta Rower features a touchscreen display that offers up competitions with other users and goal-driven workouts.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ke6WQbthvP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1-future/">Can Tonal become the luxury fitness market champion?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Can Tonal become the luxury fitness market champion?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1-future/embed/#?secret=Ke6WQbthvP" data-secret="Ke6WQbthvP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/gamified-connecting-rowing-machine-maker-ergatta-raises-30m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144372</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kaia Health grabs $75M on surging interest in its virtual therapies for chronic pain and COPD</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/kaia-health-grabs-75m-on-surging-interest-in-its-virtual-therapies-for-chronic-pain-and-copd/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/kaia-health-grabs-75m-on-surging-interest-in-its-virtual-therapies-for-chronic-pain-and-copd/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 14:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Balderton Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chronic disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chronic pain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eurazeo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heartcore Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kaia Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile devices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[munich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Omada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Optum Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physical therapy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telehealth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telemedicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2143157</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New York headquartered Kaia Health, which offers AI-assisted digital therapies via a mobile app for chronic pain related to musculoskeletal (MSK) disorders and for Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD), has raised a $75 million Series C. The round was led by an unnamed leading growth equity fund with support from existing investors, including Optum Ventures, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">New York headquartered <a href="https://www.kaiahealth.com">Kaia Health</a>, which offers AI-assisted digital therapies via a mobile app for chronic pain related to musculoskeletal (MSK) disorders and for Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD), has raised a $75 million Series C.</p>
<p>The round was led by an unnamed leading growth equity fund with support from existing investors, including Optum Ventures, Eurazeo, 3VC, Balderton Capital, Heartcore Capital, Symphony Ventures (golfer Rory McIlroy&#8217;s investment vehicle), and A Round Capital.</p>
<p>The funding fast-follows a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/18/kaia-health-gets-26m-to-show-it-can-do-more-with-digital-therapeutics/">$26M Series B</a> closed last summer. The pandemic has accelerated the uptake of telemedicine, generally &#8212; and Kaia has, unsurprisingly, seen a particular surge of interest in its virtual treatments.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>After all, DIY home working set-ups are unlikely to have done much good for the average information worker&#8217;s back in the pandemic-struck year. Kaia&#8217;s real-time feedback generating motion coach is also able to offer treatment for neck, hip, knee, shoulder, hand/wrist, and foot/ankle pain.</p>
<p>A digital health solution may have been the only lockdown-friendly option for treating conditions considered &#8216;elective care&#8217; during COVID-19 &#8212; meaning suffers of chronic pain may have faced restrictions on accessing physical healthcare provision like in-person physiotherapy. Kaia says it grew its business book 600% in 2020.</p>
<p>Given the U.S. healthcare sales cycle is heavily focused on January onboarding of new medical benefits by employers &#8212; who are key customers for Kaia in the market, where it now has around 50 employer and health plan clients &#8212; it&#8217;s expecting another big onboarding bump next January. And while it hadn&#8217;t been looking to raise again so soon after the Series B, doing so was &#8220;a very easy process&#8221;, says co-founder and CEO Konstantin Mehl.</p>
<p>&#8220;We actually planned to start the raise in the end of this year and then the pandemic happened and of course we had a huge boost because the healthcare system was pretty much shut down for in person elected treatments and chronic diseases are considered to be elected treatments which I think is a bit of a mistake.</p>
<p>&#8220;The thing is that the big b2b partners they are really scared that they will have this big backlog of surgical interventions that are very expensive&#8230; Pre-pandemic I think 20% of employers in the US were even interested in offering a digital therapy and then that changed to 100% immediately. So that was a big boost,&#8221; he goes on. &#8220;The other thing is that our market got really hot. We don&#8217;t really need the money right now but we met these investors and it was a very easy process.&#8221;</p>
<p>Kaia says that globally its digital MSK platform is accessible to 60M patients &#8212; which it claims makes it by far the biggest player in the space in terms of covered lives. (Other startups in the space include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/hinge-healthy-d/">Hinge Health</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/16/tackling-the-190-billion-physical-therapy-market-sword-health-raises-8-million-from-khosla-ventures/">Sword Health</a> which are both also focused on MSK; and Physera, a virtual physical therapy provider that was <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/05/19/omada-health-raises-57-million-acquires-physera-for-30-million.html">acquired by Omada last year</a>.)</p>
<p>The plan for Kaia&#8217;s (unexpectedly rapid) funding boost is &#8220;to be much more aggressive in building out our commercial team&#8221;, Mehl tells TechCrunch. &#8220;We are very proud of being a product focused company but it also gets a bit stupid at the point where you just need to bring the product in front of the relevant customer so we are investing a lot in that and also in computer vision because it&#8217;s still our USP.&#8221;</p>
<p>Kaia&#8217;s digital therapies rely on using computer vision to digitize proven treatments so they can be delivered outside traditional healthcare environments, with the app helping patients perform exercises correctly by themselves.</p>
<p>The user only needs a smartphone or tablet with a camera for the app to do real-time, posture-tracking and provide feedback. No wearables are required. Although Kaia is researching how 3D data from depth-sensing cameras which are now being embedded in higher end mobile devices may further feed the accuracy of its body tracking models.</p>
<p>&#8220;We basically can have the same correction functionality in your home that you have can have with a PT [personal trainer],&#8221; says Mehl. &#8220;We want to invest a lot more in computer vision and build out that team so we can also do that more aggressively now [with the Series C funding] which is cool.&#8221;</p>
<p>Kaia has started to use motion-tracking in another way in its patient-facing chronic pain app &#8212; as a way to track progress. So as well as asking patients to quantify their pain (which is a subjective measure) it can have an objective biomarker alongside patients&#8217; pain assessments by getting them to do regular tests that track their body movements.</p>
<p>&#8220;We started to use motion-tracking besides the correction-tracking functionality also as a biomarker. So we basically can measure your body functionality. Now we can, for example, see which body parts are less flexible and that&#8217;s how we can measure the disease progression, instead of asking you how is the pain level today,&#8221; he explains. &#8220;Pain is the number one cause for work disability and the reason is because your body functionality decreases so if we can measure that correctly then we can also escalate it to the right speciality doctor, for example.&#8221;</p>
<p>Kaia can also quantify the progress of COPD patients in a similar way &#8212; by tracking them performing a sit-down, stand-up test.</p>
<p>Care for COPD has had a particular imperative during the pandemic as people with the chronic inflammatory lung disease who catch COVID-19 have the highest mortality rate among COVID-19-infected patients, per Mehl.</p>
<p>At the same time, pulmonary rehabilitation centers have been shut down during the pandemic because of the risk of infection to patients. So, once again, Kaia&#8217;s app has provided an alternative for suffers of chronic conditions to continue their rehab at home.</p>
<p>In the US Kaia focuses on activation rate as a percentage of the employer population &#8212; and Mehl says this stands between 5%-10%, depending on how the app is communicated to potential users. &#8220;We also had a company that had 15% of their population active it one year but you always have these outliers,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p>Looking ahead to the coming 12 months, he says he expects to be able to grow revenue 5x-10x as a number of bigger partnerships kick in.</p>
<p>In Germany, where Kaia plans to start prescribing its app (via doctors), he&#8217;s hopeful they&#8217;ll be able to get 10,000 prescriptions done over the same period, once it has approval to do so under a national reimbursement system.</p>
<h2>Plugging Kaia into wider healthcare provision</h2>
<p>Integrating into a wider care pathway by being able to loop in healthcare providers where appropriate has been a big recent focus for Kaia.</p>
<p>In February it kicked off a major integration of its patient-facing MSK therapy/pain-management app with a referral system that plugs into services offered by other healthcare providers &#8212; using an escalation algorithm and screening and triage system, which it calls Kaia Gateway &#8212; to identify patients at risk of needing more invasive or intense treatment than the digital therapies its app can provide. It&#8217;s working with a number of premium partners for this referral path (i.e. within an employer or health plan’s ecosystem).</p>
<p>Its partners can provide additional medical services to relevant patients, both general and specialty care solutions, including disease management programs, PT, telemedicine, care navigation, and expert medical opinion services. Partners also get access to detailed treatment history on referred patients from Kaia, including via APIs.</p>
<p>&#8220;Besides being just an app-based therapy we want to expand more down the treatment path,&#8221; explains Mehl. &#8220;And also work with external medical providers &#8212; doctors etc &#8212; and bring our users at the right point to the right doctor to prevent any deterioration in pain that we cannot treat in the app. I think that brings a lot of trust, also, to the app.</p>
<p>&#8220;Because I think what&#8217;s happening now is that there&#8217;s so many digital therapies popping up everywhere. And one thing that is happening in the beginning when you&#8217;re small, like us three years ago, we just offered this app and said we don&#8217;t really know what&#8217;s happening before or after&#8230; Now we really want to integrate.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We have some cool partnerships coming up in the U.S. &#8212; partner with bigger medical providers that have thousands of medical providers on their payroll,&#8221; he goes on. &#8220;And then integrate with them so we can optimize the full treatment path. Because then the patients can really feel safe and say hey they don&#8217;t keep me in the app-based therapy when they know I should actually see somebody else because it&#8217;s not the best care anymore.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We have this platform approach but then we saw now it really makes sense to go deeper in these two diseases,&#8221; Mehl adds. &#8220;We start with our chronic pain approach in the U.S. and say we really want to go down the treatment path. And because the main problem is if people then start to be frustrated in our app and say I need something else and then they get back to this, for example, pain killers, opioids, surgery, cycle, and then they&#8217;re back in the system where we actually wanted to help them getting out of it so that&#8217;s why we say it&#8217;s not really possible to not integrate with healthcare professionals.</p>
<p>&#8220;You need to integrate them. If not you cannot always offer best care and then the patients realize at one point this app is not enough &#8212; but I also don&#8217;t get directed to a medical professional who could offer a new diagnosis or a different prescription. And then your trust is lost.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The other point is when you think about different levels of chronification, because we&#8217;re so scalable we can catch people much earlier in their chronification journey when the disease is still reversible. And even if our app is still the best treatment it helps to get an additional medical professional involvement to validate a diagnosis &#8212; or to just talk with a patient so that they really know that they&#8217;re safe here. So just reassuring, motivation and also diagnosis, to really say okay just to be sure we should make this diagnosis just to be sure you are getting best care. So I think that&#8217;s a huge product task and operational task for us.&#8221;</p>
<p>Kaia is starting by doing case referrals manually in-house &#8212; by setting up a medical case review team, staffed by doctors and therapies it employs &#8212; aided by a triage system that automatically flags patients for the team to review. But Mehl hopes this process will be increasingly assisted by AI.</p>
<p>&#8220;We assume yellow flags from what they told us in the entry test or from their exercise feedback or therapy feedback. Or from the interactions they have with their motivational coaches,&#8221; he explains of how the case review system works now. &#8220;Then [the case review team] has a look at them and decides if they should see an external medical provider partner and at what time.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Over time this should get more and more automated,&#8221; he adds. &#8220;We hope that we can make this better and better with machine learning over time and show that we can optimize the treatment path much better than just having this manual oversight. And that&#8217;s a huge challenge. If you think about what you need to do to get there I think it will define our product roadmap for years&#8230; But that&#8217;s also where the most value is to increase the quality of care. If not you just have siloed solutions everywhere&#8230; and the patient suffers because the treatment path is torn apart and it doesn&#8217;t feel like one thing.</p>
<p>&#8220;We will always need this clinical oversight. But where we can use machine learning is to help these medical professionals to look at the right patients at the right time. Because they cannot look at everybody all the time so there needs to be some filtering. And I think that filtering &#8212; or that triage &#8212; that can be really done by machine learning.&#8221;</p>
<p>Would Kaia ever consider becoming a healthcare provider itself? Combining a telemedicine service with some digitally delivered treatments is something that Sweden&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/25/kry-launches-free-service-for-doctors-to-do-video-consultations-during-covid-19-crisis/">Kry</a>, for example, has done &#8212; launching online cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) treatments in its home market back in 2018 while also offering a telehealth platform and running a full healthcare service in some markets.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ri9tansCpy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/25/kry-launches-free-service-for-doctors-to-do-video-consultations-during-covid-19-crisis/">Kry launches free service for doctors to do video consultations during COVID-19 crisis</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Kry launches free service for doctors to do video consultations during COVID-19 crisis&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/25/kry-launches-free-service-for-doctors-to-do-video-consultations-during-covid-19-crisis/embed/#?secret=Ri9tansCpy" data-secret="Ri9tansCpy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Mehl suggests not, arguing that telemedicine companies are by necessity generalists, since they are catering to &#8220;the top of the funnel&#8221;, handling and filtering patients with all sorts of complaints &#8212; which he says makes them less suited to focus deeply on catering to specific disease.</p>
<p>While, for Kaia, it&#8217;s deeply focused on building tech to treat a few specific diseases &#8212; and so, likewise, isn&#8217;t best suited to general medical service delivery. Partnering with medical service providers is therefore the obvious choice.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think about the patient journey and for the telemedicine companies&#8230; they might have some treatment paths integrated but they&#8217;re never as good as completely owning one chronic disease as we can be,&#8221; he says. &#8220;Most of chronic disease patients they just want to start a treatment because they talked with so many doctors. They want to find something that helps them and then at the right moment talk to the right medical professional. So that&#8217;s a difference in how telemedicine companies are doing it.</p>
<p>&#8220;The other question is how much of the medical provider job of the treatment path do we want to internalize? And we really are a tech company. We&#8217;re not very keen on becoming a medical provider. And we see that there are so many amazing medical providers in the landscape here &#8212; in different countries &#8212; that during COVID-19 had to become more digital, so it&#8217;s easy to partner with them, and why would we want to learn how to run a hospital where there are all these people who did it for decades and are really good at it, and we are really good at tech.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s really cool for the patient in the end. They know they get the best of both worlds and it&#8217;s optimized and ideally these offline medical providers get data from us so they can make better decisions &#8212; so they can also have a higher quality of decision-making because they have more data than just talking with a patient for two minutes. They can see our complete dashboard and how the patient progressed over time and everything &#8212; so the quality of decision-making gets higher.&#8221;</p>
<p>The U.S. overtook Europe as Kaia&#8217;s biggest market in recent years so it&#8217;s inexorably been focusing a lot of energy on serving its growing number of U.S. customers. The size of the addressable market in the U.S. is also massive, with ~100M chronic pain patients in the country, or around a third of the population.</p>
<p>But Kaia continues to develop its proposition in a number of European markets, including Germany which was where the business started. Mehl says its team in Munich is looking at how to make a recent reimbursement law for app-based health treatments will work for it in practice. It hasn&#8217;t yet obtained the necessary reimbursement code for doctors there to start prescribing its tech to their patients but it&#8217;s taking steps to change that.</p>
<p>At the same time, Mehl concedes that learning how to make doctors want to prescribe its app is an &#8220;open challenge&#8221; in the market.</p>
<p>&#8220;Some startups started doing it but &#8212; at scale &#8212; I still think there have to be some learning to be made to really scale it up,&#8221; he says of the German app prescriptions, adding that it&#8217;s preparing to hand in its application in relation to its COPD app which it will be bringing to market in Europe with a pharma partner.</p>
<p>&#8220;We also closed a partnership with a pharma company for Germany, UK and France to distribute our app through the pulmonologists &#8212; which is pretty cool. So we&#8217;re launching that partnership now,&#8221; he adds. &#8220;That will be exciting to see where the prescriptions start.&#8221;</p>
<p>Mehl professes himself a fan of Germany&#8217;s approach to digital healthcare &#8212; saying that it makes it easy to obtain a general reimbursement code which then gives the app-maker a year to prove any cost savings and deliver the care they say they do &#8212; couching that as a compromise between the &#8220;really long&#8221; process of getting approval for a medicine and the data-driven needs of startups where founders need to be able to show traction to get investment to build and grow a business in the first place.</p>
<p>&#8220;Healthcare&#8217;s already tough because you have to do clinical trials and it&#8217;s already a bit slower. So a longer approval process makes it even more difficult to launch something useful and I can see the UK, France, the Nordics bringing out some similar legislation to facilitate that,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p>&#8220;We expect in other European countries &#8212; and in other countries in generally, like Canada, Australia and in Asia too &#8212; that they update their regulation to cover digital therapies. And then that will be good because we will know how to get apps prescribed and we know the other way, like in the U.S., [i.e. without needing to go through a doctor first]&#8230; And so with our app being so scalable we could easily launch in these countries compared to other companies in the market that are more reliant on one specific healthcare system or on hardware or anything that limits the scalability.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="T3WbxyD0Az"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/18/kaia-health-gets-26m-to-show-it-can-do-more-with-digital-therapeutics/">Kaia Health gets $26M to show it can do more with digital therapeutics</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Kaia Health gets $26M to show it can do more with digital therapeutics&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/18/kaia-health-gets-26m-to-show-it-can-do-more-with-digital-therapeutics/embed/#?secret=T3WbxyD0Az" data-secret="T3WbxyD0Az" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RwhID5KvKQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/21/kaia-health-gets-10m-support-for-ai-powered-management-of-chronic-pain/">Kaia Health gets $10M support for AI-powered management of chronic pain</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Kaia Health gets $10M support for AI-powered management of chronic pain&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/21/kaia-health-gets-10m-support-for-ai-powered-management-of-chronic-pain/embed/#?secret=RwhID5KvKQ" data-secret="RwhID5KvKQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XtuXc3Y5VD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/31/leading-health-tech-vcs-on-how-covid-19-has-impacted-the-world-of-digital-health/">Leading VCs discuss how COVID-19 has impacted the world of digital health</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Leading VCs discuss how COVID-19 has impacted the world of digital health&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/31/leading-health-tech-vcs-on-how-covid-19-has-impacted-the-world-of-digital-health/embed/#?secret=XtuXc3Y5VD" data-secret="XtuXc3Y5VD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/kaia-health-grabs-75m-on-surging-interest-in-its-virtual-therapies-for-chronic-pain-and-copd/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2143157</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Entrepreneurs Roundtable Accelerator launches 12 new startups at demo day tomorrow</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/entrepreneurs-roundtable-accelerator-launches-12-new-startups-at-demo-day/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/entrepreneurs-roundtable-accelerator-launches-12-new-startups-at-demo-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 13:55:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurs roundtable accelerator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Entrepreneurs Roundtable Accelerator, an incubator based in New York, is introducing 12 new companies at its 20th demo day tomorrow. ERA has thus far had more than 226 companies go through the program that have raised more than $1 billion in capital and collectively share a market cap over $5 billion. So without any [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Entrepreneurs Roundtable Accelerator, an incubator based in New York, is introducing 12 new companies at its 20th demo day tomorrow.</p>
<p>ERA has thus far had more than 226 companies go through the program that have raised more than $1 billion in capital and collectively share a market cap over $5 billion.</p>
<p>So without any further ado, here are the 12 companies launching out of ERA today.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://www.baristavalet.com/">Barista Valet</a> is a virtual coffee shop, delivered via app, for luxury rental properties. Essentially, BaristaValet is emulating the cloud kitchen model with coffee, focusing only on delivery and not on an in-store experience. The company sells through to buildings and offices, allowing those entities to tack it onto existing costs as an amenity to tenants. The startup is currently operating in NYC.</p>
<p><a href="https://blendedcourse.com/">BlendED</a> is a platform and marketplace that allows professors to build, deliver and monetize course curriculum. Professors can upload their syllabus, integrate other technology like Zoom, Google Docs, etc., and integrate with existing Learning Management Systems to deliver rich digital experiences within their classes without the extra friction of having students join yet another platform. The startup is launching this fall with 700 professors and 11,000 students.</p>
<p><a href="https://carrotfi.com/">CarrotFI</a> is a platform that focuses on optimizing mortgage asset performance, and avoid foreclosures. It does this by giving lenders a better way to engage with mortgage customers, matching them proactively with borrowers with personal finance counseling that creates liquidity across household expenses.</p>
<p><a href="https://getmr.com/">GETMr.</a> is a skin health brand focused on men. Their first product is The Daily, which is a 3-in-1 moisturizer, aftershave and sunscreen, aimed at reducing the risk of cancer and skin damage. The products are all natural and developed by dermatologists. The company&#8217;s distribution methods are D2C as well as tapping large dermatology networks, with pricing at $24.49 for a subscription. The Daily is registered with the FDA.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.get-hopscotch.com/">Hopscotch</a> is targeting the pediatric behavioral health sector with a SaaS platform that allows providers to use digitized treatment programs for both in-person and virtual sessions. It includes gamified tools for patients and follow-up care and family/child portals. Hopscotch uses a freemium model for clinicians and offers a site license fee for hospitals, and currently has more than 1,500 clinicians on the platform across 46 states.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.yourmagpie.com/">Magpie</a> looks to offer users a digital vault for their collections of luxury goods,  and treat them as a true asset class,  complete with portfolio management. Authentication of these goods is automated, and Magpie offers pricing and demand transparency for things like sneakers, handbags, baseball cards and more. The startup also offers insurance. It uses a freemium subscription model and has more than 1000 people on the waitlist.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.neurobotx.ai/">neurobotx</a> was built on the heels of 30. years of Nobel Laureate R&amp;D and aims to decrease cloud computing costs and increase efficiency in the autonomous robotics space by isolating and detecting only the relevant pixels. It operates on a B2B SaaS model and the company is testing the platform in four upcoming pilots.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.otonomi.ai/">OTONOMI</a> is looking to disrupt the air cargo insurance industry by offering a more efficient product that uses data-activated triggers, smart contracts and integrated digital wallets, creating a more transparent and cost-efficient experience for both parties. The company claims to reduce claim resolution times from 45 days to 45 minutes, ultimately lowering costs. In beta, partnered with an unnamed &#8216;top-tier affiliate insurance administrator&#8217;, the company has already automated more than 1,000 policies.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.revmo.app/">Revmo</a> looks to bring warm introductions to every new connection you might want to make. Users enter in the person they want to be connected with and Revmo uses data from your existing networks to do a fast search of who might connect you, automating a warm email/SMS introduction within the network of your customers, colleagues, classmates, etc. It operates on a B2B SaaS model and has a waitlist of 600+ business users.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.sensegrass.com/">Sensegrass</a> is an agtech company that uses a combination of machine learning and soil sensors to deliver real-time soil health analysis and nutrient management recommendations to farmers. The hope is to reduce chemical fertilizer use, increase crop yields and help farmers grow sustainably. <span style="font-weight: 400;">Sensegrass charges via subscription based on usage requirements per acre depending on crop type and some other factors. </span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.theverticale.com/">The Veritcale</a> is an ecommerce marketplace that allows users to shop for brands based on a variety of factors, including sustainability, ethical production, and &#8216;for women by women.&#8217; This gives brands that fit into these verticals the chance to be highlighted and find their target customer base, and gives consumers an easy place to find what they&#8217;re looking (with single-cart checkout across multiple brands) for without doing all the research. The Verticale makes money by taking a commission on every order.</p>
<p><a href="https://getturnout.com/">Turnout</a> is a platform built specifically for internal communities and groups within an organization, making it easier for employees to host events and discussions across their company. Employee Resource Groups are a generally underserved demographic, with little to no tools built specifically for them. Turnout wants to change that. Thus far, it&#8217;s launched with several enterprise customers and is working directly with D&amp;I teams to better support underrepresented employees.</p>
<p><em>Editor&#8217;s Note: An earlier version of this story said that demo day was today. It is actually tomorrow, April 29. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/entrepreneurs-roundtable-accelerator-launches-12-new-startups-at-demo-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144971</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Forerunner&#8217;s Eurie Kim will share why she invested in Oura on Extra Crunch Live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/forerunners-eurie-kim-will-share-why-she-invested-in-oura-on-extra-crunch-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/forerunners-eurie-kim-will-share-why-she-invested-in-oura-on-extra-crunch-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 13:50:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch live announcement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2133989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When it comes to building a successful startup, biotech and hardware happen to be two of the most difficult verticals in the tech industry. But Oura is doing it anyway. The health and fitness tracking ring has been used in a number of studies around COVID-19 and been worn by NBA and WNBA players to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When it comes to building a successful startup, biotech and hardware happen to be two of the most difficult verticals in the tech industry. But Oura is doing it anyway.</p>
<p>The health and fitness tracking ring has been used in a number of studies around COVID-19 and been worn by NBA and WNBA players to help prevent outbreaks in the league. Oura has raised nearly $50 million from investors including Lifeline Ventures, Bold Capital Partners and Forerunner.</p>
<p>So it should come as no surprise that we&#8217;re thrilled to have Forerunner&#8217;s Eurie Kim and Oura CEO Harpreet Rai join us on a forthcoming episode of <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-forerunner-and-oura">Extra Crunch Live</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Kim is herself a former entrepreneur and joined Forerunner in 2012. She sits on the boards of companies like The Farmer’s Dog, Curology, Attabotics, Oura Ring, Eclipse, Juni, among others, and found herself on the Midas Brink List in 2020.</p>
<p>Rai, for his part, is CEO at Oura, where he leads a team of over 150 employees. Before Oura, Rai was a portfolio manager at Eminence Capital for nine years.</p>
<p>On <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-forerunner-and-oura">Extra Crunch Live</a>, the duo will talk about how Oura went about raising its $28 million Series B round and why Kim took a bet on the startup. We&#8217;ll also ask about tactical advice for founders looking to fundraise and grow their businesses.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DXrZ56rDNW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/12/the-oura-ring-is-the-personal-health-tracking-device-to-beat-in-2020/">The Oura Ring is the personal health tracking device to beat in 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Oura Ring is the personal health tracking device to beat in 2020&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/12/the-oura-ring-is-the-personal-health-tracking-device-to-beat-in-2020/embed/#?secret=DXrZ56rDNW" data-secret="DXrZ56rDNW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Anyone can join the live event, which goes down on April 28 at noon PDT/3 p.m. EDT. <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-forerunner-and-oura">REGISTER FOR FREE HERE</a>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/forerunners-eurie-kim-will-share-why-she-invested-in-oura-on-extra-crunch-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2133989</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>OpenClassrooms raises $80 million for its online education platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/openclassrooms-raises-80-million-for-its-online-education-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/openclassrooms-raises-80-million-for-its-online-education-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 13:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OpenClassrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reskilling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upskilling]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup OpenClassrooms has raised an $80 million Series C funding round led by Lumos Capital Group. The company operates an online education platform in French and English. Users can choose among 54 training programs and get a diploma at the end of the program — some of those program lead to French-state-recognized bachelor and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://openclassrooms.com/en/">OpenClassrooms</a> has raised an $80 million Series C funding round led by Lumos Capital Group. The company operates an online education platform in French and English. Users can choose among 54 training programs and get a diploma at the end of the program — some of those program lead to French-state-recognized bachelor and master diplomas.</p>
<p>GSV, the Chan Zuckerberg Initiative (CZI) and Salesforce Ventures also participated in today’s funding round. Existing investors General Atlantic and Bpifrance invested once again in the company.</p>
<p>OpenClassrooms covers many different fields, from web development to digital marketing, product management, HR and sales. Those paths are quite demanding as it can take 6 to 12 months of full-time work to complete a training program. OpenClassrooms partners with mentors so that they can help you remain motivated.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>At the end of the program, the startup guarantees that you’ll find a job. If you have a hard time finding a job, the company works with career coaches to make sure that you find a job that fits you. In 2020, 4,300 students found a job or received a promotion after participating in an OpenClassrooms program.</p>
<p>In France, people qualify for public subsidies in order to fund professional education programs. And students can pay for OpenClassrooms courses using those public subsidies.</p>
<p>The company says that the pandemic has had a positive impact on online education. Many people are looking for reskilling and upskilling opportunities and end up on OpenClassrooms. In addition to programs for individuals, the startup also offers courses to 1,400 companies.</p>
<p>Some companies, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/02/openclassrooms-and-capgemini-team-up-and-launch-an-online-apprenticeship-program/">such as Capgemini</a>, have teamed up with OpenClassrooms to offer apprenticeship programs. Students get to learn new skills and work for Capgemini at the same time. The apprenticeship program could be particularly attractive for companies with a high turnover that can’t find talent to fill open positions. There are currently 1,500 students following an apprenticeship program.</p>
<p>All of this has been working well as revenue during the first quarter of 2021 is 140% higher than Q1 2020 revenue. Recently, OpenClassrooms applied for the B-Corp certification. The company still offers <a href="https://openclassrooms.com/fr/courses">free classes</a> if you’re looking for your next weekend project.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="45lVWXi9mm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/02/openclassrooms-and-capgemini-team-up-and-launch-an-online-apprenticeship-program/">OpenClassrooms and Capgemini team up and launch an online apprenticeship program</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;OpenClassrooms and Capgemini team up and launch an online apprenticeship program&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/02/openclassrooms-and-capgemini-team-up-and-launch-an-online-apprenticeship-program/embed/#?secret=45lVWXi9mm" data-secret="45lVWXi9mm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/openclassrooms-raises-80-million-for-its-online-education-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144980</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CES will return to Las Vegas in 2022</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/ces-will-return-to-las-vegas-in-2022/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/ces-will-return-to-las-vegas-in-2022/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 13:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CES]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144974</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It was, I admit, slightly strange not feeling the extreme anxiety over the holidays at having to return to Las Vegas this past year. But nature is healing. Vaccinations have begun rolling out in much of the world, and CES is ready to return. The massive consumer electronic show’s governing board, the CTA, announced this [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It was, I admit, slightly strange not feeling the extreme anxiety over the holidays at having to return to Las Vegas this past year. But nature is healing. Vaccinations have begun rolling out in much of the world, and CES is ready to return.</p>
<p>The massive consumer electronic show’s governing board, the CTA, announced this morning that the event will return to the City of Second Chances January 5-8 (with media days eating into that post New Year’s glow starting on the 3rd). Per a press release, roughly 1,000 companies have committed to returning.</p>
<p>The list thus far includes, Amazon, AMD, AT&amp;T, Daimler AG, Dell, Google, Hyundai, IBM, Intel, Lenovo, LG Electronics, Panasonic, Qualcomm, Samsung Electronics and Sony. Given how the past year has gone, however, it’s important to note that everything is always subject to change.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Our customers are enthusiastic about returning to a live event in Las Vegas,” CTA EVP Karen Chupka said in a release tied to the news. “Global brands and startups have shared that plans are already well underway and are committed to sharing the magic of an in-person CES with even more people from around the world.”</p>
<p>Of course, things will very much feel up in the air until our respective planes have landed at the Las Vegas Airport (and I may or may not still be wearing a mask). And the CTA is quick to note that there will continue to be a digital element. That will almost certainly continue to be an important aspect of these shows moving forward. Will it seemed unlikely that the pandemic would kill trade shows altogether (particularly hardware trade shows), like many things in life, there are some aspects that will simply never be the same.</p>
<p>In 2020, the CTA escaped the wrath of Covid-19 just under the wire, roughly two months before the virus really began doing damage stateside. CES&#8217;s first (and, for the foreseeable future, only) all-virtual event was greeted with&#8230;mixed results. Anecdotally, the experience left a lot to be desire &#8212; perhaps understandable, given sheer size and breadth of a show like this. Now that the infrastructure is in place, however, it would be silly to abandon it altogether &#8212; especially after the past year left many questioning their attendance of these sorts of events in general.</p>
<p>As for the 2021 shows &#8212; a number, including MWC and IFA in Europe &#8212; are still planning to go forward, with enhanced safety precautions. The size and scope of these shows, however, remain in flux, as a number of companies have announced their intention to only attend the show virtually.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9v2uG6QAlH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/can-the-tech-trade-show-return-in-2021/">Can the tech trade show return in 2021?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Can the tech trade show return in 2021?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/can-the-tech-trade-show-return-in-2021/embed/#?secret=9v2uG6QAlH" data-secret="9v2uG6QAlH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/ces-will-return-to-las-vegas-in-2022/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144974</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>EasyMile raises $66M for its autonomous people-and-goods shuttles</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/easymile-raises-66m-for-its-autonomous-people-and-goods-shuttles/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/easymile-raises-66m-for-its-autonomous-people-and-goods-shuttles/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 13:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous shuttles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autononomous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easymile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shuttle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144912</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We may still be a long way off from Level 5, fully self-driving cars on the open road, but companies building autonomous vehicles and shuttles for specific uses within closed-campus deployments say they are on their way to commercial operations and are raising money to get there. In the latest development, a startup out of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We may still be a long way off from Level 5, fully self-driving cars on the open road, but companies building autonomous vehicles and shuttles for specific uses within closed-campus deployments say they are on their way to commercial operations and are raising money to get there. In the latest development, a startup out of Toulouse, France, called <a href="https://easymile.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EasyMile</a> &#8212; which builds shuttles for transporting both people and goods &#8212; has closed a Series B of €55 million ($66 million).</p>
<p>The funding is being led by Searchlight Capital Partners &#8212; the investor that just earlier this week appointed <a href="https://au.finance.yahoo.com/news/searchlight-capital-partners-announces-appointment-133700322.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">former FCC chairman Ajit Pai as its newest partner</a> &#8212; with McWin and NextStage AM also participating. Previous investors rail industry heavyweight Alstom, Bpifrance and auto giant Continental also participated. Searchlight is also an investor in Get Your Guide and Univision.</p>
<p>EasyMile claims to be the world leader in autonomous shuttles with 60% of the global market using its vehicles. It says that its vehicles have racked up 800,000 kilometers in over 300 locations in 30 countries. But as a mark of how small and nascent that market is today, EasyMile also says that it has just 180 vehicles deployed worldwide. (One big competitor, Navya, also happens to be based out of France, interestingly.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>EasyMile said it will use the funds to scale its business, by securing and building out commercial deployments in closed-campus environments. It will also continue to invest in its longer term strategy, to deploy its vehicles and technology in public transportation networks, although the company said believes its focus on more immediate use cases is what has helped it grow and attract new investment.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have stayed focused on what we can deliver in a reasonable timeframe and partnered with leaders in niche markets that are addressable now,&#8221; said EasyMile Founder and CEO Gilbert Gagnaire in a statement. “The participation of all of EasyMile’s earlier investors in the round is a strong vote of confidence in our expansion plan, and we are very happy to welcome Searchlight, McWin and NextStage and look forward to accelerating our growth thanks to their expertise.&#8221;</p>
<p>EasyMile is not disclosing its valuation, nor how much it has raised to date in what it described as an oversubscribed round. We are asking the company and will update this post as we learn more.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">EasyMile&#8217;s vehicles include the EZ10 people shuttles and TractEasy, an autonomous &#8220;tractor&#8221; trailer system for moving goods, and its over the years inked deals with companies like </span><a style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px; background-color: #ffffff;" href="https://www.tld-group.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TLD</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> (which runs ground transport and support in air cargo) and is currently working with the Peugeot, Chrysler and Fiat group Stellantis to build an autonomous vehicle using EasyMile technology.</span></p>
<p>The company has also had some setbacks. Last year, the <a href="https://www.cnet.com/roadshow/news/self-driving-startup-easy-mile-injury/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NHTSA barred EasyMile from running any services with passengers</a> on board after the company had an accident. (It can still operate vehicles without passengers.) We have asked the company to update us on the latest developments on this front.</p>
<p>On that front, it will be interesting to see how and if its new investor will have an impact in terms of helping with regulatory issues.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are excited to be investing in EasyMile at this critical juncture in the firm’s trajectory,&#8221; said Ralf Ackermann, a partner at Searchlight Capital, in a statement. &#8220;Having observed its robust, quality-driven approach and industry-leading technology, we are confident that it is well positioned to scale commercially and are delighted to be part of the journey.&#8221;</p>
<p>The fundraising is interesting in that it is coming at a time when we&#8217;re seeing some reshuffling and in some cases retrenchment in the autonomous driving space. Just this week <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/lyft-sells-self-driving-unit-to-toyotas-woven-planet-for-550m/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lyft sold off its Level 5 division to Toyota&#8217;s Woven Planet for $550 million</a>. EasyMile believes that its continuing focus on specific markets around shuttles in closed-loops has helped it stay the course and build more traction and profile in what is still an early market and bound to go through more changes, and hiccups.</p>
<p>“This injection of capital validates EasyMile’s strategy and will allow us to finalize our technical development and finance our scaleup strategy. We’ll bring the technology up to a level that can be industrialized and deliver a real commercial service,&#8221; said GM Benoit Perrin, in a statement.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/easymile-raises-66m-for-its-autonomous-people-and-goods-shuttles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144912</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
