<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 22:07:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Pitch us, Pittsburgh</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/pitch-us-pittsburgh/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/pitch-us-pittsburgh/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 20:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pittsburgh City Spotlight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch City Spotlight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164487</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We’re getting closer to putting our spotlight on Pittsburgh, and there’s quite a bit going on behind the scenes. We’ve been spending a ton of time chatting with folks who are on the ground in the city, and we’ve had a great time learning and listening, which we think will make this installment of our Spotlight [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We’re getting closer to putting our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/calling-all-yinzers-techcrunch-is-virtually-headed-to-pittsburgh/?tpcc=ECTW2020">spotlight on Pittsburgh</a>, and there’s quite a bit going on behind the scenes. We’ve been spending a ton of time chatting with folks who are on the ground in the city, and we’ve had a great time learning and listening, which we think will make this installment of our Spotlight series the most dynamic yet.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary">As we share more details on who will be participating, such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/carnegie-mellon-university-president-farnam-jahanian-is-speaking-at-techcrunch-city-spotlight-pittsburgh/">CMU’s President Farnam Jahanian,</a> we <b><i>still</i></b> want to hear from those of you building companies in the ‘Burgh.</p>
<p>We’ve heard from nearly 50 companies focusing on things like digital health, small business loans, patent development, robotics and clean tech, and we’ll be picking three companies to pitch live during <a href="https://hopin.com/events/techcrunch-city-spotlight-pittsburg">the event on June 29th</a>.</p>
<p>Because we expect all types of attendees, including investors, this could be an opportunity to take things to the next level, be it through recruiting new employees or finding a new advisor. After all, <i>anything</i> can happen at a TechCrunch event.</p>
<p>Simply <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/F2JkiUKt">fill out this form</a> and your company could be chosen to pitch during the event.</p>
<p>Additionally, and to learn more about who’s who and what’s what in Pittsburgh, we’re going to be <a href="https://twitter.com/i/spaces/1dRJZNQayLwJB">hosting a conversation on Twitter Spaces tomorrow (Friday) at 4 p.m. ET</a>. Co-hosting will be one of our favorite Yinzers, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kitmueller">Kit Mueller</a>. Expect a bit of trivia, updates on news and happenings in the city and more.</p>
<p><a href="https://hopin.com/events/techcrunch-city-spotlight-pittsburg">Register for the event</a> today, come chat with us tomorrow and <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/F2JkiUKt">submit your company</a> or pass the word along to someone who should!</p>
<h2>Agenda</h2>
<p><strong>June 29, 2021</strong></p>
<p>2:00 p.m. EDT<br />
<b>Building Pittsburgh. </b>Speaker to be announced!</p>
<p>2:20 p.m. EDT<br />
<b>Developing Duolingo. </b>Karin Tsai, head of engineering, is set to speak on the trade-offs between engagement and edtech, scale and satisfaction, and how a simple A/B test can help.</p>
<p>2:40 p.m. EDT<br />
<b>From Student to Startup. </b>CMU President Farnam Jahanian will speak on the school’s cutting-edge robotics and automation research and how it’s keeping innovative startups in Pittsburgh.</p>
<p>3:10 p.m. EDT<br />
<b>Pittsburgh Pitch-off. </b>Startups will have two minutes to deliver their pitch, and our speakers will have four minutes to give their feedback. Pittsburgh startups should apply here</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/pitch-us-pittsburgh/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164487</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple&#8217;s latest accessibility features are for those with limb and vocal differences</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/apples-latest-accessibility-features-are-for-those-with-limb-and-vocal-differences/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/apples-latest-accessibility-features-are-for-those-with-limb-and-vocal-differences/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 20:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accessibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WWDC 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164534</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple announced a batch of accessibility features at WWDC 2021 that cover a wide variety of needs, among them a few for people who can&#8217;t touch or speak to their devices in the ordinary way. With Assistive Touch, Sound Control, and other improvements, these folks have new options for interacting with an iPhone or Apple [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple announced a batch of accessibility features at WWDC 2021 that cover a wide variety of needs, among them a few for people who can&#8217;t touch or speak to their devices in the ordinary way. With Assistive Touch, Sound Control, and other improvements, these folks have new options for interacting with an iPhone or Apple Watch.</p>
<p>We covered Assistive Touch when it was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/apple-watch-gets-a-motion-controlled-cursor-with-assistive-touch/">first announced</a>, but recently got a few more details. This feature lets anyone with an Apple Watch operate it with one hand by means of a variety of gestures. It came about when Apple heard from the community of people with limb differences — whether they&#8217;re missing an arm, or unable to use it reliably, or anything else — that as much as they liked the Apple Watch, they were tired of answering calls with their noses.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Esfz50PG9F"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/apple-watch-gets-a-motion-controlled-cursor-with-assistive-touch/">Apple Watch gets a motion-controlled cursor with &#8216;Assistive Touch&#8217;</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple Watch gets a motion-controlled cursor with &#8216;Assistive Touch&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/apple-watch-gets-a-motion-controlled-cursor-with-assistive-touch/embed/#?secret=Esfz50PG9F" data-secret="Esfz50PG9F" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The research team cooked up a way to reliably detect the gestures of pinching one finger to the thumb, or clenching the hand into a fist, based on how doing them causes the watch to move — it&#8217;s not detecting nervous system signals or anything. These gestures, as well as double versions of them, can be set to a variety of quick actions. Among them is opening the &#8220;motion cursor,&#8221; a little dot that mimics the movements of the user&#8217;s wrist.</p>
<p>Considering how many people don&#8217;t have the use of a hand, this could be a really helpful way to get basic messaging, calling, and health-tracking tasks done without needing to resort to voice control.</p>
<p>Speaking of voice, that&#8217;s also something not everyone has at their disposal. Many of those who can&#8217;t speak fluently, however, can make a bunch of basic sounds, which can carry meaning for those who have learned — not so much Siri. But a new accessibility option called &#8220;Sound Control&#8221; lets these sounds be used as voice commands. You access it through Switch Control, not audio or voice, and add an audio switch.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2164719" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/audio-switch.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164719" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2164719" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/audio-switch.png" alt="Images of the process of adding an audio switch to the iPhone." width="1024" height="678" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/audio-switch.png 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/audio-switch.png?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/audio-switch.png?resize=300,199 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/audio-switch.png?resize=768,509 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/audio-switch.png?resize=680,450 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/audio-switch.png?resize=1536,1017 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/audio-switch.png?resize=2048,1357 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/audio-switch.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2164719" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>The setup menu lets the user choose from a variety of possible sounds: click, cluck, e, eh, k, la, muh, oo, pop, sh, and more. Picking one brings up a quick training process to let the user make sure the system understands the sound correctly, and then it can be set to any of a wide selection of actions, from launching apps to asking commonly spoken questions or invoking other tools.</p>
<p>For those who prefer to interact with their Apple devices through a switch system, the company has a big surprise: Game controllers, once only able to be used for gaming, now work for general purposes as well. Specifically noted is the amazing Xbox Adaptive Controller, a hub and group of buttons, switches, and other accessories that improves the accessibility of console games. This powerful tool is used by many, and no doubt they will appreciate not having to switch control methods entirely when they&#8217;re done with Fortnite and want to listen to a podcast.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2162438" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-update.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2162438" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2162438" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-update.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-update.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-update.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-update.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-update.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-update.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-update.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-update.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/wwdc-2021-health-update.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2162438" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>One more interesting capability in iOS that sits at the edge of accessibility is Walking Steadiness. This feature, available to anyone with an iPhone, tracks (as you might guess) the steadiness of the user&#8217;s walk. This metric, tracked throughout a day or week, can potentially give real insight into how and when a person&#8217;s locomotion is better and worse. It&#8217;s based on a bunch of data collected in the Apple Heart and Movement study, including actual falls and the unsteady movement that led to them.</p>
<p>If the user is someone who recently was fitted for a prosthesis, or had foot surgery, or suffers from vertigo, knowing when and why they are at risk of falling can be very important. They may not realize it, but perhaps their movements are less steady towards the end of the day, or after climbing a flight of steps, or after waiting in line for a long time. It could also show steady improvements as they get used to an artificial limb or chronic pain declines.</p>
<p>Exactly how this data may be used by an actual physical therapist or doctor is an open question, but importantly it&#8217;s something that can easily be tracked and understood by the users themselves.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2164702" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apple-memoji.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164702" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2164702" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apple-memoji.jpg" alt="Images of Apple Memoji with a cochlear implant, an oxygen tube, and a soft helmet." width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apple-memoji.jpg 1960w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apple-memoji.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apple-memoji.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apple-memoji.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apple-memoji.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apple-memoji.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apple-memoji.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2164702" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>Among Apple&#8217;s other assistive features are new languages for voice control, improved headphone acoustic accommodation, support for bidirectional hearing aids, and of course the addition of cochlear implants and oxygen tubes for memoji. As an Apple representative put it, they don&#8217;t want to embrace differences just in features, but on the personalization and fun side as well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/apples-latest-accessibility-features-are-for-those-with-limb-and-vocal-differences/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164534</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ledger raises $380 million for its crypto hardware wallet</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/ledger-raises-380-million-for-its-crypto-hardware-wallet/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/ledger-raises-380-million-for-its-crypto-hardware-wallet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 19:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hardware wallet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ledger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ledger Wallet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wallet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164632</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup Ledger has raised a $380 million Series C funding round led by 10T Holdings. Following today’s funding round, the company has reached a valuation of $1.5 billion. Other investors in the funding round include existing investors Cathay Innovation, Draper Associates, Draper Dragon, Draper Esprit, DCG, Korelya Capital and Wicklow Capital. Some new investors [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://www.ledger.com">Ledger</a> has raised a $380 million Series C funding round led by 10T Holdings. Following today’s funding round, the company has reached a valuation of $1.5 billion.</p>
<p>Other investors in the funding round include existing investors Cathay Innovation, Draper Associates, Draper Dragon, Draper Esprit, DCG, Korelya Capital and Wicklow Capital. Some new investors are joining the round, such as Tekne Capital, Uphold Ventures, Felix Capital, Inherent, Financière Agache and iAngels Technologies.</p>
<p>Ledger’s main product is a hardware wallet to manage your crypto assets. They are shaped like USB keys and feature a tiny screen to confirm transactions on the device. The reason why that screen is important is that your private keys never leave your Ledger device.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In other words, if you want to store large amount of cryptocurrencies, you don’t want to leave them on an exchange account. If someone manages to sign in, they could withdraw all your crypto assets. With a hardware wallet, you remain in control of your crypto assets.</p>
<p>The company first launched the Ledger Nano S. You have to connect the device to a computer using a USB cable. More recently, with the Ledger Nano X, you can send and receive assets from your phone as the Nano X works over Bluetooth. Ledger also provides an <a href="https://enterprise.ledger.com">enterprise solution</a> for companies that want to add cryptocurrencies to their balance sheet.</p>
<p>Overall, Ledger has sold over 3 million hardware wallets. Every month, 1.5 million people use Ledger Live, the company’s software solution to manage your crypto assets. The company even says that it currently secures around 15% of all cryptocurrency assets globally.</p>
<p>It hasn’t been a smooth ride as the company has been around for seven years. After the crypto boom of 2018, interests for hardware wallets faded away. Moreover, as the company secures expensive assets, it has also suffered from a serious data breach —&nbsp;<a href="https://support.ledger.com/hc/en-us/articles/360015559320-E-commerce-and-Marketing-data-breach-FAQ">272,000 customers</a> have been affected.</p>
<p>With today’s funding round, the company plans to launch new products, add more DeFi features to Ledger Live and support the growth of the crypto ecosystem in general.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/ledger-raises-380-million-for-its-crypto-hardware-wallet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164632</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Growth marketing amid the pandemic: An interview with Right Side Up&#8217;s Tyler Elliston</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/growth-marketing-amid-the-pandemic-an-interview-with-right-side-ups-tyler-elliston/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/growth-marketing-amid-the-pandemic-an-interview-with-right-side-ups-tyler-elliston/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Halpern]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 19:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth hacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164576</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We caught up with Tyler Elliston, founder of growth marketing firm Right Side Up and occasional contributor at TechCrunch, about his experiences and what he’s seeing as we exit the pandemic.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Growth marketers are busy today helping all sorts of startups take advantage of the market boom, but it has been a hard journey through the pandemic.</p>
<p>We caught up with Tyler Elliston, founder of growth marketing firm <a href="https://rightsideup.com/">Right Side Up</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/author/tyler-elliston/">occasional contributor</a> at TechCrunch, about his experiences and what he’s seeing now.</p>
<p>It’s part of our new initiative to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/help-techcrunch-find-the-best-growth-marketers-for-startups/">find the best growth marketers for startups</a> based on founder recommendations. (Have a recommendation to share? <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">Please fill out the survey here</a>.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Keep reading for more from Tyler about maintaining focus and resources on the right kind of growth, even when the markets are rollicking.</p>
<p><strong>It&#8217;s been a while since we last spoke with you. How have the trends in growth marketing shifted between the beginning of the pandemic and now, as we begin to exit lockdowns?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tyler Elliston:</strong> It’s been a rollercoaster! Early in the pandemic, we saw plummeting CPMs and slashed budgets. The rebound started relatively quickly over the summer of 2020 and accelerated into the fall and now 2021.</p>
<p>First, it was e-com companies, both those with strong pre-COVID sales online and historically brick-and-mortar brands scrambling to shift online to find much-needed sales. Then many other businesses &#8212; both new and existing &#8212; emerged with new products, value propositions and positioning to survive or even thrive in the pandemic.</p>
<p>Now, we continue to see very high consumer demand broadly and a corresponding eagerness amongst brands to accelerate customer acquisition, including through paid advertising. <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/monthly-funding-recap-funding-new-unicorns-and-exits-continue-at-a-strong-pace-in-may-2021/?utm_source=cb_daily&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=20210609&amp;utm_content=intro&amp;utm_term=content&amp;utm_source=cb_daily&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=20210609">Very active investors</a> have been a strong tailwind with respect to budgets.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;">Have you worked with a talented individual or agency who helped you find and keep more users?<br />
<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/help-techcrunch-find-the-best-growth-marketers-for-startups/">Respond to our survey</a> and help us find the best startup growth marketers!</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>We&#8217;ve talked <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/13/verified-expert-growth-marketing-agency-right-side-up/">before</a> about how you like your team to be treated as a partner rather than a vendor. How have they been able to accomplish this during the pandemic?</strong></p>
<p>The biggest thing is that we were able to lean on our reputation for being a good strategic partner that serves our clients’ best interests. Because they know we’ll tell them when we don’t think they should keep paying us for something, they also trust us when we say something like “I know this sounds crazy right now, but you should increase your budget due to a shift in your demand curve and channel economics.”</p>
<p>We were proactively honest with clients about what we believed the pandemic meant for their businesses, points of view we reached through <a href="https://rightsideup.com/growth-marketing-blog/the-case-for-channel-diversification-during-covid-19/">a framework we outlined on our blog</a>. For some, that meant supporting immediate termination of our partnership for them to conserve funds. In other cases, it meant pushing them to consider leaning into their performance marketing to capitalize on the changing environment and channel economics.</p>
<p>During the recovery, many companies have looked to external agencies and consultants to fill a temporary staffing gap in a lower-risk way. Shifting attitudes toward external resourcing and the evolution of company processes and culture to support remote workers have helped us more quickly and fully integrate with our clients’ internal teams.</p>
<p><strong>In a<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/13/verified-expert-growth-marketing-agency-right-side-up/"> previous conversation</a>, you mentioned, &#8220;We regularly tell companies, &#8216;You don’t need any growth marketing right now. Focus on product-market fit.'&#8221; How can startups tell that it’s the right time to come work with you? </strong></p>
<p>Growth marketing is an amplification tool. It shines a bright spotlight on a product or solution, believing that <em>if only people knew </em>about it, they would want it and love it. The “want it” and “love it” represent product-market fit. To measure these, we look at customer reviews, referral activity leading to organic growth, retention, product engagement, and ultimately realized and expected lifetime value.</p>
<p>Seeing good conversion rates and attractive customer acquisition costs in small-scale channel testing suggest that not only is there a group of people that love it, but that they can be reached. These are prerequisites for sustainable growth, in my view.</p>
<p><strong>If an early-stage company has limited resources, how should they prioritize their funds in regards to marketing?</strong></p>
<p>First, invest in the product to make it excellent, as judged by real, paying customers. Marketing plays a role in this iterative process of traffic acquisition, funnel measurement and feedback collection; it’s just not “growth marketing.” It’s better considered to be “go-to-market marketing,” typically staffed by a product marketer or similar.</p>
<p>Once the product is in a good place, I typically recommend at least some investment in nonpaid marketing efforts and some testing of paid advertising, most often Facebook and/or Google. It’s rare for a company to find a great scalable channel if neither of these work. They serve as bellwethers for online marketing performance, generally speaking.</p>
<p>The best nonpaid marketing investments are highly contextual on the target customer and a company’s differentiation from the competitive landscape.</p>
<p><strong>What do startups continue to get wrong?</strong></p>
<p>Focusing on growth before finding product/market fit is the biggest [thing that startups continue to get wrong]. Early-stage founders are under intense pressure to grow successfully. For all but the lucky few who find incredible early customer success, finding product-market fit requires an unbelievable dose of patience. I think this is one of the reasons we see a pattern of success among founders who are solving a problem they deeply care about personally. For them, it’s first and foremost about solving the problem for themselves, not others. It’s not about money or some notion of macro success. It’s about micro success. From there, it’s an easy jump to passionately share this solution you so desperately needed.</p>
<p>From an advertising standpoint, many companies try to run too many channels at once and expect success too quickly, leading to false negatives. Most channels are quite nuanced at this point and require both expertise and patience to crack, for most businesses.</p>
<p><strong>How do your growth marketing strategies change when working with early-stage startups as opposed to mature companies?</strong></p>
<p>With very early-stage companies, our work is typically not related to growth, per se. It’s more about getting a foundation in place (ex: pixels, tech stack, initial value props, early staffing), driving traffic through new funnels to gather early data, or setting up email campaigns. Once the product is in a good place, we are often working with a founder or first marketing hire to stand up their initial paid channels and try to get them from 0 to 1. Can we spend $5,000, $10,000, $20,000/month with a good return?</p>
<p>On the nonpaid side, it could be executing a content strategy, launching a referral program or cultivating partnerships. Once a company is spending hundreds of thousands or millions of dollars per month profitably, we are typically helping them improve channel performance, better measure the incremental impact of their spend, break through to a new level of scale, or<a href="https://rightsideup.com/growth-marketing-blog/channel-diversification-which-marketing-channels-should-you-explore-next-to-scale-your-business/"> diversify channels</a> (paid or nonpaid).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ipVJfrJwxz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/13/verified-expert-growth-marketing-agency-right-side-up/">Verified Expert Growth Marketing Agency: Right Side Up</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Verified Expert Growth Marketing Agency: Right Side Up&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/13/verified-expert-growth-marketing-agency-right-side-up/embed/#?secret=ipVJfrJwxz" data-secret="ipVJfrJwxz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/growth-marketing-amid-the-pandemic-an-interview-with-right-side-ups-tyler-elliston/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164576</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scale to launch a mapping product to address the changing needs of its autonomous driving customers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/scale-to-launch-a-mapping-product-to-address-the-changing-needs-of-its-autonomous-driving-customers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/scale-to-launch-a-mapping-product-to-address-the-changing-needs-of-its-autonomous-driving-customers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 18:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[event recap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mapping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobility 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164605</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Solving the varied challenges that arise in autonomous driving is an incredibly complex task, but even attempting to get started means ensuring you have quality data that&#8217;s accurate and well-annotated. That&#8217;s where Scale comes in, having identified early on that the AV industry would require annotation of huge swaths of data, including specialized LiDAR imaging. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Solving the varied challenges that arise in autonomous driving is an incredibly complex task, but even attempting to get started means ensuring you have quality data that&#8217;s accurate and well-annotated. That&#8217;s where Scale comes in, having identified early on that the AV industry would require annotation of huge swaths of data, including specialized LiDAR imaging. Now, co-founder and CEO Alex Wang tells me at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/video/supercharging-self-driving-super-vision/">TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</a> (ExtraCrunch subscription required) that it&#8217;s moving into mapping with a new product that&#8217;s coming later this month.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our role has continued to evolve,&#8221; Wang said, regarding how it works with its transportation industry partners, which include Toyota among many others. &#8220;You know, as we work with our customers, and we solved one problem for them around data and annotational data labeling, you know, it turns out they they come to us with other problems that we can then help solve as well around data management, we launched a product called Nucleus for that. A lot of our customers are thinking a lot about mapping, and how to deploy with more robust maps. So we&#8217;re built a product, I&#8217;m going to announce that probably later this month, but we&#8217;re helping to address that problem with our customers.&#8221;</p>
<p>Despite my prodding, Wang wouldn&#8217;t provide any specifics, but he did go into more detail about the challenges of mapping, and what&#8217;s lacking in existing maps available to companies working on integrating those with AV systems that include other signals, like sensor fusion and vehicle-to-infrastructure components.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;I think a big question for the overall space has been that historically, the industry has relied very, very heavily on mapping — we relied very, very heavily on very highquality, high definition maps,&#8221; he said. &#8220;The tricky thing about the world is that sometimes these maps are wrong, and how do you deal with that? [&#8230;] How do you deal with kind of this challenge of robustness, or updates. Even, if you think about it, Google Maps, which is the best mapping infrastructure in the world, by a huge margin, you know they don&#8217;t update quickly enough for [human] drivers.&#8221;</p>
<p>Wang said that the challenge isn&#8217;t all that different from the one that Scale has been actively solving for most of its existence, which is that of the data flywheel. With autonomous driving, it&#8217;s of utmost importance to be able to collect and annotate data quickly and accurately, which results in ever better collection and annotation of future data, and more reliability for the assumptions the system is making about its environment.</p>
<p>&#8220;Figuring out how to deal with the real-time nature of how the world changes, is one really big, one really big component,&#8221; he said. While we still have to wait to see what exactly Scale has planned, it seems safe to assume that it&#8217;s all about building confidence in maps and mapping accuracy as a key ingredient in whatever they launch.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UpAq7ptoXo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/">TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TC Sessions: Mobility 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/embed/#?secret=UpAq7ptoXo" data-secret="UpAq7ptoXo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/scale-to-launch-a-mapping-product-to-address-the-changing-needs-of-its-autonomous-driving-customers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164605</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The fintech endgame: New supercompanies combine the best of software and financials</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/the-fintech-endgame-new-supercompanies-combine-the-best-of-software-and-financials/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/the-fintech-endgame-new-supercompanies-combine-the-best-of-software-and-financials/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 18:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banking-as-a-service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer service software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Ecommerce and D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164477</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new and attractive hybrid category of company is emerging at the intersection of software and financial services, creating buzz in the investment and entrepreneurial communities.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Shiran Shalev</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/shiranshalev">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Shiran Shalev is a principal at <a href="https://www.battery.com/">Battery Ventures</a>, where he focuses primarily on software and consumer investments, including fintech. 	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/09/06/why-breach-detection-ss-your-new-must-have-cyber-security-tool/">Why Breach Detection Is Your New Must-Have, Cyber Security Tool</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Aaron Rinberg</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Aaron Rinberg is a vice president at <a href="https://www.battery.com/">Battery Ventures</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/18/amazons-one-two-punch-how-traditional-retailers-can-fight-back/">Amazon’s one-two punch: How traditional retailers can fight back</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Lior Mallul</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/lior_m_">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Lior Mallul is an associate at <a href="https://www.battery.com/">Battery Ventures</a>. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">If money is the ultimate commodity, how can fintechs &#8212; which sell money, move money or sell insurance against monetary loss &#8212; build products that remain differentiated and create lasting value over time?</p>
<p>And why are so many software companies — which already boast highly differentiated offerings and serve huge markets— moving to offer financial services embedded within their products?</p>
<p>A new and attractive hybrid category of company is emerging at the intersection of software and financial services, creating buzz in the investment and entrepreneurial communities, as we discussed at our “<a href="https://www.battery.com/newsevents/fintech-the-endgame/">Fintech: The Endgame</a>” virtual conference and accompanying report this week.</p>
<p>These specialized companies — in some cases, software companies that also process payments and hold funds on behalf of their customers, and in others, financial-first companies that integrate workflow and features more reminiscent of software companies &#8212; combine some of the best attributes of both categories.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2164479" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164479" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2164479" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/fintech-image-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="470" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/fintech-image-1.png 1425w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/fintech-image-1.png?resize=150,69 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/fintech-image-1.png?resize=300,138 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/fintech-image-1.png?resize=768,352 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/fintech-image-1.png?resize=680,312 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/fintech-image-1.png?resize=50,23 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164479" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Battery Ventures</p></div></p>
<p>From software, they design for strong user engagement linked to helpful, intuitive products that drive retention over the long term. From financials, they draw on the ability to earn revenues indexed to the growth of a customer’s business.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Fintech is poised to revolutionize financial services, both through reinventing existing products and driving new business models as financial services become more pervasive within other sectors.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>The powerful combination of these two models is rapidly driving both public and private market value as investors grant these “super” companies premium valuations &#8212; in the public sphere, nearly twice the median multiple of pure software companies, according to a Battery analysis.</p>
<p>The near-perfect example of this phenomenon is Shopify, the company that made its name selling software to help business owners launch and manage online stores. Despite achieving notable scale with this original SaaS product, Shopify today makes twice as much revenue from payments as it does from software by enabling those business owners to accept credit card payments and acting as its own payment processor.</p>
<p>The combination of a software solution indexed to e-commerce growth, combined with a profitable payments stream growing even faster than its software revenues, has investors granting Shopify a 31x multiple on its forward revenues, according to CapIQ data as of May 26.</p>
<h2>How should we value these fintech companies, anyway?</h2>
<p>Before even talking about how investors should value these hybrid companies, it’s worth making the point that in both private and public markets, fintechs have been notoriously hard to value, fomenting controversy and debate in the investment community.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/the-fintech-endgame-new-supercompanies-combine-the-best-of-software-and-financials/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164477</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Course Hero acquires LitCharts, founded by the creators of SparkNotes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/course-hero-acquires-litcharts-founded-by-the-creators-of-sparknotes/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/course-hero-acquires-litcharts-founded-by-the-creators-of-sparknotes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 18:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Course Hero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[litcharts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164591</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ll admit it: I was the student that tipped the teacher off that half of our English class, including me, was using SparkNotes to “read” &#8220;Twelfth Night&#8221; by Shakespeare, instead of actually reading the text itself. The site, which offered summaries of books on a chapter-by-chapter basis, was the best way to review novels before [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">I’ll admit it: I was the student that tipped the teacher off that half of our English class, including me, was using SparkNotes to “read” &#8220;Twelfth Night&#8221; by Shakespeare, instead of actually reading the text itself. The site, which offered summaries of books on a chapter-by-chapter basis, was the best way to review novels before a quiz &#8212; or, was the best last-minute savior if you procrastinated too much and never got around to opening the book in the first place.</p>
<p>History in mind, it makes sense that the creators of everyone’s favorite procrastination tool, SparkNotes, are getting noticed by an edtech unicorn. <a href="https://www.litcharts.com/">LitCharts</a>, an offshoot of SparkNotes, got scooped up today by a newly minted edtech unicorn, Course Hero. The price of the deal was undisclosed. That said, Course Hero last raised an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/26/course-hero-a-profitable-edtech-unicorn-raises-rare-cash/">$80 million Series B in August 2020</a>, and assumedly a portion of that check went to this deal.</p>
<p>The creators of SparkNotes, Ben Florman and Justin Kestler, created LitCharts as an extension of their initial success. LitCharts provides notes, definitions and translations on over 2,000 literary texts. Similar to SparkNotes, LitCharts is all about making complex passages less complex. Course Hero founder Andrew Grauer estimates that about 30% of LitCharts’ subscribers are teachers and educators.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“We want to make sure that we have the best solution for a specific area, and then at the right moment in time, be able to make a really authentic recommendation of another tool or another offering that can be helpful for you [as a student],” Grauer said of Course Hero’s long-term ambition. That webbing — or connecting students from one resource to another — could be one of the benefits of virtual education, because there is essentially a history log of every error, stumble and pause that a student makes as they’re going through a lesson.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dxFyTKCoVy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/to-win-post-pandemic-edtech-needs-to-start-thinking-big/">To win post-pandemic, edtech needs to start thinking big</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;To win post-pandemic, edtech needs to start thinking big&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/to-win-post-pandemic-edtech-needs-to-start-thinking-big/embed/#?secret=dxFyTKCoVy" data-secret="dxFyTKCoVy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The heart of Course Hero, says Grauer, is to create a question-and-answer platform with extreme levels of specificity for students. It sells subscriptions to students that unlock access to all of its learning and teaching content, which include course-specific material created by teachers and publishers. Naturally, a big part of Course Hero’s strategy is to offer material on common subjects that students struggle with — English being one of those subjects.</p>
<p>“We&#8217;ve been looking at the data on the platform, and where students are actually getting stuck the most, where they need the most help, and where they are asking the most questions,” said Grauer. “And that&#8217;s quite informative.”</p>
<p>The company has been building out its literature library for the past five to six years. With LitCharts under its wing, Course Hero is putting a significant investment in its literature library, which is chockfull of videos, illustrations and notes on texts.</p>
<p>This is Course Hero’s second acquisition in the past eight months. In October, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/27/course-hero-symbolab-makes-a-rare-edtech-acquisition/">Course Hero acquired Symbolab</a>, an artificial-intelligence-powered calculator that helps students answer and understand complex math questions. That deal helped bolster Course Hero’s math offering, and today’s acquisition should help Course Hero deepen its literature resources. Both of these brands will continue to operate independently — a choice that Grauer says is part of his operating thesis of supporting the &#8220;decentralized empowerment of entrepreneurs.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;If you centralize everything, maybe there&#8217;s power to that [since] it all looks the same, but actually in doing [that too] many times … you can actually move slower and not be able to move fast and make decisions and make progress toward the goal because you&#8217;re optimizing for so many small specific use cases,&#8221; he said. The two recent startups that Course Hero acquired have been operating for over a decade, and Grauer thinks that their scale and brand power is worth keeping as is, instead of forcing into an umbrella brand.</p>
<p>Across its various platforms, Course Hero estimates that it will hit between 2 million to 3 million paid subscribers this year, up from 1 million subscribers the year prior.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="St87xeTflg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/how-is-edtech-spending-its-extra-capital/">How is edtech spending its extra capital?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How is edtech spending its extra capital?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/how-is-edtech-spending-its-extra-capital/embed/#?secret=St87xeTflg" data-secret="St87xeTflg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/course-hero-acquires-litcharts-founded-by-the-creators-of-sparknotes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164591</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Macron says G7 countries should work together to tackle toxic online content</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/macron-says-g7-countries-should-work-together-to-tackle-toxic-online-content/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/macron-says-g7-countries-should-work-together-to-tackle-toxic-online-content/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 18:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emmanuel Macron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hate speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Macron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toxic content]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164590</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a press conference at the Élysée Palace, French President Emmanuel Macron reiterated his focus on online regulation, and more particularly toxic content. He called for more international cooperation as the Group of Seven (G7) summit is taking place later this week in the U.K. “The third big topic that could benefit from efficient multilateralism [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In a <a href="https://www.elysee.fr/emmanuel-macron/2021/06/10/conference-de-presse-en-amont-des-sommets-du-g7-et-de-lotan">press conference</a> at the Élysée Palace, French President Emmanuel Macron reiterated his focus on online regulation, and more particularly toxic content. He called for more international cooperation as the Group of Seven (G7) summit is taking place later this week in the U.K.</p>
<p>“The third big topic that could benefit from efficient multilateralism and that we’re going to bring up during this G7 summit is online regulation,” Macron said. “This topic, and I’m sure we’ll talk about it again, is essential for our democracies.”</p>
<p>Macron also used that opportunity to sum up France’s efforts on this front. “During the summer of 2017, we launched an initiative to tackle online terrorist content with then Prime Minister Theresa May. At first, and as crazy as it sounds today, we mostly failed. Because of free speech, people told us to mind our own business, more or less.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In 2019, there was a horrendous mass mosque shooting in Christchurch, New Zealand. And you could <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/15/new-zealand-tragedy-social-media-responmse/">find multiple copies</a> of the shooting videos on Facebook, YouTube and Twitter. Macron invited New Zealand Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern, several digital ministers of the G7 and tech companies to Paris.</p>
<p>They all signed a nonbinding pledge called the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/14/world-leaders-ask-tech-giants-to-tackle-toxic-content-with-christchurch-call/">Christchurch Call</a>. Essentially, tech companies that operate social platforms agreed to increase their efforts when it comes to blocking toxic content —&nbsp;and terrorist content in particular.</p>
<p>Facebook, Twitter, Google (and YouTube), Microsoft, Amazon and <a href="https://www.christchurchcall.com/supporters.html">other</a> tech companies signed the pledge. 17 countries and the European Commission also backed the Christchurch Call. There was one notable exception — the U.S. didn’t sign it.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FphH1aFpb9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/14/world-leaders-ask-tech-giants-to-tackle-toxic-content-with-christchurch-call/">World leaders ask tech giants to tackle toxic content with Christchurch Call</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;World leaders ask tech giants to tackle toxic content with Christchurch Call&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/14/world-leaders-ask-tech-giants-to-tackle-toxic-content-with-christchurch-call/embed/#?secret=FphH1aFpb9" data-secret="FphH1aFpb9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“This strategy led to some concrete results because all online platforms that signed it have followed through,” Macron said. “Evidence of this lies in what happened in France last fall when we faced terrorist attacks.” In October 2020, French middle-school teacher Samuel Paty was <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Murder_of_Samuel_Paty">killed</a> and beheaded by a terrorist.</p>
<p>“Platforms flagged content and removed content within an hour,” he added.</p>
<p>Over time, more countries and online platforms <a href="https://www.christchurchcall.com/supporters.html">announced</a> their support for the Christchurch Call. In May, President Joe Biden <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/08/christchurch-call-biden-backs-new-zealand-stand-against-online-extremism">joined</a> the international bid against toxic content. “Given the number of companies incorporated in the U.S., it’s a major step and I welcome it,” Macron said today.</p>
<p>But what comes next after the Christchurch Call? First, Macron wants to convince more countries to back the call — China and Russia aren’t part of the supporters for instance.</p>
<p>“The second thing is that we have to push forward to create a framework for all sorts of online hate speech, racist speech, anti-semitic speech and everything related to online harassment,” Macron said.</p>
<p>He then briefly referred to French regulation on this front. Last year, French regulation on hate speech on online platforms has been widely deemed as unconstitutional by France’s Constitutional Council, the top authority in charge of ruling whether a new law complies with the constitution.</p>
<p>The list of hate-speech content was long and broad while potential fines were very high. The Constitutional Council feared that online platforms would censor content a bit too quickly.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ufWaJDnzNU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/19/french-constitutional-authority-rejects-law-forcing-online-platforms-to-delete-hate-speech-content/">French constitutional authority rejects law forcing online platforms to delete hate-speech content</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;French constitutional authority rejects law forcing online platforms to delete hate-speech content&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/19/french-constitutional-authority-rejects-law-forcing-online-platforms-to-delete-hate-speech-content/embed/#?secret=ufWaJDnzNU" data-secret="ufWaJDnzNU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But that doesn’t seem to be stopping Macron from backing new regulation on online content at the European level and at the G7 level.</p>
<p>“It’s the only way to build an efficient framework that we can bring at the G20 summit and that can help us fight against wild behavior in online interactions — and therefore wild behavior in our new world order,” Macron said, using the controversial ‘wild behavior’ metaphor (<em>ensauvagement</em>). That term was <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/09/04/world/europe/france-ensauvagement-far-right-racism.html">first popularized</a> by far-right political figures.</p>
<p>According to him, if world leaders fail to find some common grounds when it comes to online regulation, it’ll lead to internet fragmentation. Some countries may choose to block several online services for instance.</p>
<p>And yet, recent events have showed us that this ship has sailed already. The Nigerian government <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/nigeria-suspends-twitter-operations-says-platform-undermines-its-corporate-existence/">suspended Twitter operations</a> in the country just a few days ago. It’s easy to agree to block terrorist content, but it becomes tedious quite quickly when you want to moderate other content.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/macron-says-g7-countries-should-work-together-to-tackle-toxic-online-content/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164590</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Productivity startup Time is Ltd raises $5.6M to be the &#8216;Google Analytics for company time&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/productivity-startup-time-is-ltd-raises-5-6m-to-be-the-google-analytics-for-company-time/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/productivity-startup-time-is-ltd-raises-5-6m-to-be-the-google-analytics-for-company-time/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 17:19:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[board member]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chairman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-grocery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Chalfen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seal Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[serial entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Socialbakers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the wall street journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time is Ltd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video conferencing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WebEX]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164556</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Productivity analytics startup Time is Ltd wants to be the Google Analytics for company time. Or perhaps a sort of &#8220;Apple Screen Time&#8221; for companies. Whatever the case, the founders reckon that if you can map how time is spent in a company enormous productivity gains can be unlocked and, money better spent. It’s now [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Productivity analytics startup <a href="https://www.timeisltd.com">Time is Ltd</a> wants to be the Google Analytics for company time. Or perhaps a sort of &#8220;Apple Screen Time&#8221; for companies. Whatever the case, the founders reckon that if you can map how time is spent in a company enormous productivity gains can be unlocked and, money better spent.</p>
<p>It’s now raised a $5.6 million late seed funding round led by Mike Chalfen, of London-based Chalfen Ventures, with participation from Illuminate Financial Management and existing investor Accel. Acequia Capital and former Seal Software chairman Paul Sallaberry are also contributing to the new round, as is former Seal board member Clark Golestani. Furthermore, Ulf Zetterberg, founder and former CEO of contract discovery and analytics company Seal Software, is joining as President and co-founder.</p>
<p>The venture is the latest from serial entrepreneur <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/janrezab/">Jan Rezab</a>, better known for founding SocialBakers, which was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/09/astute-acquires-socialbakers/">acquired last year</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>We are all familiar with inefficient meetings, pestering notifications chat, video conferencing tools and the deluge of emails. Time is Ltd. says it plans to address this by acquiring insights and data platforms such as Microsoft 365, Google Workspace, Zoom, Webex, MS Teams, Slack, and more. The data and insights gathered would then help managers to understand and take a new approach to measure productivity, engagement, and collaboration, the startup says.</p>
<p>The startup says it has now gathered 400 indicators that companies can choose from. For example, a task set by The Wall Street Journal for Time is Ltd. found the average response time for Slack users vs. email was 16.3 minutes, comparing to emails which was 72 minutes.</p>
<p>Chalfen commented: &#8220;Measuring hybrid and distributed work patterns is critical for every business. Time Is Ltd.&#8217;s platform makes such measurement easily available and actionable for so many different types of organizations that I believe it could make work better for every business in the world.”</p>
<p>Rezab said: “The opportunity to analyze these kinds of collaboration and communication data in a privacy-compliant way alongside existing business metrics is the future of understanding the heartbeat of every company &#8211; I believe in 10 years time we will be looking at how we could have ignored insights from these platforms.”</p>
<p>Tomas Cupr, Founder and Group CEO of Rohlik Group, the European leader of e-grocery, said: “Alongside our traditional BI approaches using performance data, we use Time is Ltd. to help improve the way we collaborate in our teams and improve the way we work both internally and with our vendors &#8211; data that Time is Ltd. provides is a must-have for business leaders.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/productivity-startup-time-is-ltd-raises-5-6m-to-be-the-google-analytics-for-company-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164556</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dark Sky iOS app and website are likely shutting down at the end of 2022</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/dark-sky-ios-app-and-website-are-likely-shutting-down-at-the-end-of-2022/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/dark-sky-ios-app-and-website-are-likely-shutting-down-at-the-end-of-2022/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 17:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dark Sky]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164559</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After Apple acquired Dark Sky in March of 2020, we all knew the super-granular weather app was probably headed for shutdown. But while the company announced that the Android app would go dark in July of the same year, things were left a bit more open-ended for the iOS app. There would be &#8220;no changes&#8221; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After Apple <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/31/apple-acquires-dark-sky-android-version-shutting-down-in-july/">acquired Dark Sky in March of 2020</a>, we all knew the super-granular weather app was probably headed for shutdown. But while the company announced that the Android app would go dark in July of the same year, things were left a bit more open-ended for the iOS app. There would be &#8220;no changes&#8221; for Dark Sky on iOS, they said, &#8220;at this time.&#8221;</p>
<p>A year later, a small update to the Dark Sky blog (as pointed out <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/06/10/dark-sky-apple-acquisition-shutdown-date/">by 9to5mac</a>) seems to be putting a new expiration date on the Dark Sky iOS App, API and website. <a href="https://blog.darksky.net">Writes co-founder Adam Grossman</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Support for the Dark Sky API service for existing customers will continue until the end of 2022. The iOS app and Dark Sky website will also be available until the end of 2022.</p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that there&#8217;s a little room for interpretation there, in that they don&#8217;t explicitly say it <em>will</em> shut down at the end of 2022 — just that they&#8217;re committing to running it until the end of 2022, perhaps suggesting its fate after that is in flux. We&#8217;ve reached out to Apple for clarification on that point — but until we hear back, we&#8217;re taking this as a heads up that shutdown is on the horizon.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="X5WWpXwXLD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/31/apple-acquires-dark-sky-android-version-shutting-down-in-july/">Apple acquires Dark Sky, Android version shutting down in July</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple acquires Dark Sky, Android version shutting down in July&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/31/apple-acquires-dark-sky-android-version-shutting-down-in-july/embed/#?secret=X5WWpXwXLD" data-secret="X5WWpXwXLD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>On the upside, this is actually an <em>extension</em> for the API and the Dark Sky website. The website was previously scheduled to shut down in August of 2020; the API, meanwhile, was scheduled to be shuttered at the end of 2021.</p>
<p>This news comes just a few days after Apple <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-finally-updates-its-weather-app-with-dynamic-backgrounds-maps-and-way-more-data/">announced an overhaul to iOS&#8217; built-in Weather app</a> during WWDC.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wBr5nmlW0M"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-finally-updates-its-weather-app-with-dynamic-backgrounds-maps-and-way-more-data/">Apple (finally) updates its weather app with dynamic backgrounds, maps and way more data</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple (finally) updates its weather app with dynamic backgrounds, maps and way more data&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-finally-updates-its-weather-app-with-dynamic-backgrounds-maps-and-way-more-data/embed/#?secret=wBr5nmlW0M" data-secret="wBr5nmlW0M" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/dark-sky-ios-app-and-website-are-likely-shutting-down-at-the-end-of-2022/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164559</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Homebuying startup Flyhomes closes $150 million Series C</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/homebuying-startup-flyhomes-closes-150-million-series-c/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/homebuying-startup-flyhomes-closes-150-million-series-c/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 17:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Camber Creek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fifth wall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flyhomes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[norwest venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Redfin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spencer rascoff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zillow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amid a recent tear in residential real estate investment, venture capitalists are looking to get a piece of homebuying startup Flyhomes. The five-year-old startup announced today that they&#8217;ve closed a $150 million Series C round co-led by Norwest Venture Partners and Battery Ventures. Fifth Wall, Camber Creek, Balyasny Asset Management, Zillow&#8217;s Spencer Rascoff and existing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Amid a recent tear in residential real estate investment, venture capitalists are looking to get a piece of homebuying startup <a href="https://www.flyhomes.com/">Flyhomes</a>.</p>
<p>The five-year-old startup announced today that they&#8217;ve closed a $150 million Series C round co-led by Norwest Venture Partners and Battery Ventures. Fifth Wall, Camber Creek, Balyasny Asset Management, Zillow&#8217;s Spencer Rascoff and existing investors Andreessen Horowitz and Canvas Partners also participated in the round. Norwest&#8217;s Lisa Wu and Battery&#8217;s Roger Lee are joining <span class="il">Flyhomes</span>’ board as part of the deal.</p>
<p>The end-to-end residential real estate startup says they handle &#8220;every step of the homebuying process, from brokerage to mortgage,&#8221; building financial tools that customers need throughout the process. The company has now raised some $310 million in total.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup is well-positioned during a historic run-up of home prices in the U.S. that has made deals more competitive than ever for prospective buyers. A recent report by <a href="https://www.redfin.com/news/housing-market-update-home-prices-surge-24-pct/">Redfin</a> notes that more than half of U.S. homes are selling above their asking price right now, up from one in four a year ago. A <a href="https://www.zillow.com/research/days-to-pending-april-2021-29511/">Zillow</a> report notes that nearly half of U.S. homes are selling within one week of going on the market.</p>
<p>Flyhomes&#8217;s Cash Offer lending product allows consumers purchasing homes to make more attractive all-cash offers to sellers, with the company noting that even if a buyer ends up backing out of the deal, Flyhomes will still buy the home themselves. Central to the startup&#8217;s business is sellers being more amenable to all-cash offers, allowing consumers making them to win deals even when they aren&#8217;t the highest bidders.</p>
<p><span class="il">The company says it</span> has bought and sold more than $2.6 billion worth of <span class="il">homes</span> since launching in 2016.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1woeRWUevk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/no-pen-required-the-digital-future-of-real-estate-closings/">No pen required: The digital future of real estate closings</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;No pen required: The digital future of real estate closings&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/no-pen-required-the-digital-future-of-real-estate-closings/embed/#?secret=1woeRWUevk" data-secret="1woeRWUevk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/homebuying-startup-flyhomes-closes-150-million-series-c/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164512</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What SOSV&#8217;s Climate Tech 100 tells founders about investors in the space</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/what-sosvs-climate-tech-100-tells-founders-about-investors-in-the-space/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/what-sosvs-climate-tech-100-tells-founders-about-investors-in-the-space/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 16:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Food Climate and Sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sosv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sosv climate tech 100]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164396</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Who's investing in technology and startups that promise better human and planetary health? Here's a definitive who's-who of top climate tech VCs, angels and more.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Benjamin Joffe</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/SOSV">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Benjamin Joffe is a partner at <a href="https://sosv.com/">SOSV</a>. 	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/23/twelve-key-lessons-about-tech-mergers-and-acquisitions-from-ciscos-john-chambers/">10 key lessons about tech mergers and acquisitions from Cisco&#8217;s John Chambers</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/31/what-every-startup-founder-should-know-about-exits/">What every startup founder should know about exits</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Meghan Hind</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/hax_co">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/meghan-hind-73099419b/">Meghan Hind</a> is an operations analyst for SOSV. Her role includes gathering and analysing data on SOSV portfolio companies and syndicate investors, managing the funds’ databases and CRM, and reporting SOSV’s quarterly investments to external data providers.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">On Earth Day, April 22, SOSV published the <a href="https://sosv.com/SOSV-climate-tech-100-list">SOSV Climate Tech 100</a>, a list of the best startups that we’ve supported from their earliest stages to address climate change. There are always valuable insights embedded in a list like the 100. A <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/sosvs-burgeoning-climate-portfolio-is-worth-nearly-6-billion-as-planetary-health-bets-pay-off/">TechCrunch story</a> captured the investment perspective, and an <a href="https://medium.com/sosv-accelerator-vc/behind-the-numbers-at-sosvs-climate-tech-100-2ab258caef8f">SOSV post</a> went deeper into the companies’ category breakdown and founder profiles.</p>
<p>But what can founders learn from the list about climate tech investors? In other words, who invested in the Climate Tech 100? We dug into the &#8220;who&#8217;s who&#8221; of the list, which had more than 500 investors, and here&#8217;s what we found.</p>
<h2>An active but fragmented landscape</h2>
<p>If you think 500 investors in 100 companies is a lot of investors, you’re right. There are clearly a lot of investors interested in climate tech, and most are generalists just testing the waters. For the Climate Tech 100, about 10% of investors put their money in more than one startup and only seven (less than 2%) wrote a check to four or more. These included <a href="https://www.bluehorizon.com">Blue Horizon</a>, <a href="https://cptcap.com">CPT Capital</a>, <a href="https://www.joinef.com/">EF</a>, <a href="https://fiftyyears.com">Fifty Years</a>, <a href="https://www.hemisphere.com">Hemisphere Ventures</a> and <a href="https://www.horizonsventures.com">Horizons Ventures</a>.</p>
<p>That pattern tracks well with data from PwC, which found that 2,700 unique investors had backed 1,200 startups in its <a href="https://www.pwc.com/gx/en/services/sustainability/assets/pwc-the-state-of-climate-tech-2020.pdf">State of Climate Tech 2020</a> report covering the 2013-2019 period. The report found that only 10 firms out of 2,700 made four or more climate tech deals per year, on average, over the 2013-2019 period. The most active firms are listed in the table below.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2164452" style="width: 1930px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164452" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2164452 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/image1-1.jpg" alt="Most active investors in SOSV Climate Tech 100" width="1920" height="1080" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/image1-1.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/image1-1.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/image1-1.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/image1-1.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/image1-1.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/image1-1.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/image1-1.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164452" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> PwC, 2020; additional research by SOSV</p></div></p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Capital deployed in climate tech grew at five times the venture capital overall growth rate over the 2013-2019 period.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>There is reason to believe that the fragmentation will diminish with the launch of more funds focused on climate tech. Four funds worth more than a billion dollars each have launched since 2020 that fit the description (see chart below).</p>
<p>It’s also encouraging to see that capital deployed in climate tech grew <a href="https://www.pwc.com/gx/en/news-room/press-releases/2020/climate-tech-investment-report-climate-week.html">at five times</a> the venture capital overall growth rate over the 2013-2019 period.</p>
<p>Even so, climate tech still only represented 6% of total venture capital deployed in 2019, so there is plenty of room to grow.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/what-sosvs-climate-tech-100-tells-founders-about-investors-in-the-space/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164396</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fuel Ventures launches its new $63.6M early-stage VC fund, aiming for 60 startups inside 12 months</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/fuel-ventures-launches-its-new-63-6m-early-stage-vc-fund-aiming-for-60-startups-inside-12-months/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/fuel-ventures-launches-its-new-63-6m-early-stage-vc-fund-aiming-for-60-startups-inside-12-months/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 16:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fuel.Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164498</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You may have heard of payments startup Paddle, which has raised $93.3 million. Or perhaps Heroes, which raised $65 million to become the &#8220;Thrasio of Europe.” But you might not have heard so much about a backer of these startups: Fuel Ventures. At least not yet. That&#8217;s about to change, as Fuel Ventures comes out [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">You may have heard of payments startup <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/paddle">Paddle</a>, which has raised $93.3 million. Or perhaps Heroes, which raised $65 million to become the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/heroes/">&#8220;Thrasio of Europe.”</a> But you might not have heard so much about a backer of these startups: <a href="https://fuel.ventures/">Fuel Ventures</a>. At least not yet.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s about to change, as Fuel Ventures comes out of the door with a new £45 million / $63.6 million early-stage focused VC fund, aiming at 60 U.K. tech startups over the next 12 months. This is quite the pace for an early-stage fund, but Fuel’s founder and managing partner Mark Pearson told me at length how he is confident of making it one of the most prolific early-stage investors in the U.K.</p>
<p>Since launching in 2015, Fuel has raised £80 million in capital to invest in seed and series A founders, and the VC will also be aiming for pre-seed ventures with the new fund.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In the last 12 months Fuel says its founders have raised over £180 million in follow-on funding. Notable investments include: OnBuy (e-commerce marketplace), Capdesk (equity management platform), OutFund (alternative finance provider), Heroes (scaling Amazon businesses) and Moot Group (homeware and furnishing e-commerce business).</p>
<p>Mark Pearson, founder and managing partner of Fuel Ventures, said: “Since we launched our first fund five years ago the country’s tech ecosystem has gone from strength to strength and evolved into an ecosystem that’s the envy of many around the world. Now is not the time to take the foot off the pedal and say job done. We have a responsibility to invest in the future of the U.K. tech landscape and build on the strong work done so far. This, for us, means making sure we are providing capital for forward-thinking entrepreneurs and their innovative early-stage businesses &#8212; even if that means just having an idea or MVP.”</p>
<p>In addition to the new £45 million fund, Fuel is also opening up a workspace in central London to serve its portfolio.</p>
<p>Speaking to me over a call, Pearson, who cut his teeth at a startup called MyVoucherCodes, said: “I exited that successfully and left it with about 10 million in revenues. I then started to be a pretty active angel investor, such as in Paddle. When I sold my company I decided to do this full time and found there weren&#8217;t many entrepreneurial investors with startup experience themselves, compared to what you see in the U.S. So I put my entrepreneur hat on, trying to be as founder-friendly as possible. That was five years ago when Fuel Ventures started.”</p>
<p>He told me: &#8220;I still think there&#8217;s a funding gap between the seed and the Series A. We have always sat in the seed stage. We wanted to just write a decent check to allow these companies what it takes to hire the best talent, build out their product at scale and get them into the institutional funds. We can help you, we will roll up our sleeves, and we&#8217;re going to build the business with you. Our network of investors and LPS tend to be entrepreneur types as it is.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qf2shG4TAE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/venture-capital-is-going-to-get-even-bigger-faster-and-more-expensive-this-year/">Venture capital is going to get even bigger, faster and more expensive this year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Venture capital is going to get even bigger, faster and more expensive this year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/venture-capital-is-going-to-get-even-bigger-faster-and-more-expensive-this-year/embed/#?secret=qf2shG4TAE" data-secret="qf2shG4TAE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/fuel-ventures-launches-its-new-63-6m-early-stage-vc-fund-aiming-for-60-startups-inside-12-months/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164498</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Messenger adds Venmo-like QR codes for person-to-person payments in the US</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/messenger-adds-venmo-like-qr-codes-for-person-to-person-payments-in-the-u-s/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/messenger-adds-venmo-like-qr-codes-for-person-to-person-payments-in-the-u-s/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 16:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook messenger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messenger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[qr code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venmo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164486</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This spring, Facebook confirmed it was testing Venmo-like QR codes for person-to-person payments inside its app in the U.S. Today, the company announced those codes are now launching publicly to all U.S. users, allowing anyone to send or request money through Facebook Pay &#8212; even if they&#8217;re not Facebook friends. The QR codes work similarly [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This spring, Facebook <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/facebook-confirms-test-of-venmo-like-qr-codes-for-person-to-person-payments-in-u-s/">confirmed</a> it was testing Venmo-like QR codes for person-to-person payments inside its app in the U.S. Today, the company announced those codes are now launching publicly to all U.S. users, allowing anyone to send or request money through Facebook Pay &#8212; even if they&#8217;re not Facebook friends.</p>
<p>The QR codes work similarly to those found in other payment apps, like Venmo.</p>
<p>The feature can be found under the &#8220;Facebook Pay&#8221; section in Messenger&#8217;s settings, accessed by tapping on your profile icon at the top left of the screen. Here, you&#8217;ll be presented with your personalized QR code which looks much like a regular QR code except that it features your profile icon in the middle.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Underneath, you&#8217;ll be shown your personal Facebook Pay UR which is in the format of &#8220;https://m.me/pay/UserName.&#8221; This can also be copied and sent to other users when you&#8217;re requesting a payment.</p>
<p>Facebook notes that the codes will work between any U.S. Messenger users, and won&#8217;t require a separate payment app or any sort of contact entry or upload process to get started.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="I3dmcbjWPv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/facebook-confirms-test-of-venmo-like-qr-codes-for-person-to-person-payments-in-u-s/">Facebook confirms &#8216;test&#8217; of Venmo-like QR codes for person-to-person payments in US</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook confirms &#8216;test&#8217; of Venmo-like QR codes for person-to-person payments in US&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/facebook-confirms-test-of-venmo-like-qr-codes-for-person-to-person-payments-in-u-s/embed/#?secret=I3dmcbjWPv" data-secret="I3dmcbjWPv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Users who want to be able to send and receive money in Messenger have to be at least 18 years old, and will have to have a <a href="https://www.facebook.com/help/1528535330720775">Visa or Mastercard debit card</a>, a<a href="https://www.facebook.com/help/1528535330720775"> PayPal account</a> or one of the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/help/1528535330720775">supported</a> prepaid cards or government-issued cards, in order to use the payments feature. They’ll also need to <a href="https://www.facebook.com/help/217942441564255/">set</a> their preferred currency to U.S. dollars in the app.</p>
<p>After setup is complete, you can choose which payment method you want as your default and optionally protect payments behind a PIN code of your choosing.</p>
<p>The QR code is also available from the Facebook Pay section of the main Facebook app, in a carousel at the top of the screen.</p>
<p>Facebook Pay first <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2019/11/simplifying-payments-with-facebook-pay/">launched</a> in November 2019, as a way to establish a payment system that extends across the company’s apps for not just person-to-person payments, but also other features, like donations, Stars and e-commerce, among other things. Though the QR codes take cues from Venmo and others, the service as it stands today is not necessarily a rival to payment apps because Facebook partners with PayPal as one of the supported payment methods.</p>
<p>However, although the payments experience is separate from Facebook’s <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2020/05/welcome-to-novi/">cryptocurrency wallet</a>, <a href="https://www.novi.com/">Novi,</a> that&#8217;s something that could perhaps change in the future.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2164493" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164493" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2164493" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chat-Theme-Still-3-Up-Alt.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chat-Theme-Still-3-Up-Alt.png 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chat-Theme-Still-3-Up-Alt.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chat-Theme-Still-3-Up-Alt.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chat-Theme-Still-3-Up-Alt.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chat-Theme-Still-3-Up-Alt.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chat-Theme-Still-3-Up-Alt.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Chat-Theme-Still-3-Up-Alt.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164493" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>The feature was <a href="https://messengernews.fb.com/2021/06/10/new-chat-themes-and-more-now-on-messenger/">introduced</a> alongside a few other Messenger updates, including a new Quick Reply bar that makes it easier to respond to a photo or video without having to return to the main chat thread. Facebook also added new chat themes including one for Olivia Rodrigo fans, another for World Oceans Day, and one that promotes the new F9 movie.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LfrHmnaW8u"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/21/all-b2b-startups-are-in-the-payments-business/">All B2B startups are in the payments business</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;All B2B startups are in the payments business&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/21/all-b2b-startups-are-in-the-payments-business/embed/#?secret=LfrHmnaW8u" data-secret="LfrHmnaW8u" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/messenger-adds-venmo-like-qr-codes-for-person-to-person-payments-in-the-u-s/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164486</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Atomic-backed Jumpcut uses data to advance diversity in film</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/atomic-backed-jumpcut-uses-data-to-advance-diversity-in-film/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/atomic-backed-jumpcut-uses-data-to-advance-diversity-in-film/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 16:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[actress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advisors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atomic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buzzfeed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chuck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hollywood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jumpcut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kartik hosanagar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[producer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product manager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[svp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Include]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WarnerMedia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wattpad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2163933</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jumpcut founder Kartik Hosanagar is a professor at the Wharton School, but about 10 years ago, he spent his summer in an unlikely way: he wrote a screenplay. Set in India, his script garnered some interest from producers, but no one took the plunge to fund a film by a first-time Indian director. Now, films [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Jumpcut founder <a href="https://www.hosanagar.com/">Kartik Hosanagar</a> is a professor at the Wharton School, but about 10 years ago, he spent his summer in an unlikely way: he wrote a screenplay. Set in India, his script garnered some interest from producers, but no one took the plunge to fund a film by a first-time Indian director.</p>
<p>Now, films featuring diverse casts are gaining traction &#8212; this year, Chloé Zhao became the first woman of color, and only the second woman ever, to win the Academy Award for Best Director. At the previous ceremony, Bong Joon-ho&#8217;s &#8220;Parasite&#8221; became the first non-English language film to win the Academy Award for Best Picture. Still, according to a recent report from McKinsey &amp; Company, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/11/movies/hollywood-black-representation.html">Hollywood leaves $10 billion on the table</a> each year due to the industry&#8217;s lack of diversity.</p>
<p>&#8220;How do you make a bet on underrepresented voices or underrepresented stories?&#8221; asked Hosanagar. &#8220;While there&#8217;s awareness, there&#8217;s no action, because nobody knows how to do it. So that&#8217;s what got me into <a href="https://jumpcutmedia.com/">Jumpcut</a>. It&#8217;s this rare company where 20 years of my work on data science and entrepreneurship meets with who I am outside of my work.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>At Wharton, Hosanagar is the Faculty Lead for the <a href="https://analytics.wharton.upenn.edu/programs/ai-for-business/">AI for Business</a> program. He was a founder of Yodle, which was acquired by web.com for $340 million in 2016. But for this next venture, he wanted to tackle Hollywood&#8217;s homogeneity hands-on by using his experience with data science to de-risk media projects from underrepresented creators.</p>
<p>&#8220;The vision is to create a more inclusive era of global content creation,&#8221; he said to TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Hosanagar started working on Jumpcut in 2019, but today, the <a href="https://atomic.vc/">Atomic</a>-backed company launches out of stealth as the first data science-driven studio working to elevate underrepresented voices in film. Already the studio has 12 TV and film projects in the works, with partners like 36-time Academy Award nominee Lawrence Bender (&#8220;Pulp Fiction,&#8221; &#8220;Good Will Hunting&#8221;), Emmy Award-winning producer Shelby Stone (&#8220;Bessie,&#8221; &#8220;The Chi&#8221;) and showrunner Scott Rosenbaum (&#8220;Chuck,&#8221; &#8220;The Shield&#8221;).</p>
<p>Jumpcut models itself after Y Combinator in its approach, pairing emerging talent with buyers and producers. First, Jumpcut uses an algorithm to scan hundreds of thousands of videos from platforms like YouTube, Reddit and Wattpad to find promising talent. The algorithm narrows down the extensive field to locate creators who are consistently finding new audiences and increasing their engagement. Then, the Jumpcut team &#8212; including advisors and veterans from Netflix, BuzzFeed, CBS, Sony and WarnerMedia &#8212; identifies who to connect with.</p>
<p>In one example of the algorithm&#8217;s success, Hosanagar pointed to Anna Hopkins, an actress who has appeared on shows like &#8220;The Expanse&#8221; and &#8220;Shadowhunters.&#8221; Though Hopkins has found some success in front of the camera, she also wants to write.</p>
<p>&#8220;We discovered some of her short films, and the algorithm identified it because people had strong emotional reactions in the comments, like, &#8216;heartwarming but in a positive way,&#8217; or &#8216;give me a tissue,&#8217; &#8221; Hosanagar explained. Since Hopkins isn&#8217;t publicly known as a writer, she assumed that Jumpcut found her through a television network she had pitched a script to, but that wasn&#8217;t the case. &#8220;We said, &#8216;no, our algorithms found you.&#8217; &#8221;</p>
<p>Once a creator is identified by Jumpcut, they can A/B test their ideas with audiences of over 100,000 potential viewers, which helps the company prove to funders through data science that these ideas can sell.</p>
<p>&#8220;The idea there is that we don&#8217;t wait for creators to get discovered by the traditional Hollywood agencies, because that requires the creators to have access to the top agents, and that again brings you back to the old boys club,&#8221; Hosanagar said. &#8220;We&#8217;re automating a lot of that process and discovering these people who are creating great stories that are resonating with audiences, not waiting for some Hollywood agency to discover them.&#8221;</p>
<p>Once the creators have an idea that tests well with a wide audience, they&#8217;re invited to Jumpcut Collective, an incubator program that helps artists develop an idea from a concept to a pitch in six weeks. Then, Jumpcut helps match projects with producing partners and buyers.</p>
<p>So far, Jumpcut has hosted three incubator programs. Out of the 12 Jumpcut projects currently underway, Hosanagar says that nine or 10 of them came out of the incubator. One project, for example, is now being developed in partnership with Disney&#8217;s Asia Pacific Division.</p>
<p>Jumpcut isn&#8217;t disclosing the amount raised in this round of seed funding, but confirms that Atomic is the only investor in their seed round.</p>
<p>Hosanagar is joined on the project by Dilip Rajan, his former student and a former product manager at BuzzFeed, and Winnie Kemp, a former SVP of Originals at Super Deluxe and CBS. There, she developed and executive produced &#8220;Chambers,&#8221; the first show with a Native American lead, and &#8220;This Close,&#8221; the first show with deaf creators and cast. Most of their funding will go toward payroll, which includes engineers, data scientists and product managers on the product side of the company, as well as development executives on the creative side, who run the incubator.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fZdbBjSLbK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/17/a-diversity-and-inclusion-playbook/">A diversity and inclusion playbook</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A diversity and inclusion playbook&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/17/a-diversity-and-inclusion-playbook/embed/#?secret=fZdbBjSLbK" data-secret="fZdbBjSLbK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/atomic-backed-jumpcut-uses-data-to-advance-diversity-in-film/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2163933</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Widespread electrification requires us to rethink battery technology</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/widespread-electrification-requires-us-to-rethink-battery-technology/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/widespread-electrification-requires-us-to-rethink-battery-technology/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 15:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EVs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lithium ion batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rechargeable batteries]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2163707</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The global transition to electrification has increased demand for longer-lasting and faster-charging batteries. But battery innovation hasn’t kept pace with society’s ambitions. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Moshiel Biton</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/moshielb">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Dr. <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/moshiel/?originalSubdomain=il">Moshiel Biton</a> is the CEO and co-founder of <a href="https://www.addionics.com/">Addionics</a>, a battery technology company providing AI-optimized, Smart 3D Electrodes for the next generation of energy storage.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The global economy’s transition to widespread electrification has increased the demand for longer-lasting and faster-charging batteries across industries including transportation, consumer electronics, medical devices and residential energy storage. While the benefits of this transition are well understood, the reality is that battery innovation hasn’t kept pace with society’s ambitions.</p>
<p>With<a href="https://public.wmo.int/en/media/press-release/new-climate-predictions-increase-likelihood-of-temporarily-reaching-15-%C2%B0c-next-5"> reports forecasting a 40% chance</a> that the world’s temperature will rise over the next five years beyond the limit of 1.5 degrees Celsius laid out in the Paris climate agreement, it is clear that there’s little time to waste when it comes to creating next-generation batteries, which can easily take <a href="https://www.autoweek.com/news/green-cars/a35367888/the-eternal-promise-of-solid-state-batteries/">another 10 years to fully commercialize</a>.</p>
<p>To meet the increasing pressures to electrify, a completely novel approach to building batteries is the only way to scale rechargeable batteries quickly enough to curb greenhouse-gas emissions globally and avoid the worst-case scenario for the climate crisis.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>The challenges to battery innovation</h2>
<p>Over the last few decades, battery experts, automakers, Tier 1 suppliers, investors and others looking to electrify have spent billions of dollars globally on creating next-generation batteries by focusing predominantly on battery chemistry. Yet the industry is still grappling with two major fundamental technical challenges that are stunting the proliferation of batteries:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Energy/power tradeoff: </strong>All batteries manufactured today face an energy-to-power tradeoff. Batteries can store more energy <em>or</em> they can charge/discharge more quickly. In terms of electric vehicles, this means no single battery can provide both long range and fast charging.</li>
<li><strong>Anode-cathode mismatch: </strong>Today’s most promising battery technologies maximize the energy density of anodes, the negative electrode of the pair of electrodes that make up every lithium-ion battery cell. However, anodes already have greater energy density than their positive counterpart, the cathode. Cathode energy density needs to eventually match that of the anode in order to get the most energy storage capacity out of a certain battery size. Without breakthroughs in increasing cathode energy density, many of today’s most exciting battery technologies will not be able to deliver on their full potential. As it currently stands, the most commonly used lithium-ion battery cannot meet the needs of the wide-ranging applications of an all-electric future. Many companies have tried to address these demands through new battery chemistries to optimize the high-power-to-energy-density ratio to varying degrees of success, but very few are close to achieving the performance metrics required for mass scale and commercialization.</li>
</ol>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Ultimately, the winning technologies in the race toward total electrification will be the ones that have the most significant impact on performance, lowered costs and compatibility with existing manufacturing infrastructure.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<h2>Are solid-state batteries the holy grail?</h2>
<p>Battery researchers have championed the solid-state battery as the holy grail of battery technology due to its ability to achieve high energy density and increased safety. However, until recently, the technology has fallen short in practice.</p>
<p>Solid-state batteries have significantly higher energy density and are potentially safer because they do not use flammable liquid electrolytes. However, the technology is still nascent and has a long way to go to achieve commercialization. The manufacturing process for solid-state batteries has to be improved to lower costs, especially for an automotive industry that aims to achieve aggressive cost reductions as low as $50/kWh in the coming years.</p>
<p>The other substantial challenge to implementing solid-state technology is the limitation of total energy density that can be stored in the cathodes per unit of volume. The obvious solution to this dilemma would be to have batteries with thicker cathodes. However, a thicker cathode would reduce the mechanical and thermal stability of the battery. That instability leads to delamination (a mode of failure where a material fractures into layers), cracks and separation &#8212; all of which cause premature battery failure. In addition, thicker cathodes limit diffusion and decrease power. The result is that there is a practical limit to the thickness of cathodes, which restricts the power of anodes.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3d7ulgV9Ns"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/can-solid-state-batteries-power-up-for-the-next-generation-of-evs/">Can solid state batteries power up for the next generation of EVs?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Can solid state batteries power up for the next generation of EVs?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/can-solid-state-batteries-power-up-for-the-next-generation-of-evs/embed/#?secret=3d7ulgV9Ns" data-secret="3d7ulgV9Ns" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>New takes on materials with silicon</h2>
<p>In most cases, companies that are developing silicon-based batteries are mixing up to 30% silicon with graphite to boost energy density. The batteries made by <a href="https://silanano.com/">Sila Nanotechnologies</a> are an illustrative example of using a silicon mix to increase energy density. Another approach is to use 100% pure silicon anodes, which are limited by very thin electrodes and high production costs, to generate even higher energy density, like <a href="https://www.amprius.com/technology">Amprius’</a> approach.</p>
<p>While silicon provides considerably greater energy density, there is a significant drawback that has limited its adoption until now: The material undergoes volume expansion and shrinkage while charging and discharging, limiting battery life and performance. This leads to degradation issues that manufacturers need to solve before commercial adoption. Despite those challenges, some silicon-based batteries are already being deployed commercially, including in the automotive sector, where Tesla leads in silicon adoption for EVs.</p>
<h2>The imperative for electrification requires a new focus on battery design</h2>
<p>Advances to battery architecture and cell design show significant promise for unlocking improvements with existing and emerging battery chemistries.</p>
<p>Probably the most notable from a mainstream perspective is Tesla’s “biscuit tin” battery cell that the company unveiled at its 2020 Battery Day. It&#8217;s still using lithium-ion chemistry, but the company removed the tabs in the cell that act as the positive and negative connection points between the anode and cathode and the battery casing, and instead use a shingled design within the cell. This change in design helps reduce manufacturing costs while boosting driving range and removes many of the thermal barriers that a cell can encounter when fast-charging with DC electricity.</p>
<p>Transitioning away from a traditional 2D electrode structure to a 3D structure is another approach that is gaining traction in the industry. The 3D structure yields high energy <em>and</em> high power performance in both the anode and cathode for every battery chemistry.</p>
<p>Although still in the R&amp;D and testing phases, 3D electrodes have achieved two times higher accessible capacity, 50% less charging time and 150% longer lifetime for high-performance products at market-competitive prices. Therefore, in order to advance battery capabilities to unlock the full potential of energy storage for a range of applications, it is critical to develop solutions that emphasize altering the physical structure of batteries.</p>
<h2>Winning the battery race</h2>
<p>It’s not just performance improvements that will win the battery race, but perfecting production and cost reduction as well. To capture a considerable share of the ballooning battery market that is projected to reach <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2021/04/08/2206703/28124/en/Global-Battery-Market-Report-2020-2027.html">$279.7 billion by 2027</a>, countries around the world must find ways to achieve low-cost battery manufacturing at scale. Prioritizing “drop-in” solutions and innovative production methods that can be incorporated with existing assembly lines and materials will be key.</p>
<p>The Biden administration’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/18/fact-sheet-the-american-jobs-plan-supercharges-the-future-of-transportation-and-manufacturing/">American Jobs Plan</a> highlights the importance of domestic battery production to the country’s goal of being a leader in electrification while meeting ambitious carbon reduction targets. Commitments like these will play a key role in establishing who can maintain a critical competitive edge in the battery space and take the largest share of <a href="https://www.alliedmarketresearch.com/electric-vehicle-market">the $162 billion global EV market</a>.</p>
<p>Ultimately, the winning technologies in the race toward total electrification will be the ones that have the most significant impact on performance, lowered costs and compatibility with existing manufacturing infrastructure. By taking a holistic approach and focusing more on innovating cell design while also fine-tuning leading chemistries, we can achieve the next steps in battery performance and rapid commercialization that the world desperately needs.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OqguTcYN1h"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/giving-ev-batteries-a-second-life-for-sustainability-and-profit/">Giving EV batteries a second life for sustainability and profit</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Giving EV batteries a second life for sustainability and profit&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/giving-ev-batteries-a-second-life-for-sustainability-and-profit/embed/#?secret=OqguTcYN1h" data-secret="OqguTcYN1h" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/widespread-electrification-requires-us-to-rethink-battery-technology/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2163707</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cityblock&#8217;s Iya Romm and Maverick Ventures&#8217; Ambar Bhattacharyya are joining us on Extra Crunch Live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/cityblocks-iya-romm-and-maverick-ventures-ambar-bhattacharyya-are-joining-us-on-extra-crunch-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/cityblocks-iya-romm-and-maverick-ventures-ambar-bhattacharyya-are-joining-us-on-extra-crunch-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 15:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ambar Bhattacharyya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Live]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iya Romm]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164088</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If the pandemic achieved anything good, it was putting health front and center in the minds of the general public, elected officials, investors and innovators. Cityblock has been working on solutions for bringing together the healthcare industry and communities since long before now, but it raised a total of $372 million spanning December through March, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If the pandemic achieved anything good, it was putting health front and center in the minds of the general public, elected officials, investors and innovators. Cityblock has been working on solutions for bringing together the healthcare industry and communities since long before now, but it raised a total of $372 million spanning December through March, so it&#8217;s definitely seeing the impact of the visibility of its mission in light of a worldwide healthcare crisis.</p>
<p>On <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-maverick-ventures-and-cityblock-health?ref=f959abde89a4">June 30 at noon PT/3PM ET</a>, Cityblock co-founder and CEO Iyah Romm will join us for an episode of Extra Crunch Live, along with Cityblock investor and Maverick Ventures managing partner Ambar Bhattacharyya. We&#8217;ll talk about the process of fundraising for this critical area in urgent need of innovation, and what it&#8217;s like trying to manage that process when the business you&#8217;re in is experiencing one of its busiest and most fraught times ever. <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-maverick-ventures-and-cityblock-health?ref=f959abde89a4">Register here for free</a>.</p>
<p>Romm and Bhattacharyya will also be providing live feedback to participants in our weekly Extra Crunch Live pitch-off, which you can apply to join live during the event.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>But we&#8217;ve talked about Cityblock a bit, let&#8217;s take a step back and look at our guests.</p>
<p>Iyah Romm co-founded Cityblock in 2017 and has been its chief executive ever since. Before that, he was entrepreneur in residence at Sidewalk Labs, from which Cityblock spun out. He has a long history in public health and private care, including as chief transformation officer at Commonwealth Care Alliance, and a stint at the Health Policy Commission and the Massachusetts Department of Public Health.</p>
<p>Bhattacharyya has spent more than a decade in VC, including at Bessemer and Bain, as well as in his current role at Maverick Ventures. His track record includes investments in companies that have had a total of 11 exists via IPO and acquisition, including four public market unicorns. His specific focus has been on early and growth-stage healthcare companies, so it&#8217;s a space he knows very well.</p>
<p>Maverick participated in Cityblock&#8217;s Series A, as well as its Series B and both the C and C extension rounds from this past year.</p>
<p>The episode goes down at noon PT/3PM ET on June 30 and is free to all who want to check it out live. On-demand access to the content is reserved for Extra Crunch members only. <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-maverick-ventures-and-cityblock-health?ref=f959abde89a4">Register to come hang out with us here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/cityblocks-iya-romm-and-maverick-ventures-ambar-bhattacharyya-are-joining-us-on-extra-crunch-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164088</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Final 2 days for early-bird savings to TC Early Stage 2021: Marketing &#038; Fundraising</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/final-2-days-for-early-bird-savings-to-tc-early-stage-2021-marketing-fundraising/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/final-2-days-for-early-bird-savings-to-tc-early-stage-2021-marketing-fundraising/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 15:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Early Stage 2021: Marketing & Fundraising]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2162030</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Listen up, all you budget-conscious early-stage founders. That sound you hear is the countdown clock for serious savings to TC Early Stage 2021: Marketing &#38; Fundraising on July 8-9. You have just two days left to score early-bird savings and keep $100 in your wallet. Want loads of opportunity for less money? Beat the deadline [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Listen up, all you budget-conscious early-stage founders. That sound you hear is the countdown clock for serious savings to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/?promo=5reasonspost&amp;display=true">TC Early Stage 2021: Marketing &amp; Fundraising</a> on July 8-9. You have just two days left to score early-bird savings and keep $100 in your wallet. Want loads of opportunity for less money? Beat the deadline and <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/#tickets">register here</a> before Friday, June 11 at 11:59 p.m. (PT)</strong>.</p>
<p>We’ve packed this two-day virtual event with more than a dozen (and counting) presentations by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/#3e01330b-4bf1-4206-b038-769db50898a0">leading startup experts</a> holding forth on a range of topics every startup founder needs to master — or at least understand enough to outsource wisely. We’re talking essentials like product-market fit, paid marketing strategies and, every founder’s favorite topic, fundraising.</p>
<p>But this isn’t a one-way situation. Nope, these are highly interactive sessions, and you’ll have plenty of time to get answers to your most pressing questions. Check <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/#eb734612-27f1-4c57-96ec-246fab3228a8">the event agenda</a> and start planning your schedule.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Here’s just a taste of the topics on tap:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>How to Line Up Your Growth with Your Goals:</strong> Unlike giant brands, startups need to use their marketing spend wisely and efficiently. Sound Ventures’ Susan Su is a growth marketing expert and will share how to define growth based on your startup’s goals, and how to take a framework-based approach to growth, rather than relying on old playbooks that aren’t relevant.</li>
<li><strong>How to Navigate the Ever-Changing World of Early-Stage VC:</strong> With over 25 personal investments, AngelList Venture CEO Avlok Kohli knows a thing or two about early-stage fundraising. At Early Stage, Kohli will explain the landscape of the early-stage fundraising market and how to take advantage of the changes in the VC world over the past year.</li>
<li><strong>Nail the Narrative:</strong> Storytelling is a critical skill for startups. Coatue Management partner Caryn Marooney, formerly head of comms for Facebook, Instagram, WhatsApp and Oculus, will share how to frame the narrative for a startup depending on the audience and ensure that when you’re talking about your company, people are not only listening, but they want to learn more.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Pro Tip:</strong> Your pass includes access to video-on-demand. With VOD flexibility, you can watch sessions you missed and/or review sessions you attended to absorb the details on a cellular level.</p>
<p>Still on the fence? Here’s what Ashley Barrington, founder of MarketPearl, told us about her experience at Early Stage 2020:</p>
<blockquote><p>I recommend going to Early Stage. The virtual aspect helps in terms of scheduling, it offers community-building through networking, and it gives early-stage founders a framework for navigating the startup ecosystem. This is the stage where founders need more support, especially if they haven’t done this before.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/?promo=5reasonspost&amp;display=true">TC Early Stage 2021: Marketing &amp; Fundraising</a> takes place on July 8-9, but the clock is ticking. If you want to save $100, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/#tickets">buy your pass</a> before <strong>Friday, June 11 at 11:59 p.m. (PT)</strong>. Find loads of opportunity for less money. It’s the TechCrunch way!</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at Early Stage 2021 – Marketing &amp; Fundraising? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-5411631f4bb18bf52c73b95079bc13e0"
			width="99%"
			height="1010"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/5411631f4bb18bf52c73b95079bc13e0"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="bizzabo"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-5411631f4bb18bf52c73b95079bc13e0')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-5411631f4bb18bf52c73b95079bc13e0'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/final-2-days-for-early-bird-savings-to-tc-early-stage-2021-marketing-fundraising/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2162030</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Money Minx aims to build a &#8216;Personal Finance&#8217; OS for the everyday investor</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/money-minx-aims-to-build-a-personal-finance-os-for-the-everyday-investor/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/money-minx-aims-to-build-a-personal-finance-os-for-the-everyday-investor/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 15:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crowdfunding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial advisor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Money Minx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san diego]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TrueBill]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2164428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New regulations are making it easier to invest in alternative assets via crowdfunding, and the recent explosion of crypto and NFTs means that investors are more diversified than ever.  Keeping up with such a variety of investments may prove difficult to those who want to handle managing their investment portfolios on their own. Money Minx, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">New regulations are making it easier to invest in alternative assets via </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/gumroad-wants-to-make-equity-crowdfunding-mainstream/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">crowdfunding</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and the recent explosion of crypto and NFTs means that investors are more diversified than ever. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keeping up with such a variety of investments may prove difficult to those who want to handle managing their investment portfolios </span><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/11/11/99percent-of-americans-dont-use-a-financial-advisor-heres-why.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">on their own</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><a href="https://www.moneyminx.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Money Minx</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a new San Diego-based startup co-founded by husband and wife team Hussein and Jessica Yahfoufi, wants to help with that.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Put simply, Money Minx aims to build a &#8220;Personal Finance OS&#8221; for every household. The platform is designed to help people track all of their investments &#8212; yes, including crypto and NFTs &#8212; in one place, in whatever currency. The company claims that its AI can also go a step further, and help people spot opportunities in their portfolio as well as catch potential risks.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We built Money Minx to help people cover all their bases, better understand their personal balance sheet and grow their net worth,” Hussein said. “No financial advisor needed.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Money Minx also aims to provide people with easy-to-use tools to create dashboards and reports. In its &#8220;soft launch&#8221; phase, the startup has been growing rapidly &#8212; from $15 million in assets tracked at the end of March to $107 million by mid-May. Its user base is growing by 40% month over month.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MVmc63Frwn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/alexa-von-tobel-outlines-how-founders-should-manage-personal-finances/">Alexa von Tobel outlines how founders should manage personal finances</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Alexa von Tobel outlines how founders should manage personal finances&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/alexa-von-tobel-outlines-how-founders-should-manage-personal-finances/embed/#?secret=MVmc63Frwn" data-secret="MVmc63Frwn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As many founders do, Hussein says he and Jessica developed the platform to meet a need of their own.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We built this because we needed it as ‘do it yourself investors,’ said Hussein, who previously started crowdfunding site </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/06/03/appsplit-is-crowdfunding-for-apps/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">appsplit</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and works as a CTO at a San Diego-based fintech company. “I didn’t </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">want to hire a financial advisor and spend 1% of my portfolio every year for them to tell me what to do. So I started to do it on my own on a spreadsheet and then started building this tool last year.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hussein talked to other investors and realized that many were also managing their own finances and had also moved into investing outside the stock market.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2164446" style="width: 235px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164446" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-2164446" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Hussein.jpg?w=225" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Hussein.jpg 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Hussein.jpg?resize=113,150 113w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Hussein.jpg?resize=225,300 225w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Hussein.jpg?resize=768,1024 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Hussein.jpg?resize=510,680 510w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Hussein.jpg?resize=1152,1536 1152w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Hussein.jpg?resize=38,50 38w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164446" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Money Minx co-founders Jessica and Hussein Yahfoufi / Money Minx</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Everyday investors are preferring to invest more in crowdfunding sites and </span><a href="https://www.preqin.com/insights/research/reports/alternatives-in-2021"><span style="font-weight: 400;">alternative assets</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> than the traditional stock market,&#8221; he said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This shift has created a gap in the market for an easy way to track investments across multiple platforms, the Yahfoufis believe. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Money Minx operates as a SaaS business and charges a monthly subscription fee across three different plans ranging from $10 to $30 a month. Looking ahead, Hussein is considering building out a white-glove service.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although Money Minx has been approached by interested VCs, Hussein says the company prefers to stay bootstrapped &#8212; for now.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Indeed, VCs are pouring money into the space. Just last week, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">personal finance startup Truebill announced it had raised </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/01/truebill-raises-45-million-for-its-personal-finance-app/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a $45 million Series D funding round </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">led by Accel.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mwUt7LQXA0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/01/truebill-raises-45-million-for-its-personal-finance-app/">Truebill raises $45 million for its personal finance app</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Truebill raises $45 million for its personal finance app&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/01/truebill-raises-45-million-for-its-personal-finance-app/embed/#?secret=mwUt7LQXA0" data-secret="mwUt7LQXA0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/money-minx-aims-to-build-a-personal-finance-os-for-the-everyday-investor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2164428</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple&#8217;s StoreKit 2 simplifies App Store subscriptions and refunds by making them accessible inside apps</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/apples-storekit-2-simplifies-app-store-subscriptions-and-refunds-by-making-them-accessible-inside-apps/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/apples-storekit-2-simplifies-app-store-subscriptions-and-refunds-by-making-them-accessible-inside-apps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 15:43:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app stores]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple id]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Refunds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RevenueCat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscriptions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WWDC 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2163786</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;ve ever bought a subscription inside an iOS app and later decided you wanted to cancel, upgrade or downgrade, or ask for a refund, you may have had trouble figuring out how to go about making that request or change. Some people today still believe that they can stop their subscription charges simply by [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If you&#8217;ve ever bought a subscription inside an iOS app and later decided you wanted to cancel, upgrade or downgrade, or ask for a refund, you may have had trouble figuring out how to go about making that request or change. Some people today still believe that they can stop their subscription charges simply by deleting an app from their iPhone. Others may dig around unsuccessfully inside their iPhone&#8217;s Settings or on the App Store to try to find out how to ask for a refund. With the updates Apple announced in <a href="https://developer.apple.com/storekit/">StoreKit 2</a> during its Worldwide Developers Conference this week, things may start to get a little easier for app customers.</p>
<p>StoreKit is Apple&#8217;s developer framework for managing in-app purchases &#8212; an area that&#8217;s become more complex in recent years, as apps have transitioned from offering one-time purchases to ongoing subscriptions with different tiers, lengths and feature sets.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2163943" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2163943" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2163943" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-12.59.21-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="308" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-12.59.21-PM.jpg 1198w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-12.59.21-PM.jpg?resize=150,68 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-12.59.21-PM.jpg?resize=300,136 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-12.59.21-PM.jpg?resize=768,347 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-12.59.21-PM.jpg?resize=680,308 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-09-at-12.59.21-PM.jpg?resize=50,23 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2163943" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Currently, users who want to manage or <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202039">cancel subscriptions</a> can do so from the App Store or their iPhone Settings. But some don&#8217;t realize the path to this section from Settings starts by tapping on your Apple ID (your name and profile photo at the top of the screen). They may also get frustrated if they&#8217;re not familiar with how to navigate their Settings or the App Store.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, there are a <a href="https://www.imore.com/how-to-get-refund-itunes-app-store">variety of ways</a> users can request refunds on their in-app subscriptions. They can dig in their inbox for their receipt from Apple, then click the &#8220;Report a Problem&#8221; link it includes to request a refund when something went wrong. This could be useful in scenarios where you&#8217;ve bought a subscription by mistake (or your kid has!), or where the promised features didn&#8217;t work as intended.</p>
<p>Apple also<a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT204084"> provides</a> a <a href="https://reportaproblem.apple.com/?s=6">dedicated website</a> where users can directly request refunds for apps or content. (When you Google for something like &#8220;request a refund apple&#8221; or similar queries, a page that explains the process typically comes up at the top of the search results.)</p>
<p>Still, many users aren&#8217;t technically savvy. For them, the easiest way to manage subscriptions or ask for refunds would be to do so from within the app itself. For this reason, many conscientious app developers tend to include links to point customers to Apple&#8217;s pages for subscription management or refunds inside their apps.</p>
<p>But StoreKit 2 is introducing new tools that will allow developers to implement these sort of features more easily.</p>
<p>One new tool is a Manage subscriptions API, which lets an app developer display the manage subscriptions page for their customer directly inside their app &#8212; without redirecting the customer to the App Store. Optionally, developers can choose to display a &#8220;Save Offer&#8221; screen to present the customer with a discount of some kind to keep them from cancelling, or it could display an exit survey so you can ask the customer why they decided to end their subscription.</p>
<p>When implemented, the customer will be able to view a screen inside the app that looks just like the one they&#8217;d visit in the App Store to cancel or change a subscription. After canceling, they&#8217;ll be shown a confirmation screen with the cancellation details and the service expiration date.</p>
<p>If the customer wants to request a refund, a new Refund request API will allow the customer to begin their refund request directly in the app itself &#8212; again, without being redirected to the App Store or other website. On the screen that displays, the customer can select for which item they want a refund and check the reason why they&#8217;re making the request. Apple handles the refund process and will send either an approval or refund declined notification back to the developer&#8217;s server.</p>
<p>However, some developers argue that the changes don&#8217;t go far enough. They want to be in charge of managing customer subscriptions and handling refunds themselves, through programmatic means. Plus, Apple can <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT210904">take up to 48 hours</a> for the customer to receive an update on their refund request, which can be confusing.</p>
<p>&#8220;They&#8217;ve made the process a bit smoother, but developers still can&#8217;t initiate refunds or cancellations themselves,&#8221; notes <a href="https://www.revenuecat.com/">RevenueCat</a> CEO Jacob Eiting, whose company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/revenuecat-raises-40m-series-b-for-its-in-app-subscription-platform/">provides tools</a> to app developers to manage their in-app purchases. &#8220;It&#8217;s a step in the right direction, but could actually lead to more confusion between developers and consumers about who is responsible for issuing refunds.&#8221;</p>
<p>In other words, because the forms are now going to be more accessible from inside the app, the customer may believe the developer is handling the refund process when, really, Apple continues to do so.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">People could write in after uninstalling the app. Or have subscribed on a device they no longer have. There are so many cases that this ignores.</p>
<p>This is only a marginal improvement over opening the manage subscriptions URL.</p>
<p>&mdash; Jacob Eiting (@jeiting) <a href="https://twitter.com/jeiting/status/1402232229196140551?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 8, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Some developers pointed out that there are other scenarios this process doesn&#8217;t address. For example, if the customer has already uninstalled the app or no longer has the device in question, they&#8217;ll still need to be directed to other means of asking for refunds, just as before.</p>
<p>For consumers, though, subscription management tools like this mean more developers may begin to put buttons to manage subscriptions and ask for refunds directly inside their app, which is a better experience. In time, as customers learn they can more easily use the app and manage subscriptions, app developers may see better customer retention, higher engagement, and better App Store reviews, notes Apple.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">The new additions to SwiftUI, been wanting Pull to Refresh and to improve accessibility. Then surprisingly StoreKit 2, especially for users requesting refunds and managaging subscriptions seamlessly (also great for Buffer).</p>
<p>&mdash; Andrew Yates (@ay8s) <a href="https://twitter.com/ay8s/status/1402263554514952213?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 8, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The StoreKit 2 changes weren&#8217;t limited to APIs for managing subscriptions and refunds.</p>
<p>Developers will also gain access to a new Invoice Lookup API that allows them to look up the in-app purchases for the customer, validate their invoice and identify any problems with the purchase &#8212; for example, if there were any refunds already provided by the App Store.</p>
<p>A new Refunded Purchases API will allow developers to look up all the refunds for the customer.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Sounds like StoreKit can validate receipts on device and allow users to request refunds. Didn’t have those on my bingo card but wow those are some nice quality-of-life updates!</p>
<p>&mdash; Conrad Stoll (@conradstoll) <a href="https://twitter.com/conradstoll/status/1402006616438820874?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 7, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>A new Renewal Extension API will allow developers to extend the renewal data for paid, active subscriptions in the case of an outage &#8212; like when dealing with customer support issues when a streaming service went down, for example. This API lets developers extend the subscription up to twice per calendar year, each up to 90 days in the future.</p>
<p>And finally, a new Consumption API will allow developers to share information about a customer&#8217;s in-app purchase with the App Store. In most cases, customers begin consuming content soon after purchase &#8212; information that&#8217;s helpful in the refund decision process. The API will allow the App Store to see if the user consumed the in-app purchase partially, fully, or not at all.</p>
<p>Another change will help customers when they reinstall apps or download them on new devices. Before, users would have to manually &#8220;restore purchases&#8221; to sync the status of the completed transactions back to that newly downloaded or reinstalled app. Now, that information will be automatically fetched by StoreKit 2 so the apps are immediately up-to-date with whatever it is the user paid for.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Very interesting changes to StoreKit. Apps will now be able to automatically restore and sync purchases, so users won&#39;t need to restore when the app is reinstalled or downloaded on a new device! <a href="https://t.co/WSs6L9rTvK">https://t.co/WSs6L9rTvK</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Marcos Tanaka (@mactanaka) <a href="https://twitter.com/mactanaka/status/1402328794430590985?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 8, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>While, overall, the changes make for a significant update to the StoreKit framework, Apple&#8217;s hesitancy to allow developers more control over their own subscription-based customers speaks, in part, to how much it wants to control in-app purchases. This is perhaps because it got burned in the past when it tried allowing developers to manage their own refunds.</p>
<p>As <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423410/apple-hulu-subscription-in-app-purchase-tweet">The Verge noted last month</a> while the Epic Games-Apple antitrust trial was underway, Apple had once provided Hulu will access to a subscription API, then discovered Hulu had been offering a way to automatically cancel subscriptions made through the App Store when customers wanted to upgrade to higher-priced subscription plans. Apple realized it needed to take action to protect against this misuse of the API, and Hulu later lost access. It has not since made that API more broadly available.</p>
<p>On the flip side, having Apple, not the developers, in charge of subscription management and refunds means Apple takes on the responsibilities around preventing fraud &#8212; including fraud perpetrated by both customers and developers alike. Customers may also prefer that there&#8217;s one single place to go for managing their subscription billing: Apple. They may not want to have to deal with each developer individually, as their experience would end up being inconsistent.</p>
<p>These changes matter because subscription revenue contributes to a sizable amount of Apple&#8217;s lucrative App Store business. Ahead of WWDC 21, Apple <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/apples-app-store-facilitated-643-billion-in-commerce-up-24-from-last-year/">reported</a> the sale of digital goods and services on the App Store grew to $86 billion in 2020, up 40% over the the year prior. Earlier this year, Apple <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/01/apple-services-entertain-inform-and-connect-the-world-in-unprecedented-year/">said it paid out more than $200 billion</a> to developers since the App Store launched in 2008.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/WWDC-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/wwdc-2021-banner.jpg" alt="read more about Apple's WWDC 2021 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/apples-storekit-2-simplifies-app-store-subscriptions-and-refunds-by-making-them-accessible-inside-apps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2163786</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
