<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 15:35:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Snapchat revamps creator payouts by offering chance to win prizes with Spotlight Challenges</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/snapchat-revamps-creator-payouts-by-offering-chance-to-win-prizes-with-spotlight-challenges/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/snapchat-revamps-creator-payouts-by-offering-chance-to-win-prizes-with-spotlight-challenges/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 15:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snap inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vertical Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As competition for creator talent heats up, Snap today introduced a series of new tools, programs, and features that will enable creators on its platform to generate revenue. These include the expansion of a Gifting feature to worldwide creators, the expansion of the Creator Marketplace to include Snap Stars (top creators with verified accounts), the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As competition for creator talent heats up, Snap today <a href="https://newsroom.snap.com/spotlight-challenges">introduced</a> a series of new tools, programs, and features that will enable creators on its platform to generate revenue. These include the expansion of a Gifting feature to worldwide creators, the expansion of the Creator Marketplace to include Snap Stars (top creators with verified accounts), the launch of a how-to resource called the Creator Hub, and a new way for Snapchat creators to be rewarded for making short-form video for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/snapchat-launches-a-tiktok-like-feed-called-spotlight-kick-started-by-paying-creators/">its in-app TikTok rival,</a> known as Spotlight.</p>
<p>The latter, called Spotlight Challenges, will offer cash prizes for top-performing Spotlight content, as directed by Snap itself. This is different from other social apps&#8217; Creator Funds, which pay out based on metrics like views and engagement to anyone who qualifies. Instead, this is a &#8220;chance&#8221; to win cash where each individual challenge will reward an average of 3 to 5 creators as the winners &#8212; though sometimes that figure will be more or less, Snap notes. The minimum prize will be $250. Typically, the total prize pots for individual challenges will range from $1,000 to $25,000, but Snap says it may sometimes offer a larger sum.</p>
<p>The challenges will be designed to encourage the use of specific Lenses, Sounds or #Topics, rather than paying out for any top-performing content. These challenges will be featured on Spotlight&#8217;s &#8220;Trending&#8221; page, which you access by tapping the trending up icon in the top-right of Spotlight&#8217;s main screen in the Snapchat app. Here, users will be able to view the available challenges, read the details about submission details and associated prize, then tap to open the camera and create content.</p>
<p>The addition follows complaints expressed by Snap creators who had earlier this year <a href="https://www.socialmediatoday.com/news/snapchat-creators-report-frustration-with-spotlight-payments-as-spotlight-u/602906/">grown frustrated</a> with Spotlight payment delays and later, the dwindling amount of money they could earn. While previously, Snap was paying out an incredible $1 million per day to get its TikTok competitor Spotlight off the ground, it <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/05/20/media/snapchat-spotlight/index.html">stopped</a> that program in late May saying it would decrease payments to&#8221;millions&#8221; per month as of June.</p>
<p>But creators who had grown to expect larger paydays were not happy with the change, and <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/11/snap-creators-say-theyre-leaving-the-apps-spotlight-feature-as-payments-dry-up.html">some began to look for better opportunities on other apps</a>. Today, there are many options to choose from, as Facebook, Instagram, YouTube, TikTok and Twitter are all trying to woo creators in their own ways &#8212; including, in some cases, with direct payments in addition to revenue sharing from ads.</p>
<p>Snap&#8217;s <a href="https://www.snap.com/terms/spotlight-challenges-official-rules">new system</a> of &#8220;challenges&#8221; would seem to offer a bit more transparency around payments, as creators will be able to see in advance what the prizes may be. But on the flip side, and perhaps most importantly, it signals to creators there is no guaranteed payday coming here &#8212; it&#8217;s a &#8220;prize,&#8221; not a paycheck. That means creators could still produce well-performing content and not &#8220;win&#8221; the cash.</p>
<p>However, Snap tells TechCrunch it&#8217;s not replacing creator payouts with prizes. The new feature will be in addition to the millions it distributes per month to the top Spotlight creators.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The new feature will be rolled out in the U.S. next month on iOS and Android before expanding to more markets.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2213477" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Gifting_Sending.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Gifting_Sending.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Gifting_Sending.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Gifting_Sending.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Gifting_Sending.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Gifting_Sending.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Gifting_Sending.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Gifting_Sending.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>Other additions today include a <a href="https://creators.snap.com/">Snapchat Creator Hub</a> that offers information about getting started in Spotlight and other tips and the expansion of the Gifting feature to Snap Stars worldwide (see above). This feature <a href="https://newsroom.snap.com/new-tools-and-monetization-opportunities-for-creators">had been announced in May</a> and allows fans to support creators using Snap Tokens through Story Replies. The Snap Stars receive a share of the revenue from the Gifts they receive, as a sort of virtual tip.</p>
<p>Snap is also expanding the<a href="https://creatormarketplace.tiktok.com/"> Creator Marketplace,</a> which was previously <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/snap-to-launch-a-new-creator-marketplace-this-month-initially-focused-on-lens-creators/">working to connect Lens creators</a>, developers and partners with businesses who wanted to run AR ads with their support.</p>
<p>Now, the marketplace will serve another purpose as well: it will connect businesses with Snap Stars worldwide for brand deals. This is how creator marketplaces across other top social platforms, like <a href="https://www.facebook.com/creators/introducing-brand-collabs-manager">Facebook, Instagram</a>, <a href="https://creatormarketplace.tiktok.com/">TikTok</a>, and <a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/9385307?hl=en">YouTube</a> already work, so this is a bit of catch-up on Snap&#8217;s part.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2213475" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Creator-Marketplace.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Creator-Marketplace.png 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Creator-Marketplace.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Creator-Marketplace.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Creator-Marketplace.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Creator-Marketplace.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Creator-Marketplace.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Creator-Marketplace.png?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Creator-Marketplace.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>Related to this move, Snap is also introducing a &#8220;Sponsored by&#8221; tag for businesses with Public Profiles so Snap Stars can tag brands in their sponsored content for transparency. In this case, 100% of the transactions will go directly to creators, Snap says.</p>
<p>Despite the changes to Snap&#8217;s earlier monetization efforts, the company claims the production of Spotlight content is booming. During its second-quarter earnings, Snap said Spotlight submissions more than tripled, daily time spent per user in the U.S. grew over 60% from the prior quarter, and daily active users were up 49%.</p>
<p>To date, Snap has paid out over $130 million to creators, it says. And it has seen &#8220;all-time highs&#8221; in terms of the number of creators posting to Spotlight since the June 1 revamp, the company noted.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/snapchat-revamps-creator-payouts-by-offering-chance-to-win-prizes-with-spotlight-challenges/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213417</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Y Combinator-backed CostCertified lands $8.45M to build the &#8216;Amazon for construction&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/y-combinator-backed-costcertified-lands-8-45m-to-build-the-amazon-for-construction/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/y-combinator-backed-costcertified-lands-8-45m-to-build-the-amazon-for-construction/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 15:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brendan Wales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[construction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CostCertified]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FUSE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213171</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[CostCertified, a Canadian startup which provides real-time, interactive residential construction estimates, raised $8.45 million in a seed round of funding. FUSE, a Pacific Northwest venture firm which counts former Microsoft CFO John Connors and Seattle Seahawks linebacker Bobby Wagner as venture partners, led the round.  The company is also backed by Y Combinator (having participated [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://costcertified.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CostCertified</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a Canadian startup which provides real-time, interactive residential construction estimates, raised $8.45 million in a seed round of funding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">FUSE, a Pacific Northwest venture firm which counts former Microsoft CFO John Connors and Seattle Seahawks linebacker Bobby Wagner as venture partners, led the round. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company is also backed by Y Combinator (having participated in the accelerator’s S21 batch), I2BF Global Ventures, Soma Capital and a number of proptech/construction tech founders such as Willy Schlacks, CEO and co-founder of EquipmentShare; Ryan Sutton-Gee, PlanGrid co-founder and former COO; Jonathan Wasserstrum, co-founder and CEO of SquareFoot and Bill Smith, founder and CEO of Landing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The raise marks CostCertified’s first external round of funding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Put simply, CostCertified today is a price configurator tool for construction, but the Calgary, Alberta-based company’s end goal is to build the “Amazon for construction.” CostCertified allows contractors to send a shoppable interactive estimate to homeowners so that they can choose their selections during a project, and see the effect on price instantly. If you&#8217;ve ever performed a home remodeling project, you would understand that this is something that would be incredibly useful considering all the various decisions required around vendors and products. Being able to see your options and how specific choices will impact your end cost in one place can certainly help make the project less stressful.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2213354" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2213354" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2213354 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CostCertified.jpg?w=680" alt="CostCertified" width="680" height="527" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CostCertified.jpg 2164w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CostCertified.jpg?resize=150,116 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CostCertified.jpg?resize=300,233 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CostCertified.jpg?resize=768,596 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CostCertified.jpg?resize=680,527 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CostCertified.jpg?resize=1536,1191 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CostCertified.jpg?resize=2048,1588 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CostCertified.jpg?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2213354" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> CostCertified</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CEO </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mike Bignold teamed up with David Vass to start CostCertified in 2017 after running his own construction business and realizing the need for contractors to provide estimates in a more modern way.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I ended up booking a pretty large project. And I hired a really great project manager who was really good with construction but not comfortable at all with tech,” Bignold recalls. “And that job ended up getting delayed as a result.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hTE4U35fZI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/10-proptech-investors-see-better-era-for-residential-and-retail-after-pandemic/">10 proptech investors see better era for residential and retail after pandemic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;10 proptech investors see better era for residential and retail after pandemic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/10-proptech-investors-see-better-era-for-residential-and-retail-after-pandemic/embed/#?secret=hTE4U35fZI" data-secret="hTE4U35fZI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bignold, who did some coding during college, put together a simple prototype of an app that generated a document with an estimate of project costs that was sent out via email to potential customers. Essentially, he had built a </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">quoting engine that gave contractors a way to provide consumers with “an interactive, shoppable experience” while managing a project.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a contractor, I didn’t have the tools to support the price complexity of a large construction project.” Bignold said. “I thought to myself, ‘Why can’t you buy or sell construction services with the convenience of an Amazon-like, or Shopify, experience.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2017, he ended up selling his construction business with the intention of spinning out the app he had built into its company. He teamed up with Vass, who had helped him get that contracting business “to the top of Google.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some of Vass’s other contracting clients were looking for a system similar to what Bignold had built so the pair got beta customers to use the app, and become early adopters.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I don’t think I realized the complex problems that I was getting into solving for large construction companies,” he told TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pair spent several years on R&amp;D, iterating the app “over and over, listening to customers constantly.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There were big structural problems in the industry that we were trying to solve for,” Bignold said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The SaaS platform came out of beta in early 2021, and today, CostCertified has $72 million in annualized GMV, and says it has seen 2,203% YoY growth (albeit it from a small base).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Users can do things like select their finishes, upgrade, downgrade, and build their own renovation or or new construction with real-time price changes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The software also allows built-in financing and payments that CostCertified says automates workflow and ultimately, reduces the cost and risk for everyone involved in the such projects &#8212; from general contractors to subcontractors to the consumers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We leveraged our capabilities by bringing retailers, the people who sell things like countertops and plumbing fixtures, into the point of sale,” Bignold said. “By bringing all selections to the POS, customers know exactly what they are getting and what it will cost. The contractor can also make more money on upgrades and justify the cost.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, CostCertified has a team of 25 and it plans to use its new capital in part to increase its headcount by over 100 people over the next year and on product development, sales and growth.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">FUSE’s Brendan Wales said his firm was impressed with the CostCertified team’s “deep level of experience within the home renovation market.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“They have lived the pain of being a contractor and built the product for themselves. The product is robust and fully featured for its stage; the product is far greater than seed stage,” he wrote via email. “The customers love the product and that can be seen in the monthly logo growth, which is compounding. Lastly, they are playing within a large global market and there are many ways to monetize this audience than just SaaS fees.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another unique thing about the startup, he said, is that most renovation software vendors often only think about how the contractors will use the product.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“CostCertified has put the contractor&#8217;s customer to the forefront,” he wrote. “They enable the end consumers of the renovation services to have a more dynamic and transparent service, more akin to a wonderful e-commerce experience, than a construction purchase.&#8221;</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/y-combinator-backed-costcertified-lands-8-45m-to-build-the-amazon-for-construction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213171</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vlad Novakovski and Nicole Quinn to elucidate Series A fundraising</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/vlad-novakovski-and-nicole-quinn-to-elucidate-series-a-fundraising/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/vlad-novakovski-and-nicole-quinn-to-elucidate-series-a-fundraising/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 14:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nicole Quinn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Live]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[techcrunch live announcement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2210859</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vlad Novakovski co-founded Lunchclub in 2017 as a way to improve professional networking. In 2020, the company made a large push toward videos (thanks, COVID) and eventually saw enough traction to raise a $24.2 million Series A at a valuation above $100 million. Nicole Quinn from Lightspeed Ventures lead the raise. We’re thrilled to have [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Vlad Novakovski co-founded Lunchclub in 2017 as a way to improve professional networking. In 2020, the company made a large push toward videos (thanks, COVID) and eventually saw enough traction to raise a $24.2 million Series A at a valuation above $100 million. Nicole Quinn from Lightspeed Ventures lead the raise.</p>
<p>We’re thrilled to have both on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/check-out-the-amazing-speakers-joining-us-on-extra-cru-ahem-techcrunch-live/">TechCrunch Live</a> to help explain how to raise a Series A financing round.</p>
<p>TechCrunch Live also features the TCL Pitch-Off, which gives folks in the audience the chance to raise their hand and pitch their startup to our guests, who will give their live feedback.</p>
<p>Nicole Quinn is a leader in venture capital and her portfolio is impressive, with such investments as Cameo, Zola, Goop, Calm, Haus Laboratories and others.</p>
<p>Vlad Novakovski co-founded Lunchclub in 2017 with Scott Wu and Hayley Leibson. In 2019 the company raised a $4 million seed round led by Andreessen Horowitz with other investments coming in from Quora’s co-founder, the Robinhood co-founders and Flexport’s co-founders. When the pandemic hit in early 2020, the company quickly turned its focus to connecting professionals virtually.</p>
<p>Who reached out to whom? What did it take for Quinn to write the check to Novakovski and team? How do they work together now? <a href="https://hopin.com/events/techcrunch-live-with-lightspeed-venture-partners-and-lunchclub?ref=527261cda3f7">Join us on TechCrunch Live on Wednesday, October 6, at 12 p.m. PDT/3 p.m. EDT to find out!</a></p>
<p>TechCrunch Live is 100% free to folks who attend live, but only TechCrunch+ members can access the content on-demand. If you’re not yet a TechCrunch+ member, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">sign up here</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/vlad-novakovski-and-nicole-quinn-to-elucidate-series-a-fundraising/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2210859</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting the details right in your pitch deck</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/getting-the-details-right-in-your-pitch-deck/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/getting-the-details-right-in-your-pitch-deck/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 14:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC TechCrunch Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pitch deck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pitch Deck Teardown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup fundraising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup pitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2208016</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This year's Pitch Deck Teardown at TechCrunch Disrupt was full of invaluable advice from an exceptional VC panel about how to capture investors' attention.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">VCs read pitch decks extremely quickly, which means that every detail holds the potential to get them to double down on a startup or just pass altogether. While crafting the high-level narrative is critical, of course, founders can’t skimp on the details either.</p>
<p>That’s why every Disrupt, we host a session we call Pitch Deck Teardown. It’s a convivial workshop where founders in the audience send me their decks, and I walk through a curated set of them live in front of an exceptional VC panel, who critique the deck slide by slide. This year at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a>, we were joined by Maren Bannon, co-founder and managing partner at <a href="https://www.january.ventures">January Ventures</a>; Vanessa Larco, partner at <a href="https://www.nea.com">NEA</a>; and Ben Ling, founder and general partner of <a href="https://www.blingcap.com">Bling Capital</a>.</p>
<p>We went through two decks — one consumer and one enterprise — covering about 30 slides in total. It’s honestly hard to summarize all the discussions we had on the panel — there were just so many interesting viewpoints that I highly recommend reading the transcript or watching the video included below.</p>
<p>So for this summary, I decided to pick four slides, two from each deck, that provoked our panelists to show how VCs can have radically different views on the same material.</p>
<h2 id="Product slide">Product slide</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2208018" style="width: 1716px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2208018" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2208018 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Slide-1.png" alt="" width="1706" height="958" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Slide-1.png 1706w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Slide-1.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Slide-1.png?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Slide-1.png?resize=768,431 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Slide-1.png?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Slide-1.png?resize=1536,863 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Slide-1.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1706px) 100vw, 1706px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2208018" class="wp-caption-text"><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Most consumer decks, like this one targeting dog owners, will have some form of product slide that shows exactly what a startup is building. It’s a critical slide, but one that can be easy to get wrong.</span></p></div></p>
<p>Larco liked the design, but suggested offering investors ways to dive deeper:</p>
<blockquote><p>Screenshots are typically great, but if it piques your interest, it would be great if they had a link to a Loom video or something so that if I did want to go deeper and if I was really curious about what the product actually looks like, I could. That said, when it launches automatically into video, I find it typically hard to sift through it unless I am really interested already. So I think screenshots with an option to go deeper is great. But this looks great, the UI is great and clean. It explains the three core components of the app, which is basically what I asked for upfront. So this is pretty well executed. <em><b>(Timestamp: 9:00)</b></em></p></blockquote>
<p>The company had an additional slide just like this one with three more product screenshots. Larco felt that this maybe added a bit too much information about the UI.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/getting-the-details-right-in-your-pitch-deck/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2208016</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Athletic&#8217;s numbers look fine actually?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/the-athletics-numbers-look-fine-actually/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/the-athletics-numbers-look-fine-actually/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 14:47:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Athletic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212195</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Next year, The Athletic expects cash consumption of merely $7 million against $119 million in revenue. That seems just fine.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Information <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/the-athletic-burned-through-95-million-between-2019-and-2020?utm_source=sg&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=article_email&amp;utm_content=article-6356">broke some neat news</a> earlier this week about The Athletic, the subscription sports media website that has raised lots of money and, per the report, spent lots of it.</p>
<p>While we have all become inured to a degree regarding losses at quickly growing, venture-backed companies, seeing a media business lose software-style money <a href="https://twitter.com/scottgoodacre/status/1445326454515019776">was</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/fpmarconi/status/1445160886650408962">eyebrow</a>&#8211;<a href="https://twitter.com/TiagoDF/status/1445136214760345610">raising</a>. However, after a quick scan of the numbers, I have to wonder a bit. It kinda looks like The Athletic is doing fine?</p>
<p>Per <a href="https://twitter.com/jtoonkel">Jessica Toonkel&#8217;s</a> reporting, The Athletic burned $54 million in cash in 2019 against revenues of $26 million. That&#8217;s a lot of burn, right! Maybe? It depends whether the site was hiring lots of staff, building out its product, and setting the groundwork for future revenue growth.</p>
<p>So, did the spend work out? Seems like it: The Athletic racked up $47 million in revenues and burned $41 million worth of cash in 2020, according to The Information, despite the pandemic kicking sports in the shins that year.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/the-athletics-numbers-look-fine-actually/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212195</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On heels of IBM partnership, Celonis announces one with ServiceNow</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/on-heels-of-ibm-partnership-celonis-announces-one-with-servicenow/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/on-heels-of-ibm-partnership-celonis-announces-one-with-servicenow/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 14:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Celonis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partnerships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[process mining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ServiceNow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workflow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Celonis, the late stage processing mining startup with a gaudy $11 billion valuation, announced a new partnership today, this one with ServiceNow. Celonis co-founder and CEO Alexander Rinke says that he and ServiceNow CEO Bill McDermott go back a long way together, and that working together should provide big benefits for the two companies.&#8221;With ServiceNow, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://celonis.com">Celonis</a>, the late stage processing mining startup with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/celonis-snares-1b-series-d-on-11b-valuation/">a gaudy $11 billion valuation</a>, announced a new partnership today, this one with ServiceNow.</p>
<p>Celonis co-founder and CEO Alexander Rinke says that he and ServiceNow CEO Bill McDermott go back a long way together, and that working together should provide big benefits for the two companies.&#8221;With ServiceNow, we can both increase the benefits that customers receive, ensure we’re helping businesses modernize their underlying processes and the systems those processes run on,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The two companies will be working together to combine the ServiceNow low-code workflow automation tool <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/servicenow-adds-new-no-code-capabilities/">it announced in March</a> with Celonis&#8217; process mining tooling. Dave Wright, Chief Innovation Officer at ServiceNow says that by bringing together Celonis’ process execution expertise with ServiceNow’s automation, machine learning, robotic process automation and low-code app development capabilities, they can improve workflow for their mutual customers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FSdlr8xaEK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/no-code-workflow-and-rpa-line-up-for-their-automation-moment/">No code, workflow and RPA line up for their automation moment</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;No code, workflow and RPA line up for their automation moment&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/no-code-workflow-and-rpa-line-up-for-their-automation-moment/embed/#?secret=FSdlr8xaEK" data-secret="FSdlr8xaEK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;This is about helping customers more deeply understand how work moves across the enterprise and applying those insights to accelerate digital innovation and predict how to make work better,&#8221; Wright said.</p>
<p>Today&#8217;s announcement comes on the heels of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/celonis-announces-significant-partnership-with-ibm-to-sell-its-process-mining-software/">a similar agreement with IBM</a> announced in April, and gives the company another large organization to help it sell its software.  Rinke says that the three companies can actually work together.</p>
<p>&#8220;This partnership is designed to benefit all of our customers and strategic partners including IBM Global Business Services (GBS). IBM GBS has experience with both ServiceNow and Celonis and could now combine both platforms to deliver much more rapid and substantial transformation of enterprise processes,&#8221; he said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>These big companies and investors see something here, and it&#8217;s a company that builds process mining software to help customers understand how work flows through their organizations, and from there how to make it more efficient through automation. Working together with these larger organizations should help drive Celonis&#8217; business growth, while giving these larger public companies access to some sophisticated software that they can combine with software and services they are already offering.</p>
<p>ServiceNow has also been moving into automation in a big way in the last year announcing a number of moves to accelerate this shift. That included <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/servicenow-takes-rpa-plunge-by-acquiring-india-based-startup-intellibot/">acquiring RPA vendor Intellibot</a> and announcing no-code workflow building tools in March.</p>
<p>The $11 billion valuation came in June when Celonis <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/celonis-snares-1b-series-d-on-11b-valuation/">announced a $1 billion Series D</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/on-heels-of-ibm-partnership-celonis-announces-one-with-servicenow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213397</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GM, General Electric agree to develop rare earth materials used in EV manufacturing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/gm-general-electric-agree-to-develop-rare-earth-materials-used-in-ev-manufacturing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/gm-general-electric-agree-to-develop-rare-earth-materials-used-in-ev-manufacturing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 14:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Electric]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213409</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In yet another sign that automakers are determined to get ahead of the supply chain curve, General Motors said Wednesday it had signed a memorandum of understanding (MOU) with General Electric for the supply of rare earth materials, the kind used to manufacture electric vehicles and clean energy equipment. The non-binding agreement is with GE’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In yet another sign that automakers are determined to get ahead of the supply chain curve, General Motors said Wednesday it had signed a memorandum of understanding (MOU) with General Electric for the supply of rare earth materials, the kind used to manufacture electric vehicles and clean energy equipment.</p>
<p>The non-binding agreement is with GE’s clean energy arm, GE Renewable Energy. In addition to rare earth materials, the collaboration will also look at ways to improve supplies of magnets, copper and electrical steel.</p>
<p>Initially, the collaboration will be focused on establishing a supply chain for magnet manufacturing in North American and Europe – significant, as the main producers of magnets are in countries like China, Brazil and India. The two companies will also explore new supply chains for copper and “eSteel,” a material composed in part of recycled materials, to be used in automotive traction motors and renewable power generation.</p>
<p>The agreement is yet another sign that North American automakers are keen to decrease their reliance on foreign countries for critical minerals. The news is prescient as both President Joe Biden and former President Donald Trump have called for a bolstering of domestic sources of minerals like copper and lithium, in order to stay competitive in the transition to electric-everything.</p>
<p>To that point, the two companies said they would also look to collaborate via public policy, to seek out policies that support the establishment of North American and European-based supply chains for these materials.</p>
<p>&#8220;A secure, sustainable and resilient local supply chain for electric vehicle materials is critical to the execution of GM’s vision of an all-electric future,&#8221; Shilpan Amin, GM’s vice president for global purchasing and supply chain, explained in a statement. &#8220;Motors are one of the most important components of our Ultium Platform, and the heavy and light rare earth materials are an essential ingredient in our motor magnets.”</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/gm-general-electric-agree-to-develop-rare-earth-materials-used-in-ev-manufacturing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213409</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Copper Banking adds $9M in funding as digital banks clamor for teen customers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/copper-banking-adds-9m-in-funding-as-digital-bans-clamor-for-teen-customers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/copper-banking-adds-9m-in-funding-as-digital-bans-clamor-for-teen-customers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 14:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Copper Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eddie Behringer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neobank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PSL Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seattle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213041</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Copper Banking, a digital banking service aimed at teens, announced today it has raised a total of $13.3 million in seed funding. PSL Ventures, an arm of Pioneer Square Labs, led a $4.3 million raise for Seattle-based Copper last year and an additional $9 million this year. Other investors in the fintech startup include Clocktower [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.getcopper.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Copper Banking</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a digital banking service aimed at teens, announced today it has raised a total of $13.3 million in seed funding.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/psl-ventures"><span style="font-weight: 400;">PSL Ventures</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, an arm of </span><a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/pioneer-square-labs"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pioneer Square Labs</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, led a</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> $4.3 million raise</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for Seattle-based Copper last year and an additional $9 million this year. Other investors in the fintech startup include Clocktower Ventures, Index Ventures Scout Fund, Launchpad Capital, Financial Venture Studio, Maven Ventures, Fiat Ventures and Arnold Ventures.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Copper Banking CEO and co-founder </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eddie Behringer</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> believes the startup has a few competitive advantages.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For one, Behringer and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">CFO Stefan Berglund</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> previously co-founded Snap! Raise, a youth-oriented crowdfunding platform that has raised over $90 million in venture funding. The pair attribute Snap! Raise’s success to deep grassroots-level relationships in high schools. They are emulating that model to power Copper’s growth. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We worked with millions of teens and parents in our previous company,” Behringer told TechCrunch. “That playbook is one of the core reasons we’ve seen such great growth so quickly. We’ve gone this route before &#8212; partnering at the community level. That’s something that is typically overlooked in tech models today.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, Copper Banking has incorporated financial education into its offering so that teens are not just able to spend money, but also better manage it. For example, financial tips built into the app are aimed at helping teens “learn the essential money lessons they’ll need throughout life,” the company says.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“One really good example of that is that teens have the ability to tell Copper what they want, which we then translate into savings goals that really teaches them,” Behringer added.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DXBd6DnM4P"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/02/which-neobanks-will-rise-or-fall/">Which neobanks will rise or fall?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Which neobanks will rise or fall?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/02/which-neobanks-will-rise-or-fall/embed/#?secret=DXBd6DnM4P" data-secret="DXBd6DnM4P" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So far, Copper’s strategy seems to be working. The two-year-old startup launched earlier this year, and today has over 350,000 users on its platform. Since its launch, Copper has been seeing about 70% month-over-month growth and about 70% of users are being drawn to the platform through “organic word of mouth,” Behringer said. The average Copper customer is 15 years old and often refers another friend, not including their own siblings, according to the company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In emulating Snap! Raise’s model, Copper Banking also relies on a network of youth ambassadors who promote the platform through schools, clubs and sports teams. The result, Behringer adds, is fewer fees for its teen customers. And for Copper, the approach has resulted in customer acquisition costs that it says are drastically lower than those of traditional banks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We realized, when growing Snap! Raise, that very little had been done to prepare this generation to be financially successful,” Behringer told TechCrunch. “One of the first things we noticed is that banks have set the bar extremely low for pre-18 banking.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Copper Banking provides an FDIC-backed digital bank account linked to 50,000 ATMs. Teens also get a personalized Copper debit card, P2P payments, direct deposit and automatic savings options. Parents must sign up their teens for an account, and can </span><a href="https://getcopper.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360057843033-Why-do-I-need-to-link-a-Parent-or-Guardian-to-my-account-"><span style="font-weight: 400;">link their traditional bank accounts</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to Copper Banking cards to provide an automatic &#8220;teen salary&#8221; allowance. They also receive alerts and smart controls over spending behavior. </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2213061" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2213061" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2213061" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Copper-Banking.jpg?w=377" alt="Copper Banking" width="300" height="541" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Copper-Banking.jpg 1343w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Copper-Banking.jpg?resize=83,150 83w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Copper-Banking.jpg?resize=166,300 166w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Copper-Banking.jpg?resize=768,1384 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Copper-Banking.jpg?resize=377,680 377w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Copper-Banking.jpg?resize=852,1536 852w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Copper-Banking.jpg?resize=1136,2048 1136w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Copper-Banking.jpg?resize=28,50 28w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2213061" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Copper Banking</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Copper offers co-parent functionality for separated parents living in different households. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company plans to use its new capital mostly to continue the development of its banking platform and products as well as to focus on its go-to-market strategy. It also, naturally, is hiring across several departments &#8212; including engineering, compliance, marketing, sales and operations. Copper currently has about 25 employees.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Geoff Entress, managing director and co-founder of lead investor PSL Ventures, said the </span><span class="s1"> Copper management team&#8217;s extensive experience growing early-stage companies really shows in their metrics. </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">&#8220;Their adoption, conversion to funded accounts and recommendation metrics beat most DTC metrics you see out there, which speaks to Copper’s incredible resonance with customers,&#8221; he wrote via email. &#8220;As an investor, those are the signals you want to see. We believe Copper Banking is ideally positioned to help set the next generation of Americans on a path to better financial health.&#8221;</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Ben Savage, partner at Clocktower Ventures, believes that the teen market is incredibly attractive for neobanks, but that &#8220;teens don’t want one imposed on them by their parents.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">“Copper has the brand, the product and the go-to-market model to fill that void,&#8221; he said in a written statement.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Copper emphasizes that it is a digital bank. Evolve Bank &amp; Trust provides its banking services.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the startup’s focus is on teens, anyone over the age of six can get an account if they have a phone. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The landscape for banking services aimed at youth is an increasingly crowded on. In April, Step &#8212; which is also focused on teens &#8212; closed on </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/teen-banking-service-step-raises-100m-series-c-announces-steph-currys-investment/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a $100 million Series C round of funding</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Greenlight, a fintech company that pitches parents on kid-friendly bank accounts, </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/kids-focused-fintech-greenlight-raises-260m-in-a16z-led-series-d-nearly-doubles-valuation-to-2-3b/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">raised $260 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in a Series D funding round that nearly doubled its valuation to $2.3 billion.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/copper-banking-adds-9m-in-funding-as-digital-bans-clamor-for-teen-customers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213041</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The metaverse is coming for Squid Game</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/the-metaverse-is-coming-for-squid-game/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/the-metaverse-is-coming-for-squid-game/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 14:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metaverse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212742</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch&#8217;s venture capital focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. This is our Wednesday show, the time of the week when we niche down to a single topic. Today? Gaming. Natasha and Danny and Alex got together to discuss the gaming world from a few perspectives, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/3a79b68b-89f3-442c-a8f0-a6c769800ec1?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch&#8217;s venture capital focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. This is our Wednesday show, the time of the week when we niche down to a single topic. Today? Gaming.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/dannycrichton">Danny</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> got together to discuss the gaming world from a few perspectives, including those of startups and the largest platform players in tech. Alex is a gamer. Danny is a <em>board</em> gamer. And Natasha isn&#8217;t big on digital games. So, we had a good array of viewpoints. The goal of our episode was to understand why gaming is garnering more interest from Big Tech and startups alike, and how the business model and environment has evolved over the years.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s what we got into:</p>
<ul>
<li>A <a href="https://www.protocol.com/andreessen-horowitz-gaming-fund">new gaming fund from a16z</a>, and recent venture capital totals, as <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/its-game-on-for-gaming-startups/">compiled by our friends over at Crunchbase News</a>.</li>
<li>Amazon&#8217;s new hit game, and <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-doesnt-make-videogames-but-its-the-hottest-player-in-gaming-11633147211">Apple&#8217;s epic gaming profits.</a></li>
<li>It appears, by our read, that the gaming industry has evolved from single-sale titles to games with recurring incomes that studios have become venture-backable; this is testament to both business model evolution and general gaming popularity, as much as it is indicative of how much money it is possible to earn <em>supporting </em>the games industry as a tech shop as well.</li>
<li>Still, we wanted to spend a few minutes on the challenges that still await those trying to spin up a game overnight.</li>
<li>After we talked through the context and challenges, we riffed on the why! It includes just what a metaverse is, how NFTs can slot into the conversation, and more.</li>
</ul>
<p>All we need now is a release date for <a href="https://ck3.paradoxwikis.com/Royal_Court">Royal Court</a>, Paradox.</p>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 a.m. PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts!</i></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/the-metaverse-is-coming-for-squid-game/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212742</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Matter raises $7 million Series A to build a better reading app</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/matter-raises-7-million-series-a-to-build-a-better-reading-app/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/matter-raises-7-million-series-a-to-build-a-better-reading-app/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 13:59:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212509</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A startup called Matter, which aims to build a better reading app for today&#8217;s internet, is launching out of private beta testing and announcing the close of its $7 million Series A, led by GV (formerly Google Ventures.) The app enters a space where technologies for saving articles to read later, like Instapaper and Pocket, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A startup called <a href="https://getmatter.app/">Matter</a>, which aims to build a better reading app for today&#8217;s internet, is launching out of private beta testing and announcing the close of its $7 million Series A, led by GV (formerly Google Ventures.) The app enters a space where technologies for saving articles to read later, like Instapaper and Pocket, have lagged behind how people are now consuming online reading &#8212; through newsletters, personalized recommendations in other apps, or through suggestions from peers on social platforms, for example. And people don&#8217;t only want to consume reading material as text &#8212; they want to listen to articles as audio, highlight key points, and discuss with fellow readers.</p>
<p>The frustrations with the current set of reading apps drove Matter co-founders <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/benspringwater/">Ben Springwater</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/robert-n-mackenzie/">Robert Mackenzie</a> &#8212; who met while working at Nextdoor &#8212; to take on the challenge of building a new tool for online reading.</p>
<p>&#8220;There were all of these pain points and frictions around reading online, and the media ecosystem was changing &#8212; you have the rise of newsletters you have the rise of individual creators, alternative media &#8212; and also that there was all this potential around what you could do to e-reading. It&#8217;s still just words on a screen, but there&#8217;s a lot more you can do and overlay to that,&#8221; explains Springwater. &#8220;It just became more and more apparent to us that there was an opportunity to build a better reading product,&#8221; he says.</p>
<p>The co-founders began the development of Matter in early 2020, after raising an angel round, and later participated in startup accelerator Y Combinator&#8217;s summer 2020 batch.</p>
<p>At the outset, one of Matter&#8217;s larger goals was to help people make better decisions about what to read.</p>
<p>Today, there are many places where people discover new material, from news headlines to Twitter and other social apps to newsletters hitting the inbox, and more. But there isn&#8217;t an app that&#8217;s working to create what Matter calls a &#8220;recommendation&#8221; graph, where the best material is filtered, curated, and brought to the forefront.</p>
<p>This is what <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/matter-reader/id1501592184">Matter</a> is aiming to do. On the app&#8217;s homepage, you&#8217;ll discover recommended content that comes from a set of articles recommended by a group of &#8220;public thinkers&#8221; on Twitter who often share interesting news and links. From their tweets, Matter&#8217;s team curates their recommendations further, to hand-select the best articles to share in the app. Matter users can also feed in their recommendations to the app, which the team then curates, sending a subset of those suggestions to the homepage, as well.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2212579" style="width: 372px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2212579" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2212579" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Discover.png?w=362" alt="" width="362" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Discover.png 982w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Discover.png?resize=80,150 80w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Discover.png?resize=160,300 160w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Discover.png?resize=768,1442 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Discover.png?resize=362,680 362w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Discover.png?resize=818,1536 818w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Discover.png?resize=27,50 27w" sizes="(max-width: 362px) 100vw, 362px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2212579" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Matter (Matter&#8217;s homepage)</p></div></p>
<p>Like other &#8220;read it later&#8221; apps like those offered by Pocket or Instapaper, Matter users can install a Chrome extension to build their reading list in the app, or they can make a recommendation directly in the mobile app itself. Users&#8217; reading lists are private by default, but you can choose which articles from the list you want to post publicly to the Matter community.</p>
<p>This sharing feature makes Matter a bit of a social network, as users can also highlight articles as they share, in addition to highlighting privately.</p>
<p>&#8220;You can think of it as like a lightweight way of broadcasting what you&#8217;re reading,&#8221; says Springwater of the highlighting feature.</p>
<p>If someone follows you in Matter, they&#8217;ll see your highlights and annotations overlaid on the article when they read the same article. This sounds similar to what digital publishing platform <a href="https://medium.com/">Medium</a> offers across its own website and app. But Matter makes the option available across all the reading material being shared. These highlights are also saved to users&#8217; profiles, so you can visit someone you follow and see what sort of things they had made note of and shared.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2212578" style="width: 372px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2212578" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2212578" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Queue.png?w=362" alt="" width="362" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Queue.png 982w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Queue.png?resize=80,150 80w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Queue.png?resize=160,300 160w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Queue.png?resize=768,1442 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Queue.png?resize=362,680 362w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Queue.png?resize=818,1536 818w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Queue.png?resize=27,50 27w" sizes="(max-width: 362px) 100vw, 362px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2212578" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Matter (a user&#8217;s private queue)</p></div></p>
<p>Users on Matter can follow others, in a model similar to social networks like Twitter. This allows you to track the shares from people whose suggestions you generally like. The feature recalls the recently shuttered app Nuzzel, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/twitter-acquires-distraction-free-reading-service-scroll-to-beef-up-its-subscription-product/">acquired by Twitter when it bought Scroll</a> earlier this year. Nuzzel had a small but devoted following for its Twitter-based reading recommendations. While not entirely based on Twitter, Matter&#8217;s idea to follow people, and what they read and share, feels similar.</p>
<p>A commenting feature enables discussions on shared articles, but to what extent you&#8217;ll see much action here may depend on who you follow. During Matter&#8217;s private beta, moderation hasn&#8217;t been an issue. But it&#8217;s one the company will need to address as it scales to a broader audience.</p>
<p>The app also addresses a number of other pain points associated with online reading and the current crop of reading apps.</p>
<p>It gives you tools to get your newsletters into Matter in a couple of ways, for instance &#8212; either by having you set up filters to forward mail or by using a special email address just for Matter.</p>
<p>It offers a way to listen to individual articles as audio, but in a far less robotic-sounding voice than is available in some other reading apps. It lets you sync other accounts where you collect reading material, like Twitter, Notion, and Readwise. It allows you to view and save the full, paywalled content, if you&#8217;re a paid subscriber to a news site or newsletter.  And it offers weekly roundups with Staff Picks for those times when you&#8217;ve been too busy to keep up.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2212580" style="width: 372px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2212580" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2212580" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Audio.png?w=362" alt="" width="362" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Audio.png 982w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Audio.png?resize=80,150 80w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Audio.png?resize=160,300 160w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Audio.png?resize=768,1442 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Audio.png?resize=362,680 362w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Audio.png?resize=818,1536 818w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Audio.png?resize=27,50 27w" sizes="(max-width: 362px) 100vw, 362px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2212580" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Matter (listening to audio)</p></div></p>
<p>In time, Matter also wants to add more personalization to its service, which will involve investing in semantic technology on the backend to understand the topics in articles being shared. But the startup is weighing how exactly to bring this in.</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s a limit to how heavily we want to lean on personalization because there&#8217;s a balance that needs to be struck between narrowing in on someone&#8217;s interests and giving them more of what they have indicated they want through the signals they&#8217;ve given you, and introducing enough novelty and serendipity,&#8221; explains Springwater. &#8220;People&#8217;s interests evolve and you&#8217;re never going to be able to zero in on them completely,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p>As Matter exits private beta, the app will be open to anyone who wants to download it from the App Store.</p>
<p>In addition to GV&#8217;s investment, led by M.G. Siegler, investors in Matter include Outliers, Shrug, James Beshara, Calvin French-Owen, and many other angels. And, from its $2 million seed, Stripe co-founder and CEO <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/patrick-collison">Patrick Collison</a>; former Stripe product manager turned investor Lachy Groom; and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/01/31/business/julia-hartz-eventbrite-corner-office.html">Eventbrite co-founders</a> Kevin and Julia Hartz invested.</p>
<p>It will also use its Series A funding to invest in further building out the Matter experience and scaling, hiring engineers and designers, and building web and Android clients.</p>
<p>&#8220;The first generation of read-it-later services were amazing, and perhaps no one was a bigger user of them than myself. But they were also built in a different era,&#8221; said Siegler about GV&#8217;s investment. &#8220;The content we now consume in a number of different ways, on a number of different devices, required an updated vessel purpose-built from the ground up,&#8221; he continued.</p>
<p>&#8220;On top of that, there&#8217;s more content than ever before to read, and more of it is great than ever before. But we need an effective way to surface that content. This was the initial premise of Matter and having watched Ben and Rob build this from the ground up, to today&#8217;s robust app built by a growing team, has been awesome to watch. So we jumped at the chance to give them more resources to keep at it without slowing down. I&#8217;m excited to see how others will use Matter and how the service will grow with more people powering it forward,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Matter&#8217;s<a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/matter-reader/id1501592184"> iOS app</a> is currently free, with plans to monetize via a consumer subscription model in the future. The app is launching into public beta starting today, meaning there will no longer be an invite requirement to try it out.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/matter-raises-7-million-series-a-to-build-a-better-reading-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212509</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tracking CO2 emissions for supply chains leads Normative to a €10M fund raise</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/tracking-co2-emissions-for-supply-chains-leads-normative-to-a-e10m-fund-raise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/tracking-co2-emissions-for-supply-chains-leads-normative-to-a-e10m-fund-raise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 13:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon footprint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lowercarbon Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Luminar Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oxford university]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stockholm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[united nations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213351</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Increasingly, companies are being encouraged by governments to engage in carbon accounting, but of course, only a small number of companies actually do. Even those probably count only 10% of their emissions because they don’t account for the emissions of their supply chain, which, when looked at, probably accounts for 90% of their total emissions. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Increasingly, companies are being encouraged by governments to engage in carbon accounting, but of course, only a small number of companies actually do. Even those probably count only 10% of their emissions because they don’t account for the emissions of their supply chain, which, when looked at, probably accounts for 90% of their total emissions. It’s the equivalent of handing your financial report on the back of an envelope. But tracking supply chain emissions is fiendishly tricky.</p>
<p>Perhaps that’s why <a href="https://normative.io/">Normative</a>, an emissions ‘accounting engine’ which can track supply chain emissions, has now raised €10 million from a clutch of European and US climate tech funds. The round was led by <a href="https://www.2150.vc/">2150</a> and <a href="https://etfpartners.capital/">ETF Partners</a>, but also includes new investors Chris Sacca&#8217;s <a href="https://lowercarboncapital.com/">LowerCarbon Capital</a>, while existing investors ByFounders and Luminar Ventures also participated.</p>
<p>Stockholm-headquartered Normative’s emissions database has made a name for itself by landing partners such as the <a href="https://unfccc.int/climate-action/race-to-zero-campaign">United Nations Race to Zero</a> campaign (which aims to drive change to a decarbonized economy ahead of COP26), the UK’s <a href="https://smeclimatehub.org/uk/">SME Climate Hub</a> (through which thousands of UK companies have committed to ‘net zero’ on their climate emissions) and a free starter plan in collaboration with Google.org for small businesses.</p>
<p>Normative&#8217;s approach is to standardize the often inconsistent, expensive, and people-intensive process of carbon accounting.</p>
<p>Co-founder and CEO Kristian Rönn said: &#8220;Ahead of COP26, it is time for everyone and businesses, in particular, to be courageous. We are in a climate emergency and we must take action, real action. But businesses also need to be pragmatic &#8211; and realize that removing carbon inside their operations and their supply chains makes good business sense. The cost of carbon is a huge liability on your balance sheet and you need to act to ensure that your business will survive.” Rönn was previously a global risks analyst at the Future of Humanity Institute at Oxford University.</p>
<p>Jacob Bro, partner and co-founder at 2150, said: “Carbon accounting is the first truly global software vertical in climate tech and we see accelerating demand as millions of companies realize that measuring, reporting and managing their carbon footprint is a necessity to remain competitive and compliant.&#8221;</p>
<p>Fabrice Bienfait, a partner at ETF Partners, said: “Businesses know they need to have better, more accurate data on their emissions, both for compliance purposes but also so they can have a credible plan to get to net-zero.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Speaking to me over a call Rönn added: “We have built the first emissions accounting engine. Our clients upload all of their accounting data, every single transaction &#8211; invoices for heating offices, invoices for transportation, business travel, specific raw materials &#8211; and then we basically assess the carbon impact of everything that they have ever purchased.”</p>
<p>He says the big difference between it and its competitors is that it “really gets them up to 100% of their carbon accounting. So our competitors still account for emissions in the supply chain, but it all has to be manual. We have seven years experience in this space and can process the carbon impact of millions of suppliers.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/tracking-co2-emissions-for-supply-chains-leads-normative-to-a-e10m-fund-raise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213351</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spotify&#8217;s podcast creation tool Anchor gains access to the company&#8217;s larger audio ad network</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/spotifys-podcast-creation-tool-anchor-gains-access-to-the-companys-larger-audio-ad-network/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/spotifys-podcast-creation-tool-anchor-gains-access-to-the-companys-larger-audio-ad-network/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 13:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alyssa Milano]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ambassador]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anchor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mass media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Megaphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saks Fifth Avenue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213322</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier this year, Spotify introduced its new audio advertising marketplace, the Spotify Audience Network, which allows advertisers to reach audiences across Spotify&#8217;s ad-supported music and original and exclusive podcast programs, as well as third-party podcasts from Megaphone publishers, all in one place. Today, the company is launching access to the Spotify Audience Network to creators [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Earlier this year, Spotify <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/22/spotify-to-launch-spotify-audience-network-an-audio-ad-marketplace/">introduced</a> its new audio advertising marketplace, the Spotify Audience Network, which allows advertisers to reach audiences across Spotify&#8217;s ad-supported music and original and exclusive podcast programs, as well as third-party podcasts from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/spotify-buying-podcast-hosting-and-ad-company-megaphone-for-235m/">Megaphone</a> publishers, all in one place. Today, the company is <a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2021-10-06/the-latest-spotify-audience-network-innovations-for-advertisers-and-anchor-creators/">launching</a> access to the Spotify Audience Network to creators who use its Anchor podcast publishing tool in the U.S.</p>
<p>Support for Anchor had been previously announced when Spotify <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/22/spotify-to-launch-spotify-audience-network-an-audio-ad-marketplace/">first unveiled its plans</a> for the Spotify Audience Network back in February during its &#8220;Stream On&#8221; live event. The company described the new platform as a potential game changer for the world of podcast monetization, as it would give advertisers tools to reach the Spotify audience of hundreds of millions.</p>
<p>The news had shortly followed an investigative report by <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/21/22241066/spotify-anchor-sponsorships-ad-money-spend-podcasting">The Verge</a>, which found that Anchor was struggling to find sponsors for smaller podcasters, as it had promised to do. Instead, Spotify itself was found to be the main sponsor for Anchor advertising to date. The debut of the Spotify Audience Network, however, put that report into perspective. It seemed that Spotify may have chosen to prioritize the building out of this larger ad marketplace, rather than working on sponsor outreach for smaller shows.</p>
<p>The Spotify Audience Network has already launched in the U.S., U.K., Canada, and Australia, where it now powers advertising across Spotify&#8217;s shows and other third-party podcasts, like those from The Wall St. Journal and ViacomCBS. Though the company today declined to say how many total podcasts are participating in the marketplace, it said the total has risen by more than 50% since launch, and about 4x more advertisers are now running ads on the network. Many are first-time podcast advertisers, like Saks Fifth Avenue.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, when it added Megaphone inventory to the Spotify Audience Network, it increased advertiser reach by 30%. In June, Megaphone publishers saw fill rates increase by over 10% in June and CPMs increase by over 40%, Spotify claims.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2213368" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2213368" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2213368" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Spotify-Audience-Network-Oct-2021-1.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" /><p id="caption-attachment-2213368" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Spotify</p></div></p>
<p>With the additional support for Anchor, Spotify notes advertisers will be able to reach a large swath of Spotify&#8217;s podcast catalog as Anchor powers 70% of the podcasts on Spotify. It will also enable advertisers to reach popular shows like &#8220;Alyssa Milano: Sorry Not Sorry,&#8221; &#8220;How Long Gone,&#8221; and &#8220;Office Hours live with Tim Heidecker,&#8221; the company noted.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Instead of taking a percentage revenue share from advertiser payments, Anchor creators who are part of the Spotify Audience Network will receive a flat rate RPM (revenue per thousand listeners), the company told TechCrunch. But this detail isn&#8217;t mentioned on the <a href="https://anchor.fm/ads">website</a> which presents the ad options to Anchor creators. Spotify says the <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">rate will be visible to participating creators in the money tab of their Anchor dashboard, and at this time the rate is a $13 RPM.</span></p>
<p>Spotify said the expansion is only one way it&#8217;s working to make it easier for advertisers to reach the podcast listener base on its platform.</p>
<p>The company is also soon launching support for podcast ad buying in <a href="https://adstudio.spotify.com/signup/form?lang=en">Spotify Ad Studio</a>, its self-serve channel now live in 26 global markets. Before, advertisers would have needed a direct relationship with the Spotify team and a sizable budget to advertise on its podcast network. But the Ad Studio&#8217;s launch of podcast ad buying will enable smaller advertisers, like universities, independent artists, app developers, and others, to now buy ads on podcasts, Spotify says. This launch will take place in the U.S. before rolling out to more markets.</p>
<p>An early beta tester of this functionality included Two Men and a Truck, which used the Spotify Ad Studio to test advertising in podcasts for the first time. The business says it will now make podcast advertising a part of its marketing plan going forward, as a result.</p>
<p>Related to today&#8217;s news, Spotify announced it was joining the Global Alliance of Responsible Media (GARM), as the first audio platform member. Here, it will help to set the brand safety standards for the audio industry.</p>
<p>It also announced it would give advertisers tools to exclude sensitive topics from their ad buys, to give them more control over where their messages are heard. And it will offer new controls that will allow advertisers to target ads by context. Spotify offered an example of this by explaining how an animal shelter could target ads at a podcast about pets.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YZ_oYxqWL9g?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>Podcasts <a href="https://www.adexchanger.com/the-sell-sider/direct-podcast-monetization-is-challenging-heres-what-publishers-can-do/">historically have struggled to monetize</a> effectively, outside of larger networks that could deliver sizable audiences across their various programs. That&#8217;s why Spotify has been snatching up various networks over the years, like Megaphone, Gimlet, Parcast, and The Ringer, for example. But for smaller publishers, it&#8217;s been difficult to compete and capture much, if any, of the potential advertising revenue.</p>
<p>With the expansion of the Spotify Audience Network to Anchor, creators would at least have a better chance at being exposed to more advertisers and campaigns. But as the payouts are still based on their audience size, it won&#8217;t likely dramatically change their fortunes overnight. However, Anchor does offer podcasters a few other ways to monetize, including its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/spotifys-podcasts-subscriptions-service-is-now-open-to-all-u-s-creators/">newer podcast subscriptions</a> and Ambassador ads (which lets creators with over 50 listeners promote Anchor), in addition the premium sponsorships available to shows with larger audiences.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/spotifys-podcast-creation-tool-anchor-gains-access-to-the-companys-larger-audio-ad-network/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213322</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alphabet&#8217;s Wing tests drone deliveries from shopping center rooftops in Australia</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/alphabets-wing-tests-drone-deliveries-from-shopping-center-rooftops-in-australia/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/alphabets-wing-tests-drone-deliveries-from-shopping-center-rooftops-in-australia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drone delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213337</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Alphabet subsidiary Wing has launched a pilot program that will have its drones fly products from the rooftops of shopping centers, kicking off the program  n its biggest market: Logan, Australia.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Mariella Moon</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Mariella Moon is an associate editor at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/amazon-opens-its-first-4-star-store-outside-the-us/">Amazon opens its first 4-star store outside the US</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/fcc-proposes-new-rules-to-combat-sim-swapping-scams/">FCC proposes new rules to combat SIM swapping scams</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Alphabet subsidiary <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-04-09-alphabet-wing-drone-delivery-service-australia.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="14" data-v9y="1">Wing</a> has launched a pilot program that will have its drones fly products from the rooftops of shopping centers. In fact, it has already started the program in its biggest market, Logan, Australia. The subsidiary has teamed up with Australian retail property group, Vicinity Centres, to test the new model at Logan&#8217;s Grand Plaza, where Wing&#8217;s drones have been flying orders to customers from businesses directly below their launching pad.</p>
<p>Wing has been operating in Logan over the past two years, but up until now, businesses have had to co-locate their products at the company&#8217;s delivery facility. This is the first time the subsidiary is conducting deliveries from participating merchants&#8217; existing location instead. Wing has been flying its drones from the rooftop of Grand Plaza since mid-August, delivering sushi, bubble tea, smoothies and other products from merchants in the shopping center. Starting today, the drones will also deliver over-the-counter medicine and personal care and beauty products.</p>
<p>Within the first six weeks of operating from the Grand Plaza, Wing&#8217;s drones have already made 2,500 deliveries to several Logan suburbs. The Alphabet company plans to expand not just its partner merchants in the center, but also its delivery coverage area. Jesse Suskin, Wing’s Head of Policy &amp; Community Affairs in Australia, also said that if the Grand Plaza pilot is successful, the company can &#8220;potentially roll out similar models in other locations across Vicinity Centres’ retail property portfolio.&#8221;</p>
<p>While it remains to be seen whether the Grand Plaza pilot will lead to rooftop deliveries from more Vicinity locations, Wing has been quite successful in Logan. It has already made more than 50,000 deliveries in the city this year alone and has celebrated its 100,000th delivery overall last August.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/alphabet-wing-drone-deliveries-shopping-center-rooftops-pilot-130022044.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/alphabets-wing-tests-drone-deliveries-from-shopping-center-rooftops-in-australia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213337</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitch source code and creator payout data leaks online</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/hacker-leaks-twitch-source-code-and-creator-payout-data/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/hacker-leaks-twitch-source-code-and-creator-payout-data/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 13:16:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A huge cache of source code repositories, creator payouts, and other internal data from Twitch has been published online after an apparent hack. In a post on Tuesday (but which was widely circulated on Wednesday), the leaker claims to have taken the video game streaming giant&#8217;s source code, as well as proprietary SDKs, or software [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A huge cache of source code repositories, creator payouts, and other internal data from Twitch has been published online after an apparent hack.</p>
<p>In a post on Tuesday (but which was widely circulated on Wednesday), the leaker claims to have taken the video game streaming giant&#8217;s source code, as well as proprietary SDKs, or software development kits, which let developers integrate Twitch into their apps and services. The leaker also claims to have taken unreleased software as well as hacking tools used by the company to stress-test its own network from security threats.</p>
<p>The leaker says the cache, seen in part by TechCrunch, is &#8220;part one,&#8221; suggesting more data is expected to leak. The news was first reported by <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/the-entirety-of-twitch-has-reportedly-been-leaked/">Video Games Chronicle</a>, which said Twitch was internally &#8220;aware&#8221; of the leak on Monday. Twitch has not yet confirmed a breach, and has not responded to a request comment by TechCrunch.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2213340" style="width: 910px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2213340" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2213340" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/posting-twitch.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="900" height="542" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/posting-twitch.jpg 1906w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/posting-twitch.jpg?resize=150,90 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/posting-twitch.jpg?resize=300,181 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/posting-twitch.jpg?resize=768,463 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/posting-twitch.jpg?resize=680,410 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/posting-twitch.jpg?resize=1536,925 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/posting-twitch.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2213340" class="wp-caption-text">The leaker&#8217;s listing. (Image: TechCrunch/screenshot)</p></div></p>
<p>But streamers were quick to lend credence to the apparent breach after creator payout figures were also leaked. (TechCrunch is not linking to the data since it contains personal information.) The data contains payouts for each Twitch user, some of which reach into the six-figures and more.</p>
<p>Several Twitch streamers have confirmed that the leaked records match their own. &#8220;I looked at a line from June 2019 and literally 100% match to the information showing on my analytics on my dashboard,&#8221; said <a href="https://twitter.com/BigJon06/status/1445699831666675723">one user</a>.</p>
<p>The leak of internal source code could also represent a security risk, since it now allows practically anyone to search for security vulnerabilities in the code.</p>
<p>The breach comes almost exactly a month after Twitch streamers <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/streamers-are-boycotting-twitch-today-to-protest-the-platforms-lack-of-action-on-hate-raids/">took September 1 to protest</a> the company&#8217;s lack of action against &#8220;hate raids,&#8221; where bots are used to flood other streamers with hate and harassment.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lpQmFIj50s"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/streamers-are-boycotting-twitch-today-to-protest-the-platforms-lack-of-action-on-hate-raids/">Streamers are boycotting Twitch today to protest the platform&#8217;s lack of action on &#8216;hate raids&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Streamers are boycotting Twitch today to protest the platform&#8217;s lack of action on &#8216;hate raids&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/streamers-are-boycotting-twitch-today-to-protest-the-platforms-lack-of-action-on-hate-raids/embed/#?secret=lpQmFIj50s" data-secret="lpQmFIj50s" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/hacker-leaks-twitch-source-code-and-creator-payout-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213334</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8216;Metroid: Dread&#8217; is a tense and fluid return to form for Nintendo&#8217;s enduring series</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/metroid-dread-is-a-tense-and-fluid-return-to-form-for-nintendos-enduring-series/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/metroid-dread-is-a-tense-and-fluid-return-to-form-for-nintendos-enduring-series/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 13:01:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metroid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metroid dread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2210924</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nintendo seems as unable to let go of its decades-old franchises as it is unwilling to stop reinventing them. But in Metroid: Dread the company has acknowledged that sometimes it really is better not to mess with a good thing. The game&#8217;s traditional approach may not move the genre forward like some recent standouts, but [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Nintendo seems as unable to let go of its decades-old franchises as it is unwilling to stop reinventing them. But in <a href="https://metroid.nintendo.com/"><em>Metroid: Dread</em> </a>the company has acknowledged that sometimes it really is better not to mess with a good thing. The game&#8217;s traditional approach may not move the genre forward like some recent standouts, but it&#8217;s a hell of a good time to play.</p>
<p>The first new &#8220;mainline&#8221; <em>Metroid</em> game to come out in more than a decade, <em>Dread</em> is a direct sequel to <em>Fusion</em>, though I&#8217;ll spare you the plot summary — like <em>Mario</em> and <em>Zelda</em> games, the story is secondary to the moment-to-moment experience. But suffice it to say that galactic bounty hunter Samus Aran finds herself stranded on ZDR, an alien planet she has been sent to investigate, and afflicted with an inexplicable &#8220;physical amnesia&#8221; that prevents her from using all the abilities we all know by now.</p>
<p>What follows, as far as I am permitted to say within the confines of Nintendo&#8217;s review guidelines, is a very <em>Metroid</em>-esque tunnel crawl through environments artificial and natural, all the while collecting new weapons and abilities that unlock new paths and generally imbue you with new power and confidence. In other words, not much has changed since 1986.</p>
<h3>Smooth sixty</h3>
<p>The first thing that must be said about Dread is that the controls and gameplay feel of Samus are wonderfully fluid and responsive. This was a big worry for me, as the feel of the main character is one of the most important parts of any game like this. In <em>Hollow Knight</em>, your character feels crisp and precise; in <em>Blasphemous</em>, he&#8217;s deliberate and weighty; in newcomer <em>Death&#8217;s Door</em>, smoothly maneuverable. In <em>Metroid: Dread</em>, Samus feels <em>fast </em>and <em>agile</em>.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2213073" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-4.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2213073" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2213073" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-4.jpg" alt="A screenshot of Metroid Dread for Nintendo Switch." width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-4.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-4.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-4.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-4.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-4.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-4.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-4.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2213073" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> A screenshot of Metroid Dread for Nintendo Switch.</p></div></p>
<p>Running at a steady 60 FPS, and with a base movement speed that feels like a sprint rather than the sedate jog Samus has sometimes used, it&#8217;s clear in this game that you are meant to be both hunter and hunted, moving quickly and responding quickly. Every action is fast and at your fingertips, and the game seems to want you to play on the run, picking off enemies at speed rather than hanging back in safety. You feel reasonably powerful, but your agility is your best asset.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s especially true in <em>Dread&#8217;s</em> signature areas where invincible hunter-killer robots known as EMMIs roam, listening for Samus&#8217;s step and pursuing doggedly if they detect her presence. Fast and able to scale walls and creep through crawl spaces, EMMIs are rather like <em>Alien</em>&#8216;s xenomorphs, and like one of those, if it gets hold of you it&#8217;s all over unless you can pull off a counter with very precise timing.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2213072" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-3.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2213072" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2213072" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-3.jpg" alt="A screenshot of Metroid Dread for Nintendo Switch." width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-3.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-3.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-3.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-3.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-3.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-3.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-3.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2213072" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> A screenshot of Metroid Dread for Nintendo Switch.</p></div></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s be very clear on this: you will die in <em>Metroid: Dread</em>, and you will die a lot. Probably about half the the time it will be an EMMI, which clambers out of a chute right in front of you and snatches you up as you panic, or corners you as you&#8217;re trying to find a safe place to hide. The rest of the time it will probably as you learn the unforgiving patterns of the various bosses. The overworld doesn&#8217;t seem quite so threatening once you have an energy tank or two — but when you enter one of those special EMMI zone doors (and thank god it saves when you do), your stress levels will skyrocket. Even the cloaking ability you gain a short way into the game is alarmingly limited in preventing your capture. And your one surefire way of defeating them, paradoxically, requires you to stand your ground, which is even worse than running away!</p>
<p>For the most part the game is tough but fair — I doubt it will present much of a challenge to the more masochistic class of gamers who do no-hit runs of <em>Demon&#8217;s Souls</em>, but it provides a consistent level of danger such that you&#8217;re always relieved to reach a save room. I&#8217;ve played up to the very end of the game and while there are definitely some difficulty spikes and some hilariously difficult counter timings, generally after a few tries you&#8217;ll understand what the game requires of you. Or you&#8217;ll get lucky.</p>
<p>You won&#8217;t be doing anything in the pause screen other than checking the map or re-checking the tutorial for a new item — there&#8217;s no inventory or loadout, every action is available by some combination of buttons, and this can get a bit unwieldy. Hold left bumper to free aim, right trigger to activate grapple, left stick to aim, jump with B and then hit Y&#8230; if you can.</p>
<h3>Saga of Samus</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2213074" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-5.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2213074" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2213074" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-5.jpg" alt="A screenshot of Metroid Dread for Nintendo Switch." width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-5.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-5.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-5.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-5.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-5.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-5.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-5.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2213074" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> A screenshot of Metroid Dread for Nintendo Switch.</p></div></p>
<p>While as mentioned, the story isn&#8217;t really the point of <em>Metroid</em> games, it is valuable, and the events in <em>Dread</em> do provide interesting beats and revelations in the ongoing saga. I&#8217;m forbidden to speak of it beyond the first couple areas, but I can say that compared with my personal favorite, <em>Hollow Knight</em>, there isn&#8217;t a lot of emotional investment. In that game, the combination of visual storytelling and music was a wonder to behold, and you got a sense of the places you visited being storied and tragic. In <em>Dread</em>, they feel much more like video game levels — with different feels and themes to be sure, but not the kind of ineffable <em>consequence</em> that has become a part of gaming vocabulary especially since the likes of <em>Dark Souls</em>.</p>
<p>The upside of that is that the level designers engineer these places very, very cleverly. The way you are funneled and looped through locations in the first few areas in fact makes them almost completely linear, yet you feel like you&#8217;re ranging around and following your nose — &#8220;Ah,&#8221; you think, &#8220;I remember seeing a door that I couldn&#8217;t open before&#8230; I&#8217;ll go back there,&#8221; not realizing it&#8217;s literally the only place you <em>can</em> go. Fortunately the upgrades you get to suit and weapons usually feel consequential outside acting as a key to open certain doors.</p>
<p>There are certainly points where things open up somewhat, but this is very much a guided tour of ZDR. At times it can even feel too restrictive and streamlined — while there is certainly backtracking, much of it is obviated by suspiciously conveniently placed teleporters, which tend to take you exactly where you need to go next. It takes a lot of the guesswork out of the game, which is a mixed blessing — I&#8217;ve been stumped in Metroidvanias many a time, but figuring out what to do next is part of the challenge.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2213075" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-map.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2213075" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2213075" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-map.jpg" alt="A screenshot of Metroid Dread for Nintendo Switch." width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-map.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-map.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-map.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-map.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-map.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-map.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-map.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2213075" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nintendo</p></div></p>
<p>The map is very nice, though, informative without revealing too much, and a &#8220;something is around here&#8221; flash fills every journey with pit stops as you blast the landscape trying to find the secret passage to the missile tank. Being able to show all of a certain type of door or item is a very helpful time-saver as well.</p>
<h3>And here we have the water area</h3>
<p>Feeling like you&#8217;re in a cohesive world is also nice, and something that <em>Dread</em> doesn&#8217;t really accomplish. The different areas you&#8217;ll visit are all distinct in look and feel, but they don&#8217;t really fit into one another at all. You get in a train or elevator and you&#8217;re in a whole new zone, with no overlaps or secret passages between them. In <em>Super Metroid</em>, for instance, you have the rocky surface with a secret base embedded in it, the wrecked ship crashed into a large ocean zone, all above the fiery core, and you travel through them logically. In <em>Dread</em>, you have the rocky area, the jungly area, the hot area, and so on, but they don&#8217;t feel connected.</p>
<p>While it may lack that exploratory <em>je ne sais quoi</em>, the areas themselves are beautiful and fun to get around, and you do repeatedly visit them unlocking whole new sections you had no idea existed. They also change over time as the plot and your abilities evolve, and these changes can feel both clever and overly limiting.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2213070" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2213070" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2213070" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-1.jpg" alt="A screenshot of Metroid Dread for Nintendo Switch." width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-1.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-1.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-1.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-1.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-1.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-1.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/metroid-1.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2213070" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> A screenshot of Metroid Dread for Nintendo Switch.</p></div></p>
<p>My journey in Dread lasted a little over 8 hours, up to what I believe is the final boss encounter (which I have not yet beat — it&#8217;s hard, okay?), though honestly it felt considerably longer than that even though I rushed through it. And of course like all <em>Metroid</em> games, there is pleasure in playing it multiple times with accumulated expertise. If there&#8217;s a significantly different new game plus mode I haven&#8217;t heard about it, and from what I could tell there isn&#8217;t much opportunity to sequence break — a major hobby of <em>Metroid</em> fandom, meaning skipping a boss or ability to tackle areas in a different order. I&#8217;m probably wrong, though.</p>
<p><em>Metroid: Dread</em> is a <em>Metroid</em> game through and through, and while it may not have the sheer size of some of the games that have taken up its mantle in recent years, it makes up for it with its incredibly fluid gameplay systems and propulsive energy. I always wanted to continue playing and had to peel myself away every night, though I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;d have been able to take my time even had the review deadline not been approaching. This is a game that wants to be played, but also treats your time respectfully, with minimal padding and constant forward movement. It&#8217;s not an epic, but not every game needs to be in order to be worth your time and money.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/metroid-dread-is-a-tense-and-fluid-return-to-form-for-nintendos-enduring-series/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2210924</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mindee’s API automagically parses documents without manual data entry</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/mindees-api-automagically-parses-documents-without-manual-data-entry/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/mindees-api-automagically-parses-documents-without-manual-data-entry/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 13:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mindee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ocr]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212761</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mindee offers an API that lets you turn raw data in a paper document into structured data. The startup is coming out of stealth mode and has raised a $14 million Series A round led by GGV Capital. Other investors in today’s funding round include Alven, Serena Capital, Bpifrance’s Digital Venture fund as well as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://mindee.com">Mindee</a> offers an API that lets you turn raw data in a paper document into structured data. The startup is coming out of stealth mode and has raised a $14 million Series A round led by GGV Capital.</p>
<p>Other investors in today’s funding round include Alven, Serena Capital, Bpifrance’s Digital Venture fund as well as several business angels, such as Algolia co-founder Nicolas Dessaigne and Datadog co-founder Alexis Lê-Quôc.</p>
<p>If you’re working on a product that involves saving paper receipts, scanning driver licenses or entering invoices in a system, chances are you’ve been looking at ways to automate that process as much as possible. Many companies rely on OCR services (optical character recognition) from Google or Amazon.</p>
<p>But turning text into raw digital text isn’t the most complicated step. After that, you want to turn raw digital text into structured data. This is much more complicated as companies often rely on humans to identify the right information and paste it in the right data field.</p>
<p>Essentially, you can process a photo through Mindee API and turn it into relevant data for your product without any manual data entry. Many industries could use this kind of API-based product, from expense management to procurement, accounting, loan applications and more.</p>
<p>Some of Mindee’s clients include Qonto, Payfit, Spendesk and Lucca. With the new funding, the startup plans to get more customers in Europe and expand to the U.S.</p>
<p>Behind the scenes, the company has trained its algorithms using machine learning on large data sets of documents. It is supposed to get better over time as it processes more documents. The company already processes millions of pages every month from its customers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup charges its clients based on volume. Once you go over the free tier, you get charged per processed page. And because it’s a hosted API, integrating Mindee in your product doesn’t require a ton of changes in your product. You call an API and receive structured data in return.</p>
<p>What makes Mindee special is that the experience for the end user is much better. For instance, when you try to sign up to a service that requires your passport information, you usually have to enter your personal information, take a photo and wait. It’ll ping someone so that they can make sure it’s the same information in the registration system and on the photo.</p>
<p>If Mindee manages to capture data in near real-time and with a near perfect level of accuracy, you could get a much snappier experience. And that could lead to more customers for Mindee’s clients.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/mindees-api-automagically-parses-documents-without-manual-data-entry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212761</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marc Lore-backed &#8216;conversational commerce&#8217; startup Wizard raises $50M Series A from NEA</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/marc-lore-backed-conversational-commerce-startup-wizard-raises-50m-series-a-from-nea/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/marc-lore-backed-conversational-commerce-startup-wizard-raises-50m-series-a-from-nea/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 13:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[a.i.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[allbirds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[austin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief people officer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conversational commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imessage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marc Lore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[messages]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messenger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[natural language processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neiman Marcus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sameer Gandhi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sephora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tony Florence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wizard]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212799</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Marc Lore, who earlier this year stepped down from his role as Walmart&#8217;s head of U.S. e-commerce, is now backing a new startup in the e-commerce space called Wizard. Lore has taken on the roles of co-founder, chairman of the board and investor in Wizard, a B2B startup in the &#8220;conversational commerce&#8221; space which believes [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Marc Lore, who earlier this year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/marc-lore-leaves-walmart-a-little-over-four-years-after-selling-jet-com-for-3b/">stepped down from his role</a> as Walmart&#8217;s head of U.S. e-commerce, is now backing a new startup in the e-commerce space called <a href="https://wizard.com/">Wizard</a>. Lore has taken on the roles of co-founder, chairman of the board and investor in Wizard, a B2B startup in the &#8220;conversational commerce&#8221; space which believes the future of mobile commerce will take place over text. Ahead of its official launch, Wizard today is announcing its $50 million Series A, led by NEA&#8217;s Tony Florence.</p>
<p>Both Lore and Accel also participated in the round. Florence, Lore and Accel&#8217;s Sameer Gandhi have board seats alongside Wizard&#8217;s co-founder and CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/melissabridgeford">Melissa Bridgeford.</a></p>
<p>The startup has an interesting founding story, as it&#8217;s not quite as new as it would have you believe.</p>
<p>Bridgeford, who once left a finance career in New York, founded and ran Austin-based <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/stylust">Stylust</a>, a text-based shopping platform that aimed to offer a shopping assistant for consumers. Its users could text screenshots and photos and be served recommendations of products they could then buy over text, without visiting a website. Stylust took advantage of AI and image recognition capabilities to help provide consumers with options of what to buy. There was also a B2B component to Stylust, which promised brands a &#8220;one-text checkout&#8221; experience. <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210304132801/https://stylust.com/">According to a cached version of its website</a>, the company touted a 35% conversion rate &#8212; or 10x higher performance than web-based commerce.</p>
<p>Wizard says it &#8220;acquired&#8221; Stylust, but the entire team (minus a few new C-Suite hires in September), are all prior Stylelust employees. Wizard did not have a product in the market at the time of the acquisition.</p>
<p>Technically speaking, it&#8217;s a brand-new company &#8212; and one that now has the ability to lean on Lore&#8217;s experience in e-commerce as well as that of top-tier investors.</p>
<p>Bridgeford described Wizard as an opportunity &#8220;to build our vision on a much larger scale and to partner with Marc, who&#8217;s really a tremendous visionary in retail tech and really a proven founder and a proven operator.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We really share the vision that conversational commerce is the future of retail,&#8221; Bridgeford adds.</p>
<p>The company isn&#8217;t yet willing to talk in detail about its product, however. Instead, it describes the B2B service as one that will enable brands and retailers to transact with consumers over text. The service is positioned as &#8220;an end-to-end shopping experience&#8221; on mobile from opt-in to search to payments and shipping and even reorders.</p>
<p>These text-based chats won&#8217;t feel like the annoying interactions you may have had with messaging app chatbots in the past, Bridgeford claims.</p>
<p>&#8220;What we&#8217;ve found is a combination of automation and human touch really provides the optimal experience for users, while also building a powerful technology on the backend that&#8217;s built to scale. That&#8217;s really where the Holy Grail is,&#8221; she explains. &#8220;And that&#8217;s really what we see for the future of conversational commerce&#8230;we&#8217;re incorporating chat abilities, natural language processing &#8212; all of those technologies are moving very quickly.&#8221;</p>
<p>In other words, the frustrating experience you may have had with a chatbot a year or two ago, may not be the experience you would have today.</p>
<p>&#8220;The goal of the technology is to make it seem like you are speaking with a human, when it&#8217;s really technology-enabled,&#8221; Bridgeford adds.</p>
<p>Stylust also brought its brand relationships to Wizard as part of the deal.</p>
<p>An earlier version of the Stylust website listed clients including <a href="https://laughingglasscocktails.com/">Laughing Glass Cocktails</a>, <a href="https://www.desolasmezcal.com/">Desolas Mezcal</a>, <a href="https://www.pinhookbourbon.com/">Pinhook Bourbon</a>, <a href="https://marshhouse.com/">Marsh House Rum</a> and <a href="https://www.neftvodkaus.com/">Neft Vodkas</a>. A focus on wine and spirits retail was also mentioned in <a href="https://www.bizjournals.com/bizwomen/news/latest-news/2020/12/text-based-shopping-startup.html?page=all">an Austin Biz Journal feature</a>. However, a write-up about <a href="https://stpetecatalyst.com/florida-funders-backs-text-based-shopping-platform/">Florida Funders&#8217; backing of Stylust in 2020</a> noted relationships with top-tier retailers like Neiman Marcus, Walmart, Sephora and Allbirds.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s unclear which relationships will continue with Wizard or whether it will continue to focus on the alcohol brands or other retailers, as the company declined to discuss any details related to its business beyond the funding.</p>
<p>The startup plans to use the funds to hire in areas like AI, machine learning and natural language processing, as well as in non-tech roles, like sales, finance, and operations. One of the key hires it&#8217;s still looking to make is a chief people officer. Though the current team is working in offices based in both New York and Austin, Wizard is hiring nationwide to fill roles on its remote tech team, it says.</p>
<p>Wizard already has some competitors whose services address certain aspects of its business, particularly in the text marketing space. But more broadly, there are other ways that consumers interact with brands over messaging which could evolve into more fully-formed products over time, too. Today, consumers often discover products on social media, like Facebook and Instagram, then turn to Messenger or DMs for product questions. WhatsApp is <a href="https://faq.whatsapp.com/general/account-and-profile/about-catalog/?lang=en">building out a product catalog for businesses</a> that enables consumers to discover products and services directly in the app. Even Apple entered the market with <a href="https://www.apple.com/ios/business-chat/">Business Chat</a>, which already allows for purchases made through iMessage chats.</p>
<p>Wizard&#8217;s focus on SMS instead of requiring a dedicated messaging app or, say, an iPhone with iMessage, for instance, could help it to differentiate from competitors. Still, betting on SMS &#8212; increasingly a <a href="https://www.unionrecorder.com/news/bbb-receive-a-text-with-a-surprise-offer-don-t-click-that-link/article_8a30b040-2519-11ec-8ad9-e3fa5edf338d.html">home</a> to <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/news-events/blog/2020/03/02/mobile-phone-texts-spam-and-scams">text-based spam</a> and <a href="https://www.thestreet.com/personal-finance/phone-scams-getting-worse-how-to-protect-yourself">scams</a> &#8212; is a riskier bet. But it&#8217;s one Lore is willing to make.</p>
<p>&#8220;Having spent most of my career so far in e-commerce, it’s been clear that conversational commerce is the future of retail,&#8221; said Lore. &#8220;With deep learning becoming more pervasive, the ability to create a hyper-personalized, conversational shopping experience is going to transform how people shop — and I’m confident that what Melissa and the team at Wizard are building will lead that transformation.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>Correction, 10/6/21 10:12 AM ET: The name of Bridgeford&#8217;s prior company was Stylust, not Stylelust. We have corrected this. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/marc-lore-backed-conversational-commerce-startup-wizard-raises-50m-series-a-from-nea/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212799</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>As Logicworks approaches $100M in revenue, it announces new cloud migration platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/as-logicworks-approaches-100m-in-revenue-it-announces-new-cloud-migration-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/as-logicworks-approaches-100m-in-revenue-it-announces-new-cloud-migration-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 13:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud migration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logicworks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Logicworks might not be a household name, but since 2012 it has been working with customers to help them move to the cloud and manage their workloads once they get there. By following that approach, the late stage startup is closing in on $100 million in revenue. Today, it announced a new Cloud Reliability Platform [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.logicworks.com/">Logicworks</a> might not be a household name, but since 2012 it has been working with customers to help them move to the cloud and manage their workloads once they get there. By following that approach, the late stage startup is closing in on $100 million in revenue. Today, it announced a new Cloud Reliability Platform (CRP) designed to help companies migrate to AWS or Azure safely in a compliant way &#8212; and to keep that revenue engine cranking.</p>
<p>CEO Ken Ziegler says that Logicworks has taken a long view to building the business, and today&#8217;s announcement is the culmination of a lot of work over the years of staying tightly connected to the major cloud platforms.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve taken a much longer approach, which is you build a platform from day one where basically you pick which cloud you&#8217;re going to support and then build really high quality tooling, telemetry and automation around those platforms. Over time you end up with this really nice high margin recurring revenue engine that becomes an integral part of our customers long term success and operations because we&#8217;re tying in compliance, security and scalability,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>As companies move ever faster to the cloud, Logicworks is helping their customers by using a template approach to migrate in a secure way, while remaining in compliance with whatever industry standard is applicable whether that&#8217;s HIPPA, FINRA or any other set of rules. Customers can choose the template that applies to their industry, apply whatever customizations are required and then move in a secure and compliant fashion to the cloud.</p>
<p>As the company approaches that $100 million revenue threshold, it has numbers that are solid enough to support an IPO, but Ziegler says that he is content to continue building the company for now and to take advantage of the more generalized growth in the cloud market, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/cloud-infrastructure-market-kept-growing-in-q2-reaching-42b/">reached $42 billion last quarter</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xBdbf8NKrj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/12/14/logicworks-raises-135m-for-its-cloud-automation-and-management-platform/">Logicworks raises $135M for its cloud automation and management platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Logicworks raises $135M for its cloud automation and management platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2016/12/14/logicworks-raises-135m-for-its-cloud-automation-and-management-platform/embed/#?secret=xBdbf8NKrj" data-secret="xBdbf8NKrj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In fact, Ziegler says that in his conversations with AWS executives they are indicating the bottleneck for customers is getting to the cloud in the first place, and that is the sweet spot of Logicworks &#8212; helping companies migrate to the cloud</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;That&#8217;s really what we built this platform to do, and if we can maintain credibility to really unstick migrations, and then show how they can run successfully, [we can continue to grow],&#8221; he said. He adds that because the company has a long term relationship with the cloud providers, it can also help customers take advantage of the continued innovation happening on these platforms.</p>
<p>&#8220;The cloud operators aren&#8217;t sitting still, so if you want to maintain that innovation curve, which is why you&#8217;re to going to the cloud in the first place, you want to work with someone that&#8217;s going to make sure that that&#8217;s included with the long term success as part of the partnership,&#8221; he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/as-logicworks-approaches-100m-in-revenue-it-announces-new-cloud-migration-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213287</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cabify bolts on grocery deliveries in Spain with Lola Market tie-up</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/cabify-bolts-on-grocery-deliveries-in-spain-with-lola-market-tie-up/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/cabify-bolts-on-grocery-deliveries-in-spain-with-lola-market-tie-up/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 12:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carrefour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glovo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grocery deliveries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lola Market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[madrid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ride hailing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Spanish ride-hailing unicorn Cabify is getting into grocery deliveries as it looks to add another string to its multi-modal mobility and urban utility bow. It announced the addition of a &#8216;Super&#8217; option in its app today &#8212; which is available for users in nine cities in its home market, namely: A Coruña, Alicante, Barcelona, Madrid, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Spanish ride-hailing unicorn Cabify is getting into grocery deliveries as it looks to add another string to its multi-modal mobility and urban utility bow.</p>
<p>It announced the addition of a &#8216;Super&#8217; option in its app today &#8212; which is available for users in nine cities in its home market, namely: A Coruña, Alicante, Barcelona, Madrid, Malaga, Murcia, Seville, Valencia and Zaragoza.</p>
<p>The grocery delivery service is powered by a partnership with local grocery picking startup, Lola Market. But there&#8217;s an added twist here because the latter was acquired by Spain&#8217;s on-demand delivery platform giant, Glovo, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/glovo-bags-two-grocery-picking-and-delivery-startups/">last month</a> &#8212; as part of its efforts to expand a speedy urban grocery delivery business. So it&#8217;s been a busy few months (of being <em>in</em> demand) for the smaller Spanish startup.</p>
<p>The relationship between Cabify and Glovo (via Lola Market) looks to be only at the level of a strategic partnership for now.</p>
<p>Last month Glovo said Lola Market would retain its brand and operate independently post-acquisition — led by Gonçalo Soares da Costa, CEO of a second grocery picking business, Mercadão, that Glovo simultaneously acquired.</p>
<p>And while Cabify is touting the new &#8216;Super&#8217; offering as the first time its users will be able to grocery shop via its app, the service (including delivery) is being fulfilled by Lola Market. So it&#8217;s a purely technical integration &#8212; and looks like a play to cross-sell the ride-hailing platform&#8217;s users on the convenience of push-button, app-based supermarket shopping too.</p>
<p>Madrid-based Lola Market, meanwhile, deliveries groceries from Spanish supermarket chains including Makro, Lidl, Carrefour, Mercadona, DIA, Alcampo, as well as saying it can do picking from traditional markets and some specialised shops.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2213301" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2213301" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2213301" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Cabify_Groceries_LolaMarket-3.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="510" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Cabify_Groceries_LolaMarket-3.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Cabify_Groceries_LolaMarket-3.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Cabify_Groceries_LolaMarket-3.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Cabify_Groceries_LolaMarket-3.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Cabify_Groceries_LolaMarket-3.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Cabify_Groceries_LolaMarket-3.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Cabify_Groceries_LolaMarket-3.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2213301" class="wp-caption-text">The new &#8216;Super&#8217; option in Cabify&#8217;s app in Spain (Image credits: Cabify)</p></div></p>
<p>This summer Cabify rolled out a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/cabify-launches-cabify-go-a-multi-modal-subscription-service/">pilot multimodal subscription offering in Madrid</a> &#8212; seeking to nudge users towards subscription plans that make use of its different mobility offerings &#8212; ride-hailing, its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/10/movo-grabs-22-5m-to-get-more-cities-in-latam-scooting/">electric micromobility subsidiary MOVO</a>, bike subscription service Bive and courier service.</p>
<p>With the new grocery tie-up it&#8217;s billing the move as a further expansion of this multi-modality strategy &#8212; and trying to claim green credentials, by suggesting it will reduce trips in private cars and help improve the urban environment by reducing emissions through grouped deliveries.</p>
<p>Though of course ride-hailing can negatively impact cities by clogging roads and causing congestion that can degrade the quality of public transport services and other emissions-free mobility options (e.g. biking and walking), as well as worsening air quality (even electric cars can produce pollution by generating particulate matter, such as from wear to car tyres).</p>
<p>Ride-hailing services also took a knock during the pandemic &#8212; while grocery deliveries surged during lockdowns. So diversification looks sensible.</p>
<p>&#8220;This new service expands the concept of what we know as &#8216;multi-mobility&#8217;,&#8221; said Lucía Chávarri, VP of new business at Cabify in a statement. &#8220;With the &#8216;Super&#8217; service, thanks to the collaboration with Lola Market, we avoid trips to supermarkets in private cars, which are often occupied by only one person, and which are very common in cities. &#8220;In addition, online shopping improves the efficiency of available resources, because delivery allows different orders to be grouped together and delivered following the best route.&#8221;</p>
<p>Luis Pérez del Val, the founder and CEO of Lola Market, suggested the &#8220;collaboration&#8221; with Cabify will allow it to reach many more users and &#8220;take advantage of our infrastructure, making the service accessible to many more people in major cities&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;With this integration we will be able to further optimise the efforts of our Personal Shoppers,&#8221; he also said, sketching the use-case of a Cabify user getting picked up at the airport and on the way to their destination having time to buy their groceries in the app and receive them when they arrive home.</p>
<p>&#8220;The possibility of shopping in 1 hour or at the scheduled time is a huge opportunity for this collaboration,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Cabify also operates its ride-hailing platform in a number of cities in Latin America. We&#8217;ve asked if it has any plans to add grocery deliveries for users in that region.</p>
<p>More broadly, the lines between different on-demand city-based &#8216;convenience&#8217; services continue to blur in Europe and the Americas as different platform giants jockey for position and profitability &#8212; chasing the dream of a <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-55929418">China-style &#8216;super app&#8217;</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/cabify-bolts-on-grocery-deliveries-in-spain-with-lola-market-tie-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213284</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pandemic-driven boom in e-commerce helps Huboo&#8217;s warehousing platform close $81M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/pandemic-driven-boom-in-e-commerce-helps-huboos-warehousing-platform-close-81m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/pandemic-driven-boom-in-e-commerce-helps-huboos-warehousing-platform-close-81m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 12:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ada Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bristol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eBay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fred destin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hearst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Huboo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maersk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Martin Bysh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mubadala Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mubadala Capital Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netherlands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online marketplace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online marketplaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Publishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stride]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warehouse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2213291</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many e-commerce businesses run their entire order fulfillment process in-house because outsourcing it can be expensive. But the COVID-19 pandemic has supercharged many small and medium-sized businesses (SMBs) as consumers switched to home deliveries and ‘digitized’ their lifestyles to a far greater extent. It means this surge in e-commerce sales is subsequently leading to a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Many e-commerce businesses run their entire order fulfillment process in-house because outsourcing it can be expensive. But the COVID-19 pandemic has supercharged many small and medium-sized businesses (SMBs) as consumers switched to home deliveries and ‘digitized’ their lifestyles to a far greater extent. It means this surge in e-commerce sales is subsequently leading to a boom in warehousing and shipping.</p>
<p>It would seem then that <a href="https://www.huboo.co.uk/">Huboo</a> was virtually tailor-made for the post-pandemic era. It has a full-stack, software-driven e-commerce warehousing and fulfillment system that is turning out to be a boon to these e-commerce-driven SMBs.</p>
<p>It’s now closed a £60 million ($81.4m) Series B financing led by US-based Mubadala Capital. The round was joined by existing investors including Stride, Ada Ventures, Hearst, Episode 1 and Maersk Growth, and takes Huboo’s total funding raised to nearly £80 million since April 2019, after its £14 million Series A funding, raised last year.<br />
 <br />
Founded in 2017 by Martin Bysh and Paul Dodd out of one warehouse in Bristol, the company now has four fulfilment centres across the UK, a site in the Netherlands, and has plans to roll out across other European markets. Each center is split into a ‘micro-hub’ of a few hundred square foot enabling staff to pick and pack inventory more efficiently. It says it has over 1,000 customers, small and large.</p>
<p>The company’s merchant platform uses APIs to integrate with popular sales channels and online marketplaces such as Amazon, eBay, and Shopify. These allow D2C brands to view and track orders and manage their inventory on a dashboard. It also has proprietary software to manage warehouse operations.</p>
<p>Martin Bysh, co-founder and CEO of Huboo, said: “Scores of new and existing retail businesses now see their future in e-commerce, but while anyone can set up an online store-front and start selling within hours, the infrastructure powering e-commerce is alarmingly outdated, inefficient, inflexible and expensive.”<br />
 <br />
He said this hub model addresses this: “It brings flexibility and affordability to the incredibly complex fulfilment piece so that online retailers of all sizes – from part-timers to fast-growth D2C leaders – can benefit.”</p>
<p>Over a call, he added: “We win clients from Amazon’s ‘Fulfilled By Amazon’ (FBA) because part of the 20% that the seller pays to Amazon goes to cross-subsidize the inexpensive fulfillment, but if you&#8217;re trying to use FBA (because you&#8217;re selling on eBay or Shopify) it&#8217;s hopeless. It’s, like, three times as expensive. So we get people using Shopify or eBay. They love what we&#8217;re doing… We compete very effectively against them… They&#8217;re not the nimble creature they were years ago.”<br />
 <br />
Fatou Bintou Sagnang, Partner at Mubadala Capital Ventures, said: “Huboo’s product solves one of the most critical pain points for e-commerce companies &#8211; while order fulfillment is a core function for these companies, it is not part of their core competency. By combining logistics with a user-friendly software platform, Huboo delivers a superior fulfillment experience and allows businesses of all sizes to continue focusing on core activities such as product development while managing growing demand from their customers.” <br />
 <br />
Matt Penneycard, Founding Partner at Ada Ventures, said: “Huboo is a shining light of UK tech, and we’re particularly delighted for a Bristol-based company to be succeeding this way! Martin and Paul’s incredible vision is becoming a global reality at supersonic speed.” </p>
<p>Fred Destin, Founder at Stride.VC, said: “Huboo does the seemingly impossible &#8211; to deliver high-precision e-commerce fulfillment cost-effectively to businesses of all sizes and levels of complexity. Huboo innovates both in how it looks at logistics, as an interlocked set of lego blocks connected by software, and how it looks at people, as a team of empowered self-starters obsessed about customer success.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/pandemic-driven-boom-in-e-commerce-helps-huboos-warehousing-platform-close-81m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2213291</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
