<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 20:07:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Japanese startup ispace raises $46M to support planned moon missions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/japanese-startup-ispace-raises-46m-to-support-planned-moon-missions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/japanese-startup-ispace-raises-46m-to-support-planned-moon-missions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 18:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Incubate Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ispace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185770</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Japanese startup ispace has raised $46 million in a fresh round of Series C funding as it looks to complete three lunar lander missions in three years. The funding will go toward the second and third of the planned missions, scheduled for 2023 and 2024. The first mission, which ispace aims to conduct in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Japanese startup ispace has raised $46 million in a fresh round of Series C funding as it looks to complete three lunar lander missions in three years.</p>
<p>The funding will go toward the second and third of the planned missions, scheduled for 2023 and 2024. The first mission, which ispace aims to conduct in the latter half of 2022, is being furnished by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/20/moon-lander-startup-ispace-raises-28-million-and-launches-a-new-lunar-data-platform/">earlier financing</a>.</p>
<p>The Series C was led by Japanese VC firm Incubate Fund, with additional investment from partnerships managed by Innovation Engine, funds managed by SBI Investment Co., Katsunori Sago, Aizawa Investments and funds managed by HiJoJo Partners and Aizawa Asset Management. Incubate Fund’s investments in ispace stretch back to the company’s seed round in 2014.</p>
<p>Ispace’s total funding now stands at $195.5 million.</p>
<p>The company said last month it had started building the lunar landing flight module for the 2022 mission at a facility owned by space launch company ArianeGroup, in Lampoldshausen, Germany. The lander for that first mission, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/30/ispace-reveals-the-final-design-of-its-lunar-lander-ahead-of-its-first-mission-to-the-moon-in-2022/">the Hakuto-R</a>, will take three months to reach the moon, largely to save costs and additional weight from propellant. It<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/japanese-space-company-ispace-aims-to-send-landers-to-the-moon/"> will deliver</a> a 22-pound rover for Saudi Arabia’s Mohammed bin Rashid Space Center, a lunar robot for the Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency and payload from three Canadian companies. The lander will reach the moon aboard a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket.</p>
<p>The 7.5 foot-tall Hakuto-R will also be used in the second mission in 2023, to deposit a small ispace rover that will collect data to support the company&#8217;s subsequent missions to the moon. For the final mission, the Toyko-based startup is developing a larger lander in the United States.</p>
<p><iframe title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qAzfpOkACDk?start=1" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Ispace describes its long-term goal as being a &#8220;gateway for private sector companies to bring their business to the Moon.&#8221; The company has particular interest in helping spur a space-based economy, noting on its <a href="https://ispace-inc.com/">website</a> that the moon&#8217;s water resources represent &#8220;untapped potential.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nKwcBSavA0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/29/as-launch-market-matures-space-opportunities-on-the-ground-take-off/">As launch market matures, space opportunities on the ground take off</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As launch market matures, space opportunities on the ground take off&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/29/as-launch-market-matures-space-opportunities-on-the-ground-take-off/embed/#?secret=nKwcBSavA0" data-secret="nKwcBSavA0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/japanese-startup-ispace-raises-46m-to-support-planned-moon-missions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185770</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Enterprise AI 2.0: The acceleration of B2B AI innovation has begun</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/enterprise-ai-2-0-the-acceleration-of-b2b-innovation-has-begun/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/enterprise-ai-2-0-the-acceleration-of-b2b-innovation-has-begun/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 18:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B2B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybernetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Cloud and Enterprise Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two decades after businesses started deploying AI solutions, one can argue they’ve made little progress in achieving significant gains in efficiency relative to the hype that drove expectations.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Eshwar Belani</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/EshwarBelani">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Eshwar Belani is an operating partner at <a href="https://www.symphonyai.com/">Symphony AI</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Two decades after businesses first started deploying AI solutions, one can argue that they’ve made little progress in achieving significant gains in efficiency and profitability relative to the hype that drove initial expectations.</p>
<p>On the surface, recent data supports AI skeptics. Almost <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2019/07/19/why-do-87-of-data-science-projects-never-make-it-into-production/">90%</a> of data science projects never make it to production; only <a href="https://blogs.gartner.com/andrew_white/2019/01/03/our-top-data-and-analytics-predicts-for-2019/">20%</a> of analytics insights through 2022 will achieve business outcomes; and even companies that have developed an enterprisewide AI strategy are seeing failure rates of up to <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20190708005039/en/">50%</a>.</p>
<p>But the past 25 years have only been the first phase in the evolution of enterprise AI — or what we might call Enterprise AI 1.0. That’s where many businesses remain today. However, companies on the leading edge of AI innovation have advanced to the next generation, which will define the coming decade of big data, analytics and automation — Enterprise AI 2.0.</p>
<p>The difference between these two generations of enterprise AI is not academic. For executives across the business spectrum — from healthcare and retail to media and finance — the evolution from 1.0 to 2.0 is a chance to learn and adapt from past failures, create concrete expectations for future uses and justify the rising investment in AI that we see across industries.</p>
<p>Two decades from now, when business leaders look back to the 2020s, the companies who achieved Enterprise AI 2.0 first will have come to be big winners in the economy, having differentiated their services, scooped up market share and positioned themselves for ongoing innovation.</p>
<p>Framing the digital transformations of the future as an evolution from Enterprise AI 1.0 to 2.0 provides a conceptual model for business leaders developing strategies to compete in the age of automation and advanced analytics.</p>
<h2>Enterprise AI 1.0 (the status quo)</h2>
<p>Starting in the mid-1990s, AI was a sector marked by speculative testing, experimental interest and exploration. These activities occurred almost exclusively in the domain of data scientists. As Gartner wrote in a recent <a href="https://blogs.gartner.com/andrew_white/2019/01/03/our-top-data-and-analytics-predicts-for-2019/">report</a>, these efforts were “alchemy … run by wizards whose talents will not scale in the organization.”<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/enterprise-ai-2-0-the-acceleration-of-b2b-innovation-has-begun/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185512</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook cuts off NYU researcher access, prompting rebuke from lawmakers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/facebook-ad-observatory-nyu-researchers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/facebook-ad-observatory-nyu-researchers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 18:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook Ad Library]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Trade Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Julia Angwin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mark warner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NYU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ron Wyden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook shut down accounts belonging to two academic researchers late Tuesday, cutting off their ability to study political ads and misinformation on the world&#8217;s biggest social network. The company accused the academics of engaging in &#8220;unauthorized scraping&#8221; and compromising user privacy on the platform, claims that Facebook&#8217;s many critics are slamming as a thin pretense [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook shut down accounts belonging to two academic researchers late Tuesday, cutting off their ability to study political ads and misinformation on the world&#8217;s biggest social network.</p>
<p>The company accused the academics of engaging in &#8220;unauthorized scraping&#8221; and compromising user privacy on the platform, claims that Facebook&#8217;s many critics are slamming as a <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/08/research-cannot-be-the-justification-for-compromising-peoples-privacy/">thin pretense</a> for killing the transparency work.</p>
<p>The company took action against Laura Edelson and Damon McCoy, two well-known researchers affiliated with<a href="https://cybersecurityfordemocracy.org/"> NYU&#8217;s Cybersecurity for Democracy project</a> who have long sparred with the company. The move cuts off their access to Facebook&#8217;s Ad Library — one of the company&#8217;s only meaningful transparency efforts to date — and data on popular posts from the social media monitoring service CrowdTangle.</p>
<p>Facebook has a history with Edelson and McCoy. The company served the pair cease and desist letters<a href="https://www.niemanlab.org/2020/10/facebooks-threat-to-the-nyu-ad-observatory-is-an-attack-on-ethical-research/"> just weeks before the 2020 election</a>, calling on the team to disable an opt-in browser tool called Ad Observer and unpublish their findings. Ad Observer is a <a href="https://adobserver.org/">browser tool anyone can install</a> that&#8217;s designed to give researchers a rare glimpse into how Facebook targets the ads that have transformed it into a trillion-dollar company.</p>
<p>&#8220;Over the last several years, we’ve used this access to uncover systemic flaws in the Facebook Ad Library, identify misinformation in political ads including many sowing distrust in our election system, and to study Facebook’s apparent amplification of partisan misinformation,&#8221; Edelson said on Twitter.</p>
<p>&#8220;By suspending our accounts, Facebook has effectively ended all this work. Facebook has also effectively cut off access to more than two dozen other researchers and journalists who get access to Facebook data through our project, including our work measuring vaccine misinformation with the<a href="https://www.viralityproject.org/"> Virality Project</a> and many other partners who rely on our data.&#8221;</p>
<p>The incident set off a fresh round of criticism about the company&#8217;s preference for opacity over transparency when it comes to some of the more dangerous behavior that the platform incubates.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>By Wednesday, Facebook&#8217;s actions had attracted the attention of some members of Congress. Sen. Ron Wyden (D-OR) criticized Facebook&#8217;s decision to punish the researchers under the pretense of protecting users in light of the company&#8217;s long history of invasive privacy practices. Wyden also called Facebook&#8217;s bluff over its claim that revoking researcher access is an effort to <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2020/04/ftc-gives-final-approval-modify-ftcs-2012-privacy-order-facebook">comply with a privacy order from the FTC</a> that the company was issued for its previous user privacy violations.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">After years of abusing users&#39; privacy, it&#39;s rich for Facebook to use it as an excuse to crack down on researchers exposing its problems. I&#39;ve asked the FTC to confirm that this excuse is as bogus as it sounds. <a href="https://t.co/eHuPiVYFe9">https://t.co/eHuPiVYFe9</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Ron Wyden (@RonWyden) <a href="https://twitter.com/RonWyden/status/1422961646096424963?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 4, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Sen. Mark Warner (D-VA) also weighed in on Facebook&#8217;s latest controversy, calling the decision &#8220;deeply concerning.&#8221; Warner praised independent researchers for &#8220;consistently [improving] the integrity and safety of social media platforms by exposing harmful and exploitative activity.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;It’s past time for Congress to act to bring greater transparency to the shadowy world of online advertising, which continues to be a major vector for fraud and misconduct,&#8221; Warner said.</p>
<p>Firefox developer Mozilla came to the <a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/news/why-facebooks-claims-about-the-ad-observer-are-wrong/">defense of Ad Observer</a> on Wednesday, noting that the company &#8220;reviewed it twice, conducting both a code review and examining the consent flow&#8221; before recommending the browser extension through its storefront. In a blog post, Mozilla&#8217;s head of trust stated that Facebook&#8217;s claims &#8220;simply do not hold water.&#8221;</p>
<p>A number of <a href="https://knightcolumbia.org/content/researchers-nyu-knight-institute-condemn-facebooks-effort-to-squelch-independent-research-about-misinformation">free press organizations</a>, researchers and misinformation experts also condemned Facebook&#8217;s decision Wednesday. &#8220;Facebook’s cavalier approach to privacy enabled it to become so dominant,&#8221; <a href="https://themarkup.org/press-release-20210804">The Markup&#8217;s Julia Angwin and Nabiha Syed</a> wrote in a joint statement.</p>
<p>&#8220;But now, when independent researchers want to interrogate that platform and the influence it commands, Facebook is propping up user privacy as a shield to hide behind.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="M9nQo6gRoq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/24/facebook-settles-with-ftc-5-billion-and-new-privacy-guarantees/">Facebook settles with FTC: $5 billion and new privacy guarantees</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook settles with FTC: $5 billion and new privacy guarantees&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/24/facebook-settles-with-ftc-5-billion-and-new-privacy-guarantees/embed/#?secret=M9nQo6gRoq" data-secret="M9nQo6gRoq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sdzCcozlua"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/24/9-reasons-the-facebook-ftc-settlement-is-a-joke/">9 reasons the Facebook FTC settlement is a joke</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;9 reasons the Facebook FTC settlement is a joke&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/24/9-reasons-the-facebook-ftc-settlement-is-a-joke/embed/#?secret=sdzCcozlua" data-secret="sdzCcozlua" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/facebook-ad-observatory-nyu-researchers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185737</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: Which immigration options allow me to launch my own startup?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/dear-sophie-which-immigration-options-allow-me-to-launch-my-own-startup/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/dear-sophie-which-immigration-options-allow-me-to-launch-my-own-startup/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 18:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B visa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup visa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zoe Lofgren]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185480</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m appreciative that I made it through the H-1B lottery, but I’m stuck in a rut. I really want to start something of my own. Are there any immigration options that would allow me to do that?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/dear-sophie-should-we-sponsor-international-hires-for-h-1b-transfers-and-green-cards/">Dear Sophie: Should we sponsor international hires for H-1B transfers and green cards? </a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/dear-sophie-should-we-look-to-canada-to-retain-international-talent/">Dear Sophie: Should we look to Canada to retain international talent?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>Extra Crunch members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Dear Sophie,</strong></p>
<p><strong>I’ve been working on an H-1B in the U.S. for nearly two years. </strong></p>
<p><strong>While I’m immensely appreciative of my company’s sponsorship and that I made it through the H-1B lottery and am working, I’m stuck in a rut. I really want to start something of my own and work on my own terms in the United States. </strong></p>
<p><strong>Are there any immigration options that would allow me to do that?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Seeking Satisfaction near Stanford</strong></p>
<p>Dear Seeking,</p>
<p>A couple of exciting immigration news updates to get us started today! In <a href="https://bit.ly/3fsIUZ0">breaking startup founder news</a>, U.S. Rep. Zoe Lofgren (D-CA) introduced the <a href="https://lofgren.house.gov/media/press-releases/lofgren-introduces-legislation-create-new-visa-program-immigrant-entrepreneurs">LIKE Act</a> for startup founders in the House of Representatives last week. Below, we’ll share what this could mean for your startup aspirations. Also, U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) conducted a second H-1B lottery because it didn’t receive enough H-1B petitions to meet the annual cap. So, if you or your employer were selected, be sure to file an H-1B petition by November 3.</p>
<p>Although job dissatisfaction and frustration on an H-1B can be normal, according to <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/edwardgorbis/">Edward Gorbis</a>, there’s a lot you can do to take control of your U.S. immigration situation and go out on your own. I interviewed Gorbis for <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/076-coaching-immigrant-leaders-with-edward-gorbis/">my podcast</a>; he’s the founder of <a href="https://www.careermeetsworld.com/">Career Meets World</a> and a performance coach who works with immigrants and first-generation professionals to help them find fulfillment and thrive in their careers and life. Gorbis said that “once immigrants reach stability, they start to think, ‘Who am I, what do I value, what’s my core identity?’” It’s possible for any of us to retrain our brain for success.</p>
<p>Gorbis said that imagining overcoming the hurdles that stand in the way of doing the work that will fulfill you is the first step. So, here are some options that can help you imagine how to build the life of your dreams.</p>
<h2>Become a founding CEO and raise $250,000</h2>
<p>A great new option for aspiring entrepreneurs is <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/073-international-entrepreneur-parole-is-back/">International Entrepreneur Parole</a> (IEP), a new immigration program in the United States that allows CEOs, CTOs and others to live in the U.S. and run their company for 2.5 years with an option for a 2.5-year extension. Your spouse can obtain a work permit.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://www.alcorn.law/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/International-Entrepreneur-Parole.pdf?7fd8bf&amp;7fd8bf">How to qualify?</a> You need to own at least 10% of a U.S. company, such as a Delaware C corporation registered in California. Ideally, you’ll want to show that your company bank account has at least $250,000 raised from qualified U.S. investors, but you can use other evidence to demonstrate that your company has the potential to grow rapidly and create jobs in the U.S.</p>
<p>A startup visa and path to a green card may be soon on the way for entrepreneurs and their crucial employees: Last week, Lofgren introduced the <a href="https://lofgren.house.gov/sites/lofgren.house.gov/files/7.26.21%20-%20LIKE%20Act%20Full%20Text.pdf">Let Immigrants Kickstart Employment (LIKE) Act</a>. The requirements for the proposed startup visa are the same as for IEP but would allow a longer stay &#8212; up to eight years total if the startup creates jobs and generates substantial revenue.</p>
<p>I’m <a href="https://bit.ly/3fsIUZ0">very proud</a> to have aided in drafting the LIKE Act. It’s a thrill to see how my suggestions were included, such as making Startup Green Cards not subject to the visa bulletin, clarifying that you can seek consecutive Startup Visas from different companies, how to allocate employee visas to startups, ensuring the Startup Visa is a dual intent status, and adding premium processing. It was such a joy to be able to contribute ideas to this amazing process. I look forward to supporting this bill to become a law; please reach out to me if you want to support this worthy cause.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100312" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100312" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2100312" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg" alt="A composite image of immigration law attorney Sophie Alcorn in front of a background with a TechCrunch logo." width="1024" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=1536,1013 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Joanna Buniak / <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sophie Alcorn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<h2>See yourself at another company</h2>
<p>There is technically no limit to how many <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/what-we-do/h-1b_speciality_occupations/">H-1B</a> employers you can have or how many — or few — hours you work in an H-1B position. So, think about other companies.</p>
<p>One option would be to have concurrent H-1Bs: Keep your current H-1B job for stability and start your own company, preferably with another individual or two, and have your startup sponsor you for an H-1B. Take a look at this <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/dear-sophie-can-i-transfer-my-h-1b-to-a-startup-i-founded/#:~:text=But%20yes%2C%20it%20is%20possible,to%20work%20at%20the%20startup.">Dear Sophie column</a> for what to do before embarking on this path.</p>
<p>Another option would be to <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/h-1b/031-h-1b-nitty-gritty-2-h-1b-transfer-for-startup-founders/">transfer your H-1B</a> to another employer, or your own startup if you are going to work there. Since you already went through the H-1B lottery with your current employer, you will not have to go through the lottery process again for a second H-1B whether you choose the concurrent or transfer option.</p>
<p>Setting up a startup that can sponsor you for an H-1B is complicated, so I suggest you work with both a corporate attorney and an immigration attorney. Keep in mind that you will not be able to do any work for your startup until an H-1B with your startup has been approved, which is why having co-founders is helpful. Another reason is H-1Bs require an employer-employee relationship between a startup and the H-1B candidate. That means a co-founder — or the startup’s board — must supervise you and have the ability to fire you. Moreover, we often advise founders that it may be best to own less than a 50% stake in the startup when applying for an H-1B.</p>
<h2>Consider a green card</h2>
<p>If you end up pursuing concurrent H-1Bs, consider asking your employer whether it is willing to sponsor you for a green card. If that’s not the case, your startup can sponsor you for one, or you can self-petition for a green card:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.alcorn.law/eb-1a-green-card/">EB-1A extraordinary ability green card</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.alcorn.law/eb-2-niw-startup-green-card-dhanasar-national-interest-waiver/">EB-2 NIW (National Interest Waiver) green card</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.alcorn.law/eb-2-green-card-advanced-degree/">EB-2 green card for professionals holding advanced degrees</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.alcorn.law/eb-2-green-card-exceptional-ability/">EB-2 exceptional ability green card</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.alcorn.law/eb-3-green-card-skilled-workers-professionals">EB-3 green cards for skilled workers and professionals</a></li>
</ul>
<p>All EB-2 green cards — except the EB-2 NIW — and the EB-3 green card require labor certification approval (<a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/020-sponsoring-employees-for-perm-green-cards/">PERM</a>) from the U.S. Department of Labor. The two green cards that allow an individual to self-sponsor are the EB-1A and EB-2 NIW.</p>
<h2>Imagine yourself doing gigs in your field</h2>
<p>Many startup founders qualify for an <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/o-1a-extraordinary-ability/">O-1A</a> extraordinary ability visa. However, you cannot have both an H-1B and an <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/015-extraordinary-ability-bootcamp/">O-1A</a> at the same time, so if your startup sponsors you for an O-1A, you will be required to leave your current H-1B job once an O-1A is approved.</p>
<p>An O-1A offers more flexibility than an H-1B. You can work for a single petitioning company or on multiple gigs through an agent. However, qualifying for an O-1A is more difficult than an H-1B. Resources, such as through my firm, support people with getting qualified. The one similarity with the H-1B is that you must show your startup and you have an employer-employee relationship.</p>
<h2>Invest in your own company</h2>
<p>The <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/e-2-visa-treaty-investors/">E-2 visa</a> for treaty investors and employees is ideal for startup founders whose home country has a treaty of commerce and navigation with the U.S. Here is a list of <a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/us-visas/visa-information-resources/fees/treaty.html">treaty countries</a>. For more details on E-2 visas for founders and employees, check out this previous <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/dear-sophie-whats-the-best-option-for-international-founders-to-expand-in-the-us/">Dear Sophie column</a> and <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/016-e-2-visa-for-founders-and-employees/">podcast episode</a>.</p>
<p>Although there is no minimum dollar amount that a founder must invest in a startup to qualify for an E-2, we often advise founders to invest at least $100,000 to have a strong case. You cannot have both an H-1B and an E-2, so you will need to leave your current H-1B job if your E-2 is approved.</p>
<p>An immigration attorney can offer additional options based on your personal circumstances and legal advice tailored to you.</p>
<p>Enjoy the journey of building your dreams!</p>
<p>Sophie</p>
<hr />
<p>Have a question for Sophie? <a href="https://webforms.pipedrive.com/f/1FRtXDHbec94FLVsSrWoOE362FDjgK7JkmZmK9g2IiOhbJLDMHtEAapwnHIfqC89l">Ask it here</a>. We reserve the right to edit your submission for clarity and/or space.</p>
<p>The information provided in “Dear Sophie” is general information and not legal advice. For more information on the limitations of “Dear Sophie,” please view <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/attorney-advertising/">our full disclaimer</a>. You can contact Sophie directly at <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a>.</p>
<p>Sophie’s podcast, <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/">Immigration Law for Tech Startups</a>, is available on all major platforms. If you’d like to be a guest, she’s accepting applications!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/dear-sophie-which-immigration-options-allow-me-to-launch-my-own-startup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185480</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Match Group to add audio and video chat, including group live video, to its dating app portfolio</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/match-group-to-add-live-audio-and-video-to-its-dating-app-portfolio-starting-in-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/match-group-to-add-live-audio-and-video-to-its-dating-app-portfolio-starting-in-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 17:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[a.i.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app maker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dating apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hyperconnect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[live audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[live video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Livestreaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Match Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tinder]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185588</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dating app maker and Tinder parent Match Group said during its Q2 earnings it will bring audio and video chat, including group live video, and other livestreaming technologies to several of the company&#8217;s brands over the next 12 to 24 months. The developments will be powered by innovations from Hyperconnect, the social networking company that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Dating app maker and Tinder parent Match Group said during its Q2 <a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/match-sales-grow-faster-than-expected-as-u-s-dating-scene-recovers-but-earnings-miss-hits-stock-11628021471">earnings</a> it will bring audio and video chat, including group live video, and other livestreaming technologies to several of the company&#8217;s brands over the next 12 to 24 months. The developments will be powered by innovations from Hyperconnect, the social networking company that this year became Match&#8217;s biggest acquisition to date when it bought the Korean app maker for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/match-hyperconnect-acquisition/">a sizable $1.73 billion. </a></p>
<p>Since then, Match Group has been relatively quiet about its specific plans for Hyperconnect&#8217;s tech or its longer-term strategy with the operation, although Tinder was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/tinder-tested-group-video-chat-ahead-of-matchs-move-into-social-discovery-with-hyperconnect-deal/">briefly spotted testing a group video chat</a> feature called Tinder Mixer earlier this summer. The move had seemed to signal some exploration of social discovery features in the wake of the Hyperconnect deal. However, Tinder told us at the time the company had no plans to bring that specific product to market in the year ahead.</p>
<p>On Tuesday&#8217;s earnings, Match Group offered a little more insight into the future of Hyperconnect, following the acquisition&#8217;s official <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/match-group-closes-acquisition-of-hyperconnect-301314582.html">close</a> in mid-June.</p>
<p>According to Match Group CEO Shar Dubey, who <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/match-group-names-sharmistha-dubey-chief-executive-officer-300994817.html">stepped into the top job</a> last January, the company is excited about the potential to integrate technologies Hyperconnect has developed into existing Match-owned dating apps.</p>
<p>This includes, she said, &#8220;AR features, self-expression tools, conversational AI and a number of what we would consider metaverse elements, which have the element to transform the online meeting and getting-to-know-each-other process,&#8221; Dubey explained, without offering further specific details about how the products would work or which apps would receive these enhancements.</p>
<p>Many of these technologies emerged from Hyperconnect&#8217;s lab, <a href="http://3.112.16.158/hyper-x/?lang=en">Hyper X</a> &#8212; the same in-house incubator <a href="http://3.112.16.158/hyper-x/?lang=en">whose first product</a> is now one of the company&#8217;s flagship apps, Azar, which joined Match Group with the acquisition.</p>
<p>Dubey also noted that the work to begin these tech integrations was already underway at the company.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>By year-end, Match Group said it expects to have at least two of its brands integrated with technologies from Hyperconnect. A number of other brands will implement Hyperconnect capabilities by year-end 2022.</p>
<p>In doing so, Match aims to transform what people think of when it comes to online dating.</p>
<p>To date, online dating has been a fairly static experience across the industry, where apps focus largely on profiles and photos, and then offer some sort of matching technique &#8212; whether swipes or quizzes or something else. Tinder, in more recent years, began to break out of that mold as it innovated with an array of different experiences, like its choose-your-own-adventure in-app video series, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/tinders-interactive-video-event-swipe-night-will-launch-in-international-markets-this-month/">&#8220;Swipe Night,&#8221;</a> <a href="https://www.tinderpressroom.com/2021-06-22-Tinder-Expands-Into-Video-and-Social-Experiences">video profiles</a>, instant chat features (via Tinder&#8217;s product, <a href="https://www.tinderpressroom.com/2021-06-22-Tinder-Expands-Into-Video-and-Social-Experiences">Hot Takes</a>) and others. But it still lacked some of the real-time elements that people have when meeting one another in the real world.</p>
<p>This is an area where Match believes Hyperconnect can help to improve the online dating experience.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of the holy grails for us in online dating has always been to bridge the disconnect that happens between people chatting online and then meeting someone in person,&#8221; Dubey said. &#8220;These technologies will eventually allow us to build experiences that will help people determine if they have that much elusive chemistry or not&#8230; Our ultimate vision here is for people to never have to go on a bad first date again,&#8221; she added.</p>
<p>Of course, Match Group&#8217;s positioning of the Hyperconnect deal as being more interesting because the innovation it brings &#8212; and not just the standalone apps it operates &#8212; also comes at a time when those apps have not met the company&#8217;s expectations on revenue.</p>
<p>In the second half the of 2021, Match Group said it expects Hyperconnect to contribute to $125 to $135 million in revenue &#8212; a financial outlook that the company admits reflects some pullback. It attributed this largely to COVID impacts, particularly in the Asia-Pacific region where Hyperconnect&#8217;s apps operate. Other impacts to Hyperconnect&#8217;s growth included a more crowded marketplace and Apple&#8217;s <a href="https://developer.apple.com/app-store/user-privacy-and-data-use/">changes</a> to IDFA (Identifier for Advertisers), which has impacted a number of apps &#8212; including other social networking apps, like Facebook.</p>
<p>While Match still believes Hyperconnect will post &#8220;solid revenue growth&#8221; in 2021, it said that these new technology integrations into the Match Group portfolio are now &#8220;a higher priority&#8221; for the company.</p>
<p>Match Group posted mixed <a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/match-sales-grow-faster-than-expected-as-u-s-dating-scene-recovers-but-earnings-miss-hits-stock-11628021471">earnings</a> in Q1, with revenue of $707.8 million, above analyst estimates, but earnings per share of 46 cents, below projections of 49 cents a share. Paying customers grew 15% to 15 million, up from 13 million in the year-ago quarter. Shares declined by 7% on Wednesday morning, following the earnings announcement.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PQomMehSpn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/livestream-e-commerce-why-companies-and-brands-need-to-tune-in/">Livestream e-commerce: Why companies and brands need to tune in</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Livestream e-commerce: Why companies and brands need to tune in&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/livestream-e-commerce-why-companies-and-brands-need-to-tune-in/embed/#?secret=PQomMehSpn" data-secret="PQomMehSpn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/match-group-to-add-live-audio-and-video-to-its-dating-app-portfolio-starting-in-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185588</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>YELA secures $2M to reproduce Cameo&#8217;s celebrity success with an app for the Middle East</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/yela-secures-2m-to-reproduce-cameos-celebrity-success-with-an-app-for-the-middle-east/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/yela-secures-2m-to-reproduce-cameos-celebrity-success-with-an-app-for-the-middle-east/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 17:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ascension Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[board member]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hambro Perks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JAM Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Justin Mateen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MENA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Middle East]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rakuten]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sean Rad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tinder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Cameo app, where celebrities send video messages to paying fans, has taken off globally. But now the concept is set to come to the Middle East and South Asia. Tech startup YELA has secured $2 million in investment to support its launch, and will — similar to Cameo — offer users the opportunity to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Cameo app, where celebrities send video messages to paying fans, has taken off globally. But now the concept is set to come to the Middle East and South Asia.</p>
<p>Tech startup <a href="http://yela.com">YELA</a> has secured $2 million in investment to support its launch, and will — similar to Cameo — offer users the opportunity to get close to their idols via voice, video and direct text messages.</p>
<p>The investment is led by U.S investors Justin Mateen (co-founder of Tinder) and general partner of JAM Fund, joined by Sean Rad (co-founder Tinder) and general partner of RAD Fund. Participation from the U.S. also includes Graph Ventures, championed by Razmig Hovaghimian (board member at Rakuten). In addition, U.K investment comes from Samos Fund, Ascension Ventures, and from MENA-based Hambro Perks Oryx Fund, who joined the round.</p>
<p>The twist is that YELA plans to sign some big celebrities known in the region, but less so in the Western world. That doesn’t mean the market is small. There are over 365 million Arabic speakers online and over 65% of the population is under 35. Meanwhile, smartphone penetration is very high.</p>
<p>Alex Eid, CEO and co-founder of YELA said: &#8220;There is a huge appetite in the MENA market for a premium offering in the creator space.”</p>
<p>He said YELA has onboarded high-profile celebrities, confirming A-list signees including <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amr_Diab">Amr Diab</a>, the multiaward-winning Egyptian singer, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Haifa_Wehbe">Haifa Wehbe</a>, three-time Big Apple Music Award winner, amongst others.</p>
<p>YELA will launch in August 2021 with prices starting from $100.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="obaLJYhHXq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/9-vcs-say-interactivity-regulation-and-independent-creators-will-reshape-digital-media-in-2021/">10 VCs say interactivity, regulation and independent creators will reshape digital media in 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;10 VCs say interactivity, regulation and independent creators will reshape digital media in 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/9-vcs-say-interactivity-regulation-and-independent-creators-will-reshape-digital-media-in-2021/embed/#?secret=obaLJYhHXq" data-secret="obaLJYhHXq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/yela-secures-2m-to-reproduce-cameos-celebrity-success-with-an-app-for-the-middle-east/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185688</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>As the delta variant surges, a nonprofit app lets hospital patients call home for free on any device </title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/as-the-delta-variant-surges-a-non-profit-app-lets-hospital-patients-call-home-for-free-on-any-device/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/as-the-delta-variant-surges-a-non-profit-app-lets-hospital-patients-call-home-for-free-on-any-device/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Betuel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 17:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telehealth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video chat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185664</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[COVID Tech Connect, a nonprofit created during the first wave of the coronavirus pandemic in the United States, is launching a free app aimed at helping hospital patients call home. As the delta variant drives a new upward surge in critical COVID-19 cases, the new offering is, sadly, well timed. COVID Tech Connect originated as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">COVID Tech Connect, a nonprofit created during the first wave of the coronavirus pandemic in the United States, is launching a free app aimed at helping hospital patients call home. As the delta variant drives a new upward surge in critical COVID-19 cases, the new offering is, sadly, well timed.</p>
<p>COVID Tech Connect originated as a nonprofit organization in spring 2020, right before the initial summer surge in COVID-19 cases. At the time, the initiative was dedicated to collecting and donating hardware — tablets, phones, etc. — to hospitals where ICU beds were filling up, and COVID protocols prevented families from visiting sick relatives. So far, the organization has donated over 20,000 devices to 1,600 hospitals and care facilities, and 30,000 charging cords to an additional 248 hospitals.</p>
<p>The nonprofit is headed by a roster of proven entrepreneurs, including <a href="https://www.anjalikumar.com/">Anjali Kumar,</a> <a href="https://benishshah.com/">Benish Shah</a>, <a href="http://www.christinawallace.com/entrepreneur">Christina Wallace</a>, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/katie-jacobs-stanton">Katie Stanton</a>, <a href="https://www.kristinalibby.com/">Kristina Libby</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sararodell/">Sarah Rodell</a>. Since 2020, COVID Tech Connect has been run by <a href="ttps://www.linkedin.com/in/elien-blue-becque-8487aa7/">Elien Becque</a>, also an entrepreneur and the non-profit&#8217;s product director and program manager <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/karaivy/">Kara Goldberg-King</a>.</p>
<p>The device donation program was promoted to hospitals, but never actively promoted to care facilities. Still, the program generated organic interest among those facilities too. &#8220;We didn&#8217;t really put anything behind it [promoting to care facilities], but we were always being flooded with requests for devices,&#8221; Elien Becque, product director at COVID Tech Connect tells TechCrunch.</p>
<p>During its first year, COVID Tech Connect raised $4 million in funding from a variety of sources including Google.org, private donors, including <a href="https://www.covidtechconnect.com/our-story">Ellen DeGeneres and Shutterfly</a>, and about $200,000 from a <a href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/GivingDignity">GoFundMe</a>. Right now, COVID Tech Connect’s fiscal sponsor is The Giving Back Fund, another nonprofit that manages charitable donations from pro athletes, celebrities or high-net-worth individuals.</p>
<p>About one year after its original debut, COVID Tech Connect expanded into software with an app called <a href="https://www.telehomeapp.com/">TeleHome</a>. TeleHome, which soft launched in May, is a device-agnostic, HIPAA-compliant way to perform a video call within a hospital.</p>
<p>The TeleHome rollout comes during a confusing and critical time in the pandemic. While some hospital systems are now allowing visitors, others, like some <a href="https://www.miamiherald.com/news/coronavirus/article252902678.html">Florida hospitals</a>, <a href="https://storage.googleapis.com/jackson-library/notices/COVID-19-Visitor-Policy.pdf">are suspending</a> or limiting visits in response to the delta variant.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Generally speaking, the CDC still recommends hospitals facilitate other ways for patients to visit with family — <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/non-us-settings/hcf-visitors.html">especially video or audio calls</a>.</p>
<p>The TeleHome app was designed through a partnership with Caregility, a for-profit company that already provides telehealth services for hospitals. Caregility provided the back-end functionality for the app, while the front end was developed by COVID Tech Connect’s team.</p>
<p>“The idea for TeleHome was born out of conversations that the COVID Tech Connect team was having with hospitals about the specific use case of using smart devices to connect patients in hospital settings,” says Becque.</p>
<p>“The whole point of TeleHome really was to make our mission scalable beyond just the physical devices.”</p>
<p>The obvious critique of yet another video calling app is that it’s already a flooded space, though TeleHome does offer some services that are unique, and that make the app particularly useful for hospitals.</p>
<p>Hospitals have already used apps like FaceTime to connect patients with their families with success. A <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7571754/">2020 study</a> on the effects of 350 FaceTime calls made in U.K. hospitals noted that the feedback was “very positive.” But the hospitals did run into IT issues — the use of FaceTime software, the study notes, limited calls to relatives who own Apple devices. (Apple’s new <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/06/ios-15-brings-powerful-new-features-to-stay-connected-focus-explore-and-more/">iOS 15 operating system</a> will allow Android and Windows-based devices to run FaceTime, however, once it&#8217;s released widely in the fall).</p>
<p>By comparison TeleHome works on any device. A hospital can request a TeleHome login (provided again, for free). Once it’s installed using that one-time login, patients can use a hospital’s device to send a link via text to another person. Clicking that link will take participants to a Zoom-call like format in an internet browser — regardless of whether they have an iPhone, Android, computer or any other type of device.</p>
<p>“TeleHome was a natural extension for us beyond hardware and into software, especially for those hospitals that couldn&#8217;t accept the Android devices from us,” Kara Goldberg-King, program manager at COVID Tech Health tells TechCrunch.</p>
<p>TeleHome also comes with some privacy features that may be attractive to hospitals. To address patient privacy mandates by HIPAA requirements, Becque notes that “literally no data is collected.” There is evidence that a call link was generated but there are no recordings, logs or transcripts and the link itself expires after five minutes.</p>
<p>So far, the app has about 3,400 downloads.</p>
<p>The one thing TeleHome can’t get around is the need for a device in the first place, though COVID Tech Connect does donate devices as well, addressing that concern in part. But it does cut out technical details usually required to get a call up and running.</p>
<p>TechCrunch conducted about half of this interview with Becque and Goldberg-King over the TeleHome platform –– the platform works relatively seamlessly, provided you don’t have strict privacy settings limiting microphone or camera use. A test run of the video chat service worked like a charm on a computer, but I struggled to get the chat up and running while navigating the microphone or camera permissions menus on an iPhone.</p>
<p>There are some signs that some of the infrastructure of COVID Tech Connect may outlast the pandemic. For instance, COVID Tech Connect is in touch with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/14/ameelio-wants-to-take-on-for-profit-prison-calling-rackets-after-starting-with-free-letters-to-inmates/">Ameelio</a>, an app that allows incarcerated people and their families to send letters and schedule video calls for free. But for now, COVID Tech Connect remains focused on the problem it set out to solve: closing the gulf between COVID-19 patients who enter the hospital and families on the outside.</p>
<p>As long as the nonprofit exists, the workforce plans to keep the service free.</p>
<p>“We&#8217;re really grateful to have been able to execute on the mission with TeleHome and make it scalable and we are not going to turn it into a company,” Becque adds. “It’s free now and it’s always going to be free.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EyntKN5l4J"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/17/an-unsurprising-wave-of-video-focused-startups-is-trying-to-make-video-calls-better/">An unsurprising wave of video-focused startups is trying to make video calls better</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;An unsurprising wave of video-focused startups is trying to make video calls better&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/17/an-unsurprising-wave-of-video-focused-startups-is-trying-to-make-video-calls-better/embed/#?secret=EyntKN5l4J" data-secret="EyntKN5l4J" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/as-the-delta-variant-surges-a-non-profit-app-lets-hospital-patients-call-home-for-free-on-any-device/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185664</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Launchpad hiccups indefinitely delay Boeing&#8217;s troubled Starliner orbital test</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/launchpad-hiccups-indefinitely-delay-boeings-troubled-starliner-orbital-test/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/launchpad-hiccups-indefinitely-delay-boeings-troubled-starliner-orbital-test/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 17:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boeing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial crew]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial crew program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[launches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starliner]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185618</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Boeing&#8217;s Starliner capsule is leaving the launchpad after a series of delays that prevented takeoff over the last few days. NASA and the beleaguered aerospace giant will take &#8220;whatever time is necessary&#8221; to find and fix the issue, but it&#8217;s beginning to feel like this long-in-development spacecraft may never make it to the ISS. This [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Boeing&#8217;s Starliner capsule is <a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/commercialcrew/2021/08/03/nasa-boeing-standing-down-on-aug-4-starliner-launch-attempt/">leaving the launchpad</a> after a series of delays that prevented takeoff over the last few days. NASA and the beleaguered aerospace giant will take &#8220;whatever time is necessary&#8221; to find and fix the issue, but it&#8217;s beginning to feel like this long-in-development spacecraft may never make it to the ISS.</p>
<p>This is the second major launch attempt after the Starliner <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/20/boeings-starliner-crew-capsule-fails-to-enter-planned-target-orbit-for-space-station-docking/">failed to enter the correct orbit in a 2019 launch</a>. The rescheduled ISS rendezvous launch was originally scheduled for March of this year, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/watch-boeing-try-its-pivotal-crew-spacecraft-orbital-demonstration-launch-for-the-second-time/">but eventually delayed to this week</a>. A valve issue prompted a countdown halt yesterday, but the ground teams have been unable to resolve the problem as the whole operation has had to stand down as a result.</p>
<p>&#8220;Engineering teams have ruled out a number of potential causes, including software, but additional time is needed to complete the assessment,&#8221; wrote NASA in a news release. &#8220;Mission teams have decided to roll the Atlas V and Starliner back to the Vertical Integration Facility (VIF) for further inspection and testing where access to the spacecraft is available. Boeing will power down the Starliner spacecraft this evening.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s another major setback for Boeing&#8217;s shot at providing crew launch capability, something its rival SpaceX has achieved now multiple times despite originally working on a very similar timeline. Both experienced years of delays, but ultimately Crew Dragon was successfully piloted to the ISS while Starliner has yet to make a successful orbital trip at all, let alone one with astronauts on board.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CtmRorrdJl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/04/this-is-certainly-different-astronauts-on-controlling-the-dragon-spacecraft-via-touchscreen/">&#8216;This is certainly different&#8217;: Astronauts on controlling the Dragon spacecraft via touchscreen</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;&#8216;This is certainly different&#8217;: Astronauts on controlling the Dragon spacecraft via touchscreen&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/04/this-is-certainly-different-astronauts-on-controlling-the-dragon-spacecraft-via-touchscreen/embed/#?secret=CtmRorrdJl" data-secret="CtmRorrdJl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Some may wonder whether this is throwing good money after bad, since the race is apparently lost. But Boeing knows better than many that this is a marathon, not a sprint, and that the demand for orbital launches is nearly insatiable. Even if SpaceX has a multiyear lead on Boeing, Boeing has a multiyear lead on some of its other competitors and if it can get Starliner working there will likely be enough customers to make even its tortuous development worthwhile.</p>
<p>Depending on how quickly this valve issue is resolved, it could be weeks or months before there&#8217;s another launch attempt.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/launchpad-hiccups-indefinitely-delay-boeings-troubled-starliner-orbital-test/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185618</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cybersecurity trainer HackerU acquires Cybint for $50M, say sources</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/cybersecurity-trainer-hackeru-acquires-cybint-for-50m-say-sources/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/cybersecurity-trainer-hackeru-acquires-cybint-for-50m-say-sources/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 17:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybersecurity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cybint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dan Vigdor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HackerU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Training]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185656</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Florida-based HackerU, which creates cybersecurity and other digital skills programs, is acquiring Cybint, a SaaS-based cyber education company. TechCrunch sources understand this to be a $50 million acquisition, though both companies declined to comment on the price. HackerU provided digital workforce training to students, post-graduate professionals and the community in the U.S., Europe and Asia [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Florida-based <a href="https://hackeru.com/">HackerU</a>, which creates cybersecurity and other digital skills programs, is acquiring <a href="https://www.cybintsolutions.com/">Cybint</a>, a SaaS-based cyber education company. TechCrunch sources understand this to be a $50 million acquisition, though both companies declined to comment on the price.</p>
<p>HackerU provided digital workforce training to students, post-graduate professionals and the community in the U.S., Europe and Asia through partnerships with universities. The acquisition will mean the combined entity’s geographic footprint will now increase, and it will now rebrand as ThriveDX, standing for &#8220;digital transformation.&#8221;</p>
<p>Cybint had previously raised $7.5 million thus far. HackerU has been around for 15 years and in the past four years raised around $100 million from Prytek, as well as Liquidity Capital and Shintilla Cap. The company had a number of global initiatives including a partnership with Southern New Hampshire University, where it created boot camps training cybersecurity skills and preparing Black and refugee students based in southeast Africa through remote training for long-term job opportunities.</p>
<p>ThriveDX’s main competitor will be 2U, which <a href="https://thepienews.com/news/2u-acquires-trilogy-education-for-750m/">acquired</a> Trilogy in 2019 for $750 million.</p>
<p>In a statement, Dan Vigdor, co-founder and executive chairman of HackerU said: &#8220;The combination of our two companies’ positions the new ThriveDX group as the category leader worldwide and solidifies our ability to reskill and upskill individuals at any stage of their professional life.”</p>
<p>Both rising incidences of cybersecurity breaches and the switch to remote working means the cyber world is booming right now — but there is a huge shortage of staff. According to ISC2, some 3.1 million cybersecurity vacancies were left unfilled in 2020, with 63% of corporations reporting their employees are underqualified in cybersecurity.</p>
<p>Vigdor added: “The pandemic accelerated a huge transformation across the global workforce, leaving companies in dire need of workers with specific skills — and job candidates in need of training.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Roy Zur, founder and CEO of Cybint said: “The Cybint team will support HackerU by signing additional partnerships and accelerating the development of software as a service (SaaS) training solutions with a strong emphasis on corporate training and cybersecurity education solutions globally.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="E5mDoRC3lW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/to-guard-against-data-loss-and-misuse-the-cybersecurity-conversation-must-evolve/">To guard against data loss and misuse, the cybersecurity conversation must evolve</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;To guard against data loss and misuse, the cybersecurity conversation must evolve&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/to-guard-against-data-loss-and-misuse-the-cybersecurity-conversation-must-evolve/embed/#?secret=E5mDoRC3lW" data-secret="E5mDoRC3lW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/cybersecurity-trainer-hackeru-acquires-cybint-for-50m-say-sources/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185656</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Human Interest raises $200M at a $1B valuation, plans for an IPO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/human-interest-raises-200m-at-a-1b-valuation-plans-for-an-ipo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/human-interest-raises-200m-at-a-1b-valuation-plans-for-an-ipo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 16:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crosslink capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glynn Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Human Interest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank Vision Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[susa ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncork Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wing venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Less than six months after raising $55 million in a Series C round of funding, SMB 401(k) provider Human Interest today announced it has raised $200 million in a round that propels it to unicorn status. The Rise Fund, TPG’s global impact investing platform, led the round and was joined by SoftBank Vision Fund 2. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Less than six months after raising $55 million in a Series C round of funding, SMB 401(k) provider Human Interest today announced it has raised $200 million in a round that propels it to unicorn status.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Rise Fund, TPG’s global impact investing platform, led the round and was joined by SoftBank Vision Fund 2. The financing included participation from new investor Crosslink Capital and existing backers NewView Capital, Glynn Capital, U.S. Venture Partners, Wing Venture Capital, Uncork Capital, Slow Capital, Susa Ventures and others. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the past year, the San Francisco-based company has raised $305 million. With the latest financing, it has</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> now raised a total of $336.7 million since its 2015 inception.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MpF0TubBI3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/401k-provider-human-interest-doubles-valuation-with-55m-fundraise/">401(k) provider Human Interest doubles valuation with $55M fundraise</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;401(k) provider Human Interest doubles valuation with $55M fundraise&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/401k-provider-human-interest-doubles-valuation-with-55m-fundraise/embed/#?secret=MpF0TubBI3" data-secret="MpF0TubBI3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company admittedly has an IPO in its sights, as evidenced by the appointment of former Yodlee CFO Mike Armsby to the role of CFO at Human Interest. It&#8217;s targeting a traditional IPO sometime in 2023, with execs saying the target is to have &#8220;$200 million+ in run-rate revenue before going public.&#8221; Currently, it&#8217;s at &#8220;tens of millions of run-rate revenue&#8221; now, and adding millions of new revenue each month.</span></p>
<p>Human Interest’s digital retirement benefits platform allows users “to launch a retirement plan in minutes and put it on autopilot,” according to the company.  It also touts that it has eliminated all 401(k) transaction fees<b>.</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Demand for 401(k)s by SMBs appears to be at an all-time high, with Human Interest reporting that its sales tripled over the last year. The company has also more than doubled its headcount over the last 12 months to 350 employees.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup said it is seeing strong adoption in verticals that have not previously had retirement benefits, including construction, retail, manufacturing, restaurants, nonprofits and hospitality. For example, over the past three quarters, Human Interest has seen 4.5x customer growth in the restaurant sector. Since the start of the pandemic, Human Interest has experienced 2x higher enrollment growth among hourly workers than salaried workers, and hourly worker assets have tripled.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Promoting financial health is a core investment pillar for The Rise Fund. Human Interest delivers one of the most compelling solutions to the persistent problem that roughly half of Americans will not have enough savings when they reach retirement age,” said Maya Chorengel, co-managing partner at The Rise Fund, in a written statement. “Despite recent legislation, primarily at the state level, legacy programs have not, to date, produced the same participant outcomes as Human Interest.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company said it will be using its new capital to expand its network of integrations and partnerships with financial advisers, benefits brokers and payroll companies. It also expects to, naturally, do some hiring –– another</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 200 employees by year’s end, primarily in its product, engineering and revenue teams.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 401(k) for SMB space is heating up as of late. In June, competitor Guideline </span><a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210616005127/en/Guideline-Raises-200M-in-Funding-Led-by-General-Atlantic-to-Fuel-Growth-of-Comprehensive-Retirement-Plan-Solutions"><span style="font-weight: 400;">also raised $200 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in a round led by General Atlantic. </span></p>
<p><em>Additional details around the IPO and revenue were added post-publication.</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2Mj07y7c33"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/investors-dont-expect-the-us-startup-funding-market-to-slow-down/">Investors don’t expect the US startup funding market to slow down</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Investors don’t expect the US startup funding market to slow down&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/investors-dont-expect-the-us-startup-funding-market-to-slow-down/embed/#?secret=2Mj07y7c33" data-secret="2Mj07y7c33" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/human-interest-raises-200m-at-a-1b-valuation-plans-for-an-ipo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185640</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Heatworks opens pre-orders for its plumbing-free countertop dishwasher</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/heatworks-opens-pre-orders-for-its-plumbing-free-countertop-dishwasher/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/heatworks-opens-pre-orders-for-its-plumbing-free-countertop-dishwasher/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 16:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Heatworks has at long last opened pre-orders for the Tetra, a countertop dishwasher that debuted at CES 2018. The Tetra doesn't require any plumbing, just an electrical outlet.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Kris Holt</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://www.twitter.com/krisholt">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Kris Holt is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com/">Engadget</a>. 	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/uber-expands-its-grocery-delivery-service-to-more-than-400-us-cities-and-towns/">Uber expands its grocery delivery service to more than 400 US cities and towns</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/16/tumblrs-parent-company-is-buying-popular-podcast-app-pocket-casts/">Tumblr&#8217;s parent company is buying popular podcast app Pocket Casts</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/heatworks" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="16" data-v9y="1">Heatworks</a> has at long last <a href="https://myheatworks.com/products/tetra-specs" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="17" data-v9y="1">opened pre-orders</a> for the Tetra, a countertop dishwasher the company unveiled to some fanfare <a href="https://www.cnet.com/home/smart-home/heatworks-countertop-dishwasher-is-pretty-and-practical/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="18" data-v9y="1">at CES 2018</a>. Since the Tetra doesn&#8217;t require any plumbing, the only thing you need to connect it to is an electrical outlet. The appliance has a three-liter tank you fill with water manually. Once the cycle (which takes less than an hour on the shortest setting) is complete, you disconnect the greywater tank and pour out the used water.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/dishwasher" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1">dishwasher</a> can wash and dry three place settings worth of dishes per load. On the surface, it might seem wasteful compared with cleaning those plates, cups and utensils manually, not to mention the counter space the machine will hog. However, Heatworks claims the machine requires less water than handwashing and rinsing the dishes.</p>
<p>There are several settings, including a &#8220;fruit&#8221; one for washing produce. In addition, the dishwasher uses recyclable cartridges with concentrated detergent in an attempt to reduce waste.</p>
<p>The Tetra also requires less power than a standard dishwasher, according to the company. To heat up water, Heatworks uses Ohmic Array Technology, as <a href="https://gizmodo.com/you-can-finally-buy-the-plumbing-free-countertop-dishwa-1847395855" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1"><em>Gizmodo</em></a> notes. The Tetra takes a microwave-style approach to heating water rather than harnessing traditional metal elements. It <a href="https://myheatworks.com/blogs/press/heatworks-announces-tetra-the-connected-countertop-dishwasher-at-ces" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="22" data-v9y="1">uses</a> graphite electrodes and &#8220;advanced electronic controls&#8221; to excite natural minerals in water. That setup allows the Tetra to efficiently heat water and maintain precise temperature control, according to Heatworks.</p>
<p>While there are <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07VR22832/ref=as_sl_pc_qf_sp_asin_til?tag=productpost2021-20&amp;linkCode=w00&amp;linkId=63145939387785dd7b5b8b2e58a8720d&amp;creativeASIN=B07VR22832" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="23" data-v9y="1">other countertop dishwashers</a> that don&#8217;t need a plumbing connection, the Tetra has a smaller water tank than many of its rivals. Farberware&#8217;s FDW05ASBWHA model (which is currently <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07VR22832/ref=as_sl_pc_qf_sp_asin_til?tag=productpost2021-20&amp;linkCode=w00&amp;linkId=63145939387785dd7b5b8b2e58a8720d&amp;creativeASIN=B07VR22832&amp;th=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="24" data-v9y="1">$340</a>) has a five-liter capacity. The Tetra may heat water more efficiently than other models as well.</p>
<p>The Tetra will typically cost $499, but Heatworks is offering a $100 discount to those who <a href="https://myheatworks.com/products/tetra-specs" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="25" data-v9y="1">lock in a preorder now</a>. The detergent cartridges will cost around $6 each and they should be good for 20 loads depending on the setting and load capacity. Heatworks expects to start shipping the Tetra by May 18th, 2022, which is No Dirty Dishes Day.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note: </strong><em>This post first appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/heatworks-tetra-plumbing-free-countertop-dishwasher-pre-orders-161727197.html?src=rss">Engadget</a>.</em></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/heatworks-opens-pre-orders-for-its-plumbing-free-countertop-dishwasher/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185623</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Supercritical launches carbon removal offset marketplace for tech firms to reach net zero</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/supercritical-launches-carbon-removal-offset-marketplace-for-tech-firms-reach-netzero/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/supercritical-launches-carbon-removal-offset-marketplace-for-tech-firms-reach-netzero/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 16:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon dioxide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon footprint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon offset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Localglobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[songkick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Supercritical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185586</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s a little known fact that the carbon footprint of the technology sector is greater than the entire aviation industry (Aalto University and LUT University). At the same time, tech companies (like many others) are generally attracted to carbon offsetting schemes which don’t actually remove carbon from the environment and are often riddled with flaws. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It’s a little known fact that the carbon footprint of the technology sector is greater than <a href="https://www.aalto.fi/en/news/digital-services-have-a-greater-carbon-footprint-than-aviation-does-research-project-aims-at">the entire aviation industry</a> (Aalto University and LUT University). At the same time, tech companies (like many others) are generally attracted to carbon <em>offsetting</em><em> schemes which don’t actually remove carbon from the environment and are often </em><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/04/carbon-offsets-used-by-major-airlines-based-on-flawed-system-warn-experts">riddled with flaws</a>.</p>
<p>Only carbon <em>removal</em> offsets contribute toward net zero because they actively take carbon out of the sky. And yet, so far there are very few schemes making carbon removal a focus, largely because only the biggest companies are able to play in this space, partly due to cost and the nascent nature of the technology.</p>
<p>This is where new startup <a href="https://gosupercritical.com/">Supercritical</a> comes in.</p>
<p>The startup says its platform can help businesses get to net zero by measuring their climate impact and selling high-impact carbon removal offsets.</p>
<p>It has now raised £2 million / $2.7 million in pre-seed funding led by London’s LocalGlobe venture firm. The raise is also significant because the team was that which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/07/14/warner-music-group-buys-concert-discovery-service-songkick/">took Songkick to exit</a>.</p>
<p>Supercritical says its platform assesses a company’s carbon impact, creates an actionable plan for reducing their emissions and recommends a portfolio of high-quality carbon removal offsets for companies to purchase. It will effectively be building a marketplace of carbon removal projects such as enhanced weathering, bio-oil sequestration and direct air capture.</p>
<p>Right now these technologies tend to be costly, as many are so early in development, but the opportunity is for Supercritical to become a market-maker for these emerging solutions, aggregating demand to help them scale and innovate faster.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup already has clients, including accuRx, Tide and what3words. Supercritical is also a member of the <a href="https://techzero.technation.io/">TechZero</a> task force, a group of U.K. tech companies claiming to work toward NetZero Carbon impact.</p>
<p>Supercritical CEO and co-founder Michelle You said: “Businesses are rightly suspicious of traditional carbon offsetting options, which do nothing at best and at worst are outright fraud, but most companies lack the time and the expertise to find an adequate alternative. Our mission is to make it possible for any business to start the journey to net zero. Climate action can’t just be the reserve of the world’s biggest companies, and this is a crisis that can’t wait.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AWWGzJRmVQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/corporate-sustainability-initiatives-may-open-doors-for-carbon-offset-startups/">Corporate sustainability initiatives may open doors for carbon offset startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Corporate sustainability initiatives may open doors for carbon offset startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/corporate-sustainability-initiatives-may-open-doors-for-carbon-offset-startups/embed/#?secret=AWWGzJRmVQ" data-secret="AWWGzJRmVQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Remus Brett, who led the investment from LocalGlobe, said: “Supercritical is providing a service that is as timely as it is essential. With COP26 approaching, the question of how businesses can meaningfully address their climate impact is a critical CEO issue. We are excited to be backing the exceptional team at Supercritical as they scale the only platform that helps companies focus their efforts on carbon removal rather than offsets.”</p>
<p>The startup is pushing at an open door. To keep warming below 1.5°C &#8212; one of the key goals of the <a href="https://unfccc.int/process-and-meetings/the-paris-agreement/the-paris-agreement">2015 Paris Agreement</a> &#8212; at least <a href="https://wedocs.unep.org/bitstream/handle/20.500.11822/22070/EGR_2017.pdf">8 billion tonnes</a> of carbon needs to be removed from the atmosphere every year, so the voluntary carbon offset market is set to be worth at least <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2021-06-02/carbon-offsets-new-100-billion-market-faces-disputes-over-trading-rules?sref=XydSzIeb">$100 billion by 2030</a>, and that&#8217;s inside nine years.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/supercritical-launches-carbon-removal-offset-marketplace-for-tech-firms-reach-netzero/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185586</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GM is adding two new zero-emission commercial vehicles to its lineup</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/gm-is-adding-to-two-new-zero-emission-commercial-vehicles-to-its-lineup/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/gm-is-adding-to-two-new-zero-emission-commercial-vehicles-to-its-lineup/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 16:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BrightDrop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mary barra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ultium Cells]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zero-emission]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[General Motors said Wednesday it is adding two new zero-emissions vehicles to its commercial portfolio as it looks to expand its first-to-last-mile business arm, BrightDrop. The first vehicle will be a battery electric cargo van under the Chevrolet brand that will likely be similar to the popular Chevy Express van. The second will be a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">General Motors said Wednesday it is adding two new zero-emissions vehicles to its commercial portfolio as it looks to expand its first-to-last-mile business arm, BrightDrop.</p>
<p>The first vehicle will be a battery electric cargo van under the Chevrolet brand that will likely be similar to the popular Chevy Express van. The second will be a medium-duty truck that CEO Mary Barra said “will put both the Ultium and Hydrotec hydrogen fuel cell technology to work.”</p>
<p>Much has been made of GM’s commitment to invest in electric passenger vehicles, but the company has also been busy targeting commercial customers with zero-emitting technologies. GM&#8217;s go-to technologies are battery electric and hydrogen fuel cells for heavy-duty and long-haul purposes.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4M2jaWGC9Y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/inside-gms-startup-incubator-strategy/">Inside GM&#8217;s startup incubator strategy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Inside GM&#8217;s startup incubator strategy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/inside-gms-startup-incubator-strategy/embed/#?secret=4M2jaWGC9Y" data-secret="4M2jaWGC9Y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>GM in January said it would supply Hydrotec Hydrogen Fuel Cell Power Cubes to trucking manufacturer Navistar, with the first hydrogen trucks anticipated to go on sale in 2024. The automaker also penned a deal with Wabtec to develop hydrogen fuel cells and batteries for locomotives.</p>
<p>GM launched BrightDrop in January in a bid to offer commercial customers, starting with a contract with FedEx, an ecosystem of electric and connected products.</p>
<p>BrightDrop started with two main products, an electric van called the EV600 with an estimate range of 250 miles and a pod-like electric pallet dubbed EP1. BrightDrop executives previously hinted that the business unit was working on other products, including a medium-distance vehicle that transports multiple electric pallets known as EP1 and rapid load delivery vehicle concept.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Between these new trucks, BrightDrop, EV pickups coming from Chevrolet and GMC, and our work with Wabtec on locomotives, and Navistar on semi trucks, we will have electric solutions for almost any towing or hauling job you can imagine,” Barra said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="D0xJJhxpqd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/gms-newest-startup-aims-squarely-at-the-commercial-ev-market/">GM&#8217;s newest startup aims squarely at the commercial EV market</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;GM&#8217;s newest startup aims squarely at the commercial EV market&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/gms-newest-startup-aims-squarely-at-the-commercial-ev-market/embed/#?secret=D0xJJhxpqd" data-secret="D0xJJhxpqd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/gm-is-adding-to-two-new-zero-emission-commercial-vehicles-to-its-lineup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185579</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Work-Bench will continue supporting early-stage enterprise startups with new $100M fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/work-bench-will-continue-supporting-early-stage-enterprise-startups-with-new-100m-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/work-bench-will-continue-supporting-early-stage-enterprise-startups-with-new-100m-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 16:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jonathan Lehr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seed investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work-Bench]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185574</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In spite of the pandemic, New York City remains the center of commerce and business, and over the last decade a robust startup community has developed there. Work-Bench, the NYC VC firm that concentrates on early-stage enterprise seed investments, announced its $100 million Fund 3 this morning. The company started back in 2013, when most [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In spite of the pandemic, New York City remains the center of commerce and business, and over the last decade a robust startup community has developed there. <a href="https://www.work-bench.com/">Work-Bench</a>, the NYC VC firm that concentrates on early-stage enterprise seed investments, announced its $100 million Fund 3 this morning.</p>
<p>The company started back in 2013, when most investment was still concentrated in Silicon Valley, but founders Jonathan Lehr and Jessica Lin believed there was room for a new firm in NYC that concentrated on writing first checks for enterprise startups. The founding team knew IT and believed that with the concentration of Fortune 500 companies in the city, they could build something that took advantage of that proximity.</p>
<p>The bet has paid off in a big way with investments in successful startups like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/20/firehyrdant-lands-8m-series-a-for-disaster-management-tool/">Cockroach Labs</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/30/catalyst-raises-15m-from-accel-to-transform-data-driven-customer-success/">Catalyst</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/dialpad-raises-100m-series-e-at-a-1-2b-valuation/">Dialpad</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/20/firehyrdant-lands-8m-series-a-for-disaster-management-tool/">FireHydrant</a> (all companies TechCrunch has covered). Big exits include CoreOs, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/30/red-hat-acquirescoreos-for-250-million-in-kubernetes-expansion/">which Red Hat acquired</a> for $250 million in 2018.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mTMdSWtCuY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/13/nycs-work-bench-announces-47m-enterprise-investment-fund/">NYC&#8217;s Work-Bench announces $47M enterprise investment fund</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;NYC&#8217;s Work-Bench announces $47M enterprise investment fund&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/13/nycs-work-bench-announces-47m-enterprise-investment-fund/embed/#?secret=mTMdSWtCuY" data-secret="mTMdSWtCuY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Writing <a href="https://medium.com/work-bench/announcing-our-100m-work-bench-fund-3-1b1a8132b84e">in a blog post</a> announcing the new fund, Lehr and Lin said their initial idea has grown far beyond anything they could have hoped for in those early days. &#8220;By utilizing our deep corporate network of Fortune 500 customers here in NYC, we can get conviction in companies early on, and before they have the metrics other VC firms require. It’s also through this network of customers that we can land critical early customer logos and through our extensive community events and playbooks that we can enable pivotal knowledge sharing,&#8221; the two founders wrote.</p>
<p>Lehr says, even with the pandemic, which could have allowed it to expand its reach, the company is mostly sticking to its NYC focus with the majority of investments based there. &#8220;This may sound ironic, but while businesses went virtual, the pandemic reinforced our focus on New York City. Our city was hit first and hardest by COVID, but despite it all, VC funding activity for local enterprise startups actually increased substantially during the pandemic. Along with that, with so many Fortune 500s in NYC all going through accelerated digital transformation during the pandemic, there was a ton of work to be done and numerous customer opportunities right here in our own backyard,&#8221; Lehr said.</p>
<p>He says that the<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/13/nycs-work-bench-announces-47m-enterprise-investment-fund/"> $47 million Fund 2 portfolio</a> was deployed to 70% NYC-based startups, and he predicts that Fund 3 will have a similar composition, if not slightly more concentrated in New York.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company didn&#8217;t just decide to write first checks though, it tried to build the community by offering workspace in their offices where early-stage companies could feed off one another (at least until the pandemic came along). The founders have also offered events where various speakers came to their offices, hosting hundreds of events since inception, while going virtual when the pandemic closed down in-person gatherings.</p>
<p>Lehr says as the company deploys Fund 3 money, it is looking for ways to invest in a more diverse group of founders. &#8220;Right now, 20% of our portfolio is made up of women founders. While we are proud of that number within an enterprise context, we believe there is so much room for improvement. As we’ve learned, deal flow doesn’t become diverse on its own &#8212; you need to make it diverse, which is why we place a huge emphasis on identifying and amplifying the voices of women and diverse founders within our own Investment Committee meetings and across the rest of the VC and enterprise tech community.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company will continue to look at enterprise startups, particularly in New York City, as it looks to distribute these new funds.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2k0MReZsQn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/us-seed-stage-investing-flourished-during-pandemic/">US seed-stage investing flourished during pandemic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;US seed-stage investing flourished during pandemic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/24/us-seed-stage-investing-flourished-during-pandemic/embed/#?secret=2k0MReZsQn" data-secret="2k0MReZsQn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/work-bench-will-continue-supporting-early-stage-enterprise-startups-with-new-100m-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185574</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Next up on Synapse&#8217;s fintech services platform: White-labeled credit products</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/synapse-mastercard-credit-hub/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/synapse-mastercard-credit-hub/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 16:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mastercard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Synapse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185412</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When Sankaet Pathak co-founded Synapse in 2014, he had a vision of doing more than just building a platform that enables banks and fintech companies to easily develop financial services.  He wanted to build a company that helped provide greater access to financial services to a larger pool of people &#8212; regardless of their net [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When Sankaet Pathak co-founded</span><a href="https://synapsefi.com"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Synapse</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2014, he had a vision of doing more than just building a platform </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">that enables banks and fintech companies to easily develop financial services.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He wanted to build a company that helped provide </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">greater access</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to financial services to a larger pool of people &#8212; regardless of their net worth or their country of origin. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the years, San Francisco-based Synapse has steadily grown its Deposit Hub, its product that is aimed at making it “faster and easier” for fintech companies to launch and scale foundational financial products to their customers. Synapse’s banking-as-a-service platform provides payment, card issuance, deposit, lending, compliance, credit and investment products as APIs. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Through those white-labeled developer- and bank-facing APIs, Synapse aims to make it easier for companies to connect with banks, and, in turn, for banks to automate and extend their back-end operations.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> And that line of its business</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">has been doing well. Last year, for example, Synapse doubled its revenue, and this year, so far, it has increased it by 150%.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, the company is going a step further and announcing a new platform &#8212; its </span><a href="https://synapsefi.com/credit-hub"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Credit Hub</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a full-stack API platform designed to give fintech companies and neobanks a way to make credit products “easier and smarter” for everyday Americans. The platform is designed to allow any company to build white-labeled credit products — including card issuance, credit-building tools, lending accounts and cashback rewards — in as little as six weeks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Or, as Pathak puts it, “We want to democratize credit, so that the credit invisible can build, and get access to, credit.”</span></p>
<p>In private beta until now, the company&#8217;s Credit Hub has so far helped facilitate the issuance of one million<b> </b>credit accounts, and the platform has extended more than $40 million in credit.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Synapse is launching its Credit Hub by leveraging the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Masterc</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">a</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">rd</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> network. With the Synapse Credit Hub platform, companies can offer a “comprehensive” suite of products, including card issuance, credit-building tools, accounts and cashback rewards, among other things, Pathak said.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We realized that </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">no good solution existed for the credit market. Companies would have to piecemeal it together,” Pathak said. “It takes a year or 18 months to take products to market, at a minimum. So we’re taking the same speed we brought to the deposits space to the credit space so developers can democratize credit for everyday Americans and hopefully in the future, globally.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Synapse was founded in 2014 by Bryan Keltner and Pathak, who came to the U.S. from India to study but grew frustrated at the difficulty of opening a bank account without U.S. social security history. Specifically, as an astrophysics grad student at the University of Tennessee, Pathak was denied a bank account that he applied for alongside an American colleague. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even today, Pathak says he &#8212; as CEO and co-founder of a company that in 2019 raised over </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/07/synapse-raises-33m/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$33 million in a Series B funding round</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> led by Andreessen Horowitz (a16z) –– considered himself one of the “credit invisible.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Pretty much the American dream is to essentially get a house. But If you&#8217;re a person who is credit invisible, you cannot get a house. I could not get a house in America &#8212; and I&#8217;ve done decently well for myself &#8212; because I&#8217;m an immigrant,” he said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But of course, the underbanked doesn’t just include immigrants. It also includes minorities and other populations who have been caught in a cycle of not having access to certain banking services, including credit. He said that the goal is that people with</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> little to no financial expertise can take financial services to market. That’s not the case with other providers that require more expertise to get products and services to market, he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Synapse Credit Hub, he said, specifically supports a new class of flexible, personalized accounts, cash advances and lines of credit for businesses, and increases access to credit-building and borrowing services for end-users. The platform also gives companies the ability to go to market in as little as six weeks with “out-of-the-box” access to multiple bank partnerships; a full suite of KYC and card issuance features; and a full stack of payment tools, including ACH, checks, wires, bill pay and card processing. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Until now, nobody could provide a comprehensive solution that enables the developer to go live with a feature-rich credit product in just weeks,” Pathak said. “We created Synapse to democratize and drive innovation in fintech, and our Credit Hub operates alongside our deposit products to provide a full-featured digital banking experience.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9udMhskY7z"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/the-fintech-endgame-new-supercompanies-combine-the-best-of-software-and-financials/">The fintech endgame: New supercompanies combine the best of software and financials</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The fintech endgame: New supercompanies combine the best of software and financials&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/the-fintech-endgame-new-supercompanies-combine-the-best-of-software-and-financials/embed/#?secret=9udMhskY7z" data-secret="9udMhskY7z" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The various types of credit accounts that can be built using Credit Hub offer different services, such as a credit card, a spend card, buy now, pay later and the ability to issue one-time or revolving loans to enable customers to build credit. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Synapse shares in Mastercard’s commitment to offering and delivering a frictionless payments experience that is easy to access and always on,&#8221; wrote Sherri Haymond, executive vice president of digital partnerships at Mastercard via e-mail. &#8220;With their Credit Hub platform, Synapse is enabling partners to accelerate the launch of credit products, allowing new solutions to go to market in a matter of weeks instead of months. We’re pleased that Synapse is leveraging the Mastercard network to make credit products more accessible.” </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/synapse-mastercard-credit-hub/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185412</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Expand your SaaS empire: Network with CrunchMatch at TC Sessions: SaaS 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/expand-your-saas-empire-network-with-crunchmatch-at-tc-sessions-saas-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/expand-your-saas-empire-network-with-crunchmatch-at-tc-sessions-saas-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 16:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CrunchMatch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions: SaaS 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184485</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The power of networking will be in full force at TC Sessions: SaaS 2021 on October 27. This day-long virtual gathering of the global SaaS community features the sector’s leading voices — established founders, top VCs and expert developers. That spells opportunity for early-stage founders who want to expand their network and drive their business [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The power of networking will be in full force at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=crunchmatchpost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=crunchmatchpost&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TC Sessions: SaaS 2021</a> on October 27. This day-long virtual gathering of the global SaaS community features the sector’s leading voices — established founders, top VCs and expert developers. That spells opportunity for early-stage founders who want to expand their network and drive their business forward.</p>
<p><strong>Shameless, but helpful, plug:</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=crunchmatchpost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=crunchmatchpost&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Buy your TC Sessions: SaaS 2021</a> pass now and save up to $100. Prices start at $35 (for students), and we offer group discounts when you buy four or more passes.</p>
<p>The easiest way to find and meet the people you’re most interested in talking to — out of the hundreds of attendees from around the world — is by using CrunchMatch. Simply answer a few questions when you register, and our free, AI-powered platform gets to work making matches with the people who align with your specific goals.</p>
<p>CrunchMatch can help you make efficient use of your time regardless of the type of connections you seek. Looking for investors, customers, engineers or baby unicorns? CrunchMatch has your back. It will send invitations and you can schedule 1:1 video meetings — pitch your company, conduct product demos or interview prospective employees.</p>
<p>You’ll receive access to the attendees list about a week before TC Sessions: SaaS starts. Jump in early and use CrunchMatch to send out invitations and line up RSVPs in advance.</p>
<p><strong>Pro Tip:</strong> You can count on major tech media outlets covering this event. Why not use CrunchMatch to pitch your story for a chance to gain invaluable exposure?</p>
<p>CrunchMatch is the go-to networking platform at all of our TechCrunch events. Here’s what previous attendees have told us about their experiences using CrunchMatch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“The networking at TC Sessions: Mobility is terrific. Our company’s building momentum in the U.S. market, and the opportunity to meet and talk with all the players is very important. The CrunchMatch platform made it easy to connect, and I used it to schedule 22 meetings.”— Melika Jahangiri, vice president at Wunder Mobility.</p>
<p>“I used CrunchMatch to schedule meetings, and the digital aspect made connecting easier. It helped me stay organized, meet people and still have time to take in a piece of everything at Disrupt.” — JC Bodson, founder and CEO of Arbitrage Technologies.</p>
<p>We’re not quite ready to announce the TC Sessions: SaaS agenda, and we’re still accepting applications to speak at the event. Interested? <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/#a50c6764-e874-4d16-baac-2865bbcd5654">Apply here to speak</a> if you want to contribute to your SaaS community.</p>
<p>Want to stay abreast of changes as they happen in the run-up to the event? <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/#333d7903-8740-45ee-a389-8e0332035e57">Register here for updates</a> whenever we announce new speakers, add events and offer ticket discounts.</p>
<p>Get ready for serious networking at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=crunchmatchpost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=crunchmatchpost&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TC Sessions: SaaS 2021</a> on October 27. Buy your pass now to save up to $100, and use CrunchMatch to make expanding your empire quick, easy and efficient. We can’t wait to see you in October!</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at TC Sessions: SaaS 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-c594f6a45f3ff3eabbf91af2a7d9403e"
			width="100%"
			height="1000"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/c594f6a45f3ff3eabbf91af2a7d9403e"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-c594f6a45f3ff3eabbf91af2a7d9403e')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-c594f6a45f3ff3eabbf91af2a7d9403e'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/expand-your-saas-empire-network-with-crunchmatch-at-tc-sessions-saas-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184485</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Neobanks&#8217; moves toward profitability could be the path to public markets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/neobanks-moves-toward-profitability-could-be-the-path-to-public-markets/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/neobanks-moves-toward-profitability-could-be-the-path-to-public-markets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 15:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monzo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neobanks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[profits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185502</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At least a portion of the neobanking world is financially stable enough to consider public offerings. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The global venture capital bet on neobanks is massive. London-based Starling Bank has raised more than $900 million, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/starling-3/company_financials">per Crunchbase</a>. The same data source indicates that Chime <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/chime-2/company_financials">has raised $1.5 billion</a>. Monzo has <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/monzo/company_financials">raised nearly $650 million</a>. And the list goes on: E-commerce-focused neobank <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/juni-a-vertical-neobank-for-e-commerce-and-online-marketing-companies-raises-21-5m/">Juni raised $21.5 million last month</a>. Novo, an<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/novo-a-neobank-for-smbs-banks-41m/"> SMB-focused neobank, raised $41 million in June</a>. Nubank <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/nubank/company_financials">has raised $2.3 billion</a>. And FairMoney <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/predictus/company_financials">has locked down more than $50 million</a>.</p>
<p>On and on and on.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>But despite our general inclination to lump banking-focused fintech providers that serve consumers, business customers or both into a single bucket, there&#8217;s wide divergence in how the various neobank players are performing in the market.</p>
<p>Back in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/building-a-fintech-giant-is-very-expensive/">August 2020, The Exchange noted that</a> many neobanks were racking up steep losses. Our read at the time was that the capital being poured into the fintech category was being invested aggressively in the name of growth. Based on recent results, that view is holding up.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1995214 size-medium alignright" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>But not all neobanks are the unprofitable enterprises that they once were. Chime <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/18/chime-adds-485m-at-a-14-5b-valuation-claims-ebitda-profitability/">indicated in September 2020</a> that it generates positive, unadjusted EBITDA. That&#8217;s a stricter profit metric than the one that Lyft used recently to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/lyft-reaches-adjusted-profitability-milestone-despite-continuing-net-losses/">claim its ascendance into the realm of profitable companies</a>; Lyft posted positive adjusted EBITDA in its most recent quarter, but burned cash to fund its operations and posted a wide net loss in the period.</p>
<p>And Starling Bank reached what it describes as profitable territory <a href="https://www.starlingbank.com/investors/2021/letter-from-ceo-july-2021/">in October 2020</a>. Things have changed since our first look into neobank results.</p>
<p>The trend of positive neobank news continued this June, when Revolut reported its recent financial performance. The company did post rather negative aggregate results for the 2020 period. But <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/maybe-neobanks-will-break-even-after-all/">when we drilled down into its quarterly results</a>, we saw the picture of a fintech company scaling its gross margins and revenues while nearly reaching adjusted net income neutrality by Q4 2020. We were impressed.</p>
<p>This morning, let&#8217;s add to our running dig into neobank results by parsing recently released data from Starling Bank and Monzo. As we&#8217;ll see, although some neobanks are managing to clean up their ledgers and work toward profits &#8212; or reach profitability &#8212; not all are in the black.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/neobanks-moves-toward-profitability-could-be-the-path-to-public-markets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185502</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Passwordstate customers complain of silence and secrecy after cyberattack</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/passwordstate-supply-chain-attack/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/passwordstate-supply-chain-attack/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 15:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Passwordstate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SolarWinds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain attack]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184864</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It has been over three months since Click Studios, the Australian software house behind the enterprise password manager Passwordstate, warned its customers to &#8220;commence resetting all passwords.&#8221; The company was hit by a supply chain attack that sought to steal the passwords from customer servers around the world. But customers tell TechCrunch that they are [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It has been over three months since Click Studios, the Australian software house behind the enterprise password manager Passwordstate, warned its customers to &#8220;commence resetting all passwords.&#8221; The company was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/passwordstate-click-studios-password-manager-breach/">hit by a supply chain attack</a> that sought to steal the passwords from customer servers around the world.</p>
<p>But customers tell TechCrunch that they are still without answers about the attack. Several customers say they were met with silence from Click Studios, while others were asked to sign strict secrecy agreements when they asked for assurances about the security of the software.</p>
<p>One IT executive whose company was compromised by the attack said they felt &#8220;abandoned&#8221; by the software maker in the wake of the attack.</p>
<p>Passwordstate is a standalone web server that enterprise companies can use to store and share passwords and secrets for their organizations, like keys for cloud systems and databases that store sensitive customer data, or &#8220;break glass&#8221; accounts that grant emergency access to the network. Click Studios says it has 29,000 customers using Passwordstate, including banks, universities, consultants, tech companies, defense contractors and U.S. and Australian government agencies, according to public records seen by TechCrunch. The sensitive data held by these customers might be why Passwordstate was the target of this supply-chain attack.</p>
<p>Click Studios sent an email to customers on April 22 warning of a possible Passwordstate compromise, but it wasn&#8217;t until Danish security research firm CSIS published a <a href="https://www.csis.dk/newsroom-blog-overview/2021/moserpass-supply-chain/">blog post</a> the next day that revealed the existence and the extent of the breach.</p>
<p>CSIS said that cybercriminals had compromised the Passwordstate software update feature to deliver a malicious update to any customer who had updated their server during a 28-hour window between April 20-22. The malicious update was designed to steal the secrets from customers&#8217; Passwordstate servers and transmit them back to the cybercriminals.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--callout block--right" >
		<h4 class="block--callout__title">Read more on TechCrunch</h4>
		
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/passwordstate-click-studios-password-manager-breach/">Passwordstate users warned to ‘reset all passwords’ after attackers plant malicious update</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/click-studios-asks-customers-to-stop-tweeting-about-its-passwordstate-data-breach/">Click Studios asks customers to stop tweeting about its Passwordstate data breach</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/how-to-respond-to-a-data-breach/">How to respond to a data breach</a></li>
</ul>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>This is how some customers found out about the hack, they told TechCrunch. Many customers turned to social media because Click Studios shut down its blog and forums as a &#8220;precaution,&#8221; prompting customers to look for <a href="https://lordx64.medium.com/initial-analysis-of-passwordstate-supply-chain-attack-backdoor-code-aaff1df389e4">other sources of information</a>.</p>
<p>Some believed that the hack was “another SolarWinds,” referring to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/fireeye-breach-solarwinds-federal-agencies/">an incident</a> months earlier at tech company SolarWinds after the network management software it sells to customers to monitor their networks and fleets of devices was compromised. Russian spies had infiltrated SolarWinds&#8217; network and planted a backdoor in Orion&#8217;s software update feature, which was automatically pushed to customer systems. That gave the spies unfettered access to sneak around and gather information from potentially thousands of networks, including nine agencies <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/solarwinds-hackers-targeted-nasa-federal-aviation-administration-networks/">of the U.S. federal government</a>.</p>
<p>But Passwordstate was fortunate in ways that SolarWinds was not. Since new Passwordstate software updates need to be manually installed, many companies evaded compromise simply by luck. Determining whether a server had been compromised was also relatively easy by checking to see if the size of a particular file on the server was larger than it should be; the fix was fairly simple, as well.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OsBB2vRkrg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/solarwinds-hackers-targeted-nasa-federal-aviation-administration-networks/">SolarWinds hackers targeted NASA, Federal Aviation Administration networks</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SolarWinds hackers targeted NASA, Federal Aviation Administration networks&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/solarwinds-hackers-targeted-nasa-federal-aviation-administration-networks/embed/#?secret=OsBB2vRkrg" data-secret="OsBB2vRkrg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Click Studios <a href="https://clickstudios.com.au/advisories/default.aspx">went public</a> with the breach on April 24 — late on Friday night in the United States — by publishing an advisory on its website. The advisory largely repeated what it emailed to customers the day before, urging them to reset their passwords starting with all internet-facing networking gear, which, if compromised by a stolen password, would allow the cybercriminals into a victim&#8217;s network.</p>
<p>Several customers who spoke to TechCrunch about the hack, including customers with compromised servers, said the Click Studios was largely unresponsive after that.</p>
<p>The IT executive whose Passwordstate server was compromised by the attack said they updated their server during the 28-hour-long attack, but heard nothing from Click Studios besides the mass email warning of the hack. &#8220;Everything was just, &#8216;change your passwords,&#8217; &#8221; the executive said.</p>
<p>The executive&#8217;s company invoked its incident response plan and found logs showing that passwords had been exfiltrated, but found no evidence that the stolen passwords were used. Because the company uses multifactor authentication, the stolen passwords alone aren&#8217;t enough to break into its network. &#8220;None of the multifactor authentication prompts came up that would have if somebody had tried to log in with any of these accounts,&#8221; the executive said.</p>
<p>The executive offered to provide its logs to Click Studio in the hope it would help the investigation. In a reply, Click Studios apologized but did not request the logs.</p>
<p>Another compromised customer — a managed service provider — said that the attackers tried to steal the company&#8217;s passwords but a glitch stopped the exfiltration in its tracks. The company&#8217;s logs showed that the malicious update tried to communicate with the cyber-criminals&#8217; servers using a deprecated encryption protocol, which the server refused to accept. The customer said they offered to provide the logs to Click Studios, which the company agreed to and received, but that the customer heard nothing more from Click Studios after that.</p>
<p>Click Studios published two more advisories that weekend, but customers who asked for more information were only referred back to the advisories. Some vented their frustrations along with their other embattled customers on public forums.</p>
<p>By the following week, Click Studios began asking customers to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/click-studios-asks-customers-to-stop-tweeting-about-its-passwordstate-data-breach/">refrain from posting its correspondence to social media</a> after reports of phishing emails that were similarly worded to the emails sent by Click Studios, but some customers suspected the company was trying to control the fallout.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uEnMZRilTW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/fireeye-breach-solarwinds-federal-agencies/">Just how bad is that hack that hit US government agencies?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Just how bad is that hack that hit US government agencies?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/fireeye-breach-solarwinds-federal-agencies/embed/#?secret=uEnMZRilTW" data-secret="uEnMZRilTW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Months on, some customers said they feel discouraged by Click Studios&#8217; lack of response and are using what leverage they have to get answers.</p>
<p>Some customers had licenses up for renewal and wanted firm reassurances about the security and resiliency of the software. Before the incident, customers would expect an update every week or two, but Passwordstate updates were on pause indefinitely until the company&#8217;s software development line could be secured. Click Studios had a plan to prevent a similar attack in the future, but insisted on customers signing strict nondisclosure agreements before it would say anything about what changes it was making. The nondisclosure agreements also included provisions that barred anyone from revealing the very existence of the agreement.</p>
<p>Click Studios chief executive Mark Sandford has not responded to multiple requests for comment since the incident. Instead, TechCrunch received the same canned auto-response from the company’s support email saying that its staff are &#8220;focused only on assisting customers technically.&#8221;</p>
<p>In its most recent advisory, Click Studios said as of May 17 the company has returned to &#8220;normal business operations,&#8221; but has not responded to our more recent emails. Click Studios released a long-awaited update to Passwordstate on August 2 to remove the software update feature that it blamed on the supply chain attack.</p>
<p>Some organizations said they are staying on as customers despite the attack. One said while the incident was scary and that it warranted an investigation, they said the initial reporting was &#8220;vastly overblown.&#8221; Others expressed some sympathy for Click Studios for what was seen as a rare event that was unlikely to happen again.</p>
<p>&#8220;I haven&#8217;t lost faith. But this was unpleasant,&#8221; said one customer.</p>
<hr />
<p><em>You can send tips securely over Signal and WhatsApp to +1 646-755-8849. You can also send files or documents using our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/securedrop">SecureDrop</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/passwordstate-supply-chain-attack/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184864</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reserve Trust raises $30.5M to become the &#8216;Stripe for B2B payments&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/the-stripe-for-b2b-payments-reserve-trust-raises-30-5m-in-qed-led-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/the-stripe-for-b2b-payments-reserve-trust-raises-30-5m-in-qed-led-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 15:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B2B payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FinTech Collective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[QED Investors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reserve Trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reserve Trust, a Denver-based financial services provider, has raised $30.5 million in a Series A round led by QED Investors. FinTech Collective, Ardent Venture Partners, Flywire CEO Mike Massaro and Quovo founder and CEO Lowell Putnam also participated in the financing, which included $17.9 million in secondary shares. It brings the startup’s total raised since [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://www.reservetrust.com"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reserve Trust</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a Denver-based financial services provider, has raised $30.5 million in a Series A round led by QED Investors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">FinTech Collective, Ardent Venture Partners, Flywire CEO Mike Massaro and Quovo founder and CEO Lowell Putnam also participated in the financing, which included $17.9 million in secondary shares. It brings the startup’s total raised since its 2016 inception to $35.5 million.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reserve Trust describes itself as “the first fintech trust company with a Federal Reserve master account.” What does that mean exactly? Basically, a</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> federal reserve master account allows Reserve Trust to move dollars on behalf of its customers directly, via wire and ACH payment rails, without an intermediate or partner bank. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Historically, only banks were able to access these payment rails directly, which left both domestic and international fintechs “with limited partner options, poor technology and slow implementations when it came to embedding high-value B2B payments,” says COO Dave Cahill. Reserve Trust touts that its technology and services give companies all over the world the ability to “seamlessly move money via the first cloud-based payment system connected directly to the Federal Reserve” since it is not limited by legacy banking systems.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2185391" style="width: 339px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2185391" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2185391" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSC06785-2.jpg?w=269" alt="" width="329" height="367" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSC06785-2.jpg 4754w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSC06785-2.jpg?resize=134,150 134w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSC06785-2.jpg?resize=269,300 269w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSC06785-2.jpg?resize=768,857 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSC06785-2.jpg?resize=609,680 609w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSC06785-2.jpg?resize=1377,1536 1377w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSC06785-2.jpg?resize=1836,2048 1836w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DSC06785-2.jpg?resize=45,50 45w" sizes="(max-width: 329px) 100vw, 329px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2185391" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> CEO Dave Wright and COO Dave Cahill / Reserve Trust</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In conjunction with the fundraise, Reserve Trust is also announcing that Dave Wright has been named CEO and Cahill joined as COO. The pair worked together previously at SolidFire, a flash storage startup that Wright founded and </span><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/justinwarren/2015/12/21/netapp-acquires-solidfire-for-870-million/?sh=366b46d76764"><span style="font-weight: 400;">sold to NetApp for $870 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2016.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reserve Trust works with businesses that seek to embed domestic and cross-border B2B payment by offering them the ability to store funds in custody accounts that are backed by its Federal Reserve master account.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The history of the company relates back to the global financial crisis. After the crisis, banks in the U.S. went through a process called <a href="https://www.imf.org/external/pubs/ft/fandd/2017/06/adriano.htm">derisking</a>, which meant they shed businesses that on a risk return basis weren’t as strong as other businesses. One of those included the handling of U.S. dollar payments, particularly in emerging countries. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“One of the consequences of this is that it became significantly more difficult and expensive for businesses and smaller economies to trade and move U.S. dollars around the world,” Wright told TechCrunch. “And the founders of Reserve Trust saw this opportunity to build a new type of financial institution that was focused on helping to provide U.S. dollar payment services, especially to emerging fintechs in markets around the world, and helping to reconnect those economies to global trade.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But rather than start a bank, the founders (</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dennis Gingold</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Justin Guilder</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">) navigated a previously unexplored part of regulatory waters to create a state-chartered trust company with a Federal Reserve master account.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“That&#8217;s something that had never really been done before,” Wright added. “Pretty much every other trust company has to work through banks for all their payment services. Reserve Trust is the first that has actually managed to get a Federal Reserve master account and can process payments directly with the Federal Reserve.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The complex process took about three years, and in 2018, the company got a Federal Reserve master account and started providing U.S. dollar custody and payment services for fintechs all over the world. Reserve Trust began to see strong demand from payment and fintech companies that were struggling to develop strong partner bank relationships, even though fundamentally there wasn&#8217;t any reason the banks couldn&#8217;t work with them. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“They found working with banks to be a slow process, one that didn&#8217;t involve a lot of technology expertise on the side of the banks, and it was really inhibiting their ability to develop their technology,” Wright said. And that was even here in the U.S. Today, more than half of its business is from domestic fintechs, although Reserve Trust still has a strong international presence as well.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ydMJOHyZW1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/21/all-b2b-startups-are-in-the-payments-business/">All B2B startups are in the payments business</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;All B2B startups are in the payments business&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/21/all-b2b-startups-are-in-the-payments-business/embed/#?secret=ydMJOHyZW1" data-secret="ydMJOHyZW1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The new funds will mainly go toward helping the company scale to handle what Wright describes as “a fairly overwhelming amount of demand” and toward building out the team, the technology and the services it needs to address the payment needs of larger, faster growing fintechs around the world. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Most of our customers today are small and midsize fintechs, but now we&#8217;re seeing demand for much larger fintechs that have much higher payment volumes and are involved in embedded banking and B2B payments,” Wright said. “They are looking for a stronger banking partner than what they&#8217;ve been able to find among the role of traditional banks.” Customers include </span><a href="https://www.unlimint.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unlimint</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://www.vertofx.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">VertoFX</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, among others.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QED Investors partner Amias Gerety and FinTech Collective principal Matt Levinson are bullish both on Reserve Trust’s history and its potential.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pair point to payments giant Stripe as an example of how far Reserve Trust can go.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Stripe has significant market share doing merchant acquiring and processing e-commerce payments for the consumer,” Levinson said. “B2B payments is significantly bigger in terms of volume, so we&#8217;re talking about well over $20 trillion of addressable payment flow. But there&#8217;s no real technology company that&#8217;s brought the modern payments platform to market without being beholden to legacy banks. And that’s why we’re so excited about this business.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reserve Trust, he added, is giving businesses a way to facilitate B2B payments that “are smarter, faster and cheaper.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gerety agrees.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Despite all the excitement around digital payments and infrastructure, there is still no fintech that can offer direct integration with the U.S. payment system,” he said. “With Reserve Trust, we are creating foundational infrastructure to hold and move payments globally and at scale.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/the-stripe-for-b2b-payments-reserve-trust-raises-30-5m-in-qed-led-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185379</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Third Wave Automation raises $40M to bring its autonomous forklifts to warehouses</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/third-wave-automation-raises-40m-to-bring-its-autonomous-forklifts-to-warehouses/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/third-wave-automation-raises-40m-to-bring-its-autonomous-forklifts-to-warehouses/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:55:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forklift]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[norwest venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[third wave automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toyota]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185387</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The California-based startup, which was founded in 2018, has raised $40 million in a Series B round led by Norwest Venture Partners.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Fresh off a strategic partnership with Toyota Industries Corporation to build an autonomous forklift, Third Wave Automation has snagged another $40 million from investors.</p>
<p>The California-based startup, which was founded in 2018, has raised $40 million in a Series B round led by Norwest Venture Partners, including participation from prior investors Innovation Endeavors and Eclipse, along with Toyota Ventures, according to a Form D filed with regulators. Matt Howard, general partner at Norwest Venture Partners, will join Third Wave&#8217;s board of directors.</p>
<p>The injection of capital came after Howard learned of Third Wave&#8217;s partnership with Toyota Industries Corporation, which builds a third of the world&#8217;s forklifts, Third Wave CEO Arshan Poursohi told TechCrunch. Under that deal, which was announced in May, Third Wave and Toyota Industries (TICO) will develop an autonomous forklift together. The machine will be manufactured at a TICO factory and be equipped with Third Wave&#8217;s sensors and compute stack. Third Wave will support the software side.</p>
<p>Third Wave&#8217;s three co-founders &#8212; including Mac Mason, who is chief roboticist, and James Davidson, who is no longer with the company &#8212; have long backgrounds in robotics, oftentimes working together at places like Google&#8217;s robotics program and Google Research and Toyota Research Institute.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve covered just about every kind of robot there is,&#8221; Poursohi said. &#8220;But all of these robots that we built ended up, you know, sitting in a closet somewhere because ultimately, Google or, in my case, Sun Microsystems, would decide it&#8217;s not worth scaling it out because it&#8217;s not the core business, or some other reason.&#8221;</p>
<p>The co-founders struck out to form their own company to focus on robots that would be used and would meet an immediate need.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we looked at forklifts, it&#8217;s this beautiful manipulation problem, so it&#8217;s a robot that actually touches the world on purpose,&#8221; Poursohi said. &#8220;And it&#8217;s a thing that we can actually build and ship on a time horizon that is not measured in decades.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The forklifts they have developed operate under what is called shared autonomy. This means the forklift, which can lift pallets and move them around, will operate on its own 90% of the time. However, every robot can also be controlled remotely if the need arises. The robots are easy to operate, meaning the customer, not Third Wave, can have on-site employees to provide assistance remotely if the robot encounters something that prevents it from operating.</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s a big impact we can make on logistics and supply chain, just by moving pallets around, and that&#8217;s where we&#8217;ve been concentrated. The key to our technology is that it&#8217;s very fast to set up and it works in brownfield [environments],&#8221; Poursohi said.</p>
<p>Third Wave is still at an early stage in its development, but it&#8217;s making progress. The momentum from the funding and the recent completion of technical trials will allow the company to speed up its hiring effort and focus on commercialization, Poursohi said. He noted that Third Wave is in active conversations with 20 third-party logistics operators and retailers in the industry.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve tackled and have solid answers on all the technical fronts,&#8221; Poursohi said. &#8220;The next year and a half to two years is about is scaling out our operations team. And the market demand for this right now is massive.&#8221;</p>
<p>The target is to have 100 units in the field — meaning warehouses and other indoor locations — by the end of 2022 and scaling to 350 to 400 by the end of 2023.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0QSpGG7kG7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/video/mobilitys-robotic-future/">Mobility&#8217;s Robotic Future</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Mobility&#8217;s Robotic Future&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/video/mobilitys-robotic-future/embed/#?secret=0QSpGG7kG7" data-secret="0QSpGG7kG7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/third-wave-automation-raises-40m-to-bring-its-autonomous-forklifts-to-warehouses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185387</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
