<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 21:05:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>6 Miami-based investors share their views on the region&#8217;s startup scene</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/6-miami-based-investors-share-their-views-on-the-regions-startup-scene/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/6-miami-based-investors-share-their-views-on-the-regions-startup-scene/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 20:59:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alexandra Wilkis Wilson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alpaca]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clerisy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david goldberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC investor survey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founders Factory New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laura Gonzalez-Estefani]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maya Baratz Jordan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miami]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sanket S. Parekh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Secocha Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2115896</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Miami is quickly becoming a symbol for the tech exodus from Silicon Valley. The area is home to a number of investors, successful tech founders and an eager local government. For this survey, TechCrunch spoke to a number of investors about the area&#8217;s potential, opportunities and key players. This is the second survey TechCrunch published [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Miami is quickly becoming a symbol for the tech exodus from Silicon Valley. The area is home to a number of investors, successful tech founders and an eager local government.</p>
<p>For this survey, TechCrunch spoke to a number of investors about the area&#8217;s potential, opportunities and key players. This is the second survey TechCrunch published on the area and the first can be found <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/8-miami-area-investors-assess-americas-southernmost-tech-ecosystem/">here</a>.</p>
<p>In this survey, these investors agree on several aspects of Miami. They see a huge opportunity for the region to become a major startup hub by utilizing its diverse workforce and wonderful quality of life. As they say below, the future of work is uncertain and Miami is becoming more attractive as workforces disconnect from office buildings.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="N6VSCYOytJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/8-miami-area-investors-assess-americas-southernmost-tech-ecosystem/">8 Miami-area investors assess America&#8217;s southernmost tech ecosystem</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;8 Miami-area investors assess America&#8217;s southernmost tech ecosystem&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/8-miami-area-investors-assess-americas-southernmost-tech-ecosystem/embed/#?secret=N6VSCYOytJ" data-secret="N6VSCYOytJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zvm3Zsbs4y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/softbank-is-just-the-latest-validation-for-miamis-booming-startup-scene/">SoftBank is just the latest validation for Miami&#8217;s booming startup scene</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SoftBank is just the latest validation for Miami&#8217;s booming startup scene&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/softbank-is-just-the-latest-validation-for-miamis-booming-startup-scene/embed/#?secret=zvm3Zsbs4y" data-secret="zvm3Zsbs4y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>We spoke to the following investors:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Alexandra Wilkis Wilson, co-founder and managing partner, <a href="https://clerisy.com/">Clerisy</a></li>
<li>David Goldberg, general partner, <a href="https://alpaca.vc/">Alpaca</a></li>
<li>Mark Volchek, founding partner, <a href="https://www.lasolasvc.com/">Las Olas Venture Capital</a></li>
<li>Maya Baratz Jordan, CEO and founding partner, <a href="https://foundersfactory.com/newyork/">Founders Factory New York</a></li>
<li>Sanket S. Parekh, managing partner, <a href="https://www.secocha.com/index">Secocha Ventures</a></li>
<li>Laura González-Estéfani, founder, <a href="https://theventure.city/en/">TheVentureCity</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;">Use discount code <strong>MIAMICRUNCH</strong> to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">save 25% off a 1-year Extra Crunch membership</a><br />
This offer expires on April 30, 2021</p>
<hr />
<h2>Alexandra Wilkis Wilson, co-founder and managing partner, Clerisy</h2>
<p><strong>Where do you see Miami’s startup scene five years from now?</strong></p>
<p>Miami’s startup scene has been growing and evolving over the past 5+ years thanks to local organizations supporting entrepreneurship including, but not limited to Endeavor Miami, The Knight Foundation, The Lab, Rokk3r Labs, eMerge Americas, Miami Angels and Wyncode. Many of Miami’s entrepreneurs, investors and startups have historically had ties to Latin America. I think going forward, the Miami tech scene will certainly continue to be a conduit to Latin America as it has been in the past. However, I predict more non-Latin American founders, investors, engineers and operators from cities like New York, LA and San Francisco, will also choose to build their businesses in Miami due to higher quality of life and more attractive tax rates. This dynamic will bring more relevant talent and a larger, more robust tech ecosystem to South Florida.</p>
<p><strong>Remote work is pushing and pulling the global workforce. This means that offices will disappear from Miami, even with more companies moving in, but also more locals who work remotely for companies elsewhere. How do you see these factors impacting the city’s tech evolution?</strong></p>
<p>I think we will see more diverse talent flow through Miami as a result of remote work becoming the norm. If employees technically headquartered in other cities are able to work remotely from anywhere, why not try out working from home while based in sunny Miami where one can be outdoors every day of the year? I recently joined a WhatsApp chat called “Nomads in Miami” that includes a variety of intellectually curious people from all walks of life (from creatives, to entrepreneurs, to traditional professionals) who are either temporarily in Miami this winter or have made a permanent move to South Florida. This chat is reflective of new groups of people coming to experience The Magic City. Anecdotally, I’ve found that many of these people who are “testing Miami out,” had never spent significant time in Miami before. I also recently joined another WhatsApp chat #miamitechlife that includes a local community of founders, investors, executives and local leaders to meet, collaborate and network while engaging in fun activities around Miami. There is an excitement and energy in Miami right now, and I believe it’s here to stay!</p>
<p><strong>What industry sectors do you focus on within Miami (and beyond)? What is happening in Miami now that you’re most excited to fund?</strong></p>
<p>I recently launched a growth equity fund called Clerisy with my amazing business partner Lisa Myers who was most recently a partner at L Catterton, a leader in consumer private equity. We are excited to invest in fast-growing consumer and techsumer companies doing over $10 million in revenue, are quickly scaling and need growth capital. We will fund businesses that meet our criteria in categories we like such as health and wellness, consumerization of healthcare, food and beverage, beauty, and other consumer and techsumer areas. I would be thrilled to find an investment based in Miami, however Clerisy is not focused on a specific geography. We will invest in businesses located in cities or countries where we have previous business experience and ample, relevant networks.</p>
<p><strong>What are some of the local challenges you&#8217;ve encountered or seen founders struggle with? More generally, how should people looking to hire in, invest in, or relocate to Miami think about doing business in the city?</strong></p>
<p>The Miami tech ecosystem is smaller than in the Bay Area or New York and arguably less intense, with fewer exits so far of which to speak. Although tightly knit, it is indeed welcoming to newcomers. I think this local hospitality is because Miami has had a bit of a transient nature among some of its inhabitants due to many Latin Americans coming and going every year, depending on the political or economic situations in their respective home countries. I think it will be easier than ever to convince new hires to relocate to Miami. The more success and exits Miami’s existing startups have, the easier it will be to attract more investment at the local level and more future talent.</p>
<p><strong>Who are key startup people you see creating success locally, whether investors, founders or even other types of startup ecosystem roles like lawyers, designers, growth experts, etc.</strong></p>
<p>On a local level, Miami needs a range of people to support its startup ecosystem: founders, high-quality talent ranging from engineers to marketers to creatives, angel investors, venture capital and private equity funds, lawyers, and then ideally a loyal and engaged consumer base that proudly supports its local companies.</p>
<h2>David Goldberg, general partner, Alpaca</h2>
<p><strong>Where do you see Miami’s startup scene five years from now?</strong></p>
<p>Miami has everything in place to accelerate its rise to be cemented as a significant tech/startup ecosystem. It now has capital (investors), founders, talent and infrastructure, each growing by the day given the attractiveness to the area. In five years, I am confident Miami will only trail SF, NYC, LA and Boston in terms of size/deals.</p>
<p><strong>Remote work is pushing and pulling the global workforce. This means that offices will disappear from Miami, even with more companies moving in, but also more locals who work remotely for companies elsewhere. How do you see these factors impacting the city’s tech evolution?</strong></p>
<p>It&#8217;s a double-edged sword. In a positive sense, you’ll get founders moving here, building out remote/distributed/hybrid teams. You’ll also have individual employees living here, but working remotely for companies based in other areas. What will be harder to get is the giant company all built from scratch with everyone local. These successes (e.g., Uber in SF) create thousands of future founders, operators and investors that pay it forward in their ecosystem. Without that, it will be tough to truly crack the top tier.</p>
<p><strong>What industry sectors do you focus on within Miami (and beyond)? What is happening in Miami now that you’re most excited to fund?</strong></p>
<p>As a firm, we focus broadly on consumer, marketplaces, e-commerce infrastructure, real estate technology and fintech. Given the influx of talent, I’m not sure if Miami needs to be pigeonholed to a few sectors. Traditionally, it’s been known for travel/hospitality, healthcare tech and real estate tech, but I&#8217;m already seeing emerging trends around blockchain/crypto, fintech, remote work and even some traditional enterprise SaaS. Miami is also an incredible bridge to Latam and South America and I can see a slew of companies taking advantage of that.</p>
<p><strong>What are some of the local challenges you&#8217;ve encountered or seen founders struggle with? More generally, how should people looking to hire in, invest in or relocate to Miami think about doing business in the city?</strong></p>
<p>The physical dispersion can make it more difficult. Just in Miami, there are minihubs in Brickell, Wynwood/Midtown, The Grove, Coral Gables, etc. Then you have completely separate networks up north in Fort Lauderdale, Tampa, etc.</p>
<p>Additionally, Miami needs a bigger focus and contribution from its universities. Silicon Valley, LA, Boston and New York each have top-tier institutions that churn out tech talent. That’s still missing here.</p>
<p><strong>Who are key startup people you see creating success locally, whether investors, founders or even other types of startup ecosystem roles like lawyers, designers, growth experts, etc. We’re trying to highlight the movers and shakers who outsiders might not know.</strong></p>
<p>Honestly, I am uncovering more each day. And everyone likes to talk about the &#8220;big names&#8221; that have recently moved here, like Keith Rabois, Anthony Pompliano, Harry Hurst, Jon Oringer, etc. But I also have deference to the folks that have been here, working tirelessly for years, creating the foundation. Some that come to mind: Melissa Medina, Matt Haggman, Nico Berardi, Shervin Pishevar, Raul Moas, Nancy Dahlberg, Rebecca Danta, Moishe Mana, Laura Maydon, Brian Brackeen, Tony Jimenez, Brian Breslin, Juan Pablo Cappello, Mellissa Krinzman, Mark Kingdon, and now, of course, Mayor Francis Suarez.</p>
<h2>Mark Volcheck, founding partner, Las Olas Venture Capital</h2>
<p><strong>Where do you see Miami’s startup scene five years from now?</strong></p>
<p>We think that things are still very early, but are bullish on the future of Florida tech. One of the key things to work on over the next five years is the continued community building — right now, there are a lot of disparate groups and not much communication between them. Over time, that cohesiveness could really drive south Florida forward as a tech ecosystem.</p>
<p><strong>Remote work is pushing and pulling the global workforce. This means that offices will disappear from Miami, even with more companies moving in, but also more locals who work remotely for companies elsewhere. How do you see these factors impacting the city’s tech evolution?</strong></p>
<p>We do think there will be a future for offices and in-person collaboration. Across our entire portfolio nearly all companies have some plan to retain in-person talent. The biggest benefit is that remote work has enabled people in Big Tech to work outside of Silicon Valley, and it appears Miami and South Florida, more broadly, are enjoying the benefits of that decentralization. The distribution of talent will benefit founders here locally as the old VC expectations of tech talent to be hyperconcentrated in Silicon Valley is no longer as true, and people here locally will have access to better resources.</p>
<p><strong>What industry sectors do you focus on within Miami (and beyond)? What is happening in Miami now that you’re most excited to fund?</strong></p>
<p>Our fund targets two primary themes: B2B vertical SaaS and SaaS-enabled businesses/marketplaces, and broadly what we call knowledge worker tools — DevOps, cybersecurity and other typically product-led horizontal applications. Within vertical SaaS, logistics and supply chain tech has really taken off within the last few years, with even more tailwinds due to COVID&#8217;s impact on consumer demand and delivery expectations. As logistics is a huge industry for Miami and Florida, we think startups here have a very exciting opportunity in that space. We have now funded several companies in Florida across various aspects of logistics, from final mile delivery to long-haul trucking route optimization.</p>
<p><strong>What are some of the local challenges you&#8217;ve encountered or seen founders struggle with? More generally, how should people looking to hire in, invest in or relocate to Miami think about doing business in the city?</strong></p>
<p>Access to capital has been a significant problem for Florida-based founders since before we started our first fund back in 2016. There are relatively few funds actively investing in tech companies here at the seed and Series A stage, and essentially none post-Series A. Companies have historically had difficulty getting attention from Silicon Valley-based VCs due to the preconceptions of Florida as a bad place to start a company. Even as recently as last year the standard line from some Bay Area investors was, &#8220;Move out of Florida if you are serious about raising money.&#8221; That said, some of these preconceptions have been deserved, as historically South Florida as a business community has been prone to falling for flash over substance and that has occasionally been true for investors and startups as well. With the buzz around Miami and Florida as a place of interest for VCs and tech, we hope that attitudes around funding Florida companies have changed, as it is clear that good businesses can be built anywhere.</p>
<p><strong>Who are key startup people you see creating success locally, whether investors, founders or even other types of startup ecosystem roles like lawyers, designers, growth experts, etc.</strong></p>
<p>We&#8217;d like to mention all of our Florida-based companies who have been heads down building great businesses here locally — ReloQuest, CarePredict, OneRail, SmartHop and Plum. They are all hiring and growing like crazy, and several have received follow-on funding from top VCs. Check them out!</p>
<h2>Maya Baratz Jordan, CEO and founding partner, Founders Factory New York</h2>
<p><strong>Where do you see Miami’s startup scene five years from now?</strong></p>
<p>Cities with a diverse set of well-represented industries are often fertile grounds for building interesting companies. New York is a great example. Tech ecosystems thrive in an environment where you can unearth and solve a myriad of different problems versus just the problems of a single sector. The most interesting and lucrative companies tend to focus on blindspots in big markets. The blindspots are often discovered when they emerge out of silo and there&#8217;s a creative flow between industries. This is why I believe the diversity of industries and talent is ultimately a strength for Miami.</p>
<p><strong>Remote work is pushing and pulling the global workforce. This means that offices will disappear from Miami, even with more companies moving in, but also more locals who work remotely for companies elsewhere. How do you see these factors impacting the city’s tech evolution?</strong></p>
<p>One of the reasons it seems a lot of people are moving to Miami now is the fact that their job may not be tethered to a geographic location and they can work where they enjoy living. Given this unique strength to encompass work/life balance, Miami can experiment with hybrid models of working environments. Perhaps the dichotomy of working in an office versus working at home is dated. Offices were created for a time when technology used to be limited and the fastest way to communicate was in person. In-person interaction is important, but perhaps there are ways we can maintain [in-person interaction] that are not necessarily tethered to an office and that incorporate more ways to integrate with one&#8217;s life.</p>
<p><strong>What industry sectors do you focus on within Miami (and beyond)? What is happening in Miami now that you’re most excited to fund?</strong></p>
<p>Consumer healthcare is an area I&#8217;ve been actively investing in, and it seems like there&#8217;s been a lot of activity in Miami in that vertical, ranging from medical robotics to remote monitoring for chronic illnesses. I&#8217;m also interested in the future of work and the creator economy, and I believe the diverse set of industries in Miami will breed interesting companies that address the need for people to lucratively pursue their passions.</p>
<p><strong>What are some of the local challenges you&#8217;ve encountered or seen founders struggle with? More generally, how should people looking to hire in, invest in, or relocate to Miami think about doing business in the city?</strong></p>
<p>People in Miami joke that they run on &#8220;Miami time,&#8221; which is something between island time and how New Yorkers think of time.</p>
<p><strong>Who are key startup people you see creating success locally, whether investors, founders or even other types of startup ecosystem roles like lawyers, designers, growth experts, etc.</strong></p>
<p>Miami is a city built by immigrants, and that strength is what will allow Miami to thrive as a tech ecosystem; immigrants start businesses at higher rates than those who are native born. It seems like female founders in particular have been quietly building interesting and successful businesses here.</p>
<h2>Sanket S. Parekh, managing partner, Secocha Ventures</h2>
<p><strong>Where do you see Miami’s startup scene five years from now? The city has attracted a wide range of people over the years, including more tech and finance companies very recently. How will it add up to something more than the sum of the parts?</strong></p>
<p>If you think of Miami as a product and evaluate its adoption curve, it seems like we have reached the chasm. I.e., those of us who have been here pre-COVID are like those you&#8217;d characterize as innovators and the during-COVID crowd as the early adopters. Miami is at the point where we now need to prove we can continue on the curve from early adopters to early majority.</p>
<p>Five years from now we&#8217;ll hopefully be focused on headlines showcasing startups that are growing and hiring here, and not just about which investor has relocated here (which is also good, don&#8217;t get me wrong, but not the end-all).</p>
<p>We can also wish that Miami&#8217;s best traits — its international perspective, its racial, socioeconomic and cultural diversity — will infuse something unique and truly distinctive into the founders and investors building their businesses here.</p>
<p><strong>Remote work is pushing and pulling the global workforce. This means that offices will disappear from Miami, even with more companies moving in, but also more locals who work remotely for companies elsewhere. How do you see these factors impacting the city’s tech evolution?</strong></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t see a future where humans stop interacting with each other IRL. While how we &#8220;work&#8221; will look very different, offices &#8220;disappearing&#8221; is a bit of a stretch. It&#8217;s more likely that we will see an evolution of what an office looks like and how it functions as a &#8220;hub.&#8221;</p>
<p>Miami is full of disjointed &#8220;neighborhood clusters.&#8221; Up until now, this has been a negative, but given the changes we are going to see in how we work, I believe this is no longer as critical. In fact, it can be seen as an advantage where someone could live/work on the beach, and go to events/meetings at their &#8220;hub,&#8221; which may be elsewhere, when needed versus being so focused on living close to your workplace since you need to commute every day.</p>
<p><strong>What industry sectors do you focus on within Miami (and beyond)? What is happening in Miami now that you’re most excited to fund?</strong></p>
<p>While we&#8217;ve been based in Miami for the last seven years, we invest globally. In fact, COVID has made it even more acceptable to not be geographically constrained. This is the precise reason you are seeing investors move here.</p>
<p>We invest in fintech, healthcare tech, consumer tech and consumer products.</p>
<p>One of our most exciting portfolio companies is based in Broward: CarePredict. With the changes that COVID has brought about, they are uniquely placed to take advantage and provide the right dose of technology that eldercare requires.</p>
<p>Within our local ecosystem, Chewy and MagicLeap have been large employers. I&#8217;m most excited to see what their employees branch out and create in the coming years.</p>
<p>We are also excited to see a growing number of exceptionally talented founders moving to Miami to start their companies. These talents may have selected San Francisco or NYC previously, which is a great opportunity for us to meet exceptional teams at the infancy of an idea.</p>
<p><strong>What are some of the local challenges you&#8217;ve encountered or seen founders struggle with? More generally, how should people looking to hire in, invest in or relocate to Miami think about doing business in the city?</strong></p>
<p>Angel rounds are challenging here as compared to other more mature markets where founders or folks from the startup ecosystem play a larger role in angel rounds. Most local angels are used to investing in real estate, and approach early-stage deals differently than those who may be more accustomed to the asset class.</p>
<p>Hiring top-quality talent was also traditionally more challenging here than in tier-one entrepreneurial cities. With the significant influx of remote workers in the past year and the change in perceptions about Miami, we are hopeful that local companies will be able to overcome this challenge.</p>
<p>Miami is a collection of neighborhood clusters, as I mentioned earlier. If someone is looking to relocate here, they should spend some time getting to know what works for them before they commit to a neighborhood.</p>
<p><strong>Who are key startup people you see creating success locally, whether investors, founders or even other types of startup ecosystem roles like lawyers, designers, growth experts, etc.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Venture Bites is a local grassroots organization made up of people passionate about the startup ecosystem. They organize educational sessions with key players from across the country and are also organizing a pitch competition with prominent public and private partnerships already in place.</li>
<li>Refresh Miami has been a vocal supporter and &#8220;info hub&#8221; for the community.</li>
<li>Miami Angels has been working tirelessly to get more angel investors into the startup ecosystem. There are a lot of high net worth individuals here, but it&#8217;s been historically challenging to get their attention away from real estate investing to startup investing. Hopefully, with Miami crossing the chasm it&#8217;ll bring more folks into the mix.</li>
<li>Animo Ventures and Las Olas Venture Capital are two other VC firms located in South Florida from pre-COVID days. Hopefully we&#8217;ll hear of many more setting up shop here in the coming months.</li>
<li>The Knight Foundation has been one of the most consistent supporters of the ecosystem and its impact cannot be understated.</li>
<li>500 Startups is one of the very first Silicon Valley firms to have recognized the potential of Miami, setting up an office here a few years ago. Ana and her colleagues have been instrumental in stimulating and engaging the local ecosystem.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Laura González-Estéfani, founder, TheVentureCity</h2>
<p><strong>Where do you see Miami’s startup scene five years from now?</strong></p>
<p>If the leaps we have made in the last five years are any indication of the next five, we believe Miami will be the next big tech hub in the southern United States. We have all the right pieces to make that true: engineer/developer schools and academies, startup programs and accelerators for seed, a thriving tech community, exits from founders reinvesting in the next generation of founders, influx of new capital, quality of life that tech company founders and employees are starting to prioritize, engaged local government as we have recently seen, as well as an incredibly diverse pool of talent.</p>
<p><strong>Remote work is pushing and pulling the global workforce. This means that offices will disappear from Miami, even with more companies moving in, but also more locals who work remotely for companies elsewhere. How do you see these factors impacting the city’s tech evolution?</strong></p>
<p>We believe talent has no zip code and smart cities are those that attract and retain the best talent — it’s no longer just about connectivity or infrastructures exclusively. In the past, people had to relocate to work at their dream job sacrificing too much personally. 2020 has just confirmed that you don’t need to sacrifice the way you want to live your life because of a dream job. The complaint we used to hear from talent was that there were not enough mid- to senior-level roles in Miami in tech — remote work has significantly strengthened Miami. Miami is a dream destination for a lot of people in different stages of life, so we see Miami also becoming a great remote work hub for those that can be 100% remote, even if they only spend part of the year here and then migrate to other climates. The workforce has more choices now than ever before and we think people will start to really put quality of life over job location. It is a true game changer.</p>
<p><strong>What industry sectors do you focus on within Miami (and beyond)? What is happening in Miami now that you’re most excited to fund?</strong></p>
<p>We have been based in Miami for the past four years and we invest from Miami to where the best founders are. Sometimes [they are] in Miami and sometimes in other states or countries. “We are from Miami to the world.” We are now witnessing a huge internal movement from other states to Miami, but many of us moved from our countries to Miami because of the immense opportunities Miami offers. We invest in software companies disrupting traditional industries, Health tech, fintech, mobility, cybersecurity and jobs. We have also invested in marketplace business models in products disrupting travel, pets, solutions for SMBs. We love giving a first ticket from $100,000 to seed stage companies jointly with a product-led growth program or a pre-Series A to a ticket of an average of $3 million through our Fund II. We love diverse companies, international mindset and execution over anything else.</p>
<p>Miami has always been an extraordinary hub for fintech, we are closely following interesting companies in this space and obviously health tech. We have to say that we have seen very disruptive companies in proptech and also very interesting marketplaces of all kinds B2C and B2B.</p>
<p><strong>What are some of the local challenges you&#8217;ve encountered or seen founders struggle with? More generally, how should people looking to hire in, invest in or relocate to Miami think about doing business in the city?</strong></p>
<p>Our biggest challenge has always been fighting the biases of people around Miami. You have to experience Miami to understand the opportunities it brings. It’s a very welcoming city where so many people will help you land. The next biggest challenge is that the amount of capital that Miami moves versus how much is invested in tech is ridiculous, really a pity. For this reason we need a fund of funds that supports the local funds so that they can develop the ecosystem on this front. And I am not talking about leftovers of capital that need to meet a quota or small initiatives. I mean people investing with true conviction in the asset. That is what gets the flywheel running, capital to fund managers that chose the right entrepreneurs from Miami or outside [and] that create jobs, etc. Let’s not forget that capital attracts founders and founders develop a huge industry that creates thousands of jobs. It is not only about investing in Miami, it’s also about investing from here to the world.</p>
<p><strong>Who are key startup people you see creating success locally, whether investors, founders or even other types of startup ecosystems roles like lawyers, designers, growth experts, etc?</strong></p>
<p>Sure, Juha and Johanna Mikola from Wyncode [since submitting these answers, the company was acquired by Brain Station], Andrew Parker from Papa, Claudia Duran from Endeavor, Victor Servin — CTO of TheVentureCity, David Smith — chief data scientist from TheVentureCity, David Marcus — chief product officer at TheVentureCity. Jimena Zubiria — VP of People at TheVentureCity, Anabel Perez-Novo — CEO of NovoPayment, Adolfo Babatz — CEO of Clip, Rodrigo Teijeiro — CEO of RecargaPay, Jackie Baumgarten — CEO of Boatsetter, Justin Meyers — CEO of Explorest and Vivek Jayaram (lawyer).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zvm3Zsbs4y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/softbank-is-just-the-latest-validation-for-miamis-booming-startup-scene/">SoftBank is just the latest validation for Miami&#8217;s booming startup scene</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SoftBank is just the latest validation for Miami&#8217;s booming startup scene&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/softbank-is-just-the-latest-validation-for-miamis-booming-startup-scene/embed/#?secret=zvm3Zsbs4y" data-secret="zvm3Zsbs4y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/miami/"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2107272 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="141" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=150,21 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=300,41 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=768,106 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=680,94 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=1536,211 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=2048,282 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/miami-footer-banner.jpg?resize=50,7 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/6-miami-based-investors-share-their-views-on-the-regions-startup-scene/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2115896</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Streamlabs launches a &#8216;link in bio&#8217; website builder that includes tipping</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/streamlabs-launches-a-link-in-bio-website-builder-that-includes-tipping/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/streamlabs-launches-a-link-in-bio-website-builder-that-includes-tipping/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 19:33:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116655</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A number of online creators and influencers have adopted mobile-friendly &#8220;link in bio&#8221; websites, like Linktree, to point their fans to their social profiles or other content they want to promote. Today, live streaming software company Streamlabs launched its own product in this market with its new mobile website builder Willow. Its tool differentiates itself [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A number of online creators and influencers have adopted mobile-friendly &#8220;link in bio&#8221; websites, like <a href="https://linktr.ee/">Linktree</a>, to point their fans to their social profiles or other content they want to promote. Today, live streaming software company Streamlabs launched its own product in this market with its new mobile website builder <a href="https://wlo.link/">Willow</a>. Its tool differentiates itself from others in this space by integrating a tipping feature directly on the landing page.</p>
<p>&#8220;Link in bio&#8221; websites have grown in popularity because social platforms like TikTok and Instagram only allow users to feature one main URL on user profiles. But online creators and influencers often have a presence on multiple sites they want their fans to know about. That&#8217;s where these custom websites come in.</p>
<p>Like most &#8220;link in bio&#8221; website builders, Willow offers a simple way to add a list of links to a customized, mobile-optimized webpage.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The product itself is somewhat basic compared to those being offered by newer startups &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/beacons-debuts-a-link-in-bio-mobile-website-builder-that-helps-creators-make-money-not-just-list-links/">like Beacons</a>, for example, which lets users add links for donations, affiliate shopping, paid downloads, and more. In Willow&#8217;s case, you just enter a URL and it appears on your website. You can also pick from a handful of colorful designs, each with their own style and font.</p>
<p>The online website builder lets you view your site in progress as you add links or update the design, and you can preview how it looks on mobile, tablet and desktop by clicking a button.</p>
<p>But Willow&#8217;s more interesting feature is the ability to add tipping to your website.</p>
<p>To do so, you&#8217;ll just toggle on the Tips feature from the website builder interface and then connect your PayPal account to Willow. This places a &#8220;Donate!&#8221; button at the top of your link list, so you can encourage fans to leave a tip.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2116714" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2116714" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2116714" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-1.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="206" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-1.png 780w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-1.png?resize=150,45 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-1.png?resize=300,91 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-1.png?resize=768,232 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-1.png?resize=680,206 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-1.png?resize=50,15 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2116714" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Streamlabs</p></div></p>
<p>This feature will be the new website builder&#8217;s key selling point, given that today, creators who receive tips through social and streaming platforms often have to share the revenue from those transactions back with the platform itself. Tips through PayPal will be a more direct form of payment between fans and creators, beyond any applicable PayPal fees.</p>
<p>Streamlabs tells us it doesn&#8217;t keep any of the tip money &#8212; everything goes to the creator.</p>
<p>However, it does plan to soon monetize the new product in a different way. In a few weeks&#8217; time, the company will introduce a paid version for $5 per month that will include enhanced analytics like click-through rates and which days see the most clicks and views. The pro version will also include more custom themes.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2116722" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2116722" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2116722" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-2.26.38-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="409" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-2.26.38-PM.jpg 2422w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-2.26.38-PM.jpg?resize=150,90 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-2.26.38-PM.jpg?resize=300,181 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-2.26.38-PM.jpg?resize=768,462 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-2.26.38-PM.jpg?resize=680,409 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-2.26.38-PM.jpg?resize=1536,925 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-2.26.38-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1233 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-2.26.38-PM.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2116722" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> screenshot of Willow</p></div></p>
<p>Because Willow only launched today, it doesn&#8217;t have a large number of users at this time. However, a top streamer<a href="https://twitter.com/FaZeMew"> FaZe Mew </a>has already signed up, per the short Willow link (wlo.link) found on his various social media bios.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our experience building tools for live streamers inspired us to build products that cater to the greater content creator ecosystem,&#8221; said George Kurdin, Streamlabs GM. &#8220;To deliver on this mission and grow our business, we are building products that cater to more brands, businesses, and individuals,&#8221; he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/streamlabs-launches-a-link-in-bio-website-builder-that-includes-tipping/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116655</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quill, the messaging app backed by Index, quietly comes out of stealth to take on Slack</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/the-new-new-slack-quill/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/the-new-new-slack-quill/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 19:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116637</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Slack took the workplace communications landscape by storm after it launched its integration-friendly, GIF-tastic chat platform in 2013. Within the space of a decade it entered into the pantheon of big tech: first with massive growth and usage, then a series of giant VC rounds and valuations, spawning controversial competition from incumbents, followed by a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Slack took the workplace communications landscape by storm after it launched its integration-friendly, GIF-tastic chat platform in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/08/14/say-hello-to-slack-the-newest-enterprise-social-network-and-the-latest-effort-from-flickr-co-founder-stewart-butterfields-tiny-speck/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2013</a>. Within the space of a decade it entered into the pantheon of big tech: first with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/04/01/rocketship-emoji/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">massive growth and usage</a>, then a series of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/07/slack-raising/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">giant VC rounds and valuations</a>, spawning <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/22/slack-has-filed-an-antitrust-complaint-against-microsoft-teams-in-the-eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">controversial</a> competition from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/11/02/microsoft-teams-its-new-slack-rival-is-launching-today-as-part-of-office-365/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">incumbents</a>, followed by a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/20/slacks-value-rockets-as-stock-closes-up-48-5-in-public-debut/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">public listing</a> and ultimately a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$27.7 billion acquisition</a> by Salesforce. Now that the cycle is complete, the decks are clear for a Slack disruptor!</p>
<p>Today, a new app quietly launched out of stealth called <a href="http://quill.chat" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Quill</a>, available by way of apps for the web, MacOS, Windows, Linux, Android and iOS.</p>
<p>Like Slack, Quill is a messaging app for co-workers to update each other on what they are doing, have conversations about projects and more.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Unlike Slack &#8212; the implication seems to be &#8212; the difference is that Quill is about delivering messaging in a non-distracting way that doesn&#8217;t take up too much of your time, your concentration, and your energy. Quill bills itself as &#8220;messaging for people that focus.&#8221;</p>
<p>So while you get a lot of the same features you have in Slack for chatting with workers, creating channels, integrating other apps, and having video and voice conversations &#8212; one of my colleagues quipped, &#8220;It looks like Slack, but more colorful!&#8221; &#8212; it <em>also</em> includes a bunch of features that put the focus on, well, focus.</p>
<p>&#8220;We grew exhausted having to skim thousands of messages every day to keep up, so we built a way to chat that’s even better than how we already communicate in person,&#8221; Quill notes on its website. &#8220;A more deliberate way to chat. That’s what Quill is all about.&#8221;</p>
<p>For example, &#8220;structured channels&#8221; let you enforce threads in a channel for different conversations rather than view chatter in a waterfall. Automatic sorting in the app moves up active conversations you&#8217;re in above others. Limitations on notifications mean you can have more nuance in what ultimately might end up distracting you, and senders for example can alter a setting (with a !!) to notify you if something is critical and needs to ping you. Video chats come automatically with a sidebar to continue texting, too.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2116701" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-7.08.34-PM.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="600" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-7.08.34-PM.png 1462w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-7.08.34-PM.png?resize=150,132 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-7.08.34-PM.png?resize=300,265 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-7.08.34-PM.png?resize=768,678 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-7.08.34-PM.png?resize=680,600 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-7.08.34-PM.png?resize=50,44 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>Then, you get separate channels for social and non-work chat; and a series of features that let you manipulate conversations after they&#8217;ve already started: you can recast conversations into threads after they&#8217;ve already started and you have a fast way to reply to messages. There is an easier and more obvious way to pin important things to the tops of channels; and in addition to creating new threads after a conversation starts, you can also move messages from one channel or thread to another.</p>
<p><div style="width: 1844px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-2116637-1" width="1844" height="720" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/move_messages_compressed.mp4?_=1" /><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/move_messages_compressed.mp4">https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/move_messages_compressed.mp4</a></video></div></p>
<p>You can also interact with Quill chats using SMS and email, and like Slack, it offers the ability to integrate other app notifications into the process.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also working on adding a Clubhouse-like feature for voice channels, end-to-end encryption, context-based search (it already has keyword search), and user profiles.</p>
<h2>Managing &#8220;high load&#8221;</h2>
<p>The app has been in stealth mode for nearly three years, and while some projects might never go noticed in that time, this one is a little different because of the pedigree and the context.</p>
<p>For starters, Quill was founded by the former creative director of Stripe, Ludwig Pettersson, who was given a lot of the credit for the simplicity and focus of the payment company&#8217;s flagship product and platform (simplicity that became the hallmark of the service and helped it balloon into a commerce behemoth).</p>
<p>His involvement signaled that the effort might get at least a little attention. In a landscape that seemed to be all but dominated by Slack and a few huge, well-funded rivals in the form of Microsoft and Facebook, it&#8217;s notable that when Quill was just an idea, it had already picked up $2 million in seed funding, from Sam Altman (at the time the head of Y Combinator) and General Catalyst.</p>
<p>Following that it raised a Series A of $12.5 million led by Sarah Cannon of Index Ventures, totaling some <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1791759/000179175919000001/xslFormDX01/primary_doc.xml" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$14.5 million in funding</a> in all. The Series A valued the company at $62.5 million, as we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/29/slack-investor-index-ventures-backs-slack-competitor-quill/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported at the time</a>.</p>
<p>Added to this is the story behind Quill and what brought Pettersson and others on his team to the idea of building it. From what we understand, the idea in its earliest inception was to capture something of the magic of communication that you get from messaging apps, and specifically from workplace communication tools like Slack, but without the distraction and resulting frustration that often come along with them.</p>
<p>By 2018, Slack was already a big product, valued at over $7 billion and attracting millions of users. But there was also a growing number of people criticizing it for being the opposite of productive. &#8220;It&#8217;s hard to track everything that&#8217;s going on in Slack, it can be distracting. Given the network effect, Slack has become powerful, but it was not designed as a high-load system,&#8221; Sam Altman, the investor and former head of both Y-Combinator and OpenAI, said to me back in 2018 when I asked him what he knew about Quill after I first got wind of it.</p>
<p>He said he was &#8220;super impressed&#8221; by Ludwig&#8217;s work at Stripe, and then OpenAI (where he stayed for a year after leaving Stripe), so much so that when Ludwig suggested building &#8220;a better version of Slack,&#8221; it seemed like a &#8220;credible idea&#8221; and one worth backing even without a product yet to be built.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s quite fitting that for an app focused on focus, Quill launched today quietly and without much fanfare: why worry about PR distraction when you can just get something out there?</p>
<p>In any case, we&#8217;re hoping to hear more and see what kind of momentum it picks up. We&#8217;ve asked Index if we can talk to Sarah Cannon about the investment, and we are still waiting to hear back. We are also trying to see if we can talk to Pettersson. But I should mention we have been trying to talk to him since first getting wind of this app back in August of 2018, so we&#8217;re not holding our breath (nor this story).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/the-new-new-slack-quill/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116637</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SolarWinds hackers targeted NASA, Federal Aviation Administration networks</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/solarwinds-hackers-targeted-nasa-federal-aviation-administration-networks/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/solarwinds-hackers-targeted-nasa-federal-aviation-administration-networks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 19:28:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anne Neuberger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberattacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyberwarfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Director]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Aviation Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FireEye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malwarebytes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Senate Intelligence Committee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SolarWinds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain attack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Washington Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trump administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116689</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hackers are said to have broken into the networks of U.S. space agency NASA and the Federal Aviation Administration as part of a wider espionage campaign targeting U.S. government agencies and private companies. The two agencies were named by the Washington Post on Tuesday, hours ahead of a Senate Intelligence Committee hearing tasked with investigating [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hackers are said to have broken into the networks of U.S. space agency NASA and the Federal Aviation Administration as part of a wider espionage campaign targeting U.S. government agencies and private companies.</p>
<p>The two agencies were <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/biden-russia-sanctions-solarwinds-hacks/2021/02/23/b77039d6-71fa-11eb-85fa-e0ccb3660358_story.html">named by the Washington Post</a> on Tuesday, hours ahead of a Senate Intelligence Committee hearing tasked with investigating the widespread cyberattack, which the previous Trump administration said <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/fbi-nsa-says-hacks-on-us-federal-agencies-likely-russian-in-origin/">was &#8220;likely Russian in origin.&#8221;</a></p>
<p>Spokespeople for the agencies did not immediately respond to a request for comment, but did not deny the breach in remarks to the Post.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s believed NASA and the FAA are the two remaining unnamed agencies of the nine government agencies confirmed to have been breached by the attack. The other seven include the Departments of Commerce, Energy, Homeland Security, Justice, and State, the Treasury, and the National Institutes of Health, though it&#8217;s not believed the attackers breached their classified networks.</p>
<p>FireEye, Microsoft, and Malwarebytes were among a number of cybersecurity companies also breached as part of the attacks.</p>
<p>The Biden administration is reportedly preparing sanctions against Russia, in large part because of the hacking campaign, the Post also reported.</p>
<p>The attacks were <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/fireeye-breach-solarwinds-federal-agencies/">discovered last year</a> after FireEye raised the alarm about the hacking campaign after its own network was breached. Each victim was a customer of the U.S. software firm SolarWinds, whose network management tools are used across the federal government and Fortune 500 companies. The hackers broke into SolarWinds&#8217; network, planted a backdoor in its software, and pushed the backdoor to customer networks with a tainted software update.</p>
<p>It wasn&#8217;t the only way in. The hackers are also said to have targeted other companies by breaking into other devices and appliances on their victims&#8217; networks, as well as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/global-cyber-usa-idINKBN28Y1QF">targeting Microsoft vendors</a> to breach other customers&#8217; networks.</p>
<p>Last week, Anne Neuberger, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/18/nsa-anne-neuberger-hackers-covid-19/">former NSA cybersecurity director</a> who last month was elevated to the White House&#8217;s National Security Council to serve as the deputy national security adviser for cyber and emerging technology, said that the attack took &#8220;months to plan and execute,&#8221; and will &#8220;take us some time to uncover this layer by layer.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="g3xHiD7tbS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/fireeye-breach-solarwinds-federal-agencies/">Just how bad is that hack that hit US government agencies?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Just how bad is that hack that hit US government agencies?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/fireeye-breach-solarwinds-federal-agencies/embed/#?secret=g3xHiD7tbS" data-secret="g3xHiD7tbS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/solarwinds-hackers-targeted-nasa-federal-aviation-administration-networks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116689</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reddit ups Series E round by another $116 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/reddit-series-e-more-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/reddit-series-e-more-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 19:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reddit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116695</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reddit, which announced a $250 million Series E earlier this month, has added over $116 million to the financing event, upping the round’s most recent total to $367 million, according to a new SEC filing. The document shows that Reddit is aiming to raise up to $500 million in this capital raise. A Reddit spokesperson [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Reddit, which announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/reddit-raises-250-million-in-series-e-funding/">a $250 million Series E </a>earlier this month, has added over $116 million to the financing event, upping the round’s most recent total to $367 million, according to <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1713445/000171344521000001/xslFormDX01/primary_doc.xml">a new SEC filing</a>. The document shows that Reddit is aiming to raise up to $500 million in this capital raise.</p>
<p>A Reddit spokesperson confirmed the news, saying that the new capital is from ”new and existing investors.” They offered no specifics on names. The spokesperson did confirm that the new capital did not come with a new valuation, keeping the platform at its previously-announced valuation of $6 billion pre-money.</p>
<p>Reddit is a 16-year-old company with over $800 million in known venture funding. It has been in the spotlight for the past few months, with co-founder <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/05/alexis-ohanian-steps-down-reddit-board/">Alexis Ohanian resigning over moderation concerns</a>, to, more recently, its role in the Election and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/robinhood-gamestop-this-is-2021/">the meteoric rise of GameStop’s stock due to the subreddit r/WallStreetBets</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8Qtgtu4Z2c"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/reddit-raises-250-million-in-series-e-funding/">Reddit raises $250 million in Series E funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Reddit raises $250 million in Series E funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/08/reddit-raises-250-million-in-series-e-funding/embed/#?secret=8Qtgtu4Z2c" data-secret="8Qtgtu4Z2c" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/reddit-series-e-more-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116695</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Registration for TC Disrupt 2021 is now open</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/registration-for-tc-disrupt-2021-is-now-open/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/registration-for-tc-disrupt-2021-is-now-open/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 18:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116544</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mark your calendar for TechCrunch’s annual celebration of the startup community &#8212; TC Disrupt 2021 returns this September 21-23! At Disrupt, you’ll rub virtual elbows with the thousands of startup founders, investors and innovators building cutting-edge products and companies. Disrupt will be all-virtual, allowing more builders from around the world to share in the learning, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mark your calendar for TechCrunch’s annual celebration of the startup community &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?promo=regisopen">TC Disrupt 2021</a> returns this September 21-23! At <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?promo=regisopen">Disrupt</a>, you’ll rub virtual elbows with the thousands of startup founders, investors and innovators building cutting-edge products and companies. Disrupt will be all-virtual, allowing more builders from around the world to share in the learning, growth, connection and excitement that you can only experience with TechCrunch. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As always, networking will be front and center. You’ll have the opportunity to make spontaneous connections, curated connections with CrunchMatch and chat with other attendees, all while watching sessions. Between the tools provided by our virtual event platform and curated matches, you’ll make valuable connections and expand your network.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every year we iterate on the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?promo=regisopen">Disrupt experience</a> to make sure the event includes more of what founders, investors and innovators want and need to be successful. This year, on the Disrupt Stage we’ll not only bring you the minds behind the headlines but also incorporate analysts’ viewpoints, and highlight emerging founders in Startup Alley in an engaging format geared toward helping you find solutions, build your business or expand your portfolio.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’re also growing the <a href="http://techcrunch.com/startup-battlefield">Startup Battlefield</a> cohort this year. Featuring more startups means more opportunity for founders. If you&#8217;re a founder or startup selected for Startup Battlefield, you’ll be able to pitch to a panel of renowned VCs for a chance to win $100,000 in equity-free prize money. Applications for Startup Battlefield will open Q2 2021.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our Extra Crunch Stage will continue to be a valuable resource for entrepreneurs who are looking to tap the minds of experts and VCs across a variety of industries and categories. In highly interactive sessions, you’ll be able to get your questions answered live or have your pitch deck analyzed to help you refine your fundraising and business development strategies. Plus, all applicable passes will get a three-month membership to Extra Crunch, which gives you a library of insider analyst content that you can put into action at your company right away.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For those early-stage founders who are looking to get some extra exposure for their products and company, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/startup-alley/?promo=regisopen">Startup Alley experience</a> is for you. The founders who are accepted into <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/startup-alley/?promo=regisopen">Startup Alley</a> will get a dedicated listing at the virtual event, where they can hold live product demos, generate leads and chat with interested attendees. Founders in Startup Alley will also give a live 60-second elevator pitch to TechCrunch staff for feedback and there will be dedicated time for attendees to browse startups in each category during the Startup Alley Crawl. With a dedicated success manager in your corner providing you tips on how to use all of the items in your toolkit, this is a perfect opportunity to gain new customers, meet potential investors and expand your professional social graph.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">From the Startup Alley exhibitors we will also select up to 50 founders to participate in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/startup-alley?promo=regisopen">Startup Alley+</a>, which will give them access to a pre-Disrupt series of master classes to prep for the event, pitch-off opportunities at Extra Crunch Live and white-glove curated meetings with investors from the TechCrunch network. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is much more happening behind the scenes to add to your <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?promo=regisopen">TC Disrupt 2021 experience</a> that we will be sharing with you over the coming weeks, but we know you’ll want to secure your spot at Disrupt now. Passes are now available at the lowest <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?promo=regisopen&amp;display=true">Super Early-Bird rate</a>, with additional savings available on top of that for founders, students and employees of nonprofits and government organizations. These passes are your <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?promo=regisopen&amp;display=true">full-access ticket to everything Disrupt has to offer</a> and more for under $100 &#8212; but only for a limited time. Be a part of the startup world’s annual rite of passage online this September 21-23 and register today!</span></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-82435225aeb9ceafa2bddf34c78e7cba"
			width="99%"
			height="1300"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/82435225aeb9ceafa2bddf34c78e7cba"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-82435225aeb9ceafa2bddf34c78e7cba')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-82435225aeb9ceafa2bddf34c78e7cba'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/registration-for-tc-disrupt-2021-is-now-open/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116544</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to overcome the challenges of switching to usage-based pricing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/how-to-overcome-the-challenges-of-switching-to-usage-based-pricing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/how-to-overcome-the-challenges-of-switching-to-usage-based-pricing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 18:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Datadog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Cloud and Enterprise Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HubSpot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software as a service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stripe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twilio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2109014</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The shift from pure subscription to usage-based pricing is nearly as complex as going from on-premise to SaaS.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Kyle Poyar</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/poyark">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Kyle Poyar is VP of Growth at <a href="https://openviewpartners.com/people/kyle-poyar/">OpenView</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/why-do-saas-companies-with-usage-based-pricing-grow-faster/">Why do SaaS companies with usage-based pricing grow faster?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/subscription-based-pricing-is-dead-smart-saas-companies-are-shifting-to-usage-based-models/">Subscription-based pricing is dead: Smart SaaS companies are shifting to usage-based models</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The usage-based pricing model almost feels like a cheat code — it enables SaaS companies to more efficiently acquire new customers, grow with those customers as they’re successful and keep those customers on the platform.</p>
<p>Compared to their peers, companies with usage-based pricing trade at a 50% revenue multiple premium and see 10pp better net dollar retention rates.</p>
<p>But the shift from pure subscription to usage-based pricing is nearly as complex as going from on-premise to SaaS. It opens up the addressable market by lowering the purchase barrier, which then necessitates finding new ways to scalably acquire users. It more closely aligns payment with a customer’s consumption, thereby impacting cash flow and revenue recognition. And it creates less revenue predictability, which can generate pushback from procurement and legal.</p>
<p>SaaS companies exploring a usage-based model need to plan for both go-to-market and operational challenges spanning from pricing to sales compensation to billing.</p>
<h2>Selecting the right usage metric</h2>
<p>There are numerous potential usage metrics that SaaS companies could use in their pricing. Datadog charges based on hosts, HubSpot uses marketing contacts, Zapier prices by tasks and Snowflake has compute resources. Picking the wrong usage metric could have disastrous consequences for long-term growth.</p>
<p>The best usage metric meets five key criteria: value-based, flexible, scalable, predictable and feasible.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Value-based:</strong> It should align with how customers derive value from the product and how they see success. For example, Stripe charges a 2.9% transaction fee and so directly grows as customers grow their business.</li>
<li><strong>Flexible:</strong> Customers should be able to choose and pay for their exact scope of usage, starting small and scaling as they mature.</li>
<li><strong>Scalable: </strong>It should grow steadily over time for the average customer once they’ve adopted the product. There’s a reason why cell phone providers now charge based on GB of data rather than talk minutes — data volumes keep going up.</li>
<li><strong>Predictable:</strong> Customers should be able to reasonably predict their usage so they have budget predictability. (Some assistance may be required during the sales process.)</li>
<li><strong>Feasible:</strong> It should be possible to monitor, administer and police usage. The metric needs to track with the cost of delivering the service so that customers don’t become unprofitable.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Navigating enterprise legal and procurement teams</h2>
<p>Enterprise customers often crave price predictability for annual budgetary purposes. It can be tough for traditional legal and procurement teams to wrap their heads around a purchase with an unspecified cost. SaaS vendors must get creative with different usage-based pricing structures to give enterprise customers greater peace of mind.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2109016" style="width: 894px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2109016" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2109016" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/navigating-legal-and-procurement.png" alt="tips for navigating legal and procurement teams" width="884" height="354" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/navigating-legal-and-procurement.png 884w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/navigating-legal-and-procurement.png?resize=150,60 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/navigating-legal-and-procurement.png?resize=300,120 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/navigating-legal-and-procurement.png?resize=768,308 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/navigating-legal-and-procurement.png?resize=680,272 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/navigating-legal-and-procurement.png?resize=50,20 50w" sizes="(max-width: 884px) 100vw, 884px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2109016" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Kyle Poyar</p></div></p>
<p>Customer engagement software Twilio offers deeper discounts when a customer commits to usage for an extended period. AWS takes this a step further by allowing a customer to commit in advance, but still pay for their usage as it happens. Data analytics company Snowflake lets customers roll over their unused usage credits as long as their next year’s commitment is at least as large as the prior one.</p>
<h2>Handling overages</h2>
<p>Nobody wants to see a shock expense when they’ve unknowingly exceeded their usage limit. It’s important to design thoughtful overage policies that give customers the feeling of control over how much they’re spending.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/how-to-overcome-the-challenges-of-switching-to-usage-based-pricing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2109014</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kleeen raises $3.8M to make front-end design for business applications easy</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/kleeen-raises-3-8m-to-make-front-end-design-for-business-applications-easy/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/kleeen-raises-3-8m-to-make-front-end-design-for-business-applications-easy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 17:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neotribe Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silicon valley data capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Switch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116594</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Building a front-end for business applications is often a matter of reinventing the wheel, but because every business&#8217; needs are slightly different, it&#8217;s also hard to automate. Kleeen is the latest startup to attempt this, with a focus on building the user interface and experience for today&#8217;s data-centric applications. The service, which was founded by [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Building a front-end for business applications is often a matter of reinventing the wheel, but because every business&#8217; needs are slightly different, it&#8217;s also hard to automate. <a href="https://kleeen.software/#home">Kleeen</a> is the latest startup to attempt this, with a focus on building the user interface and experience for today&#8217;s data-centric applications. The service, which was founded by a team that previously ran a UI/UX studio in the Bay Area, uses a wizard-like interface to build the routine elements of the app and frees a company&#8217;s designers and developers to focus on the more custom elements of an application.</p>
<p>The company today announced that it has raised a $3.8 million seed round led by First Ray Venture Partners. Leslie Ventures, Silicon Valley Data Capital, WestWave Capital, Neotribe Ventures, AI Fund and a group of angel investors also participated in the round. Neotribe also led Kleeen&#8217;s $1.6 million pre-seed round, bringing the company&#8217;s total funding to $5.3 million.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2116620" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Authoring-Things.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2116620" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2116620" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Authoring-Things.png" alt="" width="1024" height="703" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Authoring-Things.png 1378w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Authoring-Things.png?resize=150,103 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Authoring-Things.png?resize=300,206 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Authoring-Things.png?resize=768,527 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Authoring-Things.png?resize=680,467 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Authoring-Things.png?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2116620" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Kleeen</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>After the startup he worked at sold, Kleeen co-founder, CPO and President Joshua Hailpern told me, he started his own B2B design studio, which focused on front-end design and engineering.</p>
<p>&#8220;What we ended up seeing was the same pattern that would happen over and over again,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We would go into a client, and they would be like: &#8216;we have the greatest idea ever. We want to do this, this, this and this.&#8217; And they would tell us all these really cool things and we were: &#8216;hey, we want to be part of that.&#8217; But then what we would end up doing was not that. Because when building products &#8212; there&#8217;s the showcase of the product and there&#8217;s all these parts that support that product that are necessary but you&#8217;re not going to win a deal because someone loved that config screen.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screenshot-2021-02-23-085325.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2116616" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screenshot-2021-02-23-085325.png" alt="" width="1024" height="587" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screenshot-2021-02-23-085325.png 1241w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screenshot-2021-02-23-085325.png?resize=150,86 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screenshot-2021-02-23-085325.png?resize=300,172 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screenshot-2021-02-23-085325.png?resize=768,440 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screenshot-2021-02-23-085325.png?resize=680,390 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screenshot-2021-02-23-085325.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>The idea behind Kleeen is that you can essentially tell the system what you are trying to do and what the users need to be able to accomplish &#8212; because at the end of the day, there are some variations in what companies need from these basic building blocks, but not a ton. Kleeen can then generate this user interface and workflow for you &#8212; and generate the sample data to make this mock-up come to life.</p>
<p>Once that work is done, likely after a few iterations, Kleeen can generate React code, which development teams can then take and work with directly.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2116599" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/output01.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2116599" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2116599" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/output01.png" alt="" width="1024" height="528" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/output01.png 1754w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/output01.png?resize=150,77 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/output01.png?resize=300,155 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/output01.png?resize=768,396 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/output01.png?resize=680,351 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/output01.png?resize=1536,793 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/output01.png?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2116599" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Kleeen</p></div></p>
<p>As Kleeen co-founder and CEO Matt Fox noted, the platform explicitly doesn&#8217;t want to be everything to everybody.</p>
<p>&#8220;In the no-code space, to say that you can build any app probably means that you&#8217;re not building any app very well if you&#8217;re just going to cover every use case. If someone wants to build a Bumble-style phone app where they swipe right and swipe left and find their next mate, we&#8217;re not the application platform for you. We&#8217;re focused on really data-intensive workflows.&#8221; He noted that Kleeen is at its best when developers use it to build applications that help a company analyze and monitor information and, crucially, take action on that information within the app. It&#8217;s this last part that also clearly sets it apart from a standard business intelligence platform.</p>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/kleeen-raises-3-8m-to-make-front-end-design-for-business-applications-easy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116594</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Area 120 is beginning to use Google&#8217;s massive reach to scale HTML5 GameSnacks platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/area-120-is-beginning-to-use-googles-massive-reach-to-scale-html5-gamesnacks-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/area-120-is-beginning-to-use-googles-massive-reach-to-scale-html5-gamesnacks-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 17:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Area 120]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gamesnacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[html5]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hundreds of millions of users, especially in developing markets, don’t own high-end smartphones and can’t afford fast data plans to enjoy much of anything on the web. Google has been exploring multiple ways to better serve this segment of the user base. It has tried partnerships to make the internet more affordable to tens of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hundreds of millions of users, especially in developing markets, don’t own high-end smartphones and can’t afford fast data plans to enjoy much of anything on the web.</p>
<p>Google has been exploring multiple ways to better serve this segment of the user base. It has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/17/google-ends-its-free-wi-fi-program-station/">tried partnerships</a> to make the internet <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/google-alphabet-is-shutting-down-loon-internet/">more affordable to tens of millions of users</a>. It has worked with smartphone makers to bring <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/20/googles-lightweight-search-app-google-go-launches-to-android-users-worldwide/">reliable Android experience to cheap smartphones</a>. In fact, it’s currently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/15/google-invests-4-5-billion-in-indias-reliance-jio-platforms/">working on a project with telecom operator Jio Platforms</a> in India to further lower the price point for decent Android experience.</p>
<p>For mobile games, however, Google has a slightly different idea to reach users. Area 120, Google’s in-house incubator for experimental projects, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/13/gamesnacks-from-googles-area-120-brings-fast-casual-online-games-to-developing-markets/">last year launched GameSnacks</a>. It’s an HTML5 gaming platform, where titles are bite-sized and they load much faster and consume far less resources because of the way they have been designed.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>And that idea appears to be working.</p>
<p>Google said on Tuesday that over the past year it has made inroads with GameSnacks, and is now ready to scale the platform and test monetization models to make it worthwhile for game developers.</p>
<p>In an exclusive interview with TechCrunch, Ani Mohan, General Manager of GameSnacks, said the platform has amassed over 100 titles and millions of users.</p>
<p>“HTML5 gaming has been growing, especially outside of the United States. HTML5 is a great way to get games to users who have just come online and probably haven’t played games online before. These games are cross-device, work on low-bandwidth connection, and are instantly playable as they don’t require users to install any files,” he said.</p>
<p>These single-player games, that work on any device with as low RAM as 1GB and 2G to 3G data connection, are available to users through <a href="https://gamesnacks.com/embed/">GameSnacks website</a>. They can be played on desktop as well as Chrome on an iPhone or iPad (if you wanted to give it a whirl.)</p>
<p>Now the company is using its scale to expand the reach and discoverability of GameSnacks. Mohan said in recent weeks GameSnacks games have been made available from the New Tab page in Chrome for users in India, Indonesia, Nigeria, and Kenya.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2116606" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gamesnacks.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="556" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gamesnacks.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gamesnacks.jpg?resize=150,81 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gamesnacks.jpg?resize=300,163 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gamesnacks.jpg?resize=768,417 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gamesnacks.jpg?resize=680,369 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gamesnacks.jpg?resize=1536,833 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gamesnacks.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>In India, Google’s biggest market by users, GameSnacks games are also arriving to Google Pay. The company is also experimenting with bringing GameSnacks games to Discover feed.</p>
<p>Mohan said the company is starting these integrations is select countries because that’s where many users face the challenges the platform is trying to address. “We view this as an early stage of experimentation. If it goes well, we will love to expand it,” he said.</p>
<p>Additionally, Mohan said the company is experimenting with bringing GameSnacks games to the Google Assistant.</p>
<p>“Now that few of these integrations are live, one of things we are hoping to do is talk to developers, and tell them that there is an easy way to get on Google,” he said.</p>
<p>Developers on GameSnacks currently monetize their games via a non-exclusive licensing model. Mohan said the team, which comprises six people (though more people from Google contribute to it), is working on helping these developers monetize their games using next-generation AdSense for Games ad formats.</p>
<p>&#8220;We want to help them build viable businesses over time so we&#8217;re going to start experimenting with advertising on the platform,&#8221; he said. However, this will be for a select number of GameSnacks games for now.</p>
<p>Emerging markets such as Africa and Asia are not new to the world of HTML games. In India, for instance, a gaming platform called Gamezop raised $4.2 million last year to expand its HTML5 games to reach more developers and embed them into over 1,000 apps.</p>
<p>In 2018, South African telco, MTN Group, launched the Bonus Bucks HTML5 game portal for its subscribers in the Southern African country. Facebook operated HTML5 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/11/29/messenger-instant-games/">Instant Games on Messenger for years</a> until taking it off the messaging service. A quick search on our own archive <a href="https://search.techcrunch.com/search;_ylc=X3IDMgRncHJpZAN2X09YMEhvR1FKV1ljT2JEQlJLdVNBBG5fc3VnZwM0BHBvcwMwBHBxc3RyAwRwcXN0cmwDMARxc3RybAMxMQRxdWVyeQNIVE1MNSUyMGdhbWVzBHRfc3RtcAMxNjE0MDk4NjUz?p=HTML5+games&amp;fr=techcrunch">returns scores of firms</a> that work on HTML5 games in the past, though we have seen fewer examples in recent years.</p>
<p>Mohan remains bullish that there is a big opportunity for HTML games and this extends beyond Africa and Asia. &#8220;We don&#8217;t see these markets as our only option. These are just the markets we&#8217;re starting with because the need for HTML5 games&#8230; is especially compelling. We think the market size for this is much broader because HTML has users all around the world,&#8221; he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/area-120-is-beginning-to-use-googles-massive-reach-to-scale-html5-gamesnacks-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116565</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Android&#8217;s latest update will let you schedule texts, secure your passwords and more</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/androids-latest-update-will-let-you-schedule-texts-secure-your-passwords-and-more/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/androids-latest-update-will-let-you-schedule-texts-secure-your-passwords-and-more/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 17:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accessibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[messages]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile os]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116543</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google today announced the next set of features coming to Android, including a new password checkup tool, a way to schedule your texts, along with other improvements to products like its screen reader TalkBack, Maps, Assistant and Android Auto. This spring 2021 release is latest in a series of smaller update bundles, similar to iOS [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google today <a href="https://blog.google/products/android/new-features-spring-2021/">announced</a> the next set of features coming to Android, including a new password checkup tool, a way to schedule your texts, along with other improvements to products like its screen reader TalkBack, Maps, Assistant and Android Auto. This spring 2021 release is latest in a series of smaller update bundles, similar to iOS &#8220;point releases,&#8221; that add new functionality and features to Android outside of the larger update cycle.</p>
<p>One the security front, this update will integrate a feature called <a href="https://blog.google/technology/safety-security/password-checkup/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://blog.google/technology/safety-security/password-checkup/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1614117062233000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFqozQV40KSjRi_9v1DRGAGtxo3LA">Password Checkup</a> into devices running <span class="il">Android</span> 9 and above to alert you to passwords you&#8217;re using that have been previously exposed.</p>
<p>The feature works with Autofill with Google, which lets you quickly sign in to apps and other services on Android. Now, when you use Autofill, Password Checkup will check your credentials against a list of known compromised passwords, then notify you if your credentials appear on that list and what to do about it.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2116576" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2116576" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2116576" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-11.05.36-AM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="384" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-11.05.36-AM.jpg 1946w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-11.05.36-AM.jpg?resize=150,85 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-11.05.36-AM.jpg?resize=300,170 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-11.05.36-AM.jpg?resize=768,434 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-11.05.36-AM.jpg?resize=680,384 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-11.05.36-AM.jpg?resize=1536,868 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-11.05.36-AM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2116576" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>The prompt can also direct you to your <a href="https://passwords.google.com/?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://passwords.google.com/?hl%3Den&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1614117062234000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGFDERw_ADCG9o_lUy540e_i7aTcA">Password Manager page</a> on Google, where you can review all your other saved Autofill passwords for similar issues.</p>
<p>To use this feature, you&#8217;ll need to have Autofill enabled. (Settings &gt; System &gt; Languages &amp; Input &gt; Advanced, the tap Autofill. Tap Google to ensure the setting is enabled.)</p>
<p>The new Messages feature rolling out this update could see prolific texters considering a switch to Android, as it&#8217;s one of the most in-demand features since SMS was invented: the ability to schedule your texts.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2116570" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2116570" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2116570" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ScheduleSend.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ScheduleSend.png 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ScheduleSend.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ScheduleSend.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ScheduleSend.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ScheduleSend.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ScheduleSend.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ScheduleSend.png?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ScheduleSend.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2116570" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>Android&#8217;s new scheduled send feature will allow you to compose a message ahead of time, whenever it&#8217;s convenient for you, then schedule it to be sent later when it&#8217;s a more appropriate time. This can be particularly helpful if you have friends, family or coworkers and colleagues in other timezones, and are hesitant to bother them when they could be sleeping or enjoying family time after work. It can also help those who often remember something they meant to text when it&#8217;s late at night and too late to send the message.</p>
<p>To use this feature, you&#8217;ll just write the text as usual, then press and hold the send button to select a date and time to deliver the message. You&#8217;ll need the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.messaging">latest version of the Android Messages app</a> for this feature to work.</p>
<p>Another flagship feature arriving in this Android release is aimed at making Android&#8217;s screen reader, known as TalkBack, easier to use for those users who are blind or have low vision. TalkBack today allows users to navigate their device with their voice and gestures in order to read, write, send emails, share social media, order delivery and more.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2116569" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2116569" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2116569" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Talkback.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Talkback.png 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Talkback.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Talkback.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Talkback.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Talkback.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Talkback.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Talkback.png?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Talkback.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2116569" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>The updated version (TalkBack 9.1) will now include a dozen new multifinger gestures to interact with apps and perform common actions, like selecting and editing text, controlling media or getting help. This will work on Pixel and Samsung Galaxy devices from One UI 3 onwards, Google says.</p>
<p>Google is also responding to user feedback over TalkBack&#8217;s confusing multiple menu system and has returned to the single menu system users wanted. This single menu will adapt to context while also providing consistent access to the most common functions.</p>
<p>Other TalkBack improvements includes new gestures &#8212; like an up and right swipe to access over 25 voice commands &#8212; and new reading controls that let users either skim a page, read only headlines, listen word-by-word or even character-by-character.</p>
<p>Users can also now add or remove options from the TalkBack menu or the reading controls to further customize the interface to their needs. Plus, TalkBack&#8217;s <a href="https://blog.google/products/android/braille-keyboard/">braille keyboard</a> added support for Arabic and Spanish.</p>
<p>The spring update also adds more minor improvements to Maps, Assistant and Android Auto.</p>
<p>Maps is getting a dark mode that you can enable as the default under Settings &gt; Theme and then selecting &#8220;Always in Dark Theme.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2116571" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2116571" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2116571" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GoogleMaps_NightMode.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="408" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GoogleMaps_NightMode.png 1001w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GoogleMaps_NightMode.png?resize=150,90 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GoogleMaps_NightMode.png?resize=300,180 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GoogleMaps_NightMode.png?resize=768,461 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GoogleMaps_NightMode.png?resize=680,408 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GoogleMaps_NightMode.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2116571" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>Google Assistant&#8217;s update will let you use the feature when the phone is locked or further away from you, by turning on Lock Screen Personal Results in Assistant&#8217;s Settings then saying &#8220;Hey Google,&#8221; as needed.</p>
<p>The new cards that appear when the phone is locked are meant to be easier to read with just a glance, Google says.</p>
<p>And finally, Android Auto will now include custom wallpapers and voice-activated games like trivia and &#8220;Jeopardy!&#8221; that you can ask for via the &#8220;Hey Google&#8221; command.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2116579" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2116579" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2116579 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-11.07.50-AM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="406" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-11.07.50-AM.jpg 1932w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-11.07.50-AM.jpg?resize=150,90 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-11.07.50-AM.jpg?resize=300,179 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-11.07.50-AM.jpg?resize=768,459 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-11.07.50-AM.jpg?resize=680,406 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-11.07.50-AM.jpg?resize=1536,917 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-23-at-11.07.50-AM.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2116579" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>There are also now shortcuts on the launch screen for accessing your contacts, or using Assistant to complete tasks like checking the weather or adjusting the thermostat, for example. Cars with wider screens will gain access to a split screen view with Google Maps on one side and media controls on the other.</p>
<p>Android Auto&#8217;s features will roll out in the &#8220;coming days&#8221; on phones running Android 6.0 and higher and work with <a href="https://www.android.com/auto/compatibility/">compatible cars,</a> Google notes.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5SNGGlBwgB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/google-launches-the-first-developer-preview-of-android-12/">Google launches the first developer preview of Android 12</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google launches the first developer preview of Android 12&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/18/google-launches-the-first-developer-preview-of-android-12/embed/#?secret=5SNGGlBwgB" data-secret="5SNGGlBwgB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/androids-latest-update-will-let-you-schedule-texts-secure-your-passwords-and-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116543</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Project management service ZenHub raises $4.7M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/project-management-service-zenhub-raises-4-7m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/project-management-service-zenhub-raises-4-7m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 17:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agile software development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitHub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heroku]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salesforce.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[serverless computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vancouver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webflow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116203</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ZenHub, the GitHub-centric project management service for development teams, today announced that it has raised a $4.7 million seed funding round from Canada&#8217;s BDC Capital and Ripple Ventures. This marks the first fundraise for the Vancouver, Canada-based startup after the team bootstrapped the service, which first launched back in 2014. Additional angel investors in this [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.zenhub.com/">ZenHub</a>, the GitHub-centric project management service for development teams, today announced that it has raised a $4.7 million seed funding round from Canada&#8217;s BDC Capital and Ripple Ventures. This marks the first fundraise for the Vancouver, Canada-based startup after the team bootstrapped the service, which first launched back in 2014. Additional angel investors in this round include Adam Gross (former CEO of Heroku), Jiaona Zhang (VP Product at Webflow) and Oji Udezue (VP Product at Calendly).</p>
<p>In addition to announcing this funding round, the team also today launched its newest automation feature, which makes it easier for teams to plan the development sprints, something that is core to the Agile development process but often takes a lot of time and energy &#8212; something teams are better off spending on the actual development process.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is a really exciting kind of pivot point for us as a business and gives us a lot of ammunition, I think, to really go after our vision and mission a little bit more aggressively than we have even in the past,&#8221; ZenHub co-founder and CEO Aaron Upright told me. The team, he explained, used the beginning of the pandemic to spend a lot of time with customers to better understand how they were reacting to what was happening. In the process, customers repeatedly noted that development resources were getting increasingly expensive and that teams were being stretched even farther and under a lot of pressure.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>ZenHub&#8217;s answer to this was to look into how it could automate more of the processes that constitute the most complex parts of Agile. Earlier this year, the company launched its first efforts in this area, with new tools for improving developer handoffs in GitHub and now, with the help of this new funding, it is putting the next pieces in place by helping teams automate their sprint planning.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2116249" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sprints-clip_calendarview_800px.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2116249" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2116249" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sprints-clip_calendarview_800px.gif" alt="" width="800" height="400" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2116249" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> ZenHub</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;We thought about automation as an answer to [the problems development teams were facing] and that we could take an approach to automation and to help guide teams through some of the most complex and time-consuming parts of the Agile process,&#8221; Upright said. &#8220;We raised money so that we can really accelerate toward that vision. As a self-funded company, we could have gone down that path, albeit a little bit slower. But the opportunity that we saw in the market &#8212; really brought about by the pandemic, and teams working more remotely and this pressure to produce &#8212; we wanted to provide a solution much, much faster.&#8221;</p>
<p>The spring planning feature itself is actually pretty straightforward and allows project managers to allocate a certain number of <a href="https://www.atlassian.com/agile/project-management/estimation">story points</a> (a core Agile metric to estimate the complexity of a given action item) to each sprint. ZenHub&#8217;s tool can then use that to automatically generate a list of the most highly prioritized items for the next sprint. Optionally, teams can also decide to roll over items that they didn&#8217;t finish during a given sprint into the next one.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2116250" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sprints-clip_autoaddsprinttoggle.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2116250" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2116250" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/sprints-clip_autoaddsprinttoggle.gif" alt="" width="800" height="400" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2116250" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> ZenHub</p></div></p>
<p>With that, ZenHub Sprints can automate a lot of the standard sprint meetings and lets teams focus on thinking about the overall process. Of course, teams can always overrule the automated systems.</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s nothing more that developers hate than sitting around the table for eight hours, planning sprints, when really they all just want to be working on stuff,&#8221; Upright said.</p>
<p>With this new feature, sprints become a core feature of the ZenHub experience. Typically, project managers worked around this by assigning milestones in GitHub, but having a dedicated tool and these new automation features will make this quite a bit easier.</p>
<p>Coming soon, ZenHub will also build a new feature that will automate some parts of the software estimation process, too, by launching a new tool that will help teams more easily allocate story points to routing action items so that their discussions can focus on the more contentious ones.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="32W7yaX3d9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/15/zenhubs-new-automation-tools-improve-developer-hand-offs-in-github/">ZenHub&#8217;s new automation tools improve developer hand-offs in GitHub</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;ZenHub&#8217;s new automation tools improve developer hand-offs in GitHub&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/15/zenhubs-new-automation-tools-improve-developer-hand-offs-in-github/embed/#?secret=32W7yaX3d9" data-secret="32W7yaX3d9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-inline: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/project-management-service-zenhub-raises-4-7m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116203</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Archer Aviation aims to launch network of urban air taxis in Los Angeles by 2024</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/archer-aviation-aims-to-launch-network-of-urban-air-taxis-in-los-angeles-by-2024/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/archer-aviation-aims-to-launch-network-of-urban-air-taxis-in-los-angeles-by-2024/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 16:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air taxis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archer Aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Electric Planes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eVTOL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116566</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Archer Aviation, the electric aircraft startup that recently announced a deal to go public via a merger with a blank-check company, plans to launch a network of its urban air taxis in Los Angeles by 2024. The announcement comes two months after the formation of the Urban Air Mobility Partnership, a one-year initiative between Los [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Archer Aviation, the electric aircraft startup that recently announced a deal to go public via a merger with a blank-check company, plans to launch a network of its urban air taxis in Los Angeles by 2024.</p>
<p>The announcement comes two months after the formation of the Urban Air Mobility Partnership, a one-year initiative between Los Angeles Mayor Eric Garcetti&#8217;s office, the Los Angeles Department of Transportation and Urban Movement Labs to develop a plan for how to integrate urban aircraft into existing transportation networks and land use policies. Urban Movement Labs, launched in November 2019, is a public-private partnership involving local government and companies to develop, test and deploy transportation technologies. Urban Movement Labs and the city of Los Angeles are working on the design and access of &#8220;vertiports,&#8221; where people can go to fly on an &#8220;urban air mobility&#8221; aircraft. Urban air mobility, or UAM, is industry-speak for a highly automated aircraft that can operate and transport passengers or cargo at lower altitudes within urban and suburban areas.</p>
<p>Archer Aviation&#8217;s announcement comes two weeks since it landed United Airlines as a customer and an investor in its bid to become a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/archer-lands-1-1b-order-from-united-airlines-and-a-spac-deal/">publicly traded company via a merger</a> with a special purpose acquisition company. Archer Aviation reached an agreement in early February to merge with special purpose acquisition company Atlas Crest Investment Corp., an increasingly common financial path that allows the startup to eschew the once traditional IPO process. The combined company, which will be listed on the New York Stock Exchange with ticker symbol “ACHR,” will have an equity valuation of $3.8 billion.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>United Airlines, which has a major hub in Los Angeles, was one of the investors in the deal. Under the terms of its agreement, United placed an order for $1 billion of Archer’s aircraft. United has the option to buy an additional $500 million of aircraft.</p>
<p>&#8220;Archer&#8217;s commitment to launch their first eVTOL aircraft in one of United&#8217;s hubs means our customers are another step closer to reducing their carbon footprint at every stage of their journey, before they even take their seat,&#8221; Michael Leskinen, vice president of corporate development and investor relations at United Airlines, said in a statement. &#8220;We&#8217;re confident that Los Angeles is only the beginning for Archer and we look forward to helping them extend their reach across all of our Hubs.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XYBpLeymM1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/archer-lands-1-1b-order-from-united-airlines-and-a-spac-deal/">Archer lands $1B order from United Airlines and a SPAC deal</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Archer lands $1B order from United Airlines and a SPAC deal&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/archer-lands-1-1b-order-from-united-airlines-and-a-spac-deal/embed/#?secret=XYBpLeymM1" data-secret="XYBpLeymM1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Archer has a ways to go before it&#8217;s ready to shuttle passengers. The company has yet to mass produce its electric vertical take-off and landing aircraft, which is designed to travel up to 60 miles on a single charge at speeds of 150 miles per hour. The company previously said it plans to unveil its full-scale eVTOL later this year and is aiming to begin volume manufacturing in 2023.</p>
<p>Designing and building a hub of vertiports is among the numerous tasks that must be completed in the next three years. Brett Adcock and Adam Goldstein, the company&#8217;s co-founders and co-CEOs, have said they&#8217;re open to using existing infrastructure such as helipads and parking garages in the short term. Their eVTOL, known as &#8220;Maker,&#8221; is built to fit within the size of the existing infrastructure, according to the company. That flexibility, assuming the Urban Air Mobility Partnership agrees with the strategy, could help Archer meet its 2024 deadline.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/archer-aviation-aims-to-launch-network-of-urban-air-taxis-in-los-angeles-by-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116566</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>After 80% ARR growth in 2020, Saltmine snags $20M to help employees return to a &#8216;new normal&#8217; office</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/after-80-arr-growth-in-2020-saltmine-snags-20m-to-help-employees-return-to-a-new-normal-office/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/after-80-arr-growth-in-2020-saltmine-snags-20m-to-help-employees-return-to-a-new-normal-office/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 16:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future of work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JLL Spark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JLL Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jungle ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saltmine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Xplorer Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116300</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What is working in the office going to look like in a post-COVID-19 world? That’s something one startup hopes to help companies figure out. Saltmine, which has developed a web-based workplace design platform, has raised $20 million in a Series A funding round. Existing backers Jungle Ventures and Xplorer Capital led the financing, which also [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is working in the office going to look like in a post-COVID-19 world?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That’s something one startup hopes to help companies figure out.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.saltmine.com/">Saltmine</a>, which has developed a web-based workplace design platform, has raised $20 million in a Series A funding round.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Existing backers Jungle Ventures and Xplorer Capital led the financing, which also included participation from JLL Spark, the strategic investment arm of commercial real estate brokerage JLL. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Notably, JLL is not only investing in Saltmine, but is also partnering with the San Francisco-based startup to sell its service directly to its clients &#8212; opening up a whole new revenue stream for the four-year-old company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Saltmine claims its cloud-based technology does for corporate real estate heads what Salesforce did for CROs in digitizing and streamlining the office design process. It saw an 80% spike in ARR (annual recurring revenue) last year while doubling the number of companies it works with, according to CEO and founder </span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/shagufta-anurag-524970a3/">Shagufta Anurag</a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Its more than 35 customers include PG&amp;E, Snowflake, Fidelity</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and Workday, among others. Its mission, put simply, is to help companies “create the best possible workplaces for their employees.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Saltmine claims to have a 95% customer retention rate and in 2020 saw 350% year over year growth in monthly active users of its SaaS platform. So far, the square footage of all the office real estate properties designed and analyzed by customers on Saltmine totals 50 million square feet across 1,500 projects.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2CGDuyZ5rw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/03/amid-pandemic-returning-to-offices-remains-an-open-question-for-tech-leaders/">Amid pandemic, returning to offices remains an open question for tech leaders</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amid pandemic, returning to offices remains an open question for tech leaders&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/03/amid-pandemic-returning-to-offices-remains-an-open-question-for-tech-leaders/embed/#?secret=2CGDuyZ5rw" data-secret="2CGDuyZ5rw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Saltmine says it offers companies tools to do things like establish social distancing measures in the office. Its platform, the company says, houses all workplace data &#8212; including strategy, design, pricing and portfolio analytics &#8212; in one place. It combines and analyzes floor plans with project requirements with real-time behavioral data (aggregated through a combination of utilization sensors and employee feedback) to identify companies’ design needs. Besides aiming to improve the workplace design process, Saltmine claims to be able to help companies “optimize their real estate portfolios.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pandemic has dramatically increased the need for a digital transformation of how workplaces are designed and reimagined, according to Anurag. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Given the need for social distancing capabilities and a greater emphasis on work-life balance in many office settings, few workers expect a complete &#8216;return to normal,&#8217; ” she said. “There is now enormous pressure on corporate heads of real estate to adapt and modify their workplaces.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once companies identify their new needs, Saltmine uses “immersive” digital 3D renderings to help them visualize the necessary changes to their real estate properties.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Singapore-based Anurag has previous experience in the design world, having founded </span><a href="https://www.spacematrix.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Space Matrix</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a large interior design firm in Asia, as well as </span><a href="https://www.livspace.com/in"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Livspace</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a digital home interior design company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I saw the same pain points and unmet needs in office real estate that I did in the residential market,” she said. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Real estate is the</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> second-largest cost for companies and has a direct impact on their largest cost &#8212; their people.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looking ahead, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Saltmine plans to use its new capital to (naturally) do some hiring and continue to acquire customers &#8212; in particular, seeking to expand its portfolio of Global 2000 companies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Saltmine </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">has about 125 employees in five offices across Asia, Europe and North America.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> It expects to have 170 employees by year’s end and to be profitable by the end of fiscal year 2021.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company’s initial focus has been in North America, but it is now beginning to expand into APAC and Australia. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Gm6XqX4uzX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/9-top-real-estate-and-proptech-investors-cities-and-offices-still-have-a-future/">9 top real estate and proptech investors: Cities and offices still have a future</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;9 top real estate and proptech investors: Cities and offices still have a future&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/9-top-real-estate-and-proptech-investors-cities-and-offices-still-have-a-future/embed/#?secret=Gm6XqX4uzX" data-secret="Gm6XqX4uzX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">JLL Technologies&#8217; co-CEO Yishai Lerner said JLL Spark was drawn to Saltmine’s approach of making data and analytics accessible in one place.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Having a single source of truth for data also facilitates collaboration across teams, which is important, for example, in workspace planning,” he told TechCrunch. “This reduces inefficiencies and improves workflows in today’s fragmented design, build and fit-out market.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">JLL Spark invests in companies that it believes can benefit from its distribution and network &#8212; hence the firm&#8217;s agreement to sell Saltmine’s software directly to its customers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“As JLL tenants and clients continue to embrace the future of work, they are seeking technology solutions that keep their buildings running efficiently and effectively,” Lerner said. “Saltmine’s platform checks all of the boxes by streamlining stakeholder collaboration, increasing transparency and simplifying data management.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/after-80-arr-growth-in-2020-saltmine-snags-20m-to-help-employees-return-to-a-new-normal-office/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116300</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Contra wants to be the community that independent workers are missing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/contra-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/contra-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 16:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cowboy ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freelancing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future of work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unusual Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116097</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whether you’re working on something new according to your Twitter bio, or self-employed, according to your LinkedIn bio, founder Ben Huffman thinks his platform, Contra, will be the best way for independent workers to explain and monetize what they are working on. Contra is a platform that wants professionals to create profiles that show project-based [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Whether you’re <em>working on something new</em> according to your Twitter bio, or <em>self-employed, </em>according to your LinkedIn bio, founder <a href="https://twitter.com/_BenHQ">Ben Huffman</a> thinks his platform, Contra, will be the best way for independent workers to explain and monetize what they are working on.</p>
<p><a href="https://contra.com/">Contra</a> is a platform that wants professionals to create profiles that show project-based identities, versus a role-based identity that one would show on LinkedIn. It’s been built for what Huffman thinks is the future: digital knowledge workers, a term he uses to describe independent tech workers who freelance for different companies or gigs.</p>
<p>The early adopters are independent workers who want to work or advise for a product team.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“So you can think about any type of modern-day product team consisting of like a designer, an engineer, a PM, maybe a writer, or maybe someone else distributing content. There&#8217;s a high degree of referability amongst these user types,” he said.</p>
<p>Users would showcase the tools they use, projects they’ve led and initiatives they’ve pushed instead of simply writing “Former Stripe Engineer” and calling it a day.</p>
<p>“What you don’t know is what problems they solved at Stripe,” Huffman explained, and Contra wants to give users space to explain that.</p>
<p>A Contra profile looks like a storefront for an independent creators’ business. The first thing you will see is project experience, with the option to toggle between services currently available for sale, recommendations from the referral network and, finally, the About page.</p>
<p>A goal of Contra’s, per Huffman, is to help independent workers create high-signal referral networks so they can land new opportunities and gigs. Whenever a user posts a new project experience to their resume, they can add who they worked with as a collaborator.</p>
<p>It’s different from LinkedIn, where you can add anyone you meet and they become a “connection.” Contra requires you to have work experience with your network, making the referral network high-signal. Contra positions referrals high-up on profiles, reminiscent of the MySpace Top 10.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uiZX6vxeQs"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/06/4-creator-economy-vcs-see-startup-opportunities-in-monetization-discovery-and-much-more/">5 creator economy VCs see startup opportunities in monetization, discovery and much more</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 creator economy VCs see startup opportunities in monetization, discovery and much more&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/06/4-creator-economy-vcs-see-startup-opportunities-in-monetization-discovery-and-much-more/embed/#?secret=uiZX6vxeQs" data-secret="uiZX6vxeQs" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Referrals as a core mechanism to get jobs could disproportionately hurt Black and brown founders, who have been left out of networks. But Huffman says that Contra doesn’t only rely on referrals, it also helps position someone as more than their resume.</p>
<p>“Most resumes are filtered out by AI today and have historically disadvantaged BPOC candidates,” he said. “With a project focus instead of roles and education credential-focus on the identity, we help undiscovered talent get ahead.”</p>
<p>Huffman, who experienced resume bias first-hand as a college dropout with no-credentials from a rural area, thinks that his tool can combat bias in an effective way. The best-case scenario would be if Contra could help a talented designer based in Minneapolis get an opportunity in a city like San Francisco or New York by showcasing their work.</p>
<p>But Contra has ambition to be more than just the latest startup to aim at LinkedIn, Huffman tells TechCrunch. Beyond being a professional network, it wants to also be a place where independent workers can make money for their services and get inbound customers. He describes Contra as a LinkedIn meets Shopify for independent workers.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2116099" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Contra_2.gif" alt="" width="1024" height="576" /></p>
<p>In other words, Contra is a profile that independent workers can build and then monetize off of, as well as track engagement on how certain services of theirs might be in more demand than others.</p>
<p>“We’re trying to enable people to monetize the value they create, versus the time they spend in places,” says Huffman. The goal here is to “enable people to build these identities, and give them infrastructure to be successful as an independent worker. Contra integrates with Stripe to bring on payments infrastructure, letting workers actually sell their services on the platform.</p>
<p>From an independent worker’s perspective, the internal view offers analytics to understand what the public is looking at on their profile, from what services are most in demand to what projects get the most attention. The analytics, which are private to everyone except the user, also helps workers understand what the conversion rate is once people come to their platform.</p>
<p>It is free to make money and a profile on Contra, which differentiates it from freelance marketplaces like UpWork and Fiverr, which take a percent cut of earnings. Since Contra doesn’t charge a commission on earnings, it monetizes through a SaaS subscription, $29 a month, that includes benefits such as same-day payouts and higher visibility in the platform to eventually get better opportunities.</p>
<p>A potentially large new competitor might be from LinkedIn itself, which is developing a new service called Marketplaces <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/microsofts-new-gig-a-linkedin-freelancer-market-rivaling-upwork-fiverr">to help freelancers find and book work. </a>Facebook is also working on a tool related to freelancers. Huffman sees Contra’s focus on professional identity as a competitive advantage, and the fact that the tool might be taking commissions.</p>
<p>“It makes what we are doing that much more relevant,” he said.</p>
<p>Luckily, the startup has raised a $14.5 million Series A round to meet its competition head on. The financing event was led by Unusual Ventures, with participation from Cowboy Ventures and Li Jin’s recently announced Atelier Ventures.</p>
<p>Contra wouldn’t disclose the number of users it currently has but did confirm that the total is “in the six-figure range.”</p>
<p>The cash will be used to increase the speed in which it can ship features, as well as build out an ambassador program, in which it will pay users $1,000 a month to test out the product and support the shift to independent work.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oOgbt3YML4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/20/chief-community-officer-is-the-new-cmo/">Chief community officer is the new CMO</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chief community officer is the new CMO&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/20/chief-community-officer-is-the-new-cmo/embed/#?secret=oOgbt3YML4" data-secret="oOgbt3YML4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/contra-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116097</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oscar Health&#8217;s initial IPO price is so high, it makes me want to swear</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/oscar-healths-initial-ipo-price-is-so-high-it-makes-me-want-to-swear/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/oscar-healths-initial-ipo-price-is-so-high-it-makes-me-want-to-swear/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 15:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oscar health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The TechCrunch Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2115936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The clear takeaway from the first Oscar Health IPO pricing interval is that public investors have lost their minds. Go public now.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Amidst all the hype that Lemonade (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/02/high-flying-ipos-for-lemonade-and-accolade-may-encourage-other-unicorns-to-go-public/">IPO</a>), Root (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/inside-roots-ipo-filing/">IPO</a>), Metromile (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/insurtechs-big-year-gets-bigger-as-metromile-looks-to-go-public/">SPAC-led debut</a>) and other insurtech players have generated in the last year, it&#8217;s been easy to forget about <a href="https://www.hioscar.com/">Oscar Health</a>. But now that the company founded in 2012 is approaching the public markets, one of the early tech-themed insurance companies is catching up on the attention front.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a>, or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>So this morning we&#8217;re digging into Oscar Health&#8217;s first IPO pricing interval, hoping to understand how the market is valuing its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/how-will-investors-value-metromile-and-oscar-health/">unprofitable health-insurance enterprise</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995210 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Recall that Oscar Health was valued at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/27/oscar-health-raises-165-million-at-reported-3b-valuation/">around $3.2 billion in March of 2018</a>. That datapoint, via <a href="https://pitchbook.com/">PitchBook</a>, is dated. Oscar Health raised hundreds of millions since (per several venture-capital tracking databases, including <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/">Crunchbase</a>) but we lack a final private valuation for the company.</p>
<p>Regardless, with Oscar Health now targeting <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1568651/000119312521049832/d28906ds1a.htm#toc28906_3">a $32 to $34 per-share IPO range</a>, we can get our hands dirty.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get some valuation numbers and then decide if Oscar Health feels cheap or expensive at that price.</p>
<h2>Billion-dollar IPO</h2>
<p>Oscar Health is looking to reap as much as $1.21 billion in its IPO, a huge sum. The company is selling 30,350,920 shares, with 4,650,000 additional shares reserved for its underwriters. Existing shareholders are selling another 649,080 shares.</p>
<p>This means that after the IPO, Oscar Health will have 197,037,445 Class A and B shares in circulation, or 201,687,445 after counting shares reserved for its underwriters.</p>
<p>Using the company&#8217;s $32 to $34 per-share range, we can calculate a valuation minimum of $6.31 billion for the company (lower share count, low-end of price range) and $6.86 billion (higher share count, high-end of price range). That&#8217;s the company&#8217;s <em>simple</em> IPO valuation.</p>
<p>Oscar Health may also sell up to $375 million of its shares at its IPO price to three different funds. The company advises that the &#8220;indication of interest is not a binding agreement or commitment to purchase,&#8221; so we can ignore it for now.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/oscar-healths-initial-ipo-price-is-so-high-it-makes-me-want-to-swear/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2115936</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The current narrative explaining why tech stocks are getting hammered</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/the-current-narrative-explaining-why-tech-stocks-are-getting-hammered/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/the-current-narrative-explaining-why-tech-stocks-are-getting-hammered/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 15:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LOL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stock market]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning the tech-heavy Nasdaq Composite index is off 2.34% after falling yesterday. Shares of Tesla are off more than 6% today, now mired in a bear-market correction after reaching new all-time highs earlier this year. Apple stock is worth $122.02 per share, down from over its recent highs of more than $145. After a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning the tech-heavy Nasdaq Composite index is off 2.34% after falling yesterday. Shares of Tesla are off more than 6% today, now mired in <a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/tesla-stock-tumbles-toward-2nd-bear-market-in-less-than-6-months-2021-02-23">a bear-market correction</a> after reaching new all-time highs earlier this year. Apple stock is worth $122.02 per share, down from over its recent highs of more than $145.</p>
<p>After a long period of time when it felt like tech stocks only went up, the recent correction is starting to feel material.</p>
<p>There are other ways to measure the selloff. <a href="https://www.bvp.com/bvp-nasdaq-emerging-cloud-index">Bessemer&#8217;s cloud index</a> is off 4.5% today, after falling over 5% yesterday. And the now-infamous $ARKK, or <a href="https://ark-funds.com/arkk">ARK Innovation ETF</a> that many investors have used as a proxy for growthy-tech stocks, is off 6.6% today after falling 5.9% yesterday.</p>
<p>Hell, even bitcoin has taken a pounding in the last few days, after its recent, relentless rise.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s driving the rapid turn-around in the value of tech companies, tech-focused indices, and tech-adjacents, like cryptocurrencies? Not merely one thing, of course, in an environment as complex as the world&#8217;s capital markets. But there <em>is</em> a rising narrative that you should consider.</p>
<p>Namely that the <em>money-is-cheap-and-bond-yield-is-garbage-so-everyone-is-putting-money-into-stocks</em> trade is losing steam. As some yields rise, bonds are become more attractive bets. And as COVID-19 vaccines roll out, some investors are pushing their stock-market bets into categories other than tech.</p>
<p>The result is that the landscape of value is shifting; the winds that were at the back of every tech company are receding, at least for now. If the changed weather persists until the very investment climate that tech stocks exist in reaches a new equilibrium, we could see the appetite for tech IPOs lessen, late-stage <em>private</em> valuations for startup shares dip, and more.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/02/22/stock-market-open-to-close-news.html">CNBC from earlier today on what&#8217;s changing</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Stocks dropped again on Tuesday as tech shares continued to tumble in the face of higher interest rates and a rotation into stocks more linked to the economic comeback.</p></blockquote>
<p>Here&#8217;s <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/bond-selloff-prompts-rethink-bystock-investors-11613919600">the Wall Street Journal on the same theme</a>, from yesterday:</p>
<blockquote><p>The lift in yields largely reflects investor expectations of a strong economic recovery. However, the collateral damage could include higher borrowing costs for businesses, more options for investors who had seen few alternatives to stocks and less favorable valuation models for some hot technology shares, investors and analysts said.</p></blockquote>
<p>And <a href="https://www.barrons.com/articles/tech-stocks-outside-u-s-also-hammered-as-interest-rates-rise-51614078392">here&#8217;s Barrons from this morning</a>, noting that what we&#8217;re seeing at home is not merely a US-issue:</p>
<blockquote><p>While members of the NYSE FANG+ index including Tesla, Facebook and Apple have dropped sharply as the yield on the 10-year Treasury has climbed, the sector also is on the retreat overseas.</p></blockquote>
<div class="paywall">The market could snap back. Or not. It&#8217;s worth watching stocks for the next few days.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/the-current-narrative-explaining-why-tech-stocks-are-getting-hammered/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116540</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter relaunches test that asks users to revise harmful replies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/twitter-relaunches-test-that-asks-users-to-revise-harmful-replies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/twitter-relaunches-test-that-asks-users-to-revise-harmful-replies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 15:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bullying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tweet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter is running a new test that will ask users to pause and think before they tweet. According to the company&#8217;s announcement, when Twitter detects what appears to be a potentially harmful or offensive reply to someone else&#8217;s tweet, it will prompt you to consider revising your text instead of tweeting. Users whose tweets are [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter is running a new test that will ask users to pause and think before they tweet. According to the company&#8217;s <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1363956974824550400">announcement</a>, when Twitter detects what appears to be a potentially harmful or offensive reply to someone else&#8217;s tweet, it will prompt you to consider revising your text instead of tweeting.</p>
<p>Users whose tweets are flagged in this way will see a pop-up message appear on their screen, which asks, &#8220;Want to review this before Tweeting?&#8221; There are three buttons to then choose from: one to tweet the reply anyway, an Edit button (this is as close as we&#8217;ll get, apparently), and a delete button to discard the tweet entirely. There is also a small link to report if the system got things wrong.</p>
<p>This is not the first time Twitter has run a test like this.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/05/twitter-harmful-replies-prompt-harassment-test-feature/">May 2020</a> and again in <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1292883957164281861">August 2020</a>, Twitter ran variations on this same experiment. In those cases, the text on the pop-up screen was largely the same, but the layout of the three buttons looked different and were less colorful.</p>
<p>The earlier tests ran on Android, iOS and web, but this current iteration is only on iOS in English, for the time being.</p>
<p>At the time of the initial test, Twitter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/05/twitter-harmful-replies-prompt-harassment-test-feature/">explained</a> its systems were able to detect harmful language based on the kind of language that had been used in other tweets that had been reported in the past.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Say something in the moment you might regret? <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f62c.png" alt="😬" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> We&#39;ve relaunched this experiment on iOS that asks you to review a reply that&#39;s potentially harmful or offensive. </p>
<p>Think you&#39;ve received a prompt by mistake? Share your feedback with us so we can improve. <a href="https://t.co/t68az8vlYN">pic.twitter.com/t68az8vlYN</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Twitter Support (@TwitterSupport) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1363956974824550400?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 22, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>It&#8217;s been shown that these sorts of built-in small nudges can have an impact.</p>
<p>For example, when Twitter began <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/twitter-read-before-retweet/">prompting users to read the article</a> linked in a tweet before retweeting it, the company found that users would open the articles 40% more often than without the nudge. Twitter has also built similar experiments to try to slow down the pace of online conversation on its platform, by doing things like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/09/twitter-retweet-changes-quote-tweet-election-misinformation/">discouraging retweets without commentary</a> or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/twitter-may-slow-down-users-ability-to-like-tweets-containing-misinformation/">slow down &#8220;Likes&#8221;</a> on tweets containing misinformation.</p>
<p>Other social networks use small nudges like this, too, to influence their users&#8217; behavior. Instagram back in 2019 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/08/instagram-anti-bullying-features/">launched</a> a feature that would flag potentially offensive comments before they were posted, and later <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/16/instagram-to-now-flag-potentially-offensive-captions-in-addition-to-comments/">expanded</a> this to captions. TikTok more recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-to-flag-and-downrank-unsubstantiated-claims-fact-checkers-cant-verify/">launched a banner</a> that would ask users if they were sure they wanted to share a video that contains &#8220;unverified content.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s unclear why Twitter hasn&#8217;t simply rolled out the pop-up to combat online abuse &#8212; still a serious issue on its platform &#8212; and then iterated on the design and style of the message box, as needed.</p>
<p>Compared with the much larger engineering and design efforts the company has had underway &#8212; including its newer Stories feature known as Fleets and a Clubhouse rival called Spaces &#8212; a box asking users to pause and think seems like something that could have graduated to a full product by now.</p>
<p>Twitter, however, says it chose to pause the earlier experiment because it needed to make improvements.</p>
<p>&#8220;We paused the experiment once we realized the prompt was inconsistent and that we needed to be more mindful of how we prompted potentially harmful Tweets. This led to more work being done around our health model while making it easier for people to share feedback if we get it wrong,&#8221; a Twitter spokesperson explained.</p>
<p>&#8220;We also made some changes to this reply prompt to improve how we evaluate potentially offensive language &#8211; like insults, strong language, or hateful remarks &#8211; and are offering more context for why someone may have been prompted. As we were testing last summer, we also began looking at relationships between Tweet authors and people who reply to avoid prompting replies that were jokes or banter between friends,&#8221; they added.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/twitter-relaunches-test-that-asks-users-to-revise-harmful-replies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116508</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>RIBS: The messaging framework for every company and product</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/ribs-the-messaging-framework-for-every-company-and-product/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/ribs-the-messaging-framework-for-every-company-and-product/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 15:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2115904</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Relevant. Inevitable. Believable. Simple. Behind most successful companies is a story that checks every one of those boxes.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Caryn Marooney</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/carynm650">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Caryn Marooney is general partner at <a href="https://www.coatue.com/">Coatue Management</a> and sits on the boards of Zendesk and Elastic. In prior roles she oversaw communications for Facebook, Instagram, WhatsApp and Oculus and co-founded The OutCast Agency, which served clients like Salesforce.com and Amazon.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/bottom-up-saas-a-framework-for-mapping-pricing-to-customer-value/">Bottom-up SaaS: A framework for mapping pricing to customer value</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/28/should-your-saas-startup-embrace-a-bottom-up-gtm-strategy/">Should your SaaS startup embrace a bottom-up GTM strategy?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Over more than two decades of advising founders, I’ve heard all kinds of stories &#8212; good, bad and everything in between. While everyone is different, I’ve noticed that the very best stories have something in common: They pass the RIBS test. I’ve<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/14/facebooks-former-pr-chief-explains-why-no-one-is-paying-attention-to-your-startup/"> talked a lot</a> about this over the years, and it’s stood the test of time and trends.</p>
<p>The test is designed to tell you if your story is memorable (will it “stick to your ribs?”) so you can turn it into a compelling message. It looks something like this:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>R</strong>elevant</li>
<li><strong>I</strong>nevitable</li>
<li><strong>B</strong>elievable</li>
<li><strong>S</strong>imple</li>
</ul>
<h2>Relevant</h2>
<p>Before you can come up with a good story, you need to think about the audience. Who are you trying to reach? Are you solving a problem they care about? What matters to them about that problem? Why does your solution deserve attention?</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			The test is designed to tell you if your story is memorable (will it “stick to your ribs?”) so you can turn it into a compelling message.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Marc Benioff could have launched Salesforce by describing it as an online way for companies to manage relationships with their customers. It’s true and it would have been interesting, at least to some people. But instead, Marc went bigger: He ran a campaign that described Salesforce as the “end of software.”</p>
<p>At the time, software was everywhere and it was creating all kinds of problems: It was massively expensive, time consuming and prone to failure. By taking on those issues, Marc made the company instantly more relevant to a bigger market and audience. The conversation went from a discussion of feature checklists, contacts and leads, to how an entire industry would change. Marc looked like a visionary — and Salesforce seemed revolutionary.</p>
<h2>Inevitable</h2>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/ribs-the-messaging-framework-for-every-company-and-product/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2115904</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shippo raises $45M more at $495M valuation as ecommerce booms</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/shippo-raises-45m-more-at-495m-valuation-as-ecommerce-booms/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/shippo-raises-45m-more-at-495m-valuation-as-ecommerce-booms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 15:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shippo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116243</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning Shippo, a software company that provides shipping-related services to ecommerce companies, announced a new $45 million investment. The new capital values the startup at $495 million. TechCrunch is calling the new funding a Series D as it is a priced round that followed its Series C; the company did not award the round [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a href="https://goshippo.com/">Shippo</a>, a software company that provides <a href="https://goshippo.com/products/shipping/">shipping-related services</a> to ecommerce companies, announced a new $45 million investment. The new capital values the startup at $495 million. TechCrunch is calling the new funding a Series D as it is a priced round that followed its Series C; the company did not award the round a moniker.</p>
<p>Shippo&#8217;s 2020 Series C, a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/07/shippo-raises-a-30m-series-c-after-posting-rapid-2019-growth/">$30 million transaction</a> that was announced last April, valued the company at around $220 million. D1 Capital led both Shippo&#8217;s Series C and D rounds, implying that it was content to pay around twice as much for the company&#8217;s equity in 2021 than it was in 2020. (Recall that investors doubling-down on previous bets as lead investor in successive rounds is no longer considered to be a negative signal concerning startup quality, but a <em>positive</em> indicator.)</p>
<p>Why raise more money so soon after its last round? According to Shippo CEO and founder <a href="https://twitter.com/LauraBehrensWu">Laura Behrens Wu</a>, her company made material progress on customer acquisition and partnerships last year. That led to a decision around the time of Shippo&#8217;s Q4 board meeting with her investors that it was a good time to put more capital into the company.</p>
<p>In a sense the timing is reasonable. As Shippo scales its customer base, it can negotiate better shipping deals with various providers, which, in turn, help it continue to attract new customers. Behrens Wu noted in an interview with TechCrunch that when her company was helping its early customers ship just a few packages, shipping companies it supports on its platform didn&#8217;t want to meet with the startup. Now armed with more volume, Shippo can recycle customer demand into partner leverage, improving its total customer offering.</p>
<p>Behrens Wu said that Shippo had secured such a partnership with UPS before it raised its new round.</p>
<p>Turning to growth, Shippo doubled its platform spend, or &#8220;GPV&#8221; last year. GPV is the company&#8217;s acronym for <em>gross postage volume</em>. It roughly tracks with revenue, TechCrunch confirmed. So Shippo likely doubled its top-line last year. That&#8217;s good. Shippo wants to do that again this year, Behrens Wu told TechCrunch. The startup will also double its headcount this year, adding around 150 people.</p>
<p>Now flush with more capital, what&#8217;s next for Shippo? Per its CEO, the startup wants to invest more in platforms (where Shippo is baked into a marketplace, for example), international expansion (Shippo only does a &#8220;little bit&#8221; of international shipping, per Behrens Wu), and double-down on what it considers its core customer base.</p>
<p>TechCrunch was curious about how broad Shippo might take its product from its original home in shipping labels. The startup said that there&#8217;s lots of room in the journey of a packaged, from pre-purchase on, where her company might expand into. However, Behrens Wu cautioned that such a broadening of product work is not an immediate focus at her company.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s see how long the current ecommerce boom lasts and how far this new capital can take Shippo. If it doubles in size again this year we&#8217;ll have to start its IPO countdown sometime in mid-2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/shippo-raises-45m-more-at-495m-valuation-as-ecommerce-booms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116243</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wisetack raises $19M as its buy-now-pay-later service for IRL services scales</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/wisetack-raises-19m-as-its-buy-now-pay-later-service-for-irl-services-scales/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/wisetack-raises-19m-as-its-buy-now-pay-later-service-for-irl-services-scales/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 15:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affirm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnpl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greylock]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2116172</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning Wisetack, a startup that provides buy-now-pay-later services to in-person business transactions, announced that is has closed a total of $19 million across two rounds, a seed investment and a Series A. Greylock led both rounds, with the seed round clocking in at $4 million and the Series A at $15 million. Bain Capital [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a href="https://www.wisetack.com/">Wisetack</a>, a startup that provides buy-now-pay-later services to in-person business transactions, announced that is has closed a total of $19 million across two rounds, a seed investment and a Series A.</p>
<p><a href="https://greylock.com/">Greylock</a> led both rounds, with the seed round clocking in at $4 million and the Series A at $15 million. <a href="https://www.baincapitalventures.com/">Bain Capital Ventures</a> also took part in the company&#8217;s fundraising.</p>
<p>Notably both rounds were closed in 2019, making these amongst the more aged rounds that we&#8217;ve heard of in recent quarters. However, as much venture reporting was delayed last year due to the pandemic and political unsettlement, I am still willing to cover the occasional antique deal.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Wisetack caught our eye not only due to its fundraising activity, but also thanks the buy-now-pay-later (BNPL) space becoming all the more interesting in the wake of Affirm&#8217;s direct listing. Affirm is perhaps the best-known service of its type, making its liquidity moment &#8212; and post-IPO performance &#8212; impactful for its broader business category.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Z4qDjRXNLo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/wall-street-hugs-affirm-as-it-starts-life-as-a-public-company/">Wall Street hugs Affirm as it starts life as a public company</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Wall Street hugs Affirm as it starts life as a public company&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/wall-street-hugs-affirm-as-it-starts-life-as-a-public-company/embed/#?secret=Z4qDjRXNLo" data-secret="Z4qDjRXNLo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But while Affirm wants to offer point-of-sale BNPL services to online merchants, Wisetack is taking a different approach. It focuses on the in-person business world, helping finance consumer transactions involving things like home improvement and car repair; the sort of big transactions that your average family might not have the cash to cover but also doesn&#8217;t want to put on a credit card.</p>
<p>Wisetack partners with vertical SaaS players in different areas. Say, plumbing. This allows users of those vertical SaaS applications &#8212; the plumbers, sticking to the same example &#8212; to offer Wisetack&#8217;s BNPL service to their customers.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s well known that vertical SaaS has wide application. A <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/23/atlantas-singleops-raises-6m-for-its-outdoor-care-focused-software-business/">favorite recent example is SingleOps</a>, which provides software for the so-called &#8220;green industry,&#8221; the world of lawns and landscaping. There&#8217;s SaaS for all sorts of IRL work, which could mean that Wisetack has a good number of software providers to sell into.</p>
<p>The model appears to be working, at least thus far. Wisetack shared with TechCrunch that its loan volume rose 20x between January of 2020 and January of 2021. As the company generates revenues from merchants (loan processing costs), and consumer interest, it&#8217;s likely that its revenue scales with loan volume. If the relationship is even closer to direct, Wisetack grew quite a lot last year.</p>
<p>The startup also said that the number of businesses using Wisetack grew 25-fold last year to a number in the &#8220;thousands.&#8221;</p>
<p>Wisetack fits neatly into a number of recent trends. The first is its work with vertical SaaS, a notable slice of the software market. The second is that Wisetack is another example of an API-led business, offering its service as a tech-powered add-on to other bits of code. And, third, that Wisetack had the same lead investor twice in sequential rounds. This sort of doubling-down from the venture community has become common in recent quarters as the signaling risk of having the lead twice in a row has been zeroed out by general investor enthusiasm for more equity in what appear to be winning startups.</p>
<p>Finally, the Wisetack round is interesting as it is nearly a sort of vertical BNPL, or at least a vertically focused BNPL. The company was reticent to share notes on how it comes to credit decisions, but we presume that all BNPL players that do focus on a particular niche or segment.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/23/wisetack-raises-19m-as-its-buy-now-pay-later-service-for-irl-services-scales/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2116172</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
