<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 14:35:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Stockly lets e-commerce websites sell out-of-stock items from a shared inventory</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/stockly-lets-e-commerce-websites-sell-out-of-stock-items-from-a-shared-inventory/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/stockly-lets-e-commerce-websites-sell-out-of-stock-items-from-a-shared-inventory/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 14:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stockly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131941</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Meet Stockly, a French startup that keeps the inventory of various e-commerce websites in sync. When you see an out-of-stock item on an e-commerce website, chances are you leave that website and try to find the same item on another site. If you operate an e-commerce website, Stockly lets you sell items even when they’re [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Meet <a href="https://stockly.ai">Stockly</a>, a French startup that keeps the inventory of various e-commerce websites in sync. When you see an out-of-stock item on an e-commerce website, chances are you leave that website and try to find the same item on another site.</p>
<p>If you operate an e-commerce website, Stockly lets you sell items even when they’re currently out of stock. The startup automatically finds a third-party Stockly supplier with that specific item.</p>
<p>The order will go through and be sent by that supplier directly. Stockly tells its partners to use neutral packaging so that the end consumer isn’t confused.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This could be particularly useful for small scale e-commerce companies that don’t have a healthy marketplace of third-party retailers. For instance, Amazon can already sell you an out-of-stock item if a supplier has listed that specific item on Amazon’s own marketplace. But that’s not the case for most e-commerce websites.</p>
<p>The main challenge for Stockly is that it has to sort through various catalog formats and match the different inventories of different retailers. It is focusing on clothing items at first. When an order is routed through Stockly, it selects a specific supplier based on different criteria, such as logistics, delivery time and historical data.</p>
<p>So far, Stockly has been working with Galeries Lafayette, Go Sport, Foot Shop and others. The startup has recently raised a $6 million (€5.1 million) funding round from <a href="https://www.idinvest.com">Idinvest Partners</a>, <a href="https://daphni.com">Daphni</a>, <a href="https://www.techstars.com">Techstars</a>, Checkout.com CEO Guillaume Pousaz and various business angels.</p>
<p>With this funding round, the company plans to expand its team to 20 people, add new clients and iterate on its product.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/stockly-lets-e-commerce-websites-sell-out-of-stock-items-from-a-shared-inventory/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131941</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aurora and Volvo partner to bring autonomous long-haul trucks to North America</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/aurora-and-volvo-partner-to-bring-autonomous-long-haul-trucks-to-north-america/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/aurora-and-volvo-partner-to-bring-autonomous-long-haul-trucks-to-north-america/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 14:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aurora Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous trucks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volvo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131887</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The autonomous vehicle startup Aurora Innovation said Tuesday it has reached an agreement with Volvo to jointly develop autonomous semi trucks for North America. The partnership, which the two companies say will span several years and is through Volvo&#8217;s Autonomous Solutions unit, will focus on trucks built to operate autonomously on highways between hubs for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The autonomous vehicle startup Aurora Innovation said Tuesday it has reached an agreement with Volvo to jointly develop autonomous semi trucks for North America.</p>
<p>The partnership, which the two companies say will span several years and is through Volvo&#8217;s Autonomous Solutions unit, will focus on trucks built to operate autonomously on highways between hubs for Volvo customers. The Aurora Driver technology stack – Aurora’s self-driving software, computer and sensor suite – will be integrated into Volvo trucks.</p>
<p>The announcement comes fresh on the heels of the startup’s recent <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/uber-sells-self-driving-unit-uber-atg-in-deal-that-will-push-auroras-valuation-to-10b/">acquisition of Uber’s self-driving subsidiary</a> and a separate deal with Toyota to develop self-driving minivans. Aurora now has partnerships with two of the three largest trucking manufacturers – Paccar and Volvo – that produce and sell nearly 50% of all Class 8 trucks in the country.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Our previously announced collaborations with partners such as PACCAR will continue in parallel to the collaboration with Volvo,” an Aurora spokesperson told TechCrunch. “As Paccar’s first self-driving technology partner, the unique nature of our partnership enables us to build Paccar’s first redundant truck that will be able to operate without a safety driver, bring it to market first, and deploy it broadly.&#8221;</p>
<p>Aurora said its Frequency Modulated Continuous Wave lidar  — through its acquisitions of companies Blackmore and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/aurora-acquires-a-second-lidar-company-in-push-to-bring-self-driving-trucks-to-the-road/">OURS Technology</a> — will be key to solving autonomous long-range trucking. Lidar, or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/12/wtf-is-lidar/">light detection and ranging radar</a>, is considered to be a necessary component of self-driving systems. Aurora&#8217;s pitch&#8217;s is that unlike traditional time-of-flight lidar, its technology provides the long-range visibility needed to be able to spot hazards with enough time to stop or slow down.</p>
<p>The announcement also marks a major acceleration for Volvo&#8217;s autonomous vehicle arm, Volvo Autonomous Solutions. It&#8217;s the business unit&#8217;s first deal to bring autonomous trucking to the road.</p>
<p>Since its founding in 2017, Aurora has rapidly become one of the leaders in self-driving tech, attracting backing from Amazon, Sequoia Capital and Greylock Partners. The company was founded by former executives of Uber, Tesla and Google.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/aurora-and-volvo-partner-to-bring-autonomous-long-haul-trucks-to-north-america/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131887</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>MobiKwik investigating data breach after 100M user records found online</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/mobikwik-investigating-data-breach-after-100m-user-records-found-online/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/mobikwik-investigating-data-breach-after-100m-user-records-found-online/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 14:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobikwik]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital India]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131867</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MobiKwik said on Tuesday it was investigating claims of data breach after a website claimed to have exposed private information of nearly 100 million users of the Indian mobile payments startup. Over the weekend, a site on the dark web claimed it had 8.2 terabytes of MobiKwik user data. The data included phone numbers, email [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">MobiKwik said on Tuesday it was investigating claims of data breach after a website claimed to have exposed private information of nearly 100 million users of the Indian <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/03/mobikwik-ebidta-positive/">mobile payments startup</a>.</p>
<p>Over the weekend, a site on the dark web claimed it had 8.2 terabytes of MobiKwik user data. The data included phone numbers, email addresses, scrambled passwords, transactions logs, and partial payment card numbers.</p>
<p>The website also claimed that it had &#8220;know your customer&#8221; (KYA) documents of 3.5 million users, and each visit to the website displayed four random images from the data dump. KYC documents are required in India for users who want to access certain services without any limitations. Local law requires a mobile wallet firm in India, for instance, to support monthly transactions exceeding a certain limit.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The dark web site features a searchable database that allows users to look up their phone number or email to verify the authenticity of the data breach claim. TechCrunch was able to verify the accuracy of the data in several cases.</p>
<p>A seller on a well-known cybercrime forum claims to be selling access to the database for 1.2 bitcoin — about $70,000.</p>
<p>The Sequoia Capital India-backed startup says it can&#8217;t yet prove if the data actually belongs to MobiKwik users. “It is incorrect to suggest that the data available on the darkweb has been accessed from MobiKwik or any identified source,” the startup <a href="https://blog.mobikwik.com/message-from-the-company/">wrote in a blog post</a>.</p>
<p>Rajshekhar Rajaharia, a security researcher, told TechCrunch that he alerted MobiKwik about this alleged security breach last month. In a statement, MobiKwik said the company had conducted a thorough investigation and did not find any evidence of a breach.</p>
<p>However, a screenshot leaked to TechCrunch shows a MobiKwik official asking an Amazon representative last month for logs relating to its cloud service after the startup &#8220;came to know that our S3 [cloud storage] data is downloaded by some other person outside the organization.&#8221;</p>
<p>The startup said its legal team will take “strict action against the so-called security researcher.” Rajaharia told TechCrunch that it’s his right as a user to know if his financial data is safe and that he doesn’t have the resources to fight legal battles.</p>
<p>MobiKwik said it was closely working with authorities and was confident that security protocols to store sensitive data are “robust and have not been breached.” It added that it was getting a third-party to conduct a forensic data security audit. &#8220;We are committed to a safe and secure Digital India.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/mobikwik-investigating-data-breach-after-100m-user-records-found-online/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131867</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Capitolis lands a16z-led $90M Series C for fintech SaaS platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/capitolis-lands-a16z-led-90m-series-c-for-fintech-saas-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/capitolis-lands-a16z-led-90m-series-c-for-fintech-saas-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 14:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[a16z]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131912</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Capitolis, which makes technology for capital markets players such as investment and merchant banks, has closed on a $90 million Series C funding round led by Andreessen Horowitz (a16z). The financing included participation from existing backers Index Ventures, Sequoia Capital, S Capital, Spark Capital, SVB Capital, Citi, J.P. Morgan and State Street and brings Capitolis’ [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://www.capitolis.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Capitolis</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">which makes technology for capital markets players such as investment and merchant banks, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">has closed on a $90 million Series C funding round led by Andreessen Horowitz (a16z).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The financing included participation from existing backers Index Ventures, Sequoia Capital, S Capital, Spark Capital, SVB Capital, Citi, J.P. Morgan and State Street and brings Capitolis’ total funding to date to $170 million. SVB Capital and Spark Capital co-led a $40 million Series B for the company in November 2019.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Capitolis CEO and founder Gil Mandelzis said the company’s mission since its 2017 inception has been to “fundamentally re-imagine how the capital markets operate&#8221;</span> after the last financial crisis and the &#8220;bold steps taken by regulators&#8221; in its aftermath.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup says that its <span style="font-weight: 400;">advanced workflow technology and proprietary algorithms</span> allows banks, hedge funds and asset managers to eliminate, move or create trading positions by collaborating with other financial institutions. <span style="font-weight: 400;">That results in freed up capital, open credit lines and access to capital from a bigger pool of sources, the company claims.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ultimately, Capitolis&#8217; network software is designed to help financial institutions optimize their balance sheets and reduce risk.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Seventy-five financial institutions currently use the Capitolis platform, according to the company’s website. The company says it grew its revenue run rate by &#8220;sixfold&#8221; in 2020. Since 2019, Capitolis has experienced a 230% increase in the number of users of its platform. To date, Capitolis says it has optimized $9 trillion in terms of gross notional balances.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hpyNFzkKNR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/19/ai-fintech-products-are-operating-at-scale-and-investor-interest-is-maturing/">AI fintech products are operating at scale and investor interest is maturing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;AI fintech products are operating at scale and investor interest is maturing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/19/ai-fintech-products-are-operating-at-scale-and-investor-interest-is-maturing/embed/#?secret=hpyNFzkKNR" data-secret="hpyNFzkKNR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alex Rampell, partner at a16z, said that his firm believes that what sets Capitolis apart from other financial services players “is the sheer scale of management’s ambition and the substantial talent, technology and capital milestones they have achieved.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The New York-based company says it plans to use its new capital toward product development and to boost its customer support and sales staff. It plans to increase its headcount from 90 today to over 150 by year’s end.</span></p>
<p>Capitolis currently covers foreign exchange products and equity swaps. It says it could expand into others if there is client demand.</p>
<p><em>This article was updated post-publication with additional information from the company</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/capitolis-lands-a16z-led-90m-series-c-for-fintech-saas-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131912</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google spinoff Cartken and REEF Technology launch Miami&#8217;s first delivery robots</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/google-spinoff-cartken-and-reef-technologies-launch-miamis-first-delivery-robots/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/google-spinoff-cartken-and-reef-technologies-launch-miamis-first-delivery-robots/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlanta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cartken]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief technology officer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dallas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[driver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fleet management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grubhub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miami]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postmates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reef Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving car]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131666</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Self-driving and robotics startup Cartken has partnered with REEF Technology, a startup that operates parking lots and neighborhood hubs, to bring self-driving delivery robots to the streets of downtown Miami. With this announcement, Cartken officially comes out of stealth mode. The company, founded by ex-Google engineers and colleagues behind the unrequited Bookbot, was formed to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Self-driving and robotics startup Cartken has partnered with REEF Technology, a startup that operates parking lots and neighborhood hubs, to bring self-driving delivery robots to the streets of downtown Miami.</p>
<p>With this announcement, Cartken officially comes out of stealth mode. The company, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/11/the-engineers-behind-googles-bookbot-have-launched-a-delivery-robot-startup/">founded by ex-Google engineers and colleagues behind the unrequited Bookbot</a>, was formed to develop market-ready tech in self-driving, AI-powered robotics and delivery operations in 2019, but the team has kept operations under wraps until now. This is Cartken&#8217;s first large deployment of self-driving robots on sidewalks.</p>
<p>After a few test months, the REEF-branded electric-powered robots are now delivering dinner orders from REEF&#8217;s network of delivery-only kitchens to people located within a 3/4-mile radius in downtown Miami. The robots, which are insulated and thus can preserve the heat of a plate of spaghetti or other hot food, are pre-stationed at designated logistics hubs and dispatched with orders for delivery as the food is prepared.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We want to show how future-forward Miami can be,&#8221; Matt Lindenberger, REEF&#8217;s chief technology officer, told TechCrunch. &#8220;This is a great chance to show off the capabilities of the tech. The combination of us having a big presence in Miami, the fact that there are a lot of challenges around congestion as Covid subsides, still shows a really good environment where we can show how this tech can work.&#8221;</p>
<p>Lindenberg said Miami is a great place to start, but it&#8217;s just the beginning, with potential for the Cartken robots to be used for REEF&#8217;s other last-mile delivery businesses. Currently, only two restaurant delivery robots are operating in Miami, but Lindenberger said the company is planning to expand further into the city and outward into Fort Lauderdale, as well as other large metros the company operates in, such as Dallas, Atlanta, Los Angeles and eventually New York.</p>
<p>Lindenberger is hoping the presence of robots in the streets can act as a &#8220;force multiplier&#8221; allowing them to scale while maintaining quality of service in a cost-effective way.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re seeing an explosion in deliveries right now in a post-pandemic world and we foresee that to continue, so these types of no-contact, zero-emission automation techniques are really critical,&#8221; he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TqGiLbVMaq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/03/starship-technologies-ceo-lex-bayer-on-focus-and-opportunity-in-autonomous-delivery/">Starship Technologies CEO Lex Bayer on focus and opportunity in autonomous delivery</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Starship Technologies CEO Lex Bayer on focus and opportunity in autonomous delivery&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/03/starship-technologies-ceo-lex-bayer-on-focus-and-opportunity-in-autonomous-delivery/embed/#?secret=TqGiLbVMaq" data-secret="TqGiLbVMaq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Cartken&#8217;s robots are powered by a combination of machine learning and rules-based programming to react to every situation that could occur, even if that just means safely stopping and asking for help, Christian Bersch, CEO of Cartken, told TechCrunch. REEF would have supervisors on site to remotely control the robot if needed, a caveat that was included in the<a href="https://www.flsenate.gov/Session/Bill/2017/1027/BillText/er/PDF"> 2017 legislation that allowed for the operation of self-driving delivery robots in Florida</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;The technology at the end of the day is very similar to that of a self-driving car,&#8221; said Bersch. &#8220;The robot is seeing the environment, planning around obstacles like pedestrians or lampposts. If there&#8217;s an unknown situation, someone can help the robot out safely because it can stop on a dime. But it&#8217;s important to also have that level of autonomy on the robot because it can react in a split second, faster than anybody remotely could, if something happens like someone jumps in front of it.&#8221;</p>
<p>REEF marks specific operating areas on the map for the robots and Cartken tweaks the configuration for the city, accounting for specific situations a robot might need to deal with, so that when the robots are given a delivery address, they can make moves and operate like any other delivery driver. Only this driver has an LTE connection and is constantly updating its location so REEF can integrate it into its fleet management capabilities.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2131862" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/reef-cartken-1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2131862" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2131862" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/reef-cartken-1.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="771" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/reef-cartken-1.jpg 4480w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/reef-cartken-1.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/reef-cartken-1.jpg?resize=300,226 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/reef-cartken-1.jpg?resize=768,578 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/reef-cartken-1.jpg?resize=680,512 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/reef-cartken-1.jpg?resize=1536,1157 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/reef-cartken-1.jpg?resize=2048,1542 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/reef-cartken-1.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2131862" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> REEF/Cartken</p></div></p>
<p>Eventually, Lindenberger said, they&#8217;re hoping to be able to offer the option for customers to choose robot delivery on the major food delivery platforms REEF works with like P<span style="font-weight: 400;">ostmates, UberEats, DoorDash or GrubHub. Customers would receive a text when the robot arrives so they could go outside and meet it. However, the tech is not quite there yet.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Currently the robots only make it street-level, and then the food is passed off to a human who delivers it directly to the door, which is a service that most customers prefer. Navigating into an apartment complex and to a customer&#8217;s unit is difficult for a robot to manage just yet, and many customers aren&#8217;t quite ready to interact directly with a robot. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s an interim step, but this was a path for us to move forward quickly with the technology without having any other boundaries,&#8221; said Lindenberger. &#8220;Like with any new tech, you want to take it in steps. So a super important step which we&#8217;ve now taken and works very well is the ability to dispatch robots within a certain radius and know that they&#8217;re going to arrive there. That in and of itself is a huge step and it allows us to learn what kind of challenges you have in terms of that very last step. Then we can begin to work with Cartken to solve that last piece. It&#8217;s a big step just being able to do this automation.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/google-spinoff-cartken-and-reef-technologies-launch-miamis-first-delivery-robots/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131666</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Substack really worth $650M?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/is-substack-really-worth-650m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/is-substack-really-worth-650m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 13:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[a16z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC News Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Substack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131790</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Substack didn't invent the paid newsletter, but the startup's early success with the model is enticing previous backers to more than double down on the media startup.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Substack didn&#8217;t invent the paid newsletter, but the startup&#8217;s early success with the model is enticing previous backers to more than double down on the media startup.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a>, or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>Last evening, <a href="https://www.axios.com/substack-andreessen-horowitz-newsletter-36cb98ea-a7b3-43b1-883a-fa45586eaad4.html">Axios reported</a> that Substack is &#8220;raising $65 million in new venture capital&#8221; at a valuation of &#8220;around $650 million.&#8221; As you&#8217;ve already guessed, Axios goes on to report that Andreessen Horowitz (a16z) will likely lead the investment.</p>
<p>That we&#8217;re seeing a16z pour more capital into what we could call the alt-media space is not a surprise. The investing group is ladling <a href="https://a16z.com/2021/01/25/doubling-down-marketing-update-new-media/">even more cash</a> into its in-house media efforts and has put a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/24/clubhouse-announces-plans-for-creator-payments-and-raises-new-funding-led-by-andreessen-horowitz/">small archipelago of capital</a> into audio-based social media app Clubhouse. Its internal publishing schedule is in part an attempt to <a href="https://imgur.com/a/SMFL4US">get around traditional media</a>; the Clubhouse universe is an inverted one in which tech investors are celebrities, producers and gatekeepers. And Substack is a place where publications have bled some well-known talent, shifting the center of gravity in media.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995210 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />You can detect the theme.</p>
<p>Regardless, Substack&#8217;s new valuation and investment are eye-catching. This morning, I want to collect all that we can regarding Substack&#8217;s historical growth so that we can chew on its new valuation from the best vantage point. Let&#8217;s go!</p>
<h2> $650 million?</h2>
<p>A little history to kick us off. Crunchbase <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/substack/company_financials">counts</a> Substack&#8217;s total funding to date at $17.4 million. <a href="http://pitchbook.com">PitchBook</a> puts the number at $21.21 million, inclusive of debt. Both sources agree that the company&#8217;s most recent round came in July 2019. PitchBook pegs the company&#8217;s valuation at $48.65 million at that date.</p>
<p>Raising $17 million in cash around 20 months ago, regardless of debt, is an amount of capital that the company could easily have burned through by now. Raising more funds is therefore not a surprise.</p>
<p>But the size of the new round is notable, as is its constituent valuation. Series A and B rounds have been <a href="https://files.pitchbook.com/website/files/pdf/Q4_2020_PitchBook_NVCA_Venture_Monitor.pdf">growing in size</a> in recent years. But a $65 million Series B would stand out, even by 2021 standards. Not shockingly so, but enough that any company raising that sum at its implied level of maturity would demand our attention. That we&#8217;re all familiar with Substack only makes the sum more curious.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/is-substack-really-worth-650m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131790</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PayPal&#8217;s new feature allows U.S. consumers to check out using cryptocurrency</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/paypals-new-feature-allows-u-s-consumers-to-check-out-using-cryptocurrency/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/paypals-new-feature-allows-u-s-consumers-to-check-out-using-cryptocurrency/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 13:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dan Schulman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Litecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131857</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PayPal this morning announced the launch of Checkout with Crypto, a new feature that will allow consumers to check out at millions of online businesses using cryptocurrency. The feature expands on PayPal&#8217;s current investments in the cryptocurrency market, which include its partnership with Paxos to power its service that allows customers to buy, sell and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">PayPal this morning <a href="https://newsroom.paypal-corp.com/2021-03-30-PayPal-Launches-Checkout-with-Crypto">announced</a> the launch of Checkout with Crypto, a new feature that will allow consumers to check out at millions of online businesses using cryptocurrency. The feature expands on PayPal&#8217;s current investments in the cryptocurrency market, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/paypal-says-all-users-in-u-s-can-now-buy-hold-and-sell-cryptocurrencies/">include its partnership</a> with <a href="https://www.paxos.com/">Paxos</a> to power its service that allows customers to buy, sell and hold a range of cryptocurrencies, and more recently, its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/paypal-to-acquire-cryptocurrency-custody-startup-curv/">acquisition</a> of cryptocurrency security startup Curv.</p>
<p>According to PayPal, customers with cryptocurrency holdings in the U.S. will be able to check out using their cryptocurrency at millions of businesses. The company plans to expand the service to reach PayPal&#8217;s 29 million global online businesses in months ahead. The feature will also work without any additional integrations or fees required by the businesses themselves.</p>
<p>Essentially, Checkout with Crypto allows the customers to sell their cryptocurrency through PayPal at the time of checkout, then settle the actual transaction in U.S. dollars. For the businesses, that means nothing really changes on their end &#8212; they&#8217;re still being paid in USD, not cryptocurrency. But PayPal&#8217;s feature makes it possible for this transaction to take place within the same checkout flow, making it easier on shoppers to quickly make their purchases using cryptocurrency.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>At launch, the service will support Bitcoin, Litecoin, Ethereum and Bitcoin Cash &#8212; but only one type of cryptocurrency can be used for each purchase.</p>
<p>If the customer has enough cryptocurrency to pay for their online purchase, then the Checkout with Crypto feature will appear, alongside other traditional payment methods, like the customer&#8217;s bank account, PayPal balance, or credit or debit card. Like other payment methods, Checkout with Crypto will also include PayPal&#8217;s safety and security benefits, including fraud protection, return shipping and purchase protection on eligible items, PayPal notes.</p>
<p>After the transaction completes, the customer will receive both a record of the cryptocurrency sale, as well as their purchase receipt.</p>
<p>The company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/paypal-says-all-users-in-u-s-can-now-buy-hold-and-sell-cryptocurrencies/">had announced its plans</a> to launch support for checkout with cryptocurrency last year, when it first entered the cryptocurrency market. It said that after providing support for buying and selling cryptocurrencies, it would launch a checkout feature in 2021.</p>
<p>Today, PayPal makes makes money by <a href="https://www.paypal.com/en/webapps/mpp/paypal-fees">charging transaction fees</a> when customers buy or sell their cryptocurrencies, which is why it&#8217;s not placing any fees on their merchants themselves.</p>
<p>PayPal&#8217;s launch will help to dramatically expand the number of places where cryptocurrency can be used for real-world purchases, which could help accelerate mainstream adoption of digital currencies.</p>
<p>According to Jim Magats, PayPal SVP, Omni Payments, it&#8217;s historically been difficult for businesses to offer cryptocurrency as a payment option due to integration requirements, technical barriers, and general lack of awareness among consumers.</p>
<p>&#8220;Checkout with Crypto allows businesses to accept the proceeds from sales of cryptocurrency as a payment type, all within the current PayPal integration, removing the need for any additional action for businesses,&#8221; Magats said. &#8220;PayPal handles the crypto sale and conversion with the consumer and passes on U.S. dollars to the business for the purchase, streamlining the process for businesses.&#8221;</p>
<p>PayPal&#8217;s move comes shortly after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/elon-musk-declares-you-can-now-buy-a-tesla-with-bitcoin-in-the-u-s/">last week&#8217;s announcement from Tesla</a>, which said U.S. customers could now buy a car using bitcoin, and Japanese e-commerce giant <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/e-commerce-giant-rakuten-now-lets-users-shop-with-cryptocurrency">Rakuten&#8217;s news earlier this month</a> where it said users could check out with online merchants in Japan using cryptocurrencies.</p>
<p>&#8220;As the use of digital payments and digital currencies accelerates, the introduction of Checkout with Crypto continues our focus on driving mainstream adoption of cryptocurrencies, while continuing to offer PayPal customers choice and flexibility in the ways they can pay using the PayPal wallet,&#8221; President and CEO Dan Schulman said, in a statement about the launch. &#8220;Enabling cryptocurrencies to make purchases at businesses around the world is the next chapter in driving the ubiquity and mass acceptance of digital currencies,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/EAysfZiO3Ys?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/paypals-new-feature-allows-u-s-consumers-to-check-out-using-cryptocurrency/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131857</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NBA Top Shot maker Dapper Labs is now worth $2.6 billion thanks to half of Hollywood, the NBA, and Michael Jordan</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/nba-top-shot-maker-dapper-labs-is-now-worth-2-6-billion-thanks-to-half-of-hollywood-the-nba-and-michael-jordan/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/nba-top-shot-maker-dapper-labs-is-now-worth-2-6-billion-thanks-to-half-of-hollywood-the-nba-and-michael-jordan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 13:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andre Iguodala]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ashton kutcher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coatue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dapper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dapper Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kevin Durant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lebron james]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michael jordan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mlb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national basketball association]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Football League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nfl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Chernin Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thirty Five Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ubisoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venrock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Version One]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vivek ranadive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warner media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Warner-Music-Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Will Smith]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131869</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From the early success of Crypto Kitties to the explosive growth of NBA Top Shot, Dapper Labs has been at the forefront of the cryptocurrency collectible craze known as NFTs. Now the company is reaping the benefits of its trailblazing status with a new $305 million financing led by some of the biggest names in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="note-details">
<p id="speakable-summary">From the early success of Crypto Kitties to the explosive growth of NBA Top Shot, <a href="https://www.dapperlabs.com/">Dapper Labs</a> has been at the forefront of the cryptocurrency collectible craze known as NFTs.</p>
<p>Now the company is reaping the benefits of its trailblazing status with a new $305 million financing led by some of the biggest names in Hollywood, sports, and investing.</p>
<p>The new round values the company at a whopping $2.6 billion, according to multiple media reports, and comes at a time when NFTs<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mrNOYudaMAc"> have captured the popular imagination</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/mrNOYudaMAc?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Leading the company&#8217;s financing was Coatue, the financial services firm that&#8217;s behind many of the biggest later stage tech deals. But heavy hitters from the entertainment world also took their cut &#8212; these are folks like NBA legend Michael Jordan as well as current players and funds including Kevin Durant, Andre Iguodala, Kyle Lowry, Spencer Dinwiddie, Andre Drummond, Alex Caruso, Michael Carter-Williams, Josh Hart, Udonis Haslem, JaVale McGee, Khris Middleton, Domantas Sabonis, Klay Thompson, Nikola Vucevic, Thad Young, and Richard Seymour’s 93 Ventures.</p>
<p>Entertainment and music heavyweights including Ashton Kutcher and Guy Oseary&#8217;s Sound Ventures, Will Smith and Keisuke Honda&#8217;s Dreamers VC, Shawn Mendes and Andrew Gertler&#8217;s AG Ventures, Shay Mitchell, and 2 Chainz also bought in on the action.</p>
<p>And from the venture world comes other strategic investors like Andreessen Horowitz, The Chernin Group, USV, Version One, and Venrock.</p>
<p>The company said it would use the funds to continue building out NBA Top Shot and expanding the updated digital trading card platform to other sports and a broader creator community.</p>
<p>Top Shot has already notched over $500 million in sales for its animated trading cards featuring things like LeBron James dunking and the sky (at least for now) is seemingly the limit for the collectible applications of blockchain.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s like the one thing that cryptocurrency can do really well and it&#8217;s been embraced far beyond the world of sports collectibles. The recent $69 million sale of a digital piece of art at Christies <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/beeples-69-million-nft-sale-marks-a-potentially-transformative-moment-for-the-art-world/">also marks a watershed moment for art world</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hHNTAXkZND"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/beeples-69-million-nft-sale-marks-a-potentially-transformative-moment-for-the-art-world/">Beeple&#8217;s $69 million NFT sale marks a potentially transformative moment for the art world</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Beeple&#8217;s $69 million NFT sale marks a potentially transformative moment for the art world&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/beeples-69-million-nft-sale-marks-a-potentially-transformative-moment-for-the-art-world/embed/#?secret=hHNTAXkZND" data-secret="hHNTAXkZND" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“NBA Top Shot is successful because it taps into basketball fandom – it’s a new and more exciting way for people to connect with their favorite teams and players,” said Roham Gharegozlou, CEO of Dapper Labs. “We want to bring the same magic to other sports leagues as well as help other entertainment studios and independent creators find their own approaches in exploring open platforms. NFTs unlock a new model for monetization that benefits the fans much more than advertising or sponsorships.”</p>
<p>Powering the Top Shot system and Dapper Labs&#8217; other offerings is a new blockchain protocol called Flow, which purports to handle mainstream consumer applications at scale, and can support mass adoption.</p>
<p>Flow also allows for transactions using fiat currency and credit cards in addition to provide a much needed ease of cryptocurrency, and can keep customers safe from the fraud or theft common in cryptocurrency systems, according to a statement from Dapper Labs.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kTXTNU20Dc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/the-nft-market-is-just-getting-started-but-where-is-it-headed/">The NFT market is just getting started, but where is it headed?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The NFT market is just getting started, but where is it headed?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/the-nft-market-is-just-getting-started-but-where-is-it-headed/embed/#?secret=kTXTNU20Dc" data-secret="kTXTNU20Dc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Flow enables NFT marketplaces and other decentralized applications that need to scale to handle mainstream demand without extremely high transaction costs (“gas fees”) or environmental concerns, the company said.</p>
<p>“NBA Top Shot is one of the best demonstrations we’ve seen of how quickly new technology can change the landscape for media and sports fans,” said Kevin Durant, Co-Founder of Thirty Five Ventures. &#8220;We&#8217;re excited to follow the progress with everything happening on Flow blockchain and use our platform with the Boardroom to connect with fans in a new way.&#8221;</p>
<p>Already companies like Warner Music Group, Ubisoft, Warner Media, and the UFC, as well as thousands of third party developers, artists, and other creators are using the Flow mainnet to sell collectible cards, and develop custodial wallets.</p>
<p>Additional investors in the round include: MLB players like Tim Beckham and Nolan Arenado; NFL players: Ken Crawley, Thomas Davis, Stefon Diggs, Dee Ford, Malcom Jenkins, Rodney McLeod, Jordan Matthew, Devin McCourty, Jason McCourty, DK Metcalf, Tyrod Taylor, and Trent Williams; team ownership including Vivek Ranadive (Kings), and notable sports investors Bolt Ventures.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wOrWwHoyCB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/22/nfts-could-bridge-video-games-and-the-fashion-industry/">NFTs could bridge video games and the fashion industry</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;NFTs could bridge video games and the fashion industry&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/22/nfts-could-bridge-video-games-and-the-fashion-industry/embed/#?secret=wOrWwHoyCB" data-secret="wOrWwHoyCB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/nba-top-shot-maker-dapper-labs-is-now-worth-2-6-billion-thanks-to-half-of-hollywood-the-nba-and-michael-jordan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131869</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Slice is launching a point-of-sale system for pizzerias</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/slice-is-launching-a-point-of-sale-system-for-pizzerias/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/slice-is-launching-a-point-of-sale-system-for-pizzerias/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 13:42:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pizza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131830</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Slice, the online ordering platform for independent pizzerias, announced two new offerings this morning — a point-of-sale system designed specifically for those businesses, as well as a rewards program for diners. The launch of the new Slice Register builds on last year&#8217;s acquisition of point-of-sale company Instore, and the appointment of its CEO Matt Niehaus [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://slicelife.com">Slice</a>, the online ordering platform for independent pizzerias, announced two new offerings this morning — a point-of-sale system designed specifically for those businesses, as well as a rewards program for diners.</p>
<p>The launch of the new <a href="https://register.slicelife.com">Slice Register</a> builds on last year&#8217;s acquisition of point-of-sale company Instore, and <a href="https://blog.slicelife.com/slice-welcomes-matt-niehaus-svp-payments/">the appointment of its CEO Matt Niehaus</a> as Slice&#8217;s senior vice president for payments.</p>
<p>Pizzerias might seem to be a narrow focus for a point-of-sale system, particularly given all the other POS products out there, but Niehaus suggested that many of the 15,000 pizzerias in Slice&#8217;s network are still relying on cash registers and pen-and-paper: &#8220;If you run a pizzeria, you are certainly great at making pizza, but you are typically less comfortable with the accounting side.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He also said that existing POS systems aren&#8217;t really designed for the needs and workflows of a pizzeria. Slice founder and CEO Ilir Sela added that most of them were designed for offline ordering first, with online support added later. And Niehaus suggested that the average local pizzeria is only seeing 19% of their orders coming from online sources (compared to 75% for the average Domino&#8217;s location), that&#8217;s a real problem.</p>
<p>&#8220;Domino&#8217;s is really the competition, not the POS companies,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2131877" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2131877" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2131877" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Slice-Register.jpg?w=680" alt="Slice Register" width="680" height="459" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Slice-Register.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Slice-Register.jpg?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Slice-Register.jpg?resize=300,203 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Slice-Register.jpg?resize=768,518 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Slice-Register.jpg?resize=680,459 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Slice-Register.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2131877" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Slice</p></div></p>
<p>So the Slice Register is a combined software and hardware (including an iPad) solution. Naturally, it integrates with Slice&#8217;s online ordering and also includes support for email and mobile marketing, as well as a consolidated view of each customer. Niehaus said that among other things, it&#8217;s designed to &#8220;grab those customers on one platform and nudge them online.&#8221;</p>
<p>Slice Register is available to pizzerias at no initial charge for the hardware or software. The only fee in 2021 will be for payment processing, with additional pricing announced coming next year.</p>
<p>As for the new Slice Rewards program, diners who order pizzas through Slice will get a free large cheese pizza for every eight orders of $15 or more. (Slice, not the restaurant, is paying for the free pizza.) Sela described this as a &#8220;very Domino&#8217;s-like program,&#8221; except that it works across independent pizzerias.</p>
<p>&#8220;What we’re learning the local consumer has up to four local favorites, and they love all of these locations equally,&#8221; he said. &#8220;What we think is really cool is, you&#8217;re going to get rewarded for buying at all four of your local favorites.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Igz09LKSQn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/12/slice-series-c/">Slice, an online ordering and marketing platform for pizzerias, raises $43M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Slice, an online ordering and marketing platform for pizzerias, raises $43M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/12/slice-series-c/embed/#?secret=Igz09LKSQn" data-secret="Igz09LKSQn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/slice-is-launching-a-point-of-sale-system-for-pizzerias/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131830</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spotify is getting into live audio because of course it is</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/spotify-is-getting-into-live-audio-because-of-course-it-is/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/spotify-is-getting-into-live-audio-because-of-course-it-is/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 13:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131832</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shares of Spotify are up a fraction this morning after the company announced that it will acquire Betty Labs, the company behind the Locker Room, which focuses on live audio. Prior to the deal, Betty Labs had raised more than $9 million, per Crunchbase data. Spotify is best known for its music streaming business, but [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Shares of Spotify are up a fraction this morning after the company <a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2021-03-30/spotify-acquires-locker-room-and-announces-plans-for-a-new-live-audio-experience/">announced</a> that it will acquire <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/betty-labs">Betty Labs</a>, the company behind the Locker Room, which focuses on live audio. Prior to the deal, Betty Labs had raised more than $9 million, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/betty-labs">per Crunchbase data</a>.</p>
<p>Spotify is best known for its music streaming business, but has expanded into new audio formats while hunting for both a competitive edge in its core market, and methods of generating pricing leverage.</p>
<p>The European tech giant has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/06/why-spotify-is-betting-big-on-podcasting/">spent heavily in recent years</a> on its podcast efforts, bringing marquee shows to its platform on an exclusive basis. By making its own audio-world as differentiated as possible, Spotify may be able to charge more over time, creating future growth opportunities.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Swedish public company was not shy in describing its goals for the Betty Labs deal, writing on its own blog that it will &#8220;evolve and expand Locker Room into an enhanced live audio experience for a wider range of creators and fans,&#8221; with forthcoming content including &#8220;a range of sports, music, and cultural programming, as well as a host of interactive features that enable creators to connect with audiences in real time.&#8221;</p>
<p>A mix of radio and Clubhouse, perhaps? TechCrunch will tinker with the tech when possible, as we have in recent weeks with Clubhouse and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/twitter-spaces-arrives-on-android-ahead-of-clubhouse/">Twitter&#8217;s equivalent product, Spaces</a>.</p>
<p>Clubhouse, which helped boost the present-day audio craze to new heights, has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/24/clubhouse-announces-plans-for-creator-payments-and-raises-new-funding-led-by-andreessen-horowitz/">attracted heavyweight backers</a> and a good number of early fans. But the app has also seen its audience level off in recent weeks (<a href="https://www.appannie.com/">AppAnnie data</a>), perhaps leaving room in the market for Spotify or another audio incumbent to step in and steal its thunder.</p>
<p>Spotify has a history of entering new audio categories and taking over. As <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/spotify-podcast-listeners-to-top-apples-for-the-first-time-in-2021-forecast-claims/#:~:text=Podcast%20listeners%20will%20also%20account,benefit%20Spotify%20at%20Apple's%20expense.">TechCrunch reported</a> earlier this month, &#8220;Spotify’s U.S. podcast listenership will surpass Apple Podcasts for the first time this year when 28.2 million U.S. users will listen to podcasts on Spotify at least monthly, compared with 28.0 million via Apple Podcasts,&#8221; <a href="https://www.emarketer.com/content/spotify-podcast-listener-numbers-will-surpass-apples-this-year">per data from eMarketer</a>.</p>
<p>Sure, it wasn&#8217;t cheap, but Spotify wants to lead all audio categories it appears, so its planned move into Clubhouse territory should worry current startups in the space.</p>
<p>If Spotify&#8217;s distribution advantage of working on every platform, and having a huge install base, will work in its efforts to own a new slice of the audio world is something we&#8217;ll find out this year. Until then, if you have an iOS device, you can still use Clubhouse.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/spotify-is-getting-into-live-audio-because-of-course-it-is/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131832</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple&#8217;s WWDC stays online-only, kicking off June 7</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/apples-wwdc-stays-online-only-kicking-off-june-7/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/apples-wwdc-stays-online-only-kicking-off-june-7/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 13:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wwdc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131836</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple this morning announced that it will be returning to an all-virtual format for a second year. The company went online-only for the first time in 2020, as Covid-19 ground in-person events to a halt. While vaccine rollouts have begun in much of the world, the return of the in-person event industry still seems iffy [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple this morning announced that it will be returning to an all-virtual format for a second year. The company went online-only for the first time in 2020, as Covid-19 ground in-person events to a halt. While vaccine rollouts have begun in much of the world, the return of the in-person event industry still seems iffy for most of the rest of the year. The event will run June 7-11.</p>
<p>“We are working to make WWDC21 our biggest and best yet, and are excited to offer Apple developers new tools to support them as they create apps that change the way we live, work, and play,” Developer Relations VP Susan Prescott said in a <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/03/apples-worldwide-developers-conference-is-back-in-its-all-online-format/">release tied to the news</a>.</p>
<p>The virtual format certainly has its advantage &#8212; accessibility being at the top of the list. Apple said last year&#8217;s was its &#8220;biggest ever,&#8221; and expects roughly 28 million developers from around the world at this one. In addition to not having to deal with traveling &#8212; not to mention the South Bay hotel crunch &#8212; the company offers up free access to the event for all qualified developers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The event spans Apple&#8217;s different operating systems, bringing new versions of iOS/iPadOS, macOS, watchOS and tvOS. Last year also delivered the big, long awaited arrival of Apple&#8217;s transition to first-part silicon for its Macs. Hardware news has otherwise been fairly hit or miss at the event, but after a bottleneck in H1 2020, the company could have some surprises on the way on that front.</p>
<p>Along with the big keynote and a week&#8217;s worth of developer-themed programming, the company hosts events like the Swift Student Challenge, a competition focused on young coders. Apple notes that it will also being using the opportunity to donate $1 million to SJ Aspires, an education initiative based in San Jose, where the in-person event has been held in recent years.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7TWLfrxQp5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/22/live-from-apples-virtual-wwdc-2020/">Live from Apple&#8217;s virtual WWDC 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Live from Apple&#8217;s virtual WWDC 2020&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/22/live-from-apples-virtual-wwdc-2020/embed/#?secret=7TWLfrxQp5" data-secret="7TWLfrxQp5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/apples-wwdc-stays-online-only-kicking-off-june-7/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131836</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>6sense raises $125M at a $2.1B valuation for its &#8216;ID graph&#8217;, an AI-based predictive sales and marketing platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/6sense-raises-125m-at-a-2-1b-valuation-for-its-id-graph-an-ai-based-predictive-sales-and-marketing-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/6sense-raises-125m-at-a-2-1b-valuation-for-its-id-graph-an-ai-based-predictive-sales-and-marketing-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 13:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[6sense]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[predictive sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sales and Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131823</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[AI has become a fundamental cornerstone of how tech companies are building tools for salespeople: they are useful for supercharging (and complementing) the abilities of talented humans, or helping them keep themselves significantly more organised; even if in some cases &#8212; as with chatbots &#8212; they are replacing them altogether. In the latest development, 6sense, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">AI has become a fundamental cornerstone of how tech companies are building tools for salespeople: they are useful for supercharging (and complementing) the abilities of talented humans, or helping them keep themselves significantly more organised; even if in some cases &#8212; as with chatbots &#8212; they are replacing them altogether. In the latest development, <a href="https://6sense.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6sense</a>, one of the pioneers in using AI to boost the sales and marketing experience, is announcing a major round of funding that underscores the traction AI tools are seeing in the sales realm.</p>
<p>The startup has raised $125 million at a valuation of $2.1 billion, a Series D being led by D1 Capital Partners, with Sapphire Ventures, Tiger Global and previous backer Insight Partners also participating.</p>
<p>The company plans to use the funding to expand its platform and its predictive capabilities across a wider range of sources.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For some context, this is a huge jump for the company compared to its last fundraise: at the end of 2019, when it raised $40 million, it was valued at a mere $300 million, according to <a href="https://my.pitchbook.com/profile/63251-83/company/profile" target="_blank" rel="noopener">data from PitchBook.</a></p>
<p>But it&#8217;s not a big surprise: at a time when a lot of companies are going through &#8220;digital transformation&#8221; and investing in better tools for their employees to work more efficiently remotely (especially important for sales people who might have previously worked together in physical teams), 6sense is on track for its fourth year of more than 100% growth, adding 100 new customers in the fourth quarter alone. It caters to small, medium, and large businesses, and some of its customers include Dell, Mediafly, Sage and SocialChorus.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s approach speaks to a classic problem that AI tools are often tasked with solving: the data that sales people need to use and keep up to date on customer accounts, and critically targets, lives in a number of different silos &#8212; they can include CRM systems, or large databases outside of the company, or signals on social media.</p>
<p>While some tools are being built to handle all of that from the ground up, 6sense takes a different approach, providing a way of ingesting and utilizing all of it to get a complete picture of a company and the individuals a salesperson might want to target within it. It takes into account some of the harder nuts to crack in the market, such as how to track &#8220;anonymous buying behavior&#8221; to a more concrete customer name; how to prioritizes accounts according to those most likely to buy; and planning for multi-channel campaigns.</p>
<p>6sense has patented the technology it uses to achieve this and calls its approach building an &#8220;ID graph.&#8221; (Which you can think of as the sales equivalent of the social graph of Facebook, or the knowledge graph that LinkedIn has aimed to build mapping skills and jobs globally.) The key with 6sense is that it is building a set of tools that not just sales people can use, but marketers too &#8212; useful since the two sit much closer together at companies these days.</p>
<p>Jason Zintak, the company&#8217;s CEO (who worked for many years as a salesperson himself, so gets the pain points very well), referred to the approach and concept behind 6sense as &#8220;revtech&#8221;: aimed at organizations in the business whose work generates revenue for the company.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our AI is focused on signal, identifying companies that are in the market to buy something,&#8221; said Zintak in an interview. &#8220;Once you have that you can sell to them.&#8221;</p>
<p>That focus and traction with customers is one reason investors are interested.</p>
<p class="p1">“Customer conversations are a critical part of our due diligence process, and the feedback from 6sense customers is among the best we’ve heard,” said Dan Sundheim, founder and chief investment officer at D1 Capital Partners, in a statement. “Improving revenue results is a goal for every business, but it’s easier said than done. The way 6sense consistently creates value for customers made it clear that they deliver a unique, must-have solution for B2B revenue teams.”</p>
<p class="p1">Teddie Wardi at Insight highlights that AI and the predictive elements of 6sense&#8217;s technology &#8212; which have been a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/05/19/6sense-a-predictive-sales-intelligence-tool-exits-stealth-with-12m-led-by-battery-venrock/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">consistent</a> part of the product since it was founded &#8212; are what help it stand out.</p>
<p class="p1">&#8220;AI generally is a buzzword, but here it is a key part of the solution, the brand behind the platform,&#8221; he said in an interview. &#8220;Instead of having massive funnels, 6sense switches the whole thing around. Catching the right person at the right time and in the right context make sales and marketing more effective. And the AI piece is what really powers it. It uses signals to construct the buyer journey and tell the sales person when it is the right time to engage.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/6sense-raises-125m-at-a-2-1b-valuation-for-its-id-graph-an-ai-based-predictive-sales-and-marketing-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131823</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SpaceX flies 11th Starship prototype, but loses the spacecraft during the landing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/spacex-flies-11th-starship-prototype-but-loses-the-spacecraft-mid-flight/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/spacex-flies-11th-starship-prototype-but-loses-the-spacecraft-mid-flight/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 13:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[launch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prototype]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131818</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SpaceX conducted yet another high-altitude test flight of its Starship prototype spacecraft on Tuesday, the fourth of these so far. Like all the flight testing and construction of Starship prototypes, this one took off from SpaceX&#8217;s Boca Chica, Texas development facility – a location recently renamed &#8216;Starbase&#8217; by SpaceX CEO Elon Musk. Unfortunately, things didn&#8217;t [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">SpaceX conducted yet another high-altitude test flight of its Starship prototype spacecraft on Tuesday, the fourth of these so far. Like all the flight testing and construction of Starship prototypes, this one took off from SpaceX&#8217;s Boca Chica, Texas development facility – a location recently renamed &#8216;Starbase&#8217; by SpaceX CEO Elon Musk. Unfortunately, things didn&#8217;t go great for SpaceX — the SN11 prototype was lost during its final descent. Reports from the scene suggest a large explosion that scattered debris around the landing site.</p>
<p>At this point in the program, SpaceX&#8217;s aim is to fly Starship to a high altitude (roughly 32,000 &#8211; 40,000 feet), execute a &#8216;belly flop&#8217; maneuver and then bring it back to Earth with a controlled re-orientation to vertical, followed by a soft landing on its feet. Before today, SpaceX has made progress towards that goal, with the first two attempts exploding on a harder-than-landing impact, and the third landing vertically, before also exploding just under 10 minutes later after resting apparently secure before that.</p>
<p>SpaceX&#8217;s stated specific goals at this point are around testing is to gather data on the control flaps that Starship uses to control its orientation and prepare for that soft landing. SpaceX wants to study this with low altitude flights so that it has the data it needs to make it more likely to pull this off once it starts orbital flight testing later on.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Because of foggy conditions this AM in Texas at the launch site, SpaceX didn&#8217;t have great views of the flight test, and the company hasn&#8217;t yet revealed what went wrong during the mission, but will be investigating and sharing details later on. <strong>UPDATE: Musk now says there was an issue on the second engine used during the landing burn:</strong></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Looks like engine 2 had issues on ascent &amp; didn’t reach operating chamber pressure during landing burn, but, in theory, it wasn’t needed. </p>
<p>Something significant happened shortly after landing burn start. Should know what it was once we can examine the bits later today.</p>
<p>&mdash; Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1376891464333017090?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 30, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>SpaceX CEO Elon Musk tweeted this shortly after the incident:</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">At least the crater is in the right place!</p>
<p>&mdash; Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1376889786762428421?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 30, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/spacex-flies-11th-starship-prototype-but-loses-the-spacecraft-mid-flight/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131818</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Living Security raises $14M for predictive human risk management</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/living-security-raises-14m-for-predicitive-human-risk-management/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/living-security-raises-14m-for-predicitive-human-risk-management/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 13:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131646</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cybersecurity training is one of those things that everyone has to do but not something everyone necessarily looks forward to. Living Security is an Austin-based startup out to change cybersecurity training something you look forward to, not dread. And the company has just closed on a $14 million Series B to continue its expansion beyond [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cybersecurity training is one of those things that everyone has to do but not something everyone necessarily looks forward to.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Living Security is an Austin-based startup out to change cybersecurity training something you look forward to, not dread. And the company has just closed on a $14 million Series B to continue its expansion beyond cybersecurity awareness training into human risk management.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Washington, D.C. based-Updata Partners led the financing, which also included participation from existing backers previous investors Silverton Partners, Active Capital, Rain Capital and SaaS Venture Partners. The investment comes after $5 million series A, led by Austin-based Silverton, raised last April.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Husband and wife Drew and Ashley Rose founded Living Security out of their house in June 2017 with the mission of making cybersecurity training less boring and more effective via gamified learning with live action immersive storylines, role-based micro modules and reporting.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TBcHK7N97E"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/the-cybersecurity-industry-needs-to-reinvent-itself/">The cybersecurity industry needs to reinvent itself</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The cybersecurity industry needs to reinvent itself&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/the-cybersecurity-industry-needs-to-reinvent-itself/embed/#?secret=TBcHK7N97E" data-secret="TBcHK7N97E" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Living Security launched with its flagship product &#8212; Cyber Escape Room. When the pandemic hit, the startup brought its in-person training sessions online through the launch of </span><a href="https://www.livingsecurity.com/cyberescape-online"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CyberEscape Online</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With more people working remotely, the need for the type of offering Living Security provides has become even more paramount, considering how many people use personal devices for professional reasons, among other things. Employees are more vulnerable than ever to inadvertently providing entry points into the networks of the enterprises where they work &#8212; whether through social engineering, phishing or other methods.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, Living Security works with over 100 large enterprises to train their global workforces to better protect sensitive data and secure their organizations. The startup’s customer list is impressive, and includes large enterprises such as CVS Health, Mastercard, Verizon, MassMutual, Biogen, AmerisourceBergen, Hewlett Packard, JPMorgan and Target.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So it’s not a big surprise that in 2020, Living Security tripled its revenue and employee headcount and more than doubled its customer count. The company declined to provide hard revenue figures, saying only that ARR grew nearly 200% last year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We have seen a significant increase in account growth and expansion in existing accounts..largely in part due to the scalability of our digital solution,” CEO Ashley Rose said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With the success of its escape rooms and gamified training, Living Security’s team then asked themselves how they could make their efforts “more predictable.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We added risk management and scoring so program and security owners could become more targeted and focused on the delivery of their training,” Rose said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So now Living Security aims to use behavioral data and analytics </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">to measure and manage human risk. It plans to take that data and provide “predictive interventions” to employees. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re focused on &#8216;How do we turn people from our greatest risk, to our greatest assets in cybersecurity?&#8221; Rose said. “That’s our big vision for the company.”</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2131652" style="width: 655px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2131652" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2131652" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Human-Risk-Management-screenshot-1.png?w=288" alt="" width="645" height="672" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Human-Risk-Management-screenshot-1.png 4170w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Human-Risk-Management-screenshot-1.png?resize=144,150 144w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Human-Risk-Management-screenshot-1.png?resize=288,300 288w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Human-Risk-Management-screenshot-1.png?resize=768,801 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Human-Risk-Management-screenshot-1.png?resize=652,680 652w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Human-Risk-Management-screenshot-1.png?resize=1472,1536 1472w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Human-Risk-Management-screenshot-1.png?resize=1963,2048 1963w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Human-Risk-Management-screenshot-1.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Human-Risk-Management-screenshot-1.png?resize=48,50 48w" sizes="(max-width: 645px) 100vw, 645px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2131652" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Living Security</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With its “Unify” human risk management platform, Living Security wants to provide an even more scalable solution. The company also plans to use its new capital toward expanding its geographic reach and scaling both direct and channel sales efforts.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Currently, Living Security has 55 employees with the goal of having 90 by year’s end.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Deb Walter, director of information security training and awareness at AmerisourceBergen, said she first engaged with Living Security in 2017 when she requested its </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">CyberSecurity Card game. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I wanted to gamify how I presented training,” she recalls.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Introducing episodic gamification and its “bingeable” content into her training program was a big hit with employees, according to Walter.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;Their new platform is enabling us to deploy an &#8216;Information security academy&#8217; to encourage associates and contractors to use several modes of training to earn points and track themselves on a leaderboard,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Updata General Partner </span><a href="https://updata.com/team-member/jon-seeber/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jon Seeber</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, who is taking a seat on Living Security’s board with the funding, said his firm saw “breakout potential” in the startup’s platform.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It comes </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">as close as you can to closing the loop between people and the systems on which they’re operating,” he said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Plus, he said, it does it in a way that avoids the compliance-focused, “check-the-box” mindset that so often dominates employee-focused cybersecurity solutions.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/living-security-raises-14m-for-predicitive-human-risk-management/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131646</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Atlanta&#8217;s early stage investment renaissance continues with Overline&#8217;s $27 million fund close</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/atlantas-early-stage-investment-renaissance-continues-with-overlines-27-million-fund-close/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/atlantas-early-stage-investment-renaissance-continues-with-overlines-27-million-fund-close/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 13:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accenture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advisors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arizona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlanta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CFO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[collaboration software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cox enterprises]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Cohen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delaware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mailchimp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[serial entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social leverage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechStars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131811</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Michael Cohn became a celebrity in the Atlanta startup ecosystem when the company he co-founded was sold to Accenture in a deal valued somewhere between $350 million and $400 million nearly six years ago. That same year, Sean O&#8217;Brien also made waves in the community when he helped shepherd the sale of the  collaboration software [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Michael Cohn became a celebrity in the Atlanta startup ecosystem when <a href="https://www.bizjournals.com/atlanta/blog/atlantech/2015/09/source-accenture-to-acquire-atlantas-cloud-sherpas.html">the company he co-founded was sold </a>to Accenture in a deal valued somewhere between $350 million and $400 million nearly six years ago.</p>
<p>That same year, Sean O&#8217;Brien also made waves in the community when he helped shepherd <a href="https://www.siris.com/news/pgi-announces-completion-of-acquisition-by-siris-capital-group">the sale of the  collaboration software vendor, PGi, to a private equity firm for $1.5 billion</a>.</p>
<p>The two men are now looking to become fixtures in the city&#8217;s burgeoning new tech community with the close of their seed-stage venture capital firm&#8217;s first fund, a $27.4 million investment vehicle.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Overline&#8217;s first fund has already made commitments to companies that are expanding the parameters of what&#8217;s investible in the Southeast broadly and Atlanta&#8217;s startup scene locally.</p>
<p>These are companies like <a href="https://grubblyfarms.com/?gclid=Cj0KCQjwmIuDBhDXARIsAFITC_7_TpPU4jCdL6bAE8nYN_axkVpwEVaNyLjchXuqSkTG_QAmqBZRE4kaAiqpEALw_wcB">Grubbly Farms</a>, which sells insect-based chicken feed for backyard farmers, or <a href="https://www.kayhan.space/">Kayhan Space</a>, which is aiming to be <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/13/kayhan-space-wants-to-be-the-air-traffic-control-service-for-satellites-in-space/">the air traffic control service for the space industry</a>. Others, like <span style="font-weight: 400;">Padsplit, an Atlanta-based flexible housing marketplace, are tackling America&#8217;s low income housing crisis. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our business model is very different from that of a traditional software startup, and the Overline team’s unique strengths and operator mindset have been invaluable in helping us grow the company,” said Sean Warner, CEO and co-founder of Grubbly Farms. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RG2peoBaeY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/13/kayhan-space-wants-to-be-the-air-traffic-control-service-for-satellites-in-space/">Kayhan Space wants to be the air traffic control service for satellites in space</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Kayhan Space wants to be the air traffic control service for satellites in space&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/13/kayhan-space-wants-to-be-the-air-traffic-control-service-for-satellites-in-space/embed/#?secret=RG2peoBaeY" data-secret="RG2peoBaeY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That&#8217;s on top of investments into companies building on Atlanta&#8217;s natural strengths as a financial services, payments and business software powerhouse.</p>
<p>For all of the activity in Atlanta these days, the city and the broader southeastern region is still massively underfunded, according to O&#8217;brien and Cohn. The region only received less than 10 percent of all the institutional venture investments that were committed in 2020. Indeed, only seven percent of Atlanta founders raise money locally when they&#8217;re first starting out, an Overline survey suggested.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The data reflects what we have seen throughout our careers building, growing, and investing in startups. There is no shortage of phenomenal founders and businesses coming out of Atlanta and the Southeast, but they often struggle to find institutional capital at their earliest stages,” said O’Brien, in a statement. “Overline will lead as the first institutional check for these companies and be a true partner to the Founders throughout their lifecycle—supporting them on the strategic and operational business initiatives and decisions that are critical to a company’s success.” </span></p>
<p>The limited partners in Overline&#8217;s first fund also reflects the firm&#8217;s emphasis on regional roots. The privately held email marketing behemoth Mailchimp anchored the fund, which also included partners like Cox Enterprises, Social Leverage,</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overline is supported by a bench of impressive partners that reflects the firm’s roots in the Southeast. Anchored by marketing platform, Mailchimp, additional partners include Cox Enterprises, Scottsdale, Ariz.-based Social Leverage, Wilmington, Del.-based Hallett Capital, and Atlanta Tech Village founder David Cummings, along with Techstars co-founder David Cohen. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“At Mailchimp, we love our hometown of Atlanta, and are proud of the robust startup ecosystem that&#8217;s growing in our city. The Overline founding team’s vision of deploying smart, local capital into startups in Atlanta and the Southeast aligns with our goals of promoting and advancing local innovation,&#8221; said Rick Lynch, CFO, Mailchimp, in a statement.</span></p>
<p>The firm expects to make investments of between $250,000 to $1.5 million into seed stage companies and has already backed 11 companies including, <span style="font-weight: 400;">Relay Payments, a logistics fintech company that has raised over $40 million from top-tier investors. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“When we set out to build Atlanta Tech Village almost a decade ago, one of our primary goals was to help Atlanta develop into a top 10 startup city, where all entrepreneurs would thrive. We&#8217;re making tremendous strides as a community, as evidenced by the number of newly minted unicorns,” said serial entrepreneur and Atlanta Tech Village founder David Cummings. “I believe in Overline’s thesis that value-add institutional early-stage capital is critical to the ecosystem’s continued development. Since the early days, Michael and Sean have been an active presence in our community in a way that goes far beyond being a source of capital—as mentors, advisors, and champions of Atlanta founders. I am proud to be one of their first investors.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/atlantas-early-stage-investment-renaissance-continues-with-overlines-27-million-fund-close/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131811</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Nest Hub 2 review: The solid smart screen adds sleep tracking</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/google-nest-hub-2-review-the-solid-smart-screen-adds-sleep-tracking/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/google-nest-hub-2-review-the-solid-smart-screen-adds-sleep-tracking/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 13:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Assistant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google nest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nest hub]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131511</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two-and-a-half years later, the Nest Home Hub remains one of my favorite smart screens on the market. Maybe that’s a commentary on the rate of improvement in the category, or maybe Google just got things pretty right the first time out. It remains one of the best-looking products on the market, built from solid but [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Two-and-a-half years later, the Nest Home Hub remains one of my favorite smart screens on the market. Maybe that’s a commentary on the rate of improvement in the category, or maybe Google just got things pretty right the first time out. It remains one of the best-looking products on the market, built from solid but understated material. The size is right and Google clearly put a lot of thought into the functionality.</p>
<p>Of course, these consumer electronics have spent a few decades training us to expect big, annual updates to product categories (gotta keep that demand up). By that measure, the second-gen device is something of a disappointment. There’s not really a lot new here. The product now does sleep tracking and the speaker’s bass is a bit more full. And that’s honestly pretty much it.</p>
<p>Perhaps the most fascinating thing about the new version is how Google’s engineers worked within their own self-imposed limitations. I recall very distinctly seeing original Google Home Hub at a pre-release event and asking the company about the decision not to include a camera. Surely companies like Google and Amazon were committed to collecting as much information as possible on devices like these.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2127827" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2127827" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2127827" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9019.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9019.jpeg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9019.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9019.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9019.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9019.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9019.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9019.jpeg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9019.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2127827" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>I gave the company kudos at the time for keeping the camera off the device &#8212; and I’m happy to say it continued to do so with gen 2 (of course, that was made easier with the subsequent release of the camera-sporting Nest Hub Max). And I have to say, having tested the new Echo Hub, which actually physically moves to follow you around the room, only cemented my appreciation of the intentional omission.</p>
<p>That decision was, no doubt, an integral part of why the Nest Hub has become a popular bedside device. Most of us don’t want a camera trained on us while we sleep and do…all of the other things people do in bed (eat crackers, watch scary movies, etc.).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lP3GvOTXbI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/22/google-home-hub-review/">Google Home Hub review</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google Home Hub review&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/22/google-home-hub-review/embed/#?secret=lP3GvOTXbI" data-secret="lP3GvOTXbI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Designing a second-generation version of what has become a popular bedside product made sleep tracking a no brainer. But there’s a problem: A camera seems like a pretty obvious way to do sleep tracking. But adding a camera would almost certainly make people less inclined to invite the product into their bedrooms. So, what do you do? If you’re lucky, you find a technology lying around that some company spent a bunch of money on, but ultimately had no idea what to do with.</p>
<p>So, what are the odds of something like that happening? If you’re Google, surprisingly high, it turns out.</p>
<p>Project Soli is one of those weird Google anomalies. It was a cool technology in search of a problem. The initial problem the team designated was, I suppose, that we touch our touchscreens too much. So it built the tech into the Pixel 4, allowing users to interact with a bespoke Pokémon game and a few other things. By the time the Pixel 5 rolled around, the technology was basically forgotten.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2131523" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2131523" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2131523" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9066.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9066.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9066.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9066.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9066.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9066.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9066.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9066.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9066.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2131523" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>On the face of it, camera-free sleep tracking is a much more logical implementation of the Soli tech (assuming you can get around the initial strangeness of having essentially miniature radar in the electronic device sitting next to your bed). Here’s the breakdown from Google’s product page:</p>
<blockquote><p>Sleep Sensing uses Motion Sense to track the sleep of the person closest to the display. With a low-energy radar, Motion Sense detects movement and breathing. Other sensors in Nest Hub detect sounds like snoring and coughing, and environmental factors like light and temperature in the room. That’s how Sleep Sensing determines not just when you went to bed and how long you slept, but also the quality of your sleep.</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TQyLBcdzFA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/amazon-echo-show-10-review-unmoved/">Amazon Echo Show 10 review: Unmoved</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon Echo Show 10 review: Unmoved&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/amazon-echo-show-10-review-unmoved/embed/#?secret=TQyLBcdzFA" data-secret="TQyLBcdzFA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Certainly the inclusion of sleep tracking doesn’t make the product unique among consumer electronics. It seems like every company is racing to get into sleep &#8212; understandably so. Most of us aren’t getting anywhere near enough &#8212; a trend that dates back well before COVID-19 made insomniacs out of many of us. What makes the product relatively unique, however, is that it promises to do so without making contact with either you or the bed.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SgDLsNBwB1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/09/google-nest-hub-max-review/">Google Nest Hub Max review</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google Nest Hub Max review&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/09/google-nest-hub-max-review/embed/#?secret=SgDLsNBwB1" data-secret="SgDLsNBwB1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As someone who has tested dozens of fitness trackers and smartwatches over the years, I can attest that sleeping with a wearable around your wrist kind of sucks. I mean, I have enough trouble getting to sleep without one on (if I didn’t, I probably wouldn’t be that interested in sleep tracking in the first place).</p>
<p>For my money, if you’re looking for a pure sleep tracker, I would however, take a look at something like Withings Sleep Tracking Mat, which sits under your mattress. It’s minimally invasive and doesn’t require having a screen near your bed. I can’t recommend the new Nest Hub based purely on sleep tracking, but if you were already considering sticking a smart display next to your bed, this makes one of the best models on the market that much more compelling.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2127829" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2127829" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2127829" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9024.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9024.jpeg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9024.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9024.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9024.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9024.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9024.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9024.jpeg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9024.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2127829" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>One of the downsides of the Soli tracking is that there isn’t a ton of flexibility in where you can put the device. I don’t presently have a nightstand, for instance, so I had to improvise with a chair for testing. The device needs to be on the side of the bed (not the head or foot) and level with you on the mattress. The screen should be about one or two feet from you while you sleep.</p>
<p>There’s a calibration process, too, though it’s quite quick and you only really need to do it the once, assuming you’re not going to be moving the product around. This was the one time I found myself missing one of the Echo Show’s new features: specifically, a screen that you can manually tilt up and down. It would be a great feature to see in all of the products, going forward.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="E9CzvgtKiR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/5-consumer-hardware-vcs-share-their-2021-investment-strategies/">5 consumer hardware VCs share their 2021 investment strategies</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 consumer hardware VCs share their 2021 investment strategies&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/5-consumer-hardware-vcs-share-their-2021-investment-strategies/embed/#?secret=E9CzvgtKiR" data-secret="E9CzvgtKiR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>I’ve been using the sleep tracking for several nights now and have found it pretty accurate &#8212; particularly for a product that sits a couple of feet away from the edge of my bed. (Spoiler: I sleep like crap). The on-board wellness feature drills down on the information, as well. In addition to standard info like duration and overall quality, it will tell you how many times you coughed in the night, how many minutes you spent snoring and what your average respiratory rate was throughout the night.</p>
<p>Other info is available, including room temperature (which utilizes a still relatively underused built-in thermometer) and sleep quality, broken down by wake/sleep/restlessness. It’s fairly basic, and it will be interesting to see how much detail the company is ultimately able to drill down on with the given hardware. Given the focus on respiratory health, sleep apnea seems like a no-brainer, but that will likely require some updates, coupled with regulatory scrutiny.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2127826" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2127826" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2127826" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9018.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9018.jpeg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9018.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9018.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9018.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9018.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9018.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9018.jpeg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/CMC_9018.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2127826" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>It seems that, as far as sleep is concerned, there’s likely a good deal of room for improvement using the existing hardware. That’s doubly the case, now that Google’s Fitbit acquisition has officially closed. Expect some tighter integration on that front. For now, there’s still some thoughtful sleep integration with things like wake alarms and bedroom smart light functionality.</p>
<p>At $99, Google’s dropped the asking price by a full $50, which certainly softens the blow of what is ultimately a fairly minor update. Two and half years after its introduction, the Nest Hub is still one of the best smart screens you can buy, bolstered by Google’s solid Assistant and software offerings. The new version wouldn’t be the first on my list of sleep trackers, but if you’re looking for a beside smart display/alarm clock, it’s a nice bonus.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IVrExSJPMZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/googles-soli-returns-to-track-sleep-on-the-new-nest-hub/">Google’s Soli radar returns to track sleep on the new Nest Hub</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google’s Soli radar returns to track sleep on the new Nest Hub&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/googles-soli-returns-to-track-sleep-on-the-new-nest-hub/embed/#?secret=IVrExSJPMZ" data-secret="IVrExSJPMZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/google-nest-hub-2-review-the-solid-smart-screen-adds-sleep-tracking/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131511</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hyundai IONIQ 5 will be Motional and Lyft&#8217;s first robotaxi</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/hyundai-ioniq-5-will-be-motional-and-lyfts-first-robotaxi/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/hyundai-ioniq-5-will-be-motional-and-lyfts-first-robotaxi/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 12:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aptiv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[driver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emerging-Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyundai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hyundai Motor Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Las Vegas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotaxi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transport]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Motional will integrate its driverless technology into Hyundai&#8217;s new all-electric SUV to create the company&#8217;s first robotaxi. At the start of 2023, customers in certain markets will be able to book the fully electric, fully autonomous taxi through the Lyft app. The Hyundai IONIQ 5, which was revealed in February with a consumer release date [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Motional will integrate its driverless technology into Hyundai&#8217;s new all-electric SUV to create the company&#8217;s first robotaxi. At the start of 2023, customers in certain markets will be able to book the fully electric, fully autonomous taxi through the Lyft app.</p>
<p>The Hyundai IONIQ 5, which was revealed in February with a consumer release date expected later this year, will be fully integrated with Motional&#8217;s driverless system. The vehicles will be equipped with the hardware and software needed for Level 4 autonomous driving capabilities, including LiDAR, radar and cameras to provide the vehicle&#8217;s sensing system with 360 degrees of vision, and the ability to see up to 300 meters away. This level of driverless technology means a human will not be required to take over driving.</p>
<p>The interior living space will be similar to the consumer model, but additionally equipped with features needed for robotaxi operation, according to a Motional spokesperson. Motional did not reveal whether or not the vehicle would still have a steering wheel, and images of the robotaxi aren&#8217;t yet available.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Motional&#8217;s IONIQ 5 robotaxis have already begun testing on public roads and closed courses, and they&#8217;ll be put through more months of testing and real-world experience before being deployed on Lyft&#8217;s platform. The company says it&#8217;ll complete testing only once it&#8217;s confident that the taxis are safer than a human driver.</p>
<p>Motional, the Aptiv-Hyundai $4 billion joint venture aimed at commercializing driverless cars, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/motional-and-lyft-target-2023-to-deploy-driverless-robotaxi-services-in-major-u-s-cities/">announced its partnership with Lyft in December</a>, signaling the ride-hailing company&#8217;s primary involvement in Motional&#8217;s plans. The company recently announced that it began testing its driverless tech on public roads in Las Vegas. Hyundai&#8217;s IONIQ 5 is Motional&#8217;s second platform to go driverless on public roads.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ygkxKFhvBU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/motional-and-lyft-target-2023-to-deploy-driverless-robotaxi-services-in-major-u-s-cities/">Motional and Lyft target 2023 to deploy driverless robotaxi services in major US cities</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Motional and Lyft target 2023 to deploy driverless robotaxi services in major US cities&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/motional-and-lyft-target-2023-to-deploy-driverless-robotaxi-services-in-major-u-s-cities/embed/#?secret=ygkxKFhvBU" data-secret="ygkxKFhvBU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/hyundai-ioniq-5-will-be-motional-and-lyfts-first-robotaxi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131791</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Last two crewmembers named for SpaceX&#8217;s first all-civilian human spaceflight mission</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/last-two-crewmembers-named-for-spacexs-first-all-civilian-human-spaceflight-mission/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/last-two-crewmembers-named-for-spacexs-first-all-civilian-human-spaceflight-mission/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 12:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space tourism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Air Force]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131788</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We now know the names of all four individuals who will fly on the historic Inspiration4 mission, the first all-civilian spaceflight in history. In addition to previously revealed crew members Jared Isaacman (who&#8217;s footing the entire bill) and St. Jude Children&#8217;s Hospital employee Haley Arceneaux, Inspiration4 will include Dr. Sian Proctor and Christopher Sembroski as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We now know the names of all four individuals who will fly on the historic <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/spacex-is-aiming-to-fly-the-first-all-civilian-human-space-mission-by-the-end-of-2021/">Inspiration4 mission, the first all-civilian spaceflight in history</a>. In addition to previously revealed crew members Jared Isaacman (who&#8217;s footing the entire bill) and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/22/second-crew-member-of-first-all-civilian-spacex-mission-revealed/">St. Jude Children&#8217;s Hospital employee Haley Arceneaux</a>, Inspiration4 <a href="https://www.inspiration4.com/news-release/Final-Crew-Members-Named">will include</a> Dr. Sian Proctor and Christopher Sembroski as the final two civilian astronauts. The mission will use a SpaceX Dragon capsule and is set to fly no earlier than September 15, with a total duration of three days.</p>
<p>Dr. Proctor takes the state reserved for the online business competition portion of the crew selection process, which saw entrants taken from submissions based on people who had created businesses on Isaacman&#8217;s Shift4Shop e-commerce platform. Sembroski won his seat by contributing to the ongoing St. Jude fundraising drive Isaacman is hosting as part of the mission&#8217;s promotional campaign.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2131802" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Dr.-Sian-Proctor-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2131802" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2131802" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Dr.-Sian-Proctor-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Dr.-Sian-Proctor-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Dr.-Sian-Proctor-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Dr.-Sian-Proctor-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Dr.-Sian-Proctor-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Dr.-Sian-Proctor-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Dr.-Sian-Proctor-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Dr.-Sian-Proctor-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Dr.-Sian-Proctor-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2131802" class="wp-caption-text">Inspiration4 crew member Dr. Sian Proctor</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Both Proctor and Sembroski have specific sets of skills relative to spaceflight that seem likely to have factored Ito their selection for the crew. Proctor is a trained pilot, for instance, and Sembroski is a veteran aerospace employee, most recently at Lockheed Martin, and also a literal veteran, having served in the U.S. Air Force.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2131804" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Chris-Sembroski-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2131804" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2131804" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Chris-Sembroski-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Chris-Sembroski-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Chris-Sembroski-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Chris-Sembroski-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Chris-Sembroski-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Chris-Sembroski-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Chris-Sembroski-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Chris-Sembroski-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Inspiration4-Crew-Head-Shot-Chris-Sembroski-Image-provided-by-SpaceX.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2131804" class="wp-caption-text">Inspiration4 crew member Christopher Sembroski</p></div></p>
<p>As part of this final crew reveal, Inspiration4 also shared how many entries it received in each category. Somewhat surprisingly, the Shift4Shop e-commerce platform competition only drew a total of &#8220;approximately&#8221; 200 entries — and use of &#8216;approximately&#8217; suggests fewer — while the <a href="https://www.stjude.org/get-involved/other-ways/inspiration4.html#fundraise">charity drive drew 72,000 entries,</a> and has raised around $113 million to date. That&#8217;s still short of the campaign&#8217;s $200 million goal, and includes Isaacman&#8217;s personal commitment of $100 million, but the drive continues and there are additional awards to be one, even if the top prize of the trip to space is gone.</p>
<p>This whole mission campaign has honestly been one of the most bizarre stories in spaceflight in recent memory, beginning with the big announcement, which included a press conference with SpaceX CEO Elon Musk joining Isaacman to discuss the flight, and seemingly not being aware of any relevant details about mission specifics. Isaacman also dedicated $100 million of his own money to the charity drive for St. Jude, as mentioned, but clearly donations from the community aren&#8217;t living up to expectations with around 13% of the total target raised from those to date.</p>
<p>That &#8220;approximately 200&#8221; entries in the Shift4Payments build-a-business competition might be the most perplexing, since the award was a free trip to space. In retrospect, this seems like it was the path to space with the most likelihood of working out, even if you had to convince <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/mark-benioff-and-this-panel-of-judges-will-decide-who-gets-one-seat-on-the-first-all-civilian-spaceflight/">an oddly stunt cast panel of judges to select </a><span style="color: #00a562;"><span style="caret-color: #00a562;">yours</span></span> as the winner.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DmymHFsDFF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/spacex-is-aiming-to-fly-the-first-all-civilian-human-space-mission-by-the-end-of-2021/">SpaceX is aiming to fly the first all-civilian human space mission by the end of 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SpaceX is aiming to fly the first all-civilian human space mission by the end of 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/spacex-is-aiming-to-fly-the-first-all-civilian-human-space-mission-by-the-end-of-2021/embed/#?secret=DmymHFsDFF" data-secret="DmymHFsDFF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/last-two-crewmembers-named-for-spacexs-first-all-civilian-human-spaceflight-mission/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131788</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LinkedIn adds Creator mode, video profiles, and in partnership with Microsoft, new career training tools</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/linkedin-adds-creator-mode-video-profiles-and-in-partnership-with-microsoft-new-career-training-tools/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/linkedin-adds-creator-mode-video-profiles-and-in-partnership-with-microsoft-new-career-training-tools/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 12:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131763</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[LinkedIn, the social network now with 740 million users around the world, has carved out an identity for itself as the place online where professionals go to list their places of work, get headhunted for other work, and look for work. But for years it&#8217;s been looking for ways to better leverage that position to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">LinkedIn, the social network now with 740 million users around the world, has carved out an identity for itself as the place online where professionals go to list their places of work, get headhunted for other work, and look for work. But for years it&#8217;s been looking for ways to better leverage that position to move into a plethora of adjacent areas, such as training and education, professional development, networking with others, and news. Today, the company unveiled a series of new features that it will be rolling out over the coming months to play into that strategy, and also, it hopes, increase engagement on the platform:</p>
<p>&#8212; The company is bringing more video into people&#8217;s profiles, with the launch of a &#8220;video Cover Story&#8221;, short videos that people can make talking about themselves to live on their home pages. And for people to feel more connected with how they are depicted on LinkedIn, it is also adding a pronoun feature.</p>
<p>&#8212; Alongside these, the company is officially launching a new &#8220;Creator&#8221; mode, a more refined but also more democratic version of the company&#8217;s Influencer network (anyone can be a Creator if they so choose, for a start). It&#8217;s also carving out more of a solid place for freelancers on the platform, by way of a new Service page attached to your profile.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8212; LinkedIn&#8217;s educational and training efforts are also getting some boost. The program was originally <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/30/microsoft-to-distribute-20m-in-grants-to-non-profits-offers-free-skills-training-via-linkedin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launched in June 2020</a> in the wake of the economic shift that Covid-19 brought on the world with Microsoft, which owns LinkedIn, to offer free online training in 10 different professional areas. Now that program is getting extended to the end of this year. The move comes as the companies passed <a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2021/03/30/building-a-more-inclusive-skills-based-economy-the-next-steps-for-our-global-skills-initiative/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">30 million people in 249 countries using the training service</a>. LinkedIn and Microsoft now hope that the number of companies hiring via the program will reach 250,000.</p>
<p>In another team-up with Microsoft, LinkedIn is also announcing a new Teams-based app called Career Coach aimed at students that use Teams. Using AI tools from LinkedIn, the Career Coach helps its users identify what they are interested in and might like to pursue as a profession, and it uses links through to LinkedIn and Microsoft&#8217;s learning content that could help with that journey.</p>
<p>Taken together, this seemingly disparate set of announcements all lean into an interesting development for LinkedIn. Social media &#8212; whether you are a person posting content, or simply looking at posts from others that you feel speak to your situation in life &#8212; has a strong undercurrent of individual empowerment throughout it. Through these different features and products, LinkedIn is trying in its own way to bring some of that individual identity, voice, and self-advancement, through to its own platform.</p>
<p>Below are some more detailed thoughts about the various new areas.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2131797" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Cover-Story-Playback.gif?w=163" alt="" width="163" height="300" />The video-based Cover Story plays on the idea of how people create short videos about themselves that they might post as a status on a more consumer-focused social media platform. If the list of places where you work and have worked or studied tell one kind of story about who you are, the idea is that the video selfie can tell another to fill in more gaps.</p>
<p>As LinkedIn&#8217;s chief product officer Tomer Cohen describes it, you can use the space to give yourself a more human angle, describing something about your interests or aspirations that might not come across in your resume. These also auto play when people come to visit your profile, which Cohen aptly refers to as a &#8220;Harry Potter&#8221; effect, in reference to the animated <em>Daily Prophet</em> newspaper in the wizarding world. For now these will only appear in your profile, but in time the animals may also expand to search results.</p>
<p>It all sounds interesting enough, except that it relies quite a lot on people using the format successfully rather than creating something that might actually deter recruiters. Ironically, if the trend is to remove some of what might profile and pigeonhole people too much when job-hunting, adding in these videos could serve to bring some of that kind of judgement back into play. It will depend on how they are adopted and used and viewed, at the end of the day.</p>
<p>LinkedIn&#8217;s focus on video comes as part of the company&#8217;s bigger engagement with the medium over the last several years, adding services like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/11/linkedin-debuts-linkedin-live-a-new-live-video-broadcast-service/">Live broadcasts</a> into the timeline for example. It&#8217;s no surprise, considering how sticky video has been in the bigger realm of social media across services like TikTok, Snapchat, Facebook and Twitter.</p>
<p>That seems to also be playing out at LinkedIn and areas that align more closely with the company&#8217;s business: it said in a survey it conducted, some 61% of job seekers said that recorded video could be the next iteration of the traditional cover letter, and that among hiring managers, nearly <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">80% say video figures strongly in their candidate vetting. So it&#8217;s not a matter of testing the waters, but perhaps just making sure you have the tools to stay afloat.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2131817" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Creator_Mode.gif?w=137" alt="" width="137" height="300" /></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Video is playing a bigger role beyond just that of helping everyone with profiles. For the most proactive, LinkedIn is launching a Creator mode, where people who already make LinkedIn Live videos and other content can shift over their profiles to becoming Creators instead of ordinary LinkedIn citizens. This is something you choose yourself, unlike the Influencer tag that LinkedIn confers on a smaller subset of thought leaders, and it means you can be &#8220;followed&#8221; on LinkedIn for people to watch and stay up to date with what you post.</p>
<p>While it&#8217;s hard to think of who might come to LinkedIn for entertainment in the same way that they might come to Instagram to follow a creator, the idea is that creating content for LinkedIn becomes the end in itself for both the person watching and the person being watched.</p>
<p>It looks like the natural progression of the original content that LinkedIn has been building up through its editorial operation led by Dan Roth &#8212; indeed the company announced the first steps for its Creator product <a href="https://www.axios.com/linkedin-launch-creator-program-cf3b1897-157e-4c8d-9fff-1f1566087c98.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">last month</a>, led by Roth. But unlike creators on platforms like Instagram or YouTube or TikTok, for now it doesn&#8217;t look like there are direct routes to monetization when you are a LinkedIn Creator. That might change, however.</p>
<p>&#8220;Indirectly we’ve been connecting people to opportunities since we first enabled people to share content on LinkedIn.  Our members get leads and grow their business and following on LinkedIn,&#8221; said Keren Baruch, group product manager for <span class="il">LinkedIn</span>’s creator strategy. She cited <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://nam06.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.linkedin.com%2Fin%2Ftagjustq%2F&amp;data=04%7C01%7Csowens%40linkedin.com%7C6c65d858f3c04c3b221e08d8f2deaaf6%7C72f988bf86f141af91ab2d7cd011db47%7C1%7C0%7C637526385452413279%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&amp;sdata=kzB1cjYYbdWY9MWq0nAym6LdWpgNwaJyy%2BD8EIDv6YI%3D&amp;reserved=0" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://nam06.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fwww.linkedin.com%252Fin%252Ftagjustq%252F%26data%3D04%257C01%257Csowens%2540linkedin.com%257C6c65d858f3c04c3b221e08d8f2deaaf6%257C72f988bf86f141af91ab2d7cd011db47%257C1%257C0%257C637526385452413279%257CUnknown%257CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%253D%257C1000%26sdata%3DkzB1cjYYbdWY9MWq0nAym6LdWpgNwaJyy%252BD8EIDv6YI%253D%26reserved%3D0&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1617187671588000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHWslp-rKhgB6ReSnCjI1hwTS4LHw">Quentin</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> Allums, &#8220;jobless, broke, and desperate when he started posting LinkedIn videos. Then they started to go viral and he created his own business on LinkedIn from this success.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;As we continue to listen to feedback from our members as we consider future opportunities, we’ll also continue to evolve how we create more value for our creators,&#8221; she added.</p>
<p>The Service Pages also appear to be something that is the start of a product and project that LinkedIn started to seed in February, which will comprise a larger freelancer marketplace, <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/microsofts-new-gig-a-linkedin-freelancer-market-rivaling-upwork-fiverr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reportedly by September</a>.</p>
<p>[gallery ids="2131820,2131821"]</p>
<p>As you can see, this seems to be a baby step: no links through to setting up payments or handling anything like that, and LinkedIn itself is not making a cut, as Fiverr or Freelancer.com might make from giving people a platform to generate business for themselves. For now, it could be just a way of testing the waters and getting some people to populate the site with credentials but further down the line could represent an interesting inroad into a new kind of advertising unit or payment services alongside the revenue-generating features that LinkedIn already has in the form of premium subscriptions, tools for recruiters and other kinds of advertising.</p>
<p>Lastly, given that LinkedIn has made such a big push into trying to democratize opportunity on the platform, providing a link for freelancers to post on its platform might also interestingly might open the door to more than just the knowledge workers and their skills. These currently form the majority of users of LinkedIn but are clearly not the entirety of the working world that the company hopes to address and serve in the longer term.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/linkedin-adds-creator-mode-video-profiles-and-in-partnership-with-microsoft-new-career-training-tools/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131763</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weather platform ClimaCell is now Tomorrow.io and raises $77M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/weather-platform-climacell-is-now-tomorrow-io-and-raises-77m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/weather-platform-climacell-is-now-tomorrow-io-and-raises-77m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climacell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stonecourt Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tomorrow.io]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather forecasting]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131458</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Weather intelligence platform ClimaCell today announced that it has raised a $77 million Series D funding round led by private equity firm Stonecourt Capital, with participation by Highline Capital. This brings the company&#8217;s total funding to about $185 million. In addition to the new funding, ClimaCell announced that it has changed its name to Tomorrow.io, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Weather intelligence platform <a href="https://www.climacell.co/">ClimaCell</a> today announced that it has raised a $77 million Series D funding round led by private equity firm <a href="https://www.stonecourtlp.com/">Stonecourt Capital</a>, with participation by Highline Capital. This brings the company&#8217;s total funding to about $185 million. In addition to the new funding, ClimaCell announced that it has changed its name to Tomorrow.io, with &#8220;The Tomorrow Companies Inc.&#8221; as its new legal name.</p>
<p>Today&#8217;s announcement comes only a month after the company announced that it would launch a fleet of small radar-equipped weather satellites to improve its weather monitoring and forecasting capabilities. That&#8217;s also, at least in part, where the name change comes from.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2131492" style="width: 767px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/climacell.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2131492" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2131492" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/climacell.png" alt="" width="757" height="436" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/climacell.png 757w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/climacell.png?resize=150,86 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/climacell.png?resize=300,173 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/climacell.png?resize=680,392 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/climacell.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 757px) 100vw, 757px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2131492" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> ClimaCell/Tomorrow.ai</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Originally, ClimaCell/Tomorrow.io <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/18/climacell-bets-on-iot-for-better-weather-forecasts/">built out a novel technology</a> to collect weather data using wireless network infrastructure and IoT devices. That&#8217;s where the &#8220;cell&#8221; in ClimaCell came from. But as the company&#8217;s CEO and co-founder Shimon Elkabetz told me, while the company isn&#8217;t abandoning this approach, its focus today is much broader.</p>
<p>&#8220;The mission is really to help countries, businesses, organizations, to better manage their weather-related challenges,&#8221; he said. &#8220;And the ambition was always to be that largest weather enterprise in the world, the most disruptive, the most industry-defining. And I think this is the perfect timing for us to come up with a new name, not only because of the funding but because we were able to explain to ourselves that really, we&#8217;re helping others take control of tomorrow, today.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="W5uYbXePll"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/climacell-plans-to-launch-its-own-satellites-to-improve-its-weather-predictions/">ClimaCell plans to launch its own satellites to improve its weather predictions</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;ClimaCell plans to launch its own satellites to improve its weather predictions&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/climacell-plans-to-launch-its-own-satellites-to-improve-its-weather-predictions/embed/#?secret=W5uYbXePll" data-secret="W5uYbXePll" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That&#8217;s something Stonecourt partner Rock Davis agrees with. &#8220;While the company&#8217;s growth has been tremendous since launch, there is a larger opportunity at play here,” he said. &#8220;What Tomorrow.io is building, corroborated by their recent announcement of launching radar-equipped satellites into space, is only further proof that this company represents the future of weather forecasting for the entire planet. The privatization of the weather industry is now, and that type of vision is what compels the team here at Stonecourt Capital.&#8221;</p>
<p>As Elkabetz noted, Tomorrow.io isn&#8217;t a typical investment for a private investment firm like Stonecourt. Last year, the firm <a href="https://www.stonecourtlp.com/news/2020/10/6/stonecourt-capital-acquires-365-data-centers">acquired 365 Data Centers</a>, but it is also backing the Denver-based freight rail company Alpenglow Rail, for example.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ka2tk8QZk9I?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>And while many of Tomorrow.io&#8217;s customers saw their business decline during the pandemic (the company counts Uber and Delta among its users, for example), Elkabetz tells me that its team focused on diversifying its customer base and managed to sign up a number of large logistics companies, including major railways in the U.S. and Mexico, but also smaller companies in the drone, autonomous driving and electric vehicle space. In total, the company says, it saw a 200% net revenue retention rate and its annual contract value grew 850% during the past two years.</p>
<p>The company plans to use the new funding to launch more satellites, but also to improve its overall product and accelerate its go-to-market activities.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re an interesting company because we&#8217;re a SaaS company that is now going to space,&#8221; Elkabetz said. &#8220;A lot of the Earth observations companies are now scratching their heads and saying, &#8216;Oh, we can&#8217;t just sell observations, it&#8217;s not monetizable or becoming a commodity. We now need to become a software company and build the platform and do the analytics.&#8217; Good luck.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="STY7a93XxQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/04/deep-science-using-machine-learning-to-study-anatomy-weather-and-earthquakes/">Deep Science: Using machine learning to study anatomy, weather and earthquakes</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Deep Science: Using machine learning to study anatomy, weather and earthquakes&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/04/deep-science-using-machine-learning-to-study-anatomy-weather-and-earthquakes/embed/#?secret=STY7a93XxQ" data-secret="STY7a93XxQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-end-end-radius: initial; border-end-start-radius: initial; border-inline: initial; border-start-end-radius: initial; border-start-start-radius: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-end-end-radius: initial; border-end-start-radius: initial; border-inline: initial; border-start-end-radius: initial; border-start-start-radius: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/weather-platform-climacell-is-now-tomorrow-io-and-raises-77m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131458</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
