<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 05:09:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Pet video marketplace Camlist eyes UK growth after raising $1.3 million pre-seed funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/pet-video-marketplace-camlist-eyes-uk-growth-after-raising-1-3-million-pre-seed-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/pet-video-marketplace-camlist-eyes-uk-growth-after-raising-1-3-million-pre-seed-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Njanja]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 05:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dubai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketplace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.K.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[u.s.]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2239588</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Camlist, a video marketplace for pets, has raised $1.3 million in a pre-seed round, funding that the startup plans to use to develop its platform and grow its workforce &#8212; as it looks to expand its reach in the UK, its second market (after the U.A.E.), which it entered earlier this year. Unlike other marketplaces, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.camlist.com/">Camlist</a>, a video marketplace for pets, has raised $1.3 million in a pre-seed round, funding that the startup plans to use to develop its platform and grow its workforce &#8212; as it looks to expand its reach in the UK, its second market (after the U.A.E.), which it entered earlier this year.</p>
<p>Unlike other marketplaces, Camlist (derived from camera listing) allows sellers to list videos of the pets they wish to sell, and once contact is made, the buyer and seller can engage through both video and text-chat within the app.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/peek-raises-80m-as-its-travel-experiences-software-and-marketplace-business-passes-2b-in-bookings/">marketplace</a> currently only allows the listing of pets, but it is set to diversify to other items in the near future.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2239588" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“Classifieds, or peer to peer commerce in general, has been stuck in the same old way of operation since eBay showed up. There has not been real significant innovation ever since; it&#8217;s just listings, maybe some images and phone numbers,” said Camlist co-founder and chief executive officer, Moustafa Mahmoud.</p>
<p>“But at Camlist we are changing that. We are turning the marketplace into a video experience because every pre-owned item has a story.”</p>
<p>Mahmoud said that they are building the safest way for anyone to find a pet by also ensuring verified health checks and interest free financing, in partnership with third parties, for those unable to make one-off payments. Camlist has rehomed over 6,000 pets to date.</p>
<p>“Our in-app GMV (Gross Merchandise Value) has been growing 100% every two quarters, so we&#8217;re doubling every quarter, and our total GMV is around $2 million a month,” said Mahmoud.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Y Combinator company was founded and launched in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/11/uae-b2b-e-commerce-site-dubuy-targets-africa-for-growth/">Dubai, U.A.E</a>, last year, just before Covid pandemic hit. The launch turned out to be timely and the site grew popular as people, forced to stay home, bought their own pets &#8212; partly to deal with boredom, but also because they had the time to nurture them.</p>
<p>“We&#8217;re building the marketplace category by category, and we just feel that the pets listing is so huge, and also very underserved. We plan to expand into different items as we grow,” said Mahmoud, who is also a computer scientist.</p>
<p>Other co-founders include <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/maharefai/?originalSubdomain=uk">Maha Refa</a>i, also the startup&#8217;s chief product officer, who has 16 years’ experience building and scaling digital products. She is also the creator of MBC&#8217;s (Middle East’s largest free-to-air broadcaster) premier video platform as well as other multiple video streaming products.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alsayedgamal/?originalSubdomain=eg">Alsayed Gamal</a>, who is Camlist chief technical officer, has 15 years software engineering experience. He has knowledge and experience in mobile platforms, data engineering, DevOps, API design, microservices and serverless architecture.</p>
<p>Mahmoud said the idea to start Camlist was inspired by the need to counter the bad experiences he went through while making purchases on classified sites in Dubai, U.A.E, where items were often misrepresented and scams high.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2239630" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2239630" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2239630 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/me3.jpeg" alt="" width="800" height="533" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/me3.jpeg 800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/me3.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/me3.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/me3.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/me3.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/me3.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2239630" class="wp-caption-text">Moustafa Mahmoud; Camlist chief executive officer, he co-founded the video marketplace with Maha Refai; the startup&#8217;s chief product officer and Alsayed Gamal; chief technical officer.</p></div></p>
<p>Classifieds are popular in Dubai, an expat city, as people use them to dispose of their items, but they have also provided an opportunity for scammers to target unsuspecting people. To counter this, Camlist has an option for in-app payments &#8212; with funds released once the buyers confirm receipt of the pets. This feature ensures that buyers are not defrauded by deterring cons masquerading as vendors.</p>
<p>Mahmoud and his other co-founders provide a marketplace that allows buyers to first experience items of interest, through video, before making a purchase. This is besides ensuring that buyers were protected against fraud and guaranteeing high quality services.</p>
<p>The company also follows up with the sellers on its platform to ensure that they are breeding or keeping the pets in healthy environments, as well as vaccinating, deworming, and microchipping them.</p>
<p>“We also support our buyers and sellers by providing them with free vaccinations, microchipping, deworming, insurance, and pet food. We try to provide the best experience for our buyers and our sellers,” he said.</p>
<p>The startup raised the new funding from Y-Combinator; the technology startup accelerator, Act One Ventures; an early-stage venture fund and a number of angel investors from Houseparty, Mux and Facebook.</p>
<p>“We really looked forward to investors who believe in our vision of building the marketplace of the future. And we are really fortunate to get people who believe in this vision, and who actually work and build applications in the video industry,” said Mahmoud.</p>
<p>After achieving traction in the UK, Camlist is planning to enter the US market, which it believes is going to be a huge and important market for them.</p>
<p>“So, the current state for us is expansion within the UK because it&#8217;s a pretty big market. And we can see the impact of what we&#8217;re doing here. But as soon as we reach a certain stage where we have the majority of the market, then we will start to expand into the United States,” said Mahmoud, who was born in Egypt, with his family moving to Dubai when he was six years old.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/pet-video-marketplace-camlist-eyes-uk-growth-after-raising-1-3-million-pre-seed-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2239588</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ant is changing how consumers borrow money from its app</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/ant-restructure-jiebei-huabei/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/ant-restructure-jiebei-huabei/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 04:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ant group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ant+]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[People's Bank of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[securitization]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2239625</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In December 2020, Beijing laid out a guideline for Ant Group to &#8220;rectify&#8221; its business after calling off its IPO, which could have been the largest initial public offering in history. In the plan, regulators asked Ant to revamp its credit business, among other changes that would make it subject to the same set of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In December 2020, Beijing laid out a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/27/ant-group-financial-clampdown/">guideline</a> for Ant Group to &#8220;rectify&#8221; its business after calling off its IPO, which could have been the largest initial public offering in history. In the plan, regulators asked Ant to revamp its credit business, among other changes that would make it subject to the same set of regulations overseeing financial institutions. In other words, Ant can no longer get by with its freewheeling practices by calling itself a &#8220;tech&#8221; firm.</p>
<p>Nearly a year later, the Alibaba-affiliated fintech powerhouse showed that it has almost finished restructuring its popular consumer credit products.</p>
<p>Credit loan products contributed nearly 40% of Ant&#8217;s revenues in the six months ended June 2020, according to the firm&#8217;s <a href="https://www1.hkexnews.hk/listedco/listconews/sehk/2020/1026/2020102600165.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">prospectus</a> filed last year. The two main products are Huabei (Spend), which launched in 2014 for daily expenditures by consumers, working like a virtual credit card. A year later Jiebei (Borrow) was introduced as a credit product for larger consumption transactions.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2239625" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Under the old model, Ant originated loans that were then underwritten by third-party banks and other financial institutions. As of June 2020, about 98% of Ant&#8217;s credit balance originated through its platform was underwritten by its partner financial institutions or securitized, according to the firm&#8217;s prospectus.</p>
<p>Jiebei has split itself into two brands, users reported earlier this week. Credit lines extended by third-party banks are now called Xinyong Dai (Credit Loan) on Alipay, Ant&#8217;s flagship financial services app. Those provided by Ant&#8217;s consumer finance company, which was recently established at the behest of regulators, are staying under the Jiebei brand.</p>
<p><a href="https://weibo.com/u/5445230801?layerid=4707056739157128">Huabei has similarly started a restructuring</a>, which will show users which loans are extended independently by banks and which by Ant&#8217;s consumer finance firm. Huabei will focus on &#8220;small-ticket&#8221; everyday transactions, it <a href="https://weibo.com/5445230801/L2XzPCqbC?pagetype=profilefeed" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> in a Weibo post.</p>
<p>&#8220;Following the brand differentiation, users applying for credit loan services will have more information about their credit providers to avoid brand confusion.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Huabei also noted that it&#8217;s now submitting consumer credit information to a database overseen by China&#8217;s central bank. It <a href="https://weibo.com/5445230801/KzjHoddoe?pagetype=profilefeed" target="_blank" rel="noopener">started</a> the routine in September after it established its consumer credit company, which, just like banks, need to report their credit information to the central bank in China.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mThTnzvilb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/27/ant-group-financial-clampdown/">China lays out &#8216;rectification&#8217; plan for Jack Ma&#8217;s fintech empire Ant</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;China lays out &#8216;rectification&#8217; plan for Jack Ma&#8217;s fintech empire Ant&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/27/ant-group-financial-clampdown/embed/#?secret=mThTnzvilb" data-secret="mThTnzvilb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/ant-restructure-jiebei-huabei/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2239625</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Pilot convinced Index Ventures to think long-term about margins</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/how-pilot-convinced-index-ventures-to-think-long-term-about-margins/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/how-pilot-convinced-index-ventures-to-think-long-term-about-margins/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 23:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ECL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TCL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Live Recap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Index Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jessica mckellar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mark goldberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pilot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Live]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238670</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whether you agree or not, it's hard to ignore the fact that the multipliers in Silicon Valley and the growth of software businesses have changed the way we think about a startup's timeline.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">On a recently recorded (and soon-to-be published) episode of the <a href="https://pod.link/found">Found podcast</a>, an entrepreneur told my co-host and me that he sees a broad swath of the venture capitalists out there as money managers, more focused on short-term gains and returns than long-term revolutionary technology.</p>
<p>Whether you agree or not, it&#8217;s hard to ignore the fact that the multipliers in Silicon Valley and the growth of software businesses have changed the way we think about a startup&#8217;s timeline.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			&#8220;The pressure from [Index] caused us to work a little harder and be a little bit more precise in our instrumentation to be able to prove that the long-term trajectory would achieve certain milestones that would work for everybody.&#8221;							<cite>Jessica McKellar</cite>
					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/pilot/">Pilot</a>, a bookkeeping software service that has raised more than $160 million since inception, is not necessarily a stranger to the shorter-term desires of investors. Index Ventures partner Mark Goldberg, who led the Series A and Series B rounds for the startup, would be the first to tell you that the board and the founders had some early disagreements about how the company should operate.</p>
<p>Obviously, it wasn&#8217;t enough to stop him or Index from doubling down on the business.</p>
<p>We talked about all this and more on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/techcrunch-live/">TechCrunch Live</a>.</p>
<h2>Doubling down</h2>
<p>&#8220;It was pretty terrifying,&#8221; said Goldberg. &#8220;In my gut, I thought, &#8216;Wow, we better get this right.'&#8221;</p>
<p>A few things clicked into place for Goldberg to want to keep investing in Pilot. The first was that it was a real category-creation opportunity, in that bookkeeping was a $100 billion industry that was largely fragmented.</p>
<p>The second was the customer love for the product.</p>
<p>&#8220;We started to hear customers proactively calling us from within the Index portfolio saying that they hated doing bookkeeping and back office functions, and now they don&#8217;t have to think about it. They said things like &#8216;Whoever this Pilot team is, they&#8217;re doing some wizardry so I can just shut my brain off to the part of the business I didn&#8217;t enjoy doing.'&#8221;</p>
<p>The third was the conviction and dedication of the team to empathizing with and understanding their customers.</p>
<p>He recalled a time early on when the team was no more than 10 people, most of them engineers, when he visited the office on a weekend. They were all wearing green visors, doing bookkeeping for their customers.</p>
<p>&#8220;They weren&#8217;t doing it because they needed to for customer support, but because they really wanted to empathize with the customers for the product that they were building,&#8221; said Goldberg. &#8220;That&#8217;s the sort of sweat equity and market recognition that told me, if this continues to grow, there really is no ceiling on what this business could become.&#8221;</p>
<p>While that sort of dedication to understanding the user was attractive, it was not without its costs.</p>
<h2>Counterintuitive convictions</h2>
<p>&#8220;Pilot is a technology company wrapped in this lovely human layer of high-touch support for its customers, which is a bit counter-intuitive in Silicon Valley, where most companies don&#8217;t want humans in the loop,&#8221; said Goldberg. &#8220;That&#8217;s what I know and understand, and we had a view that this sort of tech-enabled service model could be very valuable, but we wanted to make sure that they could create a financial profile that had gross margins that reflected that of a software company.&#8221;</p>
<p>In its simplest form, Jessica McKellar and her co-founders felt very strongly that they wanted to focus on the customer fully and deliver great customer service from the very beginning. In a business where you are onboarding customers by ingesting the entirety of their financials, that can be costly.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/how-pilot-convinced-index-ventures-to-think-long-term-about-margins/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238670</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: France moves to block e-commerce platform Wish over fraud, safety concerns</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/daily-crunch-98/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/daily-crunch-98/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 23:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2239430</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PST, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for November 24, 2021! A small note: This newsletter is off tomorrow but will be back Friday with a special holiday edition. In short, we’re taking advantage of a little time off to recharge. Full service returns Monday! — <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/in-a-crowded-global-market-canadian-ai-startups-fundraising-results-stand-out/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Up north, an AI boom:</a></strong> Continuing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/16/huge-deals-are-pushing-more-ai-startups-into-ipo-territory/">TechCrunch’s coverage</a> of the rapid-fire AI fundraising market, we explored the Canadian artificial-intelligence startup industry. There’s a lot more going on up north than you might expect. Consider this more evidence of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/global-startups-raise-158b-in-q3-an-all-time-record/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">increasingly global startup landscape</a>.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/france-asks-search-engines-and-app-stores-to-remove-wish/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">France moves to delist Wish:</a> </strong>Akin to a nonprofit U.S. newsroom, France decided to test its concerns about e-commerce marketplace Wish by buying stuff and checking out what they got. A bunch of violations, it turns out. France is now asking search engines and app stores to delist the public U.S. company.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/attio-wants-to-build-the-crm-for-the-airtable-generation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Attio is taking on Salesforce:</a></strong> While startups are busy attacking a host of markets, there are certain areas of the software domain that have felt too off-limits in recent years. Search is finally seeing a wave of competitors, for example. Attio, now flush with $7.7 million in capital, is taking on the old-school CRM market.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/kenyan-fintech-asilimia-raises-2-million-in-a-pre-seed-round-plans-to-extend-loans-to-msmes-and-expand-in-east-africa/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Asilimia wants to bring more loans to Kenya:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The business of loaning money to folks not supported by the traditional banking world is big business. Asilimia just raised $2 million — half debt, half equity — to keep money flowing in its home market. Per TechCrunch reporting, the company also offers “a lifeline to traders in Kenya by enabling them to make mobile money transactions that are devoid of transfer charges through its Leja app.”</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/nigerias-onepipe-raises-3-5m-to-double-down-on-its-embedded-finance-offering/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>OnePipe raises $3.5M for its fintech API business:</strong></a> Plaid is a big deal in its domestic market, but that doesn’t mean that there aren’t related startups executing similar work around the world. OnePipe is one such company, bringing fintech infra APIs to Africa. And now it has a pile of new funds to continue its work.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/india-used-cars-platform-spinny-valued-at-1-75-billion-in-over-280-million-funding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Ok *now* the used car market is out of control:</strong></a> If you read business news, you’ve read about the used car market. A chip shortage has made used cars more pricey than ever. And now Indian startup Spinny has shifted into unicorn territory with a new $280 million round. There are related companies in the U.S. market that have gone public, so Spinny is operating in a market that we understand. Let’s see how its economics bear out.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/vollebak-which-makes-clothes-for-the-future-is-closing-its-series-a-round/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Clothes for a bleak future:</strong></a><strong> </strong>If you want jackets for huge storms and a fleece for extreme conditions — wagering that climate change is going to make our home planet a bit less fun to live on — Vollebak has your, well, back. The startup just raised a Series A, likely, we guess, hoping to follow Allbirds and other recent DTC debuts to the public markets.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/juicy-marbles-gets-4-5m-to-sizzle-up-plant-based-steaks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Today in startup names we’re not sure about:</strong></a><strong> </strong>I’ve never been huge on calling meat fat “marbling” &#8212; to me, marble is the material for old-world erotic sculptures. I blame my parents’ love for art and art museums for this view. Regardless, there’s a startup called Juicy Marbles out there hoping to create “plant-based whole meat cuts.” I am in favor of the product and the company’s goals. But Juicy Marbles? There I am less confident.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Dear Sophie: How long does International Entrepreneur Parole take?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2099516" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/dear-sophie-how-long-does-international-entrepreneur-parole-take/"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2099516" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2099516 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg" alt="lone figure at entrance to maze hedge that has an American flag at the center" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2099516" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin/TechCrunch</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2239430" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Dear Sophie,</p>
<p>My co-founders and I think we might qualify for International Entrepreneur Parole.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/dear-sophie-how-long-does-international-entrepreneur-parole-take/">How long does it take to get IEP approved?</a> How does that compare to other options that are available to startup founders, and can my spouse work?</p>
<p>— Committed COO</p>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/afterpay-unveils-bnpl-subscription-offering-for-u-s-customers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BNPL giants want to get into things other than BNPL:</a> </strong>Yesterday’s news that Klarna is moving into upfront payments might have had you scratching your head. Get ready for more follicular punishment. Today, TechCrunch reported that Afterpay is getting into the installment subscription game. Sure.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/twitter-ios-update-prevents-tweets-from-disappearing-while-youre-reading-them/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Twitter brings web update to iOS so that you stop losing tweets:</strong></a> Ever been on your phone, looking at a <a href="https://twitter.com/patrickc/status/591724846280679426" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Very Good Tweet</a>, only to have it disappear from your view, gone forever into the ether that is the ever-flowing timeline? Yeah, it sucks. The company fixed the issue on the web recently and is now fixing its mobile app. Rejoice.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2217068" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217068" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217068" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg" alt="dc experts" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217068" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend growth marketers who have expertise in SEO, social, content writing and more! If you’re a growth marketer, pass this survey along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/daily-crunch-98/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2239430</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Forest bags $8M seed round to acquire Japanese e-commerce brands </title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/forest-bags-8m-seed-round-to-acquire-japanese-e-commerce-brands/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/forest-bags-8m-seed-round-to-acquire-japanese-e-commerce-brands/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 23:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce aggregator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Forest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nordstar Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The University of Tokyo Edge Capital Partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2239178</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Japan has been the birthplace of traditional arts and crafts since ancient times. Craftmanship, meticulous attention to detail and balance of design and functionality have contributed to creating unique Japanese products like pottery, traditional fabrics, washi (paper), woodwork, glasses, bento-boxes and more.  This craftsmanship continues to be passed along from generation to generation and live [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Japan has been the birthplace of traditional arts and crafts since ancient times. Craftmanship, meticulous attention to detail and balance of design and functionality have contributed to creating unique Japanese products like pottery, traditional fabrics, washi (paper), woodwork, glasses, bento-boxes and more. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">This craftsmanship continues to be passed along from generation to generation and live on in modern Japan. However, the craftsmen and women, who do not always have the skills or tools to be influential merchants, have often been left behind in the rapidly evolving business environment in the 21st century. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">In recent years, a growing number of e-commerce entrepreneurs have started to develop their own products and brands in response to a shift in consumer demand from cheap, mass-produced goods to diversified products that meet one’s unique needs and lifestyle. </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2239178" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><a href="https://www.forest-inc.jp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Forest</a>, a Japanese e-commerce aggregator, seeks to identify sustainable, high-quality products and brands that embrace the spirit of Japan </span>and help them grow and enter the global market by using the power of technology.</p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Forest announced today it has raised approximately $8 million (900 million yen) of seed round led by <a href="https://www.ut-ec.co.jp/english/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The University of Tokyo Edge Capital Partners (UTEC)</a> and <a href="https://nordstar.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nordstar Partners</a>.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The startup will use the new capital to acquire more than 300 Japanese e-commerce brands that have been carefully crafted and curated by entrepreneurs. Forest will apply digital marketing strategies at scale, optimize sales and enhance inventory planning through data analytics, as well as support cross-border e-commerce expansion. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Forest is currently in the process of finalizing its first acquisition. It will continue to look for brands that generate sales between $1 million and $5 million and target to acquire companies with more than $10 million of sales next year, said CEO of Forest <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/shingo-yuhara-74075060/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shingo Yuhara</a> told TechCrunch. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">It also plans to raise around $20 million to $30 million debt and equity capital of Series A, targeting the first half of 2022, Yuhara said.  </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Forest looks at marketplaces, including Amazon, Rakuten, </span><a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://zozo.jp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Zozotown</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true">, Yahoo Japan sellers, Shopify and more. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8Tn3dN0mGt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/founded-by-former-carousell-ovo-and-fave-execs-rainforest-raises-36m-to-aggregate-asia-pacific-amazon-marketplace-sellers/">Founded by former Carousell and Fave execs, Rainforest gets $36M to consolidate Asia-Pacific Amazon Marketplace brands</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Founded by former Carousell and Fave execs, Rainforest gets $36M to consolidate Asia-Pacific Amazon Marketplace brands&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/founded-by-former-carousell-ovo-and-fave-execs-rainforest-raises-36m-to-aggregate-asia-pacific-amazon-marketplace-sellers/embed/#?secret=8Tn3dN0mGt" data-secret="8Tn3dN0mGt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Forest, founded in July by Yuhara and COO Masa Mishizawa, will compete with other e-commerce aggregators like Rainforest, Una Brands and Thrasio in the global market. Forest said it is the first pure aggregator dedicated to the Japanese market. Given that Forest initially focuses on the Japanese market, it does not see Rainforest and Thrasio as its pure competitors, Yuhara said. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Thrasio </span><a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/thrasio-launches-in-japan-with-250-million-commitment-to-acquire-japanese-ecommerce-businesses-301251270.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">set up a Japanese office</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> in March to acquire Japanese brands and products sold on Amazon Japan and other e-commerce platforms. </span><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The Japanese e-commerce market was estimated at $165 billion (19 trillion yen) as of 2020, according to </span><a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://www.meti.go.jp/english/press/2021/0730_002.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">a report</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> by Japan’s Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">“[The] investment into Forest is one of our largest seed round investments within the IT sector. In my previous life, I managed my family-owned apparel business and personally experienced the pains and limitations of a small business. I strongly believe that Forest can solve these problems and capitalize on the potential of these businesses through the power of technology,&#8221; said partner of UTEC Hiroyuki Sakamoto. &#8220;We look forward to working with the experienced Founders who seek to challenge this attractive market opportunity and we feel privileged to participate as co-lead investor.”   </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">“We are excited to be investing in Forest that is well-positioned to take advantage of the large opportunity in acquiring and scaling niche brands in Japan,” said managing partner Ole Ruch of Nordstar. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QKa3CO1UgL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/thrasio-the-amazon-aggregator-raises-1b-in-fresh-funding-at-a-valuation-of-up-to-10-billion/">Thrasio, the Amazon aggregator, raises $1B in fresh funding at a valuation of up to $10 billion</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Thrasio, the Amazon aggregator, raises $1B in fresh funding at a valuation of up to $10 billion&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/thrasio-the-amazon-aggregator-raises-1b-in-fresh-funding-at-a-valuation-of-up-to-10-billion/embed/#?secret=QKa3CO1UgL" data-secret="QKa3CO1UgL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4T0fAJ4Jep"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/una-brands-launches-with-40m-to-acquire-brands-on-multiple-asia-pacific-e-commerce-platforms/">Una Brands launches with $40M to roll up brands on multiple Asia-Pacific e-commerce platforms</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Una Brands launches with $40M to roll up brands on multiple Asia-Pacific e-commerce platforms&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/una-brands-launches-with-40m-to-acquire-brands-on-multiple-asia-pacific-e-commerce-platforms/embed/#?secret=4T0fAJ4Jep" data-secret="4T0fAJ4Jep" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VGuuSrXMri"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/e-commerce-aggregator-rainforest-raises-20m-just-months-after-its-last-funding/">E-commerce aggregator Rainforest raises $20M just months after its last funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;E-commerce aggregator Rainforest raises $20M just months after its last funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/e-commerce-aggregator-rainforest-raises-20m-just-months-after-its-last-funding/embed/#?secret=VGuuSrXMri" data-secret="VGuuSrXMri" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/forest-bags-8m-seed-round-to-acquire-japanese-e-commerce-brands/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2239178</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coinbase acqui-hires team behind BRD crypto wallet</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/coinbase-acquihires-team-behind-brd-crypto-wallet/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/coinbase-acquihires-team-behind-brd-crypto-wallet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 21:07:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency wallet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital wallet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[East Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SBI Crypto Investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wallet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2239511</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As crypto proponents look to onboard a new generation of users, one of the major consumer onramps has been a host of consumer wallet apps with slick interfaces. Today, Coinbase announced that it is bringing on the team from BRD &#8212; a crypto wallet startup that first launched its mobile wallet back in 2014. While [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As crypto proponents look to onboard a new generation of users, one of the major consumer onramps has been a host of consumer wallet apps with slick interfaces.</p>
<p>Today, Coinbase <a href="https://twitter.com/CoinbaseWallet/status/1463589935085142020" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that it is bringing on the team from <a href="https://brd.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BRD</a> &#8212; a crypto wallet startup that first launched its mobile wallet back in 2014. While the team is transitioning over to Coinbase, BRD&#8217;s co-founders say nothing will be changing for BRD users for the time being, and that their wallets will continue to operate normally and that user &#8220;funds are safe and secure.&#8221;</p>
<p>The wallet startup was an early player in the mobile crypto wallet space that started as a place for users to store bitcoin, but grew to support a wide network of tokens and the ability to buy, sell and swap cryptocurrencies thanks to partnerships with exchanges. The startup claims to have more than 10 million users.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2239511" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;The team brings deep expertise in self-custody for crypto wallets, which will help Wallet enable more people to safely and securely access the decentralized world of crypto,&#8221; a <a href="https://twitter.com/CoinbaseWallet/status/1463589935085142020?s=20" target="_blank" rel="noopener">tweet</a> from the Coinbase Wallet Twitter account reads.</p>
<p>BRD raised a hefty amount of venture capital funding, banking nearly $55 million in venture funding from firms like SBI Crypto Investment and East Ventures.</p>
<p>Coinbase and BRD did not reveal terms of the acqui-hire.</p>
<p>Co-founder Adam Traidman and Aaron Voisine note that they plan to build out a &#8220;migration path&#8221; for users to transfer their wallet contents to the Coinbase Wallet app but that it will be entirely optional for users.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6eXYzduXNn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/cryptocurrency-wallet-brd-reaches-6-million-users-driven-by-growth-in-latin-america-and-india/">Cryptocurrency wallet BRD reaches 6 million users, driven by growth in Latin America and India</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cryptocurrency wallet BRD reaches 6 million users, driven by growth in Latin America and India&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/cryptocurrency-wallet-brd-reaches-6-million-users-driven-by-growth-in-latin-america-and-india/embed/#?secret=6eXYzduXNn" data-secret="6eXYzduXNn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/coinbase-acquihires-team-behind-brd-crypto-wallet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2239511</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gift Guide: Black Friday tech deals that really are worth looking at</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/best-black-friday-tech-gadget-deals/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/best-black-friday-tech-gadget-deals/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Backbone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gift Guide 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roku]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2239483</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It is, somehow, that time again! Thanksgiving is hours away, which means it's time to figure out what, if anything, you want to buy on Black Friday.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome to TechCrunch’s 2021 Holiday Gift Guide! Need help with gift ideas? We’ve got lots of them. We’re just starting to roll out this year’s gift guides, so <a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2021/">check back from now until the end of December for more</a>! </em></p>
<p>It is, somehow, that time again! Thanksgiving is hours away, which means it&#8217;s time to figure out what, if anything, you want to buy on Black Friday.</p>
<p><em>Should</em> you buy anything on Black Friday? It depends. Some people are able to make a game out of it and save a stack on things they were going to buy anyway. Others end up getting fleeced by sales that aren&#8217;t really sales or end-of-life TVs repackaged under new model numbers.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2239483" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>There definitely <em>are</em> deals to be found, of course — you&#8217;ve just gotta be smart about it. Some of the things we like to keep in mind:</p>
<ul>
<li>Buying stuff you already wanted, at a discount? Good. Buying stuff you didn&#8217;t want, just because it&#8217;s maybe cheaper? Not so good.</li>
<li>Make sure that thing you&#8217;re buying is <em>actually on sale</em>, and that they didn&#8217;t just hike the price up temporarily yesterday for the sake of &#8220;discounts&#8221; today. Historical price trackers like <a href="https://camelcamelcamel.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">camelcamelcamel</a> can help with that.</li>
<li>Check the model number on anything you&#8217;re buying. If you can&#8217;t find any trace of it older than a few weeks, something fishy might be going on.</li>
</ul>
<p>With all that said, here are some of the generally good deals we&#8217;ve found around the web — the stuff that&#8217;s solid, battle-tested and that we&#8217;d probably recommend at <em>full</em> price. We&#8217;ll be adding more throughout the week as we find them.</p>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic">This article contains links to affiliate partners where available. When you buy through these links, TechCrunch may earn an affiliate commission.</i></p>
<h2>Apple devices</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1905287" style="width: 3018px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1905287" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1905287 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DSCF8428.jpg" alt="Airpods Pro" width="3008" height="2000" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DSCF8428.jpg 3008w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DSCF8428.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DSCF8428.jpg?resize=300,199 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DSCF8428.jpg?resize=768,511 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DSCF8428.jpg?resize=680,452 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DSCF8428.jpg?resize=1536,1021 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DSCF8428.jpg?resize=2048,1362 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DSCF8428.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 3008px) 100vw, 3008px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1905287" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater/TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>Not too long ago, discounts on Apple gear were a rare sight — nowadays, though, it&#8217;s not too tough to at least save a couple bucks.</p>
<p>For example: Amazon&#8217;s got the latest non-pro AirPods <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09JQL3NWT/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B09JQL3NWT&amp;linkId=ae3965bc1d8487dd562f245dfd98c907" target="_blank" rel="noopener">down to $155</a> (usually $179), the AirPod Pros <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09JQMJHXY/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B09JQMJHXY&amp;linkId=7eeebf9831bb39c5ac40ffb1a4ed099f" target="_blank" rel="noopener">down to $159</a> (usually $190+) and the over ear AirPods Max <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08PZHYWJS/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B08PZHYWJS&amp;linkId=4ba59eabbaee9a54bebfed47a7ba0194" target="_blank" rel="noopener">down to $429</a> (from $549)</p>
<p>Amazon&#8217;s also got the best iPad Pro deal we&#8217;ve found so far, taking anywhere from $100 to $150 off the 2021 12.9&#8243; model — so <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0932D45W8/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B0932D45W8&amp;linkId=aafcca709f116db06b542ef2b24f5547" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$999 for the 128 GB base model</a>, for example, instead of $1099.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2046659" style="width: 2890px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2046659" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2046659 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/apple-watch-se.jpg" alt="" width="2880" height="1620" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/apple-watch-se.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/apple-watch-se.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/apple-watch-se.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/apple-watch-se.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/apple-watch-se.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/apple-watch-se.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/apple-watch-se.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/apple-watch-se.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2880px) 100vw, 2880px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2046659" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>Best Buy has the generally more budget-friendly 40 mm Apple Watch SE <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/apple-watch-se-gps-40mm-space-gray-aluminum-case-with-sport-band-space-gray/5706649.p?skuId=5706649" target="_blank" rel="noopener">marked down to $219</a>, normally $279. If you&#8217;re looking for the latest and greatest Apple Watch, your best bet is probably Amazon again, where the Series 7 has been <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09HDXS1DM/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B09HDXS1DM&amp;linkId=04e8fb151f3a45d5a638b18359b1776a">cut down to $379</a> instead of $399 — but know that inventory seems limited and you might not get the color/band you want.</p>
<p>Big discounts on M1 Macs seem rare right now — which makes sense, as they&#8217;re still relatively new. When they do pop up, stock seems to be limited or shipping is delayed well into next year. Apple will be giving out $100 gift cards with the purchase of eligible Macs (which, sadly, appears to exclude the 14&#8243; and 16&#8243; M1 MacBook Pros) but that deal seemingly doesn&#8217;t start until the actual morning of Black Friday</p>
<h2>Amazon devices</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1856217" style="width: 1400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1856217" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1856217 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/echo-show-5.jpeg" alt="echo show 5" width="1390" height="1042" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/echo-show-5.jpeg 1390w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/echo-show-5.jpeg?resize=150,112 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/echo-show-5.jpeg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/echo-show-5.jpeg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/echo-show-5.jpeg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/echo-show-5.jpeg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1390px) 100vw, 1390px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1856217" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater/TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>Amazon usually does pretty deep discounts on its own gear for Black Friday, and that&#8217;s holding true this year.</p>
<p>The 4K Fire TV stick, for example, is <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08XVYZ1Y5/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B08XVYZ1Y5&amp;linkId=bb5170f404a23e8cf5d08594c0aa94c6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">down to $25</a> (normally $50).</p>
<p>Their latest-gen Kindle, meanwhile, is <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07FRJLSFL/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B07FRJLSFL&amp;linkId=95218459756e8c8172572f663f504d31" target="_blank" rel="noopener">down to $70</a> (normally $110) if you buy the version that doesn&#8217;t come with ads splashed around the interface. If you don&#8217;t mind the ads, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07DPMXZZ7/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B07DPMXZZ7&amp;linkId=d277e71c19ea0cd22aa916de08415e05" target="_blank" rel="noopener">it&#8217;s $50</a> (normally $90).</p>
<p>Got a smart house full of Echo devices and want to add some more? The latest (4th gen) model is <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07XKF5RM3/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B07XKF5RM3&amp;linkId=82811add059421ae5c09b8a6ef294bb4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">down to $60</a> (usually $80-$100). The 2021 Echo Show, with its camera and 5.5&#8243; display, is <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08J8FFJ8H/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B08J8FFJ8H&amp;linkId=478e5a01c294d6f133ee50fc9c12ae08" target="_blank" rel="noopener">down to $45</a> (usually around $80), and the itty-bitty (if probably at the end of its lifespan) Echo Dot puck is <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07FZ8S74R/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B07FZ8S74R&amp;linkId=07214f0a4cf484ff6ab8908ee88f1a15" target="_blank" rel="noopener">down to $20</a> (usually $30).</p>
<h2>Google devices</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2054077" style="width: 2494px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2054077" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2054077 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Google-Chromecast-with-Google-TV.jpg" alt="" width="2484" height="1396" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Google-Chromecast-with-Google-TV.jpg 2484w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Google-Chromecast-with-Google-TV.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Google-Chromecast-with-Google-TV.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Google-Chromecast-with-Google-TV.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Google-Chromecast-with-Google-TV.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Google-Chromecast-with-Google-TV.jpg?resize=1536,863 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Google-Chromecast-with-Google-TV.jpg?resize=2048,1151 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Google-Chromecast-with-Google-TV.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2484px) 100vw, 2484px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2054077" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits: </strong>Google</p></div></p>
<p>Not to be outdone, Google&#8217;s got a bunch of discounts on its own devices, as well.</p>
<p>Chromecast with Google TV (the Chromecast with the remote) is <a href="https://store.google.com/config/chromecast_google_tv?hl=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener">down to $40</a> (usually $50).</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2083613" style="width: 1010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2083613" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2083613 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/google-nest-audio.png" alt="" width="1000" height="562" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/google-nest-audio.png 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/google-nest-audio.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/google-nest-audio.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/google-nest-audio.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/google-nest-audio.png?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/google-nest-audio.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2083613" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>Most of the company&#8217;s Nest stuff has been marked down — the Nest Audio smart speaker is down to $60 (usually $100), their Nest WiFi router mesh access points are <a href="https://store.google.com/config/nest_wifi?hl=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener">down $30 each</a> and the latest Nest Hub smart display has been <a href="https://store.google.com/config/nest_hub_2nd_gen?hl=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener">discounted to $50</a> (usually $100.) Even Nest&#8217;s relatively new outdoor camera is <a href="https://store.google.com/config/nest_cam_battery?hl=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener">down to $150</a> (normally $180).</p>
<h2>Roku</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2204902" style="width: 1510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2204902" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2204902 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roku-Streaming-Stick-4K-1.png" alt="" width="1500" height="844" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roku-Streaming-Stick-4K-1.png 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roku-Streaming-Stick-4K-1.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roku-Streaming-Stick-4K-1.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roku-Streaming-Stick-4K-1.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roku-Streaming-Stick-4K-1.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roku-Streaming-Stick-4K-1.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1500px) 100vw, 1500px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2204902" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Roku</p></div></p>
<p>Looking to stay out of the Apple/Google/Amazon ecosystems but still want a solid streaming device for your TV? Roku&#8217;s got a few options: The Roku Streaming Stick 4K is <a href="https://www.roku.com/products/roku-streaming-stick-4k" target="_blank" rel="noopener">down to $30</a> (generally $50), while one of their sound bars — the smaller Streambar, not the Streambar Pro — is <a href="https://www.roku.com/products/audio/roku-streambar" target="_blank" rel="noopener">down to $80</a> (generally $130.)</p>
<h2>Oculus Quest 2</h2>
<div class="mceTemp"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_1819803" style="width: 5130px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1819803" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1819803 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Oculus-Quest-2.jpg" alt="" width="5120" height="2880" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Oculus-Quest-2.jpg 5120w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Oculus-Quest-2.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Oculus-Quest-2.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Oculus-Quest-2.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Oculus-Quest-2.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Oculus-Quest-2.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Oculus-Quest-2.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Oculus-Quest-2.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 5120px) 100vw, 5120px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1819803" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Meta/Oculus</p></div></p>
<p>Oculus&#8217; Quest 2 virtual reality headset is about as good as entry-level VR gets right now. If you&#8217;re just looking to dabble or otherwise don&#8217;t want to spend a zillion dollars on a megapowerful VR rig, the Quest 2 is really a good place to start. I&#8217;ve happily recommended it to a bunch of people at the full price … so at a discount? Absolutely.</p>
<p>The best deal I&#8217;ve found so far is Target&#8217;s, where you&#8217;ll get a $50 Target gift card with either the <a href="https://www.target.com/p/oculus-quest-2-advanced-all-in-one-virtual-reality-headset-128gb/-/A-83984421" target="_blank" rel="noopener">128 GB</a> ($300) or <a href="https://www.target.com/p/oculus-quest-2-advanced-all-in-one-virtual-reality-headset-256gb/-/A-84022117" target="_blank" rel="noopener">256 GB</a> ($400) model.</p>
<h2>Backbone</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2239486" style="width: 1146px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2239486" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2239486 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/backbone.jpg" alt="" width="1136" height="572" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/backbone.jpg 1136w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/backbone.jpg?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/backbone.jpg?resize=300,151 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/backbone.jpg?resize=768,387 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/backbone.jpg?resize=680,342 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/backbone.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1136px) 100vw, 1136px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2239486" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Backbone</p></div></p>
<p>If you often use your iPhone* for things like Apple Arcade or remotely playing games on an Xbox or PlayStation, the Backbone is a very, <em>very</em> good controller add-on. It snaps on quick, it&#8217;s solid as a rock, and it&#8217;s <em>way</em> more comfortable than trying to paw at the touchscreen.</p>
<p>I thought it was almost too cheap at $99, but now they&#8217;ve marked it <a href="https://playbackbone.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">down to $85 for Black Friday</a> — and they&#8217;ve thrown in three months of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate for good measure. That&#8217;s a steal, honestly.</p>
<p><em>(* They recently added support for controlling other devices via wired USB, but that&#8217;s more of a neat bonus and less the main draw.)</em></p>
<h2>Apps and Services</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1962460" style="width: 1610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1962460" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1962460 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hulu-on-Xfinity-Hulu-Screens.jpg" alt="" width="1600" height="900" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hulu-on-Xfinity-Hulu-Screens.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hulu-on-Xfinity-Hulu-Screens.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hulu-on-Xfinity-Hulu-Screens.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hulu-on-Xfinity-Hulu-Screens.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hulu-on-Xfinity-Hulu-Screens.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hulu-on-Xfinity-Hulu-Screens.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hulu-on-Xfinity-Hulu-Screens.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1962460" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Hulu</p></div></p>
<p>A few tried-and-true apps and services are offering deals, albeit often with caveats. For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>Hulu will give you a year of <a href="https://www.hulu.com/gma" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ad-supported Hulu</a> for 99 cents a month, instead of $7 a month. The catch? It&#8217;s only for those who are new and &#8220;returning&#8221; subscribers, the latter defined as those who haven&#8217;t paid for Hulu in the last month.</li>
<li>If you don&#8217;t already have Disney+, Amazon is doing a kind of confusing deal as a tie-in with Amazon Music Unlimited. If you already have Amazon Music Unlimited, they&#8217;ll give you three months of Disney+ for free. If you don&#8217;t already have it and are willing to sign up for the $8 per month service, they&#8217;ll give you six months of Disney+.</li>
<li>Plex is selling its lifetime pass option, usually $120, <a href="https://www.plex.tv/black-friday/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">for $90</a>.</li>
<li>Adobe is selling its &#8220;All Apps&#8221; package — so access to Photoshop, Illustrator, Lightroom, Audition and everything else Adobe makes under the Creative Cloud umbrella — for <a href="https://www.adobe.com/creativecloud/plans.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$30 a month</a>, down from $52. Sadly, terms specify &#8220;first-time subscribers&#8221; only.</li>
<li>Popular password manager LastPass is <a href="https://www.lastpass.com/plans-and-pricing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">offering plans for 25% off</a> this week. USE A PASSWORD MANAGER.</li>
<li>Guided meditation app <a href="https://www.headspace.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Headspace</a> is 50%-60% off right now, depending on if you&#8217;re paying monthly or annually. If monthly, it&#8217;s 60% off — $4.99 a month, instead of $12.99. If annually, it&#8217;s 50% off — which might sound like a smaller discount, but at $35 for a year (normally $70), you&#8217;re paying about $2.91 per month (usually around $6.) Both plans renew at their respective full price after the first year.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/gift-guide-2021-banner.jpg" alt="TechCrunch Gift Guide 2021" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/best-black-friday-tech-gadget-deals/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2239483</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Robots and AI assist in designing and building Swiss university&#8217;s &#8216;hanging gardens&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/robots-and-ai-assist-in-designing-and-building-swiss-universitys-hanging-gardens/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/robots-and-ai-assist-in-designing-and-building-swiss-universitys-hanging-gardens/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 20:44:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETHZ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robots]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2239484</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Architecture and construction have always been, rather quietly, at the bleeding edge of tech and materials trends. It&#8217;s no surprise, then, especially at a renowned technical university like ETH Zurich, to find a project utilizing AI and robotics in a new approach to these arts. The automated design and construction they are experimenting with show [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Architecture and construction have always been, rather quietly, at the bleeding edge of tech and materials trends. It&#8217;s no surprise, then, especially at a renowned technical university like ETH Zurich, to find a project utilizing AI and robotics in a new approach to these arts. The automated design and construction they are experimenting with show how homes and offices might be built a decade from now.</p>
<p>The project is a sort of huge sculptural planter, &#8220;hanging gardens&#8221; inspired by the legendary structures in the ancient city of Babylon. (Incidentally, it was my ancestor, Robert Koldewey, who excavated/looted the famous <a href="https://www.livescience.com/43036-ishtar-gate.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ishtar Gate</a> to the place.)</p>
<p>Begun in 2019, Semiramis (named after the queen of Babylon back then) is a collaboration between human and AI designers. The general idea of course came from the creative minds of its creators, architecture professors <a href="https://gramaziokohler.arch.ethz.ch/web/d/projekte/409.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fabio Gramazio and Matthias Kohler</a>. But the design was achieved by putting the basic requirements, such as size, the necessity of watering and the style of construction, through a set of computer models and machine learning algorithms.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2239484" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>During the design process, for example, the team might tweak the position of one of the large &#8220;pods&#8221; that make up the 70-foot structure, or change the layout of the panels that make up its surface. The software they created would then immediately adjust the geometry of the overall structure and the other panels to accommodate these changes, making sure it would still safely bear its own weight, and so on.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2239519" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2239519" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2239519" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg" alt="Computer rendering of what the final Semiramis hanging garden structure will look like." width="1024" height="689" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg?resize=300,202 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg?resize=768,517 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg?resize=680,458 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg?resize=1536,1033 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg?resize=2048,1378 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/semiramis-render.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2239519" class="wp-caption-text">Computer rendering of what the final Semiramis hanging garden structure will look like. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Gramazio Kohler Research</p></div></p>
<p>There are many automated processes in architecture, of course, but this project pushes the boundaries out in the level of final control seemingly given to them. The point, after all, is to make it a genuine collaboration, not just a sort of architectural spell-check that makes sure the whole thing won&#8217;t collapse.</p>
<p>&#8220;The computer model lets us reverse the conventional design process and explore the full design scope for a project. This leads to new, often surprising geometries,&#8221; <a href="https://ethz.ch/en/news-and-events/eth-news/news/2021/11/robots-build-new-hanging-gardens.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kohler said in an ETHZ news post</a>.</p>
<p>Having arrived at a final design, the construction is being accomplished by another human-automation team: a set of four robotic arms operating with one mind to hold multiple heavy pieces (each pod has dozens) in place while humans apply the resin used to keep them together. It&#8217;s a step above the technique <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/22/hold-this-beam-for-me-friend-robot-and-let-us-construct-a-house-together/">we saw used a few years ago</a> by the same team when they used robots as automated assistants.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qR92gbOxfU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/22/hold-this-beam-for-me-friend-robot-and-let-us-construct-a-house-together/">Hold this beam for me, friend robot, and let us construct a house together</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hold this beam for me, friend robot, and let us construct a house together&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/22/hold-this-beam-for-me-friend-robot-and-let-us-construct-a-house-together/embed/#?secret=qR92gbOxfU" data-secret="qR92gbOxfU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Semiramis is being constructed in the workshop then shipped piece by piece to its eventual home at Tech Cluster Zug. It should be fully assembled and ready to accept soil and seeds this coming spring, so stop by if you&#8217;re in the area.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/robots-and-ai-assist-in-designing-and-building-swiss-universitys-hanging-gardens/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2239484</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TabTrader raises $5.8M for a mobile app that aggregates crypto exchange data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/tabtrader-raises-5-8m-for-a-mobile-app-that-aggregates-crypto-exchange-data/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/tabtrader-raises-5-8m-for-a-mobile-app-that-aggregates-crypto-exchange-data/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 20:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[100X Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amsterdam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Decentralized Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hashkey Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SGH Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sosv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spartan Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2239428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As many of the top cryptocurrencies seem to temporarily stabilize near all-time highs, users looking to speculate on tokens that are a bit more volatile are searching across exchanges to find deals. Amsterdam-based startup TabTrader has been capitalizing on this search with a platform that aggregates prices and token availability across dozens of exchanges. While [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As many of the top cryptocurrencies seem to temporarily stabilize near all-time highs, users looking to speculate on tokens that are a bit more volatile are searching across exchanges to find deals.</p>
<p>Amsterdam-based startup <a href="https://tab-trader.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TabTrader</a> has been capitalizing on this search with a platform that aggregates prices and token availability across dozens of exchanges. While other platforms allow users to look at token prices across exchanges, most are desktop-optimized while TabTrader has built up a substantial presence for its mobile app on iOS and Android.</p>
<p>As different exchanges take different approaches toward onboarding new tokens, crypto traders are increasingly signing up for accounts on multiple exchanges and tracking prices across multiple apps with multiple notification types set for each. Many users rely on TabTrader for its cross-exchange price alert feature, notifying users when a particular token has gone above or below a certain value. While plenty of exchanges offer this functionality inside their native apps, the reliability and customizability of these push notifications has often been inconsistent.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2239428" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>CEO Kirill Suslov tells TechCrunch that the TabTrader app has more than 400,000 active users, with particularly strong presences in Europe and Asia.</p>
<p>The startup has adopted a Kayak-like model, aggregating prices for tokens and picking up rebate fees from exchanges when users make a purchase through the app. While users plug their wallet info into the app to easily make purchases through connected exchanges, Suslov says that TabTrader never has access to user funds.</p>
<p>Alongside these rebates, TabTrader also makes money through a $12 monthly subscription for a paid version, as well as advertising. Suslov says his 20-person team has scaled to reach their current audience without any paid marketing.</p>
<p>While tens of millions of users have created accounts on centralized exchanges like Coinbase and Binance, Suslov says that TabTrader&#8217;s biggest opportunity may be embracing so-called decentralized exchanges like Uniswap, which allow users to rapidly exchange tokens with other users.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Suslov says that while the exchanges have built out great technology in the back-end, the front-end interfaces aren&#8217;t as easy for users to navigate, leaving room for an aggregator like TabTrader to streamline the user experience while allowing users to explore decentralized exchanges for the first time. The startup says they&#8217;re starting with a number of Solana-based exchanges including Serum, Raydium and Orca.</p>
<p>&#8220;[Decentralized exchanges] are the hottest topic of 2021,&#8221; Suslov says.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> &#8220;</span>We raised to get onto this rocket ship.&#8221;</p>
<p>Suslov tells TechCrunch that TabTrader has banked $5.8 million in Series A funding from 100X Ventures, Hashkey Capital, Spartan Capital, SGH Capital, SOSV and Artesian Venture Partners.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/tabtrader-raises-5-8m-for-a-mobile-app-that-aggregates-crypto-exchange-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2239428</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gift Guide: Give the gift of cannabis with these 9 high-tech smoking devices</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/gift-guide-give-the-gift-of-cannabis-with-these-9-high-tech-smoking-devices/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/gift-guide-give-the-gift-of-cannabis-with-these-9-high-tech-smoking-devices/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 20:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cannabis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gift Guide 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2237982</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cannabis is quickly going to the nerds. As it gradually becomes legal around the world, startups have responded with innovative products from laser-powered water bongs to CNC machined vapes to AI-powered herb grinders. Got a friend who wants to get a bit fancy with it? Give&#8217;m the gift of high-tech consumption. Please consume responsibility. Throughout [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Cannabis is quickly going to the nerds. As it gradually becomes legal around the world, startups have responded with innovative products from laser-powered water bongs to CNC machined vapes to AI-powered herb grinders. Got a friend who wants to get a bit fancy with it? Give&#8217;m the gift of high-tech consumption.</p>
<p>Please consume responsibility.</p>
<p>Throughout 2021, cannabis companies made major strides on the back of unprecedented consumer demand. Companies like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/in-new-round-dutchie-focused-on-smoother-cannabis-retail-sees-its-valuation-soar-by-eight-times/">Dutchie</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/cannabis-e-commerce-startup-jane-technologies-raises-100m-after-stellar-growth/">Jane Technologies</a> raised hundreds of millions in new venture financing, leading to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/14/cannabis-investment-jumps-82-the-second-half-of-2021-165-over-2020-levels/">industry investments climbing 82%</a> in the second half of 2021. Others companies like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/cannabis-giant-leafly-is-going-public-through-a-spac-merger/">Leafly</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/08/agrify-aims-to-be-the-fastest-growing-cannabis-company/">Agrify</a> turned to public markets to raise new capital. Amazon<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/amazon-to-stop-screening-employees-for-marijuana/"> stopped screening</a> employees for marijuana, and Apple started treating cannabis as it does with pharmaceuticals and started letting users order and pay for cannabis in apps (in places where that&#8217;s legal).</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2237982" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>There&#8217;s high hopes for cannabis in 2022. Cannabis is now legal for use in 36 states, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/cannabis-banking-act-passes-u-s-house-with-bipartisan-support/">there&#8217;s traction in Washington</a> that could end its federal prohibition.</p>
<h2>Puffco Budsy</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2238047" style="width: 3300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238047" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2238047 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.40.45-PM.jpg" alt="" width="3290" height="2084" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.40.45-PM.jpg 3290w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.40.45-PM.jpg?resize=150,95 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.40.45-PM.jpg?resize=300,190 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.40.45-PM.jpg?resize=768,486 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.40.45-PM.jpg?resize=680,431 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.40.45-PM.jpg?resize=1536,973 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.40.45-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1297 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.40.45-PM.jpg?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 3290px) 100vw, 3290px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2238047" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Puffco</p></div></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.puffco.com/products/budsy?variant=39699376799803" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Puffco Budsy</a> is a fantastic discrete water bong, and it&#8217;s nearly invisible thanks to the Nalgene-style bottle. Just throw some water in the bottle, pack flower in the hidden bowl and hit the trails. When you&#8217;re ready, flip up the lid, hit the bud with a lighter and inhale from the spout (which is thankfully not connected to the water). Rinse and repeat. Puffco released the Budsy on April 1, 2021 but it wasn&#8217;t a joke. This product is real, and it&#8217;s a lot of fun.</p>
<p>Roger Volodarsky founded the company in 2013 and has since led the company as CEO. Over the last several years, the company has kept pushing forward into innovative dabbing products. The Puffco Peak Pro (below) even features interchangeable ovens to allow owners to tailor their smoking experience without buying a new rig.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$50 and up</p>
<h2>Dynavap</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2238005" style="width: 777px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238005" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2238005 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RS5001_32A1631-3__FillWzc2Nyw1MDBd.jpeg" alt="" width="767" height="500" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RS5001_32A1631-3__FillWzc2Nyw1MDBd.jpeg 767w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RS5001_32A1631-3__FillWzc2Nyw1MDBd.jpeg?resize=150,98 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RS5001_32A1631-3__FillWzc2Nyw1MDBd.jpeg?resize=300,196 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RS5001_32A1631-3__FillWzc2Nyw1MDBd.jpeg?resize=680,443 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/RS5001_32A1631-3__FillWzc2Nyw1MDBd.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 100vw, 767px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2238005" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Dynavap</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://www.dynavap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dynavaps</a> are my go-to smoking device. They&#8217;re pocketable, batteryless and produce a great cloud of vapor. Think of it as a one-hitter vape with a thermometer. First, heat the tip with a torch or induction heater. In about 3-5 seconds, the cap will click, notifying the user that the herb is at the right temperature and ready to hit. The cannabis lasts about 3-4 cycles. Best yet, since the cap protects the ground flower from the flame, there&#8217;s no combustion or smoke &#8212; just vapor &#8212; and there&#8217;s very little smell.</p>
<p>Dynavap vaporizers are CNC machined in the company&#8217;s De Forest, Wisconsin facility. George Breiwa started the company in 2015 and currently employs around 40 people. Dynvap sells several versions of the little metal vape, including this <a href="https://www.dynavap.com/dynashop/ocs/the-gentleman-pipe-1/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">stately &#8220;gentleman&#8217;s pipe&#8221;</a> and the sleek, all-black Obsidium Omni for $250.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$60 and up</p>
<h2>GPen Dash</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2238024" style="width: 2058px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238024" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2238024 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/245466363_4622376851134968_4546454484048683858_n.jpeg" alt="" width="2048" height="1365" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/245466363_4622376851134968_4546454484048683858_n.jpeg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/245466363_4622376851134968_4546454484048683858_n.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/245466363_4622376851134968_4546454484048683858_n.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/245466363_4622376851134968_4546454484048683858_n.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/245466363_4622376851134968_4546454484048683858_n.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/245466363_4622376851134968_4546454484048683858_n.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/245466363_4622376851134968_4546454484048683858_n.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2048px) 100vw, 2048px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2238024" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Grenco Science</p></div></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.gpen.com/products/g-pen-dash" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GPen Dash</a> is the GoPro of vapes. This tiny vaporizer is impressive: It costs $70 and hits above its weight. The little vape has a glass-coated stainless steel heating chamber and a clean air path. The hits are smooth and plentiful. The GPen Dash is a great grab-and-go vape. Pictured here is one of the special versions; the company teamed with the nonprofit breast cancer prevention foundation Keep A Breast and made this limited edition.</p>
<p>Co-founder and CEO Chris Folkerts started Grenco Science with Anthony Barron in 2011. The company sells a wide range of vaporizers, including a portable dab rig and a battery-powered concentrate vaporizer for glass stems. In May 2020 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/01/grenco-science-acquires-stundenglass-a-contactless-water-pipe-company-founded-by-ex-apple-employee/">Grenco Science acquired Stündenglass</a>, a company founded by an ex-Apple employee that makes high-end gravity bongs.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$70</p>
<h2>Blazy Susan</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2238013" style="width: 2166px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238013" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2238013 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.07.19-PM.jpg" alt="" width="2156" height="1526" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.07.19-PM.jpg 2156w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.07.19-PM.jpg?resize=150,106 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.07.19-PM.jpg?resize=300,212 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.07.19-PM.jpg?resize=768,544 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.07.19-PM.jpg?resize=680,481 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.07.19-PM.jpg?resize=1536,1087 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.07.19-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1450 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.07.19-PM.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2156px) 100vw, 2156px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2238013" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Blazy Susan</p></div></p>
<p>There&#8217;s no tech here. The <a href="https://blazysusan.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blazy Susan</a> isn&#8217;t, technically, a high-tech gift. I don&#8217;t care. This is my list. The Blazy Susan is just a lovely weed station with little compartments to hold different toking accoutrements. There&#8217;s a dab station, a bowl cleaner and silicon inserts to make cleaning a bit easier. Prices start at around $90 and are available in different types of wood.</p>
<p>The company was started by Will Breakell and is based out of Colorado. The company also sells rolling papers, cones, grinders and a bunch of merch &#8212; everything is pink and I love it.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$90</p>
<h2>Banana Bros’ OTTO AI-enabled Grinder</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2238076" style="width: 2710px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238076" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2238076 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Banana_Bros_OTTO.jpeg" alt="" width="2700" height="1800" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Banana_Bros_OTTO.jpeg 2700w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Banana_Bros_OTTO.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Banana_Bros_OTTO.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Banana_Bros_OTTO.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Banana_Bros_OTTO.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Banana_Bros_OTTO.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Banana_Bros_OTTO.jpeg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Banana_Bros_OTTO.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2700px) 100vw, 2700px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2238076" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Banana Bros</p></div></p>
<p><em>Surprise Guest! TC&#8217;s Amanda Silberling dropped by the gift guide to add this:</em></p>
<p>If you’re still using that cheap grinder you bought on Amazon, you’re probably wondering why anyone needs an AI-powered grinder. Here&#8217;s why: The <a href="https://bananabros.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OTTO</a> considers the density, moisture level, texture and consistency of your flower, then adjusts the speed, pressure and even the grind direction. Then, the OTTO deposits the perfect ground flower into a magnetically attached chamber and evenly distributes it into a pre-rolled cone. The result is luxurious &#8212; so long as you’re not an elitist who thinks cones are a cop-out (but if you are, you can just use the grinder on its own).</p>
<p>Banana Bros says the OTTO can grind perfect herbs, spices and incense, but even though the grinder is easy to clean, you’d probably end up with slightly sedative cinnamon or strangely flavorful cones if you’re not careful. At $150, this thing isn’t cheap, but it gets the job done. Banana Bros was founded in 2017 by CEO Dave Richmond and Director of Innovation Manny Montano, whose background is in industrial and 3D design. They’ve patented the AI technology that powers the OTTO, which is the company’s first and flagship product.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$149</p>
<h2>Storz &amp; Bickel Mighty+</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2238032" style="width: 2070px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238032" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2238032 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.24.17-PM.jpg" alt="Storz &amp; Bickel Mighty+" width="2060" height="1398" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.24.17-PM.jpg 2060w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.24.17-PM.jpg?resize=150,102 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.24.17-PM.jpg?resize=300,204 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.24.17-PM.jpg?resize=768,521 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.24.17-PM.jpg?resize=680,461 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.24.17-PM.jpg?resize=1536,1042 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.24.17-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1390 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.24.17-PM.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2060px) 100vw, 2060px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2238032" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Storz &amp; Bickel</p></div></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.storz-bickel.com/en-us/mighty-plus" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mighty+</a> is the best vaporizer available. It&#8217;s reliable, can cook a lot of herb and produces some of the best vapor from any device. Sure, there are drawbacks, including its large size and $399 price, but it&#8217;s worth it. Storz &amp; Bickel released the original in 2014 and<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/storz-bickle-new-mighty-vape-features-faster-heating-usb-c-and-ul-certification/"> just released the updated version in October 2021</a>. The new Mighty+ features quicker heat-up time, USB-C recharging and a ceramic filling chamber that&#8217;s much easier to keep clean than the chamber in the original.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Quick tip:</strong> The Mighty+ features orange arrow buttons while the original&#8217;s are gray.</p></blockquote>
<p>Markus Storz started working on a herbal vaporizer in 1996 and in 2002 Jürgen Bickel joined the board forming Storz-Bickel. The company still sells its original, groundbreaking device, the Volcano, and several less expensive products. The company is based in Germany, where its vaporizers carry medical device certifications. In 2018 Canadian cannabis giant Canopy Growth acquired Storz &amp; Bickel. Jürgen Bickel remains at the company and runs the day-to-day operations.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$399</p>
<h2>Puffco Peak Pro</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2238050" style="width: 2276px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238050" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2238050 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.47.13-PM.jpg" alt="Puffco Peak Pro" width="2266" height="1780" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.47.13-PM.jpg 2266w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.47.13-PM.jpg?resize=150,118 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.47.13-PM.jpg?resize=300,236 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.47.13-PM.jpg?resize=768,603 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.47.13-PM.jpg?resize=680,534 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.47.13-PM.jpg?resize=1536,1207 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.47.13-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1609 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.47.13-PM.jpg?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2266px) 100vw, 2266px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2238050" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Puffco</p></div></p>
<p>Into dabbing? The <a href="https://www.puffco.com/products/the-peak-pro" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Puffco Peak Pro</a> is the best portable dabbing rig available. It produces an amazing cloud of tasty vapor and feels like something designed in Cupertino. The Puffco Peak Pro constantly impresses me. The Pro version packs USB-C charging, an improved oven and easier cleaning. Plus, there&#8217;s an optional wireless charging stand that works very well. Want something more unique? The company sells a handful of special editions that feature wild color schemes and glass designs.</p>
<p>Roger Volodarsky founded the company in 2013 and has since led the company as CEO. Over the last several years, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/puffco-keeps-innovating-dabbing/">the company has kept pushing forward into innovative dabbing products</a>. The Puffco Peak Pro even features interchangeable ovens to allow owners to tailor their smoking experience without buying a new rig.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$399</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lNPdFLmIUm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/puffco-keeps-innovating-dabbing/">Puffco keeps innovating dabbing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Puffco keeps innovating dabbing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/puffco-keeps-innovating-dabbing/embed/#?secret=lNPdFLmIUm" data-secret="lNPdFLmIUm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Hitoki Trident V2</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2238028" style="width: 1007px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238028" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2238028 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.21.08-PM.jpg" alt="" width="997" height="554" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.21.08-PM.jpg 997w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.21.08-PM.jpg?resize=150,83 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.21.08-PM.jpg?resize=300,167 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.21.08-PM.jpg?resize=768,427 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.21.08-PM.jpg?resize=680,378 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/apple-fall-2021-iphone-2021-11-22-at-12.21.08-PM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 997px) 100vw, 997px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2238028" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Hitoki</p></div></p>
<p>At its core, the <a href="https://hitoki.com/products/trident" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$499 Hitoki Trident V2</a> is a battery-powered water bong. The trick? It uses a laser and sealed chamber to heat the flower. When the device works, it hits like a truck. I tested the Hitoki, and it&#8217;s finicky and requires a lot of cleaning. The hose attachment is low quality, and the laser blasts the herb into a smoldering mess. So why is it on this list? Because despite its drawbacks, the Hitoki is a fun device and can produce an impressive cloud without butane. Plus lasers. You get to watch the laser light the pot and make a miniature mushroom cloud.</p>
<p>Joe and Jack Tran started Hitoki in 2019. The Trident V2 is the company&#8217;s second version of the product. The V2 version includes a carb button, a larger laser burn radius and an improved airflow path.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $499</p>
<h2>Stündenglass Kompact</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2238061" style="width: 2058px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238061" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2238061 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SFIHwn80.jpeg" alt="" width="2048" height="1365" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SFIHwn80.jpeg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SFIHwn80.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SFIHwn80.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SFIHwn80.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SFIHwn80.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SFIHwn80.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SFIHwn80.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2048px) 100vw, 2048px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2238061" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Stundenglass</p></div></p>
<p>The <a href="https://stundenglass.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stündenglass Kompact</a> is a compact version of the amazing Stündenglass gravity bong. The $599 device is made of high-end materials and works very well. Trust me. I&#8217;ve used it, and it&#8217;s smooth, rich and impressive. The device isn&#8217;t just for cannabis. It&#8217;s also a fantastic hookah, and with the right attachments, it can be used to infuse food and drinks with a burst of smokey flavor. Want a bigger hit? The full-size Stündenglass is the same price but is much less portable.</p>
<p>Stündenglass was founded by Tracey Huston and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/01/grenco-science-acquires-stundenglass-a-contactless-water-pipe-company-founded-by-ex-apple-employee/">purchased by Grenco Science in May 2020</a> for an undisclosed amount.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $599</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/gift-guide-2021-banner.jpg" alt="TechCrunch Gift Guide 2021" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/gift-guide-give-the-gift-of-cannabis-with-these-9-high-tech-smoking-devices/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2237982</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Head of Instagram Adam Mosseri will testify before the Senate on teen mental heath</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/head-of-instagram-adam-mosseri-will-testify-before-the-senate-on-teen-mental-heath/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/head-of-instagram-adam-mosseri-will-testify-before-the-senate-on-teen-mental-heath/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adam mosseri]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frances Haugen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[head]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product manager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[senate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The New York Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2239403</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Head of Instagram Adam Mosseri will testify before the Senate for the first time as part of a series of hearings about online safety for children and teens. Per The New York Times, Mosseri&#8217;s hearing will take place on December 6. Mosseri&#8217;s upcoming testimony comes after Sen. Richard Blumenthal (D-CT) wrote a letter to Facebook [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Head of Instagram Adam Mosseri will testify before the Senate for the first time as part of a series of hearings about online safety for children and teens. Per The <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/11/24/technology/adam-mosseri-instagram-testify-congress.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">New York Times</a>, Mosseri&#8217;s hearing will take place on December 6.</p>
<p>Mosseri&#8217;s upcoming testimony comes after Sen. Richard Blumenthal (D-CT) <a href="https://www.blumenthal.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/2021.10.20%20-%20Facebook%20and%20Instagram%20-%20Consumer%20Protection%20Invitation.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote a letter</a> to Facebook (now Meta) CEO Mark Zuckerberg, asking that either he or Mosseri participate in a Senate hearing.</p>
<p>Mosseri posted a video responding to the news of his forthcoming appearance on Capitol Hill. He discussed growing concerns about teen safety online, then outlined past actions Instagram has taken to protect young users, like making young teens&#8217; accounts <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/instagram-to-default-young-teens-to-private-accounts-restrict-ads-and-unwanted-adult-contact/">private by default</a> and restricting the kinds of ads they see.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2239403" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;m going to be talking about these issues with Congress relatively soon,&#8221; Mosseri <a href="https://twitter.com/mosseri" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a>. &#8220;These are important issues, but we all have shared goals. We all want young people to be safe when they&#8217;re online.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">There&#39;s an important discussion happening right now about keeping young people safe online. I&#39;ve been thinking a lot about how Instagram shows up, and I&#39;m looking forward to sharing more of the work we&#39;re doing in the weeks ahead <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f64f-1f3fc.png" alt="🙏🏼" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/dLQNDh6G34">pic.twitter.com/dLQNDh6G34</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Adam Mosseri <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f637.png" alt="😷" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@mosseri) <a href="https://twitter.com/mosseri/status/1463574645584453632?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 24, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>When reports leaked in September about Instagram&#8217;s knowledge of its <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=instagram+bad+teen+girls+wsj&amp;rlz=1C5CHFA_enUS954US954&amp;oq=instagram+bad+teen+girls+wsj&amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.2245j0j1&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">dangerous affects</a> on teen girls, the Senate <a href="https://www.commerce.senate.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Committee on Commerce, Science, &amp; Transportation</a> didn&#8217;t take it lightly. The committee <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/facebook-grilled-in-senate-hearing-over-teen-mental-health/">first questioned</a> Facebook Global Head of Security Antigone Davis, who was reticent to answer direct questions from the Senate. Then weeks later, the committee heard testimony from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-testifies-before-the-senate/">Facebook whistleblower Frances Haugen</a>, a former civic integrity product manager who leaked thousands of internal documents known as the &#8220;<a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/10/25/1049015366/the-facebook-papers-what-you-need-to-know" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Facebook Papers</a>.&#8221; In her hearing, Haugen told the Senate that Facebook cares more about profits than user safety.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;I am disappointed that Facebook has been unwilling to be fully transparent with me, other members of Congress, and the public, and appears to have concealed vital information from us about teen mental health and addiction,&#8221; <a href="https://www.blumenthal.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/2021.10.20%20-%20Facebook%20and%20Instagram%20-%20Consumer%20Protection%20Invitation.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a> Senator Blumenthal, who chairs the Senate committee hosting these hearings. &#8220;When I sought specific information about Instagram and teens in an August letter, Facebook provided clearly evasive and misleading answers that have now been directly disputed by Ms. Haugen.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="k85BjRADYJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/facebook-grilled-in-senate-hearing-over-teen-mental-health/">Facebook grilled in Senate hearing over teen mental health</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook grilled in Senate hearing over teen mental health&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/facebook-grilled-in-senate-hearing-over-teen-mental-health/embed/#?secret=k85BjRADYJ" data-secret="k85BjRADYJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Now, after hearing from executives at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/tiktok-snap-youtube-hearing-congress/">Snap, TikTok and YouTube</a> last month, the committee will convene again to hear from the head of Instagram himself. Given the committee&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/lawmakers-confront-tiktok-snapchat-and-youtube-about-eating-disorder-content/">demonstrated concern</a> about Instagram&#8217;s connection to the onset of adolescent eating disorders, it&#8217;s expected that Mosseri will be questioned about leaked internal studies that Meta conducted about Instagram&#8217;s impact on teen girls.</p>
<p>The internal study, obtained by The <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-knows-instagram-is-toxic-for-teen-girls-company-documents-show-11631620739" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wall Street Journal</a> and later <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/seeking-to-respin-instagrams-toxicity-for-teens-facebook-publishes-annotated-slide-decks/">published by Meta</a> itself, found that Instagram makes body image issues worse for one in three teen girls, and that teens blame Instagram for increases in anxiety and depression. Among teens with suicidal thoughts, the study says that 6% of users traced their desire to die by suicide to Instagram. Plus, 32% of surveyed teen girls reported that when they felt bad about their bodies, Instagram made those feelings worse.</p>
<p>Shortly after these documents were leaked, Mosseri announced that Instagram would <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/instagram-puts-kids-version-on-ice-after-critical-backlash/">pause building</a> <a href="https://about.instagram.com/blog/announcements/pausing-instagram-kids" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Instagram Kids</a>. Meta already has products like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/04/facebook-messenger-kids/">Messenger Kids</a>, which lets users under 13 chat with people approved by their parents.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="m9fpN1GWiX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-testifies-before-the-senate/">Facebook whistleblower Frances Haugen testifies before the Senate</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook whistleblower Frances Haugen testifies before the Senate&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-testifies-before-the-senate/embed/#?secret=m9fpN1GWiX" data-secret="m9fpN1GWiX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;While we stand by the need to develop this experience, we’ve decided to pause this project,&#8221; Mosseri <a href="https://about.instagram.com/blog/announcements/pausing-instagram-kids" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a>. &#8220;This will give us time to work with parents, experts, policymakers and regulators, to listen to their concerns, and to demonstrate the value and importance of this project for younger teens online today.&#8221;</p>
<p>But critics are skeptical of Meta&#8217;s ability to build an Instagram Kids product responsibly. Per research published this month, Facebook allegedly continues to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/16/facebook-accused-of-still-targeting-teens-with-ads/">surveil teens</a> for ad targeting.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is urgent and necessary for you or Mr. Adam Mosseri to testify to set the record straight and provide members of Congress and parents with a plan on how you are going to protect our kids,&#8221; Senator Blumenthal wrote to Zuckerberg.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/head-of-instagram-adam-mosseri-will-testify-before-the-senate-on-teen-mental-heath/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2239403</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ionity lands €700 million investment from BlackRock, automakers to expand EV fast-charging network</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/ionity-investment-blackrock-automakers-expand-fast-charging-network/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/ionity-investment-blackrock-automakers-expand-fast-charging-network/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlackRock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daimler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicle charging stations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ionity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volkswagen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2239397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ionity, an electric vehicle fast-charging charging network provider whose owners include Daimler AG and Volkswagen Group, has scored a €700 million ($783 million) investment from BlackRock Global and existing shareholders to expand its footprint across Europe. The company, which was founded in 2017, installs ultra-high-speed EV charging stations. It was launched as a joint venture [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Ionity, an electric vehicle fast-charging charging network provider whose owners include Daimler AG and Volkswagen Group, has scored a €700 million ($783 million) investment from BlackRock Global and existing shareholders to expand its footprint across Europe.</p>
<p>The company, which was founded in 2017, installs ultra-high-speed EV charging stations. It was launched as a joint venture between a coalition of major automakers that includes Hyundai Motor Group, Ford and BMW. The investment will allow Ionity to increase the number of charging points to 7,000 by 2025 &#8212; a more than four-fold increase from the 1,500 that are installed today.</p>
<p>The new charging stations will be situated on highways and other major roads as well as near major cities. Six to 12 charging points will be at each location, Ionity said in a statement. The firm is also planning on adding more charging points to existing sites with high demand.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2239397" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Ionity&#8217;s planned expansion includes owning and operating full service stations for drivers to &#8220;recharge&#8221; while charging their vehicles. These stations, a concept it&#8217;s calling “Oasis,” are similar to roadside rest stops today.</p>
<p>BlackRock is the first non-automotive company to invest in Ionity, through its Global Renewable Power equity investment vehicle. The investment management company raised $4.8 billion for the fund in April, a sign that institutional investors are increasingly interested in decarbonization technologies.</p>
<p>Its investment also speaks to the growing surety amongst powerful investment players in the forthcoming electric revolution in transportation. Thus far, BlackRock has mostly invested in onshore and offshore wind, and solar-powered projects, so its interest in EV charging is notable.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/ionity-investment-blackrock-automakers-expand-fast-charging-network/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2239397</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spotify tests a TikTok-like vertical video feed in its app</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/spotify-tests-a-tiktok-like-vertical-video-feed-in-its-app/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/spotify-tests-a-tiktok-like-vertical-video-feed-in-its-app/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:08:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chris messina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vertical Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2239363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TikTok has seen its short-form video feed copied by a host of competitors, from Instagram to Snap to YouTube and even Netflix. Now it looks like you can add Spotify to that list. The company has confirmed it&#8217;s currently testing a new feature in its app, Discover, which presents a vertical feed of music videos [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TikTok has seen its short-form video feed copied by a host of competitors, from Instagram to Snap to YouTube and even Netflix. Now it looks like you can add Spotify to that list. The company has confirmed it&#8217;s currently testing a new feature in its app, Discover, which presents a vertical feed of music videos that users can scroll through and optionally like or skip. For those who have access to the feature, it appears as a fourth tab in the navigation bar at the bottom of the Spotify app, in between Home and Search.</p>
<p>The new addition was first spotted by <a href="https://twitter.com/chrismessina/status/1463542273216446472" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chris Messina</a>, who tweeted out a video of the Discover feature in action. He described it as a &#8220;pared-down version&#8221; of a TikTok-style feed of music videos.</p>
<p>Messina told us he found the feature in Spotify&#8217;s TestFlight build (a beta version for iOS), where a new icon in the navigation toolbar brings you immediately to the video feed when tapped. You can then swipe up and down to move through the feed, much like you would on TikTok. In addition to tapping the heart to like songs, you also can tap the three-dot menu to bring up the standard song information sheet, he notes.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2239363" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Messina also speculated the feature may be taking advantage of Spotify&#8217;s existing Canvas format.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Not only that, <a href="https://twitter.com/Spotify?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Spotify</a> Discover is basically a pared down version of a TikTok-style feed of vertical music videos (likely using their canvas format) that you can like or skip.<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NewSpotify?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NewSpotify</a> <a href="https://t.co/hpOEZ8v9bl">pic.twitter.com/hpOEZ8v9bl</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Chris Messina ᵍᵐ (<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4dc.png" alt="📜" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />,<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f56f.png" alt="🕯" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />) (@chrismessina) <a href="https://twitter.com/chrismessina/status/1463542273216446472?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 24, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Introduced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/10/get-ready-to-see-more-looping-videos-on-spotify-as-canvas-launches-into-beta/">broadly in 2019</a>, Canvas allows artists to create videos that accompany their music on the Spotify app. The feature <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/10/get-ready-to-see-more-looping-videos-on-spotify-as-canvas-launches-into-beta/">had mixed reviews</a> from users, as some reported they preferred to see just the static album art when listening to music and found the video and its looping imagery distracting. But others said they liked it. Canvas, however, appears to drive the engagement metrics that Spotify wants &#8212; the company <a href="https://canvas.spotify.com/en-us" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> that users are more likely to keep streaming, share tracks or save tracks when they see a Canvas.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>From the video Messina shared and others we viewed, we can confirm that the videos playing in the vertical feed are the artists&#8217; existing Canvas videos. But Spotify would not confirm this to us directly.</p>
<p>TechCrunch asked Spotify for further information on the feature, including whether it had plans to roll this out further, whether it was available on both iOS and Android, which markets had access to the feature and more. The company declined to share any details about the feature but did confirm, via a statement, it was exploring the idea of a vertical video feed.</p>
<p>&#8220;At Spotify, we routinely conduct a number of tests in an effort to improve our user experience,&#8221; a spokesperson told TechCrunch. &#8220;Some of those tests end up paving the way for our broader user experience and others serve only as an important learning. We don’t have any further news to share at this time,&#8221; they added.</p>
<p>In other words, the test is still very early and may not make its way to the public. But if it did, it wouldn&#8217;t be a surprising move on Spotify&#8217;s part. The company has before looked to popular social media formats to engage its users. In the past, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/21/spotify-test-lets-influencers-post-stories-to-introduce-their-own-playlists/">Spotify tested a Stories feature</a> that allowed influencers to post Stories to introduce their own, curated playlists. But that option never became available to all Spotify users.</p>
<p>While the TikTok format has been adopted by top social platforms, including Instagram (Reels), Snapchat (Spotlight), YouTube (Shorts) and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/20/pinterest-gets-more-tiktok-like-with-a-watch-tab-for-videos-announces-20m-in-creator-rewards/">Pinterest</a> (Idea Pins), it&#8217;s also proving to be an ideal format for content discovery. Netflix, for instance, recently adopted the short-form vertical video feed in its own app with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/netflix-launches-fast-laughs-a-tiktok-like-feed-of-funny-videos/">the launch of its &#8220;Fast Laughs&#8221; feature</a>, which offers clips from its content library and tools to save the programs to a watch list or just start streaming them. Similarly, Spotify&#8217;s video-based Discover feature could help introduce users to new music and offer a way to signal their interests to Spotify in a familiar format.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/spotify-tests-a-tiktok-like-vertical-video-feed-in-its-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2239363</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>As human capital grows scarce, flexible compensation can help attract and retain talent</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/as-human-capital-grows-scarce-flexible-compensation-can-help-attract-and-retain-talent/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/as-human-capital-grows-scarce-flexible-compensation-can-help-attract-and-retain-talent/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 17:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[compensation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Future of Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity compensation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glassdoor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resource management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payroll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recruitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2239200</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Employees don't leave or stay because of their pay, but an opaque model for allocating compensation exacerbates feelings of disconnection and lowers engagement.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Boyd Davis</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/comprightinc">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/boyddavis1">Boyd Davis</a> is the CEO and co-founder of<a href="https://compright.com/"> Compright</a>, a cloud-based compensation planning tool. Previously, Boyd helped organizations deploy solutions that leveraged data and AI.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/09/03/gen-z-and-millennial-workers-are-leading-the-latest-quitting-spree-.html">Great Resignation</a> is among the most significant events in recent U.S. history. We are seeing a post-COVID-19 generation refusing to work under the same conditions as they did before. The U.S. is facing the most prominent<a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/money/2021/09/07/labor-day-2021-when-worker-shortage-end/5674223001/"> labor shortage</a> of the decade, and positions that require high-demand skills are harder than ever to fill.</p>
<p>Midsized companies are finding it particularly hard to retain qualified personnel. Confronted by notable resource constraints, smaller budgets and workers’ demand for flexible solutions, the problems for SMBs are as great or even more significant than for larger organizations.</p>
<p>One way to make your company attractive is by developing attractive compensation strategies and increasing pay transparency and equity. Employees don&#8217;t always leave or stay because of their pay, but an opaque model for allocating compensation exacerbates feelings of disconnection and lowers engagement.</p>
<p>Let’s dive into how startups can benefit from compensation analysis, and how they can utilize available data to develop a comprehensive compensation strategy.</p>
<h2>Understanding the complexity of compensation</h2>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Pay equity is one of the most pressing social issues today, and any discrepancies can have adverse spillover effects on reputation and company relationships.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>The amount that lands in an employees’ bank account is just one fragment of today’s compensation packages. Compensation can consist of a base salary, annual cash bonuses and long-term incentives.</p>
<p>When stirring a compensation mix together, there are different trade-offs to consider:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Fixed versus variable compensation:</strong> Base salary compared with bonuses.</li>
<li><strong>Long-term incentives versus short-term incentives:</strong> Short-term incentives can be in the form of annual bonus structures. Long-term incentives are usually stock or other forms of compensation that vest over the years.</li>
<li><strong>Cash versus equity:</strong> Equity can include stock options, restricted stock and performance shares.</li>
<li><strong>Group incentives versus individual incentives</strong>: You could implement a percentage-based salary increase for all positions or give bonuses to select employees.</li>
</ul>
<p>It isn&#8217;t ideal to have a uniform policy for all positions and departments. Managers should explain their reward decisions on an individual level, and compensation decisions should reflect the skills and contributions of every employee. In addition, companies are bound to have varying budgets (e.g., higher revenue during the holiday seasons) and philosophies on allocating them.</p>
<p>Many make the mistake of sticking to an approach that doesn’t pan out from a strategic standpoint or doesn’t motivate the team enough. Instead, managers should gather data, work through various analyses and scenarios and design a compensation strategy tailored to the company. This is where compensation management software comes into play.</p>
<h2>The devil is in the data</h2>
<p>Data will help you understand where the talent market is headed and where your company stands.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/as-human-capital-grows-scarce-flexible-compensation-can-help-attract-and-retain-talent/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2239200</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: How long does International Entrepreneur Parole take?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/dear-sophie-how-long-does-international-entrepreneur-parole-take/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/dear-sophie-how-long-does-international-entrepreneur-parole-take/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 17:09:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2239013</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My co-founders and I think we might qualify for International Entrepreneur Parole. How long does it take to get IEP approved? How does that compare to other options available to founders?
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/17/dear-sophie-any-advice-on-visa-issues-for-new-hires/">Dear Sophie: Any advice on visa issues for new hires?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/10/dear-sophie-can-our-employee-travel-on-daca/">Dear Sophie: Can our employee travel on DACA?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">​​Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>TechCrunch+ members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Dear Sophie,</strong></p>
<p><strong>My co-founders and I think we might qualify for International Entrepreneur Parole. </strong></p>
<p><strong>How long does it take to get IEP approved? How does that compare to other options that are available to startup founders, and can my spouse work?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Committed COO</strong></p>
<p>Dear Committed,</p>
<p>Great questions! With Thanksgiving in the United States tomorrow, I’m reflecting on how appreciative I am of you and everyone who submits questions to this column, wherever you are in the world!</p>
<p>My law partner Anita Koumriqian and I recently chatted on our <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/098-it-takes-a-village-happy-thanksgiving/">Thanksgiving gratitude podcast episode</a> about all the things we appreciate about U.S. immigration in 2021, including how grateful we are that U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) announced this year that it would continue the International Entrepreneur Parole (IEP) program. (In May, USCIS under the Biden administration announced it was rescinding a proposal created by the previous administration that would have ended the IEP program.)</p>
<p>I recommend that you consult an immigration attorney who has experience filing <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/dear-sophie-whats-the-process-for-getting-international-entrepreneur-parole/">IEP applications</a>. Remember, only up to three individuals from the same startup can get IEP. Take a look at these previous Dear Sophie columns in which I discuss the <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/dear-sophie-whats-the-difference-between-iep-and-the-latest-proposed-startup-visa/">qualifications for IEP</a> and the <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/dear-sophie-whats-the-process-for-getting-international-entrepreneur-parole/">IEP process</a>. An immigration attorney will also be able to offer alternative options and steps to take based on the unique needs and situations of you and your leadership team.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100312" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100312" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2100312" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg" alt="A composite image of immigration law attorney Sophie Alcorn in front of a background with a TechCrunch logo." width="1024" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=1536,1013 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Joanna Buniak / <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sophie Alcorn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Timing is still an unknown</h2>
<p>The time it takes USCIS to process IEP applications remains uncertain for now, but we are still fervently advocating for anyone who may be eligible to take this path.</p>
<p>USCIS began processing IEP cases just this year, and it does not offer an estimate on processing times for <a href="https://www.uscis.gov/humanitarian/humanitarian-parole/international-entrepreneur-parole">Form I-941</a>, the application for IEP, on its <a href="https://egov.uscis.gov/processing-times/">Case Processing Times</a> webpage.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/dear-sophie-how-long-does-international-entrepreneur-parole-take/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2239013</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fairphone hits software support longevity akin to Apple&#8217;s iPhone</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/fairphone-2-android-10-beta/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/fairphone-2-android-10-beta/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 16:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fairphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fairphone 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile phones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2239267</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fairphone, the Dutch social enterprise dedicated to making consumer electronics (more) sustainable and ethical, including by supporting repairability so that users can hold onto their hardware for longer, has announced public testing of Android 10 for the six-year-old Fairphone 2. Owners of the modular handset that was first released back in 2015, running Android 5, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.fairphone.com/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fairphone</a>, the Dutch social enterprise dedicated to making consumer electronics (more) sustainable and ethical, including by supporting repairability so that users can hold onto their hardware for longer, has announced public testing of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/03/google-releases-android-10/">Android 10</a> for the six-year-old <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/04/meet-the-tiny-phone-company-thats-making-modularity-sustainable/">Fairphone 2</a>.</p>
<p>Owners of the modular handset that was first released back in 2015, running Android 5, should expect to be able to upgrade to Android 10 (released date: 2019) in early 2022, Fairphone said today, announcing the beta rollout of the upgrade.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LMDVwZjYLb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/04/meet-the-tiny-phone-company-thats-making-modularity-sustainable/">Meet the tiny phone company that&#8217;s making modularity sustainable</a></p></blockquote><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2239267" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Meet the tiny phone company that&#8217;s making modularity sustainable&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/04/meet-the-tiny-phone-company-thats-making-modularity-sustainable/embed/#?secret=LMDVwZjYLb" data-secret="LMDVwZjYLb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Fairphone stopped producing (but not supporting) the Fairphone 2 back in 2018 &#8212; going on to release the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/08/fairphone-3-is-a-normal-smartphone-with-ethical-shine/">Fairphone 3</a> (in 2019), the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/27/grab-your-screwdriver/">Fairphone 3+</a> (in 2020, also available as a modular upgrade to the 3) and, earlier this fall, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/fairphone-4/">Fairphone 4</a>, its first 5G handset &#8212; which it said would be supported until at least 2025.</p>
<p>Given the Fairphone 2&#8217;s impending update to Android 10 next year &#8212; which will mean it will have been supported for a total of seven years &#8212; 2025 looks like a conservative estimate of how long Fairphone 4 owners should expect to receive software support.</p>
<p>Fairphone says it collaborated with its community of users for the Android 10 upgrade project &#8212; and with a software developer in India, <a href="https://teamb58.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://teamb58.org/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1637853157006000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2vF9VwqrfXQS42iHeRd5qr">Bharath Ravi Prakash</a>, which it says worked as a volunteer open source dev &#8212; and by doing that says it was able to streamline the process and shrink the time required to carry out the upgrade.</p>
<p>So while the prior Fairphone 2 OS update (to Android 9) took 18 months, this time the process has been condensed to 10 months.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Google, meanwhile, has gone on to release Android 11 (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/android-11-has-arrived/">2020</a>) and Android 12 (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/19/android-12-launched/">last month</a>) &#8212; for a sense of how far behind the Fairphone 2 upgrades are trailing the latest OS release.</p>
<p>&#8220;The company learned a lot from the Android 9 upgrade and although still complex, Android 10 was more predictable than Android 9,&#8221; Fairphone notes in a press release, which also quotes its head of software longevity &amp; IT, Agnes Crepet, who writes: “Our unique approach to software has allowed us to help our users keep their devices for as long as possible. We’re pleased to be able to provide our Fairphone 2 community with yet another software upgrade, reaching our goal to provide at least five years of support from launch for our phones and with the Android 10 upgrade, we’re going beyond that to seven years of support. We are constantly raising the bar for ourselves and the industry, showing that doing things more sustainably in software is possible.”</p>
<p>Seven years&#8217; support puts Fairphone into Apple iPhone software support timespans. But of course the average Android-based handset can expect fair fewer years of software love &#8212; typically Android smartphones only get around three years&#8217; support. So it&#8217;s a major achievement.</p>
<p>And while Fairphone may only now be catching up to Apple on the software longevity front it is already years ahead of Cupertino in another respect: Hardware sustainability through repairability via modular construction and offering direct-to-consumer spare parts.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/17/beginning-next-year-apple-will-mail-you-parts-and-tools-to-fix-your-iphone-and-mac-at-home/">Earlier this month</a> Apple announced that, starting next year, it would kick off a &#8220;Self Service Repair&#8221; program &#8212; shipping spare parts and repair tools to iPhone and Mac users to let them perform basic repairs at home.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s by no means full modularity from the company that has &#8212; historically &#8212; loved a hermetically sealed, stupidly thin, often <em>literally</em> glued shut box, but it is a small step in a more sustainable direction. And one that Fairphone has long pioneered.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hdeuedYQQI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/27/can-fairphone-3-scale-ethical-consumer-electronics/">Can Fairphone 3 scale ethical consumer electronics?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Can Fairphone 3 scale ethical consumer electronics?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/27/can-fairphone-3-scale-ethical-consumer-electronics/embed/#?secret=hdeuedYQQI" data-secret="hdeuedYQQI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/fairphone-2-android-10-beta/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2239267</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple alerts NSO phone hacking victims in Thailand, El Salvador and Uganda</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/apple-nso-hacking-notify/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/apple-nso-hacking-notify/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 16:23:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangkok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bryce durbin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Citizen Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[democratic party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[espionage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone 4s]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NSO Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pegasus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spyware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thailand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uganda]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2239252</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple has sent threat notification alerts to victims of state-sponsored hackers in Thailand, El Salvador and Uganda, just hours after filing a lawsuit against Israeli spyware maker NSO Group. At least six Thai activists and researchers who have been critical of the government have received the notification, according to Reuters, including Prajak Kongkirati, a political [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2201738" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2201738" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2201738 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/nso-iphone-hack.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/nso-iphone-hack.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/nso-iphone-hack.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/nso-iphone-hack.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/nso-iphone-hack.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/nso-iphone-hack.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/nso-iphone-hack.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/nso-iphone-hack.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2201738" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>Apple has sent threat notification alerts to victims of state-sponsored hackers in Thailand, El Salvador and Uganda, just hours after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/apple-nso-group-lawsuit/">filing a lawsuit against </a>Israeli spyware maker NSO Group<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/apple-nso-group-lawsuit/">.</a></p>
<p>At least six Thai activists and researchers who have been critical of the government have received the notification, according to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/apple-warns-thai-activists-state-sponsored-attackers-may-have-targeted-iphones-2021-11-24/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reuters</a>, including Prajak Kongkirati, a political scientist at Bangkok’s Thammasat University, researcher Sarinee Achananuntakul and Thai activist Yingcheep Atchanont of the legal monitoring group iLaw. Citizen Lab, which tracks illegal hacking and surveillance, identified in 2018 a Pegasus spyware operator active within Thailand.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2239252" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The alerts — which Apple says are <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-sa/HT212960" target="_blank" rel="noopener">designed to inform and assist users who may have been targeted</a> by state-sponsored attackers — were also sent to a number of users in El Salvador. This includes 12 employees from <a href="https://elfaro.net/es/202111/el_salvador/25861/Apple-env%C3%ADa-alerta-de-espionaje-patrocinado-por-el-Estado-a-12-miembros-de-El-Faro.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">El Faro</a>, an online digital newspaper that has been notoriously critical of the government, as well as two leaders of civil society organizations and two opposition politicians.</p>
<p>Norbert Mao, the president of the Democratic Party in Uganda, also said on <a href="https://twitter.com/norbertmao/status/1463364241688305664" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Twitter</a> that he had received the threat notification.</p>
<p>The alert from Apple warns: “Apple believes you are being targeted by state-sponsored attackers who are trying to remotely compromise the iPhone associated with your Apple ID. These attackers are likely targeting you individually because of who you are or what you do. If your device is compromised by a state-sponsored attacker, they may be able to remotely access your sensitive data, communications, or even the camera and microphone. While it’s possible this is a false alarm, please take this warning seriously.”</p>
<p>Apple on Tuesday sued NSO Group to seek <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/apple-nso-group-lawsuit/">a permanent injunction</a> to prevent the spyware maker from using any Apple product. This would make it more difficult for the company to find and exploit vulnerabilities in iPhone software and hack its targets.</p>
<p>“The steps we’re taking today will send a clear message: In a free society it is unacceptable to weaponize powerful state-sponsored spyware against those who seek to make the world a better place,” said Apple’s security chief Ivan Krstić. “Apple runs one of the most sophisticated security engineering operations in the world, and we will continue to work tirelessly to protect our users from abusive state-sponsored actors like NSO Group.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nH65xi99xd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/toolkit-nso-pegasus-iphone-android/">This tool tells you if NSO&#8217;s Pegasus spyware targeted your phone</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;This tool tells you if NSO&#8217;s Pegasus spyware targeted your phone&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/toolkit-nso-pegasus-iphone-android/embed/#?secret=nH65xi99xd" data-secret="nH65xi99xd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/apple-nso-hacking-notify/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2239252</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Afterpay unveils BNPL subscription offering for US customers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/afterpay-unveils-bnpl-subscription-offering-for-u-s-customers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/afterpay-unveils-bnpl-subscription-offering-for-u-s-customers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 15:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AfterPay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnpl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klarna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Square]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscription services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zahir Khoja]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2239268</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The service will launch in both the U.S. and Australia beginning early in 2022 and will be free for customers who pay on time.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">&#8220;Buy now, pay later&#8221; company <a href="https://www.afterpay.com/en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Afterpay</a> announced Wednesday that it was going after the <a href="https://www.ubs.com/global/en/wealth-management/our-approach/marketnews/article.1525238.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$1.5 trillion global subscription payments market</a> by offering to its U.S. customers payment installments for subscriptions, like gym memberships, entertainment subscriptions and online services.</p>
<p>The service will launch in both the U.S. and Australia beginning early in 2022 and will be free for customers who pay on time. IPSY, BoxyCharm, Savage X Fenty and Fabletics are among the initial list of merchants that will offer the feature. The company plans to expand the feature in-store and into other regions later, including Canada, New Zealand, the U.K. and Europe.</p>
<p>In addition to paying for subscriptions in installments, Afterpay is also enabling its offering to be used on preordered items, where users can pay in four installments over time once the item ships. Another feature coming soon will allow merchants to accept deposits on custom items.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2239268" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;By offering customers the option to pay for subscriptions with Afterpay, we&#8217;re not only giving consumers flexibility to pay for more expensive monthly costs, but we&#8217;re also helping our merchant partners capture a wider consumer base through this convenient experience,” said Zahir Khoja, general manager of North America for Afterpay, in a written statement.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/klarna-offers-pay-now-option-in-u-s-klarna-card-coming-soon/">Klarna</a>, Afterpay’s competitor in the BNPL space, also announced news this week for its U.S. customers that it was offering its “Pay Now” option.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, in August, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/square-to-buy-buy-now-pay-later-giant-afterpay-in-29b-deal/">Square announced that it was buying Afterpay</a> in an all-stock deal valued at $29 billion. Afterpay has also been on a roll with feature debuts recently, launching both Afterpay Ads, a suite of advertising products for brands to engage with shoppers within the ecosystem, and merchant analytics tool Afterpay IQ, in August.</p>
<p>Afterpay works with 100,000 retailers and has approximately <a href="https://corporate.afterpay.com/investors/asx-announcements" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10.5 million active customers in North America</a> as of June 30, up from 5.6 million the year prior. North America is the company’s “largest region in terms of underlying sales,” which grew 145% year over year, or from $4 billion in fiscal year 2020 to $9.8 billion in fiscal year 2021, according to the company.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cq5KVLk01K"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/everyone-loves-bnpl/">Credit card and payments companies compete for a slice of the growing BNPL market</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Credit card and payments companies compete for a slice of the growing BNPL market&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/everyone-loves-bnpl/embed/#?secret=cq5KVLk01K" data-secret="cq5KVLk01K" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/afterpay-unveils-bnpl-subscription-offering-for-u-s-customers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2239268</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Financial flash mobs meet fundraising memes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/financial-flash-mobs-meet-fundraising-memes/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/financial-flash-mobs-meet-fundraising-memes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 15:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[constitution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dao]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, a podcast about the business of startups where we unpack the numbers and nuance behind the headlines. This is our Wednesday episode when we niche down to a single topic, looking to expand our understanding of one particular technology trend or another. And this week, it was all about [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/equity/id1215439780" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Equity</a>, a podcast about the business of startups where we unpack the numbers and nuance behind the headlines.</p>
<p>This is our Wednesday episode when we niche down to a single topic, looking to expand our understanding of one particular technology trend or another. And this week, it was all about the ConstitutionDAO.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">For those who weren&#8217;t online last week, here&#8217;s what you missed: a not-so-subtle group of strangers on the internet banded together to try to buy one of the remaining 13 copies of the Constitution. With crypto. The bold bid eventually fell short, but many saw it as an inspiring </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/18/constitutiondaos-bold-crypto-bid-for-us-constitution-falls-short/?tpcc=tcplustwitter">onramp into how communities can mobilize around a shared goal in a web3 world. </a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The whole movement, from its meme start to its poetic, and billionaire Ken Griffin-themed, end, was just too interesting for Equity to not dedicate an entire episode to.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238783" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>So, <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alex</a> brought on <a href="https://twitter.com/lucasmtny" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lucas Matney</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/AnitaRamaswamy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anita Ramaswamy </a>to unpack, decompress and bond over our shared experience of witnessing this &#8220;financial flash mob.&#8221;</p>
<p>We talked about what a DAO is, and what they might be used for. We dug into the question of just how many folks the effort really brought to the larger &#8220;web3&#8221; space. And, of course, we had to talk about gas fees, NFTs and the pace of innovation in crypto more broadly. Lucas even broke out an excellent analogy to explain level-two chains!</p>
<p>The crew were generally bullish on the blockchain economy, if skeptical of some of its current uses. In short, the potential remains potent in crypto even if some of its projects, today at least, are a bit more boring than breakthrough. Crypto, we&#8217;re told, is going to shake up the world. More of that, we reckon, and less of the meme-wars wouldn&#8217;t be amiss.</p>
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 a.m. PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>,</i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i> Overcast</i></a><i>,</i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i> Spotify</i></a> <i>and all the casts. </i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/financial-flash-mobs-meet-fundraising-memes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238783</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In a crowded global market, Canadian AI startups&#8217; fundraising results stand out</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/in-a-crowded-global-market-canadian-ai-startups-fundraising-results-stand-out/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/in-a-crowded-global-market-canadian-ai-startups-fundraising-results-stand-out/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 15:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Geoffrey Hinton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matt Cohen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ramen Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yoshua Bengio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238772</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[More dollars, rising deal sizes. What's going on in Canada?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It’s boom times for startups building with or atop AI functionality: <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The Exchange </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/16/huge-deals-are-pushing-more-ai-startups-into-ipo-territory/">explored the rise</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> in venture capital dollars for AI startups last week, noting that investment into the business niche set all-time records in Q4 2020, and then successively in quarters one, two and three in 2021.</span></p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on TechCrunch+</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>Given how heated the overall venture capital market is proving to be, those data points were only so surprising. What did shock us a little, however, was how active the Canadian AI startup market has been this year.</p>
<p>Perhaps it shouldn’t have. <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/matt-cohen1/?originalSubdomain=ca">Matt Cohen</a>, a managing partner at Ripple Ventures, told The Exchange that “while investment in Canadian startups of all varieties has ramped up lately, AI-enabled startups are certainly leading the pack.”</p>
<p>We’re behind, it turns out. But not so far behind that we cannot catch up on the Canadian AI startup story. Our questions are simple: Why are Canadian startups seeing their fundraising fortunes rise so sharply, what parts of the AI stack are being attacked, what role does public money play in the rising investment totals and what impact do local universities have on artificial intelligence work in Canada?</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-2220366 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>To help us, we parsed a <a href="https://www.cbinsights.com/research/report/ai-trends-q3-2021/">data set from CB Insights</a> and have clarifying notes from Ripple’s Cohen along with <a href="https://twitter.com/alizhd">Ali Zahid</a>, an investor at Ramen Ventures, <a href="https://twitter.com/shawnchance">Shawn Chance</a>, a partner at OMERS, <a href="https://twitter.com/brunomorency">Bruno Morency</a>, the managing director at Techstars Montréal AI, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/louis-fischer-854829146">Louis Fischer,</a> a CB Insights intelligence analyst.</p>
<p>We’ll start with data, and then talk about what&#8217;s pushing up the numbers.</p>
<h2>From the <a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/4ALQyinHGIctf3q6YhWemg?si=c08f581ec3e74384">land of milk in a bag</a>, rising AI investment</h2>
<p>Let’s start from a yearly perspective. Funding for Canadian AI startups rose to record heights in 2019 before seeing declines in 2020 to just $488 million in total funding. But 2021 is proving to be more than a return to form for Canadian AI startups, with some $1.5 billion raised through the third quarter.</p>
<p>The results are a bit uneven, to be fair. Canada saw $895 million across 21 deals in Q2 2021 AI funding, and just $446 million in the third quarter, albeit from a slightly higher deal count of 24. But as the Q3 2021 dollar result for the country is nearly on par with its full-year 2020 total, it&#8217;s hard to be too bearish.</p>
<p>The evolution of Canadian AI funding as a portion of all venture capital funding in the country is impressive. AI companies raised 16% of known venture capital funds in 2021 thus far, a huge gain on the mere 2% that they were worth of total dollar volume in 2016.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/in-a-crowded-global-market-canadian-ai-startups-fundraising-results-stand-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238772</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
