<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 23:44:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>How to claim a student discount for TechCrunch+</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/how-to-claim-a-student-discount-for-techcrunch/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/how-to-claim-a-student-discount-for-techcrunch/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Travis Bernard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 02:08:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Students can get access to TechCrunch+ at a discounted rate of $50/year (plus tax).  Here’s how to claim the discount: Use a .edu or university email address and send a message to our customer support team at plus@techcrunch.com. Please let them know that you are seeking the student discount. The team will respond within 24-48 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Students can get access to TechCrunch+ at a discounted rate of $50/year (plus tax).  Here’s how to claim the discount:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use a .edu or university email address and send a message to our customer support team at </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">plus@techcrunch.com</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Please let them know that you are seeking the student discount.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The team will respond within 24-48 hours with a unique link to claim your discount.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are part of a student group like an entrepreneurial club and interested in getting access for a large number of users, reach out to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">travis@techcrunch.com</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to learn more about custom discounts on large groups.</span></p>
<h2><b>What is TechCrunch+?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TechCrunch+ is a membership product that provides advice and analysis to help startups get ahead. Members learn how successful startups operate through deep-dive interviews with founders and investors, including on-demand replays of sessions at TechCrunch events. M</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">arket analysis, investor surveys, and topical newsletters allow members to spot trends and opportunities, while live weekly coaching and Q&amp;A sessions help improve your pitch. TechCrunch+ also provides </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">expert advice on fundraising, growth, and management from experienced entrepreneurs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you have interest in attending TechCrunch events, you can save 20% on tickets as an TechCrunch+ member. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For questions about this offer, reach out to customer support at </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">plus@techcrunch.com</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/how-to-claim-a-student-discount-for-techcrunch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201581</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook, WhatsApp and Instagram are slowly returning. Why did they disappear to begin with?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-whatsapp-instagram-return/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-whatsapp-instagram-return/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 22:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloudflare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CTO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet traffic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messenger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[west coast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook&#8217;s day-long outage is by far its longest and most extreme in years. At around 9 a.m. PDT on the U.S. West Coast &#8212; where the social giant is headquartered &#8212; Facebook, WhatsApp, Instagram and Facebook Messenger seemed to vanish from the internet. The outage continued through market close, with the company&#8217;s stock dropping around [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-messenger-instagram-whatsapp-are-all-down/">day-long outage</a> is by far its longest and most extreme in years. At around 9 a.m. PDT on the U.S. West Coast &#8212; where the social giant is headquartered &#8212; Facebook, WhatsApp, Instagram and Facebook Messenger seemed to vanish from the internet.</p>
<p>The outage <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-stock-falls-as-global-outage-continues/">continued through market close</a>, with the company&#8217;s stock dropping around 5% below its opening price on Monday. By midafternoon, services were beginning to resume after <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/10/04/technology/facebook-down.html">Facebook reportedly</a> dispatched a team to its Santa Clara data center to &#8220;manually reset&#8221; the company&#8217;s servers.</p>
<p>But what makes the outage unique is just how extremely offline Facebook was.</p>
<p>In the morning, Facebook sent a brief tweet <a href="https://twitter.com/Facebook/status/1445061804636479493">to apologize</a> that &#8220;some people are having trouble accessing our apps and products.&#8221; Then, reports emerged that the outage was affecting not just its users, but the company itself. Employees were reportedly <a href="https://twitter.com/sheeraf/status/1445099150316503057?s=20">unable to enter their office buildings,</a> and staff called it a &#8220;snow day&#8221; &#8212; they <a href="https://twitter.com/rmac18/status/1445069187664293895">couldn&#8217;t get any work done</a> because the outage also affected internal collaboration apps.</p>
<p>Facebook hasn&#8217;t commented on the cause of the outage, though security experts said evidence pointed to a problem with the company&#8217;s network that cut off Facebook from the wider internet and also itself.</p>
<p>The first signs of trouble <a href="https://twitter.com/jgrahamc/status/1445065270272434176">were around 8:50 a.m</a>. PDT in California, according to John Graham-Cumming, CTO at networking giant Cloudflare, who said Facebook &#8220;disappeared from the internet in a flurry of BGP updates&#8221; over a two-minute window, referring to BGP, or Border Gateway Protocol, the system that networks use to figure out the fastest way to send data over the internet to another network.</p>
<p>The updates were specifically BGP route withdrawals. Essentially, Facebook had sent a message to the internet that it was closed for business, like closing the drawbridge of its castle. Without any routes into the network, Facebook was basically isolated from the rest of the internet, and because of the way Facebook&#8217;s network is structured, the route withdrawals also took out WhatsApp, Instagram, Facebook Messenger and everything inside its digital walls.</p>
<p>A few minutes after the BGP routes were withdrawn, users began to notice issues. Internet traffic that should have gone to Facebook essentially got lost on the internet and went nowhere, Rob Graham, founder of Errata Security, said in <a href="https://twitter.com/ErrataRob/status/1445132412283981835">a tweet thread</a>.</p>
<p>Users began to notice that their Facebook apps had stopped working and the websites weren&#8217;t loading and reported experiencing issues with DNS, or the domain name system, which is another critical part of how the internet works. DNS converts human-readable web addresses into machine-readable IP addresses to find where a web page is located on the internet. Without a way into Facebook&#8217;s servers, apps and browsers would keep kicking back what looked like DNS errors.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not known exactly why the BGP routes were withdrawn. BGP, which has been around since the advent of the internet, can be <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/19/cloudflare-wants-route-leak-internet-outages-to-be-a-thing-of-the-past/">manipulated and maliciously exploited</a> in ways that can lead to massive outages.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more likely is that a Facebook configuration update went terribly wrong and its failure cascaded throughout the internet. A <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/sysadmin/comments/q181fv/looks_like_facebook_is_down/hfd4dyv/?context=3">now-deleted Reddit thread</a> from a Facebook engineer described a BGP configuration error long before it was widely known.</p>
<p>But while the fix might be simple, the recovery may stretch from the next few hours into the following days because of how the internet works. Internet providers usually update their DNS records every few hours, but they can take several days to fully propagate.</p>
<p>&#8220;To the huge community of people and businesses around the world who depend on us: we&#8217;re sorry,&#8221; Facebook tweeted around 3:30 p.m. local time. &#8220;We’ve been working hard to restore access to our apps and services and are happy to report they are coming back online now. Thank you for bearing with us.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CSv37nx7ye"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-messenger-instagram-whatsapp-are-all-down/">Facebook, Messenger, Instagram and WhatsApp are all down</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook, Messenger, Instagram and WhatsApp are all down&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-messenger-instagram-whatsapp-are-all-down/embed/#?secret=CSv37nx7ye" data-secret="CSv37nx7ye" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-whatsapp-instagram-return/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212259</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: DNS outage takes down Facebook’s social networks around the globe</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/daily-crunch-70/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/daily-crunch-70/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 22:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for October 4, 2021. A lot is going on today in the world of major tech companies — as you may have noticed — but don’t worry, we have lots of startup news on deck as well to keep you up to speed! Now if someone could help Facebook fix its series of tubes … — <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<p>P.S. Our upcoming SaaS event is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/jared-spataro-will-talk-about-building-microsofts-saas-business-at-tc-sessions-saas/">going to flat-out rule</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NFPexNbpXq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/jared-spataro-will-talk-about-building-microsofts-saas-business-at-tc-sessions-saas/">Jared Spataro will talk about building Microsoft&#8217;s SaaS business at TC Sessions: SaaS</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Jared Spataro will talk about building Microsoft&#8217;s SaaS business at TC Sessions: SaaS&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/jared-spataro-will-talk-about-building-microsofts-saas-business-at-tc-sessions-saas/embed/#?secret=NFPexNbpXq" data-secret="NFPexNbpXq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-messenger-instagram-whatsapp-are-all-down/">Facebook goes down:</a></strong> The biggest news item in all of tech today was the fact that Facebook was unable to provide its services for hours and hours. Facebook, Instagram and WhatsApp are all still offline as we write to you. Given Facebook’s enormous scale, the financial damage is piling up for the social giant and its myriad customers. In other Facebook news, the European Parliament is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/leak-shows-facebooks-business-model-needs-regulating-says-mep/">less than pleased with the company</a>, TechCrunch reports.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/informaticas-ipo-will-test-public-markets-appetite-for-slower-growing-tech-offerings/"><strong>Inside Informatica’s IPO:</strong></a><strong> </strong>As technology stocks took a battering today, TechCrunch sunk its teeth into data-focused Informatica’s S-1 filing. The company went private back in 2015, moving to the cloud over the intervening half-decade. What does it look like now that it is coming back to the public markets? Indebted, for one.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/apple-watch-series-7-arrives-october-15-starting-at-399/"><strong>New Apple Watches drop this month:</strong></a><strong> </strong>If you were hoping to snag a new Apple Watch in October, good news: The company’s Series 7 device should arrive on the 15th. As a reminder, the new Watch has a 20% larger screen, which means it can hold more text. In case you love reading from your wrist.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>Before we dive into a bevy of venture capital rounds, take a peek at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/index-sequoia-and-canvas-investors-weigh-in-on-how-to-raise-your-first-dollars/">this Mary Ann Azevedo post</a> digging into advice from Index and Sequoia concerning how to go about raising your first dollars. It’s very good.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/nft-startup-dapper-labs-acquires-virtual-influencer-startup-brud/"><strong>An NFT and a virtual avatar walk into a bar:</strong></a><strong> </strong>OK so that’s the setup for a lame joke I couldn’t figure out how to finish (<em>The barkeep asks, “What do you think this is, the metaverse?”</em>) but in real news, NFT impresario Dapper Labs is buying virtual avatar startup Brud. Per TechCrunch, Brud has 32 staff, all of which will make a move to Dapper. Recall that Dapper Labs was last valued at $7.5 billion, so it 100% has some stock to throw around.</li>
<li>We had <strong>two insurtech rounds today</strong> worth discussing. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/insurtech-stable-raises-46-5m-in-greycroft-led-round-to-help-businesses-manage-volatile-commodity-prices/"><strong>The </strong><strong>first is from Stable</strong></a>, which is building an insurance product concerning the price of commodities. The value of oil, soybeans and pig bellies — not to mention copper, silicon metal and corn — can jump around quite a lot. For many producers, that’s suboptimal. Stable has raised more than $46 million to help provide more price stability — get it? — to folks previously at the vicissitude of the markets, who we presume were too small to hedge their own risk.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/ladder-raises-100m-on-a-900m-valuation-for-a-platform-selling-flexible-term-life-insurance/"><strong>The second is from Ladder</strong></a>, which just put together a $100 million funding round to remake the life insurance industry. That we have two large insurtech rounds land in a single day implies that venture sentiment around startups in the space has not waned to quiescence in the wake of public markets devaluing several public neoinsurance companies that went public in the last year.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/yc-grads-wasp-land-1-5m-seed-to-help-developers-build-web-apps-faster/"><strong>Wasp raises $1.5M for faster web app construction:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Recent Y Combinator graduate Wasp has put together a nice little round for its technology that aims to “help programmers code the business logic side of the application faster,” TechCrunch reports. It’s always nice to see a smaller round, reminders that not every company is raising nine figures in a single go these days.</li>
</ul>
<h2>As Apple messes with attribution, what does growth marketing look like in 2021?</h2>
<p>Cupertino introduced app tracking transparency in April, giving users the ability to prevent their iPhones from sharing data about their behavior. Later changes in iOS 15 permit consumers to opt into mail privacy protection and exert greater control over app permissions.</p>
<p>This is all good news for privacy-minded consumers, but for startups that live and die by their ability to measure growth and engagement, there&#8217;s widespread confusion and uncertainty.</p>
<p>To learn more about how growth marketers are recalibrating data collection, <a href="https://twitter.com/dannycrichton">Managing Editor Danny Crichton</a> interviewed three experts at TechCrunch Disrupt:</p>
<ul>
<li>Jenifer Ho, marketing VP, Elation Health</li>
<li>Shoji Ueki, head of marketing and analytics, Point</li>
<li>Nik Sharma, owner, Sharma Brands</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aVhU8TkJzU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/as-apple-messes-with-attribution-what-does-growth-marketing-look-like-in-2021/">As Apple messes with attribution, what does growth marketing look like in 2021?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As Apple messes with attribution, what does growth marketing look like in 2021?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/as-apple-messes-with-attribution-what-does-growth-marketing-look-like-in-2021/embed/#?secret=aVhU8TkJzU" data-secret="aVhU8TkJzU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/apple-makes-it-easier-to-report-bad-apps-and-scams/"><strong>Only you can help prevent scammy apps:</strong></a><strong> <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">Smokey the Bear</span> </strong>Apple would like your help rooting spammers and scammers and other miscreants off of its application marketplace. It turns out that inside of iOS 15 there’s now a way to report apps to Apple. Which is good, if Apple will, you know, ever email you back.</li>
<li>To wrap up news for the day, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/qualcomm-acquires-veoneer-for-4-5-billion-canceling-its-agreement-with-magna/"><strong>Qualcomm intends to buy Veoneer for $4.5 billion</strong></a>, which means that the smaller company’s deal with Magna is kaput. Veoneer is a “Swedish automotive tech company,” TechCrunch writes, which helps put the deal in context. Qualcomm makes chips &#8212; and cars, as we have learned in the last few months, really do need them.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Are you all caught up on last week’s coverage of growth marketing? If not, read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/how-to-be-a-growth-marketing-anti-agency/">here</a>.</p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend growth marketers who have expertise in SEO, social, content writing and more! If you’re a growth marketer, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LRPlDe3Sqv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/how-to-be-a-growth-marketing-anti-agency/">How to be a growth marketing anti-agency</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to be a growth marketing anti-agency&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/how-to-be-a-growth-marketing-anti-agency/embed/#?secret=LRPlDe3Sqv" data-secret="LRPlDe3Sqv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/daily-crunch-70/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212143</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Max Q: Blue Origin puts safety in the backseat, workers claim</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/max-q-blue-origin-puts-safety-in-the-backseat-workers-claim/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/max-q-blue-origin-puts-safety-in-the-backseat-workers-claim/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 22:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Max Q]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terran orbital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2210797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello, readers: Welcome back to Max Q. First, an introduction: I&#8217;m Aria Alamalhodaei, the resident space and transportation reporter here at TechCrunch. I&#8217;ll be taking over the Max Q newsletter from Darrell Etherington for the next few months. Tips, opinions, criticism, thoughts? Email me at aria.techcrunch@gmail.com or find me on Twitter at @breadfrom. Bezos&#8217; labor [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hello, readers: Welcome back to Max Q. First, an introduction: I&#8217;m Aria Alamalhodaei, the resident space and transportation reporter here at TechCrunch. I&#8217;ll be taking over the Max Q newsletter from Darrell Etherington for the next few months.</p>
<p>Tips, opinions, criticism, thoughts? Email me at <a href="mailto:aria.techcrunch@gmail.com">aria.techcrunch@gmail.com</a> or find me on Twitter at <a href="http://www.twitter.com/breadfrom">@breadfrom</a>.</p>
<h2>Bezos&#8217; labor woes</h2>
<p>Jeff Bezos is back in the news this week, this time over <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/current-and-former-employees-raise-major-safety-concerns-allegations-of-sexual-harassment-at-blue-origin/?tpcc=tcplustwitter">allegations of a hostile work environment and a lack of focus on safety</a> from 21 current and former employees of his space company, Blue Origin. The news couldn&#8217;t come at a worse time for the company, which is currently mired in a lawsuit against NASA over its decision to award a lunar lander contract to rival SpaceX.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.lioness.co/post/bezos-wants-to-create-a-better-future-in-space-his-company-blue-origin-is-stuck-in-a-toxic-past">The essay jointly composed by the employees</a> paints a vivid picture of Blue Origin’s work culture as one marred by sexual harassment, in which professional disagreement is stifled, environmental concerns are left unaddressed and speed of execution takes precedence over human safety.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KsJJIWLtUe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/current-and-former-employees-raise-major-safety-concerns-allegations-of-sexual-harassment-at-blue-origin/">Current and former employees raise major safety concerns, allegations of sexual harassment at Blue Origin</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Current and former employees raise major safety concerns, allegations of sexual harassment at Blue Origin&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/current-and-former-employees-raise-major-safety-concerns-allegations-of-sexual-harassment-at-blue-origin/embed/#?secret=KsJJIWLtUe" data-secret="KsJJIWLtUe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Blue Origin disputed the allegations of sexual harassment in a comment to TechCrunch, but they did not respond to a follow-up inquiry regarding safety and whether the company has inserted stifling non-disparagement clauses in employee contracts.</p>
<p>TechCrunch spoke to the sole named author of the letter, Alexandra Abrams, who said she decided to go public with her identity because she felt a sense of responsibility for other employees.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“I really felt like I had compromised my integrity at Blue Origin,” she said. “I did my best, but I was Bob’s executive communicator and helped make him look good.”</p>
<p>It’s hard to imagine how this essay could <em>not </em>affect Blue Origin’s bottom line. After the successful launch of New Shepard in July, in which Bezos and three others went to space during an 11-minute flight, the company intends to start welcoming more paying customers on flights.</p>
<p>The situation was made even more sticky when the Federal Aviation Administration confirmed to TechCrunch that &#8220;the agency is reviewing the information&#8221; in the essay. “The FAA takes every safety allegation seriously.&#8221;</p>
<p>While Abrams confirmed that the FAA had not yet reached out to her, she said she would “very much welcome” that.</p>
<p>“I feel like I’m fulfilling my job description as employee communications for the first time.”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1963591" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1177532678.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="708" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1177532678.jpg 4500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1177532678.jpg?resize=150,104 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1177532678.jpg?resize=300,207 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1177532678.jpg?resize=768,531 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1177532678.jpg?resize=680,470 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1177532678.jpg?resize=1536,1062 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1177532678.jpg?resize=2048,1416 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1177532678.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<h2>U.S. Space Force grants funds for next-gen rocket development</h2>
<p>The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/u-s-space-force-awards-87-5m-to-rocket-lab-spacex-blue-origin-ula-for-next-gen-rocket-testing/">U.S. Space Force</a> has awarded a collective $87.5 million in funding to SpaceX, Blue Origin, Rocket Lab and United Launch Alliance for projects related to next-gen rocket engine testing and upper-stage improvements &#8212; that includes Rocket Lab&#8217;s mysterious Neutron rocket and Blue Origin&#8217;s heavy-lift launch vehicle New Glenn.</p>
<p>SpaceX and ULA are already established launch providers for the U.S. government under the Space Force’s National Security Space Launch program. Both Rocket Lab and Blue Origin will be able to compete for the next series of launch procurement contracts in 2024, and contracts like these are signs that the two companies are gearing up to do so.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6VO4YDbPrE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/u-s-space-force-awards-87-5m-to-rocket-lab-spacex-blue-origin-ula-for-next-gen-rocket-testing/">US Space Force awards $87.5M to Rocket Lab, SpaceX, Blue Origin, ULA for next-gen rocket testing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;US Space Force awards $87.5M to Rocket Lab, SpaceX, Blue Origin, ULA for next-gen rocket testing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/u-s-space-force-awards-87-5m-to-rocket-lab-spacex-blue-origin-ula-for-next-gen-rocket-testing/embed/#?secret=6VO4YDbPrE" data-secret="6VO4YDbPrE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Blue Origin&#8217;s next manifest</h2>
<p>One last story related to Blue Origin this week&#8230; the company announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/dcvc-partner-and-planet-labs-co-founder-chris-boshuizen-bound-for-space-on-blue-origins-second-human-flight/">the next two people</a> that will take a ride on the New Shepard rocket: Dr. Chris Boshuizen, co-founder of Planet Labs and current partner at venture capital firm DCVC; and Glen de Vries, co-founder of the clinical trial software company Medidata Solutions.</p>
<p>The flight is scheduled to take off on Tuesday, October 12, at 9:30 AM EST from Blue Origin’s sprawling Launch Site One just outside of Van Horn, Texas. The company has not released details regarding the identities of the remaining two crew members but we&#8217;ll certainly be keeping our ear to the ground. (Read our story on Blue&#8217;s first crewed launch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/blue-origins-new-shepard-carries-jeff-bezos-and-three-crew-members-to-space-and-back/">here</a>.)</p>
<h2>Orbital servicing startup raises $7M</h2>
<p>In-orbit satellite servicing company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/starfish-space-raises-7m-for-in-orbit-servicing-space-tug/">Starfish Space</a> raised $7 million to accelerate the development of its Otter &#8220;space tug,&#8221; a spacecraft that the company says will be able to clean up orbital debris and extend the useful life of satellites in geostationary orbit. In the longer-term, Starfish even says the space tug could be used as autonomous in-orbit robots for a whole range of purposes related to the future space economy, including mining, manufacturing and recycling.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2210826" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2210826" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2210826" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Otter_Docking_Render-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="853" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Otter_Docking_Render-1.png 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Otter_Docking_Render-1.png?resize=150,125 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Otter_Docking_Render-1.png?resize=300,250 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Otter_Docking_Render-1.png?resize=768,640 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Otter_Docking_Render-1.png?resize=680,567 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Otter_Docking_Render-1.png?resize=50,42 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2210826" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://starfishspace.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Starfish Space <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<h2>A $300M satellite manufacturing facility for Florida&#8217;s Space Coast</h2>
<p>Florida&#8217;s Space Coast economy got a major boost this week when it was announced that contract manufacturer <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/terran-orbital-to-open-a-300m-satellite-manufacturing-and-component-facility-on-floridas-space-coast/">Terran Orbital</a> would build a $300 million satellite manufacturing facility at Kennedy Space Center. The 660,000-square-foot facility will be the world&#8217;s largest, according to the company, and that&#8217;s not too hard to believe, considering the anticipated output: 1,000 complete satellites and over 1 million satellite components per year.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2208789" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2208789" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2208789" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PR-TerranOrbital-ProductionBldg.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PR-TerranOrbital-ProductionBldg.jpg 3600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PR-TerranOrbital-ProductionBldg.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PR-TerranOrbital-ProductionBldg.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PR-TerranOrbital-ProductionBldg.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PR-TerranOrbital-ProductionBldg.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PR-TerranOrbital-ProductionBldg.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PR-TerranOrbital-ProductionBldg.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PR-TerranOrbital-ProductionBldg.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2208789" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.terranorbital.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Terran Orbital <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<h2>Join us at TC Sessions: Space in December</h2>
<p>Last year we held our first dedicated space event, and it went so well that we decided to host it again in 2021. This year, it’s happening December 14 and 15, and it’s once again going to be an entirely virtual conference, so people from all over the world will be able to join — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?utm_medium=TCnewsletter&amp;tpcc=TCspacenewsletter">and you can, too</a>.</p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2159308" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png" alt="" width="1024" height="575" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png 1390w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/TC-Sessions-Space-2021.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></h2>
<h2><a href="http://www.techcrunch.com">Read more stories on TechCrunch.com</a></h2>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/max-q-blue-origin-puts-safety-in-the-backseat-workers-claim/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2210797</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>YouTube making ads on connected TVs more shoppable</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/youtube-making-ads-on-connected-tvs-more-shoppable/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/youtube-making-ads-on-connected-tvs-more-shoppable/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 21:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ad tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video ads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212160</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[YouTube announced on Monday that it’s expanding video action campaigns (one of Google&#8217;s interactive ad types for video) to connected televisions (CTV) to make YouTube ads more shoppable. The company says this new move will help advertisers drive more online sales and grow their businesses. For context, when viewers see a video action campaign on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">YouTube announced on Monday that it’s expanding video action campaigns (one of Google&#8217;s interactive ad types for video) to connected televisions (CTV) to make YouTube ads more shoppable. The company says this new move will help advertisers drive more online sales and grow their businesses.</p>
<p>For context, when viewers see a video action campaign on their TV, they are invited through a URL at the bottom of their screen to continue shopping on the brand’s website from their desktop or mobile device. All of this is done without interrupting users&#8217; viewing sessions.</p>
<p>“With a quarter of logged-in YouTube CTV viewers watching primarily on TVs, the living room is becoming an essential place for brands to drive incremental conversions with new audiences. In early experiments for video action campaigns on TV screens, over 90% of conversions coming from CTV would not have been reachable on mobile and desktop devices,” said Romana Pawar, the director of product management for YouTube ads, in a <a href="https://blog.google/products/ads-commerce/expanding-video-action-campaigns-to-ctv/">blog post.</a></p>
<p>Pawar notes that more people are choosing to view YouTube on the big screen, as more than 120 million people streamed YouTube or YouTube TV on their TVs last year in December in the U.S. Further, Pawar outlined that businesses with the goal of driving online sales should use video action campaigns in order to find new customers in a single campaign by combining inventory from across YouTube and Google video partners.</p>
<p>“For the first time, performance advertisers can take advantage of YouTube on CTV to drive and measure conversions,” Pawar outlined in the blog post. “Video action campaigns on TV screens are now globally available through Google Ads.”</p>
<p>Google first announced its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/a-new-youtube-feature-will-make-its-connected-tv-ads-more-shoppable/">plans to make its connected TV ads more shoppable</a> earlier this year (in May). Consumers, particularly younger users, like to watch videos and engage while they shop. As a result, YouTube and other platforms like Facebook and Instagram have invested in live shopping and video-based shopping features.</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/youtube-making-ads-on-connected-tvs-more-shoppable/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212160</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NASA&#8217;s &#8216;Armageddon&#8217;-style asteroid deflection mission takes off in November</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/nasas-armageddon-style-asteroid-deflection-mission-takes-off-in-november/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/nasas-armageddon-style-asteroid-deflection-mission-takes-off-in-november/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 21:33:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asteroid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asteroids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Falcon 9]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212190</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NASA has a launch date for that most Hollywood of missions, the Double Asteroid Redirection Test, which is basically a dry run of the movie &#8220;Armageddon.&#8221; Unlike the film, this will not involve nukes, oil rigs or Aerosmith, but instead is a practical test of our ability to change the trajectory of an asteroid in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">NASA has a launch date for that most Hollywood of missions, the Double Asteroid Redirection Test, which is basically a dry run of the movie &#8220;Armageddon.&#8221; Unlike the film, this will not involve nukes, oil rigs or <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ujMxXOHJloI">Aerosmith</a>, but instead is a practical test of our ability to change the trajectory of an asteroid in a significant and predictable way.</p>
<p>The DART mission, managed by the Planetary Defense Coordination Office (!), involves sending a pair of satellites out to a relatively nearby pair of asteroids, known as the Didymos binary. It&#8217;s one large-ish asteroid, approximately 780 meters across — that&#8217;s Didymos proper — and a 160-meter &#8220;moonlet&#8221; in its orbit.</p>
<p>As the moonlet is more typical of the type likely to threaten Earth — there being more asteroids that are that size and not easily observed — we will be testing the possibility of intercepting one by smashing into it at nearly 15,000 miles per hour. This will change the speed of the moonlet by a mere fraction of a percent, but enough that its orbit period will be affected measurably. Knowing exactly how much will help us plan any future asteroid-deflection missions — not surprisingly, there isn&#8217;t a lot of existing science on ramming your spacecraft into space rocks.</p>
<p>A companion spacecraft, called the Light Italian CubeSat for Imagine Asteroids, or LICIACube, just had the <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/dart-gets-its-cubesat-companion-its-last-major-piece">finishing touches put on it</a> last week and will be launched shortly before the operation and will attempt to fly by at the very moment of impact and capture &#8220;the resultant plume of ejecta and possibly the newly-formed impact crater.&#8221;</p>
<p>A very exciting and interesting mission to be sure, but had to be delayed past its original launch window of this summer, and <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-invites-media-to-launch-of-double-asteroid-redirection-test">November 23 marks the first day of the new launch window</a>. DART is scheduled to launch from Vandenberg in Southern California at 10:20 PM on that date, aboard a SpaceX Falcon 9.</p>
<p>With Osiris-Rex and Japan&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/21/japans-hayabusa-2-has-landed-on-an-asteroid-shot-it-with-a-special-bullet-and-returned-to-space/">Hayabusa-2</a> missions, Earth authorities are getting pretty good at reaching out and touching asteroids. We&#8217;ll know more about the plan of attack on the Didymos binary in the run-up to launch.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Wg3UlQ27Qq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/how-to-watch-nasas-osiris-rex-snatch-a-sample-from-near-earth-asteroid-bennu/">NASA&#8217;s OSIRIS-REx just snatched a rock sample from asteroid Bennu</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;NASA&#8217;s OSIRIS-REx just snatched a rock sample from asteroid Bennu&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/how-to-watch-nasas-osiris-rex-snatch-a-sample-from-near-earth-asteroid-bennu/embed/#?secret=Wg3UlQ27Qq" data-secret="Wg3UlQ27Qq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/nasas-armageddon-style-asteroid-deflection-mission-takes-off-in-november/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212190</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NHTSA rejects petition for formal investigation into Tesla&#8217;s battery management software</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/nhtsa-rejects-petition-for-formal-investigation-into-teslas-battery-management-software/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/nhtsa-rejects-petition-for-formal-investigation-into-teslas-battery-management-software/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 21:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nhtsa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla Model x]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla Model Y]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212104</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The National Highway Traffic and Safety Administration rejected a 2019 petition requesting the agency open a formal investigation into Tesla&#8217;s battery management software over allegations that an over-the-air update was defective and caused fires in five vehicles. The agency decided not to open a formal investigation in part because the majority of those incidents occurred [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The National Highway Traffic and Safety Administration rejected a 2019 petition requesting the agency open a formal investigation into Tesla&#8217;s battery management software over allegations that an over-the-air update was defective and caused fires in five vehicles.</p>
<p>The agency decided not to open a formal investigation in part because the majority of those incidents occurred outside of the United States, according to a <a href="https://static.nhtsa.gov/odi/inv/2019/INCLA-DP19005-2413.PDF">document posted on its website</a>. None of these were related to crashes and most were parked.</p>
<p>As part of its evaluation, NHTSA reviewed 59 complaints out of the total 61,781 Model S and Model X vehicles from 2012 to 2019 included in the petition before it decided to reject it. Out of the 59 complaints, 52 alleged reductions in battery capacity and seven alleged reductions in charging speed after the software was updated. Log data from the vehicles showed that the voltage limiting firmware was enabled in 58% of the complaints, but that subsequent updates restored some or all battery capacity to those vehicles, according to the report summary.</p>
<p>The agency did find that a perfect storm caused two of the fires that occurred in China in 2019. The vehicles had recently completed fast-charging sessions, the batteries were at a high state-of-charge and were parked with the battery cooling systems shut off. The two vehicles also had histories of high-stress usage.</p>
<p>Sources familiar with Tesla&#8217;s battery management system say if there were truly a systematic software issue, way more than five cars would have caught fire. The more likely causes of such infrequent issues would be physical defects from manufacturing or physical damage in the course of use, like putting recently Supercharged vehicles under high stress, which NHTSA says is more common in China where those fires occurred.</p>
<p>There were also two fires that occurred in the U.S., but one involved a vehicle with no Supercharging history that was driving at the time of the fire, and another that couldn&#8217;t be linked back to the high-voltage battery system. The fifth fire happened in Germany with a vehicle that had been parked at a low state of charge for an extended period of time.</p>
<p>&#8220;Given the absence of any incidents in the United States related to fast charging, and the absence of any such incidents globally since May 2019, it is unlikely that an order concerning the notification and remedy of a safety-related defect would be issued due to any investigation opened as a result of granting this petition,&#8221; the petition concluded. &#8220;Therefore, upon full consideration of the information presented in the petition, and the potential risks to safety, the petition is denied.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The report did say that the agency would take further action if warranted, despite the denial of this current petition, if future findings identify safety-related defects.</p>
<p class="paywall">Even as NHTSA rejects this petition, it is still moving forward with a different<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/tesla-ordered-to-share-autopilot-data-with-the-us-traffic-safety-agency/"> investigation into Tesla&#8217;s Autopilot software</a> after certain cars that had activated the advanced driver assistance system crashed into 12 parked first responder vehicles with flashing lights, resulting in 17 injuries and one death since 2018. Tesla has until October 22 to hand over detailed Autopilot data or face fines up to $115 million, a slap on the wrist, really, considering the company&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/teslas-quarterly-profit-surpasses-1-billion/#:~:text=Tesla%20reported%20revenue%20of%20%2411.96,and%20%24600%20million%20in%20profit.">second quarter net income of $1.14 billion</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/nhtsa-rejects-petition-for-formal-investigation-into-teslas-battery-management-software/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212104</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>No-code mobile website builder Universe launches new themes, block features and more</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/no-code-mobile-website-builder-universe-launches-new-themes-block-features-and-more/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/no-code-mobile-website-builder-universe-launches-new-themes-block-features-and-more/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 20:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[website builder]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212094</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mobile website building platform Universe has launched a new update that brings advanced creative controls, enhanced themes, block features and more to its grid-based web builder. Universe allows users to create a custom site or open an e-commerce store directly from a mobile phone through a simplified grid system without the need for coding. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Mobile website building platform <a href="https://onuniverse.com/">Universe</a> has launched a new update that brings advanced creative controls, enhanced themes, block features and more to its grid-based web builder. Universe allows users to create a custom site or open an e-commerce store directly from a mobile phone through a simplified grid system without the need for coding. The new update, GRID System II, aims to simplify previously complex coding processes into intuitive gestures to make the website-building process easier.</p>
<p>“What makes Universe special is the grid system and what we’re announcing today is a big upgrade of that grid system. It’s going to allow people to do a lot more without any technical knowledge,” Universe CEO and founder Joseph Cohen told TechCrunch in an interview.</p>
<p>The website building process is based on simple building blocks, where the platform gives users a wide grid into which they can drop content. The new update brings redesigned creative controls with an improved graphical interface, which allows for control around block padding in the grid, along with granular text spacing. Cohen stated that users are now able to make the grid denser and can go up to seven columns wide. The new interface also includes enhanced color selection tools.</p>
<p>Further, Universe users can now also select from 30 new themes for their site or create their own. Prior to the addition of themes, every block was independently styled on a case-by-case basis. Now with the introduction of themes, users are able to apply consistent design elements across fonts, page backgrounds and button colors. The themes are applied to all surfaces of users’ sites, including text, backgrounds, headlines and colors.</p>
<p>“We have made 30 amazing themes that you can apply to your whole site. You could also go in and create your own theme from scratch. You can match or customize any of the ones that we give you out of the box. And any of the changes that you make will be applicable to your whole site. It&#8217;s basically a way of changing all the styles across the whole site in a visual and easy-to-use way,” Cohen stated.</p>
<p>Users can also now access new text styles, which allow them to classify text as titles, subtitles, captions and more. The company outlines that users can use the title indicator to boost SEO and enhance accessibility for their sites.</p>
<p>The new update also introduces a new layers feature that allows users to overlay blocks on top of each other. Previously, creators were unable to put two blocks, such as an image block and text block, on top of each other. With this new layers feature, users are given a lot more creative freedom with the design of their website.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Universe has also launched a new grid block feature that allows creators to combine different blocks in a sub-grid to create a cluster. It essentially lets you add a block to your site that creates another grid within that block, which can be used to add things like a photo gallery. Grid blocks allow for precise block arrangements to be placed on the grid. The sub-grid can then be dragged to any location on the page.</p>
<p>Although some may see Universe as a competitor to other popular website-building tools such as Shopify and Wix, Cohen says Universe is quite different.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2212174" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/FINAL_GRIID_Subgrid_Phone-Only.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2212174" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2212174" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/FINAL_GRIID_Subgrid_Phone-Only.gif" alt="" width="1024" height="576" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2212174" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Universe</p></div></p>
<p>“We invented a new interface called the grid, which basically allows someone who isn&#8217;t technical or isn&#8217;t a professional designer to create a totally custom website. There are other systems like Squarespace, Shopify, Weebly and Wix, but those are website builders that are desktop-based and template-based. Universe is not template-based, we do have templates available but it is not a template-based system. It&#8217;s not constrained by templates, so the grid itself is our interface for creation.”</p>
<p>In terms of usage, Cohen outlined that Universe has seen an increase in users amid the COVID-19 pandemic as many people started new businesses or side hustles and were looking to create websites. Early on in the pandemic, Universe released the ability for users to sell and ship products on their sites. As a result, users aren’t required to sign up for a third-party e-commerce tool, such as Shopify.</p>
<p>“Since the pandemic started, our business has really ballooned over the past year and a half. In terms of overall growth, we have more or less 10x the business in terms of the number of active sites that are created,” Cohen noted.</p>
<p>Further, Cohen outlined that Universe saw an increase in users from the influencer community who want a “link in bio” site, which is essentially a URL at the end of an Instagram profile&#8217;s bio that redirects users to a website outside of Instagram. The redirected site is often used to sell products, link to other social media accounts, showcase a portfolio and more. Cohen said that 40% of the sites created on Universe are for “link in bio” purposes and that these types of sites are Universe’s biggest growing areas of business, in addition to commerce.</p>
<p>Cohen says that Universe currently has hundreds of thousands of active sites and that the company plans to continue to launch more consumer-friendly updates in the future as the platform continues to grow.</p>
<p>“With this update, we’re leaping forward but we will continue to iterate this grid system for decades and in the fullness of time, anything that’s possible on the internet will be possible with our grid system. This includes the core creative elements but also the commerce capabilities around building a business,” Cohen stated.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/no-code-mobile-website-builder-universe-launches-new-themes-block-features-and-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212094</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chime&#8217;s Chris Britt and Menlo Ventures&#8217; Shawn Carolan to talk fintech on TechCrunch Live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/chimes-chris-britt-and-menlo-ventures-shawn-carolan-to-talk-fintech-on-techcrunch-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/chimes-chris-britt-and-menlo-ventures-shawn-carolan-to-talk-fintech-on-techcrunch-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 20:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Britt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch live announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[menlo ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shawn carolan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Live]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[techcrunch live announcement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211956</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a world where fintech is so hot right now, and investors are being swept up by their excitement for the space, Chime has managed to ride the wave to near perfection. The company has raised upwards of $2.6 billion, including a fresh $750 million just this year. The startup, playing in the fee-free banking [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In a world where fintech is so hot right now, and investors are being swept up by their excitement for the space, Chime has managed to ride the wave to near perfection. The company has raised upwards of <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/chime-2">$2.6 billion</a>, including a fresh $750 million just this year.</p>
<p>The startup, playing in the fee-free banking space, now has a valuation of $25 billion. Sources told The <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/chime-financial-raises-750-million-in-latest-funding-round-11628872069">Wall Street Journal</a> that an IPO is on the horizon for the startup.</p>
<p>So, we&#8217;re more than thrilled to announce that Chime founder and CEO Chris Britt will be joining us on an <a href="https://hopin.com/events/techcrunch-live-with-menlo-ventures-and-chime?ref=0b6251e1da9a">upcoming episode of TechCrunch Live (formerly Extra Crunch Live)</a>. Britt will be joined by Shawn Carolan of Menlo Ventures, who led the company&#8217;s Series C funding round back in 2018.</p>
<p>TechCrunch Live is a free, weekly event that lets folks in the audience connect with founders and the investors who finance them to learn how to build better venture-backed businesses. We talk about what drew the investors to the company, how the founder chose to partner with those particular investors and how they work together, and scale the business, moving forward.</p>
<p>In the latter half of each episode, founders in the audience are encouraged to jump on our virtual stage and pitch their products, receiving live feedback from our esteemed duos.</p>
<p>TechCrunch Live is free for anyone who would like to attend live, but only TechCrunch+ members have access to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">full library of TechCrunch Live content on demand</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://hopin.com/events/techcrunch-live-with-menlo-ventures-and-chime?ref=0b6251e1da9a">This episode of TCL goes down on October 13 at noon PDT/3 p.m. EDT</a>. See you there!</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/chimes-chris-britt-and-menlo-ventures-shawn-carolan-to-talk-fintech-on-techcrunch-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211956</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook stock falls as global outage continues</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-stock-falls-as-global-outage-continues/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-stock-falls-as-global-outage-continues/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 20:22:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outage]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook&#8217;s stock took a dive Monday as the site suffered one of its worst outages of the past decade with services across its entire suite of products going offline while the tech company struggled to even bring its own internal services back online. The stock ended the day down nearly 5%, with Facebook shedding tens [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook&#8217;s stock took a dive Monday as the site suffered one of its worst outages of the past decade with services across its entire suite of products going offline while the tech company struggled to even bring its own internal services back online.</p>
<p>The stock ended the day down nearly 5%, with Facebook shedding tens of billions in market cap value as the company sorted through the pieces attempting to diagnose what triggered the outage, and investors looked to calculate what lasting damage to the site could look like. Facebook stock has been on a tear in 2021, reaching a $1 trillion market cap in early July, though the share price has stalled in recent months with the market cap currently resting just south of $920 billion.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5jgoIuM5oS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-messenger-instagram-whatsapp-are-all-down/">Facebook, Messenger, Instagram and WhatsApp are all down</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook, Messenger, Instagram and WhatsApp are all down&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-messenger-instagram-whatsapp-are-all-down/embed/#?secret=5jgoIuM5oS" data-secret="5jgoIuM5oS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Even being down for several hours or a day could be enough to shift some users toward competing services, a threat that investors are currently weighing as the company&#8217;s share price slides.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">We’re aware that some people are having trouble accessing our apps and products. We’re working to get things back to normal as quickly as possible, and we apologize for any inconvenience.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&mdash; Andy Stone (@andymstone) <a href="https://twitter.com/andymstone/status/1445058088436908045?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 4, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-stock-falls-as-global-outage-continues/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212140</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GraphWear closes $20.5M Series B for a needle-free, nanotech-powered glucose monitor</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/graphwear-closes-20-5m-series-b-for-a-needle-free-nanotech-powered-glucose-monitor/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/graphwear-closes-20-5m-series-b-for-a-needle-free-nanotech-powered-glucose-monitor/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Betuel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 20:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graphene]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GraphWear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GraphWear Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mayfield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical devices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensors]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2210542</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[GraphWear, a company pursuing needle-free approaches to glucose monitoring, has closed a $20.5 million Series B round. This Series B round is a vote of confidence by investors in GraphWear’s approach: to monitor key metrics in the body, like glucose, without breaking the skin at all.  GraphWear Technologies was founded in 2015 by Rajatesh Gudibande [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">GraphWear, a company pursuing needle-free approaches to glucose monitoring, has closed a $20.5 million Series B round. This Series B round is a vote of confidence by investors in GraphWear’s approach: to monitor key metrics in the body, like glucose, without breaking the skin at all. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">GraphWear Technologies was founded in 2015 by Rajatesh Gudibande and Saurabh Radhakrishnan, who had both completed master’s degrees in nanotechnology at the University of Pennsylvania. Specifically, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">GraphWear is developing a skin-surface-level wearable made of graphene (more on this material later). The sensor is small, about the size of an Apple Watch &#8212; but the key piece of technology is actually housed on the bottom. It’s a thin slice of graphene that fits onto the back of the watch, or onto a sticker that can be worn on the abdomen. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This Series B round, says Gudibande, will be focused on helping the company build upon previous validation studies of the wearable, completing a pivotal trial and submitting for FDA clearance. The round was led by Mayfield, with participation from MissionBio Capital, Builders VC and VSC Ventures.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The Holy Grail problem has been: can you really know what is happening in your blood without using things to prick your skin and draw blood out,” says Ursheet Parikh the co-leader of Mayfield&#8217;s engineering biology investment practice. “We think GraphWear has made progress and is likely to be one of the first companies to actually bring a product that can get to hundreds of millions of people.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Continuous glucose monitoring has been a recent push within the diabetes community. There have been several continuous glucose monitors approved in recent years, like the FreeStyle Libre, <a href="https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/scripts/cdrh/cfdocs/cfpma/pma.cfm?id=P160030">approved by the FDA in 2017</a>. That device still uses a subcutaneous filament on an arm patch to measure glucose levels.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These devices have clear upsides for people with Type I diabetes (people whose bodies make little or no insulin). That’s about </span><a href="https://www.diabetes.org/resources/statistics/statistics-about-diabetes"><span style="font-weight: 400;">1.6 million people</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the U.S. alone. The American Diabetes Association notes that most people who regularly inject insulin “should be encouraged” to use self-monitoring glucose technologies, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">including </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">continuous glucose monitors, in </span><a href="https://care.diabetesjournals.org/content/43/Supplement_1/S77"><span style="font-weight: 400;">its 2020 guidelines</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As for people with Type II diabetes (</span><a href="https://www.cdc.gov/diabetes/basics/type2.html#:~:text=Healthy%20eating%20is%20your%20recipe,adults%20are%20also%20developing%20it."><span style="font-weight: 400;">about 34 million Americans</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">), or for people who don’t regularly inject insulin, there’s a bit more debate. <a href="https://khn.org/news/article/continuous-glucose-monitoring-blood-sugar-little-evidence-beneficial-type-2-diabetes-patients/">Some argue</a> that regularly monitoring glucose (which is what continuous glucose monitors do) isn&#8217;t worth it for these populations. For example <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/fullarticle/2630691">one 2017</a> JAMA Internal Medicine study found that routine self-monitoring of glucose didn&#8217;t lead people to improve their A1c levels (a key diabetes biomarker) after one year. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">That study, though, evaluated people who regularly used finger-stick tests, rather than non-invasive continuous glucose monitors. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still, the American Diabetes Association </span><a href="https://care.diabetesjournals.org/content/43/Supplement_1/S77"><span style="font-weight: 400;">notes that</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, if used properly, continuous glucose monitors in conjunction with insulin therapy, can be useful tools for these people as well. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">GraphWear’s sensor takes a nanotechnology-based approach to continuous glucose monitoring. And, unlike other continuous glucose monitors, which may require a small retractable filament or finger sticks to evaluate blood glucose, the device doesn’t break the skin at all, says Gudibande. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The graphene has an electric field that drags the molecules up,” Gudibande explains. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“You’re talking about about 200 molecules,” he continues. “It then ‘tastes’ it, converts it to an electrical signal, and then transports via Bluetooth to your phone that can chart and display glucose values continuously.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Note that these sensors are actually measuring the glucose present in interstitial fluid, not the glucose present in blood. However, there’s evidence glucose measured from the interstitial fluid </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">“<a href="https://care.diabetesjournals.org/content/43/Supplement_1/S77">correlates well with plasma glucose</a>”</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, per the American Diabetes Association’s 2020 guidelines, so measurements taken this way are still clinically relevant for people with diabetes. Gudibande adds, &#8220;our own empirical clinical data suggests the same.&#8221; </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">GraphWear has already completed one </span><a href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04226846"><span style="font-weight: 400;">feasibility study</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for the wearable sensor on 40 patients with both Type I and Type II diabetes. They tested the device’s glucose monitoring against glucose measures collected from venous blood draws. Results have not yet been released. However, Gudibande says that GraphWear’s accuracy was “comparable” to that of the traditional sensor. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Glucose monitoring aside, another big picture element to consider when it comes to GraphWear is the material the sensor is made of: graphene. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Graphene is a single-atom thin carbon sheet. It happens to be an </span><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nature.2014.14676"><span style="font-weight: 400;">exceptional conductor</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of electricity, and is strong, light and flexible. Since graphene was <a href="https://www.aps.org/publications/apsnews/200910/physicshistory.cfm#:~:text=The%20man%20who%20first%20discovered,State%20Physics%20in%20Chernogolovka%2C%20Russia.">discovered in 2004</a>, the material has generated a lot of hype &#8212; it was </span><a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/programmes/click_online/9491789.stm"><span style="font-weight: 400;">supposed to be the next silicon</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, though that hasn’t quite happened yet.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still, the </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/sep/27/graphene-wonder-material-national-security-china-uk"><span style="font-weight: 400;">U.K.</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, China and </span><a href="https://graphene-flagship.eu/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the EU</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are investing heavily in production of graphene at an industrial scale. And there are some graphene products leaking on the market already (it’s in bikes, shoes, sensors and tennis rackets, to name a few applications highlighted in a </span><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41565-019-0555-2"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2019 review paper)</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">GraphWear can keep the graphene used in its sensors “pristine,” says Gudibande, which allows it to be highly sensitive to glucose molecules that it may encounter. The company, says Parikh, can also manufacture the material at scale, and is developing new applications of nanotechnology that could be useful beyond sensing glucose. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Specifically, the team has patented a way to use </span><a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/WO2017216641A3/en"><span style="font-weight: 400;">polarized fluids as transistors</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“If your glucose molecules are on the skin, it becomes like a transient transistor that shows up,” says Parikh. “That is a new class of transistor, and that’s a fundamental innovation.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The glucose monitoring, though, is a smart first step for the company, because there&#8217;s a decently clear pathway to approval. If the company’s upcoming pivotal trial demonstrates that it’s similar to other continuous glucose monitors it could pursue FDA 510(k) clearance. Though, as Gudibande acknowledges, there could be some unforeseen pitfalls. For instance, it&#8217;s possible that GraphWear&#8217;s noninvasive approach could put it in a class of its own. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“So there’s a risk to that, of whether we will be 510(k),” Gudibande says. “But the process for that will be anywhere from six to 14 months. Our goal is to get through the trials and submit to the regulatory body.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If GraphWear can deliver on measuring other biomolecules using its graphene platform, they could use the platform to detect other molecules or continuously monitor what’s going on inside the body. This Series B round, though, will be focused on delivering the first step: a clinically evaluated, graphene-based sensor.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/graphwear-closes-20-5m-series-b-for-a-needle-free-nanotech-powered-glucose-monitor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2210542</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Investors share how infrastructure as code is taking over DevOps</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/investors-share-how-infrastructure-as-code-is-taking-over-devops/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/investors-share-how-infrastructure-as-code-is-taking-over-devops/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Karan Bhasin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 20:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aaron Jacobson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Cloud and Enterprise Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Investor Surveys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infrastructure as Code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insight Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[madrona venture group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[menlo ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new enterprise associates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[S. Somasegar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sheila Gulati]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sri Pangulur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teddie Wardi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tim Tully]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tola capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tribe Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211968</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Infrastructure as code (IaC) has been gaining wider adoption among DevOps teams in recent years, but the complexities of data center configuration and management continue to create problems — and opportunities.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Infrastructure as code (IaC) has been gaining wider adoption among DevOps teams in recent years, but the complexities of data center configuration and management continue to create problems — and opportunities.</p>
<p>We surveyed top investors in IaC startups to find out more.</p>
<p>Overall, they see a lot of room for growth given all of the manual work still done by DevOps teams across organizations of all sizes.</p>
<p>However, IaC itself requires highly trained engineers to implement and manage within organizations, and there’s a shortage of software infrastructure engineers with IaC skills. This could favor IaC startups that are trying to offer complete solutions to customers.</p>
<p>At the same time, some large companies will continue to manage data centers internally and thus build out automation internally instead of with outside startups.</p>
<p>We spoke to:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sheilagulati/">Sheila Gulati</a>, managing director, <a href="https://www.tolacapital.com/our-team/">Tola Capital</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/s-somasegar-113791a5/">S. Somasegar</a>, managing director, <a href="https://www.madrona.com/team-profiles/s-somasegar/">Madrona Venture Group</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/aaronejacobson/">Aaron Jacobson</a>, partner, <a href="https://www.nea.com/team/aaron-jacobson">New Enterprise Associates</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sripangulur/">Sri Pangulur</a>, partner, <a href="https://tribecap.co/">Tribe Capital</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/teddie/">Teddie Wardi</a>, managing director, <a href="https://www.insightpartners.com/team/teddie-wardi">Insight Partners</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/timothytully/">Tim Tully</a>, partner, <a href="https://www.menlovc.com/tim-tully">Menlo Ventures</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h2><strong>Sheila Gulati, managing director, Tola Capital</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Can infrastructure as code be the solution for the implementation and configuration of servers, similar to how cloud was the solution for physical servers? Which areas do you think IaC’s capability to set up any cloud resource will be most used?</strong></p>
<p>The world of the modern cloud has shifted how we think about infrastructure altogether. We live in a multicloud and many-cloud world and these paradigms are redefining the modern cloud era. IaC can be used for any type of cloud workload or architecture, but it is a necessity for anyone building on the modern cloud. This is especially true for modern cloud architectures such as serverless applications, containerized applications running Kubernetes, AI/ML and more. Modern cloud architectures provide many benefits such as increased innovation, faster time to market, improved reliability and reduced costs. However, this has increased the burden of managing cloud infrastructure. The number of cloud services available is growing every year and modern architectures are composed of many loosely coupled, interdependent services and APIs. The result is that the number of cloud resources that people must manage is going up at a tremendous pace. The only way to manage this complexity is with IaC.</p>
<p>Today, we are seeing a new generation of IaC platforms that are designed from the ground up to meet the demands of the modern cloud. For example, <a href="https://www.pulumi.com/">Pulumi</a> and its cloud engineering platform is helping infrastructure teams and developers tame cloud complexity by enabling them to write code in the languages that they know and love, and use software engineering practices to build, deploy and manage cloud infrastructure. In contrast to legacy IaC tools that use domain specific languages, modern IaC platforms give practitioners the full power of programming languages, which make it easier to manage the complex interdependencies of modern cloud applications. They allow developers to use existing software development tools, including IDEs, package managers and test frameworks, which enable them to build faster and reuse best practices, while testing more frequently.</p>
<p><strong>Do you see IaC’s ability to streamline processes attracting startups in competitive sectors looking to get their product across the line first?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. The companies in our portfolio who have embraced IaC and cloud engineering principles are also the ones most intent on rapid product development and streamlining their ability to bring new products to market faster. This requires investment in engineering talent, the platform and engineering practices.</p>
<p>It is important to take advantage of new cloud innovation to accelerate innovation and leverage IaC to more build products to efficiently meet customer needs. To support this it is critical for there to be partnership across providers within the IaC space to deliver the components that work together to support engineering teams.</p>
<p>Furthermore, we have seen teams that lean into more modern development platforms able to hire better developers more easily — a concern of every tech company today. The cultures that are more dev-forward and that are truly embracing the shift-left movement are where the best developers want to work!</p>
<p><strong>Why are companies hesitant to adopt infrastructure as code? Can you outline the different ways IaC providers can market themselves to build their appeal?</strong></p>
<p>IaC should be the obvious choice for any company that’s interested in delivering cloud applications at scale, reliably, and at high velocity. The concerns of the past are now obsolete. However, companies may hesitate to adopt it due to the cultural and process changes required, the risks of migrating an existing application, or they may not have the right skills on their team. In the past, we also had IaC platforms that required the use of domain-specific languages. All of this taken together can make the ramp to productivity seem steep.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/investors-share-how-infrastructure-as-code-is-taking-over-devops/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211968</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Neurodiversity and the software design dilemma</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/neurodiversity-and-the-software-design-dilemma/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/neurodiversity-and-the-software-design-dilemma/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 19:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neurodiversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211416</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Neurodiverse professionals bring different perspectives and strengths to the table and often challenge the status quo. It is this diversity of thought that gives an organization strength in special ways.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Pouyan Salehi</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/psalehi">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/pouyansalehi/">Pouyan Salehi</a> is the co-founder and CEO of <a href="https://scratchpad.com/about">Scratchpad</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Homo sapiens is truly a diverse species. We appear distinct from each other based on our origins in various regions of the planet; we communicate using thousands of languages; we have different thought patterns based on our experiences, heritage and cultures. Our brains are all unique; we analyze issues and make decisions using all of these properties &#8212; and many others.</p>
<p>These factors all directly affect how we do business and how we use tools to execute our duties. Doing business well is challenging enough for most people, but people with neurodiverse characteristics &#8212; professionals who &#8220;think different,&#8221; as the late Steve Jobs used to say &#8212; are a unique breed whose talent is too often underappreciated or untapped inside companies, which often value standardization and prefer limited deviations from normal work patterns.</p>
<h2>The role of neurodiversity</h2>
<p>Neurodivergent people process information differently from the way the mainstream does. Examples of this are people on the autism spectrum, with dyslexia, or those with attention deficit disorder, or ADD. Experts believe as much as <a href="https://adhdaware.org.uk/what-is-adhd/neurodiversity-and-other-conditions/">40% of the population</a> is neurodivergent.</p>
<p>Many think the percentage is even higher in the sales profession, given that good salespeople often are more persistent and think &#8220;out of the box.” It’s not unlikely that someone on any given sales team is a superstar salesperson but has neurological variants affecting how they interact with information and with others. That makes a particularly interesting argument for the wisdom of integrating neuroatypical people into sales organizations and enabling them to thrive.</p>
<p>For example, salespeople use customer relationship management (CRM) software systems, where all records, workflows and analytics are standardized and the user experience is constrained to the <em>one</em> way the system was configured.</p>
<p>But not everybody can use such a complicated and rigid system optimally, especially when the user interaction layer is so strictly limited. Most neurodiverse people especially have difficulty with “opinionated” applications that tend to impose a certain way of working on the user, sometimes without considering all aspects of the user’s humanness &#8212; their unique way of processing information and navigating workflows. This is why in most sales organizations, the top-performing sales reps are often the ones who update the CRM least and why most salespeople use basic note-taking applications, tasks and spreadsheets to manage their own pipeline of deals.</p>
<p>Neurodiverse professionals bring different perspectives and strengths to the table and often challenge the status quo. It is this diversity of thought that gives an organization strength in special ways.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>What do companies have to gain from neurodiverse talent?</h2>
<p>JP Morgan created a neurodiversity pilot program in 2015 called Autism at Work, and the <a href="https://www.jpmorganchase.com/news-stories/neurodiverse-hiring-brings-social-and-business-benefits">results were notable</a>. Employees in the program were 48% faster at completing tasks and 92% more productive than their peers. Preliminary <a href="https://hbr.org/2017/05/neurodiversity-as-a-competitive-advantage">results from another pilot program</a> at Australia’s Department of Human Services found that the organization’s neurodiverse software testing teams were 30% more productive than neurotypical teams.</p>
<p>Most autistic people are known to possess intense attention to detail. A 7-year-old boy on the autism spectrum, for example, has memorized the details of every shipwreck in history. This type of focus and appetite for information has remarkable potential when harnessed in the right roles. Autistic talent is often ideally suited to some of the fastest-growing segments of the knowledge economy, including data analytics, tech services and software engineering. In fact, Tesla CEO Elon Musk<a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/05/12/business/elon-musk-aspergers/index.html"> recently revealed</a> that he has Asperger’s syndrome, a form of autism.</p>
<p>In another neurodiversity area, out-of-the-box thinkers are often dyslexic. Consider some of the dyslexic people who have changed the world: Steve Jobs, Richard Branson and Bill Gates, to name a few. What they have in common is the ability to look at the world differently.</p>
<h2>The software dilemma</h2>
<p>More and more companies are getting the message: Neurodivergent employees should be appreciated as a huge source of talent and contributions. At the same time, increased awareness of social injustices of all kinds in the wake of the events of 2020 has spurred more organizations to recognize neurodiversity as part of their diversity, equity and inclusion initiatives.</p>
<p>But to this point, the focus has largely been on how hiring, training, onboarding processes, and even office design (when we all return to offices) can be more inclusive for neurodivergent people. For example, SAP and Microsoft have expanded efforts to hire more neuroatypical employees.</p>
<p>Those initiatives are important, but we believe software companies need to go a step further and change their approach at the core design level.</p>
<p>A lot of software imposes a certain way of working on users, with little to no care about how everything feels and flows from the user’s perspective. And along the way, this rigid system ends up excluding many people who are neurodiverse. As a result, users face challenges in their day-to-day jobs because the tools they’ve been provided don&#8217;t fit with how they process information and navigate their workflows, all in the name of standardization, and organizations then suffer from poor adoption of their tools and systems.</p>
<p>No vendor does this intentionally; it’s just that it’s difficult to do and do well. But it should become a core value for every software company to pursue empathetic software design that imagines and caters to all users, and helps everyone be equally efficient and productive. It starts with recognizing and appreciating that not all “users” are the same, which then leads to designing more flexible and approachable software that a larger percentage of people can use naturally.</p>
<p>If sales organizations have more than their share of neurodivergent people, imagine the effect that the wrong kind of tools can have — say, CRM software that demands a person with ADHD handle a plethora of tedious data entry tasks. Imagine all the frustration, lost potential and damaged morale because a skilled, neurodiverse salesperson simply was given the wrong tools for them to demonstrate their full potential.</p>
<p>The time has come for the industry as a whole to expand its thinking about software user experience and include flexibility as a key design principle.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/neurodiversity-and-the-software-design-dilemma/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211416</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Informatica&#8217;s IPO will test public markets&#8217; appetite for slower-growing tech offerings</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/informaticas-ipo-will-test-public-markets-appetite-for-slower-growing-tech-offerings/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/informaticas-ipo-will-test-public-markets-appetite-for-slower-growing-tech-offerings/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 19:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Databricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Cloud and Enterprise Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[informatica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211930</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How strong of a cloud business has Informatica managed to build, and how winsome is its economic profile? It has yet to set an IPO price range, but there are reports of a valuation as high as $10 billion.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Informatica <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1868778/000119312521289749/d169828ds1.htm">filed to go public</a> late last week, some six years after it was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/04/08/informatica-could-feel-a-tight-squeeze-from-its-new-owners/">taken private by two private equity teams for $5.3 billion</a>. The data-focused company used its passage through the private markets to execute a move to the cloud, work that came to a head in early 2021, when Informatica announced its <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/informaticas-journey-to-the-cloud/">dive into the lakehouse market</a>, where Databricks plays today.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll explore the company&#8217;s IPO filing to figure out just how strong of a cloud business it has managed to build and how winsome its overall economic profile appears. While the company has yet to set an initial IPO price range giving us an indicator of where it might be valued, there are media reports of a valuation <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-01/permira-backed-technology-company-informatica-files-for-ipo">as high as $10 billion</a>.</p>
<p>A number that big demands exploration. Let&#8217;s get into the numbers.</p>
<h2>Inside Informatica&#8217;s business</h2>
<p>Turning back the clock to 2015, the <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/en/news-release/2015/04/22/727263/11123/en/Informatica-Reports-First-Quarter-Results.html">final Informatica earnings release</a> that we could find from its last run at being a public company is dated April 22, 2015. That was just days after the company&#8217;s takeover was announced, so the timing makes sense.</p>
<p>At the time, Informatica reported revenues of $250.5 million, up 3% from its year-ago comp. That revenue growth number was more than anemic but did contain an interesting seed of good news, namely that &#8220;subscription revenues&#8221; at the company were up 47% on a year-over-year basis. Sure, every company wants you to focus more on its growth business than its overall performance, but the subscription result was pretty strong, even if it was from a modest base figure ($21.3 million).</p>
<p>And in that final period &#8212; the quarter ended March 31, 2015 &#8212; Informatica generated $32.2 million in operating income and $21.6 million worth of net income. At the time it went private, Informatica was profitable and slow growing, albeit with a new business arm that was putting up pretty notable revenue expansion.</p>
<p>What happened over the last half-decade or so?</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/informaticas-ipo-will-test-public-markets-appetite-for-slower-growing-tech-offerings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211930</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NFT startup Dapper Labs acquires virtual influencer startup Brud</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/nft-startup-dapper-labs-acquires-virtual-influencer-startup-brud/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/nft-startup-dapper-labs-acquires-virtual-influencer-startup-brud/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 18:33:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dapper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dapper Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musicians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national basketball association]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dapper Labs, the NFT startup behind NBA Top Shot, which was recently valued above $7.5 billion, made an interesting acquisition this morning, telling Decrypt that they have purchased virtual influencer startup Brud and will be bringing the entire 32-person team aboard. Brud is best known for its digitally rendered social media influencer characters, specifically one [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Dapper Labs, the NFT startup behind NBA Top Shot, which was recently valued above $7.5 billion, made an interesting acquisition this morning, telling <a href="https://decrypt.co/82517/dapper-labs-nfts-daos-collectives-brud">Decrypt</a> that they have purchased virtual influencer startup Brud and will be bringing the entire 32-person team aboard.</p>
<p>Brud is best known for its digitally rendered social media influencer characters, specifically one named Lil Miquela. The startup spawned several other players in the space when it caught investor attention back in 2018 but the virtual influencer space hasn&#8217;t seen any explosions in interest and has stayed a pretty niche space over the years. The company&#8217;s cache of characters have lived fictionalized lives on Instagram, racking up followers as the startup earned a $125 million valuation. Dapper didn&#8217;t disclose what it paid for Brud.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Twitter friends, I am very excited to announce today that Brud has been acquired by <a href="https://twitter.com/dapperlabs?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@dapperlabs</a>!</p>
<p>Together we will be building the decentralized, collectively owned future of media and social with DAOs on <a href="https://twitter.com/flow_blockchain?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@flow_blockchain</a>!<a href="https://t.co/H6z0DipZ5l">https://t.co/H6z0DipZ5l</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Trev<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f643.png" alt="🙃" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />r is hiring engineers! DM Me (@whatdotcd) <a href="https://twitter.com/whatdotcd/status/1445054831106924545?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 4, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The most pertinent question here is what does an NFT startup like Dapper want with Lil Miquela (now, just Miquela)?</p>
<p>Well, it seem that the short of it is &#8212; not that much? Brud&#8217;s founder Trevor McFedries has been getting deeper into the crypto world and moving his startup&#8217;s focus toward collective decision-making through decentralized autonomous organizations (DAOs), which is where Dapper&#8217;s central interest seems to lie. McFedries is already the co-founder of one of the more popular DAOs called &#8220;Friends With Benefits.&#8221; DAOs can help users team up to make investment decisions as a collective and they&#8217;ve grown more popular in the past year as developers in the crypto space have started crafting bolder projects in the space.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While McFedries says the company will continue to develop Miquela, he will now lead a division inside Dapper Labs called Dapper Collectives focused on making DAOs more user-friendly and accessible to a new generation of crypto web users while leveraging the company&#8217;s Flow blockchain.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RRf28lSRnC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/28/nba-top-shot-creator-on-the-nft-craze-and-why-ethereum-still-isnt-consumer-friendly/">NBA Top Shot creator on the NFT craze and why Ethereum still isn&#8217;t consumer friendly</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;NBA Top Shot creator on the NFT craze and why Ethereum still isn&#8217;t consumer friendly&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/28/nba-top-shot-creator-on-the-nft-craze-and-why-ethereum-still-isnt-consumer-friendly/embed/#?secret=RRf28lSRnC" data-secret="RRf28lSRnC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hXsmuTuw2q"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/14/more-investors-are-betting-on-virtual-influencers-like-lil-miquela/">More investors are betting on virtual influencers like Lil Miquela</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;More investors are betting on virtual influencers like Lil Miquela&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/14/more-investors-are-betting-on-virtual-influencers-like-lil-miquela/embed/#?secret=hXsmuTuw2q" data-secret="hXsmuTuw2q" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/nft-startup-dapper-labs-acquires-virtual-influencer-startup-brud/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212008</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Index, Sequoia and Canvas investors weigh in on how to raise your first dollars</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/index-sequoia-and-canvas-investors-weigh-in-on-how-to-raise-your-first-dollars/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/index-sequoia-and-canvas-investors-weigh-in-on-how-to-raise-your-first-dollars/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 18:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canvas Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC TechCrunch Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundraising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Index Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[luciana lixandru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rebecca Lynn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2209655</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Founders seeking to raise their first round of capital may feel overwhelmed with the prospect. There is definitely plenty of capital out there, but there are also a lot of startups clamoring for it.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Founders seeking to raise their first round of capital may feel overwhelmed by the prospect. There is definitely plenty of capital out there, but there are also a lot of startups clamoring for it.</p>
<p>To help new entrepreneurs figure out this dilemma, we invited three investors to speak at a panel titled, &#8220;How to Raise Your First Dollars,&#8221; during TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 so they could share their best tips on what you should do as you attempt to raise that money, as well as strategies for who to pitch to, when to pitch and how to pitch.</p>
<p>Index Ventures partner <a href="https://www.indexventures.com/team/nina-achadjian/">Nina Achadijan</a> started out by urging founders to first consider whether they actually really need to raise venture capital. &#8220;It’s a phenomenal time to be an early-stage entrepreneur. There&#8217;s more capital than ever before and there&#8217;s a willingness to accept technology from consumers and businesses,&#8221; she said. &#8220;And quite frankly, there&#8217;s a lot of platform shifts that are very exciting for early-stage entrepreneurs. But the first thing you need to do is ask yourself: Do you really need to raise venture capital? There are so many incredible businesses that can be built that actually don&#8217;t need VC funding.&#8221;</p>
<p>Achadijan said founders should first get clarity on what they would be using the money for. Secondly, she said, they should consider whether they want to eventually exit the company via an IPO or a sale. Once a founder decides to raise capital, the next step would be to make a list of companies that are either similar to theirs either in business model or by industry. Then using Crunchbase or PitchBook, she then recommends making a list of VCs that backed those companies, including angel investors.</p>
<p>&#8220;Then what you can start to do is go down that list and say, ‘It seems like this person focuses 100% on what I&#8217;m doing; I&#8217;m definitely going to talk to them,&#8217; or &#8216;This person has backed similar business models and I&#8217;m really excited to hear their perspective on my space or my industry!&#8217; And then once you have your target list … you can start to get introductions and basically start the process of fundraising,” she said.</p>
<p>Canvas Ventures’ co-founder and general partner <a href="https://www.canvas.vc/team-member/rebecca-lynn">Rebecca Lynn</a> agreed with the exercise. In particular, she recommended listing what’s &#8220;non-negotiable&#8221; in terms of the investor and amount of money raised, and what would be a &#8220;nice to have.&#8221;</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/index-sequoia-and-canvas-investors-weigh-in-on-how-to-raise-your-first-dollars/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2209655</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Leak shows Facebook&#8217;s business model needs regulating, says MEP</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/leak-shows-facebooks-business-model-needs-regulating-says-mep/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/leak-shows-facebooks-business-model-needs-regulating-says-mep/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 18:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alexandra Geese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christel Schaldemose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital Markets Act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital Services Act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european parliament]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frances Haugen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reuters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the wall street journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whistleblower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211955</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The European Parliament&#8217;s lead and shadow rapporteur for a major reboot of the bloc&#8217;s digital rulebook have called for an investigation following the Facebook whistleblower leaks. One of the MEPs has also called for incoming EU rules to directly tackle business models that favor &#8220;disinformation and violence over factual content&#8221;. In a joint statement, the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The European Parliament&#8217;s lead and shadow rapporteur for a major reboot of the bloc&#8217;s digital rulebook have called for an investigation following the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-whistleblower-reveals-identity-says-company-chooses-profits-over-safety/">Facebook whistleblower leaks</a>.</p>
<p>One of the MEPs has also called for incoming EU rules to directly tackle business models that favor &#8220;disinformation and violence over factual content&#8221;.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://en.alexandrageese.eu/joint-statement-alexandra-geese-christel-schaldemose-on-the-relevance-of-the-facebook-leaks-to-the-dsa-legislative-process/">joint statement</a>, the lead rapporteur for the EU&#8217;s Digital Services Act (DSA), Christel Schaldemose (S&amp;D), and Alexandra Geese (shadow rapporteur for the Greens/EFA), said they are in touch with the former Facebook employee turned whistleblower, Frances Haugen.</p>
<p>In an interview with <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-misinformation-public-60-minutes-2021-10-03/">60 Minutes</a> today, Haugen revealed herself as the source of a raft of recent leaks to The Wall Street Journal which has reported on the internal documents for a number of stories &#8212; including that Facebook&#8217;s internal research suggested Instagram <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/16/facebook-instagram-for-kids-mosseri-wsj-teen-girls/">made teenage girls&#8217; anxiety and body image issues worse</a> and that the tech giant operated policy carve-outs for <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-files-xcheck-zuckerberg-elite-rules-11631541353?mod=article_inline">whitelisting celebrities</a>.</p>
<p>The two MEPs said the leaks make it clear that Big Tech must not be allowed to continue to regulate itself.</p>
<p>The EU&#8217;s executive moved forward in<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/europe-lays-out-its-plan-to-reboot-digital-rules-and-tame-tech-giants/"> December</a> last year with a major reboot to the digital rule book &#8212; introducing the DSA and another piece of regulation that&#8217;s specifically targeted at tech giants&#8217; market power (aka the Digital Markets Act), kicking off a process of (ongoing) negotiations between EU institutions to amend and adopt legislation to extend platforms&#8217; accountability.</p>
<p>The support of the European Parliament is required to pass the digital policy packages. And Geese is unlikely to be alone in calling for stronger measures than were contained in the Commission&#8217;s original DSA proposal in light of the latest ugly Facebook revelations.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Kb67b2i9hQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-whistleblower-reveals-identity-says-company-chooses-profits-over-safety/">Facebook whistleblower reveals identity, says company &#8216;chooses profits over safety&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook whistleblower reveals identity, says company &#8216;chooses profits over safety&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-whistleblower-reveals-identity-says-company-chooses-profits-over-safety/embed/#?secret=Kb67b2i9hQ" data-secret="Kb67b2i9hQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In the joint statement, Schaldemose said that large tech companies have shown they are &#8220;<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">simply not capable&#8221; of responsible self regulation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;The governing of our shared spaces on social media must be done through democratically controlled institutions just as we have done in the parts of our society that do not lie in the digital realm. We must demand transparency from the tech companies and we must allow civil society, law makers and scholarly experts to have insight into the building blocks of the algorithms. This is the only way that we can have a public debate about the effects of these algorithms,&#8221; she also said. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;Today, we know this from the files, there are arbitrary protections of celebrities and a huge focus on negative, wrong and conflict-ridden content that threaten to undermine the very democratic conversation that we once hoped, the social media platforms could strengthen. To keep that hope alive and to allow all voices the ability to join in on the conversation, we must put firm demands to the companies governing these spaces.”</p>
<p>Geese went further &#8212; calling for the DSA to be strengthened in light of Haugen&#8217;s whistleblowing &#8212; arguing that the exposures are game-changing and make the case for regulating whole business models when they benefit from the amplification of disinformation at the expense of truthful content.</p>
<p>“I am extremely grateful for the courage of the whistleblower that finally gives us insights we need to effectively legislate. The revelations couldn’t be more timely for the work on the DSA,&#8221; said Geese. &#8220;The huge volume of documents and the person’s deep expertise are impressive. Until now, neither the public nor legislators have been able to gain such a deep insight into the mechanisms that have become far too powerful. The documents finally put all the facts on the table to allow us to adopt a stronger Digital Services Act.</p>
<p>&#8220;The conversation confirms my view that we need strong rules for content moderation and far-reaching transparency obligations in Europe. In a democracy we cannot tolerate an internet where some people have the right to promote violence and hatred in spite of the rules and others see perfectly legal content taken down by automated filters.</p>
<p>&#8220;We need to regulate the whole system and the business model that favours disinformation and violence over factual content – and enables its rapid dissemination. We also need consistent enforcement in Europe. It is naïve to appeal to corporate self-regulation and responsibility. We as elected politicians have the responsibility for democratic discourse and must exercise it in the legislative process.”</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_Lx5VmAdZSI">her interview with 60 Minutes</a>, Haugen was quizzed about a complaint made to Facebook in 2019 by major political parties across Europe &#8212; which were said to have raised concerns with the tech giant that its algorithmic preferences was forcing them to &#8220;skew negative&#8221; in their communications on its platforms and that was leading them to adopt more extreme policy positions.</p>
<p>&#8220;You are forcing us to take positions that we don&#8217;t like, that we know are bad for society, we know if we don&#8217;t take those positions we won&#8217;t win in the marketplace of social media,&#8221; said Haugen, summarizing the parties&#8217; concern in the interview.</p>
<p>Facebook was contacted for a response to the MEPs&#8217; joint statement.</p>
<p>In a statement to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/european-politicians-call-facebook-investigation-after-whistleblower-revelation-2021-10-04/">Reuters</a>, the tech giant reiterated its customary claim that it has &#8220;been advocating for updated regulations where democratic governments set industry standards to which we can all adhere&#8221;.</p>
<p>Haugen has said that she made the decision to turn whistleblower after becoming frustrated that Facebook was not responding to such concerns and that executives at the company were instead prioritizing its financial performance over making changes to its content-sorting algorithms that could reduce the platform&#8217;s negatively polarizing effects on society.</p>
<p>&#8220;Facebook has thousands of [content] options it could show you. And one of the consequences of how Facebook is picking out that content today is it optimizing for content that gets engagement or reaction. But its own research is showing that content that is hateful, that is divisive, that is polarizing &#8212; it&#8217;s easier to inspire people to anger than it is to other emotions,&#8221; Haugen also told 60 Minutes.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/21/eu-parliament-backs-tighter-rules-on-behavioural-ads/">A year ago</a> the European Parliament voted to back a call for tighter regulations on behavioral ads &#8212; such as those which power Facebook&#8217;s content-sorting social media business &#8212; advocating for less intrusive, contextual forms of advertising and urging EU lawmakers to consider further regulatory options, including asking the Commission to look at a phase-out leading to a full ban.</p>
<p>With ever more ugly revelations coming out of Facebook &#8212; seemingly on a weekly basis &#8212; momentum could well build in the European Parliament for taking a far tougher line on engagement-based business models.</p>
<p>Facebook founder Mark Zuckerberg got a frosty reception from MEPs <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/22/zuckerberg-didnt-make-any-friends-in-europe-today/">back in 2018</a> &#8212; the last time he took an in-person, publicly streamed meeting with a part of the institution, in that case in the wake of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/14/facebook-suspends-200-suspicious-apps-out-of-thousands-reviewed-so-far/">Cambridge Analytica data misuse scandal</a>.</p>
<p>Asked about the MEPs&#8217; statement today, a Commission spokesperson told the Reuters news agency that its position in favor of regulation is &#8220;clear&#8221;, adding: &#8220;The power of major platforms over public debate and social life must be subject to democratically validated rules, in particular on transparency and accountability.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rjbybMmdkq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/22/zuckerberg-didnt-make-any-friends-in-europe-today/">Zuckerberg didn&#8217;t make any friends in Europe today</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Zuckerberg didn&#8217;t make any friends in Europe today&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/22/zuckerberg-didnt-make-any-friends-in-europe-today/embed/#?secret=rjbybMmdkq" data-secret="rjbybMmdkq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/leak-shows-facebooks-business-model-needs-regulating-says-mep/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211955</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lawpath gets $7.5M AUD to become the Asia Pacific’s LegalZoom</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/lawpath-gets-7-5m-aud-to-become-the-asia-pacifics-legalzoom/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/lawpath-gets-7-5m-aud-to-become-the-asia-pacifics-legalzoom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 18:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawpath]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legal services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legaltech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LegalZoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211726</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With its subscription-based legal services platform, Lawpath wants to become the Asia Pacific’s LegalZoom (in fact, LegalZoom is one of its investors). Based in Sydney, Australia, Lawpath serves small businesses with services like legal documents, customized legal workflows, e-signatures, business registration and on-demand lawyers. The company announced today it has raised $7.5 million AUD (about [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With its subscription-based legal services platform, <a href="https://lawpath.com.au/">Lawpath</a> wants to become the Asia Pacific’s LegalZoom (in fact, LegalZoom is one of its investors). Based in Sydney, Australia, Lawpath serves small businesses with services like legal documents, customized legal workflows, e-signatures, business registration and on-demand lawyers. The company announced today it has raised $7.5 million AUD (about $5.5 million USD) to expand into new markets, including upcoming launches in New Zealand and Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>Founded in 2013, Lawpath currently has about 230,000 users, and says it is used to help form 5% of new companies in Australia.</p>
<p>Participants in this round, which brings Lawpath’s total raised to $14 million AUD, include the Gonski family; Adore Beauty chair Justin Ryan; Sandbar Investments; Ooh! Media and Readytech chair Tony Faure; LegalZoom director Khai Ha; and Bryant Stibel founding partner Gonzalo Troncoso. Existing investors Adcock Private Equity and LegalZoom also returned for this raise.</p>
<p>In addition to international expansion, the funding will also be used to double Lawpath’s current team of 40 people, especially for its product and software departments.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0YOfDSCc6N"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/lawvu-a-cloud-based-platform-for-in-house-legal-teams-raises-17m-nzd-from-insight-partners/">LawVu, a cloud-based platform for in-house legal teams, raises $17M NZD from Insight Partners</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;LawVu, a cloud-based platform for in-house legal teams, raises $17M NZD from Insight Partners&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/lawvu-a-cloud-based-platform-for-in-house-legal-teams-raises-17m-nzd-from-insight-partners/embed/#?secret=0YOfDSCc6N" data-secret="0YOfDSCc6N" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Dominic Woolrych, co-founder and chief executive officer of Lawpath, said he decided to create Lawpath while working for a large law firm, where he realized that many legal services are inaccessible to small businesses. About 98% of businesses in the world are SMEs, he told TechCrunch in an email, and 87% of them don’t seek legal help because of cost and access issues.</p>
<p>“There are millions of legal transactions that happen every day that small businesses don’t seek legal advice on simply because they can’t afford to and it’s leaving them unprotected,” he said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Lawpath’s customers are typically businesses that make less than $5 million in revenue and have up to 20 employees. About 40% of them work in online sectors, like e-commerce or the gig economy, and there has recently been an increase in professional service providers, like financial planners, accountants and other lawyers, signing up for the platform.</p>
<p>The company’s plans start at $29 AUD a month, and its most popular tier is the $89 per month “Legal Advice” plan, which includes unlimited 30-minute phone calls with a lawyer. Other services include <a href="https://lawpath.com.au/business-registrations">business registration plans </a>that automatically set up a company, completes government and tax registration and manages ongoing legal and compliance tasks, and a <a href="https://lawpath.com.au/quick-quotes">lawyer marketplace</a>.</p>
<p>Woolrych said Lawpath has seen an uptick in use during the pandemic as more companies rely on its team accounts, legal document collaboration features and e-signature tool to perform remote work. Demand for its business registration and legal plan subscriptions have also increased as people launch side hustles during lockdowns.</p>
<p>In terms of localization as it expands geographically, Lawpath’s SaaS platform acts as the underlying infrastructure for legal documents, APIs and lawyers, so it can move into new markets quickly, Woolrych said.</p>
<p>“We saw Lawpath following a similar path to accounting platform Xero,” he added. “Xero is an accounting infrastructure that small businesses use to complete their accounting. Xero has moved into many new markets by injecting local accounting methods into its platform. Lawpath can do the same for legal and become the ‘Xero of Law.’ ”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vmXlrtLtnN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/canadas-newest-unicorn-clio-raises-110m-at-a-1-6b-valuation-for-legal-tech/">Canada&#8217;s newest unicorn: Clio raises $110M at a $1.6B valuation for legal tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Canada&#8217;s newest unicorn: Clio raises $110M at a $1.6B valuation for legal tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/canadas-newest-unicorn-clio-raises-110m-at-a-1-6b-valuation-for-legal-tech/embed/#?secret=vmXlrtLtnN" data-secret="vmXlrtLtnN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/lawpath-gets-7-5m-aud-to-become-the-asia-pacifics-legalzoom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211726</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Equity Monday: Byju&#8217;s raises more money, somehow, as tech stocks fall</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/equity-monday-byjus-raises-more-money-somehow-as-tech-stocks-fall/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/equity-monday-byjus-raises-more-money-somehow-as-tech-stocks-fall/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 17:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[byju's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ladder]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211863</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. This is Equity Monday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/3ec05a20-d321-4c9f-b215-266bb663e8f2?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>This is Equity Monday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You can follow the show on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/equitypod">here</a>. I <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">also tweet</a>.</p>
<p>Sorry that the show is so delayed today, it&#8217;s utterly my fault. Regular service returns Wednesday, and we&#8217;ll make sure to not be late on a Monday again this year! Here&#8217;s what we got into on the show:</p>
<ul>
<li>Tech shares are falling in America in a larger domestic selloff &#8212; but once again we&#8217;re seeing high-valued technology stocks lose the most ground. Software companies are having a particularly rough morning.</li>
<li>The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-whistleblower-reveals-identity-says-company-chooses-profits-over-safety/">Facebook whistleblower situation</a> remains the biggest news item in the technology world this morning, dominating aggregators and conversation. Precisely what comes next isn&#8217;t clear, I reckon, but Facebook shares haven&#8217;t lost enough ground yet to be a worry for the firm; that could change with another few days&#8217; declines, however.</li>
<li>What else was on our mind? <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-doesnt-make-videogames-but-its-the-hottest-player-in-gaming-11633147211">Apple&#8217;s epic gaming profits</a>, <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2021/10/03/what-we-can-learn-from-chinas-proposed-ai-regulations/">new AI guidelines from China</a> and <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/mergers-money-investments-in-chips-hit-record-level-as-tech-giants-look-to-design-their-own/">data concerning just how much money semiconductor startups are raising</a>. It&#8217;s more, but is it <em>enough</em>?</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/indian-edtech-giant-byjus-valued-at-18-billion-in-new-funding/">Byju&#8217;s raised $300 million</a>, this time at an $18 billion valuation. Its upcoming IPO will help set the tone for global edtech valuations.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/ladder-raises-100m-on-a-900m-valuation-for-a-platform-selling-flexible-term-life-insurance/">Ladder raised $100 million</a>, proving that the insurtech market is still active. Sure, shares of public insurtech startups have taken a pounding in recent quarters, but there&#8217;s still plenty of private capital ready to make bets on the market.</li>
<li>And the Vision Fund 2 is <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-03/softbank-is-cutting-more-deals-with-fewer-staff-than-ever-before">even more Vision Fund-y than we anticipated</a>!</li>
</ul>
<p>Chat soon!</p>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 a.m. PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts!</i></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/equity-monday-byjus-raises-more-money-somehow-as-tech-stocks-fall/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211863</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tech stocks drop as Q4 begins; software shares, Facebook plunge 5%</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/tech-stocks-drop-as-q4-begins-software-shares-facebook-plunge-5/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/tech-stocks-drop-as-q4-begins-software-shares-facebook-plunge-5/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 17:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Earnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Besssemer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messenger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tech stocks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211972</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What&#8217;s the opposite of stonks? Shares of technology companies are sharply lower in the United States today, with the tech-heavy Nasdaq Composite falling 2.4% in early-afternoon trading. Inside of the larger tech industry, things are even worse. The WisdomTree Cloud Computing Fund, essentially a way to trade the Bessemer Cloud Index as an aggregate, is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">What&#8217;s the opposite of stonks?</p>
<p>Shares of technology companies are sharply lower in the United States today, with the tech-heavy Nasdaq Composite falling 2.4% in early-afternoon trading.</p>
<p>Inside of the larger tech industry, things are even worse. The WisdomTree Cloud Computing Fund, essentially a way to trade <a href="https://cloudindex.bvp.com/">the Bessemer Cloud Index</a> as an aggregate, is off some 5%. The Bessemer Cloud Index tracks a basket of public software companies, which provide their services largely through hosted (SaaS) or on-demand (API) methods.</p>
<p>TechCrunch doesn&#8217;t bring you intraday trading updates much, but because these come on the heels of larger declines, the damage is starting to pile up.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq is off 7.7% from its recent highs. That&#8217;s not <em>that</em> bad. It&#8217;s not even a technical correction, a movement that requires a 10% decline from recent highs. A bear market, as a reminder, is a <em>20%</em> correction from recent highs.</p>
<p>The SaaS and cloud market is in the worst shape, falling nearly 13% as of today&#8217;s declines. Public software companies are in a correction and are on their way toward a bear market if any more days like today crop up.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s more afoot, of course. Shares of social giant Facebook are off a little more than 5% after the company endured &#8212; even for it &#8212; a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/facebook-grilled-in-senate-hearing-over-teen-mental-health/">punishing news cycle in recent weeks</a>. A whistleblower who leaked internal Facebook material <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-whistleblower-reveals-identity-says-company-chooses-profits-over-safety/">came forward over the weekend</a>, leading to another round of coverage that Facebook would like to forget.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Then, today, Facebook&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-messenger-instagram-whatsapp-are-all-down/">entire suite of services</a> &#8212; Facebook, Messenger, Instagram, WhatsApp &#8212; went down due to an issue with its servers.</p>
<p>Shares of Facebook are off about 15.5% from recent highs, putting Zuckerberg&#8217;s empire in even worse shape than SaaS. This is despite a bullish advertising market.</p>
<p>All told, this is not the way that the stock market would have wanted to kick off its first full trading week of Q4. And because we&#8217;re expecting a few more IPOs before the end of 2021, it&#8217;s an ominous kickoff to the final public-offering push of the year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/tech-stocks-drop-as-q4-begins-software-shares-facebook-plunge-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211972</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
