<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 14:02:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Apple launches Fitness+ group workouts powered by SharePlay</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/apple-launches-fitness-group-workouts-powered-by-shareplay/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/apple-launches-fitness-group-workouts-powered-by-shareplay/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 14:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple one]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224079</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple has launched a new way for Fitness+ users to work out or meditate with people in other locations through group workouts powered by SharePlay. The tech giant first teased the feature at its September 14th virtual event. Fitness+ subscribers can use SharePlay to start a group workout or meditation session with up to 32 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple has <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/10/fitness-plus-introduces-workouts-and-meditations-with-shareplay/">launched</a> a new way for Fitness+ users to work out or meditate with people in other locations through group workouts powered by SharePlay. The tech giant first <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apple-adds-fitness-updates-including-a-group-workout-feature/">teased</a> the feature at its September 14th virtual event.</p>
<p>Fitness+ subscribers can use SharePlay to start a group workout or meditation session with up to 32 other people while using FaceTime on an iPhone or iPad. The Fitness+ session will stream completely in sync for everyone on the call.</p>
<p>To begin a group session, users need to start a FaceTime call and navigate to the Fitness+ app. From there, you can select a workout and get started. SharePlay also works with Apple TV so users can follow the workout on a larger screen while staying connected with their friends on FaceTime through their iPhone or iPad.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224079" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Apple notes that when you work out in a group through SharePlay, you’ll see their metrics and progress toward closing their Activity rings. When someone closes their Activity rings during a workout, everyone in the session will be notified.</p>
<p>Additionally, Fitness+ will be available in 15 new countries on November 3rd, including Austria, Brazil, Colombia, France, Germany, Indonesia, Italy, Malaysia, Mexico, Portugal, Russia, Saudi Arabia, Spain, Switzerland, and the United Arab Emirates. Fitness+ will be available in English, with subtitles in Brazilian Portuguese, English, French, German, Italian, Russian, and Spanish.</p>
<p>The service is currently available in the U.S., Canada, Ireland, New Zealand, Australia and the U.K. With this upcoming expansion, Fitness+ will be available in 21 countries in total.</p>
<p>Apple also says that ​​beginning November 1, 2021, around 3 million fully insured UnitedHealthcare members in the U.S. will be able to enroll with Apple Fitness+ for a year-long subscription, at no additional cost as part of their plan benefits.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Fitness+ is also introducing a new episode of its Time to Walk series, which is an immersive audio walking experience, with actor and disability advocate Marilee Talkington. In this episode, she talks about defying expectations and how she helps empower others to do the same.</p>
<p>Apple <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/apple-fitness-launches-on-december-14/">launched</a> Fitness+ on December 14, 2021, and has since worked to compete with other subscription fitness offerings, including Peloton. Fitness+ is available as a <a href="https://www.apple.com/apple-fitness-plus/">standalone subscription</a> for $9.99 per month, or as a part of the <a href="https://www.apple.com/apple-one/">Apple One Premier</a> plan for $29.95 per month, which gives users access to Apple Music, Apple TV+, Apple Arcade, Apple News+, and iCloud+ with 2TB of storage.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/apple-launches-fitness-group-workouts-powered-by-shareplay/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224079</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crossbeam lands $76M Series C as network effect fuels partner cloud growth</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/crossbeam-lands-76m-series-c-as-network-effect-fuels-partner-cloud-growth/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/crossbeam-lands-76m-series-c-as-network-effect-fuels-partner-cloud-growth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 14:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crossbeam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partnership tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Crossbeam founder and CEO Bob Moore founded his startup to help companies building sales partnerships understand their overlapping accounts, using a process called account mapping. He knew that eventually the company would benefit from a network effect as customers attracted other partners to the network. As that vision has come to fruition, it has caught [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://crossbeam.com">Crossbeam</a> founder and CEO Bob Moore founded his startup to help companies building sales partnerships understand their overlapping accounts, using a process called account mapping. He knew that eventually the company would benefit from a network effect as customers attracted other partners to the network. As that vision has come to fruition, it has caught the attention of investors and today the company announced a $76 million Series C.</p>
<p>Andreessen Horowitz led the round with participation from prior round lead investors Redpoint Ventures, FirstMark Capital, First Round Capital and Uncork Capital along with Salesforce Ventures, HubSpot Ventures and Okta Ventures. The company has now raised almost $117 million with today&#8217;s investment, according to Crunchbase data.</p>
<p>Moore says that the network effect was what is attracting investors and it provides an easy way for the company and its investors to measure success by looking at the network graph. &#8220;So all the ways that we think about if the business is working and how we measure success tends to revolve around the growth in this network graph and how many new companies are coming on board,&#8221; he said.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224064" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>That&#8217;s because many of these companies joined because they were recruited by other companies. They also can look at how deeply engaged they are in terms of using the platform and how they are collaborating across company lines, he explained. When you look at the growth from inception today, you can see that.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2224065" style="width: 489px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2224065" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2224065" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CrossbeamGrowth-Small.gif?w=479" alt="Crossbeam network growth since inception." width="479" height="281" /><p id="caption-attachment-2224065" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Crossbeam</p></div></p>
<p>Further, over the last year, they have been attracting much larger companies, which has grown the network even faster. &#8220;One of the biggest changes in the last year is that we started landing very large enterprise accounts that have these really amazing ecosystems that almost serve as their own centers of gravity [in the partnership graph],&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>He says that early on they were selling to partner teams, but now they are also moving into sales and marketing and that&#8217;s helping feed valuable data into systems like Salesforce and Hubspot (which not coincidentally are also investors). &#8220;That wider interest is driven by these integrations into products like Salesforce and HubSpot and Slack where the data can flow into where people are doing their work and actually allow them to get the answers to these questions and measure where the impact is coming from in their partner ecosystems.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In fact, it&#8217;s only when companies start putting Crossbeam data to work that they start paying. &#8220;We have a freemium model, so you can join for free, you can have unlimited partners for free and you can connect all your data for free. The point at which you start paying is when you want to take the data that you&#8217;ve been able to acquire through Crossbeam and have it exit the Crossbeam system and go out into another platform [like Salesforce],&#8221; Moore said.</p>
<p>So far that network has grown to 5000 companies. He says that about 20% of participants have become paying customers, which is a pretty standard ratio. Today, the company has around 65 employees with plans to get to 80 by the end of the year.</p>
<p>When we spoke to Moore at the time of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/06/crossbeam-announces-25m-series-b-to-keep-growing-partnerships-platform/">the company&#8217;s $25 million Series B</a> in August 2020, he talked about diversity and inclusion as part of the entire recruiting process and the culture he and the executive team are trying to create at the company &#8212; and he says that has continued as the company has grown.</p>
<p>&#8220;We talk about it openly and regularly in our executive team meetings. We have a diversity, equity and inclusion committee internally that is responsible for internal cultural efforts and checks and balances on all of our own processes, which is made up of a diverse array of employees. I think the bottom line is that our diversity numbers and representation among all ranks of the company has held up or gotten even better since the time of the Series B,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>He adds that even in a tight employment market, they have been able to attract talent because people want to work at a company that is growing quickly and attracting investors as Crossbeam is.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re a B2B company that feels almost like a consumer business in some ways because of all these network effects…and we have a great story to tell and the company is growing very rapidly. We have amazing investors and it shows in the data and we&#8217;re very transparent culturally about how things are going,&#8221; he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/crossbeam-lands-76m-series-c-as-network-effect-fuels-partner-cloud-growth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224064</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gusto buys Remote Team in bid to support more international hiring</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/gusto-buys-remoteteam-com-in-bid-to-support-more-international-hiring/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/gusto-buys-remoteteam-com-in-bid-to-support-more-international-hiring/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 14:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223817</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The labor market is changing. More workers expect to keep working in a remote manner, even if many large employers are reticent to support the movement. The longer the pandemic drags on, the more it appears that work will look quite different in the future. As TechCrunch has reported, startups have already cast their lots [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The labor market is changing. More workers expect to keep working in a remote manner, even if many large employers are <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578804/apple-employees-work-from-home-request-denied-hybrid-model">reticent to support the movement</a>. The longer the pandemic drags on, the more it appears that work will look quite different in the future. As TechCrunch has reported, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/28/the-remote-work-argument-has-already-been-won-by-startups/">startups have already cast their lots in with a remote future</a>, often building their early teams across time zones and geographies.</p>
<p>The trend is pronounced enough that we&#8217;re seeing private tech companies get acquisitive to better support it. This morning, for example, payroll and HR provider <a href="https://gusto.com/">Gusto</a> announced that it is buying <a href="https://www.remoteteam.com/">Remote Team</a>, a startup that focuses on supporting far-flung staff.</p>
<p>As part of its news item, Gusto also announced that it now supports paying contractors in 80 countries and quick tax registration in all 50 American states.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223817" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Remote Team, unlike Gusto, is an early-stage startup. Crunchbase has but a <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/remoteteam/company_financials">dusting of data</a> regarding its history and capital raises, for example. In the view of <a href="https://twitter.com/joshuareeves">Gusto CEO Josh Reeves</a>, Remote Team was at around the Series A stage of startup life. Putting current fundraising trends aside, that means that the smaller firm likely had customers and a go-to-market motion that was just hitting its stride.</p>
<p>In contrast, Gusto has raised nearly $700 million in capital, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/gusto/company_financials">again according to Crunchbase data</a>, most recently <a href="https://news.yahoo.com/hr-software-company-gusto-raises-144746285.html">adding $175 million to its accounts at a valuation of just under $9.5 billion</a>. Gusto is, therefore, in the current parlance, essentially a decacorn.</p>
<p>Or, as we like to think of it at TechCrunch, a company that should go public.</p>
<p>Regardless of our views of the current late-stage unicorn market, Gusto could offer Remote Team something that simply raising more capital could not, namely scale. Per Remote Team <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sahinboydas/">CEO and founder Sahin Boydas</a>, selling his company to Gusto made sense because it could offer more reach into the global corporate footprint than raising oodles more private funds would allow the startup on its own.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Boydas indicated that support for more countries is coming, implying that Gusto&#8217;s ability to support international hires will only grow in the coming quarters.</p>
<p>Terms of the transactions were not disclosed, but Gusto&#8217;s CEO did indicate that equity was a component of the transaction. Translating that a little, the deal was executed in both stock and cash. Regarding the latter element, Reeves told TechCrunch that his company&#8217;s Series E earlier this year was not put together to fund the company&#8217;s day-to-day operations; Gusto still had most of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/24/smb-payroll-startup-gusto-raises-200m-series-d-plans-rd-expansion-to-nyc/">its preceding round in the bank</a>. You raise extra capital when you can, and, we&#8217;d add, when you want to buy some smaller companies that have tech or staff that you want to tack on to your current business.</p>
<p>We&#8217;d not be utterly shocked if Gusto bought another company or two before it goes public. (The company has now purchased three smaller firms, counting Remote Team. The previous two were Ardius and Symmetry, for those curious.)</p>
<p>On that front, Gusto said that it is growing at around 50% per year, but didn&#8217;t share more than that. TechCrunch pressed Reeves on the lack of details regarding its financial performance, essentially curious why he won&#8217;t share more at this juncture given that we expect to be able to look back at this period when his company goes public. As with every CEO we put that question to, the answer was polite.</p>
<p>Summing: Gusto&#8217;s small and midsized business focus doesn&#8217;t preclude it from seeing demand for more international and interstate hiring, so it&#8217;s tooling its service to meet the need. It will prove interesting to see how the larger Gusto-versus-Rippling rivalry bears out. The two companies have a history of not getting along, and Rippling recently put together its own mega-round, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/parker-conrads-rippling-is-now-valued-at-6-5-billion-more-than-zenefits-at-its-peak/">adding $250 million to its coffers at a $6.5 billion valuation</a>.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, we&#8217;re curious if Gusto and related private technology companies get into the corporate spend game, another corner of the startup work that is awash in both venture capital and market demand. You can see the synergies somewhat easily; Gusto wants to help SMBs start and run their businesses regardless of where they or their workers are based. And if Gusto is going to help make payroll work for those firms, why not add in another category of spend to the mix?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/gusto-buys-remoteteam-com-in-bid-to-support-more-international-hiring/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223817</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inside the Realms of Ruin</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/inside-realms-of-ruin-ya-novelists-failed-nft-project/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/inside-realms-of-ruin-ya-novelists-failed-nft-project/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[author]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gemini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[harvard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New-York-Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The New York Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tumblr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web 3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web 3.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“The Ruin stirs, and the Five Realms rumble,” a now-archived web announcement read on Thursday morning. “You are cordially invited to join New York Times bestselling and award-winning authors Marie Lu, Tahereh Mafi, Ransom Riggs, Adam Silvera, David Yoon, and Nicola Yoon in Realms of Ruin, a collaborative fantasy epic filled with dark magic, intrigue, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">“The Ruin stirs, and the Five Realms rumble,” a now-archived <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20211020203838/https://www.realmsofruin.xyz/">web announcement</a> read on Thursday morning. “You are cordially invited to join New York Times bestselling and award-winning authors Marie Lu, Tahereh Mafi, Ransom Riggs, Adam Silvera, David Yoon, and Nicola Yoon in Realms of Ruin, a collaborative fantasy epic filled with dark magic, intrigue, and unique characters &#8212; launched online in a thrilling new way.”</p>
<p>These celebrated young adult authors shared the announcement across social media, opening a Twitter, Instagram, and Discord server for fans to discuss the buzzy new project that would propel the traditional publishing industry into the new territory of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/what-is-web3-disrupt-ben-rubin/">Web3</a>, an evolution of the decentralized internet that emphasizes privacy, data ownership and compensation for work &#8212; maybe even fan-made creative works.</p>
<p>As the catalyst for this collaborative fantasy epic, these authors would post twelve initial origin stories about their fictional universe, to which they owned the copyright. Then fans would be tasked with writing their own stories, submitting them to the Realms of Ruin universe by minting them as NFTs on the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/14/solana-a-blockchain-platform-followed-by-top-crypto-investors-says-its-a-lot-faster-than-ethereum/">Solana blockchain</a>. If the authors were to enjoy a fan’s story enough, they could declare it part of the project’s official canon.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223512" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Within hours, fans confronted the authors in the Discord server with their concerns about the project. If the authors are inviting fans to write fan fiction about a universe they created, who owns the derivative works? Does minting those stories as NFTs affect the copyright of those stories? And how are these concerns exacerbated given that these authors’ target audience is too young to buy cryptocurrency on platforms like Coinbase and Gemini?</p>
<p>Rebecca Tushnet, the Frank Stanton Professor of First Amendment Law at Harvard Law School, summed the situation up aptly. “It’s a turducken of things people don’t understand,” she said. In other words, on top of the usual NFT concerns, the team would also be facing copyright questions and confronting the historical hesitancy from fan fiction writers over monetization of their works in a commercial environment.<em> </em></p>
<p>Along with a team of nine developers, the six young adult authors spent two months working nights and weekends to bring Realms of Ruin to life. Within hours of its announcement, the project garnered so much backlash that they pulled the plug.</p>
<p>TechCrunch spoke to a source with intimate knowledge of the Realms of Ruin project who requested anonymity. They said that the authors, who also worked with a team of developers, ended the project because they felt that there was more to lose than there was to gain.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">I wish we could pretend this doesn&#39;t exist but everyone subtweeting and asking if it&#39;s true only adds to the hype, so&#8211;yes. It&#39;s real. Multiple bestselling authors joined together to get involved with NFTs. <a href="https://t.co/2NHEmzHZrV">pic.twitter.com/2NHEmzHZrV</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Amanda Woody <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f383.png" alt="🎃" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@AmandaWoody_) <a href="https://twitter.com/AmandaWoody_/status/1450874823802982404?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The project ultimately imploded due to a combination of factors. The targeted demographic had concerns over the environmental impacts related to minting NFTs, but they also didn&#8217;t fully understand how NFTs worked. Plus, various key elements of the project were poorly thought through in advance of the project&#8217;s announcement. And fans were worried about the legal ramifications of attempting to monetize their fan fiction.</p>
<h2>An emerging tech dystopia</h2>
<p>Young adult readers are often drawn to dystopian stories &#8212; like those from Realms of Ruin participants Marie Lu and Tahereh Mafi &#8212; which reflect their current anxieties about their existing reality, including climate change. Lu&#8217;s books, which are set in the future, foreshadow <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/uns-ipcc-report-on-climate-change-sounds-code-red-for-planet/">impending climate catastrophe</a>, so her readers are clued into the discussions around the environmental cost of minting NFTs.</p>
<p>Blockchains like Ethereum and Bitcoin can be less efficient because both networks are validated using &#8220;proof of work,&#8221; an algorithm that verifies the legitimacy of a transaction by solving energy-intensive math puzzles.</p>
<p>So there’s cognitive dissonance to scrolling through Twitter, seeing posts about uptick in the frequency of natural disasters interspersed among news about how people are buying expensive JPGs through an energy-intensive crypto transaction that uses enough electricity to <a href="https://digiconomist.net/ethereum-energy-consumption">power an American home</a> for almost a week. Yet Realms of Ruin downplayed those concerns by touting its use of the Solana blockchain.</p>
<p>“Realms of Ruin is built on Solana to ensure low transaction costs and minimal environmental impact,” the project’s website read, before it was taken offline. “In fact, in the time you spent reading this, your body has burnt more calories in energy than it takes to mint a story on the Solana blockchain!”</p>
<p>Unlike NFTs minted on Ethereum today, transaction fees for minting an NFT on Solana can be <a href="https://solanabeach.io/transactions">less than a cent</a>. The Head of Communications at Solana Labs, a developer of the Solana blockchain, Austin Federa told TechCrunch that boiling an ounce of water from room temperature takes more energy than minting an NFT on Solana. This is partially because Solana relies on a &#8220;proof of stake&#8221; algorithm, which requires less energy to validate than proof of work. But it&#8217;s not clear the teenaged fans fully understood the difference between blockchains, based on a number of tweets we viewed about the project following its announcement, which compared minting NFTs to burning the Amazon rainforest.</p>
<p>This lack of understanding encapsulates a larger issue that crypto has to solve, which is how to make itself more comprehensible to the general public.</p>
<p class="p1">“NFTs have either been something that sells for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/beeples-69-million-nft-sale-marks-a-potentially-transformative-moment-for-the-art-world/"><span class="s1">$69 million at Christie&#8217;s</span></a>, or they’re a very crypto native thing,” Federa told TechCrunch. “I was really excited about Realms of Ruin because they were trying to bridge that gap a little bit.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Lack of planning, explanations raised concerns</h2>
<p>Another issue that arose was a misunderstanding over NFT &#8220;gas fees.&#8221;</p>
<p>It’s standard to pay a gas fee to mint an NFT. While <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/the-nft-on-ramp-is-still-too-steep/">higher costs</a> of minting on the Ethereum blockchain still pose a serious barrier to entry, minting on the Solana blockchain can cost just pennies. Federa added that the entire Solana network is designed to keep fees low in the long term. But since a gas fee transaction would be involved in adding an installment to the Realms of Ruin universe, a misconception circulated among fans that they would have to pay the authors to write fan fiction, when really the fees were a part of minting on the blockchain.</p>
<p>As vibrant fan communities thrive online for free &#8212; often with little intervention from the author of the source material &#8212; this implication was concerning.</p>
<p>“I think NFTs are just a very new misunderstood market, and I feel that it’s really hard to step back and explain it,” said Megan Manzano, a literary agent working with young adult authors who voiced<a href="https://twitter.com/Megan_Manzano/status/1450902663302950913"> concerns about Realms of Ruin</a> on Twitter. “It just felt like it could’ve been more thought out, or even if they just had a prepared facts section somewhere&#8230; I felt like there were just a lot of questions that could have been pre-answered.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Giving up your copyright for this community means the creators can then do whatever they want with your story and give no credit, no money, and does not need to involve you in any decision making for whatever deal may arise.</p>
<p>&mdash; Meg-o-Lantern<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f383.png" alt="🎃" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> says buy The Art of Running Away! (@Megan_Manzano) <a href="https://twitter.com/Megan_Manzano/status/1450904233025343503?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>There was also confusion over Realms of Ruin&#8217;s plan to sell character NFTs as collectibles. The marketing of the project made it unclear how these digital goods intersected with the collaborative storytelling aspect.</p>
<p>TechCrunch’s source said that the character NFTs were intended to be marketed toward people already onboarded into the crypto sphere, and the profits would go toward a “community treasury,” which would be used to benefit the community by subsidizing gas fees, offering crypto incentives for the best stories, or anything else the community decided. But some fans believed that they would have to collect the character NFTs in order to be able to write about those characters, and the project’s developers didn’t do a good job at communicating that this wasn’t the case on the Realms of Ruin website.</p>
<p>The element of a community treasury was poorly explained too, the source admits.</p>
<p>“In time, the community will decide when and how to use the treasury. We will be sure to work out a structure on how we can make such decisions,” one developer said on Discord.</p>
<p>“This community is currently effectively just this discord, are you saying if we all decided that all proceeds of the treasury would be donated to UNICEF then that’s what you’d do?” a fan asked.</p>
<p>“Honestly (with a bit more complexity) yes,” the developer responded. “It’s clear we don’t have all the answers you’re looking for yet, so we will work to get these for you,” the developer said.</p>
<p>Fans pointed out that it seemed irresponsible not to have these answers at the time of the announcement. Our source, however, pointed out that the project was set to launch on November 8, and that this announcement was supposed to be a teaser, rather than a complete rollout.</p>
<h2>Fan fiction, ownership, and NFTs</h2>
<p>Fan fiction is a tricky, yet fertile ground for legal questions about copyright and ownership.</p>
<p>Sometimes, top fan fiction writers can even parlay their online success into real publishing careers. If a writer can capture the interest of tens of thousands of readers online, it’s not unreasonable to believe that, with original characters and an original story, they could do the same on the New York Times bestsellers list.</p>
<p>One recent example of this phenomenon is Tamsyn Muir’s “Gideon the Ninth,” published in 2019, which the New York Times <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/18/books/review/otherworldly-science-fiction-fantasy-amal-el-mohtar.html">called</a> &#8220;a devastating debut that deserves every ounce of hype it’s received.” But Muir <a href="https://tazmuir.tumblr.com/post/188513057993/hi-youve-mentioned-several-times-in-interviews">isn’t secretive</a> that she got her start writing fan fiction. Another unabashed <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/education/archive/2019/10/how-fanfiction-improves-writing/599197/">proponent of fan fiction</a> is N.K. Jemisin, a MacArthur Foundation “Genius Grant” awardee who is also the only writer to win the prestigious Hugo Award for Best Novel three years in a row. From a revenue standpoint, E.L. James&#8217; &#8220;Fifty Shades of Grey&#8221; series might be the best example of how a writer can start their career by posting derivative stories online &#8212; before the series was an international hit, <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/fifty-shades-of-grey-started-out-as-twilight-fan-fiction-2015-2">it was Twilight fan fiction</a>.</p>
<p>But monetizing fan fiction through online platforms is a trickier matter. For example, when Tumblr announced it would roll out Post+, a paid subscription product, the company <a href="https://postplus.tumblr.com/post/657323537298833408/hi-there-as-you-might-have-noticed-were#notes">used fan fiction writers </a>as an example of a content creator who could profit from the product. This caused concern among writers who worried that putting a derivative work behind a paywall could land them in legal trouble.</p>
<p>“My main concern was that [the Realms of Ruin project&#8217;s creators] were asking their audience to come in and write a bunch of stuff, and they would then select things to be canon in their world. And the tricky part of this is that they already made this world and copyrighted it,” said Manzano. She said it wasn&#8217;t clear if the fan fiction writers would be able to do anything more with their work or if they would be acknowledged or compensated for creating it.</p>
<p>TechCrunch’s source close to the project feels differently. Although the six established authors own the Realms of Ruin copyright (at least according to <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20211020203838/https://www.realmsofruin.xyz/">the archived version of the website</a>), writers can be paid to participate in larger publishing projects where they don’t have ownership in the franchise. Over 850 “Star Trek” novels have been published, for example, but that doesn&#8217;t mean that those authors own the rights to &#8220;Star Trek.&#8221;</p>
<p>Harvard Law professor Rebecca Tushnet &#8212; who is a member of the legal team at the Organization for Transformative Works, which runs major fan fiction site <a href="https://archiveofourown.org/">Archive of Our Own</a> &#8212; said that these questions would depend on what the actual contract is between Realms of Ruin and the writers.</p>
<p>“If they’re giving permission, there aren’t copyright infringement questions, there are ownership questions. And those would be navigated by contract. But the thing that you usually expect is that the people writing the fan works might have limited rights,” she told TechCrunch. Because the Realms of Ruin project was shut down before it officially launched, contract details weren&#8217;t available.</p>
<p>“The fan fiction part is probably the least interesting part about this,” added Tushnet. “It’s not unknown for authors to say, ‘I want to authorize you to play in my world, and you can even have some of the money.’ <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/05/22/amazon-debuts-kindle-worlds-where-your-gossip-girl-fan-fiction-can-earn-you-cash/">Kindle Worlds</a> was an attempt at this, but it ultimately did not seem to be profitable, and Amazon shut it down.”</p>
<p>Fan creators are generally skeptical of projects like Kindle Worlds since they can seem like thinly veiled ways for corporations to profit off of these communities. This mistrust goes back years to the founding of <a href="https://archiveofourown.org/">Archive of Our Own.</a></p>
<p>In 2006, a platform called FanLib raised <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/fanlib/company_financials">$3 million</a> in venture capital to launch a platform where copyright owners (like ViacomCBS, which owns &#8220;Star Trek&#8221;) could host <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070819022752/http://startrek.fanlib.com/">fan fiction contests</a> to engage fans. But existing fan fiction writers criticized FanLib for requiring that all submitters, even ones who didn’t win the contest, <a href="https://fanlore.org/wiki/FanLib">forfeit the rights</a> to their work, allowing it to be used for commercial purposes. Even though these fan fiction writers obviously didn’t own the copyright to &#8220;Star Trek,&#8221; it’s still important to these creators to own the actual words that they put on the page, as well as the ability to decide if they want ViacomCBS to commercialize their work or not.</p>
<p>The controversy around FanLib sparked speculative fiction author Naomi Novik &#8212; who also openly writes fan fiction &#8212; to pen <a href="https://fanlore.org/wiki/An_Archive_Of_One%27s_Own_(post_by_astolat)">a landmark blog post</a> in 2007 under her internet pseudonym, proposing the project that would become Archive of Our Own, an ad-free, donation-supported platform run by and for fan fiction writers that states fan fiction’s case for legality up front. By 2008, FanLib was <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/disney-buying-storytelling-social-net-fanlib-digisynd-in-process/">sold to Disney</a>, which shut the site down soon after.</p>
<p>Today, Archive of Our Own<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/8/18072622/fanfic-ao3-free-speech-censorship-fandom"> prohibits its users</a> from linking to sites like Patreon or Ko-Fi to solicit tips to keep writers protected from copyright complaints that could arise from monetization efforts.</p>
<p>“The attempt to monetize fan fiction often creates a lot of controversy,” Tushnet noted. “To the extent that they want to encourage vibrant fan communities, it turns out that one of the most successful solutions over time is to let the fan community do its thing and actually limit the interactions that you have. That seems to create the healthiest situations for fandoms, and for the authors that create the works that generate the fandom.”</p>
<p>TechCrunch’s source with knowledge of the project explained that the decision to build Realms of Ruin on a blockchain was because the technology would have enabled a new way for fan fiction writers to get paid for their work while still being able to retain credit for its creation, and do so in a legal manner.</p>
<p>On the blockchain, you could more easily track the lineage of how stories influenced one another other, allowing writers to credit one another for inspiring their work. So, if someone wrote a response to someone’s story, and the NFT representing their story was purchased for a high value, then the writer who inspired it would get a cut, too. Another appeal of NFTs for artists is that every time an NFT is sold, the original creator still gets a cut. This is different from how sales work in the existing art world. If an artist sells a painting for $100, and the buyer later resells it for $1000, the artist won’t see any more royalties, unless they had a contract outlining their right to a percentage of the sale.</p>
<p>However, Tushnet argues that the use of the blockchain alone isn&#8217;t enough to solve the pressing legal questions over derivative works.</p>
<p>“The people who are into NFTs think they’ve solved some new problem, but they really haven’t. All of the interesting legal questions, their relationship to the NFT is accidental at most. Real-world law will decide what the copyright questions are,” Tushnet said. “There’s just nothing new about this. Authors used to send manuscripts on boats across the ocean, and we had to figure out which country’s laws applied.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Update: hearing that all of the authors involved took down their announcement posts on Instagram <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f643.png" alt="🙃" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>And in the discord, this was posted: <a href="https://t.co/7jTx1bHlQA">https://t.co/7jTx1bHlQA</a> <a href="https://t.co/iFyeAGcET2">pic.twitter.com/iFyeAGcET2</a></p>
<p>&mdash; sHELLy romero <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f987.png" alt="🦇" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@_smromero) <a href="https://twitter.com/_smromero/status/1450912842769739781?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<h2>The ruins</h2>
<p>In the end, Realms of Ruin was a project that only existed outside of the Wayback Machine for a few hours. But the catastrophe of it all shows what challenges will face Web3 evangelists when they try to sway communities that are rightfully skeptical about how the spirit of their existing internet communities will be protected.</p>
<p>Interestingly, the values of Web3 aren’t too different from a fan fiction mecca like Archive of Our Own &#8212; both seek to move beyond the existing model of an ad-supported internet, which offers free access in exchange for the monetization of our attention.</p>
<p>“We’re still in incredibly early days for this technology,” said Federa. He thinks that a lot of the blowback against Realms of Ruin was factually inaccurate due to consumers’ misunderstanding of blockchain-based projects. “But every project could do a better job explaining what crypto is, and why they choose to build on it.”</p>
<p>TechCrunch’s source with knowledge of Realms of Ruin said that it was probably too early to bring Web3 into the publishing world. Even as crypto thought-leaders wax poetic about the promise of an ad-free internet where creators are fairly compensated for their content, many people remain skeptical of the ecosystem. It’s hard to blame them for that when crypto communities can appear so <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/15/opensea-admits-incident-as-top-exec-is-accused-of-trading-nfts-on-insider-information/">scammy</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/08/the-cult-of-cryptopunks/">male-dominated</a>, and inaccessible from the outside.</p>
<p>“I think it’s way too early for this to be introduced,” said Manzano. “There would need to be a conversation about copyright, and what expectations, rights, and merchandise would be linked with authors. I just worried that this would be an angle that could sort of get wishy-washy if certain rules and expectations weren’t laid out. It’s just way too new for publishing to have a certain grasp on it and how to properly integrate it into deals, merchandise, and fan exposure.”</p>
<p>The source admitted that the developers and writers collaborating on the project hadn’t thought too far down that road yet &#8212; they hadn’t yet decided what would happen, for example, if a fan adapted their Realms of Ruin story into an original novel and sold it. The opaque nature of the Realms of Ruin rollout was perhaps a bigger kiss of death than aligning itself with crypto.</p>
<p>“I thought of myself as a teenager &#8212; if I saw some of my favorite authors creating something that I can be a part of, I would have jumped all over that,” said Manzano. “It just seemed like there were other ways to include fans and rally excitement that felt less sketchy.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/inside-realms-of-ruin-ya-novelists-failed-nft-project/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223512</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GM will work with dealers to install 40,000 EV charging stations across North America</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/gm-will-work-with-dealers-to-install-40000-ev-charging-stations-across-north-america/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/gm-will-work-with-dealers-to-install-40000-ev-charging-stations-across-north-america/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicle charging stations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223650</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[General Motors said it will install up to 40,000 electric vehicle chargers across North America as part of an ambitious plan to pour nearly $750 million into charging infrastructure that will help attract drivers to its electrified models. Under the program, GM will supply the charging equipment to auto dealers across the U.S. and Canada. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">General Motors said it will install up to 40,000 electric vehicle chargers across North America as part of an ambitious plan to pour nearly <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/gm-is-upping-its-investment-in-charging-infrastructure-to-increase-confidence-in-evs/">$750 million into charging infrastructure</a> that will help attract drivers to its electrified models.</p>
<p>Under the program, GM will supply the charging equipment to auto dealers across the U.S. and Canada. Those dealers won’t deploy the chargers on their property – instead, they’ll work to identify suitable sites and get the infrastructure installed. GM will give each dealer up to 10 Ultium charging stations to deploy in their community. The automaker said it will also help dealers apply for incentives and other funding programs to install the chargers.</p>
<p>GM chose to partner with dealers under the plan — dubbed the Dealer Community Charging Program —because they’re often already engaged in their local area, Alex Keros, GM’s lead architect of EV infrastructure, told TechCrunch in a recent interview. “Dealers are already pretty active in their communities, have great relationships, they know them well and so why not leverage them?”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223650" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The new infrastructure will be called Ultium Chargers, so they&#8217;ll have clear GM branding, but unlike Tesla’s Supercharging network, GM&#8217;s 40,000 new Level 2 chargers will not be a proprietary network. <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Keros indicated that the automaker has no interest in taking an exclusive network path to boosting sales of electric vehicles.</span></p>
<p>“Our view of the world is, ‘everybody in,’” he said. “We want to make sure that we’re growing the ocean.”</p>
<p>The automaker will also be rolling out three Ultium Level 2 smart chargers, for both home and commercial uses, that were developed and manufactured in partnership with EV charging company CTEK. Two of the units will be 11.5-kilowatt capacity, and the third will be a 19.2 kW unit best suited to deliver power to the forthcoming electric GMC Hummer or Cadillac Lyriq. These chargers will be used in the Dealer Community Charging Program, but they’ll also be suitable for residential use cases, Keros said.</p>
<p>The chargers will have WiFi and Bluetooth capabilities; the more powerful unit will be outfitted with a customizable screen. The stations will also be able to load balance, meaning each unit can safely coordinate the flow of energy to the vehicle. For instance, when installed at a residence that might mean balancing the flow of electricity between the vehicle and other electrical home appliances.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Through GM’s Ultium Charge 360 app, customers will be able to get data on the charger status, set a charging schedule, and view other statistics on charging habits and history. The app already lets drivers search for chargers across seven networks in North America, including Greenlots, Blink, FLO, ChargePoint, EVgo, EV Connect, Greenlots and SemaConnect. The automaker declined to provide further details on how the charging experience might differ between GM and non-GM cars, only that every EV would be compatible.</p>
<p>GM plans to make the charging units available next year, alongside the launch of the community charging program. Customers will be able to roll in the cost of a charger to their GM Financial lease or contract.</p>
<p>The automaker is moving swiftly as it zeroes in on its target of launching 30 EVs globally by the end of 2025, with plans to invest <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/gm-increases-ev-and-av-investments-to-35b-through-2025/">$35 billion on EVs and automated technology</a> through that same year.</p>
<p>“When you look at the strong portfolio, the fact that we’re going to have affordable EVs, really affordable EVs for people and we’re also working on the ecosystem they need because for a lot of people it’s going to be their only vehicle — they need to have a reliable charging infrastructure,” chair and CEO Mary Barra said during a media briefing last week.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/gm-will-work-with-dealers-to-install-40000-ev-charging-stations-across-north-america/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223650</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>As post-pandemic e-commerce booms, Rally raises $6M for Headless Checkout platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/as-post-pandemic-e-commerce-booms-rally-raises-6m-for-headless-checkout-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/as-post-pandemic-e-commerce-booms-rally-raises-6m-for-headless-checkout-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commerce ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercetools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content management systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[felix capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[headless]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[headless commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Long Journey Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Publishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224076</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You might have heard of ‘headless’ content management systems, whereby you can run a CMS without being locked into a front-end platform. Well a similar movement is coming to e-commerce. The latest incarnation of this movement is the news that ‘Headless Checkout’ startup Rally Commerce Inc., has secured $6 million in seed funding. The wider [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">You might have heard of ‘headless’ content management systems, whereby you can run a CMS without being locked into a front-end platform. Well a similar movement is coming to e-commerce.</p>
<p>The latest incarnation of this movement is the news that ‘Headless Checkout’ startup <a href="http://rallyon.com">Rally Commerce Inc.</a>, has secured $6 million in seed funding. The wider idea here is to ‘decentralize’ e-commerce ecosystems by allowing merchants to decouple themselves from the likes of Shopify, et al. There’s also a twist. Rally combines headless commerce with a Web3 token approach, which &#8211; they claim &#8211; will allow a merchant to ‘own’ a piece of the network.</p>
<p>The funding round was led by Felix Capital, alongside Rainfall Ventures, Long Journey Ventures, Afore Ventures and Commerce Ventures.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224076" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The team behind Rally previously built CartHook, a checkout solution.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HOXQlQ7XVG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/commercetools-raises-140m-at-a-1-9b-valuation-as-headless-commerce-continues-to-boom/">Commercetools raises $140M at a $1.9B valuation as &#8216;headless&#8217; commerce continues to boom</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Commercetools raises $140M at a $1.9B valuation as &#8216;headless&#8217; commerce continues to boom&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/commercetools-raises-140m-at-a-1-9b-valuation-as-headless-commerce-continues-to-boom/embed/#?secret=HOXQlQ7XVG" data-secret="HOXQlQ7XVG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Rally says its checkout is platform-agnostic, allowing Merchants to replace their existing traditional checkouts with Rally’s, or build a headless experience, with Rally as the checkout and orchestration layer.</p>
<p>Jordan Gal, co-founder and CEO of Rally said: “Merchants are too often forced to accept the mediocre checkouts provided to them by underlying platforms, and app developers are subservient to the platforms they build for. We’re offering merchants a better conversion rate with higher average order value (AOV) and the freedom to build their businesses according to their needs.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>E-commerce is exploding post-pandemic after whole populations were forced onto online platforms, so anything e-commmerce is obviously benefitting.</p>
<p>Joseph Pizzolato, investor, Felix Capital said: “The headless commerce space is booming as merchants and investors recognize the potential to create seamless and unique customer experiences across all touchpoints. Companies like CommerceTools, Nacelle, Fabric and Bolt are revolutionizing the old e-commerce stack, driving record funding inflows and sky-high valuations. We see Rally in the same category.”</p>
<p>For context, Commercetools — a provider of e-commerce APIs that larger retailers can use to build customized payment, check-out, social commerce, marketplace and other services — recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/commercetools-raises-140m-at-a-1-9b-valuation-as-headless-commerce-continues-to-boom/">closed</a> $140 million in funding.</p>
<p>But Commercetools and Rally are not alone. Others include Spryker, Swell, Fabric, Chord and Shogun.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/as-post-pandemic-e-commerce-booms-rally-raises-6m-for-headless-checkout-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224076</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Verizon partners with Amazon to offer satellite internet in rural areas</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/verizon-partners-with-amazon-to-offer-satellite-internet-in-rural-areas/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/verizon-partners-with-amazon-to-offer-satellite-internet-in-rural-areas/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Kuiper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verizon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224077</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon's 'Project Kuiper' internet satellites will be put to work expanding rural broadband coverage. Verizon is teaming with Amazon to improve fixed wireless internet access in rural areas in the US.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jon Fingas</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jon Fingas is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/lg-will-cover-nearly-the-entire-cost-of-gms-chevy-bolt-ev-recall/">LG will cover nearly the entire cost of GM&#8217;s Chevy Bolt EV recall</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/lyft-now-lets-you-pay-for-your-tinder-dates-ride/">Lyft now lets you pay for your Tinder date&#8217;s ride</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-04-04-amazon-internet-satellite-network-project-kuiper.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1">Amazon&#8217;s internet satellites</a> will be put to work expanding rural broadband coverage. <em>CNBC</em> <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/10/26/verizon-partnering-with-amazon-project-kuiper-satellite-internet.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1">reports</a> Verizon is <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2021/10/26/2320586/0/en/5G-LEO-Verizon-and-Project-Kuiper-team-up-to-develop-consumer-and-enterprise-connectivity-solutions.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1">teaming</a> with Amazon to improve fixed wireless internet access in rural areas in the US. The alliance will initially concentrate on expanding Verizon&#8217;s LTE and 5G service using Amazon&#8217;s Project Kuiper for &#8220;backhaul,&#8221; boosting coverage in areas with little or no high-speed data.</p>
<p>Amazon and Verizon later hope to offer unified internet access for industries worldwide, including <a href="https://www.engadget.com/alphabet-x-mineral-223517153.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="22" data-v9y="1">smart farms</a> and transportation. For now, they&#8217;re establishing technical requirements for rural broadband using Project Kuiper antenna tech already in development.</p>
<p>The two didn&#8217;t provide a timeline for this satellite-augmented service. Amazon recently <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-project-kuiper-atlas-v-173405832.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="23" data-v9y="1">lined up rocket launches</a> for Project Kuiper, but it doesn&#8217;t expect to have half its satellites in low Earth orbit until 2026. The full constellation is expected no later than July 2029.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224077" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>There&#8217;s an enemy-of-my-enemy aspect to this deal. Amazon and Verizon are <a href="https://www.engadget.com/spacex-starlink-amazon-fcc-delay-195245682.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="24" data-v9y="1">racing to compete</a> with SpaceX&#8217;s rapidly developing <a href="https://www.engadget.com/starlink-beta-end-date-181729796.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="25" data-v9y="1">Starlink service</a> — they both risk losing customers if Starlink claims too strong a foothold, including corporate clients <a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-cloud-spacex-starlink-deal-114507294.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="26" data-v9y="1">like Google</a>. All the same, Americans might not mind if this brings fast internet access to more parts of the country. Rural internet coverage is still far from complete, even with the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/5g-fund-rural-america-fcc-181512779.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="27" data-v9y="1">FCC investing billions in 5G</a> — this could fill in the gaps without having to wire as much of the countryside as before.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/verizon-amazon-project-kuiper-satellite-internet-133327300.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/verizon-partners-with-amazon-to-offer-satellite-internet-in-rural-areas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224077</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Testlio raises $12M to help software developers scale testing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/testing-testing-is-this-thing-on/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/testing-testing-is-this-thing-on/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spring Lake Equity Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Testlio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While software development frameworks make developing software faster and easier than ever, pre-deployment testing gets more and more complex by the day. Over the past decade, Testlio has grown exponentially and positioned itself as an &#8220;Elance for Software Testing.&#8221; In addition to its own team of 150 or so, the company now commands an army [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">While software development frameworks make developing software faster and easier than ever, pre-deployment testing gets more and more complex by the day. Over the past decade, <a href="https://testlio.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Testlio</a> has grown exponentially and positioned itself as an &#8220;Elance for Software Testing.&#8221; In addition to its own team of 150 or so, the company now commands an army of 10,000+ vetted freelance testers across 150 countries around the world. The round of fundraising enables the company to double down on its own software platform for software testing management and further shore up its sales and operations.</p>
<p>&#8220;We work with companies that produce digital products. That includes companies like <span style="font-weight: 400;">Amazon, American Express, Fox, Microsoft, Netflix, the NBA, SAP, ViacomCBS and many more. We </span>work with some really, really big companies, and we&#8217;ve become an extended part of their quality organization,&#8221; says Steve Semelsberger, who joined Testlio as its CEO back in 2018. &#8220;We also have offerings that are tuned for early-stage companies, who may have recently raised a Series A round and are looking to better scale their testing and quality capabilities.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company today announced that it has closed $12 million in Series B <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">financing. The round was led by <a href="https://springlep.com/">Spring Lake Equity Partners</a> and was oversubscribed. It included participation from Series A co-leads Altos Ventures and Vertex Ventures US. With the round, Jeff Williams, partner at Spring Lake Equity Partners, joins the Testlio board of directors. </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223779" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company wouldn&#8217;t give a precise valuation, but Semelsberger suggests that the valuation for its series B was north of $100 million.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2223848" style="width: 235px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223848" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-2223848" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Testlio-CEO_Steve_Semelsberger.jpeg?w=225" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Testlio-CEO_Steve_Semelsberger.jpeg 3024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Testlio-CEO_Steve_Semelsberger.jpeg?resize=113,150 113w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Testlio-CEO_Steve_Semelsberger.jpeg?resize=225,300 225w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Testlio-CEO_Steve_Semelsberger.jpeg?resize=768,1024 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Testlio-CEO_Steve_Semelsberger.jpeg?resize=510,680 510w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Testlio-CEO_Steve_Semelsberger.jpeg?resize=1152,1536 1152w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Testlio-CEO_Steve_Semelsberger.jpeg?resize=1536,2048 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Testlio-CEO_Steve_Semelsberger.jpeg?resize=38,50 38w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2223848" class="wp-caption-text">Testlio&#8217;s CEO Steve Semelsberger. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Testlio</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve been profitable for 10 quarters, and actually had 75% of our cash from the Series A round,&#8221; explains Semelsberger, who highlights that the company is aiming to invest heavily in R&amp;D for a while to focus on rapid growth. &#8220;A lot of <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Series B rounds now are really big, and I would consider a $12 million round relatively small. Our strategy here is to keep the total capital into the company less than our revenue run rate. It&#8217;s an interesting way to look at fundraising. But we think</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> this Series B raised can take us, possibly as far as we need to go.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Testlio has exceeded a $20 million annualized revenue run rate this year after previously raising only <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/04/12/testlio-raises-6-25m-to-expand-its-testing-as-a-service-empire/">$7.5 million in seed and Series A capital</a>. The company has increased revenue by 50% and employees by nearly 100% year-over-year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company makes the case that demand for a more impactful approach to software testing has skyrocketed with the unprecedented proliferation of digital technologies, and that product and engineering teams are under pressure to increase development velocity and deliver exceptionally high-quality user experiences.</p>
<p>As part of the fund-raise, the company carved out a significant pay-out to its existing employees.</p>
<p>&#8220;Twenty-five percent of the round will go &#8212; or has already gone &#8212; to our employees. We decided to allow anybody who had been with us for more than three years to sell a minority part of their vested equity,&#8221; explains Semelsberger. Of course, with the fresh $12 million hitting the bank account, the company is about to go on a hiring spree, and distributing some equity to its existing staff may prove to be a shrewd investment as a recruiting tool. &#8220;The idea came from experiences <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">that a number of us have had, where sometimes it does take a while for a company &#8212; especially a company that is as intentional as ours &#8212; to reach liquidity. The way we implemented this is that employees who had been with us for more than three years were able to sell up to 19% of their vested options. The idea was that this would reward people who had been here for a while and also show others who have just joined that Testlio, that the equity is really worth something.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>In addition to hiring and building out the sales org, the company is planning to invest in its own platform, designed to make complex testing processes easier to manage and resource. The platform is a SaaS solution that enables Testlio&#8217;s customers to receive burstable and efficient testing experiences powered by &#8220;an optimized mix of humans and machines.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve built a testing management platform. Today, our platform team consists of about 50 people, which includes product managers, product designers, designers, engineers, AI, ML, data scientists and so forth,&#8221; explains Semelsberger. &#8220;That team has created a system that manages the workflow of testing itself: test-case test definition, integration between manual and automated testing, and it&#8217;s also very much a logistics management system.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Testlio is exactly the kind of company that Spring Lake Equity Partners loves to work with: growing, capital-efficient, innovating effectively and in the middle of a massive market,&#8221; said <span style="font-weight: 400;">Jeff Williams, partner at Spring Lake Equity Partners</span>. &#8220;We’ve been impressed by the Testlio team over the last two years that we’ve gotten to know them and we&#8217;re bullish for what’s ahead.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/testing-testing-is-this-thing-on/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223779</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Voxel raises $3M to make warehouse security cameras more safety conscious</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/voxel-raises-3m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/voxel-raises-3m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MTECH Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voxel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223881</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Warehouses and distribution centers are already blanketed in security cameras, but unless someone is actively monitoring them, a lot of the footage goes unexamined. Voxel wants to change that by inviting its on-premises pixel-peeping machine-vision robots to take a closer look, notifying managers when something isn&#8217;t up to snuff. The company just raised a $3 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Warehouses and distribution centers are already blanketed in security cameras, but unless someone is actively monitoring them, a lot of the footage goes unexamined. <a href="https://www.voxelsafety.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Voxel</a> wants to change that by inviting its on-premises pixel-peeping machine-vision robots to take a closer look, notifying managers when something isn&#8217;t up to snuff. The company just raised a $3 million seed round to continue building its tech and rolling out beyond its first set of beta customers.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.mtechcapital.com/">MTech Capital</a> &#8212; a VC fund focusing on insurance tech &#8212; led the funding round, and its insurance focus suggests the direction Voxel has been moving with its technology. The main push is toward reducing workers&#8217; comp and general liability insurance claims.</p>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">We are connecting to existing security cameras, and we have a computer that sits on-site. It runs our algorithms looking for things that can lead to injury or high-risk situations for companies. </span>We&#8217;ll detect issues that are precursors to accidents &#8212; anything from protective equipment such as hard hats, safety vests, or safety harnesses when someone&#8217;s elevated,&#8221; explains Alex Senemar, CEO of Voxel. In addition to personal safety equipment, the company&#8217;s tech can detect issues with powered vehicles, like trucks, forklifts and carts. &#8220;We&#8217;re looking at powered vehicle safety &#8212; are people speeding, not stopping at intersections, or other types of unsafe behaviors. We&#8217;re also looking at ergonomics risk, which is like a pretty large driver of injuries in the workplace. Anything from lifting, poor lifting form, overreaching. We also detect spills, to prevent slip-and-fall accidents, blocked aisles and vehicles that are parked where they shouldn&#8217;t be.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223881" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2223905" style="width: 2890px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223905" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2223905 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Voxel_Dashboard.png" alt="" width="2880" height="1700" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Voxel_Dashboard.png 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Voxel_Dashboard.png?resize=150,89 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Voxel_Dashboard.png?resize=300,177 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Voxel_Dashboard.png?resize=768,453 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Voxel_Dashboard.png?resize=680,401 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Voxel_Dashboard.png?resize=1536,907 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Voxel_Dashboard.png?resize=2048,1209 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Voxel_Dashboard.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2880px) 100vw, 2880px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2223905" class="wp-caption-text">Screenshot of the Voxel dashboard.</p></div></p>
<p>The company was founded a year ago, and quickly scaled to a staff of 11. The company&#8217;s longer-term vision is to become a &#8220;Risk OS&#8221; for site management. The team suggests that it is particularly focused on behavioral change and site culture, rather than a more punitive approach.</p>
<p>To date, Voxel has had four beta customers, two of whom converted into paying customers. The company&#8217;s pricing plan starts at $50,000 per month per site, which includes the first set of cameras, and goes up from there as a company adds more sites and more cameras to the mix.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have some great initial customers and we started seeing some incredible results, with the impact of the six-month trial periods. The customers started converting, and our goal right now is to get our business to a scaleable place,&#8221; says Senemar. &#8220;At our first site, they were having an injury per month. During the six months of our trial, they had zero. It&#8217;s too early to say that that&#8217;s statistically significant, and we need a lot more of these studies to start showing the value of preventative monitoring, but we are off to an extremely promising start.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company runs a hybrid architecture, where all the initial analysis and computer vision is done by adding an on-premises computer. If a safety event is detected, that is uploaded and made accessible on the SaaS online dashboard.</p>
<p>&#8220;We believe Voxel’s technology is a gamechanger in the category of workplace safety, both in monitoring and risk prevention,” said Brian McLoughlin, co-founder and partner at MTech Capital. “We have seen countless workplace safety solutions using wearables and other IoT sensors, but Voxel is the first solution that can drive down insurance costs and improve safety using a company’s existing security camera infrastructure. The customer can see a 360-degree view of the worksite with the ability to spot dangerous conditions and intervene in real time.&#8221;</p>
<p>I suggested to the founder that building a company around a highly litigious market like the U.S. could limit the international expansion possibilities for Voxel in the long run, but the CEO of the company disagreed. &#8220;As things get more litigious, the cost of these things are significantly more. Injuries are pretty expensive in general, but I think there&#8217;s definitely countries where the value prop is much more clear,&#8221; says Senemar, suggesting that countries in Western Europe spend a lot of money in this space too, but more for regulatory reasons rather than due to litigation risk. &#8220;Safety monitoring can often be a reactive and manual process, and it can be difficult to identify the root cause of injuries. In 2019 alone, U.S. employers spent $171 billion on more than 5 million injuries. Our technology gives them a way to prevent these injuries on a scale that would be nearly impossible to do without it.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/voxel-raises-3m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223881</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Immunefi raises $5.5M to squash Web3 Crypto bugs which might cost billions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/immunefi-raises-5-5m-to-squash-web3-crypto-bugs-which-might-cost-billions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/immunefi-raises-5-5m-to-squash-web3-crypto-bugs-which-might-cost-billions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bancor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bugcrowd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compound]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyberwarfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Decentralized Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HackerOne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IDEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prime Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224059</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Traditional Web site and app bug bounty platforms, such as HackerOne and BugCrowd, have been successful in that old world model. But there is a massive difference between the existing ‘Web2’ bug bounties and the new era of &#8216;Web3&#8217; bugs associated with blockchains and Crypto. In the era of Decentralised Finance (DeFi), Web3 bug bounties [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Traditional Web site and app bug bounty platforms, such as HackerOne and BugCrowd, have been successful in that old world model. But there is a massive difference between the existing ‘Web2’ bug bounties and the new era of &#8216;Web3&#8217; bugs associated with blockchains and Crypto. In the era of Decentralised Finance (DeFi), Web3 bug bounties take on the critical nature of being associated with actual monetary value, not just software bugs.</p>
<p>This would perhaps explain why <a href="https://immunefi.com/">Immunefi</a>, one of the emerging bug bounty and security services platforms for DeFi, has now raised $5.5M in funding led by <a href="https://www.electriccapital.com/">Electric Capital</a>. Also participating is Blueprint Forest, Framework Ventures, Bitscale Capital, P2P Capital, IDEO Colab, The LAO, BR Capital, 3rd Prime Ventures, North Island Ventures, and other individual investors. </p>
<p>With DeFi, billions of dollars in user funds are locked in smart contracts, visible and accessible to all. And the stakes are high. In 2020, hackers <a href="https://www.jdsupra.com/legalnews/decentralized-finance-risks-regulation-9351911/">stole</a> about $120 million from DeFi protocols in 15 separate attacks. And the problems are only getting bigger.  Hackers <a href="https://defiyield.app/rekt-database">netted</a> more than $1.7 billion this year. Polygon, which connects Ethereum blockchain networks, paid out $2,000,000 via Immunefi to a whitehat hacker who discovered a vulnerability that had put approximately $850 million of capital at risk.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224059" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Immunefi says its bug bounty platform for smart contracts and crypto projects enables security researchers to review code, disclose vulnerabilities, and get paid to do so. It also allows companies to access security talent.</p>
<p>Mitchell Amador, Founder, and CEO of Immunefi said: “DeFi is unique because vulnerabilities in code represent a possibility of a direct loss of users’ money. Bug bounty programs are open invitations to security researchers to find those vulnerabilities in exchange for a reward… We believe that by helping launch such programs on Immunefi, we contribute not only to protecting DeFi projects for today, but also to shaping the tech industry for the future.”</p>
<p>Clients for its platform include Synthetix, Chainlink, SushiSwap, PancakeSwap, Bancor, Cream Finance, Compound, Alchemix and other projects.</p>
<p>The company says that recently Belt Finance paid out $1,050,000 to a whitehat hacker, via Immunefi, who had discovered a critical vulnerability in its protocol which put more than $10 million of capital at risk.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Roy Learner, Principal at Framework Ventures said: “This year, Immunefi succeeded in becoming DeFi’s leading bug bounty platform, gaining the trust of key industry players, and we are confident Immunefi is just getting started.”</p>
<p>Speaking to TechCrunch, Amador added: “The reality is that Web3 is a far more adversarial environment, which means every part of the bug bounty process works differently from before, from the submission and processing of a report, to the validation of a report, to the negotiation for a payout. Where traditional web2 bug bounties are a convenient bugfixing tool, our Web3 bug bounties are a far more critical emergency response system for DeFi projects.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/immunefi-raises-5-5m-to-squash-web3-crypto-bugs-which-might-cost-billions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224059</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oura’s gen-3 fitness ring arrives with improved sensors, custom content</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/ouras-gen-3-fitness-ring-arrives-with-improved-sensors-custom-content/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/ouras-gen-3-fitness-ring-arrives-with-improved-sensors-custom-content/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oura]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wearables]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223743</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In early 2017, Motiv captured the tech press’ imagination by demonstrating how wearable fitness tracking could live beyond the wrist. Ultimately, however, exercise wasn’t enough for the company, which quickly looked to expanding into things like biometric device unlock. For Oura, on the other hand, health has been more than enough. In fact, the company [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In early 2017, Motiv captured the tech press’ imagination by demonstrating how wearable fitness tracking could live beyond the wrist. Ultimately, however, exercise wasn’t enough for the company, which quickly looked to expanding into things like biometric device unlock. For Oura, on the other hand, health has been more than enough.</p>
<p>In fact, the company had a banner 2020, as organizations sought an outside the box solution amid the pandemic. The startup demonstrated how its various health metrics could assist in early detection of COVID-19 and other health conditions, and some of the U.S.’s biggest sports organizations happily lined up, including, NBA, WNBA, World Surf League, USA Surfing + World Surf League, Red Bull Racing, Seattle Mariners, UFC and NASCAR.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2223769" style="width: 1610px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223769" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2223769 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/HERO_Oura-Ring-Gen3-Still-Silver-Transparent.jpg" alt="" width="1600" height="1200" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/HERO_Oura-Ring-Gen3-Still-Silver-Transparent.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/HERO_Oura-Ring-Gen3-Still-Silver-Transparent.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/HERO_Oura-Ring-Gen3-Still-Silver-Transparent.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/HERO_Oura-Ring-Gen3-Still-Silver-Transparent.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/HERO_Oura-Ring-Gen3-Still-Silver-Transparent.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/HERO_Oura-Ring-Gen3-Still-Silver-Transparent.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/HERO_Oura-Ring-Gen3-Still-Silver-Transparent.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2223769" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Oura</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223743" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Over the course of its life, Oura notes that it has sold “hundreds of thousands” of rings. Not earthshattering numbers in the world of consumer electronics, but an impressive uptick for a hardware startup &#8212; particularly in a market oversaturated with various smartwatches and fitness bands.</p>
<p>Oura has succeeded on the strength of cramming an impressive number of sensors into a discrete package, offering some quality insights into things like workouts and sleep. The new gen-3 ring reaffirms the company’s commitment to its bread and butter &#8212; not surprisingly, of course, in an era when nearly all wearable makers are making a big play for health and wellness.</p>
<p>The top-line feature here is 24/7 health tracking, courtesy, in part, of a daytime/live heart monitoring. Other major features include improved temperature monitoring, better sleep tracking and period prediction. Of the latter, the company writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>Oura accurately predicts your next period 30 days in advance and alerts you 6 days before it starts, so you’re always prepared. Instead of relying solely on the calendar method, Oura takes a more holistic approach to predicting your period as your body temperature naturally changes throughout your menstrual cycle. While most tracking methods assume your cycle is the same every month, Oura’s Period Prediction adapts its predictions as your cycle changes.</p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The news also finds the company taking a much deeper dip into workout content, joining the likes of Apple, Fitbit and Samsung. Currently listed as “coming soon,” the library will launch with more than 50 video and audio sessions, focused on workouts, meditation, sleep and breathing.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2223778" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223778" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2223778" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-25-at-4.55.31-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="736" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-25-at-4.55.31-PM.jpg 2566w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-25-at-4.55.31-PM.jpg?resize=150,108 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-25-at-4.55.31-PM.jpg?resize=300,216 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-25-at-4.55.31-PM.jpg?resize=768,552 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-25-at-4.55.31-PM.jpg?resize=680,489 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-25-at-4.55.31-PM.jpg?resize=1536,1104 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-25-at-4.55.31-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1472 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-25-at-4.55.31-PM.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2223778" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Oura</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;We’ll keep expanding that library. Both educational content &#8212; understanding the effects of things like caffeine and sleep &#8212; and also guided content,&#8221; CEO Harpreet Rai tells TechCrunch. &#8220;In the beginning, you’ll see a lot of meditation, sleep sounds. We’ve expanded that library tremendously. You’ll see more and more coming there. It’s a one-stop shop for your health.&#8221;</p>
<p>Those videos, along with deeper health insight, will be available through a newly launched $6/month Oura Membership service.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you look at Peloton, Tonal, Tempo, Hydro and all of your connected fitness, it’s hardware plus subscription,&#8221; says Rai. &#8220;You’ve seen wearables go that way, too. Do I think over time, we can go fully subscription model? There may be different ways to finance this stuff &#8212; I think you can. We haven’t ruled it out. But we’ve seen more consumers gravitate toward this, because of the total cost of ownership.&#8221;</p>
<p>The ring will continue to add new features moving forward, including SpO2 blood oxygen sensing, which is set to arrive at some point next year. The ring itself runs $300 and is up for preorder now. It starts shipping mid-November.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/ouras-gen-3-fitness-ring-arrives-with-improved-sensors-custom-content/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223743</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Piiano raises $9M to help businesses protect their PII</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/piiano-raises-9m-to-help-businesses-protect-their-pii/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/piiano-raises-9m-to-help-businesses-protect-their-pii/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Armis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[papaya global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tel Aviv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vault]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wiz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YL Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223055</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tel Aviv-based Piiano wants businesses to keep their customers&#8217; data private. The company is coming out of stealth today and announcing a $9 million funding round led by YL Ventures, together with a group of angel investors that include Snyk founder Danny Grander, Armis co-founder Nadir Izrael, Papaya Global co-founder and CEO Eynat Guez, Wiz [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tel Aviv-based Piiano wants businesses to keep their customers&#8217; data private. The company is coming out of stealth today and announcing a $9 million funding round led by YL Ventures, together with a group of angel investors that include Snyk founder Danny Grander, Armis co-founder Nadir Izrael, Papaya Global co-founder and CEO Eynat Guez, Wiz co-founder Yinon Costica, as well as well-known angel investor Ariel Maislos.</p>
<p>The premise behind Piiano is that data breaches are basically inevitable, so the way to keep user data safe is to ensure that data sets are free of personally identifiable information (PII &#8212; you can see where the company&#8217;s name comes from&#8230;) and to fully pseudonymize customer data. Today&#8217;s approaches to securing this data, the company argues, simply don&#8217;t work. Companies often don&#8217;t know where all of the PII data lives &#8212; which is why so many enterprises invest in visibility tools.</p>
<p>Piiano co-founders Gil Dabah and Ariel Shiftan likened the company&#8217;s approach to how governments handle classified data. They redact the documents and store the original in a safe spot where only a few people have access. Now, if somebody gets access to the redacted document, it&#8217;s simply not that interesting anymore because all of the most important data &#8212; at least for the hacker &#8212; isn&#8217;t in it.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223055" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;What we are trying to do with Piiano is to &#8212; because data breaches are a matter of time &#8212; bring the privacy risk to zero,&#8221; Dabah said. &#8220;And this is the name of the game: it&#8217;s about the privacy because hackers will have a way into your system. Now we need to do something about the system.&#8221;</p>
<p>So on the one hand, Piiano provides tools to pseudonymize data, and on the other hand it provides a safe place to store the original data in a vault where access is restricted.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our innovation is to say: &#8216;look, just pseudonymize the data sets, segregate the PIIs into one place where you can actually watch for it and make sure that it&#8217;s safe.&#8217; Then, nobody can come in and just say: &#8216;give me everything,'&#8221; Dabah explained.</p>
<p>The company argues that the tools on the market today are point solutions, while Piiano offers businesses a more comprehensive approach. With that, though, businesses also have to change their technical and cultural approach to privacy. That may make it more difficult for a company to implement its tools, but the team also believes that its service helps developers build privacy and security right into their code instead of having to bolt it on later.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Vault, the second piece of Piiano&#8217;s solution, is currently self-hosted inside a business&#8217; cloud. As such, customer data never leaves their systems.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/piiano-raises-9m-to-help-businesses-protect-their-pii/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223055</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Australian QuintessenceLabs grabs $25M to scale quantum-safe cybersecurity solutions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/australian-quintessencelabs-grabs-25m-series-b-to-scale-quantum-safe-crypto-solutions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/australian-quintessencelabs-grabs-25m-series-b-to-scale-quantum-safe-crypto-solutions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[csiro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emerging-Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quantum cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quantum Mechanics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TELUS Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223968</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As computing power increases exponentially, the ability to secure our data against brute force and other types of attacks gets more complicated, with the scale and sophistication of cyberattacks continuing to challenge companies&#8217; ability to implement effective data access control and encryption. To increase data security, Canberra, Australia-based quantum cybersecurity solution provider QuintessenceLabs safeguards sensitive [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As computing power increases exponentially, the ability to secure our data against brute force and other types of attacks gets more complicated, with the scale and sophistication of cyberattacks continuing to challenge companies&#8217; ability to implement effective data access control and encryption.</p>
<p>T<span data-preserver-spaces="true">o increase data security, </span>Canberra, Australia-based quantum cybersecurity solution provider <a href="https://www.quintessencelabs.com/"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">QuintessenceLabs</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> safeguards sensitive data through its quantum random number generators and advanced data access control software. </span><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The startup has now raised $25 million in a Series B round to enhance its security in quantum solutions.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The latest funding was led by <a href="https://www.mseq.vc/">Main Sequence</a> and <a href="https://www.telus.com/en/ventures">TELUS Ventures</a>, with participation from Mizuho Financial Group-backed <a href="http://www.intervalley.vc/">InterValley Ventures</a> and Capital Property Group. </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223968" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">QuintessenceLabs will use the Series B funding to expand its customer base, including private and public organizations in financial services, cloud providers, government agencies and defense sectors globally, CEO and founder of QuintessenceLabs <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/vikram-sharma-2">Vikram Sharma</a> told TechCrunch. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">QuintessenceLabs uses quantum physics to build data security tools and has developed qStream, a quantum random number generator (QRNG) that provides encryption keys with full entropy, which means they are truly random, Sharma explained. The market for this type of technology was small when QuintessenceLabs started in 2008, and it took time to mature and bring it to a commercial level, he said. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">&#8220;We have spent more than a decade getting the technology right and preparing for commercial adoption,&#8221; Sharma said. </span></p>
<p>The company sells its product to global corporations, Sharma said. In the last year, one of its significant achievements was making the approved products list for a $2 billion program run by the U.S. Department of Homeland Security, focused on strengthening data protection across participating agencies, Sharma told TechCrunch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The Australia-headquartered company opened an office in the U.S. in 2013 with an initial team of three people to make a more significant commitment to the U.S. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">As the U.S. is by far the largest cybersecurity market, QuintessenceLabs will continue to grow its team in the U.S. over the next two to three years, Sharma said. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The U.K. is the second-largest cybersecurity market and somewhat similar to Australia in terms of market dynamics, legal systems, and business culture, according to Sharma. In the first half of next year, QuintessenceLabs plans to set up an office in the U.K. that is also an ideal location for its EMEA headquarters, Sharma said, adding that it is in discussions with several U.K. institutions for strategic partnerships. </span><span data-preserver-spaces="true">In parallel, QuintessenceLabs is developing partnerships in Japan and India, Sharma noted. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">QuintessenceLabs deferred its growth plans to 12-15 months due to the uncertainty caused by a global pandemic, Sharma said. The company will implement a planned geographic and sectoral expansion strategy as the world starts to reopen around 2022, he mentioned. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Australia&#8217;s national science agency CSIRO <a href="https://www.csiro.au/en/work-with-us/services/consultancy-strategic-advice-services/csiro-futures/futures-reports/quantum">recently released a report on Australia&#8217;s quantum industry</a> in which it forecasts an $86 billion global market size in the quantum industry by 2040. The quantum communications and cybersecurity market is expected to account for about $16 billion globally. Australia&#8217;s quantum technology is projected to generate more than $4 billion in revenues and 16K new jobs by 2040, as per the report. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The company has 50 employees as of September 2021. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">&#8220;Safeguarding data – our most valuable resource – has never been more critical, and we look forward to this exciting new growth stage,&#8221; said CEO and founder of QuintessenceLabs Vikram Sharma. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">&#8220;As computing power increases exponentially, the tools needed to secure critical data and assets must stay several steps ahead,&#8221; said Bill Bartee, Partner of Main Sequence. &#8220;QuintessenceLabs is a global leader in developing quantum-based cybersecurity tools that help protect sovereign and commercially sensitive business and provide customers with a critical layer of protection.&#8221; </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wOWfcxEKgU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/05/quantum-photonics-startup-nu-quantum-raises-2-1m-from-amadeus-capital-partners/">Quantum photonics startup Nu Quantum raises £2.1M from Amadeus Capital Partners</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Quantum photonics startup Nu Quantum raises £2.1M from Amadeus Capital Partners&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/05/quantum-photonics-startup-nu-quantum-raises-2-1m-from-amadeus-capital-partners/embed/#?secret=wOWfcxEKgU" data-secret="wOWfcxEKgU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2LZ9pZJ4Aa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/08/pqshield-raises-7m-for-quantum-ready-cryptographic-security-solutions/">PQShield raises $7M for quantum-ready cryptographic security solutions</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;PQShield raises $7M for quantum-ready cryptographic security solutions&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/08/pqshield-raises-7m-for-quantum-ready-cryptographic-security-solutions/embed/#?secret=2LZ9pZJ4Aa" data-secret="2LZ9pZJ4Aa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/australian-quintessencelabs-grabs-25m-series-b-to-scale-quantum-safe-crypto-solutions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223968</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Physical security startup HiveWatch lands $20M Series A, led by Dick Costolo and Adam Bain</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/hivewatch-costolo-bain-physical-security/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/hivewatch-costolo-bain-physical-security/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adam bain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dick costolo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223999</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[HiveWatch, an LA-based startup that uses multisensor fusion to help companies better respond to physical security threats, has secured $20 million in Series A funding led by Dick Costolo and Adam Bain. The former Twitter execs — Costolo as CEO and COO, and Bain served as COO — say HiveWatch resonated with them because of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/hivewatch">HiveWatch</a>, an LA-based startup that uses multisensor fusion to help companies better respond to physical security threats, has secured $20 million in Series A funding led by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/01-advisors-the-venture-firm-of-dick-costolo-and-adam-bain-has-closed-fund-two-with-325-million/">Dick Costolo and Adam Bain</a>.</p>
<p>The former <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/twitter/">Twitter</a> execs — Costolo as CEO and COO, and Bain served as COO — say HiveWatch resonated with them because of the pain they experienced scaling their own physical security programs.</p>
<p>”When running a company, nothing is more important than your employees. Prioritizing their safety and security is imperative,” says Bain, who along with Costolo is now managing partner at venture and advisory firm 01A. “You spare no expense to do so but, the reality is that software and hardware products serving the enterprise physical security market are woefully inadequate. They’re antiquated, disconnected from each other, and make responding to incidents impossibly slow. When we saw what Ryan was building with HiveWatch, we instantly saw the value and the future of smart physical security.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223999" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>HiveWatch claims its intelligent approach to cybersecurity helps organizations to modernize their physical security. Using sensor fusion (the collection of data from multiple sensors) and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/machine-learning/">machine learning</a>, the startup’s platform pulls data from a company’s disparate monitoring systems and security sensors to provide operators the information to evaluate and respond to alerts. This, the startup claims, can help organizations to move corporate safety operations from reactive-only responses to designing proactive programs that identify threats before they happen.</p>
<p>“Existing companies who try to solve physical security problems typically fall into two camps: they are either tech-driven or security-driven,” HiveWatch CEO and founder Ryan Schonfeld told TechCrunch. “The technically-inspired companies have leadership that is solely focused on the advancement of technology at all costs, and then there’s the security practitioner-inspired, which are too far from the leading-edge technology or the required talent to execute on the solution.</p>
<p>“HiveWatch’s approach has been to bridge the gap. We’ve brought together incredible technical and security practitioners, not just to build new tech capabilities for security programs, but to collect meaningful data from their sensors and their operational processes so security leaders can constantly improve on their existing installed systems. Failures in program design shouldn&#8217;t be identified after something bad happens. That&#8217;s too late.”</p>
<p>The startup’s Series A investment, which lands less than a year after the startup’s $5 million seed raise, also saw participation from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/lachy-groom/">Lachy Groom</a>, Elad Gil, and Penny Jar Capital, along with early HiveWatch investors Crosscut Ventures, Freestyle Capital, and SaaS Ventures.</p>
<p>Schonfeld, who previously served as a consultant for the U.S. Department of State, says HiveWatch will use the newly raised funds to build a better and more cohesive customer experience and a best-in-class engineering team focused on diversity and inclusion.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iXXyBU3tae"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/butlr-privacy-sensors-coronavirus/">This startup reworked its privacy-friendly sensors to help battle COVID-19</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;This startup reworked its privacy-friendly sensors to help battle COVID-19&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/butlr-privacy-sensors-coronavirus/embed/#?secret=iXXyBU3tae" data-secret="iXXyBU3tae" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/hivewatch-costolo-bain-physical-security/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223999</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Admix raises $25M Series B to scale up in-game ads, and prep for Metaverse gaming</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/admix-raises-25m-series-b-to-scale-up-in-game-ads-and-prep-for-metaverse-gaming/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/admix-raises-25m-series-b-to-scale-up-in-game-ads-and-prep-for-metaverse-gaming/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Admix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calvin klein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colopl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managing partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[massachusetts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metaverse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Notion Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SAM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[speedinvest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sure Valley Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224038</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last year we covered Adtech startup Admix’s $7 million Series A funding. The London-based company brings ads to games, e-sports, virtual reality, and augmented reality. In-game advertising at scale, where advertisers can bid programmatically through traditional ad-buying platforms, rather than relying on an ad agency model, remains an enormous area, largely under-exploited. Today Admix is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last year we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/17/admix-series-a/">covered</a> Adtech startup <a href="https://admixplay.com/">Admix’s</a> $7 million Series A funding. The London-based company brings ads to games, e-sports, virtual reality, and augmented reality. In-game advertising at scale, where advertisers can bid programmatically through traditional ad-buying platforms, rather than relying on an ad agency model, remains an enormous area, largely under-exploited.</p>
<p>Today Admix is doubling down on this very model, with a $25 million Series B round to scale up its ‘In-Play’ solution and prep it for new platforms like metaverses &#8211; the likes of Facebook and others are <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/zuckerberg-is-turning-trillion-dollar-facebook-into-a-metaverse-company-he-tells-investors/">clearly building</a>.</p>
<p>The new raise brings Admix’s total funding to USD $37 million.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224038" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The round was co-led by Elefund and DIP capital. Also participating is Force Over Mass, Notion Capital, Speedinvest, Rocket Capital, Colopl Next, Sure Valley Ventures, and Sidedoor Ventures as well as growth investor Kuvi Capital and angels from the gaming industry.</p>
<p>Samuel Huber, CEO and Co-founder at Admix, commented:“We see the internet entering a new stage: Web 3.0 or the metaverse, characterized by real-time 3D interactions and a new creator economy, spearheaded by the video games industry&#8230; While many players in our industry are essentially agencies, Admix is building critical infrastructure for creators to monetize their content in the best way possible.”</p>
<p>Serik Kaldykulov, Founder and Managing Partner at Elefund, commented: “Sam and Joe are exactly the type of founders we want to work with at Elefund. They created Admix and In-Play with their incredible vision for the future of digital gaming, and we believe that they will continue to play a significant role in shaping how consumers and businesses exist and interact in what the world will come to know as the metaverse.&#8221;</p>
<p>Elaborating, Huber told me that companies in the same space include Bidstack, Adverty, Anzu and Frameplay. However, he said the difference with these entities is that Admix is “building infrastructure to automate the process and serve non-intrusive ads to the right user in the right game at the right time, using data. This tech means scalability (across 300+ games and hundred of advertisers we worked with in the last 2 years, 90% are self onboarded) and network effects defensibility, which is why VCs are betting on us to dominate the category.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Admix recently signed deals for In-Play campaigns with Calvin Klein, Schuh, Movember, and Sky.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/admix-raises-25m-series-b-to-scale-up-in-game-ads-and-prep-for-metaverse-gaming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224038</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adobe continues its AI push in Creative Cloud</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/adobe-continues-its-ai-push-in-creative-cloud/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/adobe-continues-its-ai-push-in-creative-cloud/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adobe lightroom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adobe photoshop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neural network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222998</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the course of the last few years, Adobe has gone all-in on AI. At its MAX conference this year, that&#8217;s once again on full display across updates for virtually all of its products, powered by its Sensei AI platform. Those range from smarter masking tools and preset recommendations in Lightroom to the ability to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Over the course of the last few years, Adobe has gone all-in on AI. At its MAX conference this year, that&#8217;s once again on full display across updates for virtually all of its products, powered by its Sensei AI platform. Those range from smarter masking tools and preset recommendations in Lightroom to the ability to transfer colors between images in Photoshop, all the way to a body tracker in Character Animator.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve ever worked with Photoshop, you know the pain of trying to precisely select an object in order to then manipulate it. Using the &#8220;magic wand,&#8221; after all, often felt anything but magical. Last year, Adobe added the object selection tool, which uses AI to help you with that. Now, with the latest update, Adobe is also introducing auto-masking, which takes this one step further by automatically recognizing the different objects in an image. Adobe is quite open about the fact that it won&#8217;t detect everything just yet, but the company also notes that this feature will improve over time.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2223387" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Photoshop_Auto-Mask_GIF.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223387" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2223387" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Photoshop_Auto-Mask_GIF.gif" alt="" width="1024" height="677" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2223387" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Adobe</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2222998" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Similarly, last year, Adobe introduced what it calls &#8220;<a href="https://helpx.adobe.com/photoshop/using/neural-filters.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">neural filters</a>.&#8221; These added the ability to colorize an old black and white image, improve portraits, add depth blur or zoom into an image, with the neural network automatically trying to recreate all of the details.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2223389" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Photoshop_Neural-Filter-Harmonization.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223389" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2223389" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Photoshop_Neural-Filter-Harmonization.png" alt="" width="1024" height="928" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Photoshop_Neural-Filter-Harmonization.png 3310w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Photoshop_Neural-Filter-Harmonization.png?resize=150,136 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Photoshop_Neural-Filter-Harmonization.png?resize=300,272 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Photoshop_Neural-Filter-Harmonization.png?resize=768,696 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Photoshop_Neural-Filter-Harmonization.png?resize=680,616 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Photoshop_Neural-Filter-Harmonization.png?resize=1536,1392 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Photoshop_Neural-Filter-Harmonization.png?resize=2048,1856 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Photoshop_Neural-Filter-Harmonization.png?resize=50,45 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2223389" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Adobe</p></div></p>
<p>This year, it is introdu0cing a feature called &#8220;landscape mixer.&#8221; By moving a few sliders, you can make your photo look like it was taken in the fall or winter, for example, either using a set of presets or by creating your own custom ones. Say there&#8217;s a bit of a drab foreground but you want a green image; find yourself an image with a verdant green landscape to transfer that style and you&#8217;re good to go.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2223396" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/landscape_mixer.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223396" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2223396" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/landscape_mixer.gif" alt="" width="600" height="338" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2223396" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Adobe</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Also, depth blur, which was previously available, now lets you change your focal distance after the fact, which looks quite a bit more professional than the previous filter, which mostly focused on blurring everything around an object in an image.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, in Lightroom, photo editors can now use a new feature to automatically select the sky (and invert that to select everything else, too). Also new in Lightroom, though not AI-related, is a new Remix tab in the Discover section that allows photographers to share their work and lets others see the edits they made &#8212; and maybe make some changes to it.</p>
<p>For videographers, Adobe is adding a new AI feature to Premiere Pro that can automatically adjust the length of a music clip to the length of a video sequence. First introduced in Adobe Audition, the audio editor in the Creative Cloud suite, this new feature (somewhat confusingly also called &#8220;Remix&#8221;), makes sure that you don&#8217;t just fade out in the middle of a song when a sequence is over. It automatically cuts the audio so the end of the song is still there at the end of the sequence when you shorten a music clip.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2223408" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Premiere-Pro_SimplifySequence.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223408" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2223408" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Premiere-Pro_SimplifySequence.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="558" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Premiere-Pro_SimplifySequence.jpg 3990w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Premiere-Pro_SimplifySequence.jpg?resize=150,82 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Premiere-Pro_SimplifySequence.jpg?resize=300,163 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Premiere-Pro_SimplifySequence.jpg?resize=768,418 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Premiere-Pro_SimplifySequence.jpg?resize=680,371 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Premiere-Pro_SimplifySequence.jpg?resize=1536,837 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Premiere-Pro_SimplifySequence.jpg?resize=2048,1116 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Premiere-Pro_SimplifySequence.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2223408" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Adobe</p></div></p>
<p>Among some of the other updates to Creative Cloud are Creative Cloud Web, a new hub to access, organize and share files and libraries on the web. It&#8217;s still a private beta and will only be available in Fresco, Illustrator, XD and Photoshop. It&#8217;ll feature a real-time collaboration space where teams can add text, stickers and images to assets. It&#8217;s worth noting that this isn&#8217;t Photoshop or XD on the web. It&#8217;s merely a place to discuss projects and assets.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2223003" style="width: 830px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/photoshop_illustrator_web.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223003" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2223003" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/photoshop_illustrator_web.jpg" alt="" width="820" height="871" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/photoshop_illustrator_web.jpg 820w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/photoshop_illustrator_web.jpg?resize=141,150 141w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/photoshop_illustrator_web.jpg?resize=282,300 282w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/photoshop_illustrator_web.jpg?resize=768,816 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/photoshop_illustrator_web.jpg?resize=640,680 640w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/photoshop_illustrator_web.jpg?resize=47,50 47w" sizes="(max-width: 820px) 100vw, 820px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2223003" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Adobe</p></div></p>
<p>But don&#8217;t despair, because Photoshop and Illustrator on the web are also getting support for some basic editing tools in the browser.</p>
<p>As usual, there are also a slew of other updates to all of the Creative Cloud tools. What&#8217;s clear, though, is that Adobe is betting big on AI to make life easier for creative professionals and hobbyists. In some respects, it is catching up to competitors like Skylum&#8217;s <a href="https://skylum.com/luminar-ai-b" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Luminar AI</a>, which have made AI the central focus of their applications. Adobe&#8217;s advantage is the breadth of its feature set, though, which is going to be hard to replicate for any newcomer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/adobe-continues-its-ai-push-in-creative-cloud/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222998</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon Kindle Paperwhite Signature Edition review</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-signature-edition-review/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-signature-edition-review/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-reader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paperwhite]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223614</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I just pulled my iPhone off my Qi charger and tossed on the new Kindle. Honestly, not a sentence I ever expected to write. I realize this isn’t an exciting sentiment &#8212; certainly not in 2021 &#8212; but let’s face it, the pace of e-reader innovation is downright glacial compared to the rest of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">I just pulled my iPhone off my Qi charger and tossed on the new Kindle. Honestly, not a sentence I ever expected to write. I realize this isn’t an exciting sentiment &#8212; certainly not in 2021 &#8212; but let’s face it, the pace of e-reader innovation is downright glacial compared to the rest of the industry.</p>
<p>This is due, in no small part, to the fact that the competition has dwindled. Formerly big players like Sony long ago abandoned ship, and while Barnes &amp; Noble is ostensibly still in the Nook business, whatever glory days it might have had are long behind it. For big players, that pretty much leaves Kobo, which is still kicking, and, of course, Amazon.</p>
<p>And let’s be real &#8212; in terms of major scale and presence here in the U.S., well, that pretty much leaves Amazon. Like so many things it has touched, the retail giant dominates the category. That’s helped along by its overwhelming presence in the publishing industry and having one of the world’s best online billboards in its home page. It’s also not hurt by the fact that the company, on the whole, produces nice e-reader hardware.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223614" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2223710" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223710" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2223710" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0626.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0626.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0626.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0626.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0626.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0626.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0626.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0626.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0626.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2223710" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>Limited competition in the category means that we’ll probably never again see a heated race for manufacturers to one-up one another. In other words, don’t expect to see something akin to the smartphone wars &#8212; or even the kind of competition we saw in the category, say, 10 years ago.</p>
<p>For that reason, it’s genuinely exciting when a new Kindle drops. It feels like this category still has a bit of life in it yet. The line long ago took a backseat to products like the Echo and Fire TV, and on a good year, we get one new Kindle a year.</p>
<p>The new Paperwhite was announced late last month, bringing with it a few features that blurred the line between it and the high-end Oasis, as well as some genuine surprises. Wireless charging (which, mind, is only available on the “Signature Edition” for an extra $50) and USB-C firmly fit in the latter category. It’s, honestly, genuinely strange to see a new port on the bottom of this device after so many generations of microUSB.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2223711" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223711" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2223711" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0629.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0629.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0629.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0629.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0629.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0629.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0629.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0629.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0629.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2223711" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>Along with USB-C comes faster charging, topping the device up in around two-and-a-half hours (3.5 for wireless). Really, though, the main benefit here for me is that it means carrying around one less cable when I travel. The Kindle was one of the last microUSB holdouts in my regular stable of devices. Of course, that point is rendered somewhat moot by the battery life on these things. The new Paperwhite is currently rated at 10 weeks of battery life (with wireless off and 30 minutes of reading a day).</p>
<p>That’s up from six weeks, which, as far as gadget batteries go, is still very good. It’s one of the few consumer devices where you’re talking weeks, rather than days or even hours. That highlights the general strangeness around the fact that so many of the feature updates on these things tend to focus on battery and charging &#8212; though additions like audio books through Bluetooth audio certainly put more of a strain on the battery than standard reading.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2223712" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223712" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2223712" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0632.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0632.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0632.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0632.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0632.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0632.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0632.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0632.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0632.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2223712" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>The new Paperwhite looks a fair bit like its predecessors at first glance, though like the Oasis before it, the bezels and display are now flush, adding to an already solid build. Overall, it still doesn’t feel as premium as the $250 Oasis, however, dropping that model’s metal backing and physical page buttons &#8212; the latter of which is a nice luxury I do actually miss here.</p>
<p>Interestingly, there’s not a lot of difference in the screens. Both have a 300 ppi resolution (same as last gen), significantly more than the standard Kindle’s 167. The new model increases size slightly from 6.6 to 6.8 inches &#8212; just a hair below the Oasis’ seven. Both models have IPX8 waterproofing, as well &#8212; always nice for those who like to read near the pool, tub or any body of water.</p>
<p>The Oasis still wins out on front lighting, with 25 to the Paperwhite’s 17 (owing, at least in part, to a smaller screen), though the lighting is uniform and does a fine job when reading in the dark. The system gets the color temperature adjust introduced in the 2019 Oasis &#8212; a feature that reduces blue lighting on a schedule, which can be detrimental to your sleep patterns. An ambient light sensor to adjust brightness is only available on the Signature edition.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2223708" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223708" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2223708" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0623.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0623.jpg 6720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0623.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0623.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0623.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0623.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0623.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0623.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CMC_0623.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2223708" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater</p></div></p>
<p>On-board storage is the other major difference between the standard Paperwhite and Signature Edition, bumping things up from 8 to 32GB. Those are the two things I’d miss most, bumping it down to the standard edition &#8212; I’d say wireless charging is superfluous for most people most of the time on an e-reader and certainly not enough to justify the price gap between $140 and $190. That’s doubly the case knowing that the $30 charging dock is sold separately (my Anker phone charger works fine, thanks).</p>
<p>All in all, lots of welcome additions here. If you have a 2018 Paperwhite, it’s probably not worth the upgrade, but if you’re looking for a well-rounded e-reader, this is probably the one. The new features blur the lines between the premium Oasis. That $250 has a more premium look and feel, but for a majority of readers, the new Paperwhite makes a lot more sense.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-signature-edition-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223614</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adobe brings content attribution tools to PhotoShop</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/adobe-brings-content-attribution-tools-to-photoshop/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/adobe-brings-content-attribution-tools-to-photoshop/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adobe photoshop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223006</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Adobe is launching new tools in beta today to help creatives ensure that their work isn&#8217;t stolen and for the public to see how images were created (and potentially manipulated). The company, together with a set of partners, first launched its Content Authenticity Initiative two years ago. Today&#8217;s work expands on this mission to preserve [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Adobe is launching new tools in beta today to help creatives ensure that their work isn&#8217;t stolen and for the public to see how images were created (and potentially manipulated). The company, together with a set of partners, first launched its <a href="https://contentauthenticity.org/">Content Authenticity Initiative</a> two years ago. Today&#8217;s work expands on this mission to preserve provenance and attribution data for digital content in order to combat misinformation and brings it directly into PhotoShop.</p>
<p>Specifically, Adobe is launching what it calls &#8216;content credentials.&#8217; This includes an opt-in feature in Photoshop that cryptographically signs the metadata and edit history of content credentials-enabled images, as well as the automatic download of content credentials from Adobe Stock, the company&#8217;s stock imagery service. As you edit photos in Photoshop, the application will automatically update the edit history &#8212; including the use of AI tools &#8212; and a list of assets you used to create your images in the background.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2223008" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/content-credentials.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223008" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2223008" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/content-credentials.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="737" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/content-credentials.jpg 1187w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/content-credentials.jpg?resize=150,108 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/content-credentials.jpg?resize=300,216 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/content-credentials.jpg?resize=768,553 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/content-credentials.jpg?resize=680,489 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/content-credentials.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2223008" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Adobe</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223006" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Creatives can also link their social media profiles to crypto wallet addresses from within Photoshop and connect their wallets to Behance, for example.</p>
<p>For consumers, Adobe is now making it easier to see content credentials thanks to its new <a href="https://verify.contentauthenticity.org/inspect">Verify site</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/adobe-brings-content-attribution-tools-to-photoshop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223006</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adobe&#8217;s Behance adds support for NFTs and paid subscriptions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/adobes-behance-adds-support-for-nfts-and-paid-subscriptions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/adobes-behance-adds-support-for-nfts-and-paid-subscriptions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adobe Creative Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adobe max 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adobe photoshop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[behance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tezos]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2223684</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At its annual MAX conference, Adobe today announced a number of interesting updates to its Behance portfolio site for creatives. According to Adobe over 160 million people visited the site in the last year and viewed the work of the creatives on the site over 2.25 billion times. That&#8217;s a highly active community and it&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At its annual <a href="https://max.adobe.com/">MAX conference</a>, Adobe today announced a number of interesting updates to its <a href="https://www.behance.net/">Behance</a> portfolio site for creatives. According to Adobe over 160 million people visited the site in the last year and viewed the work of the creatives on the site over 2.25 billion times. That&#8217;s a highly active community and it&#8217;s maybe no surprise then that the company is adding a number of new features that will allow its users to directly &#8212; and indirectly &#8212; profit from this.</p>
<p>Maybe the most headline-grabbing feature Adobe is adding is the ability to better showcase NFT artwork on the site. Creatives can now connect their crypto wallets with Behance. The company is working to include blockchains like Polygon, Solana, Flow and Tezos. It is also partnering with NFT marketplaces like <span class="s1"><a href="https://opensea.io/">OpenSea</a></span><span class="s2">, <a href="https://superrare.com/"><span class="s1">SuperRare</span></a>, <a href="https://knownorigin.io/"><span class="s1">KnownOrigin</span></a>, and <a href="https://rarible.com/"><span class="s1">Rarible</span></a> to display provenance data from the Content Authenticity Initiative &#8212; which is now built into a number of Creative Cloud tools &#8212; visible on their sites, in addition to Behance.</span></p>
<p>Will Allen, the Adobe VP in charge of Behance (among other things), noted that Adobe isn&#8217;t interested in creating its own NFT marketplace. &#8220;We&#8217;re really just focused on enabling these creators to showcase their work,&#8221; he said. &#8220;That&#8217;s the key focus of what I think we can do particularly well as allow them to showcase their work and then make these transactions wherever they want to be.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2223684" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2223753" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Behance_Creator-Subscriptions-Source-Files-in-Livestreams.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2223753" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2223753" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Behance_Creator-Subscriptions-Source-Files-in-Livestreams.png" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Behance_Creator-Subscriptions-Source-Files-in-Livestreams.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Behance_Creator-Subscriptions-Source-Files-in-Livestreams.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Behance_Creator-Subscriptions-Source-Files-in-Livestreams.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Behance_Creator-Subscriptions-Source-Files-in-Livestreams.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Behance_Creator-Subscriptions-Source-Files-in-Livestreams.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Behance_Creator-Subscriptions-Source-Files-in-Livestreams.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Behance_Creator-Subscriptions-Source-Files-in-Livestreams.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2223753" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Adobe</p></div></p>
<p>As Allen told me, a lot of Behance users are subscribing to fellow creatives to learn. &#8220;I do find a common theme is that they want to learn,&#8221; he said. &#8220;They want to seebehind the scenes of like, &#8216;Hey, this is a phenomenal illustrator, let me just watch them create and see how to do these things. Let me get access to their PSDs, so I use those as a template and take my creativity to the next level.'&#8221;</p>
<p>Creatives can now also sell subscriptions on Behance to sell access to their tutorials, workshops and live streams. Creatives can set their own prices for these subscriptions and Adobe tells me that it doesn&#8217;t take any commission from those sales.</p>
<p>Also new on Behance is the ability to indicate that somebody is available for work. Finding job opportunities has always been the goal of many Behance users, but with the help of a new button, creatives can now make this explicit. Creatives can indicate whether they are available for freelance or full-time work.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/adobes-behance-adds-support-for-nfts-and-paid-subscriptions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2223684</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Nike innovates for everyday athletes </title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/nike-sport-research-lab-lebron-james-innovation-center/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/nike-sport-research-lab-lebron-james-innovation-center/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Henry Pickavet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 12:47:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lebron james]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LeBron James Innovation Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nike Sport Research Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222909</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Eight years ago, Nike decided it was time to expand the Nike Sports Research Lab (NSRL), which was housed in the Mia Hamm building across company headquarters. Now a full five times the size of its former self, the NSRL, which occupies the top floor of the brand-new LeBron James Innovation Center, is big enough [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Eight years ago, Nike decided it was time to expand the Nike Sports Research Lab (NSRL), which was housed in the Mia Hamm building across company headquarters.</p>
<p>Now a full five times the size of its former self, the NSRL, which occupies the top floor of the brand-new LeBron James Innovation Center, is big enough to allow collaboration among athletes, researchers and innovators as they develop the products we wear every day.</p>
<p>Studying soccer stars like Megan Rapinoe and the world’s fastest marathon runner Eliud Kipchoge &#8212; for everything from the differences in millimeters between each of their feet to the amount of force projected every time their feet touch the ground &#8212; helps researchers develop guidelines that help creators design apparel and footwear to enhance performance. Athletes also train with the support of Nike scientists in order to learn more about themselves and their bodies to benefit their performance.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2222909" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>But the NSRL is not just for the world’s elite athletes; it’s for those who play pick-up basketball games on concrete courts in city parks, neighborhood runners and expectant and new parents like those highlighted in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_-5MGkUwe6w">Nike’s “The Toughest Athlete” film</a>.</p>
<p>Matt Nurse, vice president of the Nike Explore Team Sport Research Lab, says there are times Nike tries to pursue a deeper understanding more quickly.</p>
<p>“The other type of science is this big data, observational stuff using machine learning or AI to start to understand lots of different inventions for movement.”</p>
<p>He says 80% to 85% of the people who come through the lab are everyday athletes from different backgrounds with diverse body types. With a plan to bring thousands of active bodies through the door, Nike can increase the learnings and the speed of development with the new space.</p>
<p>Nike recently invited members of the media to experience firsthand how athletes, researchers and innovators interact to develop Nike products.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2222915" style="width: 2616px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2222915" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2222915 size-full" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Center-composite.jpg" alt="Entrance to the LeBron James Innovation Center" width="2606" height="1466" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Center-composite.jpg 2606w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Center-composite.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Center-composite.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Center-composite.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Center-composite.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Center-composite.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Center-composite.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Center-composite.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2606px) 100vw, 2606px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2222915" class="wp-caption-text">Entrance to the LeBron James Innovation Center. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Rae Witte / Composite: Bryce Durbin/TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>The entranceway of the 750,000-square-foot LeBron James Innovation Center sets the tone for Nike’s commitment, nearly a decade in the making, to utilizing data and design for innovation.</p>
<p>Every one of James’ shot attempts that led to his 30,000 professional career points is mapped on the polished concrete floor in front of a golden hoop. Shots are differentiated by golden dots and empty zeros, representative of points made and missed. Milestone moments are highlighted with larger captioned markers on the floor, including his first made shot and his 20,000th point.</p>
<p>Above the main floor are the apparel and footwear prototypes: Designers and creators occupy spaces with robotics and 3D printers, as well as knit, textile and embroidery sections. There is even a replica of the Winnebago that Nike co-founder Phil Knight traveled to track meets in. Once there, he&#8217;d pass out the earliest iterations of Nike footwear in order to get feedback from the athletes.</p>
<p>The 84,000-square-foot NSRL occupies the top floor of the building and is where researchers and athletes come together to develop Nike footwear and attire. The NSRL includes a full-size, NBA regulation court, a 200-meter track, climate chambers and artificial training turf. These areas contain a combination of 92 force plates, 400 motion capture cameras and 80 prototyping machines.</p>
<p>Force plates, which Nurse describes as glorified bathroom scales, are located beneath the surface of the track, turf and basketball courts. Unlike the typical bathroom scale that offers one reading when you step on it, he says, “these measure tens of thousands of times a second in three dimensions. So not just straight up and down but side to side, back and front.”</p>
<p>For example, for a runner on the track, they’d be able to measure the force with which the foot is connecting and pushing off the ground.</p>
<p>The additional space in the NSRL allows for more fluid and less restricted gameplay and movement.</p>
<p>“One of the goals here is to allow athletes to come in full speed, full motion and also [in] continuous play,” Nurse said. “Sometimes in small facilities, the movements become choreographed, and that’s it. Now, we can have people come in and play.”</p>
<h2>Sweating in the lab</h2>
<p>To inform researchers how all of the tools within the space are leveraged for controlled experimentation and observational big data collection, Nurse said they try to understand three pillars of the triangle: “What’s the dose, what’s the behavior and what’s the response. If we have the dose, response and behavior, a prototype has to give us enough information to do that. We think it’s a solution to look for problems.”</p>
<p>On our tour of the lab, we underwent some of the same testing that Nike designed for its athletes, which included work on the basketball court, track and turf and in the treadmill bays.</p>
<p>We started with a collection of baseline data: a full body scan to determine optimal Nike apparel fit; morphological body size tracking and skeletal and muscular asymmetries; a separate, three-dimensional scan of my feet and ankles; and a barefoot walking pressure test before the Applied Performance Innovation Treadmill. I chose a comfortable speed for a jog and was instructed to run for two to three minutes while they recorded it for analysis.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8JRnTIUh5Qo?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>Researchers can provide observations on form, such as whether athletes are too bouncy, run on their toes or lean forward too much.</p>
<p>They can also make functional recommendations. For example, a runner who leans forward too much may need to strengthen their glutes or hamstrings for a more efficient gait.</p>
<p>Based on what they know biomechanically and through their algorithm development to understand products and athletes, using this testing combined with the baseline data, researchers can make footwear recommendations for optimal efficiency &#8212; whether that’s running faster, longer and/or with less stress on the body.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cHTkMwqiLmk?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<h2>The track</h2>
<p>The track itself surrounds both the turf and the basketball court, and it features force plates and motion capture cameras that can be utilized for long runs or more segmented testing, such as starts. An LED Rabbit or pacer offers another layer of control to experiments, and there’s a 100-meter concrete strip to simulate running outdoors.</p>
<p>On the track I was able to test out two different footwear options. Their Infinity Reacts are meant for protection, lower stress on the body and stability. I was able to make it around the track at a comfortable rate in front of the Nike Run Club average runner’s mile pace of 11:37 and well behind sub-2-hour marathoner Eliud Kipchoge’s pace, as indicated by a glowing green LED pacer that spun around the track all day.</p>
<p>However, when I attempted to do a lap with the elite runner’s race shoe of choice, the ZoomX Invincible, we discovered that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/how-nike-is-making-footwear-to-improve-athletes-efficiency-for-the-tokyo-olympics/">the cushion system</a> &#8212; made to be super lightweight with a carbon plate within their exaggerated foam and air system sole &#8212; was not a match for the mechanics of my feet.</p>
<p>The construction, which lends optimal efficiency for some, afforded me &#8212; admittedly a non-runner despite finding I have decent form &#8212; and my very narrow feet, previously injured ankle and flexible (or what I think are loose or weak) ankles a very unstable running experience. I didn&#8217;t even complete the 200-meter lap.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2222916" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2222916" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2222916" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Track-Nike-Sport-Research-Lab.jpg" alt="Athletes run on the track at the Nike Sport Research Lab" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Track-Nike-Sport-Research-Lab.jpg 2800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Track-Nike-Sport-Research-Lab.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Track-Nike-Sport-Research-Lab.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Track-Nike-Sport-Research-Lab.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Track-Nike-Sport-Research-Lab.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Track-Nike-Sport-Research-Lab.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Track-Nike-Sport-Research-Lab.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Track-Nike-Sport-Research-Lab.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2222916" class="wp-caption-text">Athletes run on the track at the Nike Sport Research Lab. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nike</p></div></p>
<p>This is where the range of athletes is so crucial. Studying a runner like Kipchoge is incredibly valuable. Because he is so physically efficient, he doesn’t need five hours to complete a marathon and so hasn’t ever run that long. But the global average marathon runner clocks in somewhere between 4 hours and 20 minutes to 4 hours and 40 minutes.</p>
<p>This wide range of data collection will inform footwear innovations through multiple sets of shoes, enabling Nike to develop running shoes appropriate for any runner, whether they’re an elite marathoner or a casual jogger.</p>
<h2>The turf</h2>
<p>The Turf Lab boasts the largest data capture volume in the NSRL and what Nike says may be the largest in the world. Here, force plates below the surface monitor game play and more controlled experiments, allowing researchers to collect data on up to 22 players &#8212; the amount on a soccer field during gameplay &#8212; who are moving at different speeds and directions while interacting with each other, the turf, the cleats and the ball. The turf also has a screen where targets can be projected and accuracy can be recorded for shooting and passing.</p>
<p>Two things Nike specifically focuses on for soccer players’ footwear are functionally very different — the sole for traction and the type of movement the upper requires for dribbling, passing and kicking.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2222913" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2222913" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2222913" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Nike-Sport-Research-Lab-turf-kick-1.jpg" alt="Man simulating a shot at goal in the Nike Sport Research Lab" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Nike-Sport-Research-Lab-turf-kick-1.jpg 2800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Nike-Sport-Research-Lab-turf-kick-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Nike-Sport-Research-Lab-turf-kick-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Nike-Sport-Research-Lab-turf-kick-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Nike-Sport-Research-Lab-turf-kick-1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Nike-Sport-Research-Lab-turf-kick-1.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Nike-Sport-Research-Lab-turf-kick-1.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Nike-Sport-Research-Lab-turf-kick-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2222913" class="wp-caption-text">Simulating a shot at a goal in the Nike Sport Research Lab. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nike</p></div></p>
<p>The 200 cameras surrounding the area capture submillimeter movement, and below the turf are 15 force plates. By measuring an athlete’s movement in a controlled environment, researchers can drill down into the tiniest changes to make for perform<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">ance and for protection, and a lot of the findings can apply to other field sports like baseball, football and rugby.</span></p>
<p>During the soccer test, I simulated the opportunity to take a shot on goal. This included a shuttle run as if I were tackling a defender, running around a defender and then taking the shot at a target projected on a screen within the goal.</p>
<p>In this simulation, they captured the forces when I was cutting back, the timing and agility throughout the route, the timing of my decision-making upon the appearance of the target and the accuracy of the ball with respect to the target.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/981RNphxzBo?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>The results of this test will speak to the size of the athlete, how explosive they are and how quickly they can push off the force plate beneath them. The power, in addition to the traction of the footwear, translates into the speed of their movement. If the traction were to be insufficient, the same level of force would result in a slower speed.</p>
<p>A shoe with really good traction but poor containment, afforded by the shoes’ upper, will result in the foot sliding within the shoe, because while the footwear is interacting with the ground efficiently, the foot is not.</p>
<p>By contrast, an upper providing good containment and poor traction will fit the foot, but will result in the shoe sliding on the ground. The data allows for alterations like these to be made to the footwear.</p>
<h2>The basketball court</h2>
<p>The force plates beneath the neighboring basketball court capture similar data for basketball players.</p>
<p>Fully surrounded by motion capture cameras, players wear sensors that track their heart rates and the speed of their movements on the court, which can be projected in real time on a large screen on the wall. In addition to those, a force plate with a 4K camera below it is under the hoop and can record the way in which a sneaker sole interacts with the floor.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6AGy7fRYNlg?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>Coupled with the motion sensor tracking data throughout the drill, depending on the stiffness of the sneaker or the thickness of the sole, they can track how speed is affected by the footwear, and observe and see the sole’s connection to the floor all while the sensor tracks the athlete’s heart rate throughout the movements.</p>
<p>Another camera in the hoop records the position of the ball as it goes through. The data collected from these shots provide suggestions on functional adjustments that result in a more consistent and efficient shot going through the hoop.</p>
<p>[gallery ids="2222918,2222924,2222919,2222920,2222921,2222922,2222923"]</p>
<h2>The climate chambers</h2>
<p>Understanding moisture management needs between different wearers offers designers guidelines to create more functional clothing. We toured two climate chambers, one hot and the other cold, that can regulate temperature from -20 to over 50 degrees Celsius; humidity from 10%-90%; control wind speed; and simulate the radiant heat of the sun using two different types of bulbs that match the spectral outlet of the sun’s rays.</p>
<p>The chambers can be set to such precision that their hot tank on the day we visited was set to 34 degrees Celsius and 70% humidity — the exact weather conditions on August 6 in Tokyo during this summer’s Olympic Games where some staff and athletes had to be treated for heat exhaustion.</p>
<p>Leveraging the climate chambers allows Nike to evaluate how different apparel designs or zoning of features can have the biggest impact on making garments more breathable.</p>
<p>Because sweating helps to regulate body temperature, the hot chamber is used to study sweating responses in consumers and how they vary based on sex, age and body size.</p>
<p>They showed us their Vapor Match Men’s Soccer jersey, pointing out where the changes in the knit were zoned to the most condensed perspiration areas, which can be seen in the third image <a href="https://www.nike.com/t/us-2020-vapor-match-home-mens-soccer-jersey-vXDRHv">here</a>.</p>
<p>Conversely, the Nike NSRL <a href="https://www.nike.com/t/nsrl-womens-transform-jacket-fKht8V/DB0820-010?nikemt=true&amp;cp=96413943330_search_%7cPRODUCT_GROUP%7cGOOGLE%7c71700000041489782%7cAll_X_X_X_X-Device_X_Nike-Clearance_X%7c%7cc&amp;gclid=CjwKCAjwqeWKBhBFEiwABo_XBk_BWWwhwp6j2ssabp7D6IB_8vMfkX92NE9i43d0_5FSk-a5yLVlDhoCKRYQAvD_BwE&amp;gclsrc=aw.ds">Transform Jacket</a> exhibits the manifestation of the different thermal needs for an outside run. Sleeves that zip off and tuck into chambers on the back of the jacket and removable down fill accommodates the transition from stepping outside to plateau. They’ve found that the day-to-day runner averages about 5 kilometers per run, and the biggest shift in their insulation needs is between start and 2.5 to 3 kilometers. After that, it regulates for the remainder of the exercise, which is also the case for those running beyond 5 kilometers.</p>
<p>Finally, they have thermal mannequins — that sweat! — in order to test zoning features without having to put stress on human bodies. Between the climate control and the bodies to test on that never tire, they’re able to give design teams even more to work with.</p>
<h2>The cool down</h2>
<p>We hear a lot about mental toughness in the world of sport, so it makes sense Nike would want to understand the minds of their athletes, too, particularly as they impact performance.</p>
<p>Studies and recovery at NSRL go far beyond massage, acupuncture and other bodily needs of rest and maintenance that are available in the lab. They’re also taking into account their subjects’ mental state.</p>
<p>Mental health has become a factor in discussions about elite athletes in the media, whether it’s Naomi Osaka opting out of press conferences or Simone Biles being open about her need to sit out the women&#8217;s all-around final at the 2020 Summer Olympics.</p>
<p>Before taking my baseline measurements, they gave me a cognitive assessment, and at the close of the day, we went through the learnings. Surprisingly (and probably by design), the assessment translates easily between both athletes in regard to sports as it does everyday human behavior.</p>
<p>In pointing out how uncertainty is often so much greater than certainty, the team discussed decision-making and how different results could point to whether an athlete is more prone to decision-making from a place of loss prevention or risk aversion.</p>
<p>These findings can similarly be applied to cognitive recommendations, much like the form or functional recommendations other tests offered. Not only are they trying to create better apparel and footwear, the lab is committed to furthering all aspects of athletes&#8217; abilities.</p>
<p>For example, an athlete struggling with a need for control can try to focus less on the outcome itself and more on the fact that the outcome can be leveraged as an opportunity to benefit future competitions or even process. Similarly, rather than dwelling on a moment or missed shot, sport psychologists will recommend employing mental imagery or visualizing the positive outcome for the future.</p>
<p>Ultimately, the new LeBron James Innovation Center will aid in athletes&#8217; well-being and progress as much as it will afford faster innovations of Nike’s apparel and shoes.</p>
<p>As everything is approached with steps to greater opportunities rather than ticking problems off a list with the entire team in one building, it will be incredible to see what the future holds for the space and its output.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2222927" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2222927" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2222927" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Innovation-Center.jpg" alt="Lobby of the LeBron James Innovation Center" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Innovation-Center.jpg 2800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Innovation-Center.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Innovation-Center.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Innovation-Center.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Innovation-Center.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Innovation-Center.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Innovation-Center.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/LeBron-James-Innovation-Center.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2222927" class="wp-caption-text">Lobby of the LeBron James Innovation Center. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nike</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/nike-sport-research-lab-lebron-james-innovation-center/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222909</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
